Hello, boys!
* Dee dee *
* Bom-bom, bom-bom *
* Bom-bom ba-bom-doo *
* Bom-bom bom-boom-bom **
Hey, Yaskov. How are ya?
Kendig.
What an unexpected pleasure.
- May I have it, please?
- Have what?
I got it all on film, Yaskov.
You don't wanna deal
with the West Germans.
They don't like Russian
Intelligence. You know that.
Give it to me,
and we'll forget about it.
I could make a run for it.
Come on, Yaskov.
You running, me chasing you?
We'd look like
Laurel and Hardy.
Two clowns, huh?
You're a good man, Kendig,
the best they've got.
- I wish you were with us.
- Thanks, Yaskov.
Da Svidaniya.
Lufthansa flight 22
arriving at gate 17.
Passenger Bernstein,
please go to the courtesy phone.
I didn't expect to be met, Joe.
What's the matter?
Myerson's in a sweat
because you let that Russian go.
He's talking about
the Russians in Cuba again.
Talking about
sending you to Cuba.
- Oh.
- That's why you got the chopper.
- Hi, Wanda.
- Good morning.
- How are ya?
- Welcome back.
Hi, Edie. Hi, Sherri.
- Beverly, how are you?
- Good morning, Mr. Kendig.
In here, Kendig. Cutter, stay put.
I want to see you after this.
Hi, Myerson.
I thought you were taller.
I don't remember you being this short.
How'd you get so short?
Up yours, Kendig.
Where's your report?
You haven't filed it.
I just got off the airplane.
The job's finished. What's the hurry?
Typical. It's difficult
growing up, isn't it?
Aren't you just a little senior...
to be shadowing people around
the streets of Munich personally?
I worked on thatjob
for two years.
I had a right
to be in at the finish.
You mind ifl sit down?
The object, Kendig,
was to dismantle...
the Russian network over there.
All you did was
nab a few small fry...
three clerks
and a cleaning woman.
And they blew the whistle on the others.
We got the whole kit and caboodle.
We plugged that leakfor good.
-What about Yaskov?
- What about Yaskov?
What'd you want me to do,
terminate him?
Is that the way you did things
in your dirty tricks division?
You're too new in this section
to go jumping to conclusions.
Excuse me.
- I never intended...
- Get my wife, please.
I never intended
to arrest Yas...
- Go ahead.
- I never intended to arrest...
Hello, darling.
Beverly tells me you called.
Yes, dear. It's about
the dinner party this evening.
I wanted to make quite certain
you hadn't forgotten.
Oh, no. I haven't forgotten.
- You're a good boy.
- Thank you.
- There's one other thing... the house.
- What about the house?
- Do we really have to go
down there this summer?
If you don't want to go, we just
won't go. It's your decision.
Decisions, decisions. Why do I
find it so hard to make up my mind?
Excuse me. Excuse me.
- Hello? Hello?
- Don't do that?
- Can you hear me?
- Yes, dear, I can hear you.
Now listen. Just call
that real estate dame...
and tell her to rent it out.
- Yes, dear, immediately.
- Tell her no kids, no pets, no Democrats.
Yes, dear.
Oh, one last thing.
The dinner is formal. I called
Mrs. Blandforth to make certain.
Good. I can wear
my new tuxedo.
- Good-bye, darling.
- Good-bye, dear.
- May I say something now?
- We've got a house near Savannah.
She won't give it up.
Says it's close to her mother.
She never wants
to use it though.
I never intended to arrest Yaskov.
I wanted him to stay right where he is.
You wanted.
Yes, I wanted.
I've know the man for 20 years. I
know how he thinks. I know how he acts.
We take him out,
they put another man in.
It takes us six months
to find out who.
It takes us another year and a half
to learn his style.
There are Russian combat troops
90 miles off our shore.
You had the head ofthe entire
K. G. B. for western Europe...
in your hand,
and you let him go.
That's the bottom line, isn't it?
I don't even begin to understand
the relevancy of that.
- It's my station.
- It's not your station! It's our station!
You should've learned
that one a long time ago.
You weren't there
to make policy.
You were there
to carry out policy.
Now we've had your history
of making up your own rules...
under review
for some time now.
We're reassigning you, Kendig.
You're going to sweat out
your time until pension...
running the filing section
right here.
Come on, Myerson. I'm a field man.
I've always been a field man.
The good news is I'm putting your
friend Joe Cutter in your place.
-Joe Cutter's a very good man.
- Yes, he is.
And he's 20 years
younger than you are.
Twenty-one. I don't know what's
buggin' you. You're overreacting.
I don't believe you're this upset
because ofthat Russian in Munich.
Damn it. I hate a man who doesn't
know when the party is over.
You will get that report
together, won't you?
And you can file it yourself
Monday morning.
Is this some kind ofa joke,
Myerson?
Come in, Cutter.
Congratulations, Joe.
You just got yourself a new job.
- How ya doin', Alex?
- Fine, Kendig.
Did you have the Redkskins
last Sunday?
- You bet I did.
- Good. I'm gonna look at the Kinberg file.
You know where it's at.
Okay, Alex.
Just stick with us this Sunday.
- We're gonna slaughter the Cowboys.
- I'm with you.
Mr. Myerson?
He's still not in his office.
He hasn't checked in
for two days, sir.
- Anything else?
- His apartment phone doesn't answer...
but, before he left, he put in
a call to Salzburg, Austria.
- Check it out.
- Yes, sir.
Excuse me.
I seeyou're looking
at the wine list.
-Yes, I am.
- May I perhaps suggest a wine?
That would be nice.
May I sit down, please?
Yes. Please do.
What wine do you
feel like drinking?
I'm not sure. I, uh...
Um, just a good wine.
What wine do you prefer?
Red wine? White? French? German?
I don't know. What's good
for this time ofthe day?
That would depend on what
you're thinking of eating.
Well, frankly, I... I, um...
hadn't quite made a decision
as to my meal.
- Is wine that important?
- Very important.
Do you prefer young wine
or one slightly older?
Oh, slightly... slightly older.
Mm. As a general rule,
the older wines are better.
It takes time forthe elements
in wine to resolve themselves...
into an harmonious whole.
It takes time and oxygen.
- Are you serious?
- Deadly serious.
Wine is not
a disembodied essence.
It is the product of skill,
knowledge and, in many cases, love.
Are you a...
a wine salesperson?
No. I am an ordinary person...
living quietly on
the generous endowment...
left me by my dear
departed husband.
- Oh, that's wonderful.
- Thank you.
- You certainly know a lot about wines.
- You're American.
- Yes.
- Americans hold many myths about wine.
You are all interested in fitness,
in general health.
You think wine is bad
for your liver and your heart.
This is completely not true.
It is the drinking of wine that makes
it possible to eat the rich food...
which is bad for your liver
and your heart...
because wine cuts grease.
A sip of wine leaves
your mouth completely clean...
and ready for the next bite...
of whatever it is you're eating.
Oh, where have you been,
you old goat?
You bastard. I thought
I'd never see you again.
Please watch your language.
You know how sensitive I am.
Come home with me.
I'll give you lunch.
This is a terrible place to eat.
Does he bite?
Only people he doesn't like.
Oh. I only bite people I like.
Hey, it's nice.
- How many hectares do you have?
- Two.
Nice.
Ah. Very nice indeed.
Thank you.
There's more.
- Hey, magnificent.
- Thank you.
Do you have help?
One small Austrian lady
three times a week.
And one large Austrian lady
four times a week.
- What's for lunch?
- What would you like?
You have any sausage?
Oh, yeah. I have bratwurst,
liverwurst, weisswurst.
How about some ham and eggs
and a beer?
Kitchen's downstairs.
Where do you keep
the beer, please?
Middle shelf.
- Miss the old life?
- No. Game got too dirty.
You still take
gin and ginger ale?
Mine was never
gin and ginger ale.
Montrachet '69, please.
Next to the beer.
Oh, of course.
When I first worked
for the agency...
its use seemed clear.
You knew where you stood.
The bad guys wore mustaches.
- Where's the opener?
- On the tray in front of you.
Now...
you need a scorecard to know
who the players are.
Even then, it's fuzzy.
- Where are the glasses?
- On the table in front of you.
I'm glad I'm out.
I'm out too.
What?
I quit, but they
don't know it yet.
I can't imagine you
without the agency.
It's your whole life.
They put Myerson
in charge of my section.
He wanted to retire me
behind a desk.
"See you next Tuesday" Myerson
in charge? They've gone mad.
He's got tapes on everybody
locked away.
They're scared to death ofhim.
- What are you going to do?
- I don't know. I'm working on it.
Did you come to Salzburg
to see me?
Mm! You and Mozart.
Do they still keep
tabs on me in Washington?
Well, we knew you married
some old Nazi.
- Come on, Kendig. Hewas Austrian.
- So was Hitler.
- Yes, but he had
no sense ofhumor.
Do I pass inspection?
Ah. You do.
You're so sweet and delicious.
- Mmm!
- What do you really want, hmm?
Somewhere to hide while you
decide what you're going to do.
Succor and solace
and a shoulder to cry on.
- Sounds pretty good to me. - How'd
you like to play gin rummythis evening?
- For how much?
- How much can you afford to lose?
That's the second four
you've given me.
Gin. Uh-huh, it's gin.
- Hmm. Thirty-three.
- Aha!
Blitzed and double blitzed.
What do you do with yourself
around here anyway?
Look after my late husband's
business interests.
- I keep myself occupied.
- Wanna tell me about him?
- No.
- Good.
Four... nine.
- You owe me...
- Shh, shh, shh.
You still owe me...
$135.62.
Wanna take it out in trade?
What do you have
that's worth that much?
Like antiques?
Come to bed.
I thought you'd never ask.
I hear you walked out
on your friends.
You hear, or is this
a trial balloon?
Did they force you out
because you did not arrest me?
- Right.
- I feel a bit guilty about that.
- I'd like to make amends.
- How?
I'm offering to put you
right back into the game.
Yaskov, Yaskov.
I'd make a useless double agent.
Of course you would.
Double agents must be
drab little people. Colorless.
No, that would never
do for you.
Listen, I want
to run you in the field...
as my own agent.
We'd make it worth
your while, of course.
There is plenty of money.
No.
Money is too expensive
to be earned that way, Yaskov.
Look. The human species
has been on this planet...
for, um, millions of years.
Except for the tiniest
fraction of the time...
we all lived as hunters.
Hunting... it's the only
natural way of life.
It was your way of life
until you walked away from it.
I'm offering to return it to you.
- By the way, we are being photographed.
- Yours or mine?
Yours.
I recognize the mustache.
Oh, that's Follett.
He's an idiot.
Probably no film
in the camera.
Could you be
rejecting my offer...
out of some absurd
loyalty to the flag?
You may as well give up,
tovarich. Nyet interested.
A pity. What do you intend to do
with the rest of your life, then?
Write your memoirs?
Memoirs?
That's not a bad idea.
- Have you got a typewriter?
- In the den.
What are you going to do,
write some letters?
- No. I'm going to write mymemoirs.
- Oh, that's nice.
Your childhood in the ghetto?
My last 30 years
in the ghetto.
Uh-huh. You're going to relate
some amusing incidents.
And some not so amusing.
Would you put on a record, please?
- What are you going to write about?
- I'm going to tell the truth.
Oh, it's a work of fiction.
Ah. You didn't say that.
You didn't make that clear.
Oh!
What? What's the matter?
You're insane. They will
obliterate you in five minutes.
- It'll shake 'em up.
- Shake them up?
They will send men
who will come and kill you.
I'll keep one step
ahead of them. That's enough.
Well, almost enough.
I need your help.
Oh, no. No.
I'm very sorry. No.
I have a nice life, a beautiful house,
money, the respect ofthe community.
Don't look at me
like that. No!
What do you
want me to do?
Find me a copying machine, get me a
stack of 9x12 manila mailing envelopes.
We are both mad.
Mad! Gone!
I thought perhaps you could
shed some light on this.
I know Kendig's a friend
of yours, Cutter, but...
what the fuck is he doing
drinking vodka with Yaskov?
Yaskov is the enemy, isn't he?
I don't think this is
anything to worry about.
They've known each other
for years.
He and Yaskov used to exchange
people at Checkpoint Charlie.
There's nothing sinister about it.
In Munich, he turned him loose. And
now he's having a drink with him?
Better have a look at this.
"Kendig, M."
Nothing sinister, huh?
Why has he tampered
with his file?
I don't think
this means a thing.
Probably shouldn't have done it,
but it's typical of him.
He doesn't want to be a number
in anybody's computer.
Bullshit.
He's up to something.
It's your job
to find out what it is.
You like opera?
- Yeah. You?
-Ja.
- Was ist das?
- "Barber of Seville." Figaro.
- Oh. By Mozart.
- No. That's the other Figaro.
- Huh?
- That's the...
- Figaro.
- Ah.
- AufWiedersehen.
Paris.
Peking.
Moscow.
Rome.
London.
Und Washington, D. C.
He must be out
of his freaking mind.
"Subjects to be covered in
future chapters will be...
"How much did the department of dirty
tricks have to do with the plane crash...
"which killed
Secretary Hammarskjold?
C. I. A. future plans for
clandestine operations."
My God! He sent copies to Moscow,
Peking, London, Paris, Bonn, and Rome.
Do you know he can blow every
operation we've set up for two years.
He can make some waves
ifhe goes through with it.
I don't think it's funny, Joe.
Of course it's funny, Leonard.
He's out ofhis fucking mind.
Where is he?
Well, that was mailed
from Salzburg.
But Follett says that a guy
that looked like him...
crossed over into Switzerland a couple of
days ago singing the "Barber of Seville."
Sounds like Kendig
hoping we'll chase him.
Well, let's tell Follett to quit playing
around and find the son of a bitch.
Sit down.
Voila.
Three passports... blank.
Three driving licenses... blank.
And a credit card.
"James Butler."
There is no such a thing as a
blank credit card. You know that.
These look okay. Everything except
the price you quoted on the telephone.
Five thousand francs
for the passports.
Two thousand for the licenses. And
forthe credit cards, five hundred.
They are not hot.
The numbers have been changed.
My department's on a budget.
Mais, oui. So am I.
How many years have I been
working for your agency, huh?
Am I not always reliable?
Don't I deserve
any consideration?
Six thousand for the package.
That's it.
Impossible.
Tell you what.
I'll give you 7,000.
Leave me with 500, will ya?
- For what?
Cherchezla femme.
Uh... a sandwich or something?
I don't think he'll publish it.
He's sending copies to the
intelligence people, not the publishers.
It's his fucking suicide note.
The bastard wants...
to go down in flames, and he wants
us to put him out of his misery.
He's not the suicidal type.
You put him on the bench. He's
putting himself back in the game.
- That's what it's all about.
- The game is over.
Listen, this is just a teaser.
This is just one chapter.
Suppose we don't take the bait.
If we don't play,
he'll probably have to quit.
It's no fun playing byyourself.
I've got a meeting
of the Security Council.
Walk me out.
I don't think you understand.
On this play,
we have got to take him out.
Because if we don't,
they will.
The Soviets will read that teaser...
and realize how much information
he's got in his pointed little head.
They'll drop everything in a rush
to grab him alive and squeeze him.
We can't afford that, can we?
I want you on this full-time
as of right now.
Anything you need, you ask for.
Top priority.
I want you to cancel his ticket.
We don't have to do that.
Let me try and stop him.
You're on overtime, Cutter.
Chemin de fer.
The bank closes this time
six to seven.
And the shoe passes
to a new bank.
Thank you.
Place your bets. Thank you.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you, sir.
- Sir, good night.
- Goodnight.
Would you like smoking
or nonsmoking?
Oh, nonsmoking, please, but make it an
aisle seat. I go to the bathroom a lot.
Okay. Fine.
Have you traveled Concorde before?
No, not to the best
of my recollection.
I understand you get there
before you leave.
Yes, that's right.
There you are, sir.
- Thank you very much. Have a
pleasant flight. - Thank you.
Okay. We know he's traveling
under the name of James Butler.
For the time being.
We know he left
the Grand Hotel in Marseilles...
tookan Air France
to Heathrow.
We know hewon f10,000
at the Grovener Casino...
and we're assuming
that he's still in London.
- You got a nail file? - I'd like to
have a look at his travel vouchers...
for the last year or two.
Might be something in there,
some pattern of movement.
You won't find anything
consistent on him.
His checks keep bouncing
'cause his signature varies.
He's a class act.
You like the guy, don't you?
Yes, I like him.
Let's get something to eat.
I'll get it.
762.
No. This is Leonard Ross.
Who's calling?
Start a trace.
Kendig,
what a pleasant surprise.
-Joe Cutter. Well, I'm glad they put
in the first team. - Thank you.
I mailed out another
chapter this morning.
If you're collecting stamps,
it's postmarked London.
What are you trying to prove?
I'm not trying to prove anything,
Joe. I'm just trying to have some fun.
Suppose you let me
talk you out of this...
before you find yourself at the
bottom of some river sipping sewage.
I'll be mailing it out
one chapter at a time.
Be more interesting that way.
You can tell Myerson that I'm
saving the juicy stuff for the end.
Listen, Kendig, I'm the one who's
gonna have to do the dirty work.
I don't want that.
Think of me, can't you? Don't you
have any feelings for me at all?
I'm gonna be tortured by this
for the rest ofmy life.
All my money will go
to a psychiatrist.
That's very good, Joe. Very dramatic.
I've never heard that used before.
Well, I think you've had time
to locate this call by now, kid.
So I'll be saying so long.
I'll see you around some time.
Kendig.
Kendig, are you there?
Did you get a line on that?
Are you sure?
That son of a bitch.
He's right here in Washington.
It's a local call.
- Anything?
- Nothing.
- He's probably halfway to the moon by now.
- Don't sound so pleased.
I've got everyone who knows him
by sight working the streets.
- Good work, Leonard.
- What would you suggest...
we just go back and wait
for the phone to ring again?
I don't think he's gonna call
again. He said what he has to say.
Excuse me, sir.
We found this under "B"
in the phone book.
I think we can say
good-bye to James Butler.
- Is everything okay?
-Yeah, thanks.
- More coffee?
- No, thank you.
Hello, Operator.
I'd like to make a "bill to" call
to overseas, please.
- Hello?
- Hi, Is.
Right on time. How are you?
Did you have a safe trip?
Yes. I said hello
to the folks.
They were surprised
to hear from me.
Have any of them
paid you a visit?
Only friend Follett.
He's watching me right now.
Give him a kiss for me
and tell him I'll write.
I'm sure he'd be very interested
to hear from you.
Now, you remember...
when and where
I'm gonna call you next.
Of course I remember.
And you remember to be careful.
And if you should happen
to see Kendig...
tell the horny old goat
I miss him very much and love him.
- Good-bye, Mr... - Hannaway.
Charlie Hannaway.
And I love you very much too.
Excuse me.
Mrs. Schonenberg?
- Yes?
- May I see you for a moment?
- It's about Miles Kendig.
- I thought it might be.
Not exactly friendly, is he?
Oh, he likes the people I like.
I see. You haven't by any chance
just been talking to him?
- Regretfully, no.
- That's too bad.
You see, it's important
that we reach him fast.
It's about his family.
There's been an accident.
Oh, how dreadful.
Not a tragic accident, I hope.
I'm afraid so.
His mother.
- That's more ofa miracle than a tragedy.
- What?
His mother died 25 years ago.
August 13th.
I believe itwas a Friday.
All right, Mrs. Schonenberg,
where is he?
My name is von Schonenberg.
I am an Austrian citizen
with a valid passport.
You have no right to question
or detain me without authority.
My dog is very highly strung
and has been known to attack.
I suggest you leave me alone.
Don't be too clever,
Mrs. von Schonenberg.
We're going to stop him.
Won't you have
to find him first?
Oh, do stop
following me around.
You're making my dog
very nervous.
He detests the smell of stupidity.
You know me. I cross every "T"
and dot every "I."
Is it someone
who was recommended to you?
Well, no, but I'm sure
it's quite all right.
He's putting down
a rather large cash deposit...
and he looks very reliable.
Well, I'm trusting your judgment.
Well, thank you, Mrs. Myerson.
I'm sure it'll be all right.
Lovely woman.
Very particular.
You're not a Democrat, are you?
- No, ma'am. Oh.
- Can you hear me?
Yes, Mrs. Myerson,
and I'm sure Mr. Hannaway...
is going to enjoy
your gracious home.
Now you just take care
of yourself, honey.
I will.
Well, that's settled.
Now all you have to do
is sign the papers...
and pay over
that nasty old money.
It's pretty hot out there,
isn't it?
Yes. It is 15 degrees warmer
than usual for this time ofyear.
- Is that a fact?
- Yes.
Now here's the inventory.
Now you must promise to be extra
careful with the Myerson's effects.
Oh, I will.
I certainly will, ma'am.
- Where do I sign?
- Right here.
Ah, such peace and quiet.
They say it is the coolest spot
on the island.
Should be a wonderful place
to rest up after your operation.
- What did you say it was for?
- Prostate.
Oh, of course.
Well, you know, Mr. Hannaway...
my husband had it done
two years ago.
- Is that right?
- Yes.
And I wanna tell you,
it didn't make any difference.
- I mean, we went on a second honeymoon.
- Oh, that's nice.
And, Mr. Hannaway, honey, you
take care of yourself, you hear?
Yes, ma'am.
Ooh.
Chapter two, huh?
It's embarrassing.
"Whose bright idea was it to send
the box of poison cigars to Castro?"
Is he still sending copies
to Yaskov and everybody?
Everybody.
Why can'twe find him?
Well, I told you
it wasn't going to be easy.
"Ridiculous attempt to
assassinate Papa Doc Duvalier...
by bombing
the presidential palace."
Son of a bitch.
It's a personal vendetta against me.
Well, if the shoe fits.
Do you know
which side you're on?
I'm working here, aren't I?
And I was trained by one of the
best men in the business.
We've got leads.
We know he got
rid of that car in Virginia.
A guy answering his description picked
up an old clunker in South Carolina.
We got the license plate numbers.
One thing leads to another.
We'll get him.
Morning, Mr. Myerson,
you short person.
I'll tell you something, Myerson.
The more I dig into this,
the more disgusting it gets.
Be nice to think that you had a
few second thoughts now and then...
but there's no chance
of that, is there?
You probably see yourself
as an innocent bystander betrayed.
As I look at this thing now,
I can't believe I was ever part ofit.
Tell you something, I wouldn't go
back now for any amount of money.
Sorry, sir. Mr. Maddox
says he's busy just now.
- Okay. Would you get me another beer,
please? - Sure enough.
- Are you finished?
- Yeah.
Hi, there.
- Is Leroy Maddox in?
- Yes. May I help you?
- I know the way. That's all right.
- You can't go in there, sir.
Honey, what's your name?
- My name is Sarah.
- Sarah.
- You new here, are you?
- Yes, I am.
- Well, I know Mr. Maddox a long time.
- You can't go in there.
You can't go in there, sir.
- May I help you, friend?
- Name is Jim Murdison out of Dallas.
Expect you don't remember me,
but I was up here a littlewhile back...
with ol'Jim-Bob
Fredericks of Houston.
Ah, Mr. Murdison.
Any friend of ol'Jim-Bob's.
Sit yourself down.
Tell me what I can do for you.
Well, ol'Jim-Bob said ifl ever
needed a little special help...
I should look you up.
I'd be mighty pleased to help you.
What kind of thing you have in mind?
Oh, you can drop the accent.
It's terrible.
Okay. I'd like
to charter a seaplane.
Well, now I'm not exactly
in the airplane business.
How soon would you
be needin' it?
A week from Friday.
Um, can I have
my clip back, please?
Sure.
I do happen to know
a charter pilot...
who is, uh... discreet.
I tell you what, Mr. Murdison...
you give me a call back
on Tuesday night. Okay?
Okay. And by the way,
my name is not Murdison.
Well, I didn't think it was,
Mr. Murdison.
- Howy'all doin' there?
- Pretty good.
- You have any trouble?
- No, sir.
Works just like you drew it.
Balances real good
even when she's full.
What'd you say you was
gonna use it for?
Oh, we just got some
driveways we're workin' on.
Driveways?
Yeah. You know, driveways.
Oh. Driveways.
Well, that's a...
That's a real good idea.
I sure hope it does
the trick for you, Mr. Hannaway.
$450.
- Thank you very much, sir. Thank you
very much indeed. - Thank you.
- Good-bye, sir.
- G'-bye.
G'-bye?
* Count on me, love me *
*Take me
Touch me *
*Yeah *
* Come back to bed
You been away too long *
* I need to hold you tight*
*And close my heart
until you lay beside me*
*Open all my senses
through the night**
- Areyou Murdison?
- Yeah.
I'm Carla Fleming. I fly a seaplane.
I understand you're looking for one.
Shall we sit down?
When and where
do you wanna fly?
This Friday.
A young lady and I...
- Or is it "a young lady and me"?
- "I."
- Uh, do you know where
Coffee Bluffis? - Uh-huh.
Okay, you pick us up there
and you fly us to Martinique.
Has your plane got
the range for it?
Mm-hmm.
It's a Lake Buccaneer.
It's not gonna be cheap, since
I don't know what we're carrying.
Well, I told you... a young lady.
I'm not smuggling.
I hear you saying it.
I don't wanna know eitherway.
$3,000.
I just wanna charter it.
I don't wanna buy it.
I'm sure you could get a better
price from one of the airlines.
I think the regular fare
is about $150.
Okay, okay. I'll give you the
money right before we take off.
Just as soon as possible
after dawn this Friday.
- You got it?
- I'll be there.
- Okay.
- Now you can buy me a scotch and soda.
Scotch and soda
forthe lady.
Pay attention, shorty.
I'd like to make a call
to Salzburg, Austria, please.
- Hello.
- Hello, Is.
Kendig? What the hell
are you doing?
Don't you know
this damn phone is tapped?
Watch the profanity, please.
I've been missing you,
thinking about you...
and I had this sudden urge.
- Are you drunk?
- It's Kendig!
There are 212 tape recorders
on this line.
It'll take 94 seconds
for them to trace the call.
Is Follett
still harassing you?
It's "harassing," dear.
Harassing.
He's trying,
but he's afraid of the dog.
I haven't seen him
for a few days.
He must be off somewhere
with his nose to the ground.
- Who, the dog?
- No, dear. Follett.
Are you keeping this line open
until he can pinpoint you?
Follett couldn't pinpoint his
own backside in broad daylight.
- We'll see about that.
Hurry it up.
You do know what
you're doing, don't you?
Certainly not.
How's the book coming?
Is it finished?
All but the last chapter. You know,
that's the stuff with the dynamite in it.
I'm just at the bit about Follett when
he got caught with his pants down...
writing obscenities
on the men's room wall.
Was he alone?
Very funny. Very funny.
The state ofGeorgia, sir.
They'reworking on the exchange.
Geez. Tell them to hurry it up.
Not to be gruesome, old darling,
but I hope you've written your will.
Yes. I've left everything
to the Flat Earth Society.
But don't worry about it.
I'm forted up here
with plenty of firepower.
No, sir. They'll never
take me alive.
I'm armed to the teeth.
- Good grief!.
Haven't you got it yet?
Any second now, sir.
- I'll call you again. You know
the time and place. - I do.
- Geez!
- Bye, darling.
Bye, darling.
Telephone number
area code... 311-555-1285.
Maple Road,
Adairsville, Georgia.
- Get the agency.
- Yes, sir.
What? Repeat that.
I don't fucking believe it!
Excuse me, Beverly.
Mr. Kendig has
rented out my house.
Would you get Mr. Cutter
in here right away, please?
He's actually had the balls
to hide out in my house!
It's a house on the edge ofa marsh
about five minutes from here.
I know where it is.
Is it covered?
We got a couple boys across the
road. We didn't want to alert him.
Alert him?
He knows we're coming.
Just one thing, Mr. Myerson.
This is our jurisdiction,
not yours.
It's an F. B. I. case now.
I run the show.
I want one ofmy men
in each of these cars.
Jerry, you take the back
and the far side.
Bobby, you take this side.
I'll take the front.
Bring me the bullhorn
and the gas.
Kendig.
This is the F. B. I.
We've got you surrounded.
Throw out your guns and come out
with your hands over your head.
You've got 60 seconds
before we use tear gas.
I hope your guys
aren't trigger-happy.
It'd be a shame
to damage this house.
We don't shoot first, but
if he tries to blast his way out...
- With what? He hasn't carried a gun for
years. - That's not what I was told.
"Forted up with plenty of firepower.
Armed to the teeth."
What secrets did he steal?
It's on a need-to-know basis...
a matter of national security.
Yeah.
That's a phrase that's lost
a good deal of meaning lately.
You got 20 seconds, Kendig.
Give him the gas.
Do that one more time, Kendig,
and we'll blow you to pieces.
Let him have it.
Freeze!
Keep your hands down.
Nice shootin', Ross. Eight thousand
panes, and you hit one of them.
- What's happening?
- They're shooting up your house.
Stop it! Stop it!
Cease fire!
Fucking Idiots!
Stop it! Stop it!
Get down, you idiot!
You wanna get yourself killed?
This is a mistake!
- In you go, Ross.
- Am I driving?
Move over to the other side.
Move it.
That's enough!
- You're destroying my house!
- Give it one more.
Okay, boys. Cease fire.
Soon as the smoke clears,
we'll go in and take a look.
I don't believe this.
I don't fucking believe this.
- Talk about playing into this hands.
-Just shut the fuck up!
There's a guy pulling
out of here in a pickup...
with one ofthe C. I. A. men.
Ross!
- That's him!
- Back to the cars.
- I'll call the fire department.
- Son of a bitch!
Mike, stay here.
Let's go!
Now I know what
F. B. I. stands for.
Fucking Ball-busting
Imbeciles.
Okay, Ross.
This is where you get off.
You used to be a pretty
good man. I looked up to you.
- What happened?
- Get out.
- I came to my senses, that's all.
- How do you figure that?
A few skunks in the agency
that needed flushing out.
Close the door.
Back off.
You're just making a fool of yourself,
Kendig. You don't have a chance.
Oh, yeah?
Don't bet on that, Ross.
So long, kid.
- Mornin'.
- Good mornin'.
- Hiya, kid.
- Hi.
- You alone?
- Yeah.
- Where's your lady friend?
- Her mother wouldn't let her come.
Okay. Let's get going.
One passenger or two...
the price is still the same.
Oh, that's a relief.
Three thousand bucks.
There we go.
Thank you.
Next stop... Martinique.
How about a change of course?
092 magnetic.
- Bermuda?
- Why not?
Okay by me. That'll take
about seven hours.
We haven't got a bathroom.
Can you make it?
- I'll be very careful.
- What did you do, rob a bank?
- Is that what's in the suitcase?
- Uh, yes.
Gee, I never drove a get away
car before. It's kind offun.
- You mind ifl steer a while?
- You know how?
Yeah. They trained me as
a ferry pilot for M. A. T. S.
- Still got my license.
- Sure. Who's "they"?
Guys with little
plastic I. D. cards.
They'll probably come around,
ask you a lot of questions.
Just tell them the truth.
I generally tell the truth.
It's easier that way.
- Are you going back tonight?
- Oh, noway.
I'm gonna get my hair done
and get a good night's sleep.
- Well, you certainly got enough
money for it. -Just about.
So long. Take care of yourself,
whatever you're doing.
You seem like a nice fella.
You remind me of my father.
That's always been my problem.
Here's your tea, dear. Nice and hot,
with lemon. Just the way you like it.
I don't like lemon.
I like milk.
Now, is there anything else
that I can get for you boys?
Well, don't work Mr. Cutter too
hard. After all, it is Sunday.
I'm sure he needs his rest. If you
need me, I'll be in the sewing room.
Should have terminated her
20 years ago.
Joe, maybewe've been going
about this the wrong way.
Perhaps it needs
a lighter touch.
You know, sometimes bullying
people doesn'twork.
Let's be sophisticated here.
Maybe we can use a carrot
instead of a stick.
Kendig likes girls,
doesn't he?
Listen, Myerson,
let me make a suggestion.
Why don't I go over to Salzburg
and have a little talk with Isobel?
We worked together once. Maybe
she'll listen to what I have to say.
Have you got something
going on with Isobel too?
We're always
one step behind him.
I'd like to get one step ahead
ofthe arrogant son ofa bitch.
I thought you liked
the arrogant son of a bitch?
-Welcome to London, Mr. Ross.
Business or pleasure? - Oh, yes.
- I beg your pardon?
- Oh. A little ofboth.
- I'm here to see my publisher. I'm writing
a book. - How long do you plan to stay?
That depends. I'm waiting for
some colleagues to catch upwith me.
- Enjoy your visit.
- Thank you.
- What's the name of the book?
- Hopscotch.
Good title.
- Glen.
- How are you doing?
- Will she see us? - She'll see you. You
won't get anywhere. I've already tried.
Well, maybe she'll be more
accessible to me. I'm an old friend.
- Yaskov's in town. He wants to see you.
- That's good. I'd like that.
Set a time and place
for this afternoon.
You're looking very tired, Joe.
- It's the jet lag. I can't get used to it.
- You sure that's all it is?
Now, listen, Isobel. We're
both fond ofthis character...
but he's making an ass of himself,
and he's got to cut it out.
- For his own good.
- For his own good?
You've been trying to stop him, and
I gather not having too much success.
Such a shame.
All those bright young men.
And there he is, single-handedly
running rings around you all.
He's very good.
He's as good as they come.
And he is running rings around us,
and I'm his biggest fan.
But Kendig is going
to make a mistake.
Sooner orlater, he's bound to slip.
Afterall, he's only human.
- Oh, he's extremely human.
- It's not funny, Isobel.
We're not the only people looking for him.
If the Russians get to him before we do...
You mean Myerson's methods of termination
are more humane than the Russians'?
You know what I mean.
I don't want to hurt him, Isobel. But I
have a job to do, and I'm going to do it.
He's got to stop
that book right now.
He's hadhis fun. He's made a fool
out of everyone. Now he has to stop.
He has to stop
ifhe's going to stay alive.
- Will you tell him?
- Oh, I'll tell him.
I don't think he'll stop.
Oh. You've forgotten your beer.
- Hi. I'm looking for Mr. Ludlow.
- Ah, you mean Mr. Ludlum.
- You'll find him in his office
up there, gov. - Thank you.
- Mr. Ludlum?
- Yes, sir.
I understand you have
a little old airplane for sale.
- I'm Ross. I called you this morning.
- Ah, yes, sir. Yes.
- You'd like to take a little look,
would you? - Yeah, please.
She's a Stampe, sir.
Oh, the Belgian version
ofthe old Tiger Moth.
- Yes, indeed. You know your aircraft, sir.
- Mm.
She trained a lot of good
fighter pilots in her day.
- How many hours on the engine? - A hundred
and eighteen since the last overhaul.
- A hundred and eighty? -
Eighteen, sir. One-eight.
- She's generally in very good shape.
- How much are you asking?
Well, you'll need to have a look at
the logs and certifications, won't you?
- So let's nip back to the office and
see what we can do. - Okay.
Look at Yaskov. He must have
seen Casablanca 12 times.
You better wait here.
- I know where he is.
- Who's that, comrade?
May I suggest we pool
our information?
If I tell you the city, you will know
how to find him in that city, yes?
- A new wrinkle on detente. - That
manuscript is an embarrassment to us all.
If you catch him, your people will squeeze
him. We're not crazy about that idea.
At the moment, we feel it is more
important he be neutralized.
He knows too much about
our side, as well as yours.
Well?
Sorry.
Very well.
He is back in London.
He flew there from Bermuda
two days ago.
- He's traveling under the name
of Leonard Ross. - That figures.
I'd like to be able to tell you that we
found him through brilliant detective work.
But in actual fact, one of my men just
happened to recognize him at Heathrow.
I will want a quid pro quo
one day, my good friend.
I bet you will.
See you in London.
- Well?
- He's in London.
- He gave you that for free? - Of course
not. Nothing's free with that old fox.
But it does tell us one thing.
- The Russians are just as nervous
as we are. - You're learning.
By the way, he's traveling
on your passport.
That's cheaper too.
Uh, no, I'm sorry. Sorry.
- Parlez-vous Francais, monsieur?
- No, no. This...
Can you speak French
or German, either of you?
Does Alfie Booker
still work here?
- Yeah. He's out in the back.
- May I speak to him for a moment, please?
- Sure. Help yourself.
- Thank you.
- Here, I'll take this one myself.
- Yeah, I like that one.
Alfred P. Booker.
Mr. Kendig. Hey, it's good to see you.
It's been two years.
- You lost a little weight, didn't you?
- Yeah.
- Hey, how'd that transistor job
go for you? - The transistor?
What... Oh, they never even
knew it was there. Not a clue.
I have something a little more
difficult for you this time.
May I come
around here, please?
Tell me how practical
you think that is.
- Where are we staying?
- The Hilton. - Good.
And I set up a meeting for this
afternoon with British Intelligence.
Yeah, well, there's no problem
with the electronic stuff.
That's dead easy. But it's the
mechanics I'm not sure about.
Servo motors, some sort
of hydraulic transfer.
Look, there is a chap I know in the
navy, used to know all about this stuff.
Do you want me to get ahold of
him and see ifhe can help us?
- How low do you think it will take?
- Give me a ring tonight.
I'll know by then if I can get
a hold of him. And if I can...
I'll go down to the field
tomorrow morning.
Could have it installed for you
by nightfall. How's that sound?
All right, I'll call you. Just give me
your home phone number, if you please.
Yeah.
You understand, Sir Giles, this requires
a certain delicacy on all our parts.
Yes, I'm sure it must be terribly
embarrassing for all of you.
Of course, we in
England would never allow
ourselves to get into such
a ridiculous predicament.
- You see, what we need is...
- Yes, yes, yes, I know.
But it's quite fascinating,
isn't it? The part where...
I think it's chapter three...
the bit about Somoza, Nicaragua.
Your Kendig's got
quite a sense of humor.
Sir Giles, we would appreciate it
if we could move forward with this.
Technically, it's not our problem,
is it? He's broken no laws in Britain.
But, of course, hands across the sea and
all that. We'll be happy to cooperate.
- Now, what exactly would you like
to have us do? -Manpower.
We'd like you to put a lot
of people on the ports of exit...
airlines, terminals, that stuff.
Well, that does seem
to be rather fruitless.
We don't really know what he looks like.
We do have this, sir.
Ah. Thank you.
Which one is, uh...
Well, that's Yaskov.
What's he doing with Yaskov?
- That's part of our problem.
- The main thing is...
I'll have a word with the police.
- We'll circulate copies of this to all
ports of exit. - The main thing is...
he's come to England for a reason;
he didn't pick it out of a hat.
We think he's here to
find a publisher.
There can only be so many
publishers in London.
A dozen or so major houses.
Perhaps 30 or 40 small presses.
He wants to make a big noise,
so he'd go to a big house.
But I think that's what
he'll think we're thinking...
so I think he'll
go to a small one.
All right. I've got friends
in some of the publishing firms.
I'll get in touch
and let you know what I learn.
- Where are you staying?
- The Hilton.
Yes, of course. I'll ring the Hilton the
instant we've got anything of interest.
Good-bye, Mr. Myerson.
- Yes, can I help you? - Can you call
Salzburg, Austria, for me, please?
Yes, of course.
If you'd like to sit down...
- I'll tell you as soon as we get through.
- Thank you.
-The feathers in what?
- The Feathers Inn.
The Feathers Inn.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
- Don't you remember, darling?
-Of course I remember, darling.
Why don't you go get
some lunch. I'll take over.
All right. Thanks.
Ah, Mr. Follett. Come in.
Thankyou.
- What'd you want to see me about?
- Won't you sit down?
I wanted to see you: A... Because I'm
tired of being watched 24 hours a day...
and feel that you and I could come
to some more civilized arraignment.
And B... I have just been speaking
on the telephone with Kendig.
- Where was he calling from?
- He didn't say.
He did say, however, he feels that this
has now become a ridiculous charade...
that we should all stop playing.
We'd be delighted
to stop playing.
- Would you like a drink?
- Thank you.
A little whiskey maybe.
Good. Kendig would
like to speak to you...
because he's too emotionally
involved with the others.
He said he would telephone
about 1:30, which is...
Oh, in 15 minutes. I said I felt sure
you would be here to take the call.
No ice. Excuse me.
Oh, no, no, no.
That's, uh, uh, fine.
Oh, please. An American without
ice in his drink is unthinkable...
if not unconstitutional.
Nice boy.
Goodboy.
Nice dog.
Stay. Stay.
Good boy.
Stupid animal.
It's absolutely dynamite.
It could be our biggest
book of the year.
Although, uh, I still want to
see the last chapter, of course.
I happen to have it right in my
pocket. Finished it this morning.
- Splendid. I'm sure I shan't
be disappointed. - Cheers.
Cheers.
Mr. Westlake, you probably
won't see me again.
I've given someone
a power of attorney...
to get in touch with you
regarding contracts and payments.
Under the circumstances, your absence
will probably be our best publicity.
You're at considerable risk,
aren't you?
Well, if you publish this, you're
going to be taking a risk yourself.
We've dealt with controversy
before. The spice of life.
These fellows don't play by the
Marquis of Queen... It-It is Marquis?
- Yes, Marquis.
- Marquis of Queensbury rules, you know.
Well, I certainly hope not.
Not half so much fun.
You wait here.
Mr. Westlake, I'm terribly sorry.
These gentlemen...
- It's about the Kendig manuscript.
- That's all right.
- I've been looking forward to this.
- Good.
Glad you're not gonna try one of those
I-don't-know-what-
you're-talking-about stories.
My name is Parker Westlake.
- The point is...
- What's yours?
- What?
- What are your names?
Smith and Jones.
From my reading ofthe manuscript,
you have to be Myerson.
Are you Joe Cutter, by any chance?
I'm glad to meet you.
Now, please, why don't we sit down
and reason this thing together?
Why don't you give us the
manuscript? You can't publish it.
I think you're wrong about that.
Tell him, Joe.
I'm afraid he's right.
I don't like to make threats.
They sound foolish in the daylight.
But I am to infer that if I
don't give you the manuscript...
you'll creep in here
one dark night and take it.
Oris it more along
the lines of, uh...
if you don't cooperate with us,
we'll set off bombs in your offices?
You said it, we didn't.
Gentlemen, let me
tell you something.
I think this is one of the most exciting
literary properties
I've seen in a long time.
It simply isn't possible
for you to suppress it.
Let me caution you. I've run
off copies of the manuscript...
and had them put
in safe places.
So even if I suffer
an unfortunate accident...
the process of publication
will continue.
Naturally, we don't intend to
use our usual printing house.
So no one will know
where the book is...
until it's far too late tostop
its distribution to the bookshops.
I think your friend Kendig...
has you well and truly
by the short hairs.
If you publish that book, you're
signing his death warrant.
There's only one man who can stop
the publication of that book...
and that's Kendig himself.
Why don't you
talk to him about it?
- We can't find the bastard.
- Find him?
My dear fellow, where's
the difficulty in that?
He's staying right here in London
at the Windsor Hotel.
- What?
- The Windsor Hotel in Landcaster Gate...
just north ofthe park.
Thank you.
Room 416. Apparently,
he's expecting us.
We'll take the stairs.
- How'd you get here?
- He telephoned my embassy.
- He's very democratic, isn't he?
- Yes, isn't he?
I do like him, you know.
One can't help it.
Come on.
He's not gonna shoot you.
Shh.
Kendig?
Close the door.
So he's expecting us, huh?
Hello, boys.
Thanks for coming.
Why don't you sit down?
Make yourselves comfortable.
Joe, give everyone
a drink, will ya?
Whiskey is right there
next to the tape recorder...
and there's some ice,
ifit hasn't melted by this time.
Sorry there's no vodka, Yaskov.
I simply forgot it.
- Myerson, couldn't find
any bourbon and coke.
I suppose you're
wondering where I am.
Well, we know I'm not
about to try the airports...
the boat-trains
and the liners in Southampton...
the trains to Scotland
and the ferryboats to Ireland.
Did you think of Ireland, Joe,
or did you slip up on that one?
We thought of it.
Well, I'll give you a clue
as to my whereabouts later on.
In the meanwhile, the reason I
asked you all to come up here...
is 'cause I want you to pick up
a copy of my last chapter.
It's sitting on top
ofthe chest of drawers...
right next to the recorder.
That's all. Why don't you
take it home and read it?
Enjoy yourselves.
Have a good time.
Thanks very much for coming,
and, uh, good night.
Shit.
- Good night.
- Good night, Joe.
- Yep.
Good grief, Joe,
you look terrible.
Well, you've been keeping me
up past my regular bedtime.
Mm. Chair, please.
- Myerson thrown in the towel yet?
- He wants to see you dead.
Oh, it doesn't make any difference
whether I'm dead or alive, Joe.
He's all washed up now.
Doesn't he know that?
Lean forward, please.
Hands behind your back.
- How come he hasn't quit yet?
- He's a little bit like you.
- He won't quit until he gets even.
- Should be even by now.
He tried to emasculate me,
and I retaliated.
- What's your game plan now?
- There isn't any. The game's over.
It's all finished.
I've had my fun.
- It's too late for that.
I've got my orders. -Ahh.
I understand, Joe. You'll never
see me again after tonight.
- I'll find ya.
- No.
Did you pick up
my last, uh, chapter?
Yes, I did. And I think
you went a little bit too far.
- Oh, I don't think so.
- You know, I don't understand you.
It's not like you to paint
yourself into a corner.
But I don't see where
you've got any back door.
- You're my back door, Joe.
- I can't do you any favors.
- Sure you can. You already did.
- I did?
You know I'd never use this.
You didn't do anything about it.
I'm gonna have to put
a gag in your mouth, Joe.
The cleaning lady will
turn you loose in the morning.
- I hope she's pretty.
- Open your mouth.
Oh, uh, you can call
your crowd off the airport.
I've got a little plane
on the coast near Beachy Head.
I'll be taking off first thing
in the morning across the Channel.
No bullets.
I'm proud of you, Joe.
- Yeah?
- Hello?
Joe Cutter is tied to a chair
in his room.
You'd better cut him loose.
What? Who is this?
This is Eleanor Roosevelt.
What? Who is...
Hello?
- Hello.
- Hello, Is? Did you make it?
No. No, I didn't make it.
This is a recording of
a person asleep. How are you?
Right on schedule.
As of now, the clock is running.
- Well, where is it running?
- The Pond Gemington.
The Pond where?
The Pond, near that
beautiful graveyard.
You know, the one
with the Norman church.
And all those cold stones. Yes, yes, I
remember. I'll see you there in an hour.
Damn it!
Police. Thank God.
You fellas are never supposed
to be around when you're needed.
- Having a spot of trouble, sir?
- Yeah. I got a flat tire there.
I just made a telephone call,
came back, tire was flat...
- and there's no spare in there.
- Your car, sir?
- No, it's a rental. - Well, that's
where the spare should be, sir.
Yeah, but it's not there.
Listen, superspy, I wouldn't tell
Myerson about this if I were you.
- Fuck, Myerson.
- Oh, by the way, did he get your passport?
- Where you from in America, sir?
- Flagstaff, Arizona.
Hey, is there a place around here I can
rent a car? I got to get to Eastbourne.
Well, it might be a bit difficult
at this time of the morning, sir.
Why don't you come back to the station
and wait for one ofthe garages to open?
We'll make you
a nice cup of coffee.
We'll be at the Lambath heliport
in 15 or 20 minutes. Right.
If he doesn't take off before
daylight, we mightjust catch him.
-What time is daylight?
- About 7:00. It's 6:15 now.
- Is a cab waiting for us downstairs?
-Yes, sir.
- Now I want to know...
- I owe him one.
This is the quid pro quo, right?
I'm in a little bit
of a hurry, sir.
Um, is there any chance of
getting an all-night taxi service...
from Brighton or Seaford
or one of those places?
Here, Sarge, didn't old Tony Cosgrove
used to run some sort of taxi service?
- Yeah. If he's still alive.
- He's still alive, all right.
Give him a go, Harry. We'll
have you away in no time, sir.
Thank you very much.
Sure appreciate it.
Now, let's see.
Tony Cosgrove.
This time we'll
get there before him.
He'll never expect us
to get a copter up.
- You could be right.
- You bet your fucking ass I'm right.
Straight along the A-20.
How long do you think you'll be?
- Oh, about half an hour.
- It'll be about 30 minutes, sir.
Excuse me, sir, but what
did you say your name was?
- Burton. Henry Burton.
- Oh, yes, that's right. Thank you, sir.
I wonder if you could show me
some means of identification?
- Sure. You want a passport?
Driver's license? - Either, sir.
- There.
- Thank you.
You do rather look
a bit like this chap, sir.
But I'm sure it had nothing to do
with you. Just a coincidence, eh?
We've had a bulletin, you see.
An American that you rather
resemble is wanted for questioning.
Hmm.
Well, I guess I look like
everybody and his brother.
What has this, uh...
What is this fellow wanted for?
Oh, nothing in particular. Just some people
would like to ask him a few questions.
Oh, what the hell's going on
here with the lights?
- Oh, hi, there. - Morning. When
did you join the police force?
- It's the only car I could find that
had any gas in it. - Good thinking.
Listen, no matterwhat happens,
you stay put right here.
- I'll be back within an hour, okay?
- Okay.
And if you're not back
within the hour, I'll wait
for another hour
and another and another...
Follow him!
Jesus!
Wow! I guess that
takes care of Mr. Kendig.
That takes
care of him, all right.
The son of a bitch is down there
in that undertow in 47 pieces.
The son of a gun
is dead finally.
The son of a bitch
better stay dead.
Pity. I shall miss him.
- Everything go okay?
- Fine.
Good.
- Um, South of France for two
weeks? - Sounds okay. - Good.
I hope this book is half
as exciting as they say it is.
Oh, it is. Fourteen weeks, number
one on the best seller list.
Oh, how marvelous.
They say he was murdered
by his own men, the C. I. A.
Do you think there's
any truth in that?
There are those who say he's
still alive, living in Australia.
Oh, really?
Oh, is that a fact...
This is indefensible.
You must stop
these ridiculous charades.
The agency thinks you are dead.
No one, with the possible exception
of me, gives a damn about you.
If you do not stop
these absurd disguises...
I will personally rip
that beard from your chin...
and scream "fire"
at the top of myvoice.
Okay, okay.
You madeyour point.
Good. How'd you like to play
some gin this evening?
- For how much?
- Will you never learn?