Hello, admitting.
This is Saperstein.
Where is he?
He's cleared admitting?
Right. Bring him in.
He's coming.
Good, good.
Trent?
John J.
Put him in number nine.
You son of a bitch!
Hang on to him.
Get him in there!
No, not me!
No, wait, wait!
This is wrong.
Look, I'm sorry about the balls!
It was a lucky shot, that's all!
Wait!
I'm not insane.
You hear me?
I'm not insane!
I'm not if he's not!
Me neither!
I'm not insane!
We've only just begun
Not the Carpenters, too.
So let me go
This is a rotten way to end it.
This is not the ending.
You haven't read it yet.
All right.
Came in this afternoon?
Yes. How did you
get here so fast?
We've been monitoring
all admissions...
through police
and paramedic channels.
This one fit the symptoms.
Do you think he's one of them?
Mr. Saperstein, I promise you...
that's what I'm here
to find out.
Things must be getting
pretty bad out there...
to bring youfellas in.
Is this it?
Did he make any requests?
Just...
one.
A, uh...
single black crayon.
Hang on.
What's up?
My name is Dr. Wrenn...
and I am going to try
and get you out of here.
After all my redecorating?
No. I think I'll stay.
There's a guard with a pair
of swollen testicles...
who swears you wanted
out of here.
I, uh, well...
I've changed my mind.
I see.
The crosses are a nice touch.
They'd almost have
to keep you in here...
once they'd seen these,
wouldn't they, John?
Got a smoke?
You're waiting to hear
about my "them," aren't you?
Your what?
My "them."
Every paranoid schizophrenic
has one...
a "them," a "they," an "it."
And you want to hear
about my "them," don't you?
I want to know how you got here.
Things are turning to shit
out there, aren't they?
Let's talk about you.
Your dime.
I'm, uh...
I was an insurance investigator,
freelance.
Checked outfunny claims,
frauds...
the usual kind of thing.
And lately I'd been working
for a firm here in the city.
And all of this started
with the disappearance.
The Sutter Cane...
disappearance.
It's a little hot in here,
isn't it?
It's boiling.
How long I gotta be here?
I mean, uh...
I took care
of all that paperwork.
The check was supposed
to be here three weeks ago.
Right? Isn't that right?
Well, usually, yeah,
that's the way it goes...
but I just have a few final
questions about the fire.
More questions.
I've answered
all your questions.
Enough's enough.
It was supposed
to be cut and dried.
We'll be out of here
in a minute.
See, Robby here,
he owns the company.
And he's hired me to see that
things go smoothly, understand?
It's just a little thing,
but, see...
Robby takes the view
that it was you...
who burned down your own
warehouse on Northern Boulevard.
Me? That's horseshit.
That was all my own stuff
in that warehouse.
That's my whole life.
Believe me, I sympathize.
You're really starting to sweat.
Shall I turn on
the air conditioning?
Oh, no, I'm fine.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
I'm running a little late.
Supposed to pick up my wife.
Oh, yeah, your wife.
She's a great lady.
You know her?
No, not really.
We just met briefly.
You know, when I went round
to check up on your story.
We have these photographs...
of your wife
tooling around town...
wearing various articles...
that you claim
were destroyed in the fire.
No, that's impossible.
No, this is all stuff
I boughtfor her myseif.
See, the problem is...
when I went round
to talk to her...
it turned out she knew much more
than she thought she did.
Especially...
Especially after I showed her
pictures of Miss Palminteri...
who appears to be wearing...
even more
of your destroyed articles.
Miss Palminteri?
Miss Rosa Palminteri.
A word of advice.
You want to pull a scam,
don't make your wife a partner.
If you do...
don'tfuck around
behind her back.
Trent, beautiful.
Everybody says you got the best
nose for a con in the business.
But to see itfirsthand, I mean,
to watch you work...
is incredible.
Well, it wasn't hard, Robby.
The guy's wife liked me.
Besides, he was an amateur.
It's too easy with amateurs.
You try to figure out who's
professional and who isn't.
That's when it gets fun,
when you run into a pro.
You know, most of my salesmen...
couldn't sniff out
a phony claim...
if their noses
were nailed to it, but you...
man, you never miss.
What's to miss?
You learn to expect the worst
in people, and you get it.
Everyone's looking
to play an angle.
I'm always there
to clean up the mess.
I'll tell you what.
You stop freelancing,
join my staff.
I'll make it worth your while.
Forget it, Robby.
I'm my own man.
Nobody pulls my strings.
I'm independent, I'm happy.
Well, be my man one more time.
I'm having quite
a difficult mess with Arcane.
The publishing house?
Yeah, my biggest account.
They justfiled a claim
that cost me millions.
I want you on this right away.
What's the claim?
Sutter Cane is missing.
Who?
Sutter Cane.
Do you read Sutter Cane?
What?
Horror writer Sutter Cane...
a harmless pop phenomenon...
or a deadly mad prophet
of the printed page?
This was the scene today
outside several city bookstores.
Police believe
the riots began...
because the stores
could not meet the demand...
for advance orders
of Sutter Cane's latest novel...
'In the Mouth of Madness."
When does fiction
become religion?
And are his fans dangerous?
Only if you count axes.
In related news, there were
eighteen other stores...
Mr. Harglow will see you now.
Thank you.
You're not listening to me.
I needed it yesterday.
If you wait any longer, it'll be
all over the front page.
Get it done!
Jackson Harglow, Mr. Trent.
I'm pleased to meet you.
It's a pleasure.
Excuse the commotion.
We have something
of a crisis going on.
Everybody out now, please.
I need time with Mr. Trent.
Have Sylvia hold the calls,
and you get Linda in here.
That was great.
I almost left myseif.
Sit down, please.
I am a little short
on patience these days.
So, Mr. Trent,
are youfamiliar with Arcane?
Well, aside from the fact...
that you're insured
by the company I work for...
I never heard of Arcane.
I'm sorry.
You read books?
Linda Styles, John Trent.
Linda reads books for a living.
She's one of our best editors.
Since she joined the firm...
she's been handling
Sutter Cane exclusively.
Isn't he the guy
that writes that horror crap?
Maybe he's too sophisticated
for you.
Sutter Cane happens to be...
this century's
most widely read author.
You can forget
about Stephen King.
Cane outsells them all.
So what happened
to this cash cow of yours?
Cane disappeared two months ago
without a trace.
The police
have turned up nothing.
Who was the last person
to hearfrom him?
His agent.
Cane mailed him
several chapters...
of his new book,
oh, not two weeks ago.
Plain brown wrapper.
No return address.
Oh, gee, I'm sorry.
You don't mind, do you?
What'd the agent have to say?
You heard what he had to say.
What are you talking about?
I understand you were there...
when the poor man went crazy
in midtown Manhattan.
You witnessed the shooting,
I believe.
That lunatic with the ax?
That was Cane's agent?
Hard to believe, isn't it?
Yeah, well, you'd think a guy
that outsells Stephen King...
couldfind
better representation.
Excuse me.
It's just a little joke.
Well, we're not in the mood.
I'll see you out, Mr. Trent.
Thank you.
Cane is a billion-dollar
franchise.
He's the tent pole
to this company.
We've already sold the film
rights to his new book...
as well as publication rights
in eighteen languages...
The book you can'tfind?
Well, his agentfound it,
at least part of it.
You think he took one look
at this latest work of art...
and went ax-happy
in broad daylight?
I think it's great.
It's great promotion for Arcane,
great publicity.
This was not a publicity stunt.
You were there.
Cane's writing has been known
to have an effect...
on his less stable readers.
An effect? Like what?
Well, disorientation,
memory loss...
severe paranoid reaction.
People pay money
to feel like that? It's cute.
Put it in the press kit.
We need you.
OK. Well, why don't you and I
get together after work?
We'll go through his files.
I don't think so.
I need to see his contracts,
papers, you know.
Impossible.
His agent was a total buffer.
We don't even know
where Cane lives.
What do you know?
For about a year
before he disappeared...
his work became erratic,
bent, more bizarre than usual.
He became convinced his writing
was real, notfiction.
Then the work stopped coming.
I need to know
if he's alive or dead.
And I need that book.
We've delayed publication
as long as we can.
His fans are getting
really restless.
This shit really sells,
doesn't it?
More than you'd imagine.
Surprised?
Lady, nothing surprises me.
We fucked up the air, the water,
we fucked up each other.
Why don't we finish the job...
by justflushing our brains
down the toilet?
Why don't you try
reading his stuff?
See if you can get it.
Got any on tape?
You want some, too, buddy?
No, relax, Robby.
Look, it's a scam,
of course it's a scam.
You see...
all this strange behaviorfrom
people that read the books...
and the agent
going nuts and so on...
I figure it's like
mass hysteria, you know?
It's like, um,
it's a pop phenomenon.
It's a craze. It'll pass.
It's this year's Hula-Hoop.
Something like that.
Yeah, my God, it's freaky.
No, it's a setup.
I just have to work out
how it's set up.
It's just a matter of time.
You, too?
God, I've had heartburn,
tell me about it.
Sporadic riots continue
to hit Eastern cities...
and reports of violence
from Boston and Philadelphia...
are now coming in.
Police continue to describe
barely coherent witnesses...
all reporting having read...
horror novelist
Sutter Cane's latest novel...
'Hobb's End Horror."
Many officers have been
physically attacked...
and more than
three hundred eighty people...
male andfemale, have been
jailed in New York County.
Two officers in Boston
were hacked to death...
amid jeering crowds
in an attack last night.
What is this horrible,
unexplainable madness...
that is gripping our lives?
What in the world is happening?
I can see.
Now we have an editorial...
Excuse me?
He sees you.
Great. Uh...
Tell him I say hi.
Oh, hi, Robby. Yeah.
Yeah, not a lot.
I picked up some of
these Sutter Cane books.
I've been reading them.
Well, it...
Pulp horror novels.
They're all pretty familiar.
They all seem
to have the same plot.
Slimy things in the dark,
people go mad...
they turn into monsters.
The funny thing is that they're
kind of better written...
than you'd expect.
They sort of get to you
in a way.
I don't know
if it's his style of writing...
or his use of description
or whatever, but...
No, don't be silly.
Do you want some, too, buddy?
He sees you.
What?
Aw, it's just too weird.
Beautiful.
Where'd you go?
Assuming you went somewhere.
Cute.
Now I know why Cane
had the artwork done himseif.
See this?
It's a map.
The red dot is Hobb's End.
It's not on any real map,
but look at this.
The two line up.
Like it or not...
Cane's book covers
place Hobb's End...
right in the middle
of New England.
So you're saying the man
went someplace fictional?
It's a real place
in a real state.
New Hampshire, to be precise.
But it's not on the map.
Well, not on any new ones,
but maybe on some old ones.
There's plenty of forgotten
towns across America.
Makes a great contest,
doesn't it?
Put the pieces together,
find the town...
win a Sutter Cane lunchbox.
How can you be sure he's there?
Well, I'd have to go to be sure.
You sure you want me to go?
I'm not suggesting
that you're lying...
that you're about to file
a fraudulent claim...
butforgive me if this sounds...
a little bit
like bullshit to me.
And if you're telling
the truth...
if you really want
your author back...
if you really want your book...
then maybe it's in both
our best interests...
if I go find him.
We have nothing to hide,
Mr. Trent.
I desire only ourfair share
if Cane is dead...
or our property if he's alive.
Since I assume you also
have nothing to hide...
I'm sure you won't mind
if I send Miss Styles along...
on your expedition.
Well, it's your party.
America, the
Beautiful
From sea to
Shining
Who is it? What?
You're awake.
Couldn't you just shake me,
you asshole?
What did I do?
We're lost.
We are lost because there
is no such place as Hobb's End.
Well, we'll see.
Never, never, never...
throw chips at a driver.
God damn it. Shit.
Asshole.
Styles, can I ask you something?
Do you really like working
on Cane's stuff?
Do you really like
busting people?
Yeah. I bustfrauds,
I bust phonies...
and, yeah, I love it.
Have you ever busted
anyone you know?
Yeah, sure I did.
Didn't make any difference.
You see, in my business,
you soon find out...
that anybody's
capable of anything.
If you can think of it,
they've done it.
Doesn't leave you much
to believe in.
Yeah.
But think of the upside...
it doesn't leave you much
to be disappointed in, either.
Believe me, the sooner we're off
the planet, the better.
Now you sound like Cane.
No, not me.
You're the Cane lover.
I just like being scared.
Cane's work scares me.
What's to be scared about?
It's not like it's real
or anything.
It's not real
from your point of view...
and right now reality
shares your point of view.
What scares me
about Cane's work...
is what might happen if reality
shared his point of view.
Whoa. We're not talking
about reality here.
We're talking aboutfiction.
It's different, you know.
A reality is just what
we tell each other it is.
Sane and insane could
easily switch places...
if the insane were
to become the majority.
You wouldfind yourseif
locked in a padded cell...
wondering what happened
to the world.
No, that wouldn't happen to me.
It would if you realized...
everything you ever knew
was gone.
It'd be pretty lonely
being the last one left.
Not only in Manhattan proper...
but there was that incident
in Long Island...
that was also related to it.
Come on, I don't buy this.
I mean, what are you saying?
That there's some kind
of disease...
that's spreading
across the country?
It is an addiction
that people have at this time...
fantasy-creating
out of the written material.
How could it be addicting?
Look, I mean this is words.
Or just something
that is created by the press?
No. I think it's acting stupid
is what it is.
Jesus Christ.
I saw a...
A cow, a sheep, a pig?
What'd you see?
Never mind.
It was nothing.
Good.
Don't move him!
Is he alive?
I don't know.
Just don't move.
He'll get a blanket,
so lie still.
I can't get out.
Don't move.
They won't let me out.
He was OK?
Come on, let's go.
We'll tell the cops
when we hit the next town.
You OK?
Oh, I can't believe it.
I must have slept
through the whole night.
Hey, thanks for driving.
What is it?
Look.
Styles, you're fantastic.
Youfound it.
What's wrong?
You drive.
Cute, cute, cute.
Main Street, USA.
Jesus.
Antiques.
Look at this old crap.
I wonder where they
manufacture this shit.
Look.
Those kids.
You didn't see them?
Where is everyone?
It's like the place
is picture perfect...
and there's nobody around.
Come on.
Styles, how'd you know
about this place?
I thought you'd never
been here before.
I haven't.
I've read about it.
So have you.
This is empty now.
It used to be filled
with strange growing things...
remember?
One night, the townspeople
saw something moving in here...
something enormous,
with arms like snakes.
'Hobb's End Horror."
The hotelfrom...
Styles,
you know what I'm thinking?
There's gotta be a great
tie-in for a town like this.
I mean, think of the tourist
potential, for instance, or...
There should be
a painting behind us.
It's nice.
There's a loose board there.
Good morning.
Can I help youfolks?
I certainly hope so.
We'd like a room, please.
We're on our way to Boston.
We thought we'd take a...
break in yourfamous
little town.
Famous?
Yeah, what with the whole
Sutter Cane thing and all.
Sut-Sutter who?
Cane. We heard he came
from around here...
and comes back to stay
once in a while.
Uh, I don't know anybody
named Cane.
Ha. Nobody passes
through here much anymore.
Let me get you your keys.
You want me to leave a deposit
or my credit card or something?
Oh, city folk.
Miss Styles,
if that's what you saw, then...
yeah, I guess it would
be a little... unsettling.
I'd be a little unnerved myseif.
But regardless of what you saw,
regardless of what you think...
we are not living inside
a Sutter Cane story.
They're all in here.
The Mrs. Pickman
in the book is a lunatic...
who chops her husband
into coleslaw.
That sweet old thing
that we met downstairs...
isn't capable
of anything worse than...
dipping her dentures
into her husband's beer.
Trent, I know
you think this is a joke.
Just listen to me
for a second, please.
What if Cane's work
isn'tfiction?
Oh, for Christ's sake.
This is reality.
You hear that?
Reality.
Now, if what you're saying
is true...
there should be
out that window...
a black Byzantine church with
two-hundred-fifty-foot spires...
with gold onions on the top.
Now, look.
You see?
Reality.
You didn't read closely enough.
The view is from the east.
'This place had once been
the seat of an evil...
'older than mankind...
"and wider
than the known universe.
"It was a place
of pain and suffering...
'beyond human understanding."
You got me reading this thing
like it's a guidebook.
"Originally,
there was an old stone church...
"built on this site
in seventeen eighty-eight...
'but the black church...
"swallowed up
the old sanctuary...
'the way it has swallowed
our minds.
'Now there is nothing left
of what was once here...
"except the mosaic
of our Lord and Savior...
'above the front door."
'Some believe the old sanctuary
still exists somewhere...
"trapped inside
this evil edifice.
'Lt's primeval inhabitants...
'were a murderous race
of creatures...
"whose vile existence
contaminated time itseif...
'affecting history...
'with their sadistic
wickedness."
It's the battle for heaven.
The archangel Michael's
fighting off...
Don't tell me. "Fighting off
one of the creatures...
'from the other side," right?
A representation. The things
Cane writes are indescribable.
'Beyond description."
Right.
We're wasting our time.
We ought to be asking
about Cane.
We'll have somebody to ask
in about two seconds.
Come on,
we have to get out of here.
We can't be in front
of the church, Trent.
They have guns, Trent.
No, I want to go back.
Give him back!
Johnny!
Johnny-boy!
Is that Cane?
Get in the truck!
Where are they comingfrom?
I see.
Tell me how you knew
about that mob!
You see, you can't bullshit
a bullshitter, can you?
'Cause I'll tell you how.
This whole thing
has been staged, that's how.
You, Harglow, and Cane
put me through all of this...
so I can blab to the media...
about Cane's
haunted little town...
help you sell
a few more million copies.
Well, fuck that.
- You're wrong.
- No, I'm not.
Before I leave
this shitty town...
I'm going to find someone
who's going to come clean...
and we're going to dismiss
your bullshit claim.
You're wrong, Trent.
I know you are wrong.
How am I wrong?
Because you're right.
You're haif right.
This was a hoax.
We did send Cane away
on a publicity stunt...
only he never showed up.
Harglow sent me with you
to make it look good...
only we weren't supposed to find
anything, but we did.
That's how I know
what we're seeing is real.
We didn't stage any of this.
It's all happening
for real, Trent.
And it is all in that book,
and that's how I know.
You're lying.
I read the books, too,
you remember?
There's nothing about any mob,
any little girl.
Not in the old books, Trent.
In the new one!
No one knew what was in it
except me and Cane's agent.
All right.
What's it about, the new one?
It's about the end
to everything...
and it starts here
in this place...
with an evil that returns
and takes over Hobb's End...
piece by piece,
starting with the children.
It's about people
turning into things...
creatures that aren't
human anymore.
It's fiction, Styles, fiction.
We need to read the new book
to find the way out.
How's that gonna help?
We could skip to the ending.
I really hope
you're making this up...
because if you're not,
you're actually crazy.
Please, Trent.
Don't make me do this alone,
Trent.
Are you coming with me?
Fine.
Have a nice bus ride home.
No smoking, please.
It bothers my husband.
I'm sorry.
I just can't seem to
help myseif around here.
I was just on my way out.
I thought I'd stop
and admire the artwork.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
Sure is.
Styles told me
you painted it yourseif.
You mean the pretty young thing
you came in here with?
I don't know her at all.
Does she know me?
She claims she does.
So you're not responsible
for this?
Hell, no.
Well, it's a nice place
you got here.
It must be a hell
of a thing to keep clean.
You look as if you've
been up all night.
Been reading.
Hush!
You're a writer?
You an actor?
Take a hint, leave.
This ain't no tourist town.
Oh, I've been trying to.
You guys are good, you know.
You,
the old lady at the hotel...
Really, really good.
Cane's been messing
with the church.
Now something came leaking out,
took the little ones first...
then passed it on to us.
Can I buy you a beer?
Don't let it get to you.
Just get out.
Give it.
What are you?
Where do you come from?
Where do you live?
With you.
Who takes care of you?
You do.
You're my mommy.
Know what today is?
Today is Mommy's Day.
Nice to see you again.
You can edit this one
from the inside, looking out.
It's funny, isn't it?
For years, I thought
I was making all this up.
But they were telling me
what to write...
giving me the power
to make it all real.
And now it is.
All those horrible,
slimy things...
trying to get back in?
They're all true.
Come.
See the instrument
of their homecoming.
What you have come lookingfor.
The new Bible...
that starts the change...
helps you see.
Do you like my ending?
Any suggestions?
Youfound something.
Where the hell did you go?
I'm losing me, John.
Help me.
I'm losing me.
What's happening?
I saw the book.
Don't look at it.
Don't read it, John.
I'm losing me!
Mrs. Pickman!
Come on, you old bitch.
We're going. Now.
You are a dead girl
Fuck you!
You're still here.
Busy night.
Special effects,
hidden speakers.
You people are professionals,
I'll give you that.
The thing I can't remember
is what came first...
us or the book.
We are not living
in a Sutter Cane story!
This is not reality!
Reality is not
what it used to be.
Oh, Jesus, this place
makes my head hurt.
Oh, really?
Come on, look at this.
This was done
by a five-year-old...
my five-year-old.
Johnny's sister.
She did me
after she did her mom.
You're alone.
Shit. Don't.
I have to.
He wrote me this way.
Oh, shit.
The key.
Jesus!
Christ.
Shit.
Never leave the city.
Why don't I learn?
Are we leaving?
We're already home.
You should have believed me.
Where's the fucking highway?
Cane's writing me.
He wants me to kiss you.
Why?
Because it's goodfor the book.
Jesus!
It's what the readers
want to read.
Oh, God!
Go! Get... get away from me!
Cane has a job for you.
Afew bad calls.
Afew wrong turns.
Do you want to know the problem
with places like this?
With religion in general?
It's never known how to convey
the anatomy of horror.
Religion seeks discipline
through fear...
yet doesn't understand
the true nature of creation.
No one's ever believed it enough
to make it real.
The same cannot be said
of my world.
Your books aren't real.
But they've sold
over a billion copies.
I've been translated
into eighteen languages.
More people believe in my work
than believe in the Bible.
You got a point?
I think you know it.
There has to be
some kind of an explanation...
for what I've seen tonight.
I'll sort this shit out later,
but right now...
there has to be some kind of
a simple fucking explanation.
Always lookingfor the con.
Even now you're trying
to rationalize.
Anyway...
your books suck.
You must try
reading my new one.
The others
have had quite an effect...
but this one will drive you
absolutely mad.
So I'm told.
It'll make the world ready
for the change.
It takes its power...
from new readers
and new believers.
That's the point.
Belief!
When people begin to
lose their ability...
to know the difference
between fantasy and reality...
the old ones can begin
their journey back.
The more people who believe,
the faster the journey.
And with the way
the other books have sold...
this one is bound
to be very, very popular.
Want to see?
All done.
'Ln the Mouth of Madness."
Yours to deliver, Trent.
What?
I will be joining
my new publishers now.
You take the manuscript
back to the worldfor me...
that's what you do.
What I do?
You are what I write.
Like this town.
It wasn't here
before I wrote it.
And neither were you.
I know what's real.
I know what I am...
and nobody pulls my strings.
Did you think my agent
attacked you by accident?
He read about you...
in there.
He knew you'd bring it back
and start the change...
make what's happened here
happen everywhere.
He tried to stop you.
I'm not a piece of fiction.
I think, therefore you are.
Read it if you don't
believe me.
See what I have
in store for you.
I know what I am.
Go back.
Your world lies
beyond that passage.
Go now.
I can't hold them back
any longer.
"Trent stood
at the edge of the rip...
'stared into the illimitable
guif of the unknown...
"the Stygian world
yawning blackly beyond.
'Trent's eyes refused to close.
'He did not shriek...
"but the hideous
unholy abominations...
'shriekedfor him...
'as in the same second
he saw them...
'spill and tumble upward...
'out of an enormous
carrion black pit...
"choked with
the gleaming white bones...
"of countless
unhallowed centuries.
'He began to back away
from the rip...
"as the army
of unspeakable figures...
"twilit by the glow
from the bottomless pit...
'came pouring at him
toward our world."
Come with me.
I can't.
I've read to the end.
Hey, kid.
You want a paper?
Have you been in an accident?
You want me to get somebody?
No. Just...
Just point me to the highway.
Straight up.
Hey, kid.
Did you ever hear of Hobb's End?
What?
Package for you, sir.
But nobody knows I'm here.
Well, someone does.
Who delivered this?
I don't know.
Who?!
I don't know!
I wasn't here last night.
Who was it?!
I was.
And I didn't see shit.
I remember New York
during the Depression.
They think they have it bad now.
You should have seen
the Bowery back then.
Bodies piled two, three feet
high off the gutter.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm God now.
You understand?
God's not supposed to be
a hack horror writer.
But maybe
I can help you believe.
Look around when you wake up.
Did I ever tell you
my favorite color was blue?
Relax, buddy.
Relax.
You're awake now.
It was just a bad dream.
Are you deaf and dumb, sir?
I was just there in the town...
in that town, and...
there were people there...
and shops and homes and...
I don't doubt that.
What I'm telling you
for the tenth time...
is that it couldn't
have been called Hobb's End.
There never was, is,
or shall be any such place...
by that name in this state.
Ever.
I want to see your supervisor!
Well...
that is quite a story.
If you could write it,
I'd publish it.
You don't believe it, do you?
If I don't, what's my option?
That I'm crazy?
I'm not crazy.
Have you heard the rumors...
that Cane's books
have affected certain readers?
Yeah. Styles told me.
Styles... Oh, that's the girl
you say I sent with you.
But I know I sent you off alone.
Why wouldn't I remember her?
Well...
That's easy.
She was written out.
Written out?
Look, do you think...
those books
somehow infected you?
Listen to me, Harglow.
Everything I've said is true.
It's real.
And that's why I had to destroy
the last manuscript.
But I know that's not true.
What are you talking about?
You delivered that manuscript
to me months ago.
To me personally in this room.
I did?
Yes, you did.
Last spring.
For God's sakes,
we published in July.
The book's been in the stores
for seven weeks.
Have you read it?
No.
I never read Cane's work.
I haven't got
the stomach for it.
Pull it.
Don't distribute it.
Even if everything I've said
is totally Looney Tunes...
I know this book
will drive people crazy.
Well, let's hope so.
The movie comes out next month.
Oh, Christ.
The newest, and presumably
posthumous, work...
of Sutter Cane continues
to sit at number one...
on the best-seller list.
'Ln the Mouth of Madness"
is expected to break...
all previous publishing records.
On the local scene, police
are at a loss to explain...
the outbreak of violent crime
among the city's clergy.
The mayor has called
an emergency meeting...
of law enforcement
and medical agencies...
to discuss an apparent epidemic
of paranoid schizophrenia.
Just an unbelievably
horrible story, Bob.
What began locally...
has now broken out
into a global epidemic.
An epidemic
of monumental proportions...
of senseless, seemingly
unmotivated acts of violence.
Like the book?
I love it.
Good.
Then this shouldn't
come as a surprise.
Jeez!
I don't believe he did that!
It's spreading out there,
isn't it?
Just because you know
the symptoms...
doesn't mean to say
your story's true.
It's Cane's story...
and it'll spread
with each new reader.
That's how it gets its power.
What about the people
who don't read?
There's a movie.
Oh, yes, of course.
I'm gonna leave now...
but I'll be coming back,
I promise.
I want to help you.
There's no hurry.
It's safer in here now.
It'll get worse out there.
Why?
Every species can smell
its own extinction.
The last ones left...
won't have a pretty time of it.
And in ten years, maybe less...
the human race
will just be a bedtime story...
for their children.
A myth. Nothing more.
Did he have anything to say?
No. It was useless.
He thinks he's fiction...
and that Sutter Cane's
causing the epidemic.
Do you read Sutter Cane?
Oh, God!
I'll try and continue...
this emergency broadcast as long
as we can hold out here.
Um, the city is almost
completely deserted now.
There are only a few stragglers
left on the streets.
There are
no emergency services.
The fires continue
to burn out of control.
This incredible epidemic
of random mass killing...
has spread to every country
in the civilized world.
Every hour, more people
are becoming infected...
being driven to senseless
acts of extreme violence.
We have gotten reports,
sketchy at best...
of people mutating, their bodies
swelling and distorting...
changing somehow.
Locally, the mass killings
appear to have moved inland.
All the major cities
on the East Coast are silent.
We lost contact
with Los Angeles...
and the West Coast last night...
so it's impossible
at this time to know...
how many unaffected people
are left.
If for any reason...
you are one of us
who hasn't become infected...
take shelter immediately.
Do not trust any friends
orfamily members.
I repeat... Do not...
I'm sorry about the balls!
It was a lucky shot, that's all!
What?!
I am not insane.
Do you hear me?
I am not insane!
Relax, buddy.
You're awake now.
This is not a Sutter Cane story!
This is not reality!
Not reality! Not reality!
This is reality.