- NOW, MR. GOLDEN,
HOW CAN I HELP YOU?
- "HUNK."
CALL ME "HUNK" FOR NOW.
- ALL RIGHT.
- THANKS FOR SEEING ME
ON SUCH SHORT NOTICE.
NOBODY ELSE WOULD.
- YOU MADE IT SOUND LIKE
A MATTER OF LIFE OR DEATH.
- YEAH, WELL, IT IS.
FOR HIM.
- WHO IS HE?
- HIS--HIS NAME IS
BRADLEY BRINKMAN.
- WHERE IS HE?
- RIGHT HERE.
I'M BRADLEY BRINKMAN.
ON THE INSIDE ANYWAY.
- LOOK, PLAYING AT
SCHIZOPHRENIA IS NOT MY--
- YAH, I KNOW, I KNOW,
I KNOW.
LOOK, DOC, DIDN'T YOU EVER WANT
TO BECOME SOMEBODY ELSE?
SOMEBODY EXCITING,
SOMEBODY FANTASTIC?
I JUST HAPPEN TO BE THAT
SOMEBODY FANTASTIC BRADLEY
BRINKMAN WANTED TO BECOME.
AND THEN BECAME.
- SOMEBODY WITH A FANTASTIC
IMAGINATION, YOU MEAN.
- I KNOW IT SOUNDS CRAZY,
BUT YOU GOTTA HEAR MY STORY.
TIME IS RUNNING
OUT FOR BRADLEY.
AND FOR ME.
- ALL RIGHT.
I'LL HEAR YOUR STORY, BUT TIME
IS RUNNING OUT FOR US AS WELL.
SO WHY DON'T YOU JUST BEGIN
WITH THE FIRST TIME THAT YOU
BEGAN--
- AND BRADLEY BRINKMAN.
- THE FIRST TIME THAT YOU
AND BRADLEY BRINKMAN BEGAN
TO FEEL THIS WAY.
- DOCTOR, IF I CONVINCE YOU,
WILL YOU TAKE MY CASE?
- I'M LISTENING, MR. GOLDEN.
- UP UNTIL SIX WEEKS AGO, I
REALLY WAS BRADLEY BRINKMAN.
HACK, COMPUTER HACK.
I SPENT THE FIVE YEARS
SINCE COLLEGE CHAINED TO A
COMPUTER KEYBOARD.
EXCEPT FOR MY
IMAGINATION, THAT IS.
I ALWAYS DAYDREAMED
ABOUT BEING ONE OF THOSE
IMPOSSIBLY COOL GUYS
YOU SEE IN THE MOVIES
OR COMMERCIALS.
YOU KNOW, THE GUY THAT
DRIVE MASERATIS AND RUN
MAJOR CORPORATIONS.
THE KIND THAT DRIP WITH
WOMEN AND SELF CONFIDENCE.
YOU KNOW, THE GUY THAT LOOK
GREAT IN THOSE BIKINI BRIEFS
THAT RIDE UP THE
CRACK IN YOUR BUNS.
UNFORTUNATELY, PERPETUAL
DAYDREAMING DIDN'T LOOK
GREAT TO MY BOSS,
CONSTANTINE CONSTAPOPOLIS
OF CONSTAPOPOLIS COMPUTERS.
- DAYDREAMS?
I'M PAYING YOU TO
WRITE FOR ME DAYDREAMS?
- HI, MR. CONSTAPOPOLIS.
I WAS-- I REALLY--
I JUST DRIFTED OFF.
- YES, WAY OFF, BRINKMAN.
WAY OFF.
YOUR PROGRAM
PROPOSAL'S SO BAD,
THE K-9000 SHUT
DOWN WITH D.I. AGAIN.
- "DIGITAL INDIGESTION"?
- I'LL-- LOOK AT THIS.
CAMELS 'R' US.
THE BEDOUIN PROGRAM.
WHO'S GOT A CAMEL
WITH A FLOPPY HUMP?
LOOK AT THIS ONE.
CONVERSATIONAL ICELANDIC.
WHO ARE YOU
GONNA SELL IT TO?
PENGUINS ON TOUR?
LOOK AT THIS ONE.
SUSHI TOWERS.
EAT WHAT YOU BUILD.
YOU KNOW YOUR WORK HASN'T
BEEN THE SAME EVER SINCE--
- SUSIE ELOPED WITH HER
AEROBICS INSTRUCTOR. I--
- YEAH?
- I KNOW I KNOW-- HOW WOULD YOU
FEEL IF YOUR GIRLFRIEND
REJECTED YOU BECAUSE YOU
DIDN'T WEAR A LEOTARD AND
COUNT DURING SEX?
- LOOK, I'M RUNNING A
BUSINESS HERE.
YOU HAVE TWO
WEEKS--TWO WEEKS!
--TO MAKE A MONEY-MAKING
IDEA UP HERE,
OR ELSE YOU'RE OFF STUFFING--
- THE GRAPE
all: THE GRAPE LEAVES IN MY
ONE-EYED FATHER'S
GREEK RESTAURANT,
CYCLOPS WEST.
- THANK YOU, MR. CONSTAPOPOLIS
FOR YOUR UNDERSTANDING
AND GENEROSITY.
- HAVE A GOOD DAY.
- THE NEW PROGRAM
WAS DUE AT 9:00 A.M.
I WAS DESPERATE
FOR A CONCEPT.
ANY CONCEPT BUT EVERYTHING I
WROTE READ LIKE A ONE-WAY
TICKET TO THE SOUVLAKI
LINE AT CYCLOPS WEST.
IT ALL SEEMED BEYOND HOPE
WHEN I PUNCHED A DESPERATE
PLEA INTO THE MACHINE.
AND THEN IT HAPPENED.
- WHAT HAPPENED?
- SOME KIND OF DIGITAL VULTURE
APPEARED ON MY SCREEN,
AND THEN THE
COMPUTER BEGAN WRITING THE
PROGRAM BY ITSELF.
- WHAT PROGRAM?
- THE YUPPIE PROGRAM.
A MULTI-COMPATIBLE LIFESTYLE
BUDGETING--
- YOU WROTE IT?
I CAN'T LIVE WITHOUT MINE.
WHY, I SAVED A FORTUNE
STOCKING MY WINE CELLAR ALONE.
NOT TO MENTION THE
COMPLIMENTS I GET FROM YOUR
RECIPE FOR MICROWAVE PATE.
- LIKE I SAID, THE
COMPUTER WROTE IT,
BUT I GOT THE CREDIT.
I DIDN'T KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT
PATE OR PASTA MACHINES OR
THE YUPPIE-ING OF SUBURBIA
UNTIL I STAYED UP ALL NIGHT
READING IT MYSELF.
- NOW, WAIT A MINUTE.
HOW CAN A COMPUTER
WRITE BY ITSELF?
- NOW, WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU HAVEN'T HEARD
ANYTHING YET.
I WOKE UP A HERO AND BECAME
AN EVEN BIGGER ONE WHEN
LEGIONS OF BABY BOOMERS SNAPPED
UP 50,000 COPIES
IN THE
FIRST SIX WEEKS.
MOM WAS PROUD.
DAD WAS PROUD.
HECK, EVEN SUSIE CALLED
TO SAY SHE WAS PROUD TOO.
TO HAVE YOURS TRULY FOR
A PHENOMENALLY SUCCESSFUL
EX-BOYFRIEND.
MR. CONSTAPOPOLIS PAID ME
A GIANT ROYALTY AND GAVE ME
THE SUMMER OFF WITH PAY TO
WRITE ANY PROGRAM I WANTED.
- SOUNDS WONDERFUL SO FAR.
- ALL I KNEW ABOUT YUPPIES
WAS THEY WEAR REEBOKS TO BED
AND WOULD HOCK THEIR HEALTH
CLUB CARDS FOR TEN MINUTES
ALONE WITH A DOVE BAR.
- HMM, WHERE DOES HUNK GOLDEN
FIT IN?
- AT THE BEACH HOUSE
I RENTED IN SEA SPRAY.
- SEA SPRAY?
PRETTY SWANKY PLACE.
- SWANKY?
WELL, LET'S SAY SEA
SPRAY IS SWANKY,
IF YOU'VE GOT BIG
BUCKS TO BURN.
THE ONLY THING SWANKY ABOUT
THE PLACE I COULD AFFORD WAS
THE DRIVEWAY.
THE HOUSE ITSELF WAS THE
OLDEST AND GRUNGIEST PLACE
ON SEA SPRAY BEACH.
BYE-BYE, BONUS.
IT WAS BUILT BY SOME OLD SEA
CAPTAIN WHO RAN OUT OF MONEY
AND RAN OUT OF TOWN BEFORE
HE COULD COMPLETE HIS
SAILING SHIP OF A HOUSE.
IT WAS IDEAL FOR
INVESTIGATING THE
YUPPIES-AT-PLAY LIFESTYLE
ON WHICH I WAS
SUPPOSEDLY AN EXPERT.
I'D LEISURELY CONCOCT MY
NEXT PROGRAM AND SPEND THE
REST OF MY TIME MAKING
MY DAYDREAMS COME TRUE.
- SO FAR, SO GOOD.
- EXCEPT THAT I
WENT A BIT TOO FAR.
NOW, THERE'S HELL TO PAY.
IN MY DAYDREAMS, ALL
I HAD TO DO WAS WINK,
AND THE WOMEN
WOULD COME RUNNING,
AND THERE WASN'T A BEACH
FULL OF TANNED AND TONED
COMPETITION EITHER.
THE OLD BOD DEFINITELY
COULD'VE USED A WORK-OUT.
- OH, THESE ARE FABULOUS.
LITTLE PIGGY
SALT-AND-PEPPER SHAKERS.
OH, I'VE GOTTA ADD
THESE TO MY COLLECTION.
OH, WELCOME TO SEA SPRAY,
WHERE THE WELL-TO-DO DO WELL
AT DOING WELL.
I'M POLLY CLUTTER, BUT
EVERYBODY CALLS ME "CHACHKA."
- I'M BRADLEY BRINKMAN,
BUT EVERYBODY CALLS ME
"BRADLEY."
YOU'RE IN MY LIVING ROOM.
- THOUGHT SO.
I SAW YOUR CAR OUT FRONT.
IS THAT A LOANER WHILE
THE B.M.W.'S IN THE SHOP?
- NO, ACTUALLY.
- OH, LOOK.
SOMEBODY IS GONNA FINALLY
GENTRIFY THIS OLD MESS.
GOOD FOR YOU.
- WELL, ACTUALLY, I'M JUST
RENTING THIS OLD MESS FOR
THE SUMMER.
- WELL, YOU DON'T LOOK LIKE
YOU COULD AFFORD TO BUY.
HE STARTED THIS PLACE AND
NEVER QUITE FINISHED IT.
CAPTAIN CRABIT.
- HOW DO YOU KNOW SO MUCH
ABOUT CAPTAIN CRABIT?
- WHEN I WAS A KID, I USED
TO HIDE FIRECRACKERS IN HIS
BARBECUE AND THEN LISTEN
FOR HIS HOT DOGS TO EXPLODE.
OH, HE ALWAYS HAD A FIRE
GOING, THAT CAPTAIN CRABIT.
- NO KIDDING.
- HEY, WHY DON'T YOU GO
PUT ON YOUR BATHING SUIT?
CHACHKA'S GONNA TAKE YOU
ON THE GABBY GUIDED TOUR.
- THE GABBY GUIDED TOUR?
- DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
IT'S FREE.
- SOUNDS GREAT.
HOW COME THEY
CALL YOU CHACHKA.
- OH, 'CAUSE MY HOUSE
IS FULL OF CHACHKAS.
I COLLECT THINGS.
KNICK-KNACKS.
BRIC-A-BRAC.
I'M AN INCURABLE COLLECTOR.
WHEN I MOVED OUT HERE FROM
NEW YORK IN THE '50s,
THE ONLY BUILDING
ON THE BEACH
WAS MY DAD'S HOT DOG STAND,
WEE WILLIE'S WEENIES.
- ♪ WEE WILLIE'S WEENIES, TOP
OFF WITH CHEESE AND BEANIES ♪
both: ♪ WEE WILLIE'S WEENIES,
BITE DOWN ON ONE TODAY, OLE ♪
THAT'S IT!
OH, IN THE '60s THIS PLACE WAS
BUFF BLUFF TOPLESS BEACH.
ON A HOT DAY, THE BOOBS WERE
PACKED TIGHTER THAN EGGS IN
YOUR EASTER BASKET.
- BORN TOO LATE.
- IN THE '70s MAHATMA
MAHARAJI WENT BANKRUPT
BUILDING THE WORLD'S FIRST
AND LAST CONDO COMMUNE.
NOW, WE'VE GOT YUPPIES.
WHO'S NEXT?
- SHE IS.
- WHO?
- HER.
SHE'S NOT REAL.
- WHERE IS SHE?
- RIGHT THERE.
NEXT TO THOSE SURFERS.
- THERE'S JUST A
COUPLE OF SURFERS.
- THE MOST GORGEOUS CREATURE
IN THE GALAXY IS STEAMING
RIGHT THIS WAY.
- YOU'RE IMAGINING THIS.
- HUH?
WHERE'D SHE GO?
- HEY, HEY, TAKE IT EASY.
SHE DIDN'T GO ANYWHERE,
BECAUSE SHE WAS NEVER HERE.
HEY, HEY, COME ON.
TIME TO MEET THE HEAVY HITTERS
ON THE SOCIAL CIRCUIT.
OH, YOU'RE IN LUCK.
THEY'RE ALL HERE.
- DON'T WORRY.
WE'LL GET THIS ONE.
- IN "THE ADVENTURES OF
ROCKY AND BULLWINKLE,
"ARCH-VILLAIN BORIS BADENOV
WAS NAMED AFTER THE TITLE
CHARACTER IN WHAT
FAMOUS RUSSIAN OPERA?"
- OPERA.
GIVE ME A BREAK.
- IGOR STRAVINSKY, RIGHT?
- IGOR STRAVINSKY, WRONG.
- OUR TURN?
- YOU'RE THE BEST.
- NO, YOU'RE THE BEST.
- BUT YOU'RE THE CUTEST.
- YOU'RE THE CUTEST.
both: TIE.
- BORIS GODUNOV, RIGHT?
- SEA SPRAY BEACH RULES FOR
TRIVIAL PURSUIT PROHIBIT
SAYING THE CORRECT ANSWER
TO THE LOSING TEAM.
- THEY MIGHT ACTUALLY
GET ONE RIGHT NEXT TIME.
both: NO.
- WHO IS THIS GUY, CHACHKA?
- BARRY BRINKMAN.
HE JUST MOVED IN.
- IT'S BRADLEY BRINKMAN.
SORRY.
- BRADLEY.
I WANT YOU TO MEET
COASTER ROYCE,
WALL STREET WIZ AND YOUNGEST
VICE PRESIDENT IN THE
HISTORY OF RATCHET,
SLAMMER AND HOPS.
- RATCHET, SLAMMER,
HOPS AND ROYCE,
IF I HAVE A SAY IN IT.
AND I WILL.
I ALWAYS DO.
- AND THAT JET-SET ESCAPEE
FROM EAST COAST OLD MONEY,
ALEXIS CASH.
- HA HA.
WHERE YOU MOVING
IN, BRINKMAN?
- THE CRABIT HOUSE.
- I'M GLAD SOMEONE IS
GOING TO SPRUCE UP THAT
DILAPIDATED OLD DUMP.
THANK GOD.
- WELL, ACTUALLY, I'M JUST
RENTING IT FOR THE SUMMER.
- YEAH, YOU DIDN'T LOOK LIKE
YOU COULD AFFORD TO BUY.
NEED ANY COCKROACH TRAPS?
- WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU'RE SKEET
MECKLENBURGER, RIGHT?
ALL-PRO DALLAS ANNIHILATOR
LINEBACKER, RIGHT?
- "ALL-THROUGH"
LINEBACKER, YOU MEAN.
CUT LIKE A ROOKIE ON
UNCONDITIONAL WAIVERS.
- YEAH, BUT I CAN STILL
CUT IT WITH YOU, CAN'T I,
PASSION PIE?
- WITH AN ELECTRIC
KNIFE, BABY.
- YOU REMEMBER
LAUREL SPRINGS,
CHEERLEADER QUEEN OF
WEDNESDAY NIGHT FOOTBALL.
- YEAH, I LOVE THE LITE
KNOCKWURST COMMERCIAL
YOU GUYS DO TOGETHER.
- OH, THANKS.
- A FAN.
HOW FLATTERING.
YOU PLAY V-BALL, BRINSKY?
- V-BALL?
V-BALL. OH, YEAH.
I'D LOVE TO, BUT I
HAVEN'T PLAYED IT IN AGES.
- DON'T WORRY.
SKEET KNOWS ALL THE RULES.
- THERE ARE A FEW DO'S AND
DON'TS IN V-BALL, BRINSKY,
SO LET'S START
WITH THE DON'TS.
YOU DON'T REACH
UNDER THE NET.
YOU DON'T RUN INTO THE NET.
AND YOU DON'T KICK SAND ON
AN OPPOSING PLAYER
WHEN HE'S DOWN.
GOT THE PICTURE, BRINSKY?
- SO WHAT IF THEY ALL ACTED
LIKE THEY HATED ME FROM BIRTH?
THERE WAS AN AURA
TO THEIR ARROGANCE.
I HAD TO FIT IN.
I YUPPIED OUT MY HOUSE WITH
EVERY TRENDY APPLIANCE MY
CREDIT LIMIT COULD BEAR.
AH, SO WHAT IF THE STUFF
WOULD NEVER FIT IN MY STUDIO
APARTMENT AFTER THE SUMMER.
I WAS LIVING IN THE MOMENT.
I EVEN PERSONALLY
STONEWASHED ALL MY CLOTHES.
I STILL HAVEN'T
FIGURED OUT WHY.
SEA SPRAY BY NIGHT
MEANS THE SAND CASTLE.
THE MEN ARE LOW ON BODY
FAT, THE WOMEN ARE HIGH ON
THEMSELVES ... AND WHATEVER
ELSE IS GOING AROUND.
I WAS READY FOR STEP TWO,
INVITING THE WHOLE BEACH TO
AN OPEN HOUSE AT MY PLACE.
I'D PARTY THEIR ASSES OFF.
INCLUDE MYSELF IN
WITH THE IN CROWD.
THE SEA SPRAY CROWD
ACCEPTS NO SUBSTITUTES,
AND I FELT LIKE
A SUBSTITUTE.
- HEY, HI, COASTER.
HOW'S IT GOING, GUY?
- WHERE DID YOU
GET THAT OUTFIT?
- WELL, I GOT IT AT
THE SEA SPRAY GALLERIA.
- OH, ALEXIS, DARLING.
BRINKMAN HERE WENT
SHOPPING AT
THE SEA SPRAY "SCHLOCKERIA."
- WHAT'S SO FUNNY?
WE'RE EXACTLY IDENTICAL.
- OH, FAT CHANCE.
- MIDNIGHT EXPRESS FOR MEN.
MADE IN TURKEY.
POLY-COTTON BLEND.
both: OOH.
OH, GIORGIO
SPERMATUCCI STONEWASH.
SPERMATUCCI, MY
FAVORITE DESIGNER.
- THEY'RE 100% COTTON.
- THEY STONEWASH THEIR
DENIM IN SYNTHETIC STONES.
- BRINKMAN, A LITTLE ADVICE,
THE ONLY THING THAT YOU'LL
LAY TONIGHT IN THAT
IS LINOLEUM.
- OH, YEAH, YOU GUYS,
HERE'S AN INVITATION.
MY OPEN HOUSE.
TRY AND DROP BY.
- CATERED NO DOUBT BY
CHARLES DE GRAVY DU POISSON.
OH, WE WILL BE
THERE WITH BELLS ON.
BELLS.
- DING AWAY.
- AND THEN I SAW HER.
AGAIN.
- ARE WE PUMPED
IN THERE, BRADLEY?
- I WAS DANCING WITH THAT
INCREDIBLY GORGEOUS WOMAN
FROM THE BEACH,
BUT SHE VANISHED.
- OH, SURE.
HOW COME I CAN'T SEE HER?
WHERE'D SHE GO?
- HELL, IF I KNOW.
- THE FINAL SCORE FOR MY
OPEN HOUSE WAS HOST-ONE,
GUESTS-ZERO.
TALK ABOUT WOUNDED PRIDE,
MINE WAS DEAD ON ARRIVAL.
A NIGHTMARE IN LEFTOVER
ARTICHOKE HEARTS.
- HELLO.
CHACHKA, UH-- CHACHKA,
BABY, HOW ARE YA?
OH, FANTASTIC.
FANTASTIC TURN-OUT, YEAH.
YEAH!
WHAT?
OH, YOU CAN'T MAKE IT OVER.
OH, BABE, WE'RE
GONNA MISS YA, YEAH.
GREAT PARTY, BRADLEY.
YEAH, DUDE, GREAT PARTY.
WHAT?
LEFTOVERS?
UH, NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
THESE PARTY ANIMALS,
THEY ARE PIGGING OUT.
YEAH, PIGGING OUT, YEAH.
WHAT?
BABE, I CAN'T HEAR YOU.
YOU GOTTA SPEAK UP FOR ME, OKAY?
NO, NO, HONEY
I CAN'T HEAR YOU.
I'LL TALK TO YOU
TOMORROW, OKAY?
YEAH, YEAH.
BYE!
"ANY LEFTOVERS."
SHE'LL PROBABLY BE RIGHT
OVER WITH TUPPERWARE.
- SUPPOSE YOU GAVE AN OPEN
HOUSE, AND NOBODY CAME.
WE CAN'T HAVE THAT NOW,
CAN WE, COMPUTER CHAMP?
- WAIT A MINUTE.
DON'T DISAPPEAR.
OKAY.
WHO ARE YOU, AND HOW DO YOU KNOW
SO MUCH ABOUT ME?
AND AM I THE ONLY
PERSON WHO CAN SEE YOU?
- AROUSED?
YOUR CURIOSITY, I MEAN.
BRADLEY, A GIRL IN MY LINE
WORKS UP A DEVILISH THIRST.
AREN'T YOU GONNA INVITE
ME TO STAY FOR A PERRIER?
WOW, THE FOOD'S JUST
TO DIE FOR, BRADLEY.
YOU KNOW, YOU COULD
BE ONE FABULOUS HOST.
IT'S A SHAME YOU
DON'T RECOGNIZE IT.
- YOU'VE HAD THE FOOD,
AND YOU'VE HAD YOUR FUN.
NOW, WHO ARE YOU?
- MY NAME'S O'BRIEN.
- JUST O'BRIEN?
- JUST O'BRIEN.
- AND WHERE DO
YOU LIVE, O'BRIEN?
- HELL.
I HAVE A LARGE STUDIO APARTMENT
AT 1,700 DEGREES FAHRENHEIT.
OF COURSE, I WANT A ONE-BEDROOM
AT 2,500 DEGREES FAHRENHEIT.
OR A LOFT IN THE CELSIUS
NEIGHBORHOOD,
BUT ANYTHING OVER 2,000 DEGREES
IS A FORTUNE.
IT'S HELL TO FIND A DECENT
PLACE TO LIVE IN HELL.
- WHO WRITES YOUR MATERIAL,
DAVID LETTERMAN?
CUTE.
VERY CLEVER.
WHAT DO YOU WANT FROM ME?
- OKAY, LISTEN UP, BRADLEY,
BECAUSE I'M ONLY GONNA READ
YOUR BLACK MAGIC
RIGHTS ONCE.
- OH.
- BE FOREWARNED--
- SORRY.
- BE FOREWARNED, YOU'RE
ABOUT TO BE SOLICITED FOR A
SUPERNATURAL EXPERIENCE.
YOU HAVE THE RIGHT
TO CALL AN EXORCIST.
IF YOU CANNOT
AFFORD AN EXORCIST,
ONE WILL BE
APPOINTED TO YOU.
ANY BLACK MAGIC COVENANTS
HEREAFTER EXECUTED BY YOU
CAN AND WILL BE USED TO
ASSERT DARK DOMINION OVER
YOUR SOUL.
ANY QUESTIONS?
- YEAH.
WHY ME?
- I'VE HAD MY EVIL
ON YOU A LONG TIME.
BRADLEY, YOU NEED
A FRIEND RIGHT NOW.
WHO DO YOU THINK INSPIRED
THE YUPPIE PROGRAM?
- WAIT A MINUTE.
THIS WAS ON MY COMPUTER.
YOU POSSESSED MY WORD
PROCESSOR THAT NIGHT?
- LET'S CALL IT
"TEMPORARY OCCUPANCY."
- THIS CONVERSATION IS
INSANE, AND SO ARE YOU.
- ONE QUESTION, BRADLEY.
ARE YOU HAPPY YOU RENTED THIS
FABULOUS HOUSE
SO CLOSE TO ROYCE, COULD WIPE
HIS TOPSIDERS ON YOUR FACE
AT THE DROP OF A FRISBEE?
HAPPY WOMEN AROUND HERE
WON'T GIVE YOU THE CORRECT TIME
OF DAY AT A ROLEX CONVENTION?
- WELL--
- I CAN MAKE YOU OVER.
MAKE YOU INTO THE
KIND OF MAN YOU'VE ALWAYS
DAYDREAMED ABOUT.
THE KIND OF MAN
WOMEN WANT MOST.
AND MEN WANT MOST TO BE.
A HUNK.
HANDSOME, TANNED, TONED.
RICH, BRADLEY.
SUCCESSFUL.
ADMIRED.
- WHAT'S ALL THIS
GONNA COST ME?
- OH, YOUR SOUL, SILLY BOY.
AND WOULD YOU
BELIEVE, RIGHT NOW,
WE HAVE A NO-OBLIGATION
SELL-YOUR-SOUL-FOR-THE-SUMMER
TRIAL OFFER?
AND IF YOU ARE NOT
100% SATISFIED,
YOUR OLD BODY AND OLD
SOUL WILL BE REFUNDED.
IT'S A PACKAGE DEAL.
- ARE YOU PART OF
THE PACKAGE DEAL?
- OH, THE DEVIL HIMSELF,
INCORPORATED,
FORBIDS MY DATING CLIENTS
WHILE THEIR SOUL IS IN
SPIRITUAL ESCROW.
- THE DEVIL HIMSELF,
INCORPORATED?
- THE BOSS NEEDS TAX
WRITE-OFFS JUST LIKE YOU.
- WE'LL STILL SEE
EACH OTHER, WON'T WE?
- OH, FOR ETERNITY,
IF YOU WANT.
SO GIVE IT A GO
FOR THE SUMMER?
- AND NOW I'M SUPPOSED TO SIGN
SOMETHING IN BLOOD, RIGHT?
- A HYPODERMIC PEN.
NO MUSS, NO FUSS.
IT'S MY LATEST INVENTION.
- OW!
- DONE.
- NOW WHAT?
- NOW, WAIT.
A NEW LIFE AND A NEW BODY
BEGIN TOMORROW AT SUNRISE.
SWEET DREAMS,
BRADLEY BRINKMAN.
THIS MAY BE THE LAST
WE SEE OF THE OLD YOU.
BYE.
- BYE.
OH, WEIRD.
REALLY WEIRD.
- THAT NIGHT, I
HAD A WILD DREAM.
AT LEAST, I THOUGHT
IT WAS A DREAM.
- OH, MAN, WHAT A NIGHTMARE.
WAIT A MINUTE.
WHOSE ARM IS THIS?
WHOSE ROOM IS THIS?
STILL DREAMING.
I'M NOT DREAMING.
THIS IS REAL.
WHERE'D ALL THIS COME FROM?
OH, MY GOD.
O'BRIEN REALLY DID IT.
SHE REALLY...REALLY DID IT.
HEY, THAT'S NOT OSCAR.
MY BEST FRIEND SINCE THE
SEVENTH GRADE IS MISSING.
O'BRIEN?
O'BRIEN, WHAT THE
HELL-- CHACHKA, HI.
- YOU KNOW ME? I'D REMEMBER
MEETING YOU.
IF YOU'RE ONE OF THE
LEFTOVERS FROM LAST NIGHT,
I'M GONNA KILL MYSELF
FOR MISSING YOU.
I MEAN, IT.
- YEAH, I'M WHAT'S
LEFT OVER, ALL RIGHT.
- OH, IS BODY--I
MEAN, BRADLEY--HOME?
- BRADLEY.
NO, BRADLEY'S STILL
DREAMING, I THINK.
I MEAN, HE'S STILL HUNG
OVER FROM THE PARTY.
- OH, LOOK.
HE REDECORATED
THE WHOLE PLACE.
- YEAH.
WOW.
SHE SURE DID.
I MEAN, YES.
YES, HE DID.
WHAT ARE YOU STARING AT?
- A REAL HUNK.
I MEAN, IS THAT YOUR
NEW CAR IN THE DRIVEWAY?
- NEW CAR?
WHAT NEW CAR?
YOU MEAN, THIS CAR?
- NO.
THIS IS MY GASTROMOBILE.
- AH, IT'S INTERESTING, YES.
- THE NEW CAR IS OVER HERE.
IS IT YOURS?
- CAR OF MY DAYDREAMS.
UH, I MEAN, I DON'T KNOW.
- WHO ARE YOU ANYWAY?
- I'M NOT SURE.
I MEAN, BRADLEY AND
I ARE VERY CLOSE.
LISTEN, HAVE YOU SEEN A
WOMAN ABOUT 5'9", DARK HAIR,
REALLY GORGEOUS?
- NOT YOU TOO.
- NEVER MIND.
SHE'LL TURN UP.
I HOPE.
LOOK AT THIS STUFF.
H.G. WHO IS H.G.?
NOT ONLY
WAS I NEW TO CHACHKA,
BUT EVERYTHING I NOW
OWNED WAS NEW TO ME.
HOW WE DOING, SUSIE?
"THE WHOLE PACKAGE DEAL."
O'BRIEN.
"HUNK GOLDEN?"
MY NAME IS "HUNK GOLDEN?"
I'M RICH.
WHATEVER HAPPENED
TO BRADLEY BRINKMAN?
O'BRIEN!
O'BRIEN.
- IT WAS ALL I COULD DO TO
KEEP FROM RIPPING HIS TOWEL
OFF WITH MY TEETH.
WHAT'S HIS NAME?
HE DIDN'T SAY.
- ANOTHER RENTER ASSHOLE.
- THERE HE IS NOW.
YOO-HOO!
BRADLEY'S FRIEND!
OVER HERE.
- OH, NOW, THAT'S
A PERFECT SPECIMEN.
- A MAN'S MAN-AND-A-HALF.
- PUTS YOU TWO
BOTH TO SHAME.
- YEAH, WE'LL
SEE ABOUT THAT.
- HELLO AGAIN.
I DIDN'T CATCH YOUR NAME.
- BRADLEY-- HUNK.
MY NAME IS HUNK GOLDEN.
- HUNK.
THAT SHORT FOR
HAIRDRESSER OR SOMETHING?
- UH, HUNK.
THIS IS COASTER, ALEXIS,
LAUREL AND SKEET.
- WELL, I FEEL LIKE
I KNOW YOU ALREADY.
- ISN'T HE CHARMING.
MOVING IN?
- OR MOVING ALONG?
- NO, ACTUALLY, I'M JUST
VISITING BRADLEY BRINKMAN.
- THAT SCRAWNY LITTLE WUSS?
- WELL, ACTUALLY, I'M JUST
LOOKING FOR SOMEBODY RIGHT NOW.
- WELL,
WHAT'S THE HURRY, MURRAY?
JUST SO HAPPENS WE'RE LOOKING
FOR A FOURTH FOR V-BALL.
- YOU DO KNOW HOW TO
PLAY V-BALL, DON'T YOU?
- UH, YEAH.
SOMEBODY GAVE ME A
FEW LESSONS ... ONCE.
- GO, HUNK!
- OH, I HOPE THIS
IS GONNA BE GOOD.
- ALL RIGHT!
GREAT.
- GO, HUNK! GO!
- YOU CAN SERVE, CAN'T YOU?
- YEAH.
MIND IF I PRACTICE FIRST?
- HEY, GARDENER.
YOU AND ME.
ONE ON ONE.
HOPE YOU CAN HANDLE
A GOOD SPIKE.
- GOOD LUCK.
- YEAH.
- COME ON.
GET IT UP, GORGEOUS.
- GO, HUNK.
KILL HIM, HUNK.
- I'M GONNA WRAP YOUR
NUTS AROUND YOUR NECK,
TWINKIE DICK.
- NO, SKEET.
NO!
- SKEET, DON'T DAMAGE
THE MERCHANDISE.
- SKEET, ENOUGH'S ENOUGH.
- GO, HUNK.
- OUT COLD.
- FAIR FIGHT.
HE'S MY BEST FRIEND, BUT
HE CAN REALLY ROAR LIKE AN
ASSHOLE SOMETIMES.
- WHERE'D YOU
GET THAT WALLOP?
- THAT'S WHAT
I'D LIKE TO KNOW.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU
THREW THIS TOGETHER
IN FIVE MINUTES' NOTICE, HUNK.
- WHAT A HOST.
- ODDS AND ENDS
FROM THE FRIDGE.
- ODDS AND END FOR 40.
IMPRESSIVE.
- WHERE'S BRADLEY?
- BRADLEY, HE'S DOWNTOWN.
BIG FAMILY EMERGENCY.
- FIGURES.
- I WANT A WORD WITH
YOU, MR. HUNK GOLDEN.
- THE LAST TIME SHE HAD
A WORD WITH SOMEBODY,
HE COULDN'T TALK FOR A WEEK.
WANT A CRACKER?
- I'M NOT EATING.
- WHY NOT, BUBBY?
- I'M FAT.
- YOU'RE NOT FAT.
- OH, YOU ARE NOT FAT.
YOU'RE A BEAUTIFUL GAZELLE.
- I'M HUGE.
- YOU'RE NOT HUGE.
- YOU ARE NOT.
- YOU'RE THE MOST BEAUTIFUL
THING IN THE WORLD.
- I'M A BEACHED WHALE.
- YOU'RE NOT A BEACHED WHALE.
- I'M REALLY
SORRY ABOUT SKEET.
I DON'T KNOW MY
OWN STRENGTH.
HOW IS HE?
- UNCONSCIOUS UNDER
A 20-POUND ICE PACK.
YOU ANIMAL.
- I'M AN ANIMAL?
- I'VE NEVER SEEN ANYTHING
SO SAVAGE IN MY ENTIRE LIFE.
WHO DO YOU THINK YOU ARE?
- DO I KNOW?
I JUST MET MYSELF FOR
THE FIRST TIME TODAY.
- YOU KNOW WHAT SOMEBODY
OUGHT TO DO TO A BRUTAL
BASTARD LIKE YOU?
- UH, NO.
- SOMEBODY SHOULD THANK YOU
FOR PUTTING THAT BIG LUMMOX
IN HIS PLACE.
YOU'RE A WALKING A
CHUCK NORRIS MOVIE,
AND I'M NOT WAITING TILL
YOU'RE OUT ON VIDEOCASSETTE!
- UH, IN CASE YOU
HAVEN'T NOTICED,
THIS HOUSE IS
FULL OF GUESTS.
- AND ALL THE WOMEN
WANNA TAKE YOU SOUTH OF THE
MASON-DIXON LINE.
- THINGS LIKE THIS NEVER
HAPPEN TO BRADLEY BRINKMAN.
- WELL, WHY WORRY ABOUT THAT
LITTLE OLD TADPOLE WHEN WE
GOT A BIGGER FISH TO FRY?
- WHERE'D YOU LEARN
TO JOCKEY THIS BED?
- DALLAS GENERAL HOSPITAL.
BEFORE BECOMING AN
ANNIHILATOR CHEERLEADER,
I WAS STRIPPED OF
MY CANDY STRIPES.
- WELL, ONCE A CANDY-STRIPER,
ALWAYS A CANDY-STRIPER.
THAT'S WHAT I SAY.
- YOU WANNA SEE MY STRIPES?
OKAY!
THEY'RE INVISIBLE.
- OH, I CAN SEE
'EM JUST FINE.
- WHOO!
OH-OH-OH!
- OH-OH-OH-OH-OH-OH-OH-OH!
- WHOO!
WHOO!
AH! AH! AH! AH! AH!
- OH! OH! OH!
- WHOO!
- AH AH AH!
- WHAT A DIFFERENCE
A DAY MAKES.
- IT'S ABOUT TIME.
WHERE IS BRADLEY BRINKMAN?
- YOU'RE STILL
BRADLEY INSIDE.
ONLY NOW, YOU'RE
GETTING RESULTS.
- I THOUGHT YOU WERE SOME
GORGEOUS KOOK, NOT SATANA,
QUEEN OF DARKNESS.
- WILL YOU RELAX?
ENJOY LIVING IN THIS GORGEOUS
NEW CHASSIS FOR A WHILE.
- YOU KNOW, I DRANK
EIGHT MARTINIS.
I'M NOT EVEN HUNG OVER.
- THAT'S NOTHING.
TOMORROW, WE BEGIN
NEW BODY ORIENTATION.
ARE YOU GONNA BE SURPRISED.
- WHAT ABOUT MY OLD BODY?
- THE TRIAL OFFER EXPIRES
THE MIDNIGHT AFTER LABOR DAY,
BUT YOU'LL
NEVER GO BACK.
NOBODY DOES.
TRUST ME.
I DESIGNED YOU MYSELF.
YOU'VE GOT THE THIGHS
OF SYLVESTER STALLONE,
THE PELVIS OF ELVIS PRESLEY,
THE NAVEL OF ARNOLD
SCHWARZENEGGER,
THE NIPPLES OF ROBERT REDFORD,
THE EYES OF PAUL NEWMAN, AND
THE SCHLONG OF KING KONG.
I GAVE YOU PERMA-FIRM FLESH,
WRINKLE-PROOF PERMA-TAN SKIN,
UNFRIZZABLE HAIR,
UNBREAKABLE BONES,
SELF-CLEANING CAVITY-PROOF
TEETH, ODORLESS SWEAT.
WHEN YOU DIE, YOUR SOUL
LIVES ON IN HELL IN HUNK FORM
FOR ETERNITY.
GORGE YOURSELF ON THE MOST
FATTENING FOOD
IN ALL CREATION AND
NEVER GAIN WEIGHT.
CHUG 12 TIMES THE ALCOHOL
CAPACITY OF A PERSON
TWICE YOUR SIZE.
YOUR LIVER WAS DESIGNED
BY DEAN MARTIN.
AND TO PROTECT OUR
EVIL INVESTMENT,
YOU'RE A NATURAL
MARTIAL ARTS MASTER.
JUST ASK SKEET.
LET'S NOT FORGET WHY
WE PACKAGED YOU SO STUNNINGLY--
WOMEN.
YOU'LL BE A MOVING TARGET
FROM NOW ON FOR ANYONE WHO
LOVES LUSCIOUS-LOOKING MEN.
YOU'RE BOUND TO OVERDO THE
SUPER-STUD BIT AT FIRST,
BUT YOU'LL KNOW WHEN
ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
WORSHIP THY WHEELS.
A HUNK IS NAKED
WITHOUT HIS CAR.
AND DO EVERYTHING FIRST.
A HUNK SETS TRENDS.
UNDERDRESS TO IMPRESS.
A HUNK LOOKS HIS BEST WHEN
HE LOOKS LIKE HE DOESN'T
CARE HOW HE LOOKS.
- THAT IS THE MOST
INCREDIBLE, RIDICULOUS,
PREPOSTEROUS STORY
I HAVE EVER HEARD.
- BUT IT'S TRUE.
- YOU REALIZE I JUST
TAPED YOUR ENTIRE SESSION,
AND ON THE BASIS
OF THAT ALONE,
I COULD HAVE YOU HELD FOR
OBSERVATION AT ANY MENTAL
WARD IN LOS ANGELES COUNTY,
BUT THAT'S WHAT FASCINATES ME.
YOU SOUND DELUDED, BUT
SOMETHING INSIDE ME TELLS ME
YOU'RE NOT.
- YEAH, WELL THE ME
INSIDE ME KNOWS I'M NOT.
I MEAN, WHAT IF SHE HAS A
DEMONIC WHIM AND TURNS ME
INTO A HAMSTER?
OR A HIGH SCHOOL
DRIVER'S ED INSTRUCTOR?
- DON'T PANIC, HUNK.
DO I BELIEVE YOU?
NO.
CAN I HELP YOU TO HELP YOURSELF?
MAYBE.
- ALL RIGHT.
WHERE DO I START?
- WELL, YOU SAY YOU'RE
BRADLEY BRINKMAN,
AND THAT BRADLEY BRINKMAN'S
DREAM IS TO BECOME A HUNK,
RIGHT?
- RIGHT.
- SO BE A HUNK.
I MEAN, THERE'S NOTHING
WRONG WITH THAT WHILE WE'RE
GETTING TO THE REAL
ROOT OF YOUR PROBLEM.
- YOU KNOW, MAYBE IF YOU
COULD MEET O'BRIEN
THAT WOULD PROVE EVERYTHING.
- I DOUBT WHETHER O'BRIEN OR
BRADLEY BRINKMAN EXIST
OUTSIDE OF YOUR IMAGINATION.
SO UNTIL OUR NEXT SESSION,
JUST LIGHTEN UP.
THERE ARE WORSE FATES THAN
BEING A DROP DEAD GORGEOUS GUY
WITH A PAD AT
THE BEACH, YOU KNOW.
- YOU KNOW SOMETHING, DOCTOR?
YOU'RE RIGHT.
- MY CLIENTS AND MY
FRIENDS CALL ME SUNNY.
- I'LL BE RIGHT BACK
AFTER I POWDER MY NOSE.
- YOU PROMISE.
- MM-HMM.
- WHOA.
CHICKY, CHICKY, CHICKY
DEAR OF THE SEA,
WON'T YOU TALK TO ME?
AWW, COME ON, BABE.
SAVE THAT COLD FISH STUFF
FOR ALL THESE NERDS AND
"TUNA" IN TO ME, SUSHI TAIL.
WHAT'S WRONG?
HAS CATFISH GOT
YOUR TONGUE, HUH?
- BABE!
- OOPS.
GOTTA GO.
BUT I JUST LOVE RAW FISH.
- WAS BIGGSY-WIGGSY A GOOD
WITTLE BOY WHILE MOMMY
POWDERED HER NOSY-WOSY?
- THE GOODEST.
- I'LL BET.
- EXCUSE ME.
HEY, MARTY, HOW ABOUT A CAMPARI
WITH A SPLASH OF ORANGE?
- SINCE SHE TOLD ME--
- SO HOW WAS THE
CATCH OF THE DAY?
- AH, PRETTY FRESH.
- "PRETTY FRESH"?
HEY, I PROMISED YOU PARADISE,
AND I DELIVERED.
- I KNOW, I KNOW.
A LIFE OF EARTHLY PLEASURE
IN EXCHANGE FOR AN AFTERLIFE
OF THE INTERNAL INFERNAL GOD OF
HELLFIRE AND STAPH, RIGHT?
- SOMEBODY MENTION ME?
- HUNK, MEET THE CHAIRMAN
OF THE BOARD
OF THE DEVIL HIMSELF,
INCORPORATED--DR. D.,
THE DEVIL HIMSELF.
- THE DEVIL IS A DOCTOR?
- A DOCTOR OF DEATH, SWORN
TO THE HYPOCRITIC OATH--
TO TAKE LIFE WHENEVER POSSIBLE.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU LOOK JUST LIKE THE GUY
THAT USED TO OWN THIS HOUSE.
THAT CAPTAIN CRABIT GUY.
- OH, I LOOK LIKE MANY DIFFERENT
PEOPLE THROUGHOUT HISTORY.
ALL OF THEM ROTTEN.
- WELL, YOU DRESS
LIKE GENGHIS KHAN.
- ATTILA THE HUN.
WE'RE SACKING
ROME IN 451 A.D.
ACTUALLY, I JUST POPPED
IN FOR A COKE CLASSIC.
- WHO'S SHE?
- CHINCHILLIA.
A LITTLE ROMAN SLAVE GIRL
I RESCUED
TO KEEP ME WARM AT NIGHT.
SHE ONLY SPEAKS
LATIN, I'M AFRAID.
"E PLURIBUS UNUM," MY DEAR.
- WAIT A MINUTE, WAIT A
MINUTE, WAIT A MINUTE.
451 A.D.?
THAT'S 15 CENTURIES AGO.
- WELL, IF HISTORY'S
GONNA REPEAT ITSELF,
I HAVE TO KEEP EVIL GOING
IN THE PAST AS WELL AS THE
PRESENT AND FUTURE.
THIS IS THE WORST DEMON
POWER SHORTAGE WE'VE HAD
SINCE EVERYONE WENT HOLY
FOR THOSE BLASTED CRUSADES.
THAT'S WHY I WANT YOU.
- ME?
- YES. YOU.
IN ANOTHER 50 YEARS, YOU'LL
BE ASSISTING ALL THE BIGGIES
OF BADNESS--IVAN THE
TERRIBLE, JACK THE RIPPER,
BENITO MUSSOLINI, AND FIRST
DIBS ON DELECTABLE FRINGE
BENEFITS TOO, MY BOY.
NOW, O'BRIEN, IF YOU
NEED ME ON MONDAY,
I WILL BE AT THE
FRENCH REVOLUTION,
BEHEADING AMBASSADORS.
TUESDAY, CHAMPAGNE WITH
CAIN FOR KILLING ABEL.
WEDNESDAY NIGHT, POLO WITH THE
FOUR HORSEMEN OF THE APOCALYPSE.
THURSDAY, THE
1906 SAN FRANCISCO EARTHQUAKE.
WHAT A BLAST THAT WAS.
FRI--OH, FRIDAY, I SINK
ATLANTIS FOR THE WEEKEND.
I CAN'T WAIT FOR THAT.
- WHAT, WHAT, WHAT
HAPPENS TO HER?
- OH, I'LL PROBABLY KILL HER
IN THE TROJAN WAR
OR TURN HER INTO A HULA-HOOP
IN THE 1950s.
I HAVEN'T DECIDED WHICH YET.
- KILL HER?
- YOU'RE RIGHT,
I'LL KILL HER.
A HULA-HOOP IS TOO CRUEL.
EVEN FOR ME.
- NO, NO, I DIDN'T MEAN
"TO KILL HER." NO.
- DON'T BE SO
SQUEAMISH, MY BOY.
THERE ARE VICTIMS
ALL THROUGH HISTORY.
MY VICTIMS.
O'BRIEN'S VICTIMS.
AND SOON, YOUR VICTIMS.
- BODY COUNT IS THE BOTTOM
LINE IN OUR BUSINESS.
- THIS IS BEGINNING TO SOUND
LIKE A HORROR FILM HERE,
O'BRIEN.
- OH, I ALWAYS SAY,
"ART IMITATES DEATH."
BYE-BYE, HAPPY HUNK GOLDEN.
I'LL MEET YOU BACK HERE
MIDNIGHT AFTER LABOR DAY
TO CLOSE THE DEAL.
WE'LL BE EXPECTING
APPALLING, HORRIFYING,
HORRIBLE, GHASTLY
THINGS FROM YOU.
CIAO, BABY.
- I ASSIST IVAN
THE TERRIBLE?
- IT'S NO BIGGIE.
SO EVERY FEW CENTURIES YOU
RE-PERPETUATE EVIL
SOMEWHERE IN HISTORY.
- OH, A TIME-TRAVELLING SATANIC
SALESPERSON, LIKE YOU.
- RIGHT.
THEN WE CAN BE
TOGETHER FOREVER.
THINK OF IT.
DECEMBER 6, 1941.
WE HIT TOKYO TO SCARF SOME
SAKE AND SUSHI IN TIME TO
BOMB PEARL HARBOR
ON DECEMBER 7.
TALK ABOUT ROMANTIC.
- YEAH.
FINALLY MEET A
BEAUTIFUL WOMAN,
AND SHE WANTS ME TO
BOMB PEARL HARBOR.
"TALK ABOUT ROMANTIC."
- YOU MET THE DEVIL?
- EVERYTHING WAS GOING
LIKE A CHARM TOO.
JUST LIKE O'BRIEN
SAID IT WOULD.
- AND WHAT DID THE
DEVIL LOOK LIKE?
- HIS NAME IS DR. D.
HE WAS DRESSED LIKE
ATTILA THE HUN.
- ATTILA THE HUN?
- AND HIS CAPTIVE ROMAN
SLAVE GIRL WITH HIM,
NAMED CHINCHILLA
OR SOMETHING.
- WELL, SHE'LL NEVER BE
COLD WITH A NAME LIKE THAT.
- HE'S GONNA KILL HER DURING
THE TROJAN WAR OR TURN HER
INTO A HULA-HOOP
IN THE 1950s.
HE'LL DO IT TOO.
- I'M SURE HE WILL.
- GONNA TRAVEL
THROUGH TIME TOO.
- HUNK?
- YEAH.
- HAVE YOU BEEN
TAKING DRUGS?
- FOR WHAT?
I WAS FLYING HIGH ON MY OWN
TILL DR. D. SHOWED UP.
- MAYBE WE SHOULD HAVE OUR
NEXT SESSION AT YOUR HOUSE.
- OH, YOU MAKE HOUSE CALLS?
- NO.
NOT NORMALLY.
BUT I THINK MAYBE SOMETHING
AT THE SEA SPRAY SETTING
MIGHT REVEAL CLUES THAT I
JUST CAN'T DISCOVER HERE.
- STILL THINK I'M
JOKING, DON'T YOU?
- NO.
I THINK YOUR PANIC IS GENUINE.
JUST NOT SO SURE
ABOUT THE SOURCE.
- IF I COULD ONLY GET YOU AND
O'BRIEN IN THE SAME ROOM.
SHE'S EXHIBIT A-PLUS.
- HOW'S TUESDAY AT TEN?
- GOOD.
DOC!
I MEAN, SUNNY.
UH, COME IN.
I HAD A LATE NIGHT.
- SO IT SEEMS.
- AIR DEUTSCHLAND.
THE MESSERSCHMITT SISTERS.
URSULA...
UND UMLAUT.
ICH BIN EIN BERLINER!
THEY FOLLOWED ME HOME FROM THE
7-11 AND SANG BEATLES SONGS
AT THE DOOR TO ME IN
GERMAN TILL I LET THEM IN.
- IT'S ALL PART OF OBSERVING
YOU IN YOUR
SUPERNATURAL HABITAT.
- TOUCHE.
WELL, NOW,
WHERE WERE WE, DOC?
- LET'S GET YOU
OUT IN PUBLIC.
I WANNA SEE YOUR HUNK
MAGNETISM AT WORK.
- THE BEACH.
PERFECT.
HANG ON.
HELLO?
- BRADLEY.
IT'S CONSTAPOPOLIS CALLING.
AND HOW IS DOING OUR
LITTLE GENIUS, EH?
- IT'S MY BOSS.
BRADLEY'S BOSS,
CONSTANTINE CONSTAPOPOLIS.
HELLO, MR. CONSTAPOPOLIS,
HOW ARE DEMETRA,
DEMETRIUS AND CONSTANTINE, JR.?
- IS THIS BRADLEY BRINKMAN?
- OF COURSE.
- IT DON'T SOUND
LIKE YOU, BRADLEY.
- HE DOESN'T
BELIEVE I'M BRADLEY.
- THAT MAKES TWO OF US.
YEAH, I'M GONNA HAVE TO
TRY TO DO MY OLD VOICE.
ONE MINUTE, MR. C.
DOORBELL.
UH ...
HELLO, MR. CONSTAPOPOLIS.
YES, MR. CONSTAPOPOLIS?
YOU'RE RIGHT, MR. CONSTAPOPOLIS.
GOT IT.
[as Bradley]
THANKS FOR THE BAKLAVA.
EVERYTHING WAS FANTASTIC.
- THAT'S MY BRADLEY.
SO HAVE YOU WRITTEN
PROGRAM X YET?
NO, DON'T TELL ME.
DON'T TELL ME.
I'LL WAIT TILL YOU COME
BACK AFTER LABOR DAY, HUH?
HUH?
- PROGRAM X.
LABOR DAY.
UH, RIGHT.
EVERYTHING IS COMING
ALONG JUST FINE.
- OH, LISTEN, THE
DISTRIBUTORS NEED IT BY
NOVEMBER, SO YOU MUST
DELIVER IT AFTER LABOR DAY.
NO PRESSURE, OF COURSE.
- NO SWEAT.
NO PRESSURE AT ALL. RIGHT.
COMING UP RIGHT AFTER LABOR DAY.
- GOOD, GOOD. TELL ME, BRADLEY--
WHAT IS IT? HMM?
GIVE ME A HINT.
JUST A LITTLE HINT.
JUST A TINY, LITTLE HINT.
JUST A--NO, NO, DON'T TELL ME.
NO. JUST A LITTLE.
COME ON.
- AND RUIN THE SURPRISE?
- "AND RUIN THE SURPRISE."
YOU'RE A GENIUS.
A GENIUS, YOU HEAR ME?
BRADLEY, I KISS YOU. MWAH!
"AND RUIN THE SURPRISE."
- HI, GARRISON GAYLORD HERE.
THIS WEEK ON "FILTHY RICH,"
WE SCAMPER ALONG THE SLEEK,
CHIC, SUNNY SHORES OF THE
GREEK ISLAND OF IMPHAL,
A MILLIONAIRE'S PARADISE.
- CUT!
- WHAT?
- NUMBER ONE, GARRISON,
YOUR FLY IS OPEN.
- OH.
- AND TWO, LAST
WEEK WAS IPINO.
THIS WEEK WE'RE
IN SEA SPRAY,
HOME OF THE POLAR ICE
CAP YOU'RE DRINKING.
- ALL RIGHT, ALL
RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
- OKAY.
- I'VE GOT IT NOW.
- YOU'VE GOT IT NOW.
- YES.
- I'VE GOT IT.
- OKAY, LET'S TAKE TWO.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE I FORGOT ALL
ABOUT THAT NEW PROGRAM I WAS--
I MEAN, BRADLEY
WAS SUPPOSED TO WRITE.
- DO YOU SEE HOW
THIS OBSESSION
WITH AN IMAGINARY PERSONALITY
TORMENTS YOU?
LET IT GO.
- SUNNY, BRADLEY
IS NOT IMAGINARY.
- I'M READY.
- ROLL TAPE.
- "FILTHY RICH."
TAKE 12.
- AH. HI, GARRISON GAYLORD HERE.
THIS WEEK ON "FILTHY RICH,"
WE SCAMPER ALONG THE SLEEK,
CHIC, SUNNY SHORES
OF SEA SPRAY,
HOME OF THE POLAR ICE CAP I AM
DRINKING.
OH...
- OH, NO.
NOT AGAIN, GARRISON.
- IT WAS THE SAME BLINKING
THING I DID IN MONACO.
- NO, IN MONACO, YOU SET THE
DUCHESS OF DUNGLEMORE'S WIG
ON FIRE.
DO YOU REMEMBER?
- NYET.
- I DO.
THAT'S OUR BREAK, EVERYBODY.
CUT!
GET HIM INTO WARDROBE.
- ALL MY WARDROBE IS
BACK IN MY MOTEL ROOM,
SO THAT YOUR WARDROBE PERSON
WON'T STARCH MY COLLARS
INTO CARDBOARD.
- OH, NOW HE'S WALKING--
WHERE'S HE GOING?
- ALL RIGHT. THE NEXT SHOT
IS AT THE END OF THE PIER.
- WE HAVE NO PROOF THAT
ANY AFTERLIFE
OR AFTER-DEATH EXISTS.
- I'M PROOF, SUNNY.
- MORTALITY MEANS LIVING WHO YOU
ARE AND LOVING WHO YOU ARE
RIGHT NOW.
HOW ELSE CAN
ANYONE LOVE YOU?
- I'M SORRY.
- HEY, WASN'T THAT
GARRISON GAYLORD?
- I DON'T KNOW.
- HUH.
- ANYWAY, WHAT I WAS
GOING TO SAY--
- OH, MY BLEEDING
DRIVER'S NEVER HERE.
I'LL DO IT MYSELF.
OW!
OH!
- OH!
HERE COMES GARRISON. HE'S IN
REVERSE AND OUT OF CONTROL.
- IF HE KILLS
HIMSELF ON CAMERA,
THE RATINGS ARE
GOING TO SOAR.
- YOU WANT IT?
YOU SHOOT IT.
- WATCH OUT!
- THERE IS A DARK
POWER, SUNNY.
I'LL PROVE IT
TO YOU SOMEHOW.
- HEY, YOU TWO, WATCH OUT!
- WHOO-HA-HA!
OH, I GOT THE
WHOLE THING ON TAPE!
BABY!
- THAT WAS ONE OF THE MOST
ASTONISHING FEATS I HAVE
EVER SEEN.
- HEY, CONGRATULATIONS, GUY.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU'RE A HERO.
- A SUPERHERO.
YOU SAVED US ALL.
- NEED ANY MORE
PROOF, SUNNY?
- WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
- HUNK.
HUNK GOLDEN.
- OH, "THE INCREDIBLE HUNK."
I CAN'T BEAR IT.
YOU TWO MARRIED?
- UH, NO.
I'M HIS PSYCHOLOGIST, ACTUALLY.
- OH, EVEN BETTER.
- WHAT AN EXCLUSIVE.
- PUMPING THAT MUCH
ADRENALINE MAKES
ANY MAN A SUPERMAN.
- ADRENALINE
WON'T STOP A JEEP.
- YOU JUST SAVED MY LIFE.
LOOK FOR YOUR
ANSWERS IN THAT.
HUNK GOLDEN IS A HERO
FOR A VERY GOOD REASON.
LOOK, THE MESSAGE IS SIMPLE--
THE WORLD NEEDS YOU.
THE WORLD NEEDS TO BELIEVE
IN SOMEONE
WHO RISES ABOVE THE ORDINARY.
AND THAT SOMEONE IS YOU.
- I'D REALLY GO MAD
WITHOUT YOU, SUNNY.
I'D BETTER GO. U.C.L.A.
IS RUNNING SOME MORE TESTS.
- YEAH.
THANK YOU FOR SAVING MY LIFE.
SAME TIME TUESDAY?
- YEAH.
MAKE ME FEEL LIKE
YOUR ONLY CLIENT.
- I TRY TO MAKE THEM
ALL FEEL LIKE THAT.
- YOU SURE ABOUT THAT?
- NO.
WE CAN'T.
I CAN'T HELP YOU LIKE THIS.
YOU'RE A VERY
ATTRACTIVE MAN.
INSIDE.
NOT JUST OUTSIDE.
WE BETTER--
- WAIT AND SEE.
- YEAH.
- SEE YOU TUESDAY.
- THINK YOU HOOKED HIM?
- THE CHEAP STUNT
WAS THE CLINCHER.
- HE'S A BRIGHT BOY.
THE KIND I NEED TO
START WORLD WAR III.
THERE'S JUST ONE
TEENSY LITTLE PROBLEM.
- AND WHAT'S THAT?
- YOU'RE IN LOVE WITH
ANOTHER ONE, O'BRIEN.
- I AM NOT IN
LOVE WITH HUNK.
- PROMISES, PROMISES.
YOU ALWAYS COME ON
LIKE GANGBUSTERS,
THEN YOU FALL IN LOVE
WITH THE POOR SLOB,
AND THEN YOU END UP TALKING
HIM OUT OF WHAT YOU COST ME
A FORTUNE IN SPECIAL
EFFECTS TO WOO HIM INTO.
- CAN A SORCERESS HELP IT,
IF SHE GETS EMOTIONALLY
INVOLVED WITH HER WORK?
SOUL SEDUCTION IS DRAINING.
- OH.
WHATEVER HAPPENED
TO THE BAD OLD DAYS?
LIKE WHEN YOU HAD THAT IDEA
ABOUT THE BERMUDA TRIANGLE.
A BIODEGRADABLE DEATH ZONE.
WITH GREAT FISHING.
I WAS SO PROUD OF YOU.
- I HID AL CAPONE'S SECRET
VAULTS
FROM GERALDO RIVERA,
DIDN'T I?
- THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU DID.
POOR GERALDO.
I JUST LOVED THAT.
- BESIDES, HUNK IS
FALLING RIGHT INTO LINE.
- WELL, THAT'S TRUE.
HE'S RICH.
HE'S FAMOUS.
HE'S FALLING IN LOVE.
HE'LL NEVER WANT TO
CHANGE BACK AGAIN NOW.
NOW, THAT HE FELL IN
LOVE WITH YOU, DOCTOR.
- HUNK'S OURS.
I THINK.
- YOU THINK?
YOU THINK?
I WARNED YOU ABOUT
THESE TRIAL OFFERS.
YOUR DEAL EXPIRES THE
DAY AFTER LABOR DAY TOO,
YOU KNOW, O'BRIEN.
DON'T FORGET THAT.
ANOTHER FAILURE, AND I'LL
HAVE TO TURN YOU BACK INTO--
- NO.
NOT THAT.
LOOK, JUST GIVE ME ANOTHER YEAR.
ANOTHER SIX MONTHS.
- OH, LOOK AT YOU.
LOVE. YOU REEK OF IT.
- YOU OWE ME A
SOUL A CENTURY.
YOU ARE 0 FOR 99 YEARS.
NO SOUL, NO DEAL.
NO DEAL, NO O'BRIEN.
- OKAY.
LOOK, I MAKE HUNK FALL IN
LOVE WITH SUNNY--
- AND NOT VICE VERSA.
- NOT VICE VERSA.
AND SUNNY CONVINCES
HIM TO KEEP THE DEAL,
AND THEN WHAT
HAPPENS TO SUNNY?
- SUNNY?
WHY SUNNY?
SUNNY?
THE TUESDAY AFTER LABOR
DAY, SUNNY DISAPPEARS.
HE NEVER SEES HER AGAIN.
- OH, HUNK WILL
BE HEARTBROKEN.
- OH, IF YOU'RE NOT IN LOVE
WITH HIM, IT WON'T MATTER,
WILL IT?
- IF HE EVER FINDS OUT,
HE'S GONNA HATE ME FOREVER.
- WELL, THAT
CAN BE ARRANGED.
I'LL BE WATCHING
YOU, O'BRIEN.
HEIL HITLER.
I WISH I NEVER INVENTED
THAT CLICKING BUSINESS.
CIAO, SWEETHEART.
- GARRISON GAYLORD HERE.
TWO WEEKS AGO
ON "FILTHY RICH,"
WE SHOWED YOU A REAL
LIVE ACT OF SUPERHEROISM.
AS IT UNFOLDED RIGHT
BEFORE OUR CAMERAS.
IN THE TWO WEEKS SINCE,
HUNK GOLDEN,
THE SUPERMAN WHO
SAVED MY LIFE,
HAS BECOME THE STUFF
OF AMERICAN LEGEND.
A "FILTHY RICH" CAMERA CREW
AND I SHARED IT WITH HIM.
"HUNKMANIA" IS SWEEPING
SEA SPRAY
AND THE REST OF THE COUNTRY.
HUNK WANNABES CAMP AROUND
HIS HOME 24 HOURS,
DESPERATE FOR JUST A LOOK AT
THE HUNK HIMSELF.
HUNK'S SPORT COAT IS
THE BRAND-NEW LOOK,
THE FASHION LOOK
OF THE 1980s.
PROMOTIONAL OFFERS HAVE BEEN
FLOODING IN SINCE DAY ONE.
FROM DESIGNER
JEANS TO DOG FOOD,
FROM HEALTH CLUBS
TO HEMORRHOIDS,
HUNK'S NAME IS
INDEED GOLDEN.
THREE MILLION TO BE
THE NEW JAMES BOND.
FOUR MILLION TO LOSE
TO STALLONE IN ROCKY V.
PLAYBOY WANTS HIM.
PLAYGIRL WANTS HIM.
METEORIC FAME HAS
ALREADY FORCED HUNK INTO
SELF-IMPOSED SECLUSION.
CONSTANTLY AT HIS SIDE
THROUGHOUT THE DIZZYING SIEGE
IS LOS ANGELES PSYCHOLOGIST
SUSAN "SUNNY" GRAVES
WHO HE RESCUED.
ARE THEY IN
ROMANTIC CAHOOTS?
WILL SUCCESS
SPOIL HUNK GOLDEN?
CLOSE FRIENDS SAY
HE'S CHANGED ALREADY.
- U.P.I., SHMOO-P.I.,
I THINK I HEAR A.P. CALLING.
HUNK GOLDEN.
YEAH, YEAH, HUNK-BURGER
FRANCHISES. NO, I'M SORRY.
I'M SOLD OUT TILL 1992.
UGH.
HUNK GOLDEN.
YEAH.
YES, SENATOR.
NO, I'VE ALREADY BEEN ASKED
TO BE PUT ON
THE STATE FLAG OF HAWAII, BUT--
- HUNH! HUH!
- CAN YOU HANG A SECOND,
SENATOR?
HI. AGGRESSIVE LITTLE
THING, AREN'T YOU?
THERE YOU GO.
PEOPLE ARE ALWAYS
DROPPING IN.
NO, SENATOR, I COULDN'T
PICK A FAVORITE STATE.
OF COURSE, IF YOU'D LIKE TO
SPONSOR A BILL PUTTING ME ON
THE AMERICAN FLAG, I'D
HAVE NO OBJECTIONS.
GOD DAMN IT, SUNNY!
THESE PEOPLE ARE JUST
LIKE A BUNCH OF PIRANHA!
BITE, BITE, BITE.
- HUNK, COME ON. JUST--
- SUNNY,
I'VE HAD IT OKAY.
WATCH THIS.
WAITING FOR SOMETHING
MORE GOLDEN?
WELL, HERE IT IS--A
PERSON-TO-PERSON MESSAGE.
STAY THE HELL
AWAY FROM HERE!
TAKE THAT, FAT BOY.
- STOP IT, HUNK.
THAT'S NOT FUNNY. HUNK, STOP IT.
HUNK, DO YOU WANT TO BE ON THE
SIX O'CLOCK NEWS DOING THIS?
- SURE, I DO.
I LOVE THE PUBLICITY, HONEY.
- GIVE ME THIS.
GIVE IT TO ME.
- FINE.
JUST FINE.
- YOU CAN'T LET IT
GET TO YOU LIKE THIS.
- I'M STARTING TO FEEL
DIFFERENT INSIDE.
ALMOST LIKE A DEMON.
- DEMONS DON'T EXIST.
JUST PEOPLE AND PRESSURES.
- YOU KNOW YOU'VE MADE IT WHEN
YOUR GARBAGE IS FRONT PAGE NEWS.
EXTRA! HUNK TOSSES LEAN CUISINE,
CAPPUCCINO GROUNDS
AND A PINT OF PRALINE TOFUTTI.
READ ALL ABOUT IT!
- IT WON'T ALWAYS
BE LIKE THIS.
YOU WON'T ALWAYS LIVE
UNDER THE MEDIA MICROSCOPE.
YOU'LL COOL OFF, AND THEN
WE'LL HAVE--
AND THEN YOU'LL HAVE YOUR
PRIVACY AGAIN.
- YOU CAN SAY "WE."
WE'RE IN THIS TOGETHER.
- AND AFTER LABOR DAY TOMORROW,
WE'LL BE OUT OF IT TOGETHER.
YOU'LL FINALLY BE HUNK
GOLDEN IN YOUR OWN MIND.
- KINDA LIKE BEING IN IT
TOGETHER
WITH SOMEONE LIKE YOU.
- SO DO I.
BUT THERE ARE BETTER THINGS
TO BE IN TOGETHER THAN THIS,
YOU KNOW.
- THAT'S MORE LIKE IT.
- HUNK, WAKE UP, IT'S ME.
YOUR OLD BODY?
THE BODY YOU'RE ON
VACATION FROM, REMEMBER?
- WHERE THE HELL
HAVE YOU BEEN?
- EXACTLY.
HELL.
I ESCAPED WHILE THEY WERE
WATCHING
"THE POSSESSED" AND
"THE WRESTLERS."
- HANG ON JUST A MINUTE.
HEY, SUNNY.
SUNNY, WAKE UP.
BRADLEY'S HERE.
WAKE UP.
- HUNK, I DON'T
HAVE MUCH TIME.
- WHY WERE YOU IN HELL?
- WHERE ELSE ARE THEY GONNA
HOLD THIS BODY IN ESCROW
WHILE YOU DECIDE
WHO TO BOFF NEXT?
- THAT'S NOT FAIR.
- WHAT A SLEAZEBAG
YOU'VE BECOME.
HOSING DOWN INNOCENT FANS.
- HOW'D YOU KNOW THAT?
- HOW'D I KNOW THAT?
YOU'RE RUNNING AS A
MINI-SERIES ON DEMON TV.
KILLER RATINGS.
AND EVERYONE DOWN THERE'S
RIPPING OFF THEIR COATCOAT
SLEEVESSLEEVES.
- I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S
HAPPENING TO ME?
- THE HELL YOU DON'T.
EVIL HAS TAKEN
ROOT IN YOUR SOUL.
AND IT USED TO BE
SUCH A NICE SOUL.
LONELY, BUT NICE.
- IT'S THEM.
IT'S THEM!
I CAME TO WARN YOU.
DR. D. IS FOR REAL
AND SO IS HELL.
HUNK, I KNOW YOU
CAN FEEL IT ALREADY.
- HEY, SUNNY. SUNNY. YOU'RE
MISSING IT. WAKE UP. WAKE UP.
- FORGET ABOUT HER AND
THINK ABOUT OUR FUTURE.
IT IS SLIME TIME DOWN THERE.
EX-GAME SHOW HOSTS, USED-CAR
SALESMEN, TV SPOKESMODELS.
EVEN MRS. KREPPEL.
- NO.
- YES!
MRS. KREPPEL, THAT NINTH
GRADE BIOLOGY BITCH THAT
FLUNKED US.
TWICE.
- WHAT SHOULD I DO?
- THINK. THINK IF IT'S WORTH IT.
- WHAT ABOUT SUNNY?
I'M IN LOVE WITH HER, AND IT'S
WHAT WE'VE ALWAYS WANTED.
- DON'T YOU THINK
I CAN FEEL THAT?
BUT A LIFETIME WITH HER IS A
ONE-NIGHT STAND COMPARED TO
AN ETERNITY OF EVIL.
HUNK!
I KNOW YOU. I KNOW YOU'LL MAKE
THE RIGHT DECISION.
- BRADLEY!
SUNNY'S GOTTA SEE THIS.
SUNNY, SUNNY, WAKE UP.
- WHAT IS IT?
- BRADLEY WAS JUST HERE. THEY
CAME AND CARRIED HIM
BACK TO HELL. COME ON. COME ON.
SEE FOR YOURSELF.
- I WAS IN SUCH A DEEP SLEEP.
- I KNOW, I KNOW, I KNOW.
LOOK, SUNNY.
- YOU WOKE ME UP TO SHOW
ME THE BEDROOM DOOR.
- NO, NO, NO. JUST A MINUTE AGO,
THESE ARMS CAME
AND PUNCHED HOLES RIGHT THROUGH
THE DOOR AND PULLED BRADLEY
RIGHT BACK THROUGH THE WOOD.
- HONEY, HONEY, YOU WERE
JUST DREAMING, OKAY?
- NO.
THEN HOW DID I GET THIS
SPLINTER IN MY FINGER, HUH?
- I DON'T KNOW.
I-I-I DON'T KNOW, HOW?
- FROM THE HOLE IN THE DOOR.
- HUNK, THE ONLY IN THIS
ROOM IS IN YOUR HEAD.
LOOK, YOU'RE JUST UPSET,
BECAUSE YOUR WHOLE BRADLEY
FANTASY SHATTERS
TO BITS TOMORROW.
- SUNNY, DON'T BE
MAD AT ME, OKAY?
- HONEY, I'M NOT MAD AT YOU.
I JUST WANT US
TO GET PAST THIS.
I WANT IT TO BE THE TWO OF
US, NOT THE THREE OF US.
- LOOK, YOU KNOW THAT YOU'RE
THE BEST THING THAT
EVER HAPPENED TO ME, RIGHT?
- WHY DON'T WE SHOWER AND
GO HAVE SOME BREAKFAST, HUH?
- YEAH. YEAH.
I'LL JOIN YOU IN A SECOND.
- GOOD.
- GET IN.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I WAS SWIMMING KOSHER HOT DOGS
FROM MIAMI TO HAVANA FOR FIDEL
DURING THE CUBAN MISSILE CRISIS
WHEN BRINKMAN ESCAPED.
- SPIRITUAL
SEPARATION ANXIETY.
HIS GOOD HALF IS SO STRONG.
- YES, SO DON'T WIMP OUT.
GOOD MOVE SUGGESTING
BREAKFAST.
BUT LISTEN, DON'T LET HIM
SLEEP BEFORE MIDNIGHT.
- HE'S STILL TIPPED
IN OUR DIRECTION.
- YES, BUT ONE MORE SILLY,
SAPPY, SENTIMENTAL DREAM,
AND HE'LL BACK OUT
AT THE LAST SECOND.
- TALKING TO ME, HONEY?
- [as Sonny] I'M SINGING IN
THE SHOWER, DEAR!
NOW LISTEN, KEEP HIM
AWAKE, AND HE'S OURS.
- RIGHT.
- WELL, THAT DIDN'T
SOUND LIKE SINGING TO ME.
- THEN YOU
WEREN'T LISTENING.
I LOVE YOU.
- GREAT BREAKFAST.
- MM-HMM.
- SWEETHEART, I'M STILL A
LITTLE JANGLED
FROM BRADLEY LAST NIGHT.
MIND IF I TAKE A NAP.
- MM-MM. I THINK A NAP'S
A GOOD IDEA.
YOU WANT TO BE IN TIP-TOP
SHAPE WHEN THEY PRESENT YOU
WITH THE KEY TO SEA SPRAY
AT THE CLUB TONIGHT.
- RIGHT.
- SWEET DREAMS.
BYE, HUNK!
- HELLO?
HELLO?
- HI.
- WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR NAP?
- SABOTAGED.
AFTER YOU LEFT, EVERY
APPLIANCE IN THE HOUSE
TURNED ITSELF ON.
I COULDN'T TURN 'EM OFF.
I MEAN, DON'T YOU HEAR IT?
- HEAR WHAT?
- IT STOPPED.
- HUNK, ARE YOU
HAVING ANOTHER DREAM?
- NO, NO, NOW, SUNNY,
SUNNY, I--I--NEVER,
NEVER, NEVER WENT TO SLEEP.
TEN MINUTES AGO, THEY WERE ALL
RUNNING WITHOUT ELECTRICITY.
- HUNK, NOTHING RUNS
WITHOUT ELECTRICITY.
- YEAH.
- YOU STILL HAVEN'T WRITTEN
YOUR ACCEPTANCE SPEECH FOR
THE BANQUET TONIGHT, SO WHY
DON'T--
- SUNNY, SUNNY, FORGET ABOUT THE
BANQUET.
YOU'RE MEETING THE DEVIL
TONIGHT AT MIDNIGHT.
- SETTLE DOWN.
- MAYBE O'BRIEN TOO.
- ALL RIGHT.
SUPPOSE I DO MEET THE
DEVIL, WHO YOU GONNA CHOOSE?
ME OR BRADLEY?
- I LOVE YOU SO MUCH, SUNNY.
I STILL DON'T KNOW.
- LET'S GET A SHOT
OF US SHAKING HANDS.
- WHY NOT?
- WHAT TIME IS IT?
- IT'S TWO MINUTES LATER THAN
THE LAST TIME YOU ASKED ME.
IT'S 10:32.
- WE HAVE TO MEET DR. D.
AT MIDNIGHT.
I'M GONNA SLEEP TOMORROW,
NO MATTER WHO I AM.
- AND I'LL BE WITH YOU.
- NO MATTER WHO I AM?
- YOU'LL BE HUNK.
YOU'LL SEE.
- I SURE WISH O'BRIEN
COULD SEE ME
GETTING THE KEY TO THE CITY.
- I'M SURE SHE'S WATCHING.
- LOOK AT THAT [indistinct].
REMINDS ME OF THE COCKTAIL
LOUNGE ON THE LUSITANIA.
HAPPY MEMORIES.
BON APPETIT.
- ATTENTION, EVERYBODY.
IT'S AWARD TIME.
AS PRESIDENT OF THE SEA SPRAY
HOMEOWNERS ASSOCIATION,
IT IS MY HONOR
TO HONOR ONE OF OUR OWN.
A MAN I AM PROUD
TO CALL MY FRIEND.
WHEN HE FIRST APPEARED
HERE AT SEA SPRAY,
I REALIZED HE WAS
SOMEONE VERY SPECIAL.
AND NOW THE WORLD
KNOWS IT TOO.
- WHAT A PHONY.
- HUNK, WE'RE PRESENTING YOU
WITH THE KEY TO SEA SPRAY
TONIGHT, BUT YOU'LL NEVER HAVE
TO USE IT. WHY?
BECAUSE OUR HOMES AND HEARTS
ARE OPEN TO YOU FOREVER.
- A LITTLE BIT CORNY,
BUT THE CROWD'S WITH HIM.
WHAT DO THEY KNOW?
- HUNK GOLDEN, PLEASE STEP
FORWARD FOR THE PRESENTATION.
AND IF I MAY SAY SO, THIS KEY IS
NOTHING COMPARED TO THE LADY
WHO IS THE SUNNY SIDE IN HUNK'S
LIFE--DR. SUNNY GRAVES.
AND HERE TO PRESENT THE KEY IS
THE HONORARY MAYOR OF SEA SPRAY,
THE STAR OF AMERICA'S FAVORITE
LITE KNOCKWURST COMMERCIALS,
SKEET MECKLENBURG!
- THANK YOU.
HUNK, EVERYBODY HERE KNOWS
THAT I HATED YOU ON SIGHT,
AND WELL, I'VE GOT
TO HAND IT TO YOU,
YOU DID PUT ME IN MY PLACE.
THEY CALLED YOU A SUPERMAN
FOR DOING IT AND SOMEHOW IT
SEEMS LIKE A SUPERGUY
DESERVES MORE THAN A KEY,
DESERVES A CROWN.
- SKEET, WHAT HAVE YOU DONE!
WE HAD T-SHIRT RIGHTS.
HUNK!
- HELL OF A SUPERMAN.
- IF THAT SKEET
SCREWS UP MY PLANS,
I'LL BRING HIM BACK
AS A WHOOPEE CUSHION.
- HUNK?
- HUNK, WAKE UP.
HUNK, YOU'VE GOT TO WAKE UP.
- WILL SOMEBODY WAKE THAT SUCKER
UP? I NEED HIM.
- HUNK, PLEASE, WAKE UP.
COME ON.
YOU'VE GOTTA WAKE UP.
- BRILLIANT STROKE, HUNK.
MAKING OUR DEVILS BRIGADE
RAID ON SEA SPRAY LOOK LIKE
AN ENEMY SNEAK ATTACK.
- I PROMISED YOU WORLD
WAR III BY DINNER TIME.
- LOOK, ALL THOSE YUPPIE SNOBS
YOU HATED ARE DEAD MEAT NOW.
- DEAD MEAT NOW.
- DID YOU KILL THEM
ALL YOURSELF?
- SHUCKS, DR. D.
- OH, DON'T BE MODEST.
- MAYBE JUST A LITTLE BIT.
MAYBE JUST A LITTLE BIT.
- CALM DOWN. CALM DOWN.
GOOD BOY.
THERE'S JUST ONE
LITTLE FORMALITY.
BEFORE YOU CAN TRULY COMMIT
YOUR SOUL TO MY WICKED WORK,
YOU MUST GET RID OF
YOUR BETTER HALF.
WE'VE ALL THE
FIXINGS RIGHT HERE.
THAT SAPPY, SENTIMENTAL
SIDE OF YOUR SOUL
MUST BE DESTROYED.
YOU READY TO SAVE
YOURSELF, BRINKMAN?
- HUNK, DON'T DO THIS TO US!
ALL EVIL AND NO PLAY
MAKES HUNK A DULL DEMON!
- READY.
- YOU'RE GONNA MISS ME!
THE GOOD THINGS ARE
WHAT LIFE'S ALL ABOUT.
YOU CAN'T WANNA BE THE GUY
WHO STARTED WORLD WAR III.
- AIM.
- ALL THIS JUST TO GET LAID
MORE AND A GUEST HOST
ON THE CARSON SHOW?
PLEASE, GIVE AN INNOCENT
BETTER HALF A BREAK. HUH?
- MY FAVORITE WORD--FIRE.
- HUNK! PLEASE! NO! DON'T!
- FIRE, FIRE, FI--
- WAIT. OH HE'S ALL RIGHT.
WAIT.
- YOU'RE ALL STILL ALIVE.
- OF COURSE,
WE'RE STILL ALIVE.
EXCEPT FOR THE PEOPLE
THAT ATE THE ROAST BEEF.
- FOR A SECOND THERE, I WAS
KILLING ALL MY-- --YOUR
INVESTMENTS GOODBYE.
- WHAT HAPPENED?
- SKEET CROWNED YOU WITH
THE KEY TO SEA SPRAY.
- YOU ALL RIGHT?
- YEAH.
WHAT TIME IS IT?
- MY WATCH STOPPED.
- IT'S TEN MINUTES
TO MIDNIGHT.
- HUNK!
- HUNK, COME ON.
ENOUGH FOR ONE DAY.
- YOU AND I HAVE AN
APPOINTMENT WITH DR. D.
- HUNK, YOU CAN HAVE A
CONCUSSION. NOW, COME ON.
- COME ON.
BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE.
- NOW, WAIT A MINUTE. THE KEY,
THE PRESENTATION--
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- TO THE DEVIL!
- both: OUR INVESTMENTS.
- NO WAY I'M GONNA BE THE GUY
WHO STARTED WORLD WAR III.
- HOW CAN YOU HAVE STARTED A
WAR THAT HASN'T EVEN BEGUN?
- IN THE FUTURE, IT HAS, SUNNY.
IT STARTS RIGHT
HERE IN SEA SPRAY.
- WELL, IT'S
ALMOST MIDNIGHT.
WHO ARE YOU GONNA BE
ONE MINUTE FROM NOW?
- BRADLEY BRINKMAN.
- WHAT?
- SUNNY.
SUNNY, I KNOW IF YOU TRULY
LOVE ME--THE ME INSIDE--
IT'S NOT GONNA MATTER TO YOU
IF I COME BACK JUST IN
A DIFFERENT KIND OF BODY.
- I DO LOVE YOU.
I LOVE WHAT'S INSIDE.
BUT HUNK YOU HAVE TO
ACCEPT WHO YOU ARE.
- YOU KNOW, SOMETIMES YOU
SOUND JUST LIKE O'BRIEN.
THE ONLY LIMITATION IN OUR
RELATIONSHIP IS THAT YOU
CAN'T UNDERSTAND WHAT
I'VE BEEN THROUGH.
WHEN YOU MEET DR. D. A FEW
SECONDS FROM NOW,
YOU WILL, THOUGH. COME ON.
TOLD YOU HE'D
BE HERE, SUNNY.
- IS THIS SOME
KIND OF TRICK?
- WISH IT WERE.
COME ON.
- OH, THERE YOU ARE.
WHILE YOU WERE AWAY, I
WHIPPED UP A FEW LITTLE
GOODIES TO CELEBRATE
OUR CLOSING OUR DEAL.
- DR. D., AT YOUR
SERVICE, SUNNY.
- AND IMPECCABLE SERVICE IT
IS TOO.
SEE? CANNIBAL CANAPES,
ALL-WHITE MEAT MISSIONARY
(NO AGNOSTIC FILLERS),
FANTASTIC TITANIC
ICEBERG LETTUCE SALAD,
KILLER TOMATOES, AND
DEVILED EGGS A LA MOI.
- THERE'S NO DEAL, DR. D.
- WHAT?
- A LIFE OF SELFISH PLEASURE
AND AN ETERNAL AFTERLIFE
AS ONE OF YOUR HENCHMEN
IS A ROTTEN EXCHANGE.
I WANT SUNNY TO MEET
O'BRIEN RIGHT NOW.
- O'BRIEN WILL BE
AROUND, ALL RIGHT,
BUT LET'S NOT TALK
ABOUT O'BRIEN.
WHY LET A FEW
DREAMS SCARE YOU,
WHEN YOU CAN BE A LIVING
NIGHTMARE YOURSELF?
- I WANNA BE BRADLEY
BRINKMAN AGAIN.
WHY CAN'T O'BRIEN
BE HERE TO SEE THIS?
- OH, SHE'LL SEE
IT, ALL RIGHT.
SO BE IT.
EXIT, HUNK GOLDEN.
ENTER, BRADLEY BRINKMAN.
- THIS IS BRADLEY BRINKMAN.
THIS IS ME.
IT HAD TO BE
THIS WAY, SUNNY.
- I KNOW.
- THE GAME IS UP FOR HER
TOO, BRADLEY BRINKMAN.
COME OUT, COME OUT,
WHEREVER YOU ARE.
- WHAT?
- OH, THE DEVIL
MADE HER DO IT.
- AND I THOUGHT
THAT YOU LOVED ME.
- I DID.
I MEAN, I DO.
BRADLEY, YOU MADE
THE RIGHT DECISION.
ALL THE DREAMS WERE TRUE.
I HAD TO LIE TO GET
YOU TO CLOSE THE DEAL.
YOU BELIEVED IN
YOUR OLD SELF MORE.
- AND I BELIEVED IN YOU.
NOW WHAT?
- DISMISSAL.
- MY DEAL'S UP TOO.
- YOUR DEAL?
- FABULOUS DEAL TILL SHE
GOT SENTIMENTAL AND SLOPPY.
- I HAD TO LAND A SOUL A CENTURY
FOR DR. D. OR LOSE MY DEAL.
- SHE HASN'T MADE A SCORE SINCE
OTTO VON BISMARCK IN 1887.
- I'M TOO MUCH A ROMANTIC
TO KEEP RECRUITING NICE GUYS
FOR THE DEVIL'S WORK.
NICE GUYS LIKE YOU.
- THEN WHY DO YOU
KEEP DOING IT?
- I WAS AFRAID.
I AM AFRAID.
TO BE THE REAL ME.
THE ONE THAT SOLD THEIR SOUL TO
DR. D. IN THE FIRST PLACE.
- WAIT A MINUTE. YOU'RE SUNNY.
OR YOU WERE.
YOU'RE THE ONE WHO TAUGHT
ME THAT PEOPLE EXIST ON THE
INSIDE, NOT ON THE OUTSIDE.
EVEN IF IT WAS TO DECEIVE ME,
THE LOVE I FELT FROM YOU
CAME FROM SOME WONDERFUL PERSON.
I THINK--
- I'M REALLY TOUCHED.
I -- VERY TOUCHING.
BUT IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME, I HAVE
TO CATCH AN ILL WIND TO BEIRUT.
LOOK. SINCE IT'S
HITLER'S BIRTHDAY,
I'LL MAKE YOU ONE LAST
OFFER--SIX MONTHS' EXTENSION
TO MAKE GOOD ON BEING BAD.
- NO WAY.
- SIX MONTHS?
- NO, DON'T.
WHOEVER YOU ARE OR WERE.
DON'T BE AFRAID.
THERE IS A PERSON INSIDE OF
YOU WHO IS WARM AND LOVING.
I KNOW.
I'VE FELT IT.
- O'BRIEN.
REMEMBER HOW
LONELY YOU WERE?
- CAN'T BE LONELIER THAN
RUNNING A TIME-TRAVELLING
SELL-YOUR-SOUL-TO-SATAN
SERVICE.
- WELL--
- DON'T BE AFRAID TO BE THE
PERSON WHO YOU ARE INSIDE.
- STRONG ENOUGH TO COME BACK
TO EARTH
AS YOURSELF USED TO BE?
- I WAS.
- I'M STAYING WITH--
- UNLIMITED CREDIT ON
"INFERNOCARD?"
- I'M STAYING WITH BRADLEY.
- YES!
- OH, TO HEAVEN
WITH BOTH OF YOU.
THERE ARE PLENTY OF TAKERS
ACROSS THE CENTURIES TO
CARRY OUT MY MASTER PLAN
TO MAKE ALL THE HAPPY ENDINGS IN
HISTORY
EVIL ONES.
LIKE ALL THOSE
LASSIE MOVIES.
SO BE IT.
THERE SHE IS.
PRINCESS LUCILLA OF LENINSHIRE,
JUST AS I FOUND HER IN THE
TENTH CENTURY, AFTER HER FATHER
SOLD HER TO THE VIKINGS.
NINE CENTURIES OF VICIOUS,
VILE TRAINING DOWN
THE TUBES OF TIME.
- LUCILLA.
WHY DID YOUR
FATHER SELL YOU?
- BECAUSE I WASN'T AS BEAUTIFUL
AS MY SISTER, PRINCESS KASAVA,
SO I SOLD MY SOUL
TO DR. D.
TO ESCAPE AND BECOME
BEAUTIFUL ... LIKE YOU.
- YOU'RE A PRINCESS.
- A PRINCESS WITHOUT A
CASTLE, WITHOUT A JOB.
WELL, I'LL BE GOING.
- WHOSE SIDE ARE
YOU ON THIS TIME?
- WHAT DOES IT MATTER?
AS LONG AS MANKIND
IS MISERABLE.
CIAO.
- SO YOU'VE BEEN--
- RETURNED TO EARTH TO LIVE OUT
THE REST OF MY MORTAL LIFE.
LIKE YOU.
- LIKE ME.
WHO WOULD EVER BELIEVE THIS?
- YOU WOULD, BRADLEY.
OH, MY GOODNESS BRADLEY, WHAT
ABOUT YOUR PROGRAM?
IT'S DUE TODAY.
- IT CAME TO ME LAST NIGHT
WHEN I MET THE REAL YOU.
- WHAT IS IT?
- "THE PRINCESS PROGRAM"--
HOW TO LIVE ROYALLY ON A
REGULAR WEEK'S PAY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
- WHAT DO I THINK?
BRADLEY?
- HM?
- ARE YOU
DISAPPOINTED?
- DISAPPOINTED IN WHAT?
- THAT YOU GAVE
UP THE NEW YOU,
ENDED UP WITH THE OLD ME.
WHO'S ALWAYS SECOND BEST.
- YOU'RE SECOND BEST?
NEVER.
NOT 900 YEARS AGO,
NOT NOW, NOT EVER.
- FUNNY. HUNK DISAPPEARS, AND
BRADLEY BRINKMAN RETURNS.
THEY BOTH WERE ALWAYS LOOKING
FOR THE SAME WOMAN TOO.
- AND IT LOOKS LIKE BRINKMAN
FINALLY GOT HIMSELF A GIRL.
- WHAT'D YOU EXPECT?
HUNK MUST'VE
RUBBED OFF ON HIM.