I DON'T KNOW HOW SHE DOES IT (2011)
Six years ago
I know Kate Reddy.
The smartest kid I know.
and also has a heart of gold.
All working mothers
We feel that juggling ...
... With 50 plates at once, but Kate
you can give 10 more will, too.
If you have to deliver a
report for work, do it.
If you have to make a pair of fairy wings
for the school festival, he does.
Appears Late
a relative of the husband ...
... Can stand without mixing
Zanac vodka. That's incredible.
Do not know how she does
For all the mothers at some point
where you feel you do not succeed ...
Kate ... for the moment
was three months ago.
This whole problem started with
a bake sale.
Did he tell you what the
great bake sale?
My God, the sale of
preschool cakes.
Had just arrived from Boston,
but I got the reminder
Emily's school ...
... Of the bake sale.
I promised Emily
do something homemade ...
... And was determined to stay
up all night to do so.
But the market did not have
baking ingredients.
This cake would be made at home
though it were the last to do.
Why should I care?
First of all ...
... The other mothers are small
mini army of Martha Stuart.
Their contributions would look perfect
and their daughters would feel proud.
Em also wanted to feel that way.
I tried to avoid the
News in 20 years.
Emily  friends discover
that the source of his mental problems ...
... are due to school sale
pastries. Where his mother ...
... a shadowy presence in his life ...
humiliated her in front ...
their classmates.
I was not going to disappoint Emily.
Open up.
So, so.
They do not understand. I still remember the
looks that made me in 1974 ...
... When my mother sent me to
school bake sale ...
... With two cans of chopped peaches.
You did a cake.
- Hello.
- Welcome home.
Thank you.
I thought that perhaps the
powdered sugar would help.
- This has no remedy.
- Really?
Lie down.
We have cookies, we put
in the case and will be fine.
Are you kidding?
You know what I will do these
mothers with extreme diets ...
... If the command with cookies
high in fat?
That looks very good can I have some?
Yes.
You worry too much.
I just want Emily to feel
proud of what we take for sale.
I do not feel that is different
the other children because his mother ...
... Traveling for business.
I know that I tried.
Those are nice things.
- How was Phoenix?
- Good.
Airport taxi, meeting
hotel, meeting, taxi, airport.
You must be exhausted.
Well ...
A little.
But not quite.
I am not of those wives who do not
wants to have sex with her husband.
I still think it is the
most beautiful man on earth.
Their adorable wrinkles.
His blue eyes.
Smells like after a shower.
But there is only one problem.
A recent study reported that the
64% of women with young children ...
... Do not sleep at night.
The researchers did not
find the explanation.
They could have asked me.
At night, I like the women of
around the world''do''list.
Emily's birthday theme.
¿Pirates or pop star?
Things to buy: napkins,
toothpaste, chops ...
The birthday gift for Jedda.
Find out if Jeddah is the child.
Call type of music.
Emily together with children who do not bite.
Fueling the car. Wait ...
Does not that should be on the list of Richard?
Who am I kidding,
Richard does not have a list.
Plucking something, whatever.
Call the mother
Richard to say hello.
Or just send an email greeting.
Ben Wash teddy.
Taking birth control pills.
Make cupcakes.
Complete summary of the fiscal year.
Hamster
Begin the summary of the fiscal year.
Go to the gym.
When to do Kegel exercises?
Bagles!
When I come home after a
trip to Ben does not mind my absence.
Is too small to hold a grudge.
Hello.
I love you.
I love being the mother of a 2 years.
It's like being a movie star ...
... In a world without critics.
Unfortunately my daughter
forgives not that easy.
If I go long I reward
with a set of rejection and punishment.
''Rejection''
I want Dad to take me to school.
''Rejection "
I want him to take a bath.
''Punishment''
I do not like hugs.
A working mom
say no to bribe their children ...
... Can put it
lying on your resume.
Who wants to see
cartoons?
I have your happy ending here.
Pig.
Good morning.
We have to change the carpets.
Make an estimate of the expense.
That beautiful morning.
You have something different, you ...
Am I not eating sugar?
Your big meeting is today right?
I will work, definitely.
Make a good dinner because
celebrate tonight.
Does not matter what I face
large firms with deep pockets?
If you make incredible changes in the
basement, and have bathrooms and great beds.
Not to mention a shirt without vomiting.
It seems to be the worst time
to start my own business.
It is as if the economy would
begin to crumble.
Richard.
Ruin the business with money
we have under the mattress.
Things will change because
you're very talented for it not to happen.
I hope so.
The salary is not very high,
but will ultimately be good for both.
'I will give it.
- Give it to me?
- Give it to me!
-I have to go.
- Wait.
Are you expecting a second while I
take a shower super fast?
Where is Paula? Is late
all week, talk to her.
Richard, please do not talk to
it. But keep it happy leave.
Would that be the worst in the world?
Frankly at this point,
would be easier if I were you.
You know what I mean.
He came.
Good morning little ones.
Men and women view
child care in many different ways.
The sea was beautiful today.
Richard sees it as a waste of money,
a luxury we can not afford now.
and I see a person who knows
blanket which is what Ben likes.
Paula. 8 years in college.
Has not graduated yet.
It's good work, I love
children and Kate is a wonderful boss.
What Kate is engaged?
I have no idea.
Do you work in a bank?
Is cashier, no?
Mom will be late.
Do I put this in a container?
Did you ... a cake?
Yes.
¿I can say I work for
a very powerful investment firm?
and nothing scares me more than I
scold my daughter's teacher.
When we arrived late
for the''circle time''.
- Do you want a lot or little?
- Little.
- A lot.
Have a good day. I love you.
Goodbye.
Will they take back, Ms. Reddy?
Yes, sorry.
Tomorrow will arrive on time.
Maybe.
- Good morning.
- Bake a cake?
- Are you trying to make me look bad?
- It's the store in the corner.
What about the mask? Well done.
Throw away the envelope before ¿
that he saw the babysitter?
Well done.
This is my friend Alison,
and met.
Single mother and I can always
count on it, especially when ...
... Made it worse
mine for the bake sale.
That's instant gelatin.
Kate and I became
friends immediately.
A working mother
need solidarity.
and we know in which category
with respect to reliability.
Right in the middle of''criminal''
and''shoplifters.''
It's so sad, women were
fake orgasms and making cakes.
'Now pretend cakes.
- That's a big improvement.
Thank you. I was up all night.
Shit, there they are.
There they were.
The creatures in captivity
more frightening.
The Monsters
On the right, Wendy Best.
Bridesmaid, mother,
field trip chaperone,
Vice President of the PTA,
and also as head of terror ...
Working mothers ...
with her domestic skills.
and Janine Lopietro is a lady,
do yoga, pilates, crafmaga.
Better body than a sailor
and tougher too.
There they are, not for centuries
I saw them. Honey you look great.
I'm so jealous of you
that can work in heels
and look beautiful all day and
We walk in the park.
Kate does not know how you do it.
Wendy and I always talk about that.
- A cookie?
- Sure, thank you.
Delicious.
Alison please.
Goodbye.
- That comb.
- Did you see the clothes?
When I decided to have my children ...
... Wanted to be I who brought them up
But women make
different decisions in life.
No judge, at least I try.
Do not judge.
- We speak later.
Good-bye.
Hello.
Go home.
Do not go to the street.
Now of course I'll be late.
and have to run to the office
to arrive before my boss, Clark.
- Hello Clark.
- Good morning.
How are you?
Allow me. Ladies first.
Thank you.
You're a little late today.
I come from a meeting.
I have 2 options. The
excuses of men.
A terrible traffic, a traffic light
broken, a faulty carburetor.
O. ..
An appointment for a mammogram.
I think I'll take the stairs.
It's good exercise for the heart.
Good morning.
- Meeting.
- Yes, right away.
Is that cereal?
Butter muffin is dry.
What a relief.
Momo is a brilliant analyst.
It has the work ethic
a robot and warmth.
But I do not care because
dedicates this to work.
Kate Reddy ¿?
It's the best manager we have.
He's great at his job.
It works a lot.
People think that is rare.
She ... are seen as
their children all day.
Even during lunch
when I should be working.
- Now we go to the meeting?
- I think so.
No time
talk about your roots.
I learned that Clark
received information
of our proposal
funds in New York.
New York never gives us
chance of something big.
Office treat
Boston as a sad child.
You're always tired and badly combed
and once smelled a
urinate all day but ..
... Write the best reports.
I hesitate to write them.
If you choose one would be that of Bunce ...
Do not ask me, but
this type always appears.
Speak of the devil.
Kate.
This is Chris Bunce. Our DOA.
Idiot's designated office.
A Bunce loves me to have children.
This allows you to have a
competition advantage.
The men who get
when wearing ...
... Customers to drink
dinners and golf outings.
You know that I speak.
The nudists.
There you are.
Is everything all right this morning?
Because I was
looking for and did not find you.
I hope there is
nothing happened with the children.
-I had a ...
- No questions asked.
Clark told him you were amazing
Is not it?
Do not know how he does
with all these children.
I have two.
- It's so awesome.
-You have 4 children.
Yes, but 2 are twins.
Bunce.
How am I supposed to work
equality of the sexes?
They can give you good jobs,
maternity leave ...
... But until a man programes
realize that there is no toilet paper ...
... The project is a failure.
It bothers me when people say that
there is a double standard. Men ...
... Also have a lot to
worry about. For example shoes.
Are there women's shoes
to shine every day? No.
You never see a woman
shoes shined.
Women's shoes may be flat
and boring but those of men.
That's a double standard.
Bunce had a series of
meetings this week with ...
Investors ...
Oakland that visited us.
Yes, the meetings were marvels.
To learn something
culture during their stay.
I took them to a dance.
A dance performed.
Excellent work, Bunce.
Let's talk business. Jack Abelhammer
our new boss in New York ...
... Saw a proposal to this office
and would like to meet with the author.
It's an idea worth
worthwhile to present.
Bunce ...
... Know how you waited
this opportunity.
Still waiting.
Congratulations Kate,
go to New York tonight.
You have a meeting to
9:00 am with Abelhammer.
Really?
I guess someone finally
read one of your proposals.
Go!
Congratulations.
If things are this
will be a great opportunity.
Many trips, many
Abelhammer meetings.
It would be great.
In addition to the times your child to spend
that while both have
expected ... with your nanny.
and your wife will be
happy, congratulations.
She is married.
In your marriage is
to call your husband ...
... Whenever working late ...
... Or travel the country or can not
pick up children from school.
It is as if
on probation.
and so neither will I marry
or have children.
I once had a fish.
But he was looking at me with his eyes.
Saying''feed me.''
So I threw it down the toilet.
His name was Derek.
Derek Chen.
Leave work early
and go to a bar.
Let's pretend that we are
single and rest.
Either
things or perhaps both.
Confirming our meeting
morning at 9:00 am.
I look forward to meeting you. Jack Abelhammer.
I would love to but I can not, I have to go
New York and performing oral sex to another.
Dear Jack. We also look forward
know it. Kate is ready.
Richard this is a great opportunity.
He had to choose
over others.
The chances of
that happen are very slim.
But with the quality of your ideas
Of course, achieving this.
Good luck in your meeting
and do not worry about me.
It's a short trip, no one will notice
I turn to go. I promise.
No. You just returned.
Honey I know, but it is only a
night and the phone with me.
- Call me anytime.
- Whatever you say mom.
At least you do not hate me.
Do you take Ben to get a haircut?
Yes, I had bangs for the eyes as well
I took him to the corner barbershop.
It looks ...
It's lovely, thank you ...
It was his first cut so ...
I wanted to call but not
want to disturb the work.
No, it's ...
Never bothered me.
Nothing is more important
for me than boys.
I always like to hear any
big or small thing, really.
Got it.
Thank you.
I love you.
Good-bye mom.
Good-bye baby.
I love you. Paula call me for what
it is. Regardless of the reason.
Goodbye.
The manual says that children outgrow
separation anxiety at age 2.
- Good afternoon.
- That was weird.
But that does not work for mothers.
I missed the first
Ben haircut ...
Em had no ties
violets in your size but ...
Keep looking I promise ... right?
Okay, honey.
You want a brush?
I am a little anxious
Is that a crime?
Hello.
Today is the day of the games in the park.
Confirm it with Alan's nanny.
Can you wait?
Wait yes?
I think I have the number.
Wait.
Bear with it for a moment.
Sorry.
Would you mind?
Why is wet?
Yes.
I have it.
Are you there?
-Go ahead say it.
- What?
Drop it.
No, I ...
- Do not know how the hell do you do?
'You will, too. Someday.
No, no.
- Do not have children.
- Really?
Why not?
- To begin with ...
- You hold it for a moment?
Momo ...
I promise to be a mother
is one of the experiences
more enriching
a woman can have.
Maybe it's stress.
Sorry.
Thank you.
Take my bag.
Sorry, my children
love this music.
Alison I am about to enter
to a meeting do you call later?
Sure. But because I sent a
mail telling me that longed to see me?
What?
Last night when I invited you to the bar I found
your answer made no sense so ...
No, I sent an e-
differently about ...
Oh my god, wait!
Do not you send an email
talking about oral sex?
-At least yesterday.
- Oh my god!
Are we ready?
Jack Abelhammer.
Hon Momo is an honor to meet you, Mr.
- Are we?
- Yes.
Hear Jack ...
Jack, about e
I sent you yesterday ...
The activity that I mentioned ...
That's not ...
Ah yes, I saw.
Are you still planning to start the
meeting with that plan of action?
Sorry ...
... Has been cut by
budget lately ...
So ... no.
That disappointment.
Sorry, put this thing in silence.
almost.
Sorry.
''Emily was sent back
home because they have lice.
The whole family needs to be revised.''
Are you all right?
Yes.
Oh my God.
We received many proposals
but I was intrigued by the notion of
individual investors
with limited funds.
For that work must be
actions having a high dividend.
But you also have to
avoid value traps.
I put several companies where it really
I see a multiplication of the dividend.
I see.
Hardcourt hates retirement business
What can we do to convince them ...?
- Is that a bouncy house?
- What?
What you have written in the hand
not seen him since he was 10 years.
A house is jumping
like a tent inflatable
where children come and jump.
It is the birthday of my
daughter next week.
- How many children do you have?
- 6.
- 2!
- 2
'You 2.
- They feel like 6.
The proposal is very ambitious.
Hardcourt just want to see the business potential.
The only thing that matters is
increased profits.
I know it's ambitious but ...
If it works, runs great.
Think of a retirement fund
enables people to
contribute to social service
so they can retire really.
That would mean a lot to
people of this country
they dread the future.
I got involved because I saw investment
My father wasted
each check was paid.
I wish we had kept
money in a fund like this.
He would have left something to my mother.
Instead of having two jobs, 0 savings
and a very angry dog ??named Claude.
What is it? I think I
metiste something in your mouth.
I have lice.
- Do you ...?
- Lice.
Oh my God. I did not see
Time to get out of there.
I kept imagining tiny insects
out of my head
and entering your email.
Oh my god, I'm going to vomit.
Oh no.
Richard Wait.
- I'll be with you soon.
- Do not put the phone here.
- Hello Richard. What's up?
- I got it.
Enough for me basement renovation.
Oh my god!
It's the best news in the world.
Honey I'm very proud of you.
We come home to celebrate.
Come home soon. Goodbye.
Yes.
This could be a disaster.
Clear that many children grab lice.
But only dirty.
The moms who do not properly wash your hair
because they have no time.
and above have a
lavándoselos teenager.
Come on, many children grab lice
in schools, no big deal.
Yes, there were rumors that ...
... Kate had lice.
and the world of finance is known
you can not ignore the rumors.
So ... spray my office.
Then I threw everything in the
children who were in the kitchen.
and I will ride in a
elevator or in a taxi with Kate.
''Killers''Nits.
If you get this,
you have to accept is incredible.
How I can? Richard expected to work
especially now that he has a big project.
and I am very ...
... And I have enough trouble
make things work.
Never happen. Abelhammer
clearly thought I was crazy.
I sent an email about oral sex ...
... had a bouncy house painted in hand,
I scratched like a dog.
Hello.
Hey, Clark.
I'm in ...
I am at a breakfast.
Are you all ...?
All right.
Yes, I'll be there.
Goodbye.
Abelhammer talk to me.
The call is ready,
Mr. Abelhammer just wait.
Thank you.
For God's sake.
How did this happen?
God!
How long you been there?
Enough, but still, if there
something else you need ... to adjust.
No, no.
I think I'm too tight.
Thank you.
Thank you for coming here today.
Of course.
I liked the proposal.
It has some holes, but I think
we can fix it and maybe make money.
However. The date of
delivery will be adjusted.
Hardcourt is looking at other possibilities
to make a decision by the end of the year.
This is a massive undertaking.
Mean a lot
travel, work nights,
want to make sure
not be much for you.
Considering your 6 children and lice.
God!
- How do you know?
- I saw your message.
I can read upside down.
So ...
What do you think Kate?
Do you agree?
This may be the best
happened to my career.
But the worst moment to happen.
Children spend much
time with your nanny.
Love your work more than
anyone I know.
Travel a lot, many
Abelhammer meetings.
He knew exactly what to say.
Sure I can.
¿Hold the elevator?
Thank you.
Sorry, am I
daughter turns 6 years y. ..
... Feared that there was no tomorrow balloons.
Can you pull the
lobby button for me?
Did they get all?
Everyone knows the right way
make a birthday party.
Ernesto Llamas Playtime Events.
He takes care of everything.
Invitations, balloons, perfect,
and if you give $ 50 extra ...
... Sent to the family of your husband
to the wrong address ...
... in order to spend the day
whole driving around town ...
... And appear at the end of the party.
- Hi honey.
- Mom, Dad passed.
Hi Kate.
Hello.
Thanks for coming.
- A pleasure.
- Very nice.
Good to see you.
That's lovely, thank you.
Do you bring something to drink?
Oh no!
Or candy.
- Are soft drinks to children?
- No sodas have a lot of sugar.
Yes, and dried fruit
rots their teeth.
Last year, the nursing
school made a strike against the raisins.
What still had a piñata?
That's different is ...
... Cultural enrichment.
Here is water.
- Think we're ridiculous.
- Because we are a little bit.
Are you okay?
Today you are a little off.
I? I'm fine
Why?
Came the wild.
I'll open the door.
Richard, wait, we need to talk.
- Now?
- Dad arrived.
Okay, then.
What is it, Kate?
It's just ... one thing.
It's nothing serious
talk later.
- You sure?
- Yes, yes. Open the door.
I'm sorry but you New york
liked my idea of ??retirement fund.
and want to develop it more. It
which means you have to travel
many the next 2 months.
Is that cake is made
organic flour?
Yes.
You have to change a diaper.
I have to. We
to talk about that stuff later.
Yes. I can not wait.
Is it fun?
He really is amazing with Em right?
When my children were small I do not think
Lou has changed a single diaper.
The men did not make those
things in those days.
- That's because ...
- We were terrible parents.
Neither knew it was tofu.
But they were simpler times.
Everyone knew their place.
Lou earned money and
I changed diapers.
If we could not pay the
Lou was the fault of accounts.
If the children were crying was my fault.
But you ... if something
goes wrong is the fault of all.
Do not think that anyone will do well.
I think now is more complicated.
I do not think hard
is the right word.
You know, I was wondering?
If you stay at home
Ben and speak?
Almost 2 years have
says not a real word.
Does not that worry you?
and the worst is that she
is right. Ben does not speak.
Emily recited at that age
The first chapter
Tales of
Canterbury in Old English.
and the only thing Ben does is grunt.
Kate is right, we have
mention the fact that you ...
I know Richard is a
terrible time for both
to achieve two major
projects work together.
But we can make it work, I know.
and I will do my effort to
sure not to overlook anything.
You worked hard to have a
opportunity at work, and me too.
It's a big problem.
We can do this, just
have to juggle.
I know, but if ...
I promise I will do everything
work, do not worry.
- Okay, but only tell you ...
- I said do not worry!
These screaming.
What is it that you do?
Are you about to ruin
our lives and want
use sex to
pretend that nothing happens?
- Yes.
- I like it.
I love it.
Frankly uses sex
to compensate for failures
in your relationship is the most
low that it may fall.
But sometimes you have to do it.
I do all the time.
One cup of 100% success.
Richard was right
worry would be very challenging.
Thank god Momo had to
help with the workload.
Friendly, very supportive, friendly.
It was none of those things
but was killed at work.
My job was to spend 2 or 3
days a week with Jack.
It was impressive, it was insightful,
intelligently. It was many things
and none of them was a Chris Bunce.
I think we should include a
request of insurance funds.
Exactly.
Jack I mean ...
If you go back to thank me again ...
... Please do not.
No.
It would not do it.
Not someone who would appreciate
gave me a great opportunity.
Perhaps the greatest
opportunity of my career.
What kind of person would it be?
All right. Precisely.
But thanks.
- This is what you will.
- If you are good.
I go to the bathroom.
I regret not being there to give
a goodnight kiss but ...
See you tomorrow right?
I love you. A kiss on the face.
and a hug on the neck.
A hug in the neck.
and barrel to fire ...
and without speaking in dreams.
For the section of returns, I
Thinking about making a chart showing ...
Enough talk.
Do I get my martini?
Continue by removing the edge of the table.
Sorry.
I'm surprised you do not
is cutting the steak.
- Is the force of habit.
- All right.
Do you have children?
No.
If ...
... I was married. Once.
A very sweet girl. Very special.
and then ...
two years after we
married y. .. got sick
although he fought a lot ...
- I'm sorry.
- All right.
I am well.
When something's wrong
in life will change it ...
... And change the way you see everything.
Since then I try to keep
things as simple as I can.
I love my job.
It has its ups and downs but
least not breaks your heart.
What about you? Do you like what you do?
I love my job.
The marking does not know my gender, it only
care if I'm right or not.
and I like how fair is that.
Although sometimes I wish not to love
So my job because then ...
... Could be home with your children.
You are allowed to miss your children.
I have 2 beautiful children and love them.
But life changes,
That is unquestionable.
you can not share with friends,
or entertainment,
or see a movie when you want.
- Or go bowling.
- Play bowling?
Yes, my sister and I used to play bowling
forever but now both are mothers ...
Where's the time?
We play bowling?
Sorry.
I should not have told you so
about my children. It's unprofessional.
From now on do not think
Kate me as working mothers.
But like Bill.
Your trusted financial analyst.
But studies show that the
Women are better investors ...
... But if you forget
you're a woman.
Thank you.
Well ...
- Good evening, Jack.
- Good night, Bill.
Goodbye.
From that moment
life became more complicated.
The funny thing was that it seemed to me
striving to make things work.
I once read that the important
in juggling is not catching
but throw. so I kept throwing.
and throwing.
This is new. It has spots.
My God, I have something to wear!
- How 'Ben and vomiting?
- Do not want to eat.
Emily had never seen work so hard,
but it has always been there for Ben and Emily.
She really loves those kids.
I leave my children in the
school at 7:15 am.
Such as' I arrive here at 7:45?
More or less.
I'm like the ...
... 2:00 pm.
I know you want to go. Can not
give the newspaper right?
Of course not.
I know how to give
means to you. Kill you.
You keep saying that.
I am a man journalist.
So I quit. I need to go
somewhere where it can be a woman.
Suddenly it was as if our
lives were in fast.
I had to pay attention
all at the same time.
Beware!
The other basic rule of
Juggling is that what goes up
must come down.
Beware of dog poop, baby.
At the same time Jack and I had
delivery date soon.
So our post office and no
were daily but at all times.
But I promise you tried
maintain professional distance.
Dear Jack, here is the
final version of Power Point.
Do you have a desire?
We will add the finishing touches
late to bed.
You know I bow forward.
See you soon. Kate.
Why are you still awake?
-Working.
- We are well enough.
Go to bed.
I have much to do. The
bed is a waste of time.
I hope not forever.
Good night, Kate.
Kisses, Jack.
Good night. Besos.
Good night, Kate.
No.
If firms with''kisses''best
writes''please''penétrame.
- Hello.
- Hello Dad.
Remember that Paula has
to leave at 5. Can you ...?
I have the meeting at 4:00
pm and then I have dinner.
Yes, I forgot.
- Do you think maybe you can?
- Yes, no problem, I will.
-I love you, I have to go.
-I love you too, bye.
- Where the hell is Paula?
- I do not know.
I will bring to the school.
Goodbye Daddy.
Goodbye.
Look Emily ¿
your lunch?
This week we had
excellent meetings.
Business Quarter
the destination is good.
Okay, let's make money.
- Bunce want to eat steak?
- You know I do.
I would be honored if you would let me pay.
Tomorrow I'll be late.
I have an appointment with the doctor.
All right.
Because I'm pregnant.
What about you?
I know.
Some birth control failure.
Do not worry'll take care of
it. I will not have children. Do you remember?
Wait.
I know I look Momo
and see a disaster.
Always in a hurry, without plucking eyebrows,
walking out of control ...
I understand.
But it's not just that.
There is so much joy.
and if for some reason you want
go through the craziness of having a baby
I can help. I've been
doing for a while.
I could show you useful tips
you can manage the home and work.
To either side are ...
Oh my god! What time is it?
Shit!
Shit.
Richard I am. Sorry
much, much, much love.
I know you have a dinner.
I'm on track so you can go.
I'm on the stairs, about to enter
the revolving door, I'm into it.
A woman keeps the puzzle
family in his head.
The interior of a working woman is
as the control tower of an airport.
Richard, dear.
I came.
I'm home.
- Mami.
- Where is Daddy?
He had to go to dinner.
So who are you with?
Sorry, I did not know what to do.
Yes, I know but ...
I called and asked Wendy
If your nanny could come.
''Did you call Wendy I
everything perfect''Best?
And then let my kids
I know someone who does not?
Kate, you were not here,
I left with a babysitter.
Not known.
It was okay. Sometimes it
must be sufficient.
The children are well and that this
Once the old nanny was perfect.
Get a babysitter
support is on my list.
How the list again, seriously?
Doing Pilates, baking lasagna, perhaps
want to include conquering space.
That's not very nice of you.
I do many things such list.
Sorry, honey, go to sleep right?
Richard Wait, tomorrow I have
go to Cleveland. Just for one night.
Jack and I have to see about
investors and how much they want to see
before presenting the
Hardcourt final proposal.
Come on.
Go to sleep.
I'm still here.
In this work we have to travel.
We road warrior.
and if you are tied to something ...
... Then you are a
bird can not fly.
and no one goes to a store
and ask for a pet bird can not fly.
Thank you.
I think this will convince
Hardcourt to commit.
How big was the
where did this come from potatoes?
This is the kind of thing the
that a family would laugh.
Sorry.
- Did you like investors?
- I loved it.
Are we going to visit some of the
Attractions in Cleveland?
Repíteme what they were.
Want to know what the
joke business travel?
My mother always says,''must be
exciting to see all these cities.''
But mostly what we see are the
inside of hotels and airports.
Not tonight.
- Do you play bowling?
- Is that it?
They have everything you need, but
have to wait half an hour
by a line because it is
our championship night.
Unless you want to play
with some of the groups.
May be a little competitive.
Yes, very good!
You know small but throw!
Watch and learn.
They all go down.
Timbo!
You will die.
We do not defraud, New York.
Quite simply, you rock
and aim right in the middle.
Just throw and pray.
I have it.
Good luck New York.
Yes!
Now you are those who fall.
I understand what you mean.
Bowling is fun.
Health all.
Very cute.
If you win this for us. You
Sorry to be a banker.
Yes!
Thank you.
I can not believe you're a
classic bowler.
When I went to college
here my friends played bowling
and I enjoyed it.
But not so tonight.
What then?
Then I went to my hotel room,
I ate all the candy and fell asleep.
But then he appeared at your door
Kate and I said I can not live without you ...
- ... Run away with me.
- No.
- Not so.
- Really?
Did you tell Richard
Jack your output?
No, because we go out,
we went bowling.
This is absurd.
Jack and I are just friendly.
You're right.
I know you sexy men
not support flirting
with his sexy co-workers.
He's not that scary.
How does your email signature?
What?
With:''Jack'',''greetings''
''Yours'',''thinking of you.''
I do not know.
Is it with kisses''''?
It is with''kisses''right?
Stop examined not
I am one of your cases.
'I blush.
- Of course not.
Kate promise ...
will not do anything disgusting or immoral.
But tell me everything.
Finishing out the microwave.
Come on, be cool.
Wait.
How was your trip?
What?
You went to Cleveland.
It was good.
The good news is that the project
is in good shape. Jack is happy.
Jack is happy.
Jack likes to send messages.
Jack you went crazy.
I searched on Google. Sit down.
It's horrible.
You must be a nightmare
walking with that man.
Really? I had not noticed.
You had not set.
- Not if it was cute or not.
- No, of course not.
So ... is happy.
This means that we can go home
your parents for Thanksgiving.
and then we can make a fire
shaped Christmas tree.
and I was thinking maybe ...
... We could find a new nanny.
Yes. We could look for a new
babysitter and maybe going to the movies.
- Yes. It would be fun.
- Yes.
It will be a perfect trip and fun.
I like it.
Last night I woke up and realized
we group the tables
for dividends
are grouped by type.
- We may revise this tomorrow.
- I can send it by mail.
I will not be in the office until Monday.
Really? But you said
wanted to do many things.
It's Thanksgiving.
Okay, we're fine.
- You sure?
- Yes.
and want to spend time with my family.
- One more thing.
- Yes?
I have the baby.
What?
I decided to be superior only because
I only want the best for me.
My God, momo, forget this!
I feel uncomfortable.
I am very happy for you.
I'm still uncomfortable.
There is no way that someone
can explain it is to have a baby
and once you have it
you wonder why anyone
never told you how she felt.
Please just hold me.
Happy Thanksgiving.
Same to you.
Being pregnant does not feel great.
It feels like a mistake.
But many women
have babies by mistake.
Maybe my baby will be like Justin Bieber.
He was wrong at first.
Now a billionaire.
- Good night.
- Good evening, Kate.
There you are. I heard that
you will take 5 days off.
But you know I'll be in the city.
We'll dinner to 20 people.
3 we roast turkeys.
If you need to cover you'll be here.
¿3 bucks? That is incredible.
Why not give my number to Abelhammer
if you need anything?
Happy Thanksgiving.
This is what they have
Bunce to know about.
It's those guys what they like
appear at the end and take credit
After another person
has done the hard work.
If I slip him a little
this super ready to pounce.
By the way, I
a spectacular turkey.
It's delicious.
Everyone says that my
breasts are very juicy.
My God.
You look like a mule of the
climbing the Sierra Madre.
I have diapers. The chair
laptop, a portable crib.
Pacifiers, pots
grain of children.
You do not have to pack. All
buy the things they know doubles.
Leave a lump in the
cottage and ready.
Children travel more
lighter than us.
Ready for fun?
I like the spirit.
Do not tell your mother about my new
project and I have to deliver soon.
What do you do, lie?
Let's see ... other.
She will not stay inside.
1, 2, 3.
Do not worry about that.
That is our right?
Oh no.
Who knows the lyrics?
Daddy sings.
Come on.
I love this part.
Sing, Kate.
Emily, come on.
Yes, Kate sings.
What do we do?
-Here we go.
- 1, 2 ...
Look at this, we travel.
All together in one place.
Right?
You're right, this is great.
- It's nice.
- Seriously.
These vibrating.
You can answer, okay.
I a. ..
Put it in silence y. ..
already silent. and not worry.
No. ..
Will not work, see?
I do not need.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
- You take the calls.
- I do not need.
All right.
That was a mistake.
Who wants some of me?
Here we go.
Naked.
That smells delicious.
Thank you.
Thanks for doing this.
It smells delicious, Kate.
A lot of dolls
snow stand ...
Frete to stand on
a barber shop and you say ...
Smells like carrots.
It's the same joke last year.
You ruined my joke.
30 years ago
accounts the same joke.
I do not understand.
For their noses, because they are carrots.
The road must be covered with snow
so if anyone wants to go skiing.
I promised Emily that morning
would make a snowman right?
Yes.
We can do it later.
This is delicious mom
What did you do this year?
I ran out of pumpkins
canned and I had to ...
- Did you use light cream?
- Yes, but the fat is better.
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
Yes, it's here.
- Kate is for you, someone named Nono.
- Momo.
Answer in the other room.
What do you mean, momo?
- Are you okay?
- What is your problem?
You leave an amount of messages,
Jack tries to locate you.
'll Check my phone.
Do you remember Barry
Bradwood? He was arrested.
- He is in prison.
- Really?
Bradwood Barry ¿? What did?
He got into something with a some
with a drug trafficker.
I heard even killed someone.
- Who killed him?
- I do not know.
Hello Jack, I regret not having answered your
flames, my cell reception is ...
What?
Sorry, Kate, Hardcourt changed
the time of the presentation.
You can only see us tomorrow.
Damn does that when it happened?
If you can not come perhaps Bunce can go.
Hardcourt has to go
Hong Kong after tomorrow.
Which means that tomorrow
tomorrow is our only chance
to present this thing.
But Jack Bunce said he would.
Let it go.
Come on, Richard.
I can not let stay Bunce
with this you know how much I have tried.
I can not control or as
or where he was introduced.
It's not my fault. Plan to all
so that the same is not happening.
But we would make a snowman.
Honey I know.
The next time there is snow
we will make a doll
it snows, I promise.
as you promised.
Goodbye, Ben.
Goodbye mom.
Oh my god!
He spoke.
Oh Ben!
Mom said goodbye.
Goodbye mom.
That can be useful.
- Richard ...
-You have to go, Kate.
Discuss this when you come back right?
Goodbye.
All we heard the
Thanksgiving night.
Leave after dinner.
Really? Who does that?
I'd rather be with my family.
Clean as my husband
and his friends watch football.
Chasing after children
because they ate a lot of cake.
Then make 11 appetizers
leftovers for the next day.
While my mother complains
my filling was too dry.
First time I hear
someone complain about my fill.
Just ...
It's family.
and love it.
I love it.
I feel much better,
continue with the proposal.
Maybe we can start with an overview of the
dividends compared with no dividends.
Care.
Or you can throw a few more times.
- Momo okay?
- Yes.
This does not feel like a miracle.
The morning sickness only last as ...
9 months.
I have experience.
- Are you okay?
- Do not I look good?
Let's walk.
Momo.
Oh my God.
It's official, I'm disgusting.
How did this happen?
Do not answer.
Thank you.
- Good morning.
Thank you for your sweet note
and beautiful room.
You know what?
I killed working to achieve this.
You deserve a nice room or if
we have a chance to Hardcourt
will be by the way ...
are ready to
Mr. Abelhammer you.
Come on.
Remember. We are a great team, Bill.
We are here today to
discuss possibilities.
The possibility of having
a new financial product.
That can restore some faith
our customers have lost.
We want to show that we understand
we want them to have money
we.
So I would like to start
with some tables showing
Dividend strategy design.
Momo.
The presentation went very well.
No one would realize that Momo and I ...
Were awake ...
all night rehearsing.
Until ...
It's a boy!
Last year I made 300 presentation
and never began to miss any.
Not my fault, the
pregnancy affected my brain.
I do not get the baby
is far from the brain.
What else can you do to your brain?
Sorry, I was so nervous
I forgot all part of ...
Are you kidding? That was a home run.
I did not say a word, he loved it.
Really?
You did everything perfect.
God, I love ...
... The way in which
did everything. It was brilliant.
Here let me close it is.
Are you okay?
I hope Kate does not have ruined it.
No, okay, do not worry.
Just as I thought the future is great.
Imagine what we will do in Boston.
It will take me to lunch
have many questions.
Seem to be indicated, which
mean you can not be serious.
Should I ...?
Does it return to Boston?
Yeah, I think. I call
if I find something right?
Do you know that was the first thing he said?
Where did I get this idea?
I hope you say that you took.
We developed it together.
A lot has changed since the
version with which I began.
It is not correct.
You should be at lunch.
- Hardcourt should know you.
- I know.
I already know. I was the
who made the presentation.
But now Jack will be the luncheon
Hardcourt and make sure that for dessert
this idea is all of Jack.
These guys are not giving rise to the top
credit to the team with which they work.
What am I doing?
You have to come with me.
You are where I got this idea.
It's yours.
We are a team.
and equipment are kept together.
Right, momo?
It is the turn 18. Or the 28? I do not remember.
- On 18.
- Is 18?
There was much tension. In fact I think all
at the bowling alley were silent.
and this gentleman.
This elegant, from where you are.
He gets up and says''you
are going down.''
-So.
-Just like that.
I think I yelled. Finally
I found my inner voice.
I think you said it all with an accent.
- It was a pleasure meeting you.
- Likewise.
Jack will tell you that I like
say no when I have questions
but you did a good
demonstration and I'm intrigued.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Right if you like thanks.
I'll be in touch.
That was miraculous,
never says anything positive.
Do you think I will buy it?
Yeah, I think we
a great opportunity.
Oh my god, I can not
believe that it has done so well!
Do you think you get to
time for the plane?
I do not know, I have to see what time it is.
Look at that. Finally
the battery went out.
Yes, I loaded.
Use the mine.
A lot of missed calls.
All for you.
Richard, love will arrive
as soon as possible.
Monitor them closely.
If you experience dizziness or nausea
bring it immediately.
Thank you very much.
Emily.
Ben.
- Hi, Mom.
- Hi honey.
What happened?
She stumbled and fell down the stairs.
A man says he will leave
the office to be with her son
and all look like the
paternal example to follow.
One woman says she will leave the
office to be with her sick child
and is called as disorganized
irresponsible and has no commitment.
- I know you're on the list right?
- No, forget the list.
You live here do not you have stumbled
that thing plenty of times?
At least he was here when it happened.
And I tried to call but not
answered the phone in hours.
I told you I forgot
charging the phone.
So I had to enter your computer
and get the phone to your boyfriend.
That was a great feeling.
'Oh please.
-And he did not answer.
You also forgot to charge your batteries?
Jack does not look like I know.
We were at the meeting
with Hardcourt, you know.
We were sitting naked in
a beach in Aruba drinking corn tais.
That is a denial strangely vivid.
You're right, I failed.
Ben was not here when I needed it.
What is the difference?
Even when these
here, not here.
We never sat down.
Never relax, we do not laugh.
I do not even speak of
done when we have sex.
Honestly ...
I do not know what you want from me.
I some times do not
is in a panic.
To talk about something
rather than logistics.
To pretend to laugh at my
old jokes you've heard.
Where we have 5 minutes
a silent conversation.
Only 5 min. to be together.
That's it.
My list.
1: get my life back.
2: Stop making lists.
Where is Dad?
He had to go to work early.
Em ...
You know I do not want to go
during Thanksgiving and no ...
You missed it. As you
Jamaica lost day.
and Liby birthday party.
Because you had to talk on the phone
and take a plane to New York.
I tell everyone ...
maybe one day we
a snowman together.
Or maybe not.
No, we will, I promise.
Yes?
The next time it snows.
I love you.
At work when you
behave like a man,
say you're rough and tough.
and when you behave like a woman,
say you are emotional and difficult.
So difficult is the adjective used
for everything that does not like men.
Know that I heard
be a merger of accounts in Atlanta.
If so I heard.
I need you tonight
someone to go that far.
Yes.
Hello.
What are you where?
What a pleasant surprise.
What are you doing here?
It's not just you who you are
always have to go to New York.
I like to do something
respect, especially now.
Why now?
The fund will need a name.
Wait ...
Did we?
Hardcourt only fund a project
pilot. But rarely does this ...
We did it.
Kate, I mean ...
Also came to tell you ...
You and I are a team. One very good.
Lately I've been thinking.
Kate ...
I do not usually do these things.
I check my mail every 10 seconds
to see if I got something of yours.
I want to tell all
funny things I heard in the day.
I know that given your circumstances
it's crazy but I have to tell you
if any part of
you who feel the same.
I told you my story
keep things simple.
Thou hast yet complicated.
and I for the first time in a long
time I feel ready to ...
I ...
Jack I am delighted
you feel that way ...
and now find someone.
That means so much to
you and Richard for me.
I ruined a lot of things at home and
I still hope to have a home with him.
Because that's where I belong.
It's snowing.
Yes.
God! I have to go.
Sorry.
I'll call you then there
something I have to do.
Thank you.
I need to talk to him.
It is in a meeting.
Clark came to tell you not to
I can go to Atlanta until Monday.
So ... be careful.
No. You will go this weekend.
Customers are waiting.
Can we discuss this in private?
We can talk about on Monday when you return
your trip to Atlanta this weekend.
All right.
So ...
Yeah, look ...
the problem is ...
... I ...
... I'm not available.
Why?
Because ...
... I have to make a snowman.
It is good but more work in the firm.
First, because I have two lives and I have
time to enjoy either.
It's snowing, mother comes to
home earlier today right?
No, honey, she has to
work. We will see later.
No, it will come.
Taxi.
Second, when you want to be
a man, a woman is wasted.
He said the next time it snowed
would make a snowman together.
Come, as promised. Twice.
Third, because my children will grow
in a blink of an eye
and I would be lost.
Honey your mom misses you
much, but has to work.
Really, are you sure?
Do you want to go play?
Fourth, because somehow, one day
Things have to change.
Richard I ...
I know things have
to be different.
I know that if you do not have this
improve things work
In so many ways.
But ...
But I have no job if I am not myself.
and I without you, without Ben and without Emily ...
It's nothing.
So ...
Today I went to see Clark.
I've given all I have to
this job and love it, really.
But I can not keep leaving
my family at all times.
I will not.
If I have to give you not enough ...
... Then despídeme.
But do not give up.
I will not.
I can not give up.
Then go.
You can go on Monday.
Now get out.
Prior to reconsider.
Really?
Salt
Thank you.
Bunce, take off that smile
Smarty will face.
If you make a foundation
Jack Abelhammer
talk to soften
your schedule as well.
So from now if someone
Clark will be disappointed, or Jack or Bunce
If I settle with my bosses,
then seek a new job.
There is always some
new deal to do.
But there will be only one
first haircut.
All right.
-Also, from now on ...
- Yes.
Cakes and I will show you with pride.
So, I bought the cake, yes.
What's wrong?
Richard I know you get mad but ...
I love you.
In an incredible amount.
and I very much regret what happened.
Are you done?
Yes.
Because even I have something to say.
Something to read.
A list.
Yes.
Change the carpet of the stairs.
I already did.
You have to buy a leopard
The Emily's ballet recital.
Speech therapy
Ben starts on Thursday.
Everything is ready.
I noted also
pillow nightmares.
You may never use but I scored.
me and Kate.
Yes.
Is the number one.
Richard.
It will remain a disaster.
That's all I'm still safe.
But it is our right?
- Where are they?
- I do not know.
Encontrémoslos.
Hello.
Let's make a snowman sand.
In these circumstances, a final
everything is impossible to fix.
Kate has a new fund and all
We are very happy for her.
I think of all are
is the least happy.
But I'm still very happy for her.
Momo is so beautiful.
Also ...
... It is difficult to calculate.
As they gave me was like ...
Why not tell me anything about this?
You are selfish by not sharing.
It's not funny.
If we expand globally,
rates can have up to 2%.
That would make sense but
you had smeared all over her face.
Here?
Thank you.
Are not 100%
me want to go to Aruba?
Yes.
But my friend Alison
love Aruba.
It's smart, she's beautiful.
Is available.
I love it.
How will the meeting with Victor Chao?
Will be in New York on Saturday.
He said he can see us in the morning.
I can not, I have another appointment on Saturday.
1, 2, 3.
Mami I can take it ¿?
Hit the ball.
Back in Berlin on Tuesday
and go straight to san francisco.
I will go to New York next week.
-Tremendous schedule.
- It is.
I do not remember at what Kate is engaged now?
Is it complicated
has to do with money, right?
No, it's actually very simple.
It is a juggler.
2 months later.
It has an electronic card.
Jack and Alison Greetings from Aruba.
Dear Kate, is a
wonderful girl, thank you.
Thank you, thank you.
It may be Irish or esconces.
But whatever there
beneath the kilt.
I assure you they do not tell Abelhammer
Abel''hammer''for nothing.