ABBIE: He described
the appearance of the man
that I saw in perfect detail.
He described
a man with no head.
You think we're both crazy?
Possibly.
What about Brooks?
What about him?
BROOKS: I told you to
stay away from him.
I tried,
but you didn't listen.
ABBIE:
That is not what happened.
Morales, right?
Yes, sir.
You used to date
Lieutenant Mills?
Abbie.
ABBIE:
I think I found something.
JENNY:
The square and compass.
You're a Mason?
These... these men
are my brothers.
My life is tied to the
Horseman's, and his to mine.
If I die... he dies.
I know a man who can help.
Someone who can separate you
from the Horseman.
(softly):
I feel him no more.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
(bell tolling)
(bell continues tolling)
(bell stops tolling)
The Regulars are coming.
Tell the others.
The Regulars are on the way.
The Regulars are here.
Tell the others.
The Regulars are coming.
(galloping hoofbeats)
♪
Paul!
(distorted, echoing):
They're here!
My God.
Where did you procure such
massive quantities of reserves?
Is there a nearby citadel?
A supermarket... (groans)
called Buy Plus.
Buy in bulk, spend less.
I will take you there someday.
Do you know what we
could have done
with these supplies
during the war?
We'd have taken Lexington
in a day.
Right now we have to make sure
that if the Horseman
attacks Sleepy Hollow,
you could hunker down here.
Now that your blood tie
with him his severed,
you're vulnerable.
"Pine Springs."
Is that a variation
of water?
A brand.
Cheapest one.
You paid?
For water?
(laughs)
Why not drink from one of the
thousands of taps around town?
Or the lake?
Well, tap water's
got chemicals in it.
And the lake,
you don't even want to know.
The extent of which
your generation
has defiled this earth
is truly mind-boggling.
(ringtone playing)
The Horseman
will ride after dark.
After we finish the kits,
why don't you meet
with the Masons
while I grab Corbin's shotgun
from the precinct.
Rutledge says
they've discovered information
of how best to exploit
the Horseman's weaknesses.
Are you certain you can forgo
such a conversation?
They won't let me.
The "no girls allowed" rule
really gets under my skin.
Mills!
Where were you today?
I'm on the late shift.
I'm kind of in the middle
of something right now.
What?
Prepping.
Prepping what?
For my sister, Jenny--
she's getting out
of the institution tomorrow,
moving in with me.
Wow, that's a big change.
Abs. Hey, two minutes.
Come on, I just wanted
to talk to you
without having the Brit
hovering over my shoulder.
Look, Abbie, I know things
have been weird between us
since we broke up.
I really do not
have time for this.
But I see you every day.
I don't know if it's Corbin
or Jenny or all of it,
but I care about you, Abbie.
Abbie...
Luke.
I am here.
LUKE: Before we dated, we
used to be friends, remember?
Can we at least
get back to that?
How about coffee?
Tomorrow afternoon.
Oh, slow down. I didn't think
we were gonna be
moving this fast.
Temper expectations, please.
MAN:
Morales.
Who is that?
♪
Brooks.
I-I... thought
you were dead.
Ah.
Rumors of my demise
have been...
pretty much true.
What are you?
I saw you
with Abbie Mills.
Stay away from her.
What?
Stay away from Abbie Mills.
I'm the only one that
can protect her.
You're protecting her?
From what?
The end. I can protect
her from the end.
Everyone will die...
except for the chosen few.
(distorted): There's a war going
on, Morales, a war you won't see
or hear until
it's upon you,
and by then it will be too late.
There are others like me
in Sleepy Hollow,
watching... watching...
waiting... waiting.
(panting)
The time's coming soon
for you to pick a side.
I trust you'll make
the right decision.
(faint radio transmission)
(siren wailing in distance)
♪
(alarm system chirps)
MAN (recorded): Dear Miss Mills,
I trust this aero missive,
finds you well if it finds you at all.
I'm still trying to fathom
the notion that my words
are somehow recorded
on your "smart phone."
After consideration,
I agree it is
wholly unjust that you
are prohibited from
attending the Masons assembly.
I will rectify this
the moment I arrive.
Please join us
as we strategize
our plan of attack
against the Horseman's
imminent arrival.
I am, most respectfully,
Ichabod Crane.
Hello?
(thumping)
♪
Shh.
I'll cover you.
(horse whinnies)
(horse neighing)
Come on.
(indistinct radio chatter
in distance)
ABBIE:
Right there.
Okay, that's enough for now.
This goes without saying,
but in your description
of events,
let's make sure
the perp isn't headless.
Crane, you said
you knew these men.
Who are they?
A local chapter of the Freemasons.
A centuries-old organization
of craftsmen with knowledge...
I know who the Freemasons are.
Why did they get
their heads chopped off?
For 500 years...
the Masons have been involved
in a secret war
between good and evil.
They're brave soldiers.
These were good men.
Where are all the heads?
He took them, sir.
I am running out of rope
with which to hang myself.
For now, our working theory
is cult ritual suicide,
understand?
I'm helping you.
I'm trying to give you
what you need
to take this bastard down,
but this just keeps getting
bigger and bigger,
and I still do not have proof
that the Horseman really exists.
ABBIE:
Four beheaded Masons
isn't proof?
Of four Masons
without a head, yes,
Of a headless horseman, no.
I have to notify the families.
We'll talk about this
back at the precinct.
Crane?
Find anything?
Not yet. The Masons said they had
information on the Horseman,
so it must be here somewhere.
Crane, I'm sorry.
It's war.
It's not the first time
I've lost friends in battle
and it certainly
won't be the last.
It must be here.
Horseman of Death...
(shouts)
You okay?
In 1781,
when the Horseman slashed open
my chest,
I knew I was a dead man.
But before I collapsed,
I had one last thought...
...if I die,
he's coming with me.
That dying wish became prophecy
when our bloodlines merged
on the battlefield,
entwining our mortality
and our fate.
Until the Sin Eater
severed your blood tie.
What if the Horseman came here
tonight looking for you?
Then I pray next time
he finds me.
He may kill my Mason brothers.
He may even kill me.
But I will not go alone.
I will not leave this earth
with him still on it.
He beheaded my mentor.
I want him killed
just as badly as you do.
(exhales)
I know why the Horseman
came here tonight.
He was looking for his skull.
Why would he think it was here?
The Masons are the
traditional guardians of secrets
and artifacts
for the side of good.
The Horseman would've assumed
that his skull was
in their possession.
When the Horseman came
last time,
Katrina warned us that if he got
his skull, the other three
Horsemen of the
Apocalypse would rise.
The Horseman is here to hasten
the end of days,
just as he tried before.
We must retrieve his head
before he does.
And this time...
we destroy it.
(knocking) You're asking my permission
to destroy evidence?
Agent Collins from the FBI.
Call back. I have a few more.
Marlene Ramsay?
The victim's wife. I'll call her
as soon as I'm done.
And your daughter wanted to remind you
it's Cynthia's birthday tomorrow.
She kept the damn dog.
Do I really need to call her
on her birthday?
Mother of your child.
Like I could forget.
(chuckles)
(door shuts)
I just told you I needed
more proof and you respond
by asking me to destroy evidence?
Sir,
I'll take care of it.
It'll never come back to you.
I don't have it.
I sent the skull out
to another lab.
CRANE:
Marlene Ramsay,
have you informed her
of her husband's passing?
Yes.
During the war,
I personally informed the family
when a soldier
in my regiment was killed.
There is no worse feeling
than telling someone
their loved one's gone.
Especially
when it's under your watch.
The Horseman will kill
every night
until he gets what he came for.
And you'll have to make
that call over and over again.
You've come this far, sir.
You need to trust us.
(knocking, door opens)
The D.A.'s on line one.
I'll call her from the car.
Stick around.
I won't be gone long.
(muffled music playing)
Paul?
Hey.
Thanks for coming in so late.
No problem. Unfortunately,
we still can't figure out
what kind of processes
were done to the skull.
We put it through the woodwork.
(grunts)
Biopsy came back unreadable,
so we ran cytology:
nothing. PCR?
Still nothing.
I'm running carbon dating,
but that takes
a few more weeks.
There's so much more to test.
No definable cell structure,
no DNA markers--
it's been scrubbed
of any sign of life.
And yet, there it is.
Do you have a box?
(sputters)
I know we got the right size box
in here somewhere.
If you don't have a box,
I'll take a bag.
(automatic gunfire)
Oh, my God.
(gunshots)
(cocks shotgun)
I got you, you headless son of a bitch.
(hissing)
(thunder rumbles)
(starts engine)
(tires screech)
(horse neighs)
(tires screeching)
(thunder rumbles)
I wanted to call my guys
in Manhattan and hunt him down.
But local PD says all the
surveillance cameras at the lab
cut out. There's
no evidence
of the Horseman.
It's like
at the precinct with Brooks.
They can't be seen
until they want
to be seen.
It's all true?
Everything you told me
from day one?
This is insane.
He murdered Paul
in front of me.
I need to... fill out a report.
I need to call the governor.
What are you going to tell him?
What do you think
I'm gonna tell him?
A headless horseman
is mowing people down
to bring about the end of days?
For further questions,
please call Ichabod Crane,
the man who beheaded him
in 1781.
It was a mere inquiry.
You wanted proof.
Honestly...
I wanted it to be a lie.
Well, we got him.
Now let's destroy it.
How rare to stare
into the face of Death.
It's something I never intend
to do again.
(bubbling, sizzling)
(explosion)
There's a junkyard in Tarrytown
with an industrial
car compactor.
I've seen it turn an SUV
into an ice cube.
If it can't crush the skull,
nothing can.
The myriad of destructive
devices you have in this century
is remarkable.
It's late.
They weren't there earlier.
Is that common?
Four lanterns lit in a carport?
Don't know.
Probably not.
Why?
In my day, Paul Revere developed a system:
one lantern,
the enemy comes by land.
Two, they come by sea.
Paul Revere, midnight ride.
"One if by land, two if by sea."
You've heard of it?
Word may have gotten around.
What does four lanterns mean?
Why would the Horseman do this?
The Masons believe their minds
are akin to a temple.
A sacred, holy place.
We're tampering with his head
and he's responding in kind.
He lined the heads with silver.
Is it... along the top
of the skull?
Does that mean something to you?
Paul Revere utilized
the same technique
the night the Crown arrived
in the colonies.
In 1775 Paul Revere lined
the lanterns with silver
to enhance their illumination.
I was guarding the safe house
where Sam Adams and John
Hancock were evading arrest.
When I alerted Adams
that the Crown was coming
by sea, I observed him hand
Paul Revere a document,
a continuous manuscript kept
by the Masons containing
enemy secrets that could be
used to defeat the Crown.
There was a symbol
on the manuscript,
a demonic heptagram.
I've seen it in Corbin's files.
It's a star within a star.
ABBIE: The Devil's trap--
I've seen it, too.
But it's a symbol used
to entrap and defeat demons.
Why would that be
on a manuscript
containing enemy secrets?
Maybe they weren't
secrets of the Crown.
They were secrets
for conquering evil.
My God.
The Horseman of Death was there
that night.
Where?
CRANE: Paul Revere told us of an
enemy assailant who chased him
on his ride into Lexington.
He believed it was
a cold-blooded mercenary
for the Crown, but...
But it was Death himself.
He was after the manuscript.
It must contain
a secret about him,
uh, his weakness or flaw.
Do you think that it was updated
after you cut off his head?
I do.
I'd wager that's the information
the Masons wanted
to share with us.
We got to find that manuscript.
Tarrytown Museum
of Colonial History.
This venue holds
the manuscript?
Amongst other
historical artifacts.
This might be your happy place.
GUIDE:
Paul Revere
was a Renaissance man--
a silversmith,
an early industrialist, and even
a highly acclaimed dentist.
All right, kids, follow me.
It's apocryphal, what this man
is telling these children.
Let it go.
Uh...
Were you charged a fee
for that water?
My God, it should be
an inalienable right.
Where do the courts fall on this?
GUIDE: Gather round.
Uh...Wait.
And make sure everybody can see.
Now, while Revere was,
well, revered
for his many talents,
he is most famous
for what historical event?
CHILDREN: The midnight ride.
That's right.
In fact, many refer to it
as Paul Revere's midnight ride
since he was
the first patriot to yell
"The British are coming!"
as he rode into Concord.
Uh, pardon the interruption,
but Paul Revere never arrived
in Concord.
That was
Samuel Prescott's route,
and the warning all the riders
gave, as discreetly as possible,
was "The Regulars are coming,"
not "The British are coming."
See, we, too,
were British at the time
so that would have been
most unhelpful.
Did you just say "we"?
Excuse us.
My cousin Steve forgot to take
his medication this morning.
Didn't you, Steve?
I'm the only one amongst you
who doesn't require medication.
A highly acclaimed dentist.
The man was a silversmith.
That's the last person you want
poking around in your mouth.
So I spoke to one
of the curators.
I have good news and bad news.
What do you want first?
Is this a riddle?
Never mind.
Bad news:
the manuscript's on loan
to the National Army Museum
in London.
London.
Mm-hmm.
That's a three-month voyage
by sea.
That's where
the good news comes in.
They've uploaded
the manuscript online.
That is excellent news.
You have no idea what
I'm talking about, do you?
No, I do not.
Oh, uh...
(tapping keyboard)
(murmuring)
I really hope you're right
about this manuscript.
12 hours until the
Horseman rides again.
Uh, Lieutenant, I've done
something catastrophic.
You printed this five times.
Correct.
Why?
In case the picture
vanishes from the screen
like it did a moment ago.
The manuscript-- written
in some kind of code.
Adams would have used
a Vigenère cipher.
I vaguely remember that
from Criminology 101.
It's similar
to a Caesar shift cipher,
but instead of shifting
the alphabet based on a letter,
it's based on a word.
A Vigenère cipher is several
Caesar ciphers in a sequence
with different shift values.
Therefore,
without the code word,
the text is impossible
to decrypt.
Oh, so you're looking
for a password?
This is definitely
your area of expertise.
Flummoxed by a foreign concept
that resembles close to nothing
of what you know?
Can't imagine how that feels.
(ringtone playing)
I'm trying to crack a
very complicated code.
Is that noise going to cease?
I must have quietude
to concentrate.
Calm down.
I'm gonna make a quick call,
uh, give you some privacy.
If you're going
to annul an engagement
with a man who works
across the street,
don't you think
you should do it in person?
How do you know I'm meeting
with Luke later?
You're much easier to read
than a Vigenère cipher.
(indistinct radio transmissions)
(phone ringing)
BROOKS (distorted):
There are others like me.
Except for the chosen few.
There's a war going on,
Morales.
Watching.
I saw you with Abbie Mills.
Waiting.
(ringtone playing)
Stay away from her.
I trust you'll make
the right decision.
(ringtone playing)
Stay away from Abbie Mills.
I'm the only one
that can protect her.
(ringtone playing)
Hey, this is Luke.
Leave me a message.
Hey, Luke, it's Abbie.
I know we were supposed
to have coffee today,
but something just came up
and I'm not gonna be able
to make it,
so give me a call
when you get this
and we'll figure out
another time.
Okay.
Okay, talk soon.
(Brooks groans)
Andy?
You're supposed to be dead.
(crunches)
(grunts)
I am dead.
Is that not apparent?
Brooks... what happened?
Abbie, I'm, I'm stuck.
I want this to end,
but he won't let me.
You sold your soul?
I know you don't believe me,
but I'm trying to protect you.
(tapping keyboard)
Well, how did we get here?
Well, that is wildly
inappropriate.
Hey, sexy.
Want to chat?
(clears throat)
Well, I'm flattered, madam,
but I'm afraid
I am espoused to another.
Ooh.
Still here.
♪
Cicero is the password.
Oh, Revere, you rum beggar.
You hid the password
on the back of his teeth.
The Horseman won't
stop coming after you
until he gets his head.
Well, that's not gonna happen.
Horseman's indestructible,
Abbie, he is Death.
We're getting that idea,
thank you.
That's what I'm here
to tell you.
You can't kill Death,
but you can trap him.
That's the only way
you can defeat him.
ABBIE:
How?
BROOKS:
I don't know.
I just know it's a secret
he doesn't want let out.
Brilliant.
Why should I believe
anything that you say?
Because I care
about you, Abbie.
Is that the sheriff's turncoat?
Andy Boks.
My name is Andy Brooks.
We saw you die in that cell.
Yeah.
It's not my best day.
Are you still in communication
with the Horseman?
I am... but that's
not why I'm here.
I want to help Abbie.
Here's how you can help.
Deliver this message
to the Horseman:
if he wants his head back,
he can meet me at the cemetery
when night falls.
Okay, I'll tell him.
If you return here,
there will be consequences.
Do you understand?
Don't threaten me.
You all right?
(sighs)
(cocks gun)
He said the Horseman
can't be killed.
Only trapped.
He's right.
And I think I know how.
I cracked the code.
You've got crazy
good handwriting.
This?
Chicken scratch.
There is a lot of useful
information in this manuscript.
I'm not surprised the Horseman
wanted it destroyed.
1782, the Masons updated
this manuscript
with a way to defeat
the Horseman of Death.
Then Paul Revere engraved the
key to decoding the manuscript,
the word "Cicero," in the back
of the Horseman's teeth.
What did he say about
the Horseman, post-beheading?
(papers rustling)
"Death cannot be slain,
"but it can be captured and
caged against its fiery will.
"As sunlight is
his only weakness,
"a witch must be summoned
"to cast a spell,
transforming the moon
into the sun,
whilst Death is exposed."
Great. We need a witch.
Too bad we can't
summon your wife.
Yes, the thought
had crossed my mind, thank you,
though not as a means
to defeat our present enemy.
Sorry. Understood.
Perhaps there are still witches
in Sleepy Hollow?
Lieutenant?
When Adams wrote
in this manuscript,
witches were the only means
of creating sunlight at night.
But today, we have UV light,
ultraviolet
light, also known as
artificial sunlight.
It's the modern version of
what Adams was talking about.
We can simulate the sun.
Well, as long as it doesn't
include the 'ninnanet,'
then, I'm amenable.
(slurping loudly through straw)
Aah!
(laughing):
Stop!
No excuses.
You guys have had straws
for a millennium.
Mm. This water was free
at the market.
So was the arsenic
that comes with it.
So, we have to lure him
into the tunnels.
Any ideas?
A few.
Though they require supplies
which could take
some time to prepare.
I'm not sure
they'll be completed by sundown.
What if we got help?
IRVING:
Assuming this works,
which is generous,
say we trap him.
Where are we gonna keep him?
I'm not dropping him
in the drunk tank.
The Masons have a cell protected
by a supernatural
barrier, designed
by Thomas Jefferson.
Jefferson. Huh.
What was he like?
Oh, a true Renaissance man.
Artisan, scholar.
How do you figure
a guy who wrote,
"All men are created equal"
justified owning slaves?
That's actually
a good question.
I can say with some certainty
that he recognized
the severe immorality of it.
He supported
abolition in Virginia.
Perhaps his firsthand experience
added to his eloquence
in drafting a document used
to justify it.
ABBIE:
Or
maybe Sally Hemings
inspired him.
Who is Miss Hemings?
Hogwash!
Thomas was a loyal husband.
Your press knows no bounds!
They still favor
salacious speculation to fact.
I once said to Thomas,
"A man who reads nothing at all
"is better educated than a man
who reads nothing
but newspapers."
We had a good laugh
about that one.
I hate to burst your bubble,
but we have something called
DNA evidence,
which scientifically proves
that your pal Thomas Jefferson
fathered six kids by one
of his slaves-- Sally Hemings.
ABBIE: And not to kick
you while you're down,
but... Jefferson took credit
for your line about the press.
Well...
we never really know people,
do we?
Should be ten minutes
or so till sundown.
The seventh time
you've checked.
I suspect you're also
awaiting news from Luke.
Oh, it's probably for the best.
Not like
we could've had a real...
real friendship or anything.
And why is that?
It's always gonna be this.
Canceling last minute,
lying about it,
keeping secrets.
The most important parts
of my life,
the parts
that I want to share--
they're off limits.
So what's the point?
Why are you smiling?
Katrina once expressed
a similar view.
She believed a liaison with me
would compromise our roles
in the war.
I suppose she wasn't wrong.
If you hadn't been in love,
she would've let you die
with the Horseman.
Most likely.
She wouldn't be in Purgatory.
Also true.
And you wouldn't be here.
Stuck in the modern era,
where everyone I care about
has been dead for 200 years.
That must be hard.
It's an adjustment.
If it makes you feel
any better,
I feel pretty alone
sometimes, too.
Perhaps this is the sacrifice
that witnesses must carry.
All we really get...
is one another.
(laughs)
Sun's almost down.
The Horseman's going to ride.
It's time.
(thunder crackling)
CRANE:
I received your message.
My reply.
(horse neighing)
(thunder crackling)
(gunshot)
(neighing)
(thunderclaps)
(panting)
(grunts)
Oh, that was... terrifying.
(cackling)
ABBIE:
Hey.
Do you want to talk about it?
Feeling mocked yet?
(gasps)
Snuff the light!
ABBIE:
Crane, I'm hurt.
I think I broke my ankle.
(groaning)
Crane, help me.
Keep quiet.
I'm coming for you.
Crane?!
(Abbie gasps)
Crane, he's here! (gasping)
Now!
(clacking)
(gasping)
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com