Gaetanoooo,Gaeetano, Gaetaaa!
Gaetanoo, Gaetaanoo, Gaetaaa!
Gaetanoo, Gaetano, Gaetaaaa...!
Not even the most desperate
of the saint would shout like that!
What do you want?
Nothing! Just calling you.
Just calling!
Damn! At this time...!
Gaeta', Gaetano...
People are sick,
everybody’s at home ...
..Gaità.., damn!
I would smash your face!
Every night the same story!
Why you are you looking at me?!
What were you doing?
Watching TV?
Yes, I was watching TV.
May I?!
I was watching the news!
Even the journalist,
stopped reading.
He said:
''Sorry! Can you tell me
who’s the asshole shouting
like that...
I can’t work! I can’t''
Everybody knows you!
I just wanted to know
what where you doing!?
They’re going to the movies. Are you going too?
Are you going to the movies?
- I don’t know, Raffaele!
You don’t know?
- No, I don’t!
What do you mean, you don’t know?
Either you know or you don’t!
If you know, but if you don’t...
- Are you going to?
I don’t know!
- Are you going or not!!?
Damn! I don’t know!
I can’t explain!
Now I will...
- Are you going or not?
Damn!
I can’t stand him!
Are you going or not?
- I don’t know, got it?
No, I don’t want to go!
Got it? No! Hands in your pocket!
Why are you not going?
- I am not because you...
..because I don’t like you!...Raffaele
- You can’t say that!.
I don’t like you...
- No! You can’t say that!
I don’t like you..
- No, you can’t say that...
Damn, it’s because, you talk too much.
You never let people speak!!!
- Then I talk too much...
but still you like me!
- No, you are a very unpleasant talker!
Alright! You’re always right!
So, are we going or not?
- He’s not going to the movies!
Damn!
- What can you do! A real war...!
Then, I awoke
all sweating. Like this!
Fortunately it was a dream...
- What was it?! A war!
A dreaming war!
- Right!
Damn! Don’t tell me about dreaming
wars, please!
That’s fantastic!
I dream about it every night!
As soon as I fall asleep, it’s a war.
Every night it’s a war!
I mean, as soon as I fall asleep,
war is declared!
Damn!
Fantastic!
But I never killed anybody!
I mean...considering all the wars
I went through!
I am 26 and as soon I fall asleep! I was
in the Punic wars, the independency wars
first world war, second...
All the wars...
and I never killed anybody!
Never! It never happens...I mean
I grab a rifle, a gun.
I want to shoot.
Damn...!
the enemy’s there, I say,
damn...
I’ll show you...I shoot...!
The bullet stays inside:
either the gun get stuck,
or it melts or it shoots
like  a plastic ball...!
I can never shoot!
Sometimes you feel
the shot going...
I say: Now I kill him,
damn...
I see his back and say:
''You can’t see me''
I shoot! I hear the shot… you know
.. coming out...
But! It falls on the ground!
I mean...it comes out, boom!
It falls...
And naturally, as soon as he sees me:
there he is...
he shots me four, five...
he gets angry: ''You wanted to kill me...
but how do you dare.''
...Got it?..
And I don’t have even a knife!
Nothing, nothing!..
Listen. I think it’s because
I am sleepless.
I am sleepless and every night
I fall asleep around 3,30 am or
3 am. You know what happens?
All the people that fall asleep
around 10.30pm, 11 or 12,
and dream about wars,
I mean, it’s true! I mean
They can choose the best weapons...
and say:
''This is good, this is not!
They take the guns:
this is good and this is not!
So! I arrive at 2-3 am,
and I find only the scruffs
and I can take only those pieces...
What are you talking about!
- Guys, I am going to the movies..
Are you coming or not? Let’s go!
..ok..
- Wait a moment!
Listen, come with us..
- No, no..
come on...
- No, I don’t want to!
You do, you do, you do..
- Are you starting again!
Raffaele, shut up! I don’t want to go!
Ok, you don't!
- Go away! Damn!
You’re terrible!
- Ok, I’ll stay here, or you’ll be alone...
Absolutely not! You go. Alone...
is this a desert, maybe!?
I get bored.. to the movies...
I... I am leaving tomorrow.
Tomorrow I'll go to Florence
to aunt Antonia..
Again Florence, again aunt Antonia,
but then you don’t go anywhere!
I am saying I’ll go, right?
And then...
I am going, Raffaele,
I can’t stand it anymore!
I mean...the past is past.
I am starting from three...
From zero...
- What?
Starting from zero!
Absolutely not, starting from three.
Only three things I managed
in my life, why
should I lose them
and start from zero..?! From three!
I am leaving! I can’t stand it anymore!
Gaetano, who leaves, knows what he’s leaving,
but not what he’s looking for!
What are you saying?
Who leaves...? - knows what he’s leaving,
but not what he’s looking for!
Shit…nice!
That’s your own words?
You look stupid, but...!
Be careful... you hurt me!
Good evening!
Good evening...
- Go home, mum is alone!
I must go to the church
and talk to con don Gino.
Damn! He’s going to the church
and ask a miracle
to grow his hand!
He’s going crazy! He’s convinced..
he says: ''I am a good person,
hones, a good worker...
it’s not possible
I get punished like this!
And he waits for a miracle
that will grow his hand!
So what, he’s waiting the miracle!
Why bothering?
You are more stupid than he is,
Raffaele!
The miracle that grows his hand!!!
His hand growing!
- Eh, eh!
All the miracles that I know of,
are about people..
for example, that can’t see
and then you can see...
but you already have eyes!
You don’t walk and then you can,
but you already have legs!
But have you ever seen a person
that doesn’t have something,
and then he has it!?
This is why the miracle is so difficult
and he’s concentrating,
because the miracle is difficult,
is much more difficult!
What is a difficult miracle...Why?
Difficult miracle and easy miracle,
..the one of 100 points
and the one 50 points!
Damn! A miracle, is a miracle!
All the miracles are the same!
Why then people,
when there’s a miracle,
and see something crazy they say:
''Miracleeeee, Miracleee!''
Everybody: '''Miracleee,
miracleee!
Have you ever seen somebody saying:
'' U! Miracle.'',
because is a 50 points miracle!
- No, no!
There is the:''Miiracleeee!!''
and the'' miracle''!
What are you talking about!
- Alright alright!
As far as I know, there is only:
''Miracleeeee! Miracleee!!''
Everybody: ''Miracleee! ...''
- No, no…you can’t say...
''Miracleee!
and the ''miracle''.
But if I know that everybody shouted:
''Miracleeee''..
There is the ''Miracleeee!''
or the ''miracle''.
The ''Miracleee!''
or the ''miracle''! ..Got it!
Nothing happened tonight!
No miracles! Never mind!
Don’t think I want
to put some pressure on you!
I am here! I wait!
There’re other people before me!
That’s fair!
I just wanted to say...when you
decide to grow it...
better if it happens at night!
I prefer that...just not to get scared!
So in the morning..
everything is already fixed!
I was hoping
it would grow tonight
considering we are moving,
move furniture, chairs,
and so on.. I could help!
I could give a hand...!
Anyway, it doesn’t matter...
It’s up to you!
By the way, my new address:
Via Cavallo di bronzo, 31.
Take care there’re two nr 31
not the first one....as if you would
go on the highway...,
and instead of turning left
you turn right…fine..
you know about that!
It’s your job!
You’ll find me...
(Toc, toc) Who’s there!
- Me!
Damn...Are you always locked
inside the restroom?
You can go now!
- Hurray!
You spend your life
locked inside this restroom!
It’s always locked!
- It’s Pasqualino. He has to go to the court..!
I hope he goes to jail!
Hey, don’t joke about that!
Mum, either he’s locked in the restroom, or
he’s locked in jail, that’s the same!
aah,ah!
- he’s locked anyway!
Eeeeh, damn...
Come---
Come...
come...
come...come...
Are you really calling it!
Are you talking to that?
- Rosaa, shut up!
It was really moving!
It made a movement...
it’s a matter of concentrating!
If you distract me...that’s over!
Come on! I just asked you something!
I thought you could call it
only with your mind!
I can call it also with my voice!
Maybe if it hears something,
I can convince it better!
Rosàa, can you imagine:
if I can move it
I find a solution to all my problems!
The TV people find me...
and say: ''Move that..''
and I move it!
Or: ''Move that''.
And I move it.
I solve all my problems, Rosà!
Let’s say…I stay here:
come…come...come...
and Pasqualino gets out the restroom.
Finally!
Anyway…if he should come out,
remember me!
Why you want to leave!?
We have a new house!
Why do you want to emigrate?
Mum, I don’t want to emigrate!
I want to travel, to know!
It’s not true that
I am unhappy here...
Now that you found a good job!
A good job!
Every morning at five
inside that train..
start squeezing oranges...
Mum, I can’t stand it anymore!
Ah, Pasqualino…yesterday night
a girl called you!
Who was she?
- I didn’t understand!
She told her name two or three times.
But...I didn’t understand!
You should write it down!
He already said he didn’t understand,
what should she write:
''I didn’t understand!''
Gaetano, as for the money that you make,
that’s useful to us!
I mean, I don’t care about the money!
No no, I do!
Listen...I have two choices:
either I leave...
Or?
- Or? Or I leave!
Which is the other choice?
Which other choice?
You said there were
TWO choices!?
I said there were two choices?
Yes! - No, I said:
'' There’ s one ..'' I remember!
One choice! I always had
just one choice
and now you’re talking
about a second choice!?
That’s impossible
really…always one choice!
Where’re you coming from?
Naples.
Immigrant!
No!
No! I mean... I have
a job in Naples...
A normal life ...
like everybody! I worked..
No, I left...to travel...
to know things..
- That’s good, for young people!
You don’t like something,
you just stop and change your life.
That would be too late for me!
Too late!
I sacrificed all my life!
My family, my job. All my life!
And know there’s nothing left
but stop it!
If it would be a mortal
a mortal sin...
to commit suicide!
I would have done it long time ago.
There could be a way
to let things appear natural..
And I found it!
A car accident!
So many people die like this!
You run because you’re late...
then your car crashes.
Don’t run,,,
- Do you think they would notice?
They would notice...always
they would notice.... that...
go…slowly! Even I do..
sometimes…things that
things that  I think
.. if they would notice..!.
They always look at me…slowly!
I mean, how can it be!?
They always look at me!
You do something...! But, after you do it,
they were looking at you!
Everybody...because they
like to know.. slowly!
And then they notice!
It would be a sin!
- A mortal sin!
If you can call it a sin:
''A venial sin?''.
Ok...maybe you could...
don’t run!
No! It’s mortal! The hell...
- The hell!
The hell!
- Another one!
After all what I went through,
another hell! No..no no!
I need a piece of paradise!
Instead I find the hell!
I need to rest.
Now I am feeling sick!
I am very sick,
I can’t go on like this!
I am sick...
- Slowly...Don’t run...
There’s only one place where they know
what to do, when I am so sick..
could you drive me there?
- ..What?
Could you bring me there?
- There..I...
There..
- No…I’ve arrived...now!
No!
- Let me go...I don’t know anything!
I’ll tell you!
Can you bring me?
- Ok!...
Can you drive?
- Yes, slow down...!
- Yes..!
What?
- What?
I can’t help it.
I can’t help it, doctor!
The usual thoughts..
- Come...
Same thoughts..
Something that...
Listen, I try explain:
it’s like an idea hunts me...
- Ok, I go.
An idea...so!
You understand…an idea!
- Come in.
Better to leave him alone.
Are you a relative?
- No...Just hitchhiking
and suddenly he started to say...
Yes, don’t worry, we’ll take care!
I don’t really care!
Wait here!
Listen..! I said I don’t know him..
Why should I wait!!
Damn!!!!
'Morning..
Bho!
Bo! MA! ma!
NO! Pride and dignity!
Dignity and pride!
NO!
Pride..
- and dignity
Dignity--! I...I
don’t care about dignity!
liiiih! Ehe! I don’t care!
If somebody would ask me:
''Do you want to change personality?''
''Become somebody else?''
You know my answer?
''Yes!!! Sure!''
What is my answer
''Yes, sure!''!
- Good!
Good! I am not hypocrite.
You know, if you ask somebody
on the street:
''Do you want to become Gianni Agnelli?''
''To become - as for beauty
- Alain Delon?'' For example...
Just ask him. You’ll see
what they answer!
You know the answer? ''NO!''
SUUURRRE!
But if you ask me...
ask me!
''Do you want to become Gianni Agnelli or Alain Delon''
- Ask me.
...or Alain Delon?
- Just ask me:
''Do you want to become Gianni
Agnelli or Alain Delon?''
See what I will answer!
If you ask me now...
- ''Do you want to become Gianni Agnelli or Alain Delon?''
Let’s pretend you asked it to me!
No...I did ask! I really asked:
''Do you want to become...''
Anyway, you are confused.
You should ask me...
You really didn’t!
I will say that...
''Do you want to become
Gianni Agnelli or Alain Delon?''
See what I answer!
You know what I answer?
You know what I answer? ''YYYESS!''
''Sure!''
Sure! They have everything!
They have women...they are rich..
they are nice...
and healthy, and
keys to their houses...
and pianos and safety boxes
and cakes and drinks
and champagne boxes
and burying boxes!
and I have a shit! Look
what a difference...yes or not!
Yes or not...?
- He’s crazy!
That guy is weird!
In America they’re not so weird!!
I’ve been to America...
Really weird!
- Are you scared?
Yes. At some point
I went in and he looked like that,-
above! I turned around
and nobody was there!
I mean, that blocked me,
his look.. you understand!
Ok! Bye, I go... bye!!
Gaetano, when do you want to leave?
I don’t know yet, auntie.
Just feel at home here! Ok?
No compliments, Gaetà!
- Yes, yes!
Don’t you want to know each other?
You stay there, without talking...
Frank, did you talk to Gaetano?
I told you, Frank is American
and he’s a preacher,
but not like our priests,
a sort of!
But, you see, he’s normal.
He says we must
love each other;
it’s nice that such a young person
says that!
Because...nowadays , there’s crime,
people are mean...
only with the Word
we can understand each other better,
he always says: the Word!
The Word.. solves everything!
Yes, but which Word?
The Word that...which Word Frank?
The Word as dialogue!
Right. As dialogue!
People should talk...
discuss! People don’t talk much!
Lack of communication!
Isolation! Not really!
Saint Francesco talked to
birds, to wolves, to dogs, to horses.
Damn it! He could talk to animals
and we Christians can’t even talk to
other Christians!
That’s not true, Frankie!
Religions are all the same!
Obligations, stuff..!
No, no..no! Our religion
is different...
You just follow  and I just ask you...
to talk..
to open...! I mean..
to talk to people! Got it?
What do you want to open, Frank!
- Why?
I am closed!
I can’t...
What can’t you do?
Stop..stop.. wait...
- What?
Damn..!
Shut up, She looks like..
the one I met where
I took that suicide!
- Don’t you want to meet her?
Yes, I do, but...
- I take care...Hallo!!!
Wait, shut up! Wait!
I want to meet her but without
noticing!
Not soon like that..!
- How do you want to do?
Wait! Just shut up a moment!
You know what I do? ..
I run around the building
I mean, all around the building
and meet her on the other side,
then I can say:
''Hi, how’re you?''
Good idea, right?
Your bag!
Damn!
Damn!... That’s too heavy!
Hi, what are you doing here?
What?
What’s going on?
Did you run?
No..
- I am exhausted, I’ve been walking for hours...
you don’t even know
my name!
And I don’t know yours!
I am, now you know. And you?
A...et.a!
- What?
Gaetano!
- Ah, now I know!
Is he a friend of yours?
No…I don’t know him…just
somebody.. I don’t really know him.
I don’t know!
- Stay with me!
Go away!
- No...no, just one, thanks!
Well…that’s nice here..!
- Nice...
What can i say!? I mean...!
How’s the suicide?
Fine! Suicide?! Do you think
people suicide so easily?
What do you mean, easily?
Easily! No!
-...there’s somebody in Naples, it’s a true story..
- Why don’t you take off your coat?.
..Coat!
Can I put it here?
It’s clean!
Somebody in Naples, he pretended...,
he was married, got it?
and his wife..- how many people like that!?
You meet them and think.. what can it be! -
His wife left it - right?-
because she said that he didn’t
love her enough..
guess it! She left. When she left,
he committed suicide!
He poisoned himself! Then his wife
thought it was a love sacrifice...
and she came back to him
and her lover committed suicide!
But people don’t commit suicide...
- What did she do?
Nothing...she stayed
with her husband...
She chose the easiest way!
- No, no. She chose the worse!
Her husband was really mad! Look...
- Come on!!!!
That’s not true, you invented it!
No really...!..Really
... it really happened!
Nice! I mean that’s bad
because there’s a suicide
but, as a story,
is unbelievable!
For example, I am writing a book
and I’m always afraid to write things
too much afar from reality
then, you listen to true stories
beyond any imagination!
Yes... no…because it looks as if
.. can you ever imagine
the lover...the husband..! I mean...that’s it!!
A story... I like this place, really
nice! Nice...I like all this...
like...
Like what?
It’s really nice...
- Why did you leave Naples?
You know...eventually... who leaves
knows what he’s leaving,
but doesn’t know what he’s looking for!
What? You talk with other
people’s words?
Why, do you know Lello?
Who’s Lello?
Lello Sodano! The short one,
with his face... a little...
.., what did I say?!
- It’s from Montaigne.
Ah, Montaigne, the sentence..!.
No, nothing..!
- Who’s Lello?.
Nothing.. My mistake,
I said... it’s from Montaigne!
Gaetano! It’s seven o’clock!.
Everything is inside this bag!
The bread with sausages
and a bottle of mineral water.
There is also a cake!
I am going out.
Are you falling asleep again?!
Better if I open the window.
Or you miss the bus!
I don’t care about
The Abbey of Casamari!
That’s an excuse
to stay together...
this is how I started to open myself,
to talk to people...
Hi, Frank!
- Hi!
this is how I started to open myself,
to talk to people,
thanks to this meetings.
What are you saying?
I am still asleep, Frank!
I am really...
- Why didn’t you invite Marta?
Where, here?
- Why not?
Frank! I don’t know her...
The first time I go out with a woman
where do we go?!!! On a bus trip
to the Abbey!
Here is full of old people!
Not even ...
That’s not true! There are some young people!
This way, careful.. careful.
That’s nice to talk! Saint Francesco
talked to birds!
Frank, please! Again with the story
Saint Francesco
talking to birds!
I can’t stand it anymore
and listen to the same story...
what was Saint Francesco doing?
Was he always talking to birds!?
Was he continuously in the ears
of those poor animals that.
just wanted to be in peace, but
they had to listen at Saint Francesco
in their ears all the time!
Come on! I think those birds
were really fed up of Saint Francesco!
As soon as they saw him, they said:
''Saint Francesco is arriving!''
When they saw him..'/'Saint
Francesco''!!!! tweet tweet tweet!
They all ran away the trees...
I think that it was
Saint Francesco’s fault
if the bird’s migration started!
They couldn’t stand him anymore!
Come on! Let’s go...
- No Frank..
I am not going...
- Why not?! Come on..
Nooo I am..! I am still asleep!
- Don’t do this...!
No, Frank, listen to me...
- This is a great experience!?
No, first of all, I am asleep!
I would fall asleep on the bus!
Second thing...I don’t want to!
Take this!
You share with the others, ok?
There’s some bread with sausages,
mineral water and a cake...!
The cake is good!
Tell him to give you a piece of cake!
He’s American!
He takes everything for himself!
See you!
G..mornin.
- Good morning...
Well.. isn’t my aunt living here?
When?
No…Up to
this morning.... she was...
I remember because she gave me
the cake...
Is Mrs Tortora your aunt?
Yes, Mrs Tortora!
Professor Fabio Capecchi
Please! Your aunt will be back soon.
You come here, in your aunt’s house
but you find me!
Who is this man going around the house
dressed like that?
Who could I be?
Bbbut! I mean...not...a thief!
Come on!
No, I said no..!
A thief wouldn’t be dressed...
Young man! The situation
is very clear...
Yes...
- But you shouldn’t judge from the appearance!
As for me: I am a well known
professor of arts...
as for your aunt: she is a very
deserving person!
Yes?! Yes, yes, I know!.
You might think
that it’s not good that your aunt
has a partner,
a lover! Whatever!
In truth your aunt is still
a married woman..
and we are not so young!
Not so young!..
Is it a shame?!
But...! Did you read Cooper?
Do you know what he says?
Cooper…said many things....
Cooperrr!?...
Maybe he said...that..
The birth of love is a subversion
of any kind of social order
on our life!
Cooper said this!
And this is what happened to us!
Gaetano! Didn’t you go...
You met him!?
Aunt...
- No no no no, please, don’t think bad!
I love you!
- Aunt, I am not thinking anything..
No, no! I must explain
everything...
There’s nothing...
- No, no no! Come with me!
I must explain
I...no you don’t think bad...
Her husband... her husband!!
What should I do?!
What should I do?! I waited,
Gaetano, I waited!
I suffered too much solitude!
Too much solitude, too much!!!
Be quiet! Aunt, don’t worry...
Be quiet...
Fabio is such a good person!
You meet him, didn’t you?
- He’s...really a nice person!
He’s so nice... You shouldn’t
go away, Gaetano!...
Don’t leave me.. because of Fabio...
You must stay with me, you understand!
Aunt, don’t shout, please!
It’s full of people...I am not
going because of Fabio...
I am going because it’s fair
that you live together...
you see...! The professor...
live your life!
Aunt, don’t shout, please!
Aunt!
- Thanks! Thanks for understanding!
You are a modern man!
Not like your father...
he chased always
all my boyfriends!
When he saw me with somebody:
'' You stay away from
my sister!
Go away!
If I see you again with her,
I’ll smash your face, you understand me!!!
Don’t shout, auntie, please!
And my mother...my sister in law
and all the other ones!..
'' See? She has another boyfriend,
she’s a bitch!
What!? At her age!
Shame on her?!''
Why? Does love ever
gets old?
Why?!! Am I old, Gaetano???
No, auntie! I am not saying that...
You can...
.. even  Cooper said that..
stop it, please!..
AUNTIE!
I mean... calm down...
I am happy, Gaetano!
I don’t care at all!
Yes....this is good!
A U N T I E!
Thanks!
Thank you very much!
And he quotes Cooperr..
who’s Cooper!
My aunt really made me ashamed
in that cafe, you should see...
now. nothing! I need time
to fix things...
think if I should leave...or..
- Ok..ok
Anyway…these  are the keys.
This is the door...and this is the gate.
Can you make a copy?
And if you stay longtime,
you have nowhere to go...
no problem, ok?!.
No, I have nowhere to go!.
I just know my aunt
and you! This is fine,
I would stop longtime
but…I don’t want to bother you,
..I don’t want to be a problem!
No, no problem!
If you feel fine!
If you could open yourself...
and talk to people...
you can come with me
to some houses...
and bring the word!
I don’t think I stay longtime!
Come on!
I don’t know what to say...
I am going... but I don’t know...
Come on…let’s go!
- But you talk!
I am not saying anything! You do..
- Ok, Ok...don’t worry...
I am not worried!
I don’t understand! What’s the use of
selling door to door
Jesus Christ as if he is
an encyclopedia!
I don’t understand!
What if they chase us away!!
That can happen!
- Ah! Therefore...!..
Don’t worry! They are my friends.
I’ve been here before...
they like us. Let’s go!
Damn, damn...
Robertino, somebody’s here!?...
Come on, Frank!...
Hello! This is Gaetano.
Are you happy to see Frank?
Is Gaetano American?
He is from Naples.
- Immigrant!
No..I am not..I had a job,
in Naples,
I mean...I worked ..and
I left just to travel, to know!
Then I met Frank and here I am!
Well! I’ll get you a nice
cup of warm tea!
Frankie, would you like to help me?
- No, no. Let’s go
No! Robertino, you stay here!
You stay with Gaetano.
uum time.. ..stay ..with Franky???
.... what?
Have you longtime...with Frankie?!
You..no.. sorry, I can’t understand you.
Have you met Frankie since long?
He said: ''Have you met Frankie
since long!''
Ah! I understood: ''Is he dead
the guy living with Frankie''
He’s talking...!
Here’s the tea!
And Frank...
Look Frank, all negative!
Ah, very good!
I am really happy!
They found some glucose
in my blood!
No wonder..! When you’re getting old..
Come on, old lady...
I am not that young, do you know?
But I am happy because nowadays young people
are never happy.
They want everything
and they want it now.
Who’s the father of rush?!
Who creates rush?
The devil!
Right. The devil!
The loss of young people started with...
- With the hippies...
The hippies!
- The mini...
The mini...
The gramophone...
Not the gramophone...
- In some part also the gramophone!
Yes, and because of all that
people are reached the point where..
they have sex on the street!
But…having sex is not
a bad thing!
The problem arises when you don’t
make it moderately!
I do too…also Gaetano..
we make love!
Just moderately..
Just moderately…we know,
there is a limit!
Ok! With limitation is ok!
But are young people able
to create limitations?
I think so.
- I don’t!
I trust young people, Mrs lda!
Listen...how do you understand
when there is a limit?
I mean...the limit of..
Well...first of all... you start
from human resistance...got it?
I mean...first of all…never
more than five...
never more than five.. when you
make that... love...
never more than five...I mean..
I mean…are you graduated?
Yes.
- Never more than four...
Never more than four...but..
you must measure the intensity..
I mean...you don’t do just four...
because...with the intensity
they...can become five...
no...if they are four, you must consider that
in one time you shouldn’t make two!
Is it correct? For example
it happens that you make it once
and you do it so intensely
that two come out of that!
So, what happens...?
If that time, you made two out of one,
you just wasted one, got it?
I mean, you lost it...then,
in that case, never more than three!
Because.. it is very difficult!
Maybe a little bit...
it depends on the person!
I mean, if you do it,
and you do with good feelings,
and give yourself a limit,
- right?
- then you realize if in one time you made it twice!
Evident! You realize because of
the way you did it..- right?!-
Is it clear?
- Yes!
Good, Roberto!
There’s rule! Roberto! You must
go out, save yourself, Roberto!
They closed you inside
this museum, listen to me
Roberto, listen to me!
You must get out!
You must run away...
on the road... touch the women,
go to a pub, do whatever you feel,
just do it...
- But mummy...
Mummy will drive you crazy!
She will drive you crazy, Robertooo!
Get out...do something...complexes..
Good for you! No complexes! You have
an orchestra in your mind, Roberto!
Roberto, do something...
- Mummyyy...
Wait..! No mummy...! I am doing
this for your sake. I don’t care
if you go crazy or not...
I really don’t care!
Mummyyy! - Robè..
Mummyyy! - Robéee
Robeeertooo!
- MUMMMYYY!
Fuck yourself and your mummy!
Come here...damn! Come...
Why don’t you come over here!?
You’re just an object!
You can’t say: ''If I move,
I’ll change''..!
No! You’re an object here or there!!
Come on! Move on and come here.
Why can’t you do that?
You would solve all the problems
all my life!.
Come on, come here!.
Come!
No way...there was…a step...!
Listen Gaetano, I am pleased
that you care for me...
I am pleased that you are
pleased to stay with me,
but I would like if everything
would me more spontaneous and normal!
I mean, you shouldn’t behave like
you are going to conquer me...
Nooo! What did I do..?
I mean...is something wrong?
- No.
Eh! I am...
- No, you did nothing wrong!
...maybe you did something!
Gaetano, you like me...
- No.
Well, then I got it wrong!
I mean, I like you, but
without...I mean...
I like you...like this...
..like...a sister...!..
Well, then!
Hi Frank!
Hi Frank! Excuse me Frank,
where’s the key?
I don’t know!
Strange. It has always been there!
I don’t know.
- I got your ''I don’t know!!.
I can’t do that...
I get a block...when I am...
even in public restrooms,
I can never...
I am always afraid if somebody
come is and I get a block!.
But it’s only you and me,
I know that you are inside.
That’s true!
Excuse me Frank, what time is it?
I don’t know!
Frank, I know, it’s about
what happened today!
Sure!
Sure. It wasn’t a question..
I got it!
Sure...
- Maybe I insisted too much to bring you with me..
and I committed a mistake!
I surely did a mistake!
But you had no right
to have fun of those nice people!
Mrs Ida is pissed off
because of that!
Yes.. Mrs lda!
Frank, you saw the way she treats him?!!
So what, do you think you helped him?
And what if you were in his place?!
Ah! If it was for my father,
I would surely be like!
Sure! But fortunately
I realized it. And I am safe!
Right, because the sons need to
get safe from their fathers!
Right! But...for my father,
you can’t understand..!
I mean...for my father
I’ve always been stupid!
Whatever I did,
he didn’t like it!
Whatever I did, there was always
somebody that did it better,
somebody’s son was always better
than me!
I remember…there was a child..
that lived just nearby...
his name was Angelo!
I will never forget him, Angelo!
He ruined my life,
that child!
How old was he?
seven or eight.
Damn!
He knew by heart the multiplication table!
He knew all the capitals of the world!
He could do summation, substraction,
multiplication, division
and he even played piano.
Disgusting!!!
That was not a child!
He was a monster!
I mean, thinking of all the people
that live in Naples
just a monster like that
lived near my house!
And the parents! If you have
a monster child...
bring him to other monsters!
Don’t bring him to me
just to poison my life!
And what when you grew up?
When I grew up, you can see..
I can’t pee in public restrooms...
I can’t face situations...
I am always in awe...
How is it going with Marta?
Bo', sometimes it makes noises...
She’s not a TV!
No! How is the relationship going?
Just going! I can’t tell!
Ok, ok. Good night!
(ring)
Hello, yes, who’s speaking?
Here he is...
It’s for you...
- For me?
Hello, who is it?
Where are you? Don’t be silly
Lello, you are in Naples!
I can hear you far away!
We agreed that if you come
to Florence you would have told me.
Come on, you are in Naples!
Don’t be silly!
Listen, don’t let me get out..
...and then is a lie!
No, 5 minutes..10,
5..10 minutes, I am close!
Then I picked up the telephone
and started slowly to dial!
5, 5, 9.. all the ones
and I hear :''...Hello, Hello''.
I thought: ''Does Gaetano
speaks English?'' But...
Listen.. where can I sleep
tonight?
Raffaele...I don’t know!
We agreed you would call me!
You should have called and I
would have told you
that I was not at my aunt’s,
and what happened...
I would explain everything!
I called you
10 days ago?!
Ten days ago!
It looks as if you say,
I called you yesterday!
But even though you would call me
one day in advance
and  I tell you:
''It’s ok. Come!''
Then, for example,
they rob me!
Just think! Is it my fault
if you come and I am not there?
Then what, if everything is fine
and I am arriving,
should I get down the train
every station
and say: ''Hello, is all ok?
I am arriving,
has Gaetano been robbed?''
- Ok! - In any case, I am the one
that doesn’t have a bed to sleep!
Is it my fault?
- Is it my fault?!
- No, it’ my fault!
I should have get down the train
and call!
Ok, Raffaele,
let’s go!
And I need to find an hotel,
a pension...
Who know how much it costs!
It was a stupid idea to come here!
Raffaele, don’t worry!
I know a pension.
We can ask how much it costs.
Yes, yes..ok!
Raffaele, listen...
what about that thing....
...who leaves knows what he’s running from
but doesn’t know what he’s looking for!!!
Is it yours, right?!
You embarrassed me so much, you did!
Raffaele, my god, let’s go there!
Listen! It’s really far!
Not at all! Now we take this way
..seven..800metres
and there we are..
- Where is the bus stop?
Which bus stop?
- The bus stop to the pension.
Raffaele, this is not Naples!
Just around the corner!
7, 800 meters and we are there.
No, where are you going!
My legs are weak!
I can’t walk anymore!
Raffaele! It’s really close!
- No noo no!
No noo no...
- There is a bike!
You can’t bike!
Take the bike and go!
You take me with the bike!
Silly! I prefer to walk!
You and the bike!
- Take! Hold a second...
No.. Raffale, please
I can’t do it!
You are not nice...
- I can’t even bike alone...
I’ll be light, I’ll be light!
Wait a moment, I’ll be light!
I’ll be light!
- I can’t bike that well!
Both of us!
- Go, go...go.. I am light!
No! That way! This way! Be light!
- How can I be light!?
Why do you say then:
''I’ll be light!''
Go, go...
- You just walk! Be light!
Liar!
Did you find?
- Eh...found!?
7000 liras! A room.
7000 liras!
Be patient! Just tell me...
how much would you pay the pension?
Apart that I wouldn’t spend
anything...
-My god, again!
-Because when a friend calls you
and say: ''Come to Florence, don’t worry,
I take care!''
Then you realize than 7000 liras
are a lot of money!
Raffaele, I just can’t
understand!
Any pension we go
you start talking about money!
So what, is it forbidden?
Surely not!
It’s the fourth time you do that!
Surely yes! If any pension we go
is expensive, I do that!
You’re so difficult!
That room is too big,
that room is too small!
That costs 7000lira, that one costs
12000!...It goes on and on!
I understand! I am too difficult!
Drive me to another pension!
As if I were a taxi driver!
Light!
- I can’t stand my legs anymore!
I’ll get light!
Listen...why don’t we go to that pension
close by...
Are you in a hurry?
Do you have an appointment?
No, just to  know! But
Do you have an appointment!?
Eh! Just to know, Raffaele!?
It’s the fourth time you ask me:
'' Do you have an appointment?''!
Yes, but you are not answering!
You and your secrets!
My secrets! I have an appointment,
got it?
With whom?
- Damn! ‘‘Just to know’’, eh?
But since you are going to tell me, just do that!
I am not going to tell you, Raffaele!
You’ve been buzzing in my ears:
'' Where are you going, where?''
And I am the one that keeps secrets!
Are you going to tell me or not?
With a woman,... is it fine?
A woman?! A woman?!'
'A woman?!'
A woman!
A normal woman, I mean....normal!
Are you happy?
Yes but, what if I can’t find a pension??
You call me at Frank’s
and see what we can do, is it ok?
Please Raffaele, I have to go...
- Wait...leave me the bike!
Raffaele, you can’t bike!
- Maybe somebody will drive me to!
I can get light, you know,
don’t worry!
What do you mean...somebody!
Ok, keep the bike!
I feel a bit anxious!
Oh god!
Gaetaaa
- Oooh!
Gaetaaa, somebody called
from the hospital...
your friend Lello
had an accident!
What? An accident?
I didn’t quite understand..
nothing serious, though.
An accident with the bike!
- He’s such an idiot!
Should I go to the hospital?
- I don’t know...
Damn... my appointment
what should I do know!?
Doctor, a visit for Mr Sodano.
He wants to talk to you.
Are you Mr Sodano’s friend?
Yes.
- It is just  a little shock!
Deriving from fear more than the fall..
it is usually always like that!
We’ve visited him carefully
because he looks very plethoric!
- Plethoric...?!
..He’s a nice guy!
I can assure you!
I mean a nice guy, he is so..
He’s so young!
So, sometimes....
you know…he thinks that...
he starts being plethoric!
Are you from Naples?
- Yes!
Immigrant?
Lello...Lello...LELLO!
- Eee!
I am Remigio!
There you are..
I was looking for you...
I came in, calling at any bed!
Yes, I saw you!
Well, why didn’t you call me!
I bothered those people!
What happened!
I fell from the bike!
You stupid!
- My head is turning and turning..!
That’s nothing...
- Right.. nothing..!
I talked to the doctor!
He said: ''A little shock!
A shock is a shock!
Yes but, if it’s only a shock...
then you are fine!
I thought: It may be big,
or small, got it?
Ok but he really specified:
''It’s a little shock!''
How much is little! It’s nothing!
Yes, but I can’t even raise
my head!
Don’t worry! Listen...it’s late.
Everybody is asleep.
I go away.
See you tomorrow.
Ok, ok. Can you give me some water?
I’ve something in my throat...
Here it is!
- Thanks!
Ok?
- Yes!
I am going.
Don’ worry, ok?
He said it:' It’s nothing...''
- He doesn’t know!
He knows! He’s a specialist!
He speaks German!
German?!!
- He’s German. He speaks German.
He says: ''DO NOT WORRRRY!'',
with all those German ‘‘rrrr’’!
I think he is...!
You know, those people...
Talking about the doctor...
what do you think about him?
Why you ask me?- - He’s fine,
but I think he’s too much...
He was nice to me!
- Was he? Alright then!
Why you ask?
- Nothing! I just think he’s too much...
Too much...always with that ‘rrr’...
really German...you know!
Did he take something out of his pocket?
Nooo! That’s his finger!
His stiff finger, like that!
As long as it is just the finger, so what?!
- I know, but he always keeps it...
that piece of finger
so German! ..That finger...
Don’t scare me!
I am going to stay all night here!!
No, it’s just his finger!
- Don’t say anything then!
I insist...to be true...he always keep it...
but he wasn’t threatening...
it’s just a finger... German or Italian!
- That’s the same!
I am going then, ok?
Ehe!
- See you tomorrow.
I still have that appointment.
I ran here!
- Be patient, give me some more water,
please! It’s not going away...
Did it?
- I think so.
Listen, the important thing is...
...I was a little scared...
But this German guy told me..
I mean...he has that finger..
but he’s really comforting!
Ok? In any case
tonight you have a bed!
You saved 7000 liras!
My head is still turning!
- Be quiet, don’t worry!
See you tomorrow!?
- Yes!..Fine...some more water, please!
More water...
- What do you have?
A thing in my throat is not going away!
Did it?
- I think so!
I ran here..Frank told me.
He said to go.....
You’re right...
- Don’t worry..It’s a little shock
He’s German, but his finger..
Everything will be fine, ok?
- Don’ worry...
Be good! Don’t scare me!
I am going...the bottle is here...
in case you need!
Bye!
Do you want some champagne?
We celebrate!
Did you want to cheer?
No..I just wanted...!
You want to cheer!
Confess it!
No.. I always do that before...
nothing!.. Sorry, I wanted to cheer...
Where are you going?
- I need the restroom!
Listen Gaetano, your shyness
I think, is something
you hide behind..
you are always too worried
about yourself,
about what you do, what you say...
you think that everybody’s always
looking at you!
To spy you, to control you! And this
blocks you.
This is being arrogant, not being shy!
How can you think that people
has nothing else to do
other than taking care of you!
This is the way I am, I am weird!
No..no.
- Don’t you need to pee!
I mean..! When there’s somebody
around I can’t...
Why don’t you say that?!
I am closing the door!
But talk to me. Talk!
TALK!
When?..Now?
What time is it?
It’s two!
Damn! It’s late!
For what?
- For what?
Late for what..to sleep?
No...no..no!
Are you sleepy?
No, it’s late because...I mean..
two a.m. has always been late to me!
I remember...when I was home
some friends, with somebody..
at some point we said:
''What time is it?''
''It’s two am!''.. Wow! It’s late!
I mean.. at two am is always late!
Do you want to sleep here?
If not...it’s late...
Which side do you sleep?
It’s the same to me!
Then you sleep here.
Can I sleep here?
Sure.
- I am closer to the door, you know! I am more..
I go to the restroom!
Snifff!
(water flush)
It’s because you don’t trust yourself!
Come on silly, I know you’re not asleep!
But, before, I was sleeping, I swear!
Hey, we need more wine!
Raffaee, Raffaeee! Eeee Raffaeee..
Eee!
- Come here a moment!
I am eating!
The bottle is falling!
Thanks, Gianna!
Why don’t you come down!
I am eating!
Finally you have some wine too!
Are you from Naples?
- Yes, but I am not an immigrant.
No, no. Just pointing out as if
Naples people can’t travel!
As if they just immigrate!
Can’t you just travel!
Naples people travel, that’s normal!
Gaetano, I was thinking...
I could sleep at Frank’s...
What do you mean you sleep
at Frank’s!
I sleep at Frank’s!
Listen: at Frank’s you
have a bed, right?
I have a bed at Frank’s...
So, since you have a bed,
we could do this:
I lay on the top, you lay
on the feet side, and we fit well!
Frank’s bed is so small:
you on the top side
and me on the feet side!
That’s easy!
I can get very small!
The same way you get light on the bike!
What do you mean, didn’t I
get light?
Raffaele, please, sit down!
We talk about it later...go away.
But I am spending a lot of money,
you understand!?
What money! Sit down!
We talk later! Damn!
I can’t understand...if you have
a tractor in the countryside that doesn’t work!
I think that’s impossible..
hey, Gaetano...
Do you still do the same thing?
Do you still insist!
But, if you can move it,
what’s the purpose?
What’s the purpose?
I fix everything! Tv people
start coming,
the reporters! Everybody says:
''You are the one that...
can move objects?
Move that.'' You pay..
Ya, right! As if they would pay you!
- Why not!
That would be a great thing..
the scientists would come here!
All the important people say:
''We want to study your case..
You can move objects.
Move this...!'' You pay!
It will become a job,
because, I think, it might
involve the government,
I mean the Government should create a job
like this, about having powers,
moving objects,
read the mind,
all this strange things! It should give it
to all the southern people,!
Everybody moving objects, having powers...
as the jobs created for the industry...!
Why don’t they give us those powers!
But the Government will never do that..
it would keep those powers for itself!
Ok, but give us some industry!
Just something, to make money!
Nowadays industry is powerless,
what can you do?!!
Nothing! Just being satisfied!
Just to say: ''I had the industry,
I had something too!
Just to be contented!
Come here, damned you!
Why don’t you come here!
Marta, if I would look like that...
would you love me anyway?
Yes.
And you, if I would look like that?
Like what?
Like that!
You look like that!
You are ugly!
If we make a baby.. you like that
and me like that! He would be a monster!
No, no..no. If we make a baby
he should be beautiful!
Ok. I like the idea.
How do we make he?
The eyes. Your eyes or my eyes?
Mine!
Yes, they are nicer..!
The nose?
- The nose...
My nose. Yours is too big!
Yes, I have this thing...!
My son that...
- Wait, be serious...
The mouth...
- The mouth can be...
No, no no, it’mine!
- Then I am shit!
Nothing I have is good!
Only the ears!
Your mouth is too narrow!
My mother says that people
with narrow mouth are mean!
That is nonsense!
I heard it many times
this thing of the narrow mouth!
I know somebody with such a huge mouth.
He killed father, mother, grandma!
If they wouldn’t stop him, it would’ve been a massacre!
A huge mouth...!
You now what’s really important?
Really, if we make a baby)
(ring)
..One moment.!
Who’s that?
- Hi, I am Lello!
Hi. Are you coming up?
Can I talk to Gaetano?
- Do you want to come up?
Yes, I’ll do that. Can I talk to Gaetano.
- Ok, wait..
It’s Lello.
- Is he coming up?
No. He wants to talk to you:
Better if you go to the restroom,
Lello has a narrow mouth!
Lello...Lello...
Lello...
Gaetano...
He’s behind the door!
What are you doing?''...
I was downstairs, I thought:
''I will go up..''
- You always do strange things!
I should come up and I did it!
Either you just say I wait,
or you say I come up!
You can’t do both things
at same time:
first you ask to talk on the phone..
then you decide to come up!
That’s nice here!
You found a good place!
Ash-tray, record, telephone.
Hello.. hello hello...
Raffaele shut up,
can’t you see it’s fake!
It’s not connected. Hello!
What’s the point of having
a disconnected telephone!
It’s a decoration!
Doesn’t it work?
- No, it doesn’t, it’s a decoration!
And the radio? Does it work?
- No. It doesn’t work too!
No, please Raffaele don’t touch
anything! It’s breakable!
It doesn’t work and it does...
It’s a decoration!
They’re just decorative things.
Why should you touch everything!
Why don’t you put something
in these bottles!?
They’re all empty!!
- All empty!
Some water would fit it!
- No, don’t touch anything!
She’s in the restroom...
she’ll see you touch everything!
It’s decoration...
she come out and you are...
Damn!
- I do nothing, I’m just looking!
You’re early this morning!
- So what?
It’s nine and and you’re already here!
- I had a walk...
You had a walk?! Just think!
And where did you end up to? Just here!
Just on our door!
- No. I came un purpose!
On purpose! I thought
you were passing by!
On purpose! Instead,
I was sleeping,
Sleeping? At nine...!
- Damn, what’s your problem!
Your hands are everywhere.
- That’s not true...
Don’t touch, please.
If she comes out...please!
It’s not my fault if I am so early!!
The lady knocked on my door
at 6.30:
''Did you decide?
Are you keeping the room or not?''
I said: ''No, no! I am leaving also my bag!''
I thought: ''Maybe I’ll find
a place...
or you could find it''
I would save 7000 liras..
- Me, find a place for you!?
7000 liras! I am in Florence
... just as her guest...
and should find a place for you!
If you can’t find it, who can?
- I am a guest, I can’t!
Damn! That’s true! I thought
it was a decoration!
And this too?!
- I come here, who know how..!
Your problem is that you’re
a difficult guy, Raffaele!
You are difficult! Otherwise
Marta could have a place...I mean
A bed where she works!
Is there the chance of a bed?
I mean..where does she work?
She said there’s a bed available...
Something like..
- Don’t worry then! Alright.
To me whatever is fine!
Don’t worry!
Where does Marta works?
A place nearby, she works...
What’s her job?
I told you, a place nearby!
A place where you can sleep..
Really close!
Ok, I got it. But what is it,
an industry?!
No, no, no...
- Is it an office?...
Not really, its a place...
- Industrial?...
It’s place where she goes, I mean
it’s her real job..
like... I mean..
as if she were...
I mean! She goes there...
- Right...,
Does she work there?!
- Yes.
It’s really close!
And then?
- Raffaele, why you’re so close?
There’s so much space,
and you walk just behind me?
You’re stuck to me,
I don’t feel at ease!
Take it off your hands!
Put it somewhere...
Put it there. You’re walking around
with that thing in your arms!
You are inside the house.
Can you see thieves?
Nobody will touch it, put it there!
I just don’t want to forget it,
you understand?!!
Ok, you are so difficult! I knew!
I told you it’s a place nearby!
You keep on saying: ''nearby!'',
but what’s her job?
I am just telling you!
You pretend you don’t understand!
I don’t understand? You didn’t say!
I am telling you she goes there
and she is a kind of nurse...
Ah! Then it’s an hospital?
It might be!
It might be?! Is it or not?
This place..where normal people go
first of all normal! Normal people!
Normal. Normal people!
Just keep it in your mind for the future,
when you will understand...
Normal people...go there
and then...
Nothing..you get it?
all normal people that sometimes...
But:..normal!
You don’t think. if one of them
talks to you...just ignore him!
Normal people
- ...normal people?!
Sometimes...!
I mean..like you! Are you normal?
But it happens...to people sometimes!!
What is it? Gaetano, what is it?
Normal but...you understand!?
That is not...
- What do they do?
Sometimes, Raffaele, you got it!
- What?! Do they dance! What?
Dance! Normal people,
that sometimes...!
you got it!!!
- What is it, an asylum?
Not really... Go away!
And for 7000 liras
I should go and sleep
with ‘‘normal’’ people!!
''Michele has been cheated,
forgotten.
Michele couldn’t understand
and forced me to lie,
Michele was to me
somebody far away.
He was somebody that I love
and I was loved from
but he wanted to possess me
with the blindness of a child.
(RING!)
- Stay there...
You go on, I’ll open the door!
hi..sorry..nothing, hi!
Hi!
Then?
- Finished.
Who’s this?
- I sit there...
(friends chatting)
Not in front of TV!.
No, wait..what are you doing?!
Do you think God is going to appear?
God!..That is second channel!
Ok, let us go on, ok?!
Do you feel? Or shall we continue
tomorrow at your place?
No, no. Go on.
We finish the chapter.
Well…''he wanted to possess me
with the blindness of a child.
I would have been part of his jealousy,
of his damned evidence that,
as he said, are true.
Better be a liar and pretend
he wouldn’t know,
he wouldn’t understand. I was making love.
This is what I was thinking,
while Vanni wasted his sweetness
on my body,
embittered by my mind flying away!
Vanni was young,
he was younger than me
with a tenderness not yet hardened
by life failures!
I wanted so much to make love to him
as he was so sweet and childish.
Maybe I was looking for a son,
and not for a lover!''
So! What do you think?
I think this part is too much..
- No, no. I like it..
go on...
- No, it’s nice! I like it too!
I like it because, I mean,
it’s all invented!
This fantasy that people can
invent...from nothing..!
I mean... it’s not true, is it?
Because...you know.. it’s not true?!
But still there is imagination,
got it?...
I like this power of fantasy!
Well!: ''We looked for
a place to make love,
always lost to get together on a bench,
at the bus stop,
and now that we found it,
I was thinking to something else.
Maybe Vanni noticed it
and slowly, without asking,
he laid next to me.
I don’t know why,
but then I hugged him tight,
so tight!''..
In my opinion, writers are liars!
You say it’s all fantasy
but it’s really not!
It’s all true! What about Dante!
Didn’t he know Beatrice!?
And Leopardi? He really knew Silvia!
So! It’s all true!
Leopardi knew Silvia!
Shut up! That’s nonsense!
So, you think that poets, writers...
I mean..we don’t care about what you say!
I mean..do you all guys really care?
You always interrupt!
Harmony, atmosphere!
You’ve always something to say!
That’s just fantasy! why people
start writing, then?
In my opinion,
to tell things that happen to them!
Again! You insist...damn!
He was right, that guy,
to say that you are stupid!
What? Who said I am stupid?
That guy..Marco!
Marco, did you say I am stupid?
Not at all!
What? Didn’t you say that Lello is stupid!?
Come on!
I heard...not that
Lello is stupid!
I said something like...
I heard': ''I met so many stupid guys,
but none compared to Lello!!''
Anyway, that movie was terrible!
It really scared me!
But, if they’d torture you,
like in the movie,
would you talk?
- Yes! I wouldn’t need to be tortured!
It would be enough if they tell me,
for example,
''If you don’t talk
- maybe - we torture you''
I would immediately talk, write,
or make a drawing if they can’t understand!
So you’re worse than Judas?!
Not at all! But I can’t
really stand
physical pain!
It’s something...
what has Judas got to do with it!
Everybody says: ''Judas traitor!''
You should first know what happened.
Maybe Judas had a reason
to do what he did?!
Right?
- No. That was for money!
For money! Isn’t that’s a good a reason!
If he was rich all that mess
wouldn’t have happened.
That story...the murder,
the betrayal, forget it!
Because I.. If I don’t know people,
I don’t like to judge!
So! Just think...if you need
30 coins
how much could it be,
maybe two, three hundred thousand liras,
four hundred..maybe!
That might have fixed his problems!
Maybe he went home
and his wife: ''Judas
you must get a job!
The landlord! The electricity,
the water, the telephone...!''
At some point ''We need money,
we need money!''
He got those 30 coins and thought:
''I’ll fix my problems!''
That’s just an example!
Ok! Why don’t you tell this to Marta?
She might write a novel!
When she’s back, I am going to tell her...
Are you sleeping?
No
I knew!
- I knew you would say: ''I knew!''
What if I was really sleeping?
My eyes were closed,
my breath was regular...!
Yes! Too much regular!
My sleep is regular!
If you sleep regular,
the breath is regular too!
Is the book finished or not?
No! I am completely stuck!
Three wasted days at Silvia’s!
The book is still at the same point.
I am afraid I don’t like it anymore!
Maybe it makes me sick!
And what did you do?
Nothing. I took Lello to the station.
Did he left?
Left? He sped up!
He ran to Naples!
The pension increased from 7000 liras
to 8000...
He was on the edge of committing suicide!
You should have seen him!
He really ran to Naples!
Then, yesterday, I slept at Jann’s .
Ah! You had some fun!
Not exactly! We went to dinner,
first we went to the movies,
then we went to dinner, then
we went home, we talked,
just this. We watched TV.
Then, nothing...
Goodnight..Goodnight!
And we feel asleep!
What did you talk about?
Nothing..I mean.. we talked all the time
about you.
About me!
- Yes! About you!
Well, if you just talked!!!
And about me!
Then I am happy!!!
Maybe, considering all what we said
about being jealous,
I shouldn’t, but I am happy!
You know, when you told me
that you slept at Jann’s,
I felt something like...
jealousy,
and that worried me!
I thought: ''Now he will tell me
they had sex'',
and what will I do!?
I can’t think what
my reaction might be,
and this bothers me!
And you?
- Me what?
Did you...
did it ever happened to you...
...since we are together..
that ..for example..
did you have sex with somebody else?!
Yes!
You have nothing to say?
Nothing! What should I say!
Are you jealous?
- No!
Really not! We talked a lot about
being jealous!
I am going to the toilet!
What’s up?! You must...
What’s up? I mean...! ''Did you
have sex...?'' ''Yes!''!
What I can stand is...!!
This thing...inside..! Boom, it burst inside
of me! The way she said ''Yes''!
''Did you had sex with somebody?''
- ''Yes''! Boom...!
It will go away!...
People are free!! What are you going to do?
You started a relationship
and ..chains!
.. chains!
..She meets somebody and she has sex!
I meet somebody and have sex!
Then, if she asks to me:
''Did you have sex...?'' ''Yes''!
So boom, it will burst inside of her too!
I mean...she’s free! I will meet somebody,
if I ever meet somebody else...!
If, I meet somebody else!
I meet somebody and..''Did you have
sex?''..''Yes!'' ...Boom!
So disgusting!!!
Just tell me: ''I don’t know...''
''Yes''...Boom!
I will not show my feelings, I am going there:
''Goodnight'', ''Goodnight!''
I won’t say nothing, ok?!
Just as nothing happened!
Marta, what’s the name of who invented
penicillin?
Fleming!
- Fleming! Damn it!
I was in the toilet thinking ''
...What’s his name?
What’s his name!''
I can’t remember!
That’s bad because I had the ''f''...
and couldn’t remember Fleming. Fleming!
That’s bad when you can’t remember names!
Night!
Goodnight! Fleming, Fleming! Damn...FF
...goodnight!
It’s strange!
I am almost sad that you are not jealous!
I am so stupid!
How can it be possible that you
don’t care at all?
If I were you I would die
out of curiosity!
Aren’t you really curious?
Yes. Sure!
I am curious...but now
I am really tired!
I have an headache!
Thinking about that Fleming!!!!
FFF...I got an headache!
We’ll talk about it!
Tomorrow is better!
Goodnight!
What’s up, Gaetano?
Nothing!
- You are angry!
Why should I be angry!
That’s normal!
Don’t go!
- And what about the wedding?!
My father cares about it!
A week. You said you would leave
on Thursday!
I called this morning and he said
they are already preparing..
it’s better to go...
- Gaetano, if that’s because of
what happened last night, let’s talk!
Nobody says you can’t be jealous!
I am jealous too, just...
take it easy!
- ..Take it easy!
Yes...but for women is easier!
Take it easy...!
This the way women are.
You always act like this!
Right! It’s your way!
To us poor men, they always taught
about the honor...!
And beware the honor and the cuckoos!
All these things.
So...how can you ignore them!
For women it is easier!
Then you didn’t understand anything!
Since we are together,
I’ve been talking to walls!
Not at all!
That’s my problem!
I am trying to explain
that I can’t get free of some ideas...
I think, women are more..
- The women? Women what?
Calm down! I just said:
''Women are more..''
and you already get angry!
What if I said: ''Women are less!''
Would you eat me?
I am trying to explain!
Don’t be silly!
Don’t create problems!
Come on! We don’t need to fall
into these tricks!
We don’t care about what other people do!
When there’s love, there’s everything!
No, that’s health!
Friends, let’s make a gift
to the newly-weds!
Nice party!
What a nice restaurant!
How many people!
The tenant’s daughter got married here too!
This is why they are so rich!
Nice party, Gaetano!?
Yes, very nice!
- Things are going well!
We know!... We know what happens!
Gaetano, did I tell you!
The sinners on earth will be punished!
In Heaven there’s somebody
who will take care of that!
Somebody specially appointed!
Isn’t that true, don Gino?
And I am sure that the poor man
has many other things to do,
punish this, punish that,
and sometimes he makes mistakes!
Then he goes up and says:
''I am sorry, my mistake!
I was punishing somebody,
don Ugo was coming by,
what should I do?'' And they:
'' Don’t worry,
we’ll take care!''
and just in that moment,
the miracle pops out. Got it?!
Yes, yes!
- If I would have stayed
in my old house,
I would have got a miracle too!
How do you know you can’t still get
the miracle in the old house!
This is why we are losing time, got it?!
Ehi, Ugo!
- I’m coming! Sorry don Gino, coming..
I know!! You think we’ll
drive him crazy!
Nooo! He will heal!
He’ll get back his hand! I know!
Gaetano, I tried to explain to him
there’s no punisher..
he thinks it’s an accident,
but it’s not even a punishment,
it’s a gift!
Don Gino, is it ever possible,
that you always exaggerate!
First you call it miracle!
Now it’s a gift!
This is the way it is, my son!
They award the ones who feel
closer!
The ones they love!
And so the death should be accepted
as a divine gift! We should offer to god
all these small sufferance...
and be thankful to have been chosen
for this gift!
Just explain to me, don Gino,
is my father going to hell
if he won’t accept the gift!
young people don’t believe to anybody,
nowadays!
I should pray also for you!
No! Don’t bother, don Gino, please!
I might receive a gift too! Don’t bother!
No, wait, why?
Gaetano, I think I am pregnant!
What!.. Pregnant?..
- Wait…there’s something else...
I am not really sure it’s yours!
I am not looking for a father,
or an husband!
I just want this baby with you,
or I’ll grow him up by myself!
Who is he?
Gaetano, I don’t care for him at all!
I love you!
Is it the kid of...your novel?
The one who wasted his sweetness...
- Yes!
Damn..! What I am going to say to Lello!
Damn! He told me!
And he didn’t even know her!
I am so stupid!
How old is he?
- I am not going to tell you!
Why? Is he 8 years old?!!
Seven, six...! How many?
- Seventeen!
Seventeen! Ok, maybe..
at 17 a boy  already can...
Is he already a man at 17?
I don’t remember...
And what does he think?
He doesn’t know!
Right, he might have a son
and he just goes on with his life, no problem,
all the problems to me!
What!
- Damn, it’s blood!
Let me see!
- Damn!
Are you sure...
- About what?
That you want this baby with me!
It’s because I love you..
that I wish everything..
so! anybody...
would say:.
''Listen, I have a son
with him, but...
I want to stay with you,
because I love you, I like you!
I would like to have
a baby with you!!!''
It doesn’t matter who’s son is that!
As long as you want it..!
I can’t do that...
Alright! It’s a different
culture...
I can’t say: ''It doesn’t matter!''
How can I be sure this is my son?
Just wait until he grows up.
If he looks like an ass-hole,
then it’s yours!
Let’s say this baby..
How would we call him?
Well...I don’t know yet!
Massimiliano!
No..no..no! Please!
Not Massimiliano...
we can call him..
if we decide this baby will be mine...
I thought about ''Ugo''..
Like your father?
Yes, but I don’t care about it at all!
That’s just because with that name
he’ll be a polite guy.
What’s wrong with Massimiliano?
Massimiliano is naughty!
I know about that!
That’s a naughty name!
If.. Massimiliano for example,
Massimiliano his near his mum,
and then feels like moving away,
the mum takes longtime to call him back:
''Ma..ssi...mi...li..aa..no!''
he’s already running away!
He won’t obey, that’s too long!
But if you call him: ''Ugo!'',
he’s near his mummy
but he won’t have the chance to move...
As soon as he does it :''Ugo'',
and he’s back right away!
Because he catches his name!
Maybe, if you really want,
we can call him
''Ciro''! That’s longer...
so he won’t grow up too restrained!
So: ''Ciro''..and he can take
a little breath!!! That’s it.