When Oh Jak Doo didn't say
anything...
and ran away to the countryside,
that's when you were supposed to
watch a movie with me.
You are not going to make me
wait again, are you?
No, no, no!
Never!
I met Gyeong Sook and her husband
at the broadcasting station.
Jae Hyung said we should
buy them dinner...
since the documentary
went well.
What should we do?
We can watch the movie tomorrow.
Do you want me to go there?
(Do you want me to go there?)
No, it's okay.
(Episode 23: Marriage is
having someone you always care.)
I thought you are going to be
here at night.
My student doesn't have
sensitive hands.
So I was worried.
Aren't you here because you are
not meeting Seung Joo anymore?
Why are you looking at me like that?
Because I don't even know
where to start.
Right...
I dropped by the broadcasting
station this morning,
and I knew you wouldn't be able to
see the movie with her tonight.
I knew she was going to ditch you.
Did you meet Seung Joo?
No, I just heard something
at the broadcasting station.
What is it?
Well, the documentary
was successful.
Of course, it's positive news.
It's just a problem that
you don't know what I know.
Don't talk around and
be complicated.
Can you not go back
to the countryside?
Can you just live in Seoul?
Han Seung Joo is the only one
who can suggest that to me.
You can't do that.
It looks like she can't say it
even though she wants to.
- That's why I'm saying this to you.
- She and I can...
talk about everything.
Then how did you not know that she
got the job offer from the station?
You know how much Seung Joo wants
to work at the broadcasting station.
- Of course, I know.
- She can do it now.
But she's supposed to go to
the countryside with you.
I'm sure that's why she couldn't
talk about it freely.
That's why I'm telling you
about it in advance.
Are you Seung Joo?
If there's any good news,
she'll tell me first.
If she's concerned about anything,
she'll also tell me first.
Who do you think you are
to have these unnecessary worries?
I was just...
You know you have to focus
as much as you can...
and that's not even enough
to be better than now.
Do you think you can make one
proper gayageum before you die...
when you are this distracted
by everything?
Hold the wood
and think about yourself.
Let me pick up the phone first.
Hello?
Oh, Mrs. Park!
Did you finish the paperwork?
Excuse me.
I see.
Really? If you look at the file...
I'll see you at the office.
- Take care.
- Take care, sir.
Take care, sir!
Jae Hyung, I have to go.
We are going to go get some coffee.
Why don't you join us?
I'll do that next time.
Bye! I'm going!
But...
She can take the job
for our new project.
We don't know if she's going to
work with us or not yet.
Who can say no to the position
at the broadcasting station?
That's where she always came to
get confirmations for her work.
We can just make a new team
for the new project for her.
Should we?
Sir!
Yes, Han Seung Joo?
Excuse me.
I couldn't tell
you about it properly...
when we were in the restaurant
because there were other people.
I thought about it a lot.
But I came here because I thought
it would be better...
if I told you what my opinion is.
Tell me what it is.
First, I would like to thank
you for proposing...
such a wonderful opportunity for me.
I heard you applied
for a job at our station before.
But my situation changed...
a little bit since then.
So...
You might think that I'm rude,
but could I work
by contract for each program?
There are some producers
who work by contract like that.
If you could consider my situation,
I can work harder than anyone else.
The reason why I'm trying
to recruit and hire you is...
because
our organization needs you.
I see.
I don't know what happened
to make you turn down...
such a great opportunity,
so take care of that.
I'll wait to hear good news.
Think about it and contact us.
- Okay.
- Goodbye.
Where are you?
Home.
("Home")
("I'm sorry that...")
I'm sorry that I couldn't keep...
my promise to watch a movie.
It's okay.
I didn't keep my promise back then.
I think I'm going to be
a little late today.
I'll wait.
Okay.
What is the world like?
The world?
It's frustrating.
The world...
labels me...
the minute I leave home.
Woman,
born from poor parents,
and graduated
from a third-rate university.
Do you know how hard...
it is to remove
even one of those labels?
You have to be
cowardly at least 1,000 times,
and get rid
of your pride 10,000 times.
Still then, you're not even sure
whether that will be enough or not.
But...
if I do a good job on this project,
I'm going to hide...
all of those labels
behind my name, Han Seung Joo.
Then it ended up to be...
better that Seung Joo
didn't get that job that time.
Of course.
Recruit and hire,
doesn't it even sound special?
Remember that producer Jeong gave
us the worst time...
when we went to the broadcasting
station to get confirmation.
Show him how good you are
and defeat him.
Do you think I'm going to the
broadcasting station for a revenge?
When you applied for that job last
time, producer Jeong criticized...
you the most for not having
a documentary on your filmography.
You took care of that.
The world is in your hands.
Of course. What should we eat?
This isn't a normal celebration.
I decided
to go to the country with him.
What?
After the documentary,
we're going to live
in the country together.
What will you do in the country?
I can come to Seoul sometimes...
if someone requests a job.
So does that mean that
you rejected that offer?
I didn't yet.
To be honest, I became greedy.
That's not greed.
If people knew how hard
you worked to remain in this field,
they wouldn't ask
you to keep your promise.
I have to be separated from him.
Tell him to live in Seoul together.
After watching the documentary,
even I wouldn't be able to say that.
When I got the offer,
it was my dream,
but I wanted to do it more
because of realistic reasons.
What kind of realistic reasons?
If you have 2 or 3 years
of work experience...
at a broadcasting station,
it is more stable...
to work as a freelancer
in the country.
It would also be
easier to get shows.
Seeing that she's thinking
like that,
she must have really decided to bury
her bones in the country.
Oh, my. What should we do?
Doesn't Hyuk know yet?
No.
I'm not confident of being
separated from him.
It's my greed...
to ask him to live in Seoul.
I can't see his face yet...
because I haven't organized
my thoughts yet.
How can I tell him?
You should decide with your head,
not your heart.
You won't be able to stand
giving up all of your work...
and live in the country
only because of Hyuk.
She's not giving up.
I wish Seung Joo would be
with him more...
and work less.
You can't survive only with dreams.
Aren't you going to make money?
Don't you remember how happy
Seung Joo is when she's with him?
I know, but she's not in
a situation...
where she can just be with him.
Still...
This is the news.
This is the subject
of the piano recital.
Are you home?
Yes.
- No.
- That's not enough.
There's not enough food.
- Is it okay?
- No.
Should we eat?
This is really nice.
It's really delicious.
The sudden rescue request of a hero.
Yes, I'm being in the headlines.
You can see a square filled...
with impressive buildings.
How about...
getting married?
Why?
Are you not going to get married?
Not like last time.
When you first came to me...
and asked me to marry you,
and asked me to be your husband,
it sounded like you were asking...
me to save you to me.
But...
but it also sounds like last time...
today.
Why didn't you tell me...
about the broadcasting station?
I already know everything.
Why aren't you telling me?
I was just...
sorry.
Why are you sorry?
I thought I might not be
able to keep...
my promise to go with you.
Are you going to marry me...
to make me go back
feeling relieved?
I want to be with you...
rather than a marriage like that.
I'll be...
by your side.
I know how hard it is...
for you to be in Seoul.
That's my issue to take care of.
Gushing.
Do you remember?
Yes.
Why are you throwing it out?
Isn't it a good thing...
that you got to quit
that broadcasting system?
That's why I saved them.
Let's go outside.
Cheers.
I mean... It's...
Don't we have to cheers...
in a couple's manner?
I love you.
I have to say this...
when I really want to get married
to someone.
You're right.
So you're saying you're not going
back to the country?
I just switched my time there
to the one in Seoul.
It's not that I should
come back to Seoul when I need to.
I'll be going to the country
when I'm needed.
Is it because of Seung Joo?
No, it's because of me.
For what I understand, you are
the opposite of city life.
Instead of just missing Seung Joo
in the country,
I rather see her here...
and endure my life in Seoul.
Are you going to quit gayaguem
if Seung Joo tells you to do so?
What kind of rubbish are you saying?
Have you never been in love?
It's not that
I've never been in love.
It's just that I don't want to.
If it's compared to an unemployed,
it's not that I don't want to work.
I just don't want to be in love.
There's no condition to ask for.
Do you understand?
Why do you have to be like that?
Every woman thinks I'm just a fool
with a lot of money.
My friends think of me as a saint,
but they'd just talk behind my back.
They're all fake.
Then what's real...
in your life?
Hey, Mr. Choi. How many
times do I have to tell you?
Oh Hyuk doesn't want to do...
any interviews including...
Just tell him that you'd do it.
I've already paid off all the debts.
The debts
I'm paying off from now on...
will be a debt of gratitude.
I'll call you back.
Instead, I'll leave...
a real gayageum in your life,
so get prepared for it.
Is that how he seduced Seung Joo?
Is that how?
- Let's go to work.
- I'm on my way!
What is it?
Who are you?
You startled me.
You don't look like Seung Joo
I know.
It's because I have to take
an ID photo.
Stop staring. Let's go already.
It's going to rain.
We're going to be late. Hurry.
What? Watch the road.
This won't do. Pull the car. Hurry.
Move over.
Honey.
- Stop it.
- Just drive.
Concentrate on driving.
Pull your chin a little.
Stare to your left.
Smile a little. I'm going to
take it. In 1, 2, 3.
- It's all good.
- Thank you.
That's good.
What? What is it?
Could you take us two?
Oh, no. It's okay. Don't.
- Thank you.
- What?
Okay. Here we go.
In 1, 2, 3.
This is the list of documents
you need. So prepare them.
The official appointment
will take three weeks.
Okay. Thank you.
I wanted to show you this first.
Thank you. And I'm also sorry.
Don't be.
Gosh, you startled me.
The 12 of them are done.
I've never pulled an all-nighter.
I've done enough, so I'm leaving.
Are you telling me to sit down?
My goodness.
The specialized sound in gayaguem
is never possible with this aspect.
They all need to be
in the same shape...
in order for gayaguem to play
in a synchronized sound.
Gosh, they're all in the same shape.
It's as if they're mechanized.
They all look the same.
It's just one.
It's just that one that's
in different size.
Sir, excuse me.
It takes four hours to carve this.
Do it again.
Most of documentary shows
regading Chuseok contains...
a story of people visiting
their hometown.
How about we twist it a little?
Instead of visiting the hometown,
there are many who just
try to survive in Seoul.
That's a good idea.
Chuseok.
The original one sounds so boring.
There's no similar document
in this world.
There needs to be a new perspective.
Look for more related
documents online.
Yes, sir.
I'll collect the documents found
on magazines and personal documents.
I have ones ready.
- You're so well-prepared.
- That's great.
This is called a double-resonance.
Double-resonance.
- Fit it right into its position.
- All right.
Hold on.
You're making a hole in it?
Why don't you use this?
All right. I'll put it down.
Insert this here.
Insert it and then pull it tightly.
I see.
You need to have a good ear
to differentiate good sounds...
Sir, the reporters are...
Get out.
For it to have a good sound,
you need to have a good ear.
All right.
That way,
you'll become an artisan
who can make good instruments.
All right.
Making a proper instrument...
as an artisan means...
you'll have to be responsible
for yourself.
That tells how deep that person's
life is.
Now,
you'll have to manage
everything on your own.
I know that.
What happened
to Grandfather's seal...
Here.
The reporters are waiting.
CEO Eric.
This is the first gayaguem of
Mr. Oh Geum Bok's seal.
Have you prepared any special
event for it?
There's no other interview
prepared today.
You're going to make gayageum
yourself...
and continue the legacy
of Mr. Oh Geum Bok.
Are you going to collaborate
with Oh Hyuk?
Hold on. If you're done
taking photos,
shall we wrap this up?
Can we get a separate interview
with Oh Hyuk?
Is there a special reason his
grandfather left the seal with you?
I'm sorry. Let's make another
appointment for interviews.
Gosh, I think I've seen the document
about plan somewhere.
I got it!
Grandma.
Isn't it the season for harvesting?
I bet it's really green...
to see it whenever you go out
to the town.
I bet it's full of the scent
of lilac.
It's hard to smell that scent here.
I've never noticed how the spring
has gone by.
Are you sleeping?
Why are you here?
Why are you asking me that?
Gosh, I'm busted.
It's hard to find a place...
to lie down here like this in Seoul.
But I can see the mountains
from here,
and it's not suffocating.
It's nice to come
whenever I want to relax.
If you want to go back
to your place in the country...
I become a fool without you.
Where would I go without you?
What if I'm next to you?
Then...
I'll be another type of fool.
Gosh, come on.
- What do you want?
- Gosh.
Get out already.
It's not that I asked you
to pay for everything.
Why don't you let me get a car?
How can I have a thief
inside my house?
Besides, you're full
of unrightful thoughts.
I've given up on you.
I can't handle you anymore.
- You can get out.
- What?
Excuse me,
for people to raise
a kid thesedays,
it's a must to have a car.
Yes. I told her that she can
use my car if she needs to.
When a kid has to go to a hospital
and you're away with the car,
what are you going to do?
If that's your logic,
those without cars can't bring
their kids to a hospital, can they?
I mean, why to have no hope?
We need to have hope in order
to improve...
Of course. That's right.
But for someone like her,
it's hard to have hope.
It's a relief if she doesn't
hit rock bottom.
How can she have hope?
What if she ruins everything?
I mean, she needs to keep herself
positive, doesn't she?
How can you say that?
You should get out with her.
What? What did you say?
Well...
You can't do this.
What? You think we can't?
This is why you can't have a kid.
Hey, Jeong Mi.
- How dare she...
- How dare...
- Have you seen her?
- Don't be like this.
Don't do this.
What are you doing?
Come with me.
- Hey.
- Come with me.
- Wait.
- Let go of this.
- Come with me.
Yong Min.
Jeong Mi.
Mother, where are you going?
I'll get my stuff
when Yong Min isn't here.
Just so you know.
Darn you.
- Let's go.
- Wait.
- Gosh.
- Excuse me.
Goodness.
Honey, were you harsh on them?
Why would they talk about
packing their stuff?
They'll probably spend a day or two
in a dry sauna or something.
She's done that before,
don't you know?
Honey, let's go back
to the infertility clinic.
I thought you didn't mind
having no child.
Honey, I can't stand...
Jeong Mi bragging about her
having a kid.
- Are you being jealous?
- What?
Anyway, let's make an appointment.
Oh, that flyer from the desk.
Give me that number again.
What's the number?
- Excuse me.
- Hello.
I can't read this.
Could you read this out for me?
You're not supposed to let
anyone read your security card.
Who's the person you're talking to?
They said the money in my account
keeps getting out.
The policeman told me so.
Give it to me.
Hello? You're working hard
scheming a grandma, aren't you?
Aren't you voice phising?
Then let's exchange names.
I'm a police officer too.
Since we work in the same field,
let's exchange names.
- Well...
- Gosh.
What should I do?
What's wrong?
Hold on, Jeong Mi.
Don't waste your time on this,
and get a grip, you jerk.
Grandma,
just hang up when you get a call
like this, okay?
Thank you.
- Come on.
- What's wrong?
I ran away from home.
- Go back in.
- I don't want to.
You'll only have a hard time
if you run away from home.
- Hurry. Go back.
- Don't push me. No.
Mom suddenly visited, so I think
I should have dinner. Is that okay?
Okay.
I won't be too late, okay?
Seung Joo.
I'm going.
Ever since I started
living at his home,
I've never had a chance
to have a proper meal.
How can he be so mean?
I can have this kind of meal since
you're hired, right?
Eat up.
This tastes so good because
it's expensive.
I'm so glad that you're not like
any other moms.
What do you mean?
When I was young, I talked
about this with my friends.
I told them that my mom likes
the middle part of fish.
So they thought I was weird.
Their moms all liked eating
the heads of fish.
Are you talking badly of me?
I felt bad when I was young,
but now that I think of it,
if you only sacrificed for me,
I wouldn't have felt so easy
like how I'm feeling right now.
Are you being sarcastic about how
I shouldn't expect so much from you?
Before, I used to take care of
your living expenses...
and Seung Tae's school fee...
that I never found joy in working,
but now it's different even though
I'm working the same job.
I don't expect much from you either.
So please just get married...
before Jak Doo sees
the real side of you.
Don't judge me.
I'm just being honest.
What? Is it a crime to want
a rich son-in-law?
Is that such a crime?
He has an unrivaled skill.
- He can just...
- He's...
someone who should not
care about money.
Even if we get married,
I'll be the one earning.
- What did you say?
- So...
please don't tell me
to get married,
thinking he'll bring us a fortune.
I won't sacrifice myself for you,
but I will do my duty as a daughter.
Then why don't you give me
a monthly payment as a daughter?
Well, I'm getting good responses.
Our foundation...
Hey, wait. Excuse me, Seung Joo.
Hold on. I'll call you back.
Hey, what are you doing here?
- Isn't he at his workshop?
- Wait.
He is,
but while he was trying to teach me,
one of his musicians...
who was practicing visited him
as the string broke.
Oh, he must be fixing it now.
That's right.
So...
I think you can wait for him
with me here.
Can I not watch him
fixing the string?
That's not what it is.
The gayageum player is...
Jang Eun Jo.
What?
It's Jang Eun Jo.
Jang?
I'll go watch then.
What?
Seung Joo...
Silk strings are
really weak at humidity.
The hot weather loosens it a lot.
It's been a while.
Hi.
Is it going to take a while?
No, it's almost done.
If you try to tighten
the strings up too much...
to make sounds...
when they are loose,
they can break.
I know.
You have to have spare strings.
I see.
The body of your gayageum can be
a bit shaky during the performance.
So don't forget the rosin powder.
Thank you.
Eun Jo, if you are done,
I need to have a word with you.
Okay.
- I'll go.
- Good luck with your performance.
Hey,
Strings of Gayageum...
easily break during performances.
For some performances, gayageum
makers even stay at the backstage.
That's not what it is.
I feel a bit weird.
It's not because of Jang Eun Jo.
It's because of myself.
What is it?
It feels like...
I have...
forgotten about something.
Working at the broadcasting station,
I had a lot of things
I needed to take care of.
But working there was fun.
So I couldn't really think about
other than my work.
But how can I be like this?
Did something happen to you?
I've forgotten about...
who Oh Jak Doo really was.
They are the same gayageums
you've been making.
When we were filming
the documentary,
how you looked at the studio
in the countryside...
was very different from how you are
here. Did you know that?
No, I didn't know that.
You are at somewhere
you don't belong.
How can you not know?
I...
I chose to be here because
I want to be next to you, Seung Joo.
Is that right though?
Someone I like...
doesn't look happy at all...
when he's doing his job.
So I don't know if I should make you
stay here to be next to me.
I have to reconsider it.
About what?
Us.
You made the right decision.
You have to go if you have to go.
You've been holding on to
somewhere you don't like.
Just watching you is painful.
I'm going to be here
once every two weeks.
So don't forget your homework.
I told you I'll do it!
Do you not need anything
to bring there by the way?
What should I give you?
Do you want to take this with you?
Take this.
I live on the ground.
Why would I need that?
Do you live in a mud hut?
But...
it's the most comfortable
place for me to live.
You can take my car if you want.
I stay in the mountain
6 days a week.
So I don't need a car.
If I tell you to take it,
just take it!
Why are you yelling at me?
I express my affection
by spending money...
Money is the only thing I have.
Since I was young,
that's how I've been living my life.
So I can only feel comfortable
after giving you something.
You don't want the vacuum cleaner,
but you don't want the car either.
Well...
Should I just give you cash?
We are friends. We should know
how we feel even without a word.
I can feel your heart,
Eric Cho Bong Sik.
Is this enough?
Well...
You are the cool one
in this relationship.
This is when Oh Jak Doo
comes to Seoul.
And...
This is...
when Han Seung Joo
comes here.
From now on, we are going to be...
in a long-distance relationship.
Have you heard of it before?
Long-distance?
No.
It's a romantic relationship where
they are physically far away...
because of working overseas and
countryside, or studying overseas.
So even though we are far away,
nothing changes.
We live our own lives
at our own places.
Then?
We meet each other
just once a week.
And we don't see each other
forever again.
But we've become husband and wife
as soon as we met each other.
So what are we now?
We are dating.
When you arrive at your place,
the first thing you have to do is...
finding the best spot
for your phone to work.
8am and 9pm.
We are going to talk on the phone
twice a day.
That's the basis of
the long-distance relationship.
Hello?
Hi.
This is a bit awkward, isn't it?
Are you going to work now?
Yes, I am.
Did you have breakfast?
Yes.
You found somewhere
with the good reception!
That's the first thing I did
when I got here.
How's the weather there?
It's a bit sad that I have to
enjoy this alone.
I want to be there.
I miss you.
Me too.
Are we going to meet this Saturday?
- Yes.
- That's good.
(Guardian)
Your call is not connected.
Please leave a message.
(Hang Seung Joo)
I can't talk to you right now.
Sorry.
Where's Polaris?
I could find it quickly in Seoul.
You could find it soon there
as there are not so many stars.
You can't see it well here
as there are so many stars.
Do you know how bright it is here...
at a night with a full moon?
It's as bright as day.
That's nonsense.
You're ignoring me as I don't know
much about those things.
It that a phone call?
Where's my cell phone?
(Guardian)
(Han Seung Joo)
Are you really coming?
The express bus to the nearest city
is only at 10am and 3pm.
The last bus to the town is at 7pm,
so I'll take the 10am bus.
It's hard to come here
after you get off the express bus.
Can you come here all right?
Shall I pick you up?
After I get off the express bus,
I take the intercity bus.
Then I get off at Gucheon-dong,
take the bus again,
get off at Jachori,
and I walk to Ttasoonbaegi.
After that I take
the local bus again, right?
Now I can go there
even with my eyes closed.
We might miss each other
if you come too far.
Come to the town entrance
by the time I arrive there.
Do you get it?
Yes, I do.
(Seoul express bus terminal)
(Station manager Choi)
Hello, Mr. Choi.
I got back from a business trip,
and just saw the proposal
for the Chuseok special.
- Director Han, this isn't enough.
- What?
Now?
You should report to headquarter
on Monday.
So, you have to choose a new item
and make a proposal until tomorrow.
Let's talk about the details
in my office.
Excuse me, Mr. Choi, I'm now...
Mr. Choi. Mr. Choi?
This is driving me crazy!
(Guardian)
You'll be connected
to the voice mail...
Gosh.
(Culture production department
proposal, "Her Rest Area")
Your proposal is not exciting.
That won't bring out high ratings.
Mr. Choi, I'm off today.
If you change the item
so suddenly...
People in broadcasting don't have
a day off.
You're working 24 hours
until the program is on air.
You should know better than that.
The director of the headquarters
supports this item too.
Do you have to delay the briefing
on Monday because of a day-off?
I understand.
(Han Seung Joo)
(Grandma)
- Hello?
- Jak Doo.
You have a parcel delivery.
- A parcel delivery?
- Yes.
Han Seung Joo is the name
of that miss from Seoul, right?
Wait a minute.
I'll go there right away.
Gosh. My goodness.
- You will fall down!
- Gosh, I'm so good.
Goodness, you're so good.
Gosh. Goodness gracious!
- I knew it.
- The one who falls down is out!
Jin, it's your turn.
You threw it very well.
- That's it. Good.
- You're doing good, Jin.
Jin, you're doing great.
Gan Nan and Joong Rye,
you should do this instead of me.
Jin only wants to play with you.
Even though he's young,
he knows
you're the most energetic here.
I'm truly about to get ill.
- It's Uncle.
- What?
- Uncle!
- Hi.
- How have you been, Jin?
- Good.
Haven't you met Seung Joo?
- No.
- That means she didn't come...
- and only sent the delivery?
- What?
What's this?
Seung Joo sent it.
Hasn't she called you?
- No.
- What's inside?
By the way, you must be so sorry,
Jak Doo.
She must be so busy
that she didn't come.
What if she doesn't come again?
People feel like they would come
every day when they separate.
However, out of sight, out of mind.
That's what people do.
Don't say such a thing.
She must have been busy
that she couldn't come.
Could it be something
Jak Doo used in Seoul?
Goodness. I guess she got herself
sorted at last...
and sent it to him.
Stop saying!
The phone is turned off. Please
leave a message after the beep.
There will be charges
after the beep.
What's this?
Gosh.
It's great here.
(Han Seung Joo)
(Guardian)
The phone is turned off. Please
leave a message after the beep.
There will be charges
after the beep.
(Han Seung Joo)
The phone is turned off. Please
leave a message after the beep.
Here you go.
(Unanswered Call)
I think...
(Han Seung Joo)
The phone is turned off.
Pleave a message after the beep.
With this sad song
In my small heart
I want to become
One of the stars
And shine forever
(Han Seung Joo)
What is it?
I miss you.
Me too.
Oh Jak Doo.
I'm going today.
You're not supposed to come today.
Does that mean...
I can't go?
I didn't mean that.
Just wait.
I'll wait until you come.
Can I do that?
Yes.
Come quickly.