This film is based on a true story
Paul Krantz and Guenter Scheller
hereby describe the course of events,
so no misunderstandings may arise.
Tonight we will take revenge
Revenge on those we love
and who betrayed our love.
Then we, Guenter and I,
will depart this life with a smile.
That's the whole truth.
"That's the whole truth."
That's better than any confession.
You've become quite a celebrity
in a rather short time.
"Youths, Weary of Life,
Form Suicide Club"
"Two of Four Members Found Shot Dead"
"19-Year-Old Ringleader in Custody"
"Pathological Motives Suspected"
Tell me about the girl.
Did you...
...you love her that much...
Hilde?
You write here...
"I think that love drove me
to the ultimate step"
"There are girls of such...
...of such intensity
that one is powerless to resist"
What difference does it make now?
Did this "suicide club" really exist?
Were you the leader,
or was your friend, Scheller?
What does it matter?
How come you're still alive?
"Then we, Guenter and I,
will depart this life with a smile"
You don't know anything
LOVE IN THOUGHTS
Dear Universe,
It all started at school three days ago
FRIDAY
We had detention
That Friday was the first time Guenter
invited me to the Scheller's summer house
His parents were away and I was
looking forward to the weekend
OM SUICIDE
Mainly I wanted to see
his sister Hilde again
And Guenter?
I think he was already far away by then
Gentlemen...
You can leave now
It's beautiful
Bang, bang, old man.
You're dead
I hope my sister's here already.
So do I
Hilde!
Hilde-girl?
Maybe she's not here
Maybe she's at the beach?
I warned you!
Where's Hans?
What's eating you?
Come on, stop it!
If I find that guy, I'll kill him
I haven't seen him in two weeks.
Don't give me that
I can smell the cook in this house.
I fixed myself something to eat
What's he doing here?
Hello, Hilde
This is Paul Krantz, the poet.
You know each other
We've met.
That's possible
This is like paradise
I bet you've never even looked
into one of these books
So what?
I'm just saying
If I had this many books...
You can have them
They're all yours
What's this?
No idea. A weird horoscope
contraption of my mother's
Do you know how it works?
No. Hilde does, though
We talked about Jakob von Hoddis.
The poet
And Georg Heym
The time we met.
You still want to talk about them?
Is Hans your boyfriend?
What makes you say that?
Well, the way Guenter acted...
Hans, Hans...
Hans is just Hans
I thought they were such good friends
These days all he talks about is you.
He seems to think you're a genius
Want to row across the lake with me?
Dinner's ready!
I'd like to read something of yours
None of it's very good yet.
Maybe some other time
I'd like to now
"To Love"
I didn't ask you to stay.
But you stayed
I never asked you who you were
or what you wanted
You were simply there
What do you want from me, love?
Was I not stronger alone?
And did I ever need you?
But stay a bit longer.
Not long,
Just until they stop asking
how I am
And I stop saying, "Fine"
Everyone can tell at a glance:
You are here
If you ever leave me
I will go with you
And? What do you say?
Would you really?
If I loved the person, yes.
You believe in true love?
Can you think up another poem?
Now?
Yes. One just for me
What?
Why the smile?
A comely leg shows off a hem of pink.
What a lovely, saucy sight
Wonder what it might conceal, I think?
When I dare to ask, she pales in fright
My, my, Herr Krantz.
You're a naughty one
You want me to leave?
No, no.
I'm pretty tired anyway
I'll return the favour
Did I promise you too much?
Paul...
Come with me
SATURDAY
I'm going into town.
Why?
- I'm meeting someone...
... Elli?
Oh, stay here with Paul and me.
- You have a crush on him?
No.
He's a friend from school.
What about you? Do you like him?
We'll see.
- Hilde.
Yes?
- Promise to be back by 8:00.
Why?
- I have a surprise for you.
Bring Elli, Lottchen, Rosa,
and the others, too.
Yes, Great Manitou.
By 8:00 at the latest!
How's the water?
- Is Hilde up?
She's in town.
She'll be back tonight
Besides, she left something for you.
Let me see.
Come on, let me see!
This book with your heart you wrought.
A poet's soul you have, that's sure.
Dark ideas to capture you have sought,
but the rhymes are clear and pure.
Yet you are young and to me it seems,
that you are really just a boy
Who's known love only in his dreams,
And tarried too long to savour its joy
You'll fail to win the girl you sought
If your ardour in poems alone you show
What use is love only in thought?
When the time comes, you won't know
You should save your bullet, you know.
That's no reason the trigger to pull
Far too many tears would flow
It's just not worth it for such bull
What does she mean,
"Tarried too long to savour its joy?"
That you won't deliver
when it comes down to it
My sister's not one for theory
You think I should try
a more direct approach?
Yes
NO TRESPASSING
It's pretty obvious.
She writes:
"When the time comes,
you won't show"
"You won't know"
Maybe she can tell you're a virgin
Does she have a boyfriend?
I hope not.
Then why did she go to town today?
Cause she knows you're hot for her
and will wait for her all day
She wants you crawling to Berlin,
begging for a moment with her
She's crazy
Hilde likes you, trust me.
She has a thing for proles
Hey, jackass!
May I speak to Hans, please?
From the kitchen
It's me
I was out in the country.
With my brother, who else?
Your son's repeated unexcused absences
from class are a matter of concern
Is that so?
Don't make such a fuss.
I'm coming
See you later
Elli! Get changed,
we're going to the Mokka Efti!
What, so early?
Fine, I'll be right over!
The Mokka Efti is no fun anymore.
Who's coming tonight?
Some of Guenter's friends.
Rosa. Lotte... and Paul
He's coming, too?
Yes. Nice chap. Handsome, too
Maybe a bit shy, but...
He stayed the night with us
And?
Well, you know me
Maybe you'll find one, too.
Well, look who's here.
Oh, it's you
You're not dancing.
To that music?
May I join you ladies?
Go ahead. I was just leaving anyway
Perhaps you'd care to join us?
Some other time, maybe
What about you?
Just a teeny little glass?
At the next table...
All right
Hey, doll.
Hey, soup boy
I'd almost given up on you
Ten minutes, okay?
Where were you last night?
Wouldn't you like to know
Today I won't let you off so easy
I'll come over later.
You can't
I have to go back to the country.
I promised Guenter
Now that your parents are finally away,
your jealous brother has to spoil it
Tonight... I'm staying
I'm serious.
So am I
Are you in love with Hans?
I don't know
Such things quickly pass
Never to return
Maybe it's true...
...that people are only truly happy
once in their lives
Just once
And then they are punished for it
For the rest of their lives
The punishment is that
they can never forget that one moment
I think it's best...
...to say goodbye at the right time
Namely when you're the happiest
Precisely then
At the zenith
How quiet it is here
Dear posterity,
These are the statutes
of our suicide club
The members are
Paul Krantz and Guenter Scheller
First: The name of the suicide club
shall be Fehou
Second: Love is the only reason
for which we are willing to die
Third: Love is the only reason
for which we would be willing to kill
Therefore we swear to end our lives
once we no longer feel any love
And we will take all those along
who robbed us of our love.
At last!
I thought we'd have to bore
your friend with jokes all afternoon
Oh, it wasn't that bad
It's quiet today
Could it be that you're
not too unhappy about that?
At least that way you know
you'll be safe in this... jungle
I'm afraid I don't understand.
It doesn't take a Freudian
to see that your many
suitors scare you
That's why you prefer
to attack, right?
I don't know what you're talking about.
I can't believe that
I don't care. I have better things to do
than listen to you
Come, we must leave Herr Zipfer
to his insights
Excuse me, Hilde-girl.
I didn't mean to offend you
By the way,
your fear is quite understandable
What a bang! Not bad
They're crazy!
Would you stop that, you idiots!
Tell him to put on different music
Don't drink, open the bottles!
Why open them if we can't drink?
Watch, guys
Go ahead
Coward
It was just a bit of fun.
Nothing happened, after all
This is not a toy, Jango
If any of us is ready tonight...
If he's really happy...
He can go
And the others will help him do it
Why when he's happy?
Why not?
All right, everybody
Won't be easy to close that door again
My parents haven't been here in ages
Say, where's your sister, anyway?
No idea.
She should be here by now
I came to pick you up.
Sweet of you. Have you met Elli?
We met once. You were with Guenter.
We did?
Never mind. Elli's used to that
What's wrong?
Are you okay?
If you love someone, you love only him
But if you limit yourself to one,
he'll soon try to tell you what to do
You're at his mercy. If he doesn't want
you to study or work, too bad for you
You can like many fellows at a time.
This for one reason, that for another
I heard if you can't decide,
you become a lesbian
The emancipated ones are lesbian, right?
Right. And cola turns your feet brown
You're... a silly little one
The word "naive" doesn't even cover it.
This needs more sugar
I'm liberated, and for me, a handful of
men won't do. I want a whole land-full
You think committing equals weakness
You're talking nonsense
And later?
What about later?
No one will be there to take care of you.
Parroting what that idiot said, huh?
It's true, though
Oh. is that sweet!
Well, if you ask me,
love as we know it won't exist
20 years from now
We will progress
beyond petty possessiveness
We'll live in a free society
and all love each other
It's already like that in Russia
But that's awful! Why?
You have no political consciousness
You do whatever your parents tell you
. That's not true!
What do you know, anyway?
Hey, am I happy now? Do I have to go?
Hello, Guenter!
Hope I'm not disturbing you.
What are you doing here?
I heard rumours of pretty girls
Are you alone?
On the contrary
Look what I brought along
The green fairy!
Where did you get that?
Wouldn't you like to know.
Anyone up for a little trip tonight?
What shall we drink to? Paul
Try this
To the beauty of youth
To us
Have you ever had a girlfriend?
That was a sad story.
I see
Want to hear it anyway?
In that case, no
One, two...
And let it flow
Sadly, it's simple. People come
in two kinds: those who love
and those who are loved.
like my sister
That's not the problem.
What is, then?
How long have you known Paul?
I have no idea
For...
I don't remember
Which kind is he?
A bit of both, maybe
What a beautiful night
If we could stop time now...
Right now, at this very moment
It's perfect.
There's everything we could want
Let's just go somewhere
I told you not to show your face again!
Oh, come on
And leave Hilde alone!
Get out!
Get out of my life
Hey, what's going on?
There's thirsty people out here
Go away, Bittner!
Guenter?
Go on, scram
Get lost
Got you
You're so beautiful
I never want to belong to one guy only
Not even you
What use is love in thoughts
What are you doing up there?
The view is good from here
Want to come up?
I still have some left, if you like.
Did you drink all that by yourself?
When was it that we met?
This last winter. At the Mokka Efti
With Hilde and Guenter. And Hans
You were there that time?
We went to a movie afterward,
but you didn't come along
You were short on money...
But the others didn't notice that
Shit!
Hey, Hilde.
Not in bed yet?
How did  get here?
Took the zeppelin
Oh, you two know each other?
You're right.
It really is nice up here
What, Hilde,
no one loves you anymore?
No one loves me anymore, either
And no wonder
Want a ride to the city?
Why would I go to the city?
The party is past its prime.
You and your smart-aleck comments
The city, anyone?
It's going to rain soon anyway
Has anyone seen Paul?
Yeah, a while ago. With you, I think
Oh, God. My car
Hey, you old lush
Hey, Paul
How are you?
Hey, Paul, where were you?
Swimming
How about you, Paul?
Sorry, what?
I can tell your future
Come on, this is your chance
I don't believe in that stuff.
Afraid?
Nonsense.
Says you
Sit down
Only one question. The answer's
inside you, I just help you find it
Just one question.
So consider it well
Ask if you should become a teacher.
Right
How is that supposed to work?
It's a...
...horoscope-mobile.
It's controlled by your subconscious
Pipe down, everyone
It works through a kind of magnetism
You have your question?
Yes
Give me your hands
You have to concentrate.
Close your eyes
Everyone be quiet
Now pose your question
It's the Hermit
What did he get?
The Hermit
What does that mean?
Obvious. You'll be alone a long time
What's that got to do with my question?
That's your fate
What was your question?
Whether you'll outlive me, Macke
That's a bunch of baloney
Why do you all fall for her?
I'd sleep with you
Over there, in the woods
I know you have a crush on Hilde
But there's no need to pity me
I don't
You can go on ahead
SUNDAY
I'm going to school
There's no school today, Elli
Does the shirt fit you?
I'm kind of hungry, actually
Yeah, I'll go look in the kitchen.
I'm sure I'll find something
Anyone else want anything?
Hilde, can you come with me?
Don't feel like it
We have guests.
Come on, please
Listen, loser.
You can forget about my girl
She doesn't like schoolboys.
Oh, yeah?
Sorry, but could you maybe
look after Paul a bit?
So he isn't so...
Are you crazy?
Don't get all in a lather
Yesterday was swell, wasn't it?
And besides, I have the feeling
he's got a crush on you
So what if he does?
You're really...
I'm serious, Hilde
This is my last chance with Hans
I'm going to bed.
What? At 5.00 P.M.? Why?
I'll sleep in the master bedroom
Here, take this.
Now we can relax a bit
Where's your sister?
She went to bed
Why did she do that?
She was tired
You mean she's not coming back?
So? We can ask the others
to come by after school
It's Sunday.
Or we can ring at Elli's
She lives two doors down.
Crap idea
What's the matter with you two?
Ask Guenter what time it is
Go on, ask him.
What for?
Just do it
It's really hilarious
What time is it?
I've got to take a leak
Again?
Why? What time is it?
Paul, don't you want to hit the sack?
You can sleep here if you like
You can finish your beer first.
You're making such a fool of yourself
You think so?
It's me
What was that?
Hilde...
Never mind them
I'll protect you, don't worry
I think I love you, Hans
The zenith
If you go, I'm going with you
Paul Krantz and Guenter Scheller
hereby describe the course of events,
so no misunderstandings may arise
Tonight we will take revenge
Revenge on those we love
and who betrayed our love
Then we, Guenter and I,
will depart this life with a smile
That's the whole truth
Dear Universe,
A tiny piece of the whole will die
Don't be upset
You will barely feel the loss
of one cell being extinguished
Time rolls on
What is such a little life?
A brief flicker in the world,
then merely ashes and dust
I'm leaving
It's just not worth it
I'm going home
You left long ago
Hilde, open the door
What happened to you?
Where is he?
If you mean Hans, he's long gone
What did you do that for?
Morning. Oh, you're not dressed yet.
Morning
Hello. Elli
Hello
Come
What's wrong?
They've been acting crazy all night
I had to hide Hans.
He stayed the night
I have something to tell you, too
Guenter Scheller was my friend
probably the only one
That crazy night we agreed
that the four of us would commit suicide
The fact that...that I later didn't
...that I later didn't believe in that possibility anymore
doesn't change the fact that our thoughts were wrong
it doesn't change anything
The court will now withdraw for discussion
The hall shall be cleared during that time
The verdict:
The defendant Paul Krantz will spend three weeks
in jail for possession of illegal firearms
He is cleared of all other accusations
The time he already spent in jail during
investigation will be taken into account
Supplement by Guenter Scheller...
Dear space...
When we don't exist anymore,
nobody shall miss us.
Not even one tear shall be shed for us
If anyone may want to remember us,
he shall do it with joy.
Because it's like this:
we did the only right thing
...we lived
In 1931 'Die Mietskaserne', the first novel by Paul Krantz,
was published under the synonym Ernst Erich Noth.
On the 10th of May 1933 the novel was burned
by the Nazis during their book burnings.
Paul Krantz fled from Germany on the 5th of March 1933
and went into exile.
Hilde Scheller suffered what could be called a
witch hunt after these events.
Because of the obscene coverage about her
she was forced to leave the city.
She went on to become a librarian.
Elli never got married.