The best thing about my new school
is that I met an amazing girl.
A guy like you has no chance
with Charlotte Allen.
Oh, man.
Who I then accidentally freaked out...
Who you stalking?
No one.
And scared away.
Whoa, buddy.
You need to calm down.
Charlotte?
I'm not going to pretend the
Charlotte thing didn't hurt
my confidence.
Being ignored by girls is one thing.
Actively driving them away
is a whole nother animal.
But I was determined to press on.
And at least I hadn't lost the
support of my friends...
because I never had it.
You guys think I'm attractive, right?
You look like a hobbit that's
stacked on the shoulders
of another hobbit.
You're definitely not my type.
I can't tell.
But I'll ask around.
Start with your dad.
[Snickers]
Not cool, man.
I am attractive.
Charlotte saw it.
And if I hadn't scared her away,
the whole school would have
caught on.
But even my own mom didn't
think I was attractive.
Need a ride to school?
No, Simon's gonna take us.
I love that you have
this group of friends.
I think it really helps.
Helps?
You know, with the
pressures of high school:
Girls, so obsessed with
all the popular guys.
But don't worry.
When you go to college,
you'll meet someone who'll be
able to look past what's
on the outside and see
what's underneath.
You've got a great big heart.
Will, sexiness is something
that you're born with.
For me, it's like breathing.
You're attractive?
Uh, I don't know.
Why don't you ask the hottie
I've been raw dogging
for the last three weeks.
You mean this made-up girl that
none of us have ever seen?
Because she's a prostitute, dude.
She works at night and then
sleeps in my bed during the day.
So when do you have sex with her?
At night.
And her pimp is okay with that?
He should be, 'cause it's me.
[Chairs clang]
Ugh, there's my dad.
All right, come on.
Let's go.
He's not coming to beat
you with that is he?
Worse; He's gonna remind me of
our golf match this Saturday.
1:00 tee time, pal.
Bring your "a" game and your wallet.
[Chuckles]
You bring your "a" game, old man.
Oh, God.
Why me?
I thought you like golf.
I do, just not with my dad.
He can get a little... [grunts]
God damn it!
Like that.
I have to throw every
hole so he'll stay calm.
God damn it!
He's already got two strikes
at our country club.
Wait.
Your country club has a
jacuzzi, doesn't it?
Yeah, next to the pool.
Ah, this is gonna be perfect.
You have to get me in this weekend.
What about your made-up
plans with the prostitute
that doesn't exist?
I'll blow her off.
Let's go.
[Engine turning]
♪ Oh, my, my love ♪ my
little dove ♪ my honeybee
yeah, so you'd say it's
about 102 degrees, right?
Kind of steamy, but not overly hot?
I don't know, Jay.
It's a jacuzzi.
Why do you care?
I don't care.
I mean, we're sitting here
talking about nothing.
Maybe I'm not attractive.
Maybe I'm gonna be alone forever.
So is it tile or plaster?
I don't know.
Guys!
You're ignoring will.
Is it tile or plaster?
But even though my crappy friends
had no desire to help me,
destiny did.
[Soaring pop music]
♪
Charlotte.
[Sighs]
It's over, dude.
She de-friended you.
You can't come back from that.
Well, if she just spent some
time with me, I know I could
reel her in with my wit.
That's how you got me.
Charlotte is a hot piece of ass.
I'd definitely add her to my roster.
You're not a pimp.
Not if anybody asks.
And if they don't ask.
Hey, Charlotte.
Hey, will.
Will's friends.
Simon.
Blue Jay--bird.
Ja--the letter.
Neil Patrick Sutherland.
Uh-huh.
Senior slave auction?
Yeah, the senior's raise money
for the prom by auctioning
off the coolest guys and hottest
girls to the underclassmen.
Make sure to bid on me tomorrow.
Don't bother.
She's mine.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
We spent that afternoon discussing
my plan to buy Charlotte...
[Barrel clanging]
Who I planned to eventually marry.
Getting her for one day won't make
her fall in love with you, will.
Maybe not, but having her around
will at least make me feel good.
I mean, my own mom thinks I'm a loser.
It's bad for my confidence.
Ah, the loser's right.
Buying Charlotte would be good
for all of our confidence.
[Sighs]
That's why I started doing
the spartan training.
Me too.
But the best exercise has
always been group sex.
I don't think we'll get
to have sex with her.
I mean, I don't think I want you to.
But having a hot girl around
can't be bad for a group of guys
that spend their free time in an abandoned
lot breaking things for no reason.
She's not gonna come cheap.
Well, how much do we have?
[Coins clinking]
Neil, what are those?
Baby teeth.
I never cashed them in.
The accrued interest
is gonna be massive.
Okay.
Is this really all we have?
Simon.
What?
Do you have any money?
Mm...No.
He's got money!
I do! I do!
$100?
Whoa!
Did your grandma die again?
No.
My dad pads my allowance
for every golf match.
We're playing for $10 a hole, so--
Hmm, no, he'll want it back.
'Cause you throw every hole.
'Cause he's a golf psychopath.
I saw him kill a turtle
once for distracting him.
He killed a turtle!
Oh, God, no!
[Laughs]
Simon, you're a great golfer.
You don't need to hide that from
a dad who can't handle losing.
If I beat him, he will lose his mind.
I'll come with you and absorb it.
[Sighs]
Please, Simon.
I need this.
Looks like we're buying a girl.
Here you go.
The next morning, I was ready for
the auction and all the benefits
it would provide.
Need me to pick you up today?
Nope.
There's a very special someone who
will be happy to give me a lift.
You don't mean Simon?
Nope.
About a million times hotter, mom.
A million times hotter.
And with $100 of Simon's money
in my pocket, I was ready to
rent the girl of my dreams.
All right!
Welcome to the senior slave auction.
[Cheers and applause]
Yay!
All right.
You all know him from
the football field.
Trevor Smith.
[Cheers and applause]
Okay.
Can we start the bidding off for
this future nothing at $10?
Do I hear $10?
$10.
Do I hear $20?
Hey, Simon.
Carly, hi.
You guys here to bid?
No, we're just here to
hang out with you guys.
Awesome.
Bobby's up for auction, so I have to make
sure he doesn't go to some lame girl
with a crush on him.
Psht, yeah, it's pathetic.
People do that?
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
Who are you bidding on?
We'll probably just raise our
hand randomly at one moment.
You know, get swept up
in the moment of giving.
40. $40.
Nope.
That's sweet, you guys.
We're all here to support the cause.
And if you're ever up for auction.
I'm not a senior.
I know, but if you ever just
wanted to make money for yourself.
[Snickers]
Did you just call me a whore?
No.
[Scoffs]
$80. Do I hear 85?
Keep swinging, Simon.
85.
I'm gonna cry.
It's okay.
I'm about ready to cry.
Going once, going twice... sold for $80
to the beautiful girl, the, uh...
She's beautiful.
All right, come up here
and claim your senior.
Damn it.
Carly was right.
We can't bid on Charlotte.
She'll see right through it.
Carly's with Bobby.
Who cares what she thinks?
I do.
We have to abort.
Wait.
What if we bid on a guy first?
We come in low, and then we get outbid.
That way, it looks less calculated
when we bid on Charlotte.
Then she'll be the one
who has to abort.
Good plan. Let's do that.
I'm not bidding on a dude.
Neither am I.
I came up with the plan.
It's not a big deal.
I'll do it.
Okay.
Our next senior has set records
in track, has a 4.0 grade
average, and played a half-eaten
torso in MTV's Teen Wolf.
Let's hear it for Darius hill.
$20!
Oh, [bleep].
What just happened?
Uh... okay.
It's because he's black.
We just bid on a black
guy at a slave auction.
Oh, [bleep].
Why does it matter?
We're gonna return him.
Damn it, I'd rather be a
pervert than a racist.
Why'd you bid on him, will?
Because I'm not a racist, ironically.
Okay, uh... I hear $20.
Do I hear 25?
Anybody want to bid on this very fine...
mm--slave?
Oh, my God.
Someone bid on him.
We were in trouble.
We needed somebody to bid.
Anybody.
$100!
Oh, God.
Anybody but him.
Thank God.
Sold to Neil Sutherland and,
I assume, Will Mackenzie,
Simon Cooper, and Jay Cartwright.
♪ Do is shake, shake
♪ keep your body still
where you guys going?
And last, but not
least, Charlotte Allen.
$200!
[Cheers and applause]
The rest of the day was
an utter disaster.
If the point of having a slave
was to make your life easier,
we had clearly missed the boat.
So come on, fellows.
Can I get you guys some food?
Soda or something?
No.
Can we get you anything, Darius?
You want a fry?
You guys haven't had me
do anything all day.
We're very self-sufficient.
Look. I get it.
I'm black.
You feel awkward having a black slave.
What?
Black?
We don't see color.
You're white to us.
Simon.
Okay, the senior slave auction
is like a rite of passage.
And you guys are making me look bad
in front of the other seniors.
I don't want this to be
some kind of charity case.
Isn't it, though?
You guys paid $100 for me.
That's a lot of money.
If I don't do anything, it's
like I'm stealing from you.
I don't think you steal.
We would never accuse you of stealing.
Wait! Oh.
Found my brownie.
I thought you stole it.
Seriously, guys.
Let me do something, okay?
How about this weekend?
We're just going to my
dad's country club.
Perfect. I'll drive you.
Be like having your own chauffeur.
Can you wear one of those funny hats?
No way in hell.
So not only had I lost Charlotte,
I had lost Simon's $100.
And now I had to help him face
his dad on the golf course.
I'm sorry.
I don't think he'll be allowed in.
Are you serious?
What, because he doesn't
look like the rest of us?
I mean, because he's bla...
No, because
we don't allow flip-flops or jeans.
You guys got a pro shop?
Cool.
♪ You got it all
So we headed to the golf
course, where the promise
of even more embarrassment awaited us.
♪ It's the last time ♪
♪ I sit by ♪ saving face ♪ with all
your friends ♪ 'cause it's one thing ♪
♪ to remember ♪ and another thing ♪ to
live again
Are you sure you don't want
in on this action, will?
I'll take your money too.
[Chuckles]
No, I'll just caddy for Simon.
That's more my strength.
Here's your driver, buddy.
[Sighs]
That's my putter.
♪ Ooh, ooh
♪ ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ you want it
♪ you got it all
[grunts]
Oh, no.
There's a Cooper slice.
Not as bad as Simon's, thank God.
[Laughs]
Wow.
Right behind the screws.
Okay.
Let's go play some golf.
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪ ooh, ooh, ooh ♪ ooh,
ooh ♪ you want it ♪ you got it all
And Jay finally made it to the jacuzzi
he had been so mysteriously pining for.
There it is, Neil.
Finally.
You know you can put hot
water in a bathtub, right?
No, it's no about the hot water, man.
It's about the jet.
The jacuzzi jet is the perfect
diameter to stick your dingus in
for the perfect orgasm.
Wow.
My bro told me about it last summer.
Do you remember that porn
star he used to date?
No.
Well, he did.
And he dumped her for an
old lady with a jacuzzi.
[Sighs]
Nothing can compare to that
sweet hot pleasure hole.
Wow.
What does it feel like?
Like [bleep]ing a mermaid.
Come to papa.
[Sultry rock music]
[Jets humming]
Ooh!
It's a nice one, about
to get a lot nicer.
Oh!
Unfortunately, this mermaid
was more of a sea monster
that decided to keep
Jay's penis for itself.
Ah... ugh.
[Grunting]
Oh, it's gonna pull off.
I'm stuck.
Neil.
Neil!
Neil, come here.
Come-- Do I have to whistle?
Are you a dog?
And after a trip to the pro shop,
Darius was finally able to fit in.
Yes, when you have more time, can you
bring towels to cabana five for me?
Thank you, darling.
[Upbeat rock music]
And even though watching Simon's
dad play golf was even more
painful than watching Charlotte
rub another man's shoulders...
Having me there did makes
things easier on Simon.
I'm destroying him.
I never knew it would taste
so sweet to crush my dad.
Okay, well, you can miss a few shots.
You're pretty far ahead.
No, no, no, no.
Never again.
It's his turn to be the loser.
So easy, in fact, that he had
no trouble displaying his own
lack of sportsmanship.
That's another one for me.
Vrrr!
Shh!
What was that?
Uh, just won another hole.
Boom-shaka-laka.
You want to do that thing
with your club again?
Maybe I do, dad.
Maybe I do.
I taught you better than this.
If you taught me, I'd suck.
You guys mind if we play through?
No, you will not play through!
Screw this.
I'm out of here.
What are you doing?
You can't just leave.
You play him.
Simon?
You wanted to spend the money, will.
He was right.
I deserved this.
You stay out of that clubhouse!
I see you with an order of
chicken fingers, you are done!
Back nine.
You and me.
Double or nothing.
I'm not much of a golfer.
Tee off.
Okay.
And as I hadn't gotten the
girl, and nobody considered me
attractive, it seemed like being
a friend to Simon and finishing
this game was the only
way to keep my dignity.
That's the ball retriever.
But I'd been wrong before.
Turns out golf is extremely hard.
Despite my best efforts,
I couldn't get my ball close to the hole.
While on the other side of
the club, Jay couldn't get
his balls out of the hole.
What's going on?
Kid's setting a new hot tub
record, almost two hours now.
I got a bet with my friends back here.
Is he?
Really now.
Oh, Simon, help me.
Good God, man.
Get out of there.
I can't.
[Groans]
Oh, my God. Are you--
[Straining]
I think I'm setting a
different kind of record.
Oh, no.
That's two hours.
[Cheering]
Pay up, ass[bleep].
[Applause]
Help me.
I don't even know where to start.
Start by getting my
[bleep] out of this hole.
[Whimpering]
[Straining]
Pull. Push.
No, I can't.
Ugh.
It's like Taffy, I bet.
Oh, it's in there.
It's in there for good.
And I have to live here.
Hey.
Hey, dude.
What's going on over there?
Oh, I don't know.
But Jay has been in there a
long time, and he keeps waving,
so I'm sure he's fine.
Oh, hell no.
Meanwhile, I had managed to
lose every hole of golf and was
now severely in debt to Simon's dad.
Mr. Cooper.
Yeah?
Hi.
I was just wondering if,
uh, maybe I could pay you
in installments?
Perhaps some yard work?
Come on, will.
You think I'm gonna
take money from you?
You played your heart out today.
Not your fault I'm a natural.
You keep your money.
Spend it on a girl.
Good-looking kid like you is
gonna have plenty of chances
to do that.
You think I'm good-looking?
Are you kidding me?
You got a whole Eric Bana thing going.
I would have killed for your
looks when I was younger.
My whole life would
have been different.
I was attractive.
Somebody finally saw it.
And maybe it was only a matter of
time before Charlotte did too.
I had wit, charm, and,
most importantly,
a penis that wasn't stuck in a jacuzzi.
Let me get this straight.
Your penis is engorged
inside of the jet,
because of the water pressure,
but we can't turn the jets off,
because then everyone in here
would see that you are, in fact,
making love to a jacuzzi.
Did I get that right?
Yes, sir.
Catch-22.
I swear to God the next time I
bang a pool, the pool's gonna
be a person.
Hey, what's going on?
You guys should try these piña coladas.
I've had, like, 20.
What?
How did you pay for them?
I said to charge it to Mr. Rusakov,
like the guy in front of me.
Neil!
It hurts so much.
I'm all out of love.
We got to get him out of here.
Come on.
I can't live like this, not like this.
[Sighs]
Oh... [ladies gasping]
His [bleep] was stuck in the hole.
Oh!
'Cause he was [bleep] it.
Oh, my God.
Ew.
Come on. Go.
Come on.
Come on, buddy.
No more!
In his final act of servitude,
Darius drove each of us home.
First Neil, who was finally
feeling the effect of
20 piña coladas.
♪ Once you get the feeling ♪
it wants you back for more
♪ says it's gonna heal it but ♪
♪ you won't make the call ♪
Then Jay, who was also
in a state of recovery.
I free you.
Then Simon, whose dad's victory over me
had erased his anger at Simon.
Gave will here an old-fashioned
Cooper beat-down.
Unfortunately, Simon's victory
over him erased that.
Maybe you can win a hole
against me next time.
Why don't you go [bleep] yourself!
And finally me, the
only one who had gotten
through the day completely unscathed.
Or so I had thought.
Hmm.
He is a million times
hotter than Simon.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com