Creating Destiny
Episode 29
When mom was alive, she
loved Yeo Jun, didn't she?
She did think he was good,
but knowing your situation now,
she couldn't possibly rest in peace.
Remember how your mom
struggled to bring you up?
How could she let you suffer all this?
Grandfather!
Remember my words well,
I put up with him only
because I treasured you,
but not anymore.
Yeo Jun certainly won't do.
What are you waiting for?
Go to your room.
This is all a joke.
What is a joke?
The elders tell them to
break up so they break up,
tell them to date so they date,
isn't that a joke?
And unni loves Yeo Jun oppa,
we should be on her side and support her.
You still don't understand.
Even if she marries into that family,
they might be happy for a short while,
but long term misfortune
will be awaiting her.
That is to be expected.
They said all kinds of things to our face.
When Sang Eun is there
all alone, at that time...
Give me a massage.
Episode 29
Father...
yesterday my wife said the wrong
things because she is ignorant.
Please be kind and forgive her.
Forgive her?
Forget it.
Now we have nothing to do with each other,
let's live like we're strangers.
Why must you do this, Father?
Of course I have to.
After you found out about
Sang Eun's birth mother,
your hearts must have been
very unsettled, right?
Even if they got married,
you will continue to find trouble
with Sang Eun over this matter.
That is what I'm not happy about.
Once they get married, would any
of this be a problem still?
You are such a naive man.
That is what will happen
once they get married,
why can't you understand that?
I really don't want to see
Sang Eun live like that.
But that's not how we will behave, Father.
If there is a first time,
there will be a second time.
And as an elder, I'm telling you...
stop going to my son-in-law
to plead for mercy.
I will certainly not allow this matter.
Understand?
Where did you go?
To Kyung Tae's.
Why do you have to go to their place?
Why do you always ignore what I say?
Because of that attitude of yours,
Yeo Jun is all soft-hearted too.
Really!
What's so great about your son anyway?
Other than an unreasonable mother-in-law,
she has to deal with a
troublesome family too.
What?
Are you making any sense at all?
You said worse things
to Kyung Tae, you know.
How desperate must a parent have felt
to give their child to someone else?
Why can't you just empathize with
how the other person feels?
That's right,
I just hate that family.
What?
What is happening here?
We're just into the new year, and there's
loud shouting and quarreling in the house?
I'm sorry, mother.
Why is it even you two have to quarrel?
There're enough complications
already giving me headaches.
This man's mind isn't cleared up yet,
he went looking for Kyung Tae again.
So because of your stubbornness,
I have to stop being friends with him?
For the sake of your own
child, can't you do that?
Keep it down now.
What did Kyung Tae say?
Kyung Tae isn't that upset with us,
but Father is determined to break
off ties with our family.
That's good then,
we take this opportunity to
break off all ties now.
Since I've already made it clear
to Sang Eun's birth mother,
her appearance didn't seem like
one to abandon her own child.
To you, is it really that
important whose child she is?
Of course,
isn't it important to you too, Mother?
To me, more important than
who her birth parents are,
it's the issue of trust and sincerity.
That is the crux of why I
object to the marriage.
Putting aside Sang Eun,
Kyung Tae and that old man
shouldn't have treated me like that.
Mother...
Enough.
You two leave, I'm having a headache now.
It's really been a long time.
What are you doing?
I've forgotten what your face looks like.
You just saw me this morning.
Recently, too many things
have been happening.
I really don't get what's
up with the elders.
That's true.
I said I didn't like you
right from the start.
But why only now they object to it?
That's what I'm saying.
I said I didn't like you at the start too.
I am warning you now,
don't run away just because
it gets difficult, all right?
Not to Australia nor America.
If I do, aren't you coming after me?
You know I will chase after you, right?
But I don't think we should waste
any time by running away.
Then, what should we do?
Shall we get married, Han Sang Eun?
What?
Marry me.
I can't wait anymore.
I don't want the elders nor anything else
to interfere with our love.
Grandfather said he definitely
won't allow me to marry you.
It's all right,
I'm not marrying grandfather.
We can't get married like this.
If we waited and waited and
it still doesn't work out,
I'll go ahead.
I really wonder how other
people get married.
Yeo Jun, does it bother you that
I'm that woman's daughter?
It sure does.
Because you don't look like your mother,
otherwise you're sure to be a beauty.
If that were the case,
maybe when we first met at the airport,
I might have fallen in love with you then.
Ridiculous.
That's right, it's ridiculous.
So stop saying silly things like that.
Did you come right back from the hospital?
Or did you meet with Sang Eun?
Mother.
Answer me.
Did you meet with Sang Eun?
Yes, I met Sang Eun.
Can't you sober up?
They don't agree to it and neither will I,
why do you persist?
In your eyes, I might be a perfect son,
but in reality,
I have my shortcomings too.
And only Sang Eun can
complement my shortcomings.
Other than Sang Eun, I
will not marry anyone else.
Yeo Jun!
Yeo Jun.
You'll keep fighting for it, won't you?
My experience tells me,
a marriage objected by parents
is not going to be a happy one.
- Noona...
- But,
if you really believe and love each other,
you won't be forced apart.
We will definitely not part.
Then you make sure you put Sang Eun at ease.
I know.
That's good.
I won't worry then.
Hey, stop sighing.
Why can't things just go smoothly?
If you're bothered about Doctor Kim Yeo Jun,
don't waste time worrying about him.
That guy is a perfect man,
nothing will go wrong with him.
Hey,
why don't you worry about
things happening to us?
But there's nothing about us to worry over.
So I wanted to ask,
would you like to go on a trip?
A warm and romantic place.
Why?
What do you mean why?
We're dating, aren't we?
It doesn't mean you can do anything
just because we're dating.
And what makes you think I'd trust you
enough to go on a trip with you?
Impossible.
Hey,
what do you take me for?
You're the one who's
thinking dirty thoughts.
Forget it then.
She worries about so many things.
Let's go anyway.
Really?
Who says I want to go with you?
Then who else are you going with?
My family members.
You won't follow along, will you?
Hey,
it was my idea, you know.
- I'm off.
- Thank you.
Grandfather. Dad.
- Yes.
- Let's go skiing.
Why go skiing suddenly?
Child, you want your grandfather
to break his bones?
I'd rather go for hot springs.
Fine,
we go ski this time then
hot spring next time.
You people might think it's fun,
but you think grandfather
and I think so too?
We must watch the shop too.
Then I'll go with unni.
I've been staying home since
I came to Korea, all right?
Two of you?
One night stay?
Don't you think unni is pitiful?
Grandfather wouldn't let her date,
so she's supposed to just stay at home?
She should at least release
some stress, right?
Grandfather! Daddy...
Well...
No trouble, okay?
Just skiing, no kissing.
See if you dare run out at night.
I know.
Mother.
What now?
Is it about Sang Eun?
No... well...
that's on my mind too, but I think
the factory needs an expansion.
Our production has already doubled,
but we can't keep doing it.
What should we do, Mother?
What can we do?
We wanted to let everyone
know about our rice cakes,
surely we must continue.
It seems he's really capable.
A family business which we ran for 30 years,
he expanded it in hardly a few months.
That's right.
He must be busy with lots of
matters at his company too.
It's all right, I'll leave it to you.
Yes.
Then, Mother, well...
Aigoo,
if it's about Sang Eun then stop.
I have to talk to that
old man to resolve this.
I understand.
Jin Ju, what kind of ice cream do you like?
Chocolate.
What kind of milk do you like?
Pure milk, banana or strawberry?
Banana.
Ah, banana.
What about doughnuts?
Cheese doughnuts.
How is Jin Ju?
She's fine.
She misses you.
No problem at the factory, right?
Thanks to you,
the elders are all very happy about it.
Yun Hee...
It's time for the meeting.
We'll talk again.
Hyo Eun.
Something to tell me?
I have a favor to ask you.
What?
Ski?
Yes,
Jin Ju says she wants to go ski,
do you have time?
I will make time if Jin Ju wants to go.
How about we ask Kyu Han along?
If so, forget it then.
All right, I'll make time this weekend.
The car's available but...
I thought you said you were busy,
why are you going skiing?
Noona's going too,
forget it if you don't want to.
I'll go.
Skiing?
Doctor, you're going skiing?
None of your business.
Sang Eun, long time no see.
That's right.
Unni!
Jin Ju.
Unni, you're coming along too?
Why? I can't go?
No.
Then get in, let's go.
Hyo Eun's been bugging you, right?
No, I'm so bored in the shop all the time.
Ski?
If you say you'll go, Yeo Jun oppa
will be there too, all right?
Otherwise the two of them
won't get to date at all,
the elders have such violent objections.
Wow, this place is a blast!
What a blast!
Hyo Eun, she's learning from you,
be careful what you say.
Don't worry, Jin Ju talks like that too.
Mom, when do we get to ski?
Can't we go now?
Yes, let's go now.
Since we're here already,
staying in here is just wasting time.
Let's change quickly and go.
This is great.
Jin Ju, can you ski?
No.
She'll just go on the ski chair lift.
- We can teach you how to ski.
- That's right.
Uncle Kyu Han.
Yeo Jun.
How did this happen?
Isn't it Hyo Eun's idea?
Hyo Eun!
Kyu Han owes me a favor,
so just take it as repaying me.
Instead of repaying,
I feel like I owe you another favor.
Well then repay me double with
those bright shiny things.
Hey!
You don't have to.
You're joking, right?
Bright and shiny things!
Why ask hyung for it?!
Then you get me some.
The more presents, the merrier.
Does grandfather know about this too?
I forgot to tell him,
but I didn't lie to him.
Hyo Eun, when we get back to Seoul,
I'll surely buy you a
bright and shiny thing.
I'm very happy with you for this.
Thanks.
Why must you buy bright and shiny
stuff for someone else's girl?
If you dare accept it, you're dead.
I dare you to try.
Hey! I told you no.
Oh, this feels great.
I'm not skiing. I'll take
chair lift rides with Jin Ju.
Mom, I'd like to ski.
But you can't ski.
Jin Ju, you ski with me.
Be careful.
You're ready, let's go.
Look here.
Use your leg.
Left, yes, right.
Very good.
Why this expression?
Don't tell me you can't do this?
No.
She can but she doesn't look nice on it.
That's right, you can't ride
things which sway, right?
We need to get to the top,
how do we get you up?
Shall we walk?
No,
I'll take the chair lift.
How?
Clinging to it like a lunatic,
with her eyes closed tight.
Since you have Yeo Jun oppa now,
just cling onto him will do.
Let's go, take your time, unni.
See you later.
Is this how you ride every time?
- I give up with you.
- Oh, my.
That's good.
You're not afraid coming down?
I told you, right? I'm fine
if I'm on the ground.
What's that fella doing?
Are you all right?
Let's take a break, want some coffee?
It's nice and warm.
It's been such a long time, you know?
Nothing I can do about it.
Grandmother and grandfather
oppose so strongly.
Are things okay with your mother?
Just so-so.
What about you, Yeo Jun?
You're doing all right with your mother?
I'm... still fighting.
Don't worry, I'm close to winning.
Really?
Of course.
I don't play games in which I lose.
I have never and I won't start neither.
My grandfather...
says he will object to it all the way.
Well... if this goes on,
I'll have to come up with something else.
You're not tired of it, are you?
Not yet.
That's fine then.
Father, how do you feel?
I'm not dead yet.
You don't have to worry about the company.
We've taken care of the urgent matters,
no other problem has come up yet.
Why are you here?
I'll wrap things up
and...
return there.
To be with my family.
I don't care about what you want to do.
Without you, nothing will happen
to the company anyway.
Father, most of the things
have been settled.
The vice president, the directors...
and hyung too,
they all worked very hard
at completing their tasks.
We're all doing what we should.
You can leave now.
I'm not dying yet.
All right.
Father feels a little different now.
Surely not, he's not
one to change so easily.
Are you going back to the office?
You're going too, aren't you?
Didn't you want to finish up quickly
so that you can go back?
Really.
- You're here.
- Is Sang Eun here?
She went skiing with her sister.
If I knew you were coming, you
could have gone with them.
No.
The young ones went together,
if I tagged along, I'd be a bother to them.
A bother?
Sang Eun's not so good with strangers,
she'll be fine soon.
- I found it.
- Yes.
This one is on Sang Eun.
Can I take a look?
We got this for you to take a look.
We made this in case such a day came along,
so please have it.
I'm so grateful.
Why say that?
We're the ones who are grateful instead.
What we have is not just photos,
we have the real person and even
feelings for one another too.
Who could it be at this hour?
We're not expecting anyone.
Let me go take a look.
Where is Sang Eun and Yeo Jun?
Down there,
I don't think they've had enough yet.
It's the first time I've
seen Doctor Kim so happy.
I'm happy too.
Mom, I'm feeling so happy today.
It would have been better if dad was here.
Right, mom?
Mom, when will dad be here?
When he finishes his work.
I told you that, remember?
When will he finish?
Unni, aren't you going out?
It's a rare opportunity out here.
I have to put Jin Ju to bed.
She's very tired already.
I'm not tired.
But it's time for bed.
You guys go.
Then oppa, you'll be here too, right?
What?
Kyu Han oppa,
surely you can't leave unni here
and go ski by yourself, right?
No.
Then we two will just go.
Let's go, oppa.
Ah!
We will be back very, very late.
Make sure you wait up for us.
We don't want to be light bulbs here.
Let's go!
Hey...
We're in trouble.
Why?
If we go back,
Kyu Han hyung won't be happy.
If we're out here,
Doctor Kim Yeo Jun won't be happy, right?
What are we to do tonight?
We'll just drink coffee
throughout the night then.
Cappuccino?
Cappuccino!
This is Sang Eun's mother. This is...
Yeo Jun's... no,
I'm the father of Yeo Jun
who's engaged to Sang Eun.
What engaged! It was called off, right?!
Hey, father.
Hello.
Why are you still here and not leaving?
No matter what you say,
I'm not leaving.
It's my fault that the children's
engagement was called off.
No, it's not like that.
That family has been weird
and inhuman all along.
Luckily, they're not married.
Otherwise, our Sang Eun
will lose out a big deal.
I'm sorry, it's all our fault
for thinking like that...
Sorry, my foot.
So like this,
if you kill someone, you'll
just say sorry, that's all?
Oh, father-in-law,
it's not like that, right?
But... what brings you here?
Well, since the kids are all out,
I thought of having some drinks with you.
You came empty-handed and
suggest having drinks?
But... you said the kids are out?
Where did they go?
What? So...
Hyo Eun and Sang Eun went skiing too?
Yun Hee said they'll be there too.
Don't tell me...
Hyo Eun...
I told you something was up.
But maybe they went there separately.
Try to make some sense when you talk.
See what I'll do when they get back.
Well, we don't know what they're up to yet,
but I certainly won't allow the marriage,
is that clear?
Earlier...
my wife...
made a mistake, please forgive us.
It wasn't her mistake,
it was my fault.
If only I didn't appear...
What fault?
Search everywhere for a
girl like our Sang Eun,
you search with a lantern and you still
can't find anyone like our Sang Eun.
Yes, well, all of this...
is because we're short-sighted.
Of course that's the case.
But the engagement is indeed off.
Are you all right?
It hurts.
Are things all right with your mother?
I'm not so mean to her now.
I don't mean that.
Then what?
No matter what happens, don't be sad again.
Are you troubled about something?
Nothing, just thinking about today.
We're here so what's there to think about?
When I see those people,
I think about it naturally.
You don't think about me?
Of course I won't forget
you even for a moment,
you won't let me anyway.
It's been awhile since we're together.
Are you cold?
No.
I'm fully awake now.
So many stars.
Yes, it's beautiful.
Sang Eun,
will you marry me?
What?
If we're married,
we can eat together,
even if we stayed out late,
no one will complain about us.
Let's get married.
If we're sick, we'll
worry for each other,
If we're afraid, we'll
keep each other company.
Something good happens,
we'll share it together.
From now on...
we'll face everything together.
Really, this doctor doesn't know
how to create the right ambience,
Kiss her, just kiss her.
You think Yeo Jun oppa is some wolf,
just kiss anyhow?
All men are wolves.
You're so smart but you didn't know that?
What did you say?
Really.
Hey, you pervert!
Is Jin Ju asleep?
She said she wasn't tired but
fell asleep right away.
Don't you want to be out there?
You haven't skied for a long while, right?
It's been a longer time that
I haven't been with you.
Didn't you miss me?
I was busy with the franchise business.
You're so strong even without me around.
That's not what I want.
All mothers are strong.
No,
even without Jin Ju,
you have been strong.
So strong that I can't do anything about it.
Is that so?
That's good then.
Can't you be less strong?
So that I can hold onto you.
I would like that too,
but no matter what how
hard I think about it,
I can't let that happen.
Why is it we're thinking
about the same thing,
but our answers are different?
This time round, my answer is correct.
Up until now.
You go rest, I'm tired too.
Noona,
do you think of me as a
younger brother like Yeo Jun?
A younger brother whom I
like very much, that's all.
Did you know?
A guy will control until he can't
anymore then he'll pounce.
You're not like that.
Am I interrupting something?
No, who says you're interrupting?
Hey, what did you say I did to you?
Others will get the impression
that I'm diseased or something.
You're diseased, all right.
Why pretend to be so pure?
Is this your first kiss?
Yes, it's my first! You jerk!
Hey!
You saw that?
When men can't control it
anymore, they'll pounce.
Oh really.
I'm off.
So you mean they went skiing together?
It seems so.
Crazy! Crazy!
Hey, hey. What are you doing?
Should we just leave them be?
What if something happens?
You think they're some kindergarten kids?
If they had intended to, something
would have happened earlier.
It's not like you can chase
them around 24 hours.
That's right.
The kids are so good,
they said they'll wait
for the elders' assent.
Good?
If they're so good, would they be there?
Kyu Han and Yun Hee are
there too, is that all right?
But that is...
That is...
Nothing to say, right?
They all say parents are selfish.
But I just don't know if you're the
naive one or am I the complicated one?
Aigoo...
Did Sang Eun and Yeo Jun go out so early?
They didn't waste a minute.
They were suffering for so long before this.
Mom,
can't I go skiing too?
Once you wash up and eat, you can ski too.
With Jin Ju here, all of
you will get so tired.
We're fine.
Since we bluffed the elders,
we should at least do that.
Uncle.
How dare you come in here!
I'm here to eat breakfast.
Anything I can help with?
Let me know too.
Is there anything we can do?
Oh forget it.
It'll be more troublesome. Just sit here.
Hello?
Dad.
At the ski resort.
With mom, uncle and unni.
What about you?
I'm at the office.
Are you having fun?
It's fun.
It'll be better if you were here.
Dad, I miss you.
Yes,
I wish I can be there too.
I miss you too, Jin Ju.
Then you should come.
Mom, it's dad.
I see, it's dad.
Yes.
We're all together.
Nothing much.
All right.
What? You worked overnight again?
Yes, I had something to settle.
You chair the morning meeting.
And you?
I have something to handle.
I'll head straight to the airport later.
What's up?
Your father came to see me again?
No,
my father has been settled.
He will no longer come looking for you.
I came to tell you this.
Is that so?
So one thing's settled,
then what about us dating?
That again?
I'm talking about dating, that's all.
If it doesn't work out,
we'll just break off.
Is this how you love Han Sang Eun too?
I love her more than this, I think.
Then why do you talk to me like this?
I don't want to date like this.
Even though we start to date now,
we still have other people in our hearts.
Who knows?
We start off like this,
what will happen later on?
But...
I don't know if my father will
give his approval so easily.
What a joke.
Why must I be approved by your father?
It is you who must be approved by me.
My father...
is quite a tough character.
Actually...
I have no time to go on dates,
and you might have to wait
a long time for me.
But if it's all right with you,
let's start dating.
Forget it.
I'm not sure if I can wait for you.
Waiting for someone...
just once is more than enough.
Or you could wait for me.
I'm not that free.
Han Hyo Eun.
You're upset at such small matters.
I told you not to follow me.
Mom, when will we come again?
We're not leaving yet but you're
thinking of coming again?
Dad!
What brings you all the way here?
I missed Jin Ju.
Even so,
don't tell me you started
out early this morning?
Yes.
I thought you might have left.
We can meet up in Seoul, right?
I don't have time.
After I send Jin Ju back,
I have to make a trip to China.
We should go too.
You drive.
What's going to happen to those three?
Including Jin Ju, it'll be four.
Let's go.
Dad, when will you come again?
After my trip, I'll come see you right away.
Right away is how many days?
Maybe a week, fastest will be 5 days.
Okay. Dad, goodbye.
Bye.
After I've handled the company matters,
I'll be right back.
I won't disappear again without any notice.
Let me help you.
Ah umm...
I'll call you tomorrow.
Forget it.
Brother-in-law, thanks for today.
It's nothing. I have to thank you instead.
You should go.
No matter what the elders say,
don't put it to heart.
And don't be sad either.
I know.
You should go or else you'll get scolded.
Doctor.
Hyung-nim.
Get your role sorted out.
I've not acknowledged you yet.
I don't care even if you haven't.
Maybe we might get married before you.
No way.
If you dare touch Hyo Eun,
you can stop dreaming about anything,
not to mention marriage.
So it means Hyo Eun,
you had me in the dark the whole time?
Sorry, grandfather.
Nothing to do with you.
Surely this is all Hyo Eun's idea.
How many times have I said it?
You mustn't be with him.
The elders don't have to
meet up, that will do.
What?
Why must you break them up?
That's because for your unni's sake...
How can that be for unni's sake?
Han Hyo Eun!
So you're saying,
you want to see your sister marry
into that family and suffer there?
So just let them get married and go
straight to America, won't that do?
Instead of worrying for her,
you should just send her to a safe place.
Am I right?
If you're done talking,
can we go to our room now?
I'm tired already.
Let's go.
Since when...
did Hyo Eun become so articulate?
I wonder.
Even if Yeo Jun did it,
how could you join in too?
It's because they truly love each other.
Why must you separate them by force?
You're the only kind-hearted
and soft-hearted one?
You think I'm doing this
because I hate Sang Eun?
Son!
Mother,
you're going out?
I think I should have a
talk with that old man.
Mother, what are you going to say?
We can't sit by as they going
about messing around.
Let's go.
Mother.
You came here because...
So what brings you here?
Didn't we agree not to be on talking terms?
Even though we agreed not
to speak to each other,
there are things we should
still settle and make clear.
Even if you apologize, it depends
whether we will accept or not.
A family like yours, which is
old-fashioned and unreasonable,
I have nothing to say.
Elder,
you've gone overboard when you say that.
Unreasonable?
What big sin have we committed?
Then why did you come here?
Our Sang Eun has always been a good child.
No matter who else speaks
badly about Sang Eun,
you of all people
shouldn't hurt her like this.
And Tae Soo,
no matter who says anything
bad about my family,
you of all people shouldn't
treat us like that, right?
You should stop when
you've reached the limit.
This matter has gotten this
far all because of you.
This makes me so mad,
I don't understand what I've done wrong.
If you had told us right from the start,
this matter wouldn't have gotten so serious.
What did you say?
Isn't that true?
You didn't trust me nor my son,
and you didn't trust Yeo Jun either,
that's why I didn't agree to the marriage.
You don't trust any of us,
why would you let your granddaughter
marry into our family?
What kind of reason is that?
Of course, Sang Eun is my granddaughter.
Revealing it is very serious
and create many problems,
that's why you didn't tell us,
isn't that right?
If it were me,
at least I would have made it
clear before the engagement.
Old man, you should have told us earlier,
and not let it leak out
little by little, right?
So you think we cheated you?
Otherwise,
you think I minded because Sang
Eun was an adopted child?
That makes me even more upset.
Don't I know Sang Eun by now?
But this is...
Kyung Tae, you!
You're like family to me,
I've never treated you like an outsider.
Even though the old man likes
to make big statements,
I still thought of you all as family.
But...
in the end, I'm the only
one thinking like that,
in the end, I'm the one who
got betrayed by you all.
This thought alone makes me
think how evil you are.
Are you going to insist on your innocence?
Mother, I'm very sorry,
I mistook your response,
it was totally my ignorance.
Enough.
I know what you're trying to say.
So then...
breaking the engagement...
is really not because of Sang Eun?
Old man!
If that is really what you thought,
then it was all our fault.
I'm not sure if you'd
be sad to hear this but,
I really didn't make effort to think
of the problem from your angle.
I only thought of Sang Eun,
and...
of my daughter, that's all.
Mother,
we'll carry out the marriage as planned.
No!
I will not agree to this marriage.
Daughter-in-law.
Daughter-in-law!
Mother,
he is my son.
You have to consider for me too.
Honey!
It has spread to the liver.
More tests are needed to tell
if a surgery can be done.
Even other doctors at our level,
it won't be easy to operate on this.
Mother,
I hope you can get warded for
more tests and treatment.
Forget it.
There's surgery, it's not
like there's no hope.
No, this is...
the punishment I deserve.
Then what about Sang Eun?
Yeo Jun, you're not to let her know.
I won't stay here for too long.
Please?
Please don't say thank you,
and don't say sorry either.
I myself chose to love you,
I didn't love you to make you like me.
I don't want Sang Eun to put up
with people's gossips over here,
so please take her away.
Your mother is sick,
very sick.
Mom.
I...
even for one day,
I want to live it with Sang Eun.
Mom.