Year 1941
- Irena Sendler, your work?
- Department of Social Services.
I see that, my question is about today?
What is your work today,
Why are you here?
Inspection of the refugee centers.
Prevent the spread of typhus.
You Poles must solve this
problem, it's a disgrace.
Please, buy it from me...
What do you think you are doing?
And you do not want any?
Yes.
Irena it is Sofia, I know
it's curfew but can you come?
Yes, I will come right away.
- How soon?
I will walk so, 20 minutes?
- Come now hurry
- Please, stay calm.
- Irenka?
- Its all right Mama, go back to sleep!
- Thank God you are here.
- Where is she?
With Krzysztof.
Tonight, when Krzysztof came home
the way our neighbors looked at him.
We were betrayed.
I just know, I'm sorry Irena.
If Germans find us hiding a Jew,
they will execute us.
It's all right, it's all right
Hello, Anna, it's Irena.
Do not need to be afraid.
And tonight you going to stay with me.
Would you like that?
Is that you?
Yes this is my father.
- Where is he?
- He died.
Mine too.
- Mama, you should not be up.
- Believe me, I know.
- Hello sweet heart
- Anna, this is my mother.
See what I have for you.
Look at this.
Time for bed.
- How many mothers do you have?
- I just have one.
Already, I had three.
Why do they not like me?
Who does not like you?
My mothers.
Your mothers love you.
And I love you.
And I will always love you.
Go to sleep
- Mom, we have to go now.
- Here.
It is safe to take
her out in broad daylight?
She passes as Christian.
Are you worried?
Not one bit.
- Mama, hmm?
- Ahh, good.
- Eva will love it.
- It's Perfect.
Mama! Take your medicine.
Mama, please.
The cat is counting,
playing hide-and-seek.
You make me laugh.
You're so smart.
- Come in Anna!
- Anna, this is Miss Jadwiga.
Hello sweetie, come in.
Thank you, come in.
Anna, you can play with
Miss Jadwiga's children
while I find you a lovely place to live.
Good girl.
She has passed outside
the ghetto all this time.
There must be a Polish family
who can take her.
Not any we know personally.
I'll ask father Godlewski
he will know some we can trust.
- Wait. You mean now?
- His soup kitchen's on my way.
- You're going to the ghetto?
- Yes, I’ll see you later.
Irena you remember we had a
meeting with public housing.
Be charming, give nothing.
Monsignor Godlewski. Good morning!
- Ah, Irena.
What do you hear?
In the last two weeks, they
have filled 20 train cars
of Jews in Luxemburg and Vienna,
deported them all
to the ghetto in Lodz.
And here,
every day they bring more.
You know we are doing all we can to
help Jews survive outside the ghetto.
Yes yes I know, of course.
And today I have a little girl
and no Polish family to hide her.
It's more difficult now.
Perhaps in your congregation?
Irena, please of all people, you
know the risk for a Polish family.
Even so, is it not
possible there are some
or even many Poles who want
to help but don't know how?
Yes, yes, yes
It is possible.
- Eva.
- Irena.
Come, come.
Good morning, Hannah.
Oh, Irena, always
such a faithful friend.
God bless you.
- Rabbi Rozenfeld.
- Irena, how are you this fine day?
Is this work for a Rabbi?
We all must live with dignity,
especially in the days of hatred.
Miss. Irena! Miss. Irena!
Karolyna! Or should I say, the famous
Miss Nijinska, Prima ballerina?
Do you know what I learned to do!
Do you want to see?
Of course, you must show me!
- Bravo!
- How is your mother?
Well enough. if she behaves.
And your Jacob?
Last week he came back to the
ghetto to hug his daughter.
And to kiss you,
I am sure.
Maybe yes, a little.
I brought a few things.
Let me, let me!
I brought you a skirt.
You made this?
Can you imagine me putting
two stitches together?
- Then your mother.
- She misses you, so do I.
My dearest friends in the
whole world. Please thank her.
Eva, I need to talk with you.
Over the last few weeks, they
have deported 20 freight cars
of Jews from Austria
to the ghetto in Lodz.
Yes, we heard last night.
The Jewish Council says they're
headed for work camps.
Eva, your Jewish Council
was appointed by Germans.
How many years have we listened
to their terrible propaganda?
What they say about Jews,
what they say they have in mind...
It's just talk, rumor. Who can believe it?
These are cultured people.
Anyway, we're almost five hundred thousand
in this Ghetto. What could they do?
It's so confusing.
One day someone says something
is true, another says it's not.
Every morning I wake up,
my body is cold.
We have to get you all out of here.
They would never leave.
I could never leave them.
I could find Polish families
willing to hide you.
Most people believe it's better
to stay all together, inside the wall.
I want you safe,
all of you.
Irena, what is safe?
Where?
Good morning, Miss Irena.
Good morning Doctor Majkowski,
have you had a chance to consider my...
Yes, I have selected your friend,
Maria Debinska to join your department.
Thank you, doctor.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Miss Irena.
Maria, welcome to our little
department, thank you.
My thanks to you.
- Good morning, Miss Irena.
- You missed an exciting meeting.
Issued today, the new ration card.
2613 calories a day for Germans,
699 calories for Poles,
300 calories for residents
of the ghetto.
So we will have starvation along
with a Typhus epidemic.
And winter almost here.
We'll need to bring in food,
clothing, medicine.
Maria, talk to Doctor Majkowski, see how
much Typhus vaccine you can get.
Since The Occupation Jadwiga
has done a brilliant job
trying to balance to
balance an impossible budget.
But...
But, if we continue to spread our
services over every district in Warsaw,
we will not be helping anyone.
From now on we must focus our
full attention in the Jewish ghetto
Excuse me, Miss Irena.
The Jewish Quarter is not our problem.
Why not?
The Germans put them there to protect us.
- Protect us from what?
Maria, you are a nurse, you know very well.
- What do I know, tell me?
They have lice, spread disease and...
You know what I'm talking about.
Danuta, if Jews are sick, it is
because Germans put them there.
One reason, another reason
what does it matter.
All I know is I am not going to bring
Typhus home to my family.
Whatever it is you're thinking,
I’m sorry, I can't be part of it.
Anyone else who does not
agree with this direction,
I will arrange a department transfer.
Stefania, you have only been
with us for two months.
I have not yet been inside the walls,
but I know I must do it.
Very good.
Later we go to the refuge center.
Stefania...
We are at war, you are soldier now.
A soldier must be tough
or she cannot fight.
Oh! Hold her.
Hold her still, good, good.
- Why do you bother?
- Because we want your child to survive.
If you want her to live, please,
take her from me, get her out of here.
I' begging you take her.
I’m sorry, but it's not possible.
Next please, next.
Please, Mama,
go back to bed.
I'm fine.
Do not worry.
What is it?
Tell me.
Irena?
Irenka, tell me what.
Today, I understood something.
Something about what?
I thought I was doing
all I could, but...
but the truth is
I am doing nothing.
Nothing?
Is it my imagination
or was there a little Jewish child
sleeping in your bed last night?
One child is not enough!
Oh Irena, you are so like your father.
Little Anna has always lived
outside the Ghetto.
Inside the wall there are thousands
of children who could be rescued.
Take them out?
Is that what you're thinking?
Past the Gestapo?
German soldiers, Jewish police?
How is that possible?
You are a social worker,
a good social worker
With a biggest heart I know
but to risk everything
for something you know nothing about...
I remember what father used to say.
You see a man drowning,
you must try to save him,
even if you can not swim.
Thank you.
- And you?
- Two loaves and 250 grams of butter.
- You are a Jew.
- No, I'm not.
One of those filthy little
smugglers from the ghetto.
No, I'm Polish.
Let us see you make
the sign of the cross!
Come on, come on, do it!
Every day I pray to God
this boy lives safe in this city.
But the way he looks and he behaves,
you can not imagine in
what we have been through.
Come on!
With this red hair, you do
not think you look Jewish?
- And get yourself a cap.
- Yes, miss.
If you want to survive outside the
Ghetto you must lie with more conviction.
And learn how to cross
yourself. Like this.
Now, you.
Again. Quickly!
Very good. Get out of here.
Wait!
Jasio, I have to go
on police patrol.
But, I do not want you
going out after curfew.
They can shoot you on spot.
Why risk your live
to smuggle a few potatoes?
I make enough.
You're a traitor!
Can you not understand.
I only do what I do
so that we can survive.
It is you who does not understand.
Mr. Policeman.
I want to help children
inside, the, ghetto.
It is very dangerous.
Too dangerous.
Yes, probably, but what would it take?
Well, I suppose an organized
network of people you trust,
enough money for each
child's room and board.
And if you agree,
more Polish families
willing to hide a Jewish child.
I will try to find some.
What about identity cards?
If I destroy some of the
parish death certificates,
issue new baptismal certificates.
That is all the proof Germans
need for an identity card.
The only thing is,
how to get them out?
There is someone you must talk to...
a young man who smuggles
potatoes from the Aryan side,
he works in Korczak's orphanage.
Ask him to introduce you
to Stefan Zgrzembski.
- Zgrzembski?
- Yes, that's him.
Guten morgen, Father.
Professor Korczak, how many
children live inside the ghetto?
Including all the ones
who live in the streets?
There must be at least 80 thousand,
half under the age of ten.
Be brave now.
Have you ever tried to get any out?
Out to where?
Not so many Poles want to hide
a Jewish child.
And how many Jews would let
their children live with Gentiles?
What about orphans, these ones?
Even if you found a way, most of mine
could not survive outside the wall.
- Why not?
- It's the language.
She only speaks Yiddish.
Is that not right?
They all speaks excellent Yiddish.
Polish, that's another matter.
And they are all beautiful
but most are not passable as Aryan.
Irena?
Hello, Stefan.
Hello.
Zgrzembski, Irena came to see you.
You attended my classes together.
Yes.
A long time ago.
Zgrzembski, let me deal with this
horrible little savages right here!
I've found something here with
prof. Korczak and the children.
I'm glad.
But you still smuggle potatoes.
Irena Sendler,
always straight to the point.
Tell me how.
I know a few safe ways to get out,
blind spots the Germans overlooked.
- There is the courthouse.
- Which courthouse.
On Ogrodowa street.
There also an entrance
for the ghetto's side,
and a friend with the key.
- The other ways?
- I can show you.
The main sewer line goes all the
way down to the central junction
under Gdanski station.
- And from there?
- Anywhere you want.
One line goes under Okopowa Street,
another goes under Marszalkowska,
third line goes under
New Town and Miodowa Street.
The Germans keep the courts so busy
they have forgotten this entrance.
You remember our summer walks
along the Vistula River?
- Every step.
- Shall we?
- Welcome to Warsaw.
- Thank you Stefan.
We will use this way first.
- Be careful.
- You know me.
That is what I mean.
Be careful about yourself.
Come fast, hurry!
Documents!
Hello.
My name is Irena.
Can you tell me yours?
The boy who sits beside
you every day.
Is he your brother?
He died.
I'm sorry.
Can you tell me where you live?
All right.
Come with me.
We have hot soup.
Just made for you.
Are you going to get
her changed in here?
Yes. I think it's a good idea.
All right. We need to do
something about her hair.
Can we braid it?
Please help if you would.
All right.
Lets take this skirt off.
Very good girl.
And try a beret.
It will keep you warm.
Much better.
Good girl.
You look so beautiful.
Ready for a little walk
in the courthouse?
Come on sweetie,
we must...
Such a little trouble-maker.
You have no idea.
Come along, sweetheart.
- Rabbi.
- For me?
Such a dashing fashion for a Rabbi.
And...
for you, Miss Nijinska!
Oh, yes,
I remember this book!
Welcome! Come in, come in!
Rabbi, thank you so much.
So many people without shelter.
Eva! Hannah!
Come! Help me, please.
This is perfect.
Let us read a little bit.
Blankets for you.
It's very cold outside
We are very well, Rabbi.
Come on.
Is she your little girl?
Why do I have to be a Jew?
What if I want to be something else?
I don't like being
hated by everybody.
Everybody does not hate you.
Yes they do.
You know it's true.
What did we ever do?
It's not fair.
There are ways to get out of the ghetto,
ways that are still safe.
- I cannot.
- Yes, I know.
But I've been thinking about Karolyna.
Karolyna?
We know Polish families who
can be trusted,
several priests,
convents in the countryside.
Stop, Irena!
Let me ask you one thing,
tell me from your heart.
How is it possible for a
mother to give up a child?
How?
Now I must ask you something...
a terrible thing.
No, no don't, please...
If it happened that
the rumors are true...
and if for Karolyna...
you had to choose
between life and death...
Please, I cannot face it, I cannot.
You can, Eva
and you must.
Please, speak with your Jacob.
Irenka. Do you know what this
author says about life?
Mama, please, I have to go.
Please, take one moment to breath.
What this writer says is in order
to have a happy life,
you must exercise your own free will.
Interesting. Bye-bye.
Which is why I would never
tell you not to do something
or suggest to you that I
might possibly be worried.
I would never do such a thing.
No matter what happens.
Thank you, Mama.
Thank you.
What has happened?
All the Social Service programs
have been suspended.
Who has access?
From now on only nurses, doctors,
workers in the Health Department.
Today I was told I am officially
responsible for any
further spread of Typhus.
But it is impossible,
what do they...
Of course it's impossible.
That's their point.
If I cannot help myself,
how can I help you?
I will need Health Department
work passes,
four... no, no maybe
five nurse's uniforms.
Is that all?
I hope so.
Perhaps a larger vehicle.
We will seek orphans and
homeless in the market area
and specific families we already know are
willing to let us place their children...
One of Doctor Majkowski's
drivers has volunteered,
Piotr Lipinski.
Miss Irena.
- Hello.
Thank you, Piotr.
Mr. Lipinski sprays for Typhus.
You understand the risk?
Only small problems,
but I am not too worried.
We will use my disinfectant truck.
I beg you, keep them together.
I'm sorry, its not possible.
Sister Jolanta, please understand
whatever happens they will
always have each other.
One slip, one word in Yiddish.
They could give each other away.
How will I ever find them?
I will keep a record
to where I place them.
I promise.
Mom, and I do not want to go!
Take her. Please go!
You can go.
Tell me, what do you want
to be when you grow up?
A priest.
Yes, very good,
that's perfect!
Up you go, you can do it.
Papers? Vehicle check.
What do you have in the truck?
We have a problem.
Roadblock. Vehicle check.
All right. Let's go for a walk.
Our Father who art in Heaven,
Hallowed be thy name...
Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done.
On earth,
as it is in heaven.
Give us this day.
our daily bread.
And forgive us of our trespasses.
As we forgive those
who trespass against us.
#Ashes, ashes... we all fall down#
Children!
Come now, all together.
Show Miss Irena how we
know our bedtime prayers.
Now I lay me down to sleep,
I pray the Lord my soul to keep;
And if I die before I wake,
I pray the Lord my soul to take.
First month. Room and board.
Is there anything else I should know?
She had a brother.
- This is Adam.
- Hello, Adam!
- Does he speak Polish?
- Perfectly.
Irena.
Jacob!
I didn't mean to frighten you.
I have to be so careful.
Is Eva all right, Karolyna?
Yes, everything's the same.
Irena, your instinct
to take our daughter.
It is difficult, Irena.
But it's the right thing to do.
Eva has met with community leaders.
They want to speak about
hiding their children.
Of course
And what if my wife and I do
not survive the war?
Who will claim our son?
I keep a record of every child.
And if this record or you are destroyed?
What guarantee can you give
our children will survive?
I can not guarantee anything,
not even escape from the Ghetto.
Babies will pass more easily,
but if they can speak
they must speak Polish.
They must know Catholic hymns
and prayers.
My children only speak Yiddish.
I understand this is very difficult.
They will need to memorize
their new Christian names,
their new home address,
the entire history of their new family,
harmless gossip about
their neighbors - all of it.
What you are saying is we must
teach our children to lie.
To survive, yes.
What about conversion?
I make it clear I do not wish this.
You may not wish it, but on young,
impressionable minds,
time and education will surely
dim any memories of their past.
In this case, he will grow up
a good Christian.
For mothers and fathers,
to give away a child
is an unthinkable act.
This is the truth.
The other truth is Hitler calls
Jews a cancer on the nation
and speaks openly about the annihilation
of every Jew on the continent.
Outside these walls there are
Poles prepared to risk their lives
to save your children.
We Jews, we Jews have survived
in the hardest times.
And now we are faced
with another extinction.
Perhaps this time we can only
be saved by a new generation of Jews.
How wise are we to take away
the birthright of this new generation?
I recommend we
consider this proposal.
I am not in favor of sending our
children into such a dubious world.
Now America is in the war.
This news favors our liberation
for this we should wait.
Our dear friend has presented us with
the difficult truths of our time.
We should thank her for
her courage to speak.
Jasio go back,
there's another bag!
- No! I will not.
- Go get it!
Let me go!
No, No!
Hey! Jasio! Stop!
Jasio!
Sister Jolanta. Walk with me.
Please, please.
My name is Michal Laski,
I know who you are and what you do.
The man you saw just now.
He is Untersturmfuhrer Karl Brandt.
He is in charge of Jewish Resettlement.
We are told in a few
months they will begin
to send everyone in ghetto
to work camps in the East.
- Why do you tell me this?
- I have a son, Jasio.
Ten years old.
His mother died last year,
he has no one.
- He has you.
- He lives with smugglers,
goes under the wall at night,
risks his life every day.
I want to get him out before
he's caught and shot.
If from time to time I help you,
will you help me?
Mr. Laski, I will help your
son without conditions.
If from time to time you help me,
you would be helping many
children, including your son.
There's a passage through a
brick wall on Twarda Street.
On the other side in
the abandoned house.
Your Jasio... does he
have red hair like you?
Yes but thanks to God
he now wears a cap.
You know about this new German
that is now in charge of the Ghetto.
Yes, for work camp resettlement.
Stefan!
Do not be like this.
You know how many thousands of Jews
have disappeared from the Lodz Ghetto.
Vanished. And to where?
Some place they call Resettlement.
Doctor Korczak told me
to prepare for the worst.
If there is no other way,
that is what I must do.
Where is everyone?
What has happened?
Books, bank accounts, invoices,
receipts they've taken over all of it.
Who?
The Gestapo.
Guten tag.
Amen.
Karolyna, can you tell us why this night
is different from all other nights?
Sweetheart?
I know why tonight is different.
Tonight is different because once
we were slaves and now we are free!
Jacob...
Welcome... Papa!
I am not here for Seder.
I have some news you must hear.
The underground received information
verified by Polish train machinists,
some lucky Jews who escaped,
even from a few good Germans.
They all say camps are being built.
Concentration camps, work camps.
Auschwitz is like this, we know.
You remember the thousands of Jews
who were deported from Lodz,
the ones who disappeared.
Last week 300 train cars of
clothing returned for sorting.
What else, Jacob?
We hear rumors they are building
another camp. Treblinka.
Only 90km from Warsaw.
Where there are fake station platforms.
Underground bunkers.
One thing they have not
constructed - barracks.
No barracks?
I do not understand.
Why no barracks?
Mama, they do not...
In such camps,
the only purpose is death.
We need to find a way
to get you out of the Ghetto.
Get out, you say! Get out how?
Get out to where?
Papa.
Irena has made
an offer for Karolyna.
- There is a convent in the countryside.
- This is not possible.
She will become converted!
Never!
Chaim!
These many months
I have said nothing.
Now I will give my opinion.
Our dearest Irenka has risked
her life for us many times.
Now, she has made an offer for
Karolyna we must accept.
I believe a convent is best.
- No, no, no. This must not be done.
- Chaim Rozenfeld!
You have loved me since I
was a little girl in pigtails
and after these many
years you know very well
an opinion from me
is not a suggestion.
Next time, when you come
she will be prepared.
Irena...
the Underground knows
what you're doing.
They want to help.
There's a man you should speak to,
goes by the name Trojan.
- 24 Zurawia Street.
- Zurawia, 24.
For Karolyna, I promise,
I will do everything...
We know that, Irena. We know.
You have created an efficient
network already saved many children
and so far no one has
been betrayed or exposed.
We the Underground have
a good deal of money.
And Victor here has many contacts.
It could be a good arrangement.
This money, where does it come from?
Polish government in exile in London.
- To help the Jews?
- Zegota is only for that.
- Who is Konrad Zegota?
- He does not exist.
Which makes him hard to find,
especially for the Germans
who will never stop looking.
What is your proposal?
We will help you rescue
children. If you agree.
I agree.
We will provide you with funds,
papers and identification.
You obtain this by picking
of Konrad Zegota's laundry.
A little shop on Bracka street,
near Three Crosses Square.
- Looks like we're back in business.
- Let me count.
Look. Identification cards.
Very good quality, these will work.
Hey, what's going on?
They're deporting the
section, all the orphanages.
What's happening?
They've begin Deportations,
started with the orphanages.
- Which once?
- All of them.
Stefan!
Stay quietly and obey the orders.
If you act against resettlement,
you will be shot.
Attention! All Jews.
You will be resettled to the East.
You will be safe.
But you must remain
calm and obey the orders.
Stefan!
You must be get out of here.
Do it, for me, for the children.
You must see and remember.
And then survive.
Go. Go on, quickly.
Now.
Go, go!
You know how to do it.
Attention! All Jews.
May God walk with you.
Go! Go!
Remain calm as you move forward.
If you act in any way against
resettlement you will be shot.
Attention! All Jews.
Obey the orders and remain
calm as you move forward.
If you act in any way against
resettlement you will be shot.
Thank you, Lord God.
- Mom.
They took so many children.
They took them. They took them
and there was nothing I can do.
I've heard this news.
Who told you?
Your friend, Irena.
Now we must be quiet.
Everything will be all right.
We can not do it now.
Please, one more day. Just one.
He will understand.
Now is still possible,
tomorrow is uncertain.
- This section may be emptied.
- Tomorrow he will be ready, I promise.
Look.
No more courthouse entrance.
It's a big problem.
Oh, stop fiddling,
- You're making me nervous.
- You need to get more rest
For Heaven's sake,
if I'd had a stroke, I'd be dead.
I'm telling you, I got up too fast,
I fainted. That's all.
It is serious, Janina.
With this I can hear the truth.
You are a very brave young woman.
Stefan?
There is room for two.
What are you doing?
A little carpentry.
What do you think?
I feel a little bit confined.
I think I need to get out.
It's, it's not opening.
It's stuck.
It, it, hmm...
Can you please try? Please.
- It's stuck from the outside.
- No. Please, open it. Please.
OK. All right, I need to,
we need to get out of here.
Mama?
Irenka?
Any Jew that hide and
found hiding will be shot.
Jews out!
Jasio!
Are you hungry?
Drink this.
You must drink something.
Jasio?
Do you remember?
I can't leave them.
I will not.
You have done a good thing,
Jasio, a very important thing
and it may be hard to understand but
the future will need your compassion
even more than now.
Which is why tomorrow
you must save yourself.
You know the coal room?
Where the Rabbis study?
Two o'clock tomorrow my friend
will meet you there.
She wears bright red lipstick.
Be strong,
say your good byes.
I will never see you again.
I will never see any of
you again, any of you.
Yes, you will, I promise.
No, you can't promise.
Nobody can promise anything any more!
Darling... Darling.
I love you with all my heart.
My love for you is so big and
strong it will never go away.
It will always be with you.
Whenever you think of me,
I will be there,
right over your shoulder.
Forever and ever.
- Your name?
- Aniela Procowna.
- And where are you from?
- Krakow, Poland.
But when I grow up I want
to live in Bavaria.
My uncle says Germany
is much more beautiful...
- Your name?
- Aniela Procowna.
- And where are you from?
- Krakow, Poland.
But when I grow up I want
to live in Bavaria. My uncle...
Quick, quick in!
Out, out. Get out of here.
Out, get out! Out. Out!
Leave them alone,
they are old and sick.
They did nothing to you.
Jasio?
Michal Laski!
Everybody out!
You...
Come with me!
And you, come!
Get away from here.
Walk slowly.
- I saw Jasio. He will get out.
- Thank you.
Jasio?
We can not wait for him any longer.
I know.
Come.
Jasio.
Jasio!
Jasio, no.
Papa. Papa!
- I tried to get out but they...
- It's all right, it's all right.
I am here.
I am here now.
Stay close to me.
Hold on to me.
Hold on tight.
No! He's my son!
My family is protected!
Come.
Look at that.
Thank you.
Treblinka
60 km
Papa! Papa!
Jasio, I understand now why you
lived in the street.
It was God's way to make you
strong so you can survive.
Here, give him my sweater.
I cannot do it. I'm afraid, Papa.
Please, I can't.
Yes, you can.
Listen, to me, you can do it.
Jasio, listen to me.
Land on your elbows,
keep your head down.
- Come with me.
- Keep your head down
and stay still until you
see the train is gone.
Papa, please come with me!
I love you, papa.
Then you must run as fast
as you can into the trees.
I love you, Papa. Please! Come with me.
I don't want to please!
You must be brave.
Jasio, are you ready?
I can't! Papa! I can't.
Please come with me. Please.
- One...
- No!
Two...
Three!
Papa.
Children!
Children.
This is Angela, she will be joining us.
Please don't leave me, please.
This war will end and you will survive
to be a mother and tell your story.
And one day, if we are both very clever,
I will find you.
I promise.
Now there is something you
must promise me.
You must promise that
you will always remember
that you are the famous Miss Nijinska,
Prima ballerina.
I love you.
Me too.
Go on, now.
Let me go.
Laundry Kazik
Gestapo.
Come with us!
Come!
Come on!
Over and under.
Shouldn't you have taught
me this as a child?
That is beautiful.
- You are so mean to me.
- He's telling the truth.
It's hideous.
This is never going to be...
Stay outside.
I walk into.
Gestapo!
I will do it.
Open.
Open!
- Irena Sendler?
- I am
Do you have Jews here?
Of course not.
It's against the law.
You will come with us.
Let me get a few things.
There is no need.
Irena Sendler.
Good afternoon.
I work for the city of Warsaw.
Department of Social Services.
I know. I know.
Your father was a doctor,
worked with Jews.
He worked with anyone who was sick.
Yes. Until the Jews gave him Typhus.
Who is Konrad Zegota?
Who?
I don't know.
Who is Konrad Zegota?
I don't know!
You have been denounced by many people.
For example, the little shop
where you pick up your laundry.
On Bracka street, near
Three Crosses Square.
We know you are not so involved
with these criminals.
And if you tell us where to find
this man you will not be executed.
Sendler! Get up!
Sendler!
Dentist.
You're wasting your time and mine.
"Zegota will help you"
I'm ordered to place a dressing,
I place a dressing.
For what? She will be
dead in the morning.
I do what I'm told, that's all.
Stefania?
You're alive!
I swear, I told them nothing.
I was quiet as a mouse.
You know I would never betray you.
- As a good soldier.
- Yes.
A good soldier.
You have done very well.
Out!
Thank you for what you did.
- We did it together.
- No, I mean for me.
Out!
Not you!
No! Wait!
What are you doing?
Aim!
Target!
Fire!
Get away from here.
Go!
But, I, I don't have
my identification card!
You are dead with them!
Go! Run away! Get out!
Irena!
Thank you.
They will find out.
And they will search for you.
I'll be safe.
Your mother is right.
In time you will need a specialist.
I know for you this difficult, but
please until end try to stay of them.
Hi Irenka.
What you have done,
is a good and decent thing.
So many I could not save.
Believe me, in this world...
to do a decent thing is not so bad.
It is time.
We must be in mountains before dark.
I love you.
Do not worry, I'll be fine.
Go.
- Irena...
- Trojan.
Thank you so much for all
you've done.
No. Thank you.
There's something
Konrad Zegota must have.
They are all here.
Every child.
Where we hid them.
When all this is over, they must be returned
to whatever remains of their families.
I will do it, I promise.
Thank you.
From now on you are
Irena Dabrowska.
Once upon a time,
there was a little girl.
I am so fond of stories
that begin that way.
I have kielbasa and beer with onions.
- You like it?
- Yes, I do.
- First, you must come meet my pigs.
- Really Piotr, it's not necessary.
It is true, what they said about Jews
that they're terrible farmers.
Please, please put me down.
Oh, thank God.
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
Irena and Stephen were married in 1947.
Irena Sendler saved 2500 Jewish
children during the Holocaust.
In 2007, she was nominated
for the Nobel Peace
Not so long ago it was the Mother's Day.
So today I would like us to
celebrate that holiday
in the name of some of the most
anguished mothers in the world.
The Jewish mothers who
separated from their children
during those terrible times.
And let us reflect on
those polish women.
Who took the Jewish children in and
brought them up as their own.
Risking their lives, every day
and every hour in the process.
They loved those children
so much, that when war ended.
They could hardly bare to part of them.
So let us give thought to those mothers.
Irena died in Warsaw
in May 2008. She was 98.