Siam Museum
Why do you like to take this kind of photos?
I like close-up photos because
They lead us to see something...
that we cannot see if we look widely
So When you shoot face close-up picture...
Where is your focal point?
They maybe eyes
Excuse me, my little baby is crying
So handsome
Too bad he's already had a baby
How are you my son? Why are you crying?
You must have been hungry
You look so angry
Haaeee Don't be mad at me
"All of us"
"have someone who is hidden in the bottom of the heart"
"When we think of him, we will feel like umm.."
"Always feel a little pain inside"
"But we still want to keep him"
"Even though I don't know where he is today.."
"What is he doing"
"But he is the one who makes me know this"
"A little thing called LOVE"
Mario Maurer
Pimchanok Luevisedpibool
I get it, why you ask us to visit this shop everyday is because of this
Because of what!!!
His motorbike is so strange
Hey...Look at her, she is this beautiful
Look at her
He is super smart, it's not weird that you would crazy about him
Are you non-sense? I don't
Mom, Fried rice and breakfast at this table
Nam, after you serve that table go to the market for me?
Sure
Umm Cute
How are things at School?
Good, I'm still with Cheer Gie Nim
Aren't you bored with each other? You've been with them since Grade 1
She has no choice, The appearance like P'Nam and the gang,
No one would like to be with
Friends are friends not because of only appearance
But it should be the first thing to consider
I'm lucky that I look like mom
If I looked like dad like P'Nam....
I surely couldn't have boyfriend when I grow up
Hey.... Stop Stop
You have grown up, but still have a quarrel
Pang you too, Don't speak about dad like this
If he know, he will be sad
Go to where you want
Dad is in America, he cannot hear us
Mangoes?
You want mangoes?
New Grade 10 students are all smart
Yes, we studied at girl school since kindergarten, so boring
Have you calculated it?
Nim got 28
25-35 The man who's with you must have leadership characteristic
You'll be warmed So.. He should be
P'Tom, the leader of Buddhist club
Cheer's is 15
15-25, The man who suits you is a sport man.......
So is should be P'Ken those basketball player
Uuyyyy he is not your man,then
For mine, A gangster for sure
Yes, you're right. For you, he must be
P'Maew......He is a bit wild
Nam's is 30
The man who suits you is an artist
Umm who is he?
When it is an English class, you guys look saturnine huh?
Be cheerful like when you're in the lunch time
Don't smile Nam
You're good at English subject
but for other subjects
SO BAD
Dark skin!
Ok, Today we will learn Vocab and Grammar
From lyrics
Pass the lyrics to your classmate
His name is Shone, a grade 10 freshman
But his past is so terrible, he's wicked
That's not true?
Students, for Inspiration you change A to E
Then, it will be Inspire
Two girls had to resign from school because of him, a danger boy
(I don't believe)
Don't meddle with him
You know? You know?
My friend used to be in the same school he was in
(What are you talking?)
(It's my matter)
(But I'm teaching)
But I'm teaching
Cheer
Stand up
What is the meaning of you're the inspiration?
What is the meaning!!!
Right, you're the inspiration (in Thai)
You're the inspiration
It's true, It's the thing that we must have....
Even me
I love
Read the heading line at the same time
(Women's Bathroom)
Karin
Do this question
Who did this?
"It's because of you that come to me"
"To stay in my heart every night and day"
"The world has pathway"
"This world has stairs"
"Has love and heart"
"That lead us to meet each other"
"In this world"
"Has two of us"
You're good
When will you register as a school forward player?
Playing like this everyday is fun enough
You're still scared? Let's continue to play then..
P'Shone
P'  Shone Ka
Hey, I'll be back
Who is that girl?
Where?
What she's thinking she is, P'Shone has to go for her
It may be the girl whose P'shone used to...
No way!!!
I'm sorry
Uncle Chang!!
Mom, P'Nam
Uncle Chang is here
Sawaddee ka, I miss you
Uncle
Sawaddee ka, P'Chang
Eh Pang, it's you
Haven't seen you in a long time, but your hair still has bad smell
Eh Nam, You've grown up a lot
Eh, Pim!!
You're asleep?
Yes, I still cannot adapt myself from the America flight
No
Is my dad fat like you?
He works as a chef assistant
He has to lift food tray, he has muscle
He also give you picture
Let's me see
Wait
Pim
Your husband...
want to tell you that he will send money at the end of this month
and he also told me that
(handsome voice) Pim, my darling
I promise that I won't let the house seized
Pim and daughters, be patient
Dad should come to visit us
(normal voice) Your dad told me that
If one of you get the 1st result in the exam
He will send a plane ticket from the US
but the ticket is expensive
Will he really send it to us?
because he know that this is very difficult for Pang and Nam
Let's see
I will get the 1st ranking
You will see, dad
From the 30 th?
two red, two green please
Aunt
Pepsi two glasses, Hurry we're hot
P'
Why did you do like this?
Sorry girl, I'm tired, I'm thirsty
Do you have problem?
We're the school team
Have you heard....
Please let men, children and basketball players
Because I'm a basketball player
Aunt, 4 glasses of Pepsi for football players
Is Pepsi ok?
Yes
Damn it
Hey
You're spreading the dirt on me
Sorry
Understand?
Hey, let me do this
Nam Nam Nam
They're fighting at the back of the school
STOP STOP STOP
Nam, where're you going? The motorbike is faster
Hurry
I think you can do this
You want to be the province hero like your father?
You dad couldn't kick the penalty goal successfully
Hey you guys know what...
our province didn't get the national trophy
because of his Father!
We couldn't find the opportunity like this anymore
Damn his father
Unfortunately they're gone, I want to see P'ding get punched
Let's go back
Will you drink this pepsi that P'shone give you?
Why not throw away if you won't drink
(Don't Drink!!)
If that so, why put it in the refrigerator
Ok students, today I have two things to announce
Our school is so dirty because
students don't drop garbage in cans
From now on, you will have to pay fees
1 piece, 1 Baht
You think it's too expensive?
I give you a new promotion package
throw all day, throw anywhere, do it
Pay for all the pieces, 50 Baht
Throw it scatteringly, I will clean it up
After this morning standing
Students whose name are on this list
Go to the ruling administer room urgently
Jakkawan M.4/5
and Ashawin M.4/7
cross the arms!!
If you fight each other again
I will call your parents
Understand?
Especially you, Shone
You have some skill for taking pictures
Now, The province has pictures contest
You should go to register
Maybe you will make some reputation to school
It's better than a quarrel
Understand?
Yes
You can go now
Thank you teacher
The next queue!!
P'......I umm
Yesterday..
I'm sorry
It's ok
It's not because of you
Plaster...
Get well soon
Nam
Thank you
Hey, P'Shone know my name
He know my name
Hey look at this
This shop has this kind of book?
20 Methods
Get senior to be your 'boy friend'
There they go, white ribbon gang
I'll be back
Look at her
When does she be friends with that gang?
(Get to the 1st in exam)
Are you for real?
Yes
I miss my dad
Never seen him for 5 years
Earn
P'Kai has confessed love to me
Because of this book!
Is it true?
This book works?
Yes
before Pooh becomes P'Tor girlfriend
she also bought this book
"9 recipe of love (for students)"
It really worked for her
Aww, don't you go with that gang?
No
I walked with them
but they blamed me that I stole the scene
The 1st method
win his heart by The Greek's belief
Go to the place where you can see many stars on the sky
Then, use your finger draw the line connecting stars
as the abbreviation of your man
Get out of my way
Look at them, wow
I won't step there then, the area is full!!
Hey, Nam
Don't you want to draw with us?
No, I won't
I think, it looks non-sense
Um, they are clearly seen
I will go to draw it at my home
I'll go, Nam
See you
"The only star"
"that I always wait to see everyday"
"I want it to be the same star..."
"that you also keep an eye on"
"that only star"
Oh! You guys are diligent
Where are you going to compete?
compete around here
You catch it!
Hey, my hands are not free
I told you, my hands not free
kick for what(E-san's accent)
You are Chinese?
Uh, I'm sorry
When I'm angry, I think about my ancestors
Hey, look at this
Look at this
come on Shone
The poster for the 3rd photo contest that you asking for
Look at him
He always Play
Play can play all day
But he doesn't dare to play for the school
He plays for fun, he's not serious
If he's serious, He will not dare
If only I could score that penalty kick
Again, you blame yourself again
Our son may not afraid of taking penalty kick
even though, his friends tease him about it
Or, if he's really afraid
He will pass the fear one day
Look at the real person who missed the kick
He can pass that bad time till today
Why you look strange today?
This
My doctor suggested me
He want me to use this new dental brace
Beautiful right?
Eh You think it's beautiful?
It's not beautiful at all
Hey, look at it again
I don't see it's beautiful
Hey, you intend to do it with P'Ken
Yes
YOU HAVE TO EAT, EAT
EAT,EAT,EAT
Yeah, P'Ken has eaten the rice
You're crazy
It's because he's eating
How can you call it hypnotization
What are you two doing?
This, The 2nd method
It's the old method from Mayan
we have to concentrate our mind
Then, look at our beloved
Try to control his mind
Tell him to do things we want
If he follows our command
it means that he is our soul mate
(Turn this way, Turn this way)
(Turn, Turn)
Hey, P' has turned to me
Who? Who's turned? Nam?
No, It's nothing
Did you hypnotize P'Shone?
Hey No, are you crazy?
I didn't
So, why did you tell us
This book is non-sense?
because, it takes beliefs from
many countries, that island, this island
It surely cannot be trusted
Then, did you follow the methods?
Yes, I did
Eyy
You shouldn't disclose this little matter
I'm afraid that I will be teased
You don't have to worry about being tease
Because We...
Will definitely tease you
The 3rd method
This comes from Scotland
sneaking to bring things
that have the meaning of heart to him
and he must not know who gives the gifts
so the target will know that
there's somebody who interested in him
that's My jelly, be careful
How could you make it fall?
thank you very much teacher Pon
sated egg for you
Yes
It means that when you're traveling
you thought of me all the time
I will eat them till they're all gone
Thank you very much
thank
Teacher Pon's salted egg, Eh
Pon's egg, Salted teacher, Eh!!
Teacher Pon's salted egg, Eh!!
That right
Teacher Pon's gives me ka
Teacher's Pon's salted egg
You're not going to tell me that....
Yes, Teacher Pon bought these from the trip
How many of the boxes?
4 ka
4 boxes?
Damn it, Salted egg!!
Maybe, you cannot finish all of them, be careful then
We forgot one thing
our country is tropical
Mangoes?
Yes
Other people give flower or handkerchief
but you would give him mangoes?
How is it romantic?
Hey, Hey
That's him
Oh!! He's so handsome haha
Let's go, go, go
Mango cake ka
I did it myself
Thank you
It looks delicious
Are you ok?
I'm ok
It's The end
We totally lost
She only did a little
but it works
yes
She's cute
good future housewife
How can we compete with?
Change the one you love, then
Actually
I have another appointment
But teacher Pon invites me to your house for dinner
Importantly, It's the first time
Umm...................
If you are really not free, it's ok
We can meet next term
Ohhhh, wait wait ka
Actually, In is free Ka
I can go
Teacher Pon Ka
See you this evening
But, teacher Pon
This dinner is not for the two of us?
Oyy, please don't call it dinner
It's better to call it summer celebration party
Many teachers will come to the party
I guarantee it will be fun
Uhh, ok
Teacher Orn!!!
Teacher In....
I've never surrendered to whoever
This war..
is very important!!!
Teacher!! That's my answer sheet
Ouyy!
Higher, Higher
Teacher
Lift it more, more, Nam
I get an idea
P'Shone must ride Nam to home
Yes
Nam must have dreamed about it
for once in a lifetime
It is right?
When P'Shone ride Nam to home
When getting off the motorbike
When giving mangoes
So romantic
Eyyyyy!!!
Try to look like your motorbike is breaking down
How can it break?
When he try to start...
He will know it
Uh yes
How about losing the key?
How comes it will be missing?
It's here
Hey
It has lost
P' Shone
He's there
Oops
Oww, N' Mango cake
How is your leg?
I just stumbled on the ground maybe my leg is twist
Come on, I will ride for you
Never mind, I'm ok
Oops
Come on, you better come with me
How clumsy I am
Oh, This is so drama
Did she graduate from acting school?
Bye Bye M.1(Grade 7)
Good luck my friends
See you at M.2 class
Mom, Mom
Look at this mom
Pang, stop, Pang!!
Mommy, P'Nam has a boy friend
Nam
If that so, how can you go to see dad?
For this matter, I think you should grow up more before you can involve with it
For today
You should think about studying only
Owww
Cheer, you come here?
Pang called me that her sis is being heart-broken
Have been listening to music for a weak
I think you can forget about P'Shone
Ha Ha Ha
Lower the voice!
My mom will hear
Your mom's not home, she went to the market
Cheer, it's crowd
Nam, when will your mom broaden out the stairs?
Hey Nam, Let's look at another method?
Listen carefully
The 7th method
It's the Gypsy's method
The love must build up our self
Use the power of love to make us smarter
More beautiful
and be better in everything
He will look back at us finally
Ehh, What're you doing?
P'Shone is handsome
So Nam must be beautiful
Awww!!!
Umm, her skin is almost strip out
"Monday, I'm waiting"
"Tuesday, I'm still waiting to see"
"see..see...if you are fine"
"Wednesday, you're still not here"
"Neither in the morning, nor later"
"Thursday is also empty"
"Friday or Saturday or even Sunday"
"None of the day that I don't miss you"
"None of the day that you will come back"
"To be in our old days"
"How long it will be like this? I don't know"
"How many months or years?"
"How many billions of our past memory?"
-Eh what is it?
It's Kamin (wipe for brighter skin)
"I never don't miss you"
Heyyy
Hello, girls
Tell me if you want something
Take it easy
(Shock!! Pornchai made the team lose to the champion cup)
Nam
We cannot find
Maybe he's out
Maybe he's not home
I don't see his motorbike
Hey, girls
Have you found it?
Uhhh
found it
This
Aww, what do you come to buy?
You play table-tennis?
Why do you look yellow?
Do you have Jaundice?
P'Shone
Aww, N' Mango cake
What do you come to buy?
a dozen of table-tennis balls
Ok, follow me
Ayyyyyyy
Come over hear boys and girls
register to drama club with teacher In??
Drama club is here
We have many stories to play
you can be princess, prince
Hero, heroine, it's up to you my children
Mum, Teng, Nong used to be in my club
Come on ka
Are you interested?
Uh, Khun Panya Nirankun also used to be in our club
Is it true?
If you want to be famous, come to our club
Come on children
(Thai classical dance club)
It's the place to register, not walking pass
You should take of your glasses, Nam
I'm not used to..
I think
We are not suitable for this concept at all
White skin, Beautiful, Chinese-look alike
whatever quality of that classical dancers
Yes, it's true.
Every year, teacher Orn selects only
good and beautiful children
and when they're dancing
the whole school students come to see them
Umm, that's right
it's not like those drama club students
They are all ugly
Nobody wants to see them performing
Huyyy
but we should try it
The four of us may be
not white, not look Chinese
but beautiful, dark skin
pioneer generation
Heayyy, P'Shone
P'Shone
Which club do you want to register?
Photography
You can tell me, if you want a model for pictures
I like to take scenery pics, not people
Hey, are you kidding me?
Ok, I'm kidding then
Come on
I will take it
So, you already aren't yellow?
Do you get brighter?
May be a little..
I will wait for you guys
on the school festival day
You see? Nam
You got good feedback from P'Shone
that you're brighter
You have to be confident
If we can perform the dancing
We must be famous
Must be good and beautiful
Remember it
If not sure about the beautifulness
you can go to other clubs
Hey Faye, why did you speak like that?
No, I didn't
I spoke with Kwan
Did I? Kwan?
Liar
You criticize us!!
Hey, you must stop
The ones who make problems, Go out!
Wait
Faye and Kwan
Stay here
Nam
I'm sorry for that matter
I have to apologize you too.
I bought a surplus drink
You can take it
I give you
Wait!! Stop it
Let this girl drink first
Why don't you drink
You should leave
If you don't want to drink water with fish sauce
then, don't forget to pour it away
Look at that girl's behavior
You're here!!
I've been searching for long
Look at my face
Smile
be sullen
Laugh
It's perfect
See me at the auditorium tomorrow,then
OK
Teacher ka
Don't speak out loud
cause I offer limited students
Understand?
Teacher In
Ouyy, why do you stretch your mount like that?
Teacher In, Teacher In!! How are you?
You alright?
Teacher In, are you alright?
Teacher In
Do you need something? Head master
No, Nothing
Are you fine?
I'm fine
Hmm
See you tomorrow
I'm fine
Ohhh
Water
Nooo!!
It's suitable, I'm guarantee
Teacher
Oh, you come too late
I won't let you play huh?
It's good ka
Oyyy wait wait wait
I'm just kidding
nahh
Teacher we....
are going to tell you that
Don't worry
I will let you play good roles
Umm...
Teacher ka, We are going to tell you that.......
Umm.. We'd like to dance
Do....Do
Do
Do....
Hard or not, we will never be afraid
cause we want to perform drama with you very much
For the stage drama that I will proudly present..
in this year
the name of it is..
Snow white and the seven
Dwarfs sss. sss.
Nam
You're the best in English language
So.....
You'll play as Snow white
Me????
Ready
OMG!!
A rabbit!!
What are you doing here?
Paint color
Paint color 'inside' the box?
I bough interior painting color
Go paint other place
Wait Wait
You, go jot down tel number of all art students
Must not miss any
Teacher Pon ka
My students...
have a gift for acting
I'm guarantee that...
Uhh... Teacher In krab
Are you sick?
No....
I'm ok
Orhhhhhhhh
Teacher Pon may not used to my natural face
For the lipstick...
it's wasted to apply it
More importantly
I give an advantage to 'someone'
So
Teacher In give an advantage too much?
Oyyyy!!
better measure with work result
cause about the beautifulness
I think they are about the same
and now, I taught my students
wear make up in my style
When they grow up
they will be natural beautiful
And now!!!!
This is the natural beauty!!
suit their age
Are you sure that...
You've already taught them?
Is this stage drama or...
stage comedy Teacher In?
It may be Monkey drama then, Teacher Orn
This is children's creativity
(9 recipe of love book)
Aww, you're going home?
Yes
(P'Shone 086-xxxxxxx)
Be careful
She walked normally when coming in
Why claudication when going back?
Teacher krab
Ka?
Water??
Thank you ka
Uhh
Teacher krab
Ka?
My football will become flat
I'm sorry
This is P' Pin, M.5 senior
She will take care of clothes and make up
for our drama
clap the hands welcome her
I'm counting on you Pin
I think we should start
Ok let's start..
So, start with me first.
Oyyy I forget
I don't play the drama
Let's start with Snow white
begin with Nam first??
Yes, Nam first
How about it, my make up skills?
She looks the same
Snow white with dental braces
Doctor!!
I don't want to wear dental braces anymore
Will get them out
Nam, is Nam here?
OK, You're ready. Stand by Nam
The prince? The prince?
He has diarrhea
Is he crazy? Have diarrhea in this big rehearsal day.
Hey You!!
You!
Who is painting the color?
Come on, rehearse instead of him
Me?
It's not long, act as the prince
Come closer, closer
When I say action, you'll be ready to kiss
Action!!
Oh
Ehh Nam Nam!!
You're almost fall to break your neck
Aww
You stare each other too long
Go paint!
Nam go stand by
Koy ready!
You don't know anything
Aww
Ready? Start when I say action
Action!
Hello? Sawaddee krab
Pornchai sport shop krab
I'd like to speak with Khun Shone
Yes, I'm speaking
Hello?
Aww
He's already hanged down
Aww you!!
Where're you going? Toilet?
The witch is here
It's the climax
It's an excellent part
See? See?
She not dead yet! Believe me!
Our student got the championship for photo competition
No one ever tell me
Uh.. the committeeman just called me.
Herrr Khun, You should pay attention to your student's performance
Hurry up
I'm ironing
but the heat is not enough
Khun Rabue, this!!
Uhh yes
Plug it in for me
It's marvelous
You're great. Very good
You've already ironed it
The shoe's trail is still here
Aww, I ironed it, not wash it
Or we should wash it?
It's too late
Go Go Go!! Grab your bag
Hurry
-Krab
Excellent
Ok, This evening
I will pay for your dinner!
(To Snow white)
(I've tasted it, no poison)
Wait Wait Wait
Listen to me
Not full
Not go home!!!
Hey
To Snow white
Who is the owner?
already eaten
It must be P'Shone's
You dare to speak
Hey Nam, It may be that boy
Frog prince
a frog princess and a frog prince.. suit each other
He's too bad
Why you didn't come to see the drama?
You went to see those dancers, right?
You're bad
I told you, he isn't hurt.
His head is solid
Hey
Have you greeted your daddy, my son?
Hey, How do ya come?
Hi Hi
Hey, you guys
This is my friend, Top
Known him since kindergarten
Sawaddee krab
Waddee krab
He's cute
N'
Hey, it's enough.
Go
Will you be here for long?
Umm, my dad may stay here till retire
But If I can entrance to uni in Bangkok, I will go
Who is that?
He's cute
He's cute like P' Shone
Let's go to the school cafeteria
Wow, Wow!!
Beautiful girl
Hey girl!
What's your name?
It's you.. What's your name?
Hmm, embarrassed. You're shy
Oww, where're you going? going? Hey Hey
N' come to fight with me?
Maybe Teacher In projects it.
Already shown here all day?
Hey Hey Hey
That's N' Snow white that is in the TV
She's cute
Does she has boy friend?
Might not
but I think you shouldn't court her
Hey Why?
Is she too young?
I used to ask for Tel. number of grade 5 girl.
(End of M.2)
(Passing to M.3)
Shone krab
It's your turn krab
Again, every times that I play football...
You always give me to kick penalty
Kick it by yourself, then
You still don't recover from it?
Till now, your dad may have forgotten it
No, it's not that
it's because the kick is too easy
So I don't want to kick
Oh ho, Christiano Ronaldo
P' Top ka, Could we take pictures with you?
Krab
Me too?
So, who will take it for me?
You take picture for me first ok?
Uh.. I will take it for you two
No, I won't
Thank you ka
Stand close more
One... two
three
Oh, What!!
What!! Why you're doing like this?
You must apologize!
What's going on? STOP STOP
Stop
Hey, You could make something like this?
I don't know
I'm the referee, head master
How many days left for the region sport competition?
about 2 weeks ka
but athletes and cheer students have practiced so hard
Who will be the drum major, then?
Look like I have to consult with teacher Orn
Maybe she can help
Don't worry, head master
I will get it done
My mouth is hurt
Nam!!!
Since I was born till I am fully adult
I've never seen anyone who are perfect and excellent as much as you
You're good looking very much
Teacher In, you should speak straightly
Do you have something?
Umm......I....
I want you to be a drum major for our school
In the region sport day
Ha!!!
Don't need to Ha!! anymore
It's you
You're the most suitable girl
but, it's only 2 weeks
I don't think I could do
but I don't see anyone who could help
Except you, Nam
Ok, I promise
I will become a nun for your favor
Become a nun?
How about two years?
or all of my life?
I can do it, Nam
be perpendicular
Look up
Throw
Just after throwing, look at the spear
After that, when it's near ourselves
Grab it
Then continue to walk
Is it difficult?
It's not hard at all
Can you try?
I've already had my spear
You just have to do it, that's yours
This is mine
Ready? Aim at the target
If you're ready, throw!!!
One Two Three, Throw!
It's hard
Why doesn't she find other girls?
Hey, don't get discouraged
These are only a few days
Here, this method is important
In the 9 recipe of love book
The last method was written that..
If you want to do because of love
Do it all-out with your heart
Your beloved will come to you finally
Heayy, Nam
You've come this far
Fight with all your might
It's not only for school drum major
You will be the leading drum major for our province
Fight
"Far.. Far away"
"Too far left... Too far"
Top, pass to me
Top!
"Far...Too far"
Hey
Again, you glance at  girls again
Head master
I can guarantee that our marching band will be the most remarkable
How about drum major?
Oh don't worry at all
Beautiful, Tall, White skin
Overall, she's wonderful
Teachers, Be careful!!
I'm sorry
Don't tell me she is our leading drum major
Yes but she has been doing well in all the past-time
Today, it may be her first failure
Throwing like a boomerang like this?
If she also fail in the real day, what're we going to do?
It may not happen
replace her
or else I will replace you!
but we only have 1 week left, head master
I am in trouble
The head master get hold of the spear?
Who will be the school drum major?
I don't know, serve Teacher In right
She didn't select beautiful and skillful like us
She insisted on that whoever girl
Each of Her students are so terrible
It's good we're not her students
If so, we would have low profile
How can you speak like this?
Because It's true
Bug face
I will make those girls see that
Teacher In students are not terrible
Use Broom?
Where did you get it from?
I borrowed from the janitor
Even though it's light, it's ok to use
I won't let anyone look down on us and Teacher In
Everyone
Today
Play at the utmost of your strength
That That
Will you do it?
My son is going to kick the penalty goal?
Let's get back
Wait Wait!
What a surprise, he's going to kick the penalty?
Uh, Am I deceptive?
It's ok
Do you know?
It's because of his dad, our province couldn't get the national trophy
Hey, I will let you kick the penalty again
The previous kick was just a warm up
Your aunt's house set this rule?
Yes, it's from my aunt's house
My uncle's house also has this rule
My house too
More importantly, I haven't blown the whistle
He'll kick again
You can play as a forward player for our school now
Yes
Shone is good!
Shone is good
Hmm, sweet smile huh?
I understand
"Far It's too far"
"Even though, It's too far from here"
"I will reach there"
It's perfect, my daughter
Aha, OMG
Umm, excuse me Teacher Orn
I'd like to know that Did your dancers
use to throw headdress and catch it like her?
Higher Higher
Great
How's your sister?
Is she beautiful like the mom?
Alas! She's more beautiful than mom
Very beautiful, Nam
I don't want to move anywhere
I see you speak like this every time
Nam, your beautifulness is too much huh?
On the last year Valentine, She still had dark face
haha
It's from P'Kai, It will be mine
Did Nam give you?
I don't know
Nam, I'll take this pink chocolate?
Yes
How is Nam?
She looks lonely
She's waiting for the only one
And he haven't come
Nam, Come on
Hurry
Go on
Here
It's from a friend of mine
Nam
See you tomorrow 4PM
In front of 3rd floor stairs
I have something to tell you
Hey Shone
Going home with us?
I'll go afterward
Nam
I'm certain that you would come
Is this letter from P'Top?
Yes, That's mine
Do you have something to tell?
Will you be my girl friend?
Uh, Did P'Shone has something to talk with me?
Orhh I just wanted to ask..
Why did you come up here
Now, I know the reason
What is the answer?
If you don't answer
I will think you're ok with it?
Ha!! P'Top?
How come?
P'Shone only spoke like that?
Yes
How about you, Nam?
What did you tell him?
I didn't answer
What am I going to do now, Cheer?
You should wait and see
P'Top is P'Shone best friend
If you do something without considering
P'Shone will surely be angry at you
Are you free today?
Let's go to see football match
Uh I'm not free today
It's not long
Shone will play as a real player for the first time
I can go
Nam
Water
- Thank you
Hey, do you have some drink?
No, I don't
Plan B
Run more
You know it, mr button?
I want to sit behind P'Shone on his motorbike
(The first semester has end)
(See you M.3)
Cheer, which cake do you like to eat in your birthday?
Choose it by yourself
Vanilla cake
Nam likes it
Hello, Nam?
Where are you?
We're choosing birthday cake for Cheer
I come to a dam with P'Shone and friends
I can't go on time
I called Cheer this morning but no one hung up
Happy birthday to Cheer for me then
Yes, I'm sorry
Ok Ok
I will tell Cheer
P' Ka, This piece ka
Squid
I'll be back
What are you doing here?
Uh, I think this area is beautiful
Do you want to eat Squid?
Have you heard of the squid's story?
No
I will tell you
Once upon a time
There were two squids
They had traveled till they met each other
Then, they fell in love
They became a couple
Finally
They got married
On the day of marriage
Squid priest told them to hold hands
So, they held each other hands
held the hands
held hands
held hands, held hands
Ha, P'Shone
Crazy
But cute
The teller or the squids?
The teller
Eh the squids
Umm, I'm confused
I kinda don't want to eat them
I've never eaten squids for so long
Since I heard this story
So...
Did you use to hold someone hand like the squids?
Once
An awkward-face girl
was falling down from the stage
So, I held her hand
Nam!
Why don't you eat squids?
I prepared it myself, it looks delicious
No!!
Why? It's delicious
I'm asking you straightly
Do you like Nam
Uh, You be with her
Why asking me?
It's noting
kidding nah
Are you alright?
I'm Ok, just a little hurt
Let's stand up
Come on, ride piggyback me
Mr Button
Today, P'Shone carries the bag for me
Nam??
Cheer's not home
went with Gie and Nim
Nam didn't go with them?
No ka
Try to call them
I miss the old days
When we're doing home work altogether
An angel must be in heaven
Who want to be in hell like us
Cheer calm down
we still have birth day again in the next year
Nim, I only have 3 friends
If I were her, I wouldn't do like this
Cheer, will you come to do home work at my house?
Why don't you ask P'Shone and friends?
Top has not come yet?
He appoint me to teach a M.3 student
He hasn't come
He go to borrow books to do project work
for a M.3 student
that day
My mom stayed in the hospital
Which day?
The day that my dad missed the penalty kick
I was born that day
So, my dad gave a birth day gift to me
by quitting playing football  his entire life
I'm the one who brings bad luck
Look at it
The province had never come that far till that day
Are you ok?
For me being teased?
I'm ok
I'm used to it
It becomes my surname
Shone
whose dad couldn't score penalty kick
But it's ok
I am a football player
Do you want to become a footballer?
I don't know
For now
I need somebody
Nam
I couldn't find the books
Help me find?
Wait a bit, Shone
Love you but you don't know
Only conceal it withing my heart
P'Shone, I've heard that there will be a surprise for P' Ake birthday
Let's wait and see
Want us to be together
Love you but you don't know
Love you, only if you know
It's the time for our special show tonight
It happened when we studied grade 5
That time, both of us
secretly loved the same girl
Her name is Boe, a grade 4
We tried to compete each other by practicing dancing
So one of us could dance with her in the school party
But when the real day came
Our P'Shone had chickenpox
So the right to dance with her was mine
But finally...
Khun Top gave up his right
So, we both failed
Aww, That's because our P'Shone
Intimidated that he would break up with me
After that, we promised each other...
We will not like the same girl
That's right
Come on
Islander's dance
Happy birthday to you
Nam, tomorrow I will come here the same time
Let's watch P'Shone play football
P'Top doesn't need to pick me up anymore
Why? You will not be free?
No, I mean that....
Don't involve with me anymore
You're angry at me that I kissed your cheek?
But you're my girl friend?
P' Top ka
I've never accepted that I'm your girl friend
So, what's the meaning of all these time
I'm sorry
I have the one I love
Who?
Nam, who is he?
Nam
Since I've been with girls
She is the most painful
I beg you one thing, Shone
No matter what
you won't hit on Nam?
Do you think that the reason she broke up with you is me?
No
It's just unbearable
That my best friend
be with the girl I love
You said like this
I cannot deny
Are you ok with it?
Yes
"I don't understand"
Thank you mom
"Why it must be you.."
"To be the one in my heart"
"I have met many people"
"But It must be you eventually"
"Who are in my heart"
"Love"
"Is not a coincidence"
"Can connect you with me"
"There's only the heart that knows"
"Who is the one in my dream"
"You're the one that I've been waiting"
"Because the heart is begging"
"Cause the heart is calling for"
"Born to be your forever"
"It's because my heart"
"Never confused"
"It's certain that you are the only one"
"There are not many reasons"
"It just because my heart chooses you"
Hey, I've called my friend who is the manager of Bangkok glass team
and?
He told me that
He would accept you to practice in Bangkok Glass club
You cheated me to lose the ball?
For this important matter, who are willing to lie
You should prepare yourself
Maybe after you have finished this year's exam
You might have to go study in Bangkok
Dad!!
Thank you krab
Teacher Pon should tell me sooner
so I could get a scholarship to go with you
I'm sorry
I was busy so I didn't tell you
but there will be a new sport teacher
Oh! At this point of time
No one can replace you
I confirm
Before you go
I beg you one thing
What is it?
This
It's shame
Uh, I asked for the heart
But he gives a whistle
Umm, there he is
The new sport teacher
Aho!!!!
Um I think Teacher Pon.....
should go now
You may miss the flight
Uh, I'm feeling that I'm busy right now
Hurry up
Oh Teacher Orn!!
Come fast, Claim fast?
Sawadde ka
-Sawadde krab
Are you the new teacher?
-Yes
What's your name?
- Boat krab
I want to ride a boat
(Bye Bye M.3)
(See you M.4)
Cheer, why don't you continue to study M.4 here?
cause the vocational school that I admitted
Has pink uniform
Crazy
It's cute
The whole school is pink, very sweet huh?
Monday, I'm waiting
Tuesday, I'm still waiting to see
see..see...if you are fine
Wednesday, you're still not here
Neither in the morning, nor later
Thursday is also emply
Friday, Saturday or Sunday
None of the day that I don't miss you
None of the day that you will come back
to be in our old days
The day that I met you
The day that I was close to you
The day that we held hands
The day that I loved you
The day that I spoke to you
The day that you listened to me
How long it will be like this? I don't know
How many months or years?
How many billions of our past memory?
I never don't miss you
Cheer
I'm sorry
Why you're crying?
Singing a song like this
As if we are acting in a soap opera
Yes, why we are crying?
No, we're not crying
we're laughing
"Friday, Saturday or Sunday"
"None of the day that I don't miss you"
"None of the day that you will come back"
"To be in our old days"
Nam!
We just come back from eating ice cream in the market
We met Teacher In
She said that you got the exam's...
Told that Nam....
got the position of...
got, got what?
Nam got the 1st position
I think so...
Ha!!
The first!!!
Mom, I got the first position
Nam, you can meet your dad,right?
I will meet my dad! My dad! My dad!
Let me kiss you
P' Nam, I got the 8th
Let me go too?
Yes
Heayyyyyyy
I will buy you some sweets
Nam did it
collect the snow for us?
P'Shone
Hmm, you took it? lemme see
50 Baht?
100 Baht
If you can't, hand it back
I took his picture for you
I also had to run away from dogs
How about 70?
No way
You bargain too much
Hand it back,then
No, I won't let you...
Super handsome
Pang's boy friend?
No, he's Bam's boy friend
I just took the pic
I'm a tom boy
P' Nam
Don't tell mom, please
Mom Pang....she
-No, P'Nam
Umm...Have you finished preparing the food?
Pang is hungry
Wait a bit, my daughter
I know that
Don't be precocious too much
How about you?
Dessert for children
- Thank you ka
It may help lining your stomach
Nam, Does P' Shone know?
You're so endurable
Secretly in love with him since M.1 till now
I think, you don't have to tell him
The world will record that...
There is a crazy girl trying to be beautiful
for a boy for 3 years
Even though, he never know anything
Nam! From now on, you may not see him again in all of your life
Won't you do anything?
(9 recipe of love)
I've done every methods
Don't be afraid
You still have us to support
Right?
Yes
You're this beautiful
Good studying
Good habit
So drama
and endurable very much
Why he doesn't like you?
Did you really praise me?
the 10th method
It's from Thailand
the most sincere
Nam, I give you this
Thank you ka
Sign too
Take pic
Picture!
Love
Sign upon my shirt
Thank you
(Upon)
It's the time! Go!
No you can't come in
Nam, you haven't signed my shirt?
P' Shone ka
I have something to tell you
I like you very much
been loving for 3 years
I've done everything
changed myself in every aspects
because of you
Nam
Applied for a classical dancer club
Played a stage drama
Be a drum major
Be better at studying
It's for you
But I know for now that
The thing that I should do the most
And should have done since a long time ago
Is telling you straightly that.....
I love you
(Pin love Shone)
P' Pin?
and P' Shone?
When?
Just a week ago
P' Pin and P' Shone are together
You two are suitable
Cute
Hope you'll be happy
Nam!
I'm ok
Nam
Very suitable
Nam, are you alright?
Nam!
Let her go
Nam, what's going on?
Hello dad
Welcome the junior bangkok glass player
Thank you krab dad
This is uncle Neng, the manager
Sawaddee krab uncle
- Waddee
and this is uncle Nguan, the coach
Thank you uncle Neng Uncle Nguan
Chaiyo!
He's happy haha
I'm glad with you son
Shone
Hurry to prepare your clothes
Tonight you'll have to go with Uncle Neng Uncle Nguan
Tomorrow, you'll be in the camp
Ha!! Today?
Yes, why have to be slow son
"Don't know how long is it"
"That I have to resist everything"
(This book is funny but It makes me know how much that you have tried)
"Hide all of the truth in my...heart"
Be careful
"Every time we meet"
"Every time you turn to me"
(I want to tell you that you had succeeded since you began to do)
"that I pretend to be still"
"Do you know how much I have to force myself"
"Can you hear that?"
"My heart...."
"Is telling you I love you"
She looks the same
Snow white with dental braces
(Answered Pin that she looked the same)
"But I cannot reveal my true feeling to anyone"
(She looked the same, cute as always)
"Can you hear that?"
"My heart..."
(Touched her hand for the first time)
But I had to release it cause others would curious)
"Is waiting there for you to open"
"Can only hope you will know it"
"Some day"
(Gave her an apple but I bit it)
"Though I love you"
"Though I feel it"
"But deep inside isn't brave enough"
(You've been better, Fight! Nam)
"Every time we meet"
"Every time you turn to me"
"That I pretend to be still"
"Do you know how much I have to force myself"
"Can you hear that?"
(Love can win everything especially fear)
"My heart....."
"Is telling you I love you"
(The first day)
(It was very difficult to grow)
(One worm)
It's from a friend of mine
"But I cannot reveal my true feeling to anyone"
"Can you hear that my heart.."
(Today, I gave the rose to Nam)
(I said it was from my friend)
(It's because I am tight-lipped)
"Is waiting there for you to open"
"Can only hope you will know it"
"Some day"
(Today, I saw Top confessed...)
(You know I'm hurt)
(Why our time never match?)
(Me too, wanted you to ride on my back)
Nam
Will you be my girl friend?
"Can you hear that..?"
"my heart..."
"is telling you I love you"
"But I cannot reveal my true feeling to anyone"
"Can you hear that....?"
"My heart..."
"Is still waiting there for you to open"
I beg you one thing Shone
You won't hit on Nam?
"Can only hope you will know it"
"That I'm the one here to love you"
"I'm begging you please know it"
"Some day"
9 years later
This side has windows
Kai, take care of the customers for me?
A moment
Hi, handsome boy
Do you feel asleep?
I'm sorry to bother your time, Shone
Never mind
Your son is like my son
You're a cry baby again
My hair is messing
Pin I have to go now
See you boy
If only his real father would love him like you do
Speak like this again
Call me later?
Shone
How about the TV show that called you?
Will you go?
I don't know
Bye Bye Shone
Bye Bye, you yawn
Hurry up
Continue to Break 2, are you ready?
-A min
Ok
Clothing staffs ready?
- Yes
No worry, It will be perfect
I'm ready
Please be relax
our show isn't formal
Yes
You're beautiful
-Thank you ka
It's good that P' Nam is fashionable
If P'Nam is beautiful as mom like me....
Dare to speak
Teacher Boat
Sawaddee krab
Since then, I've rode this boat all the time
I'm jealous
He likes to do sweet things
He always surprises me
Surprise again
Uh.. That.. That is a rose
I have to eat, if not he will sulk
5..4..3..2..
Now, we're here with Khun Nam
The designer of the beautiful clothes that we've just watched
Sawaddee ka
Our fans may know her well
cause she is the designer in only a few of Thais that are famous in New York
and this is the evidence
This is only a part of her work
Khun Nam, do you know that...
In Thailand, you're also well-known
I still have to develop my skill
So, what work will you do as you came back to Thailand?
There's a brand that would like to organize a fashion show
I think it's interesting, so I agree to do
and because I want to come back
I miss my mom
Khun Nam used to tell reporters that....
When you were young
Umm... I'm sorry
You were so ugly (bug face) and had bad sense of fashion
That's totally different from now
What make you've changed yourself this much?
Because, I fell in love some one
falling in love?
Could you tell the story?
Yes, He was my senior
M.4 senior
He was a football player
and very cute
At that time, I.........
Had bug face studying M.1
Developed myself a lot
If It could make me to be beautiful, to be better
I tried to do it
and tried to study better so he might interest in me
Did he know it, in the end?
He knew but it didn't have a happy ending
I went to study in the US
to stay with my dad
It's bad
but when I think about it
He is like....
my inspiration
He made me use the love in good way
He is like....
The power that support me to be better and better
Till I am today's Nam
Khun Nam, you remember this notebook?
You may recall it?
Yes, I remember
If so, let's welcome the owner of this book
Khun Shone, the former footballer of Bangkok glass
Now, he's changed his career to be a pro-photographer
I want to give it to Nam krab
Nam???
It's Nam's
Please sit
Khun Shone, after you've never met Khun Nam for 9 years.....
Do you have something to tell Khun Nam?
I want to tell you that......
This button
is not mine
It may be Ding's
How about you Khun Nam?
Do you have something to tell him?
I want to ask P' Shone that......
Have you been married?
Umm.........
Um...I have
I have been waiting for some one to come back from the US
"Can you hear that?"
"My heart.."
"Is telling you I love you"
"But I cannot reveal my true feeling to anyone"
"Can you hear that?"
"My heart......"
"Is still waiting there for you to open"
"And I can only hope you will know it"
"That I'm the one here to love you"
"I'm begging you please know it"
"Some day"