Kotoko, what are you going to do?
Next year, we are all going to
start looking for a job.
We need to start doing something.
I thought everyone
was doing amazingly.
But I thought that I hadn't found
anything that I wanted to do.
So do you think I've been egoistic
for hoping my son to...
take over my company?
But even though Naoki-kun doesn't
want to, you still have Yuki-kun.
It will be too late if we
wait for Yuki to grow up.
There is something that
I would like to talk to you about.
I'm thinking of you as my
company's official successor.
That's enough.
Not only my job, but I can't
even choose whom I love.
This is why I don't want to
stay in this house.
The house where I get tied down.
Irie-kun.
I... want to become a doctor.
Becoming a doctor was...
the first job that has
interested me in my life.
Don't tell this to anyone, okay?
Such an important thing...
Why did he tell that only to me?
I really wanted to tell this
to Naoki, too.
Actually...
Honey?
Honey. Honey, are you okay?
Naoki! Naoki!
It's an unstable angina.
I have already told him the
result of the last routine exam.
He has never said anything about it.
Really?
I assume he didn't want to make you
worry, so he didn't tell you.
So how is his condition?
Is he okay?
His attack this time was mild.
But if he keeps pushing himself...
there is a possibility that he will
have a myocardial infarction.
But that's...
We will do anything to avoid that.
So he must be on bed rest and get
treatments. Then we'll see how it goes.
He has to stop working completely.
Um, Mrs. Irie, how is Iri-chan?
It looks like he's had a problem
with his heart for a long time.
But he didn't show it to us at all.
I think he was pushing himself too hard.
Oh no...
He will be on absolute bed rest for
a while and we'll see how he does.
But he will be okay if he's on
bed rest, right?
Yes, so far.
He was suffering so much.
I had no idea what he was
going through.
I am a failure as a wife.
It's not your fault, Mrs. Irie.
Iri-chan has always had a sense of
responsibility.
I'm sure there were times he carried
a burden by himself and got stressed out.
Anyway, it's fortunate that this
was no life-threatening situation.
But what about Daddy's company?
What is going to happen to his
company if he takes days off?
I will do it.
B-but, Naoki.
You said you weren't sure if you
wanted to take over his company.
I think Dad knew about the problem
with his heart.
That's why he rushed and asked me
if I was willing to be his successor.
So... I'm going to save his company.
Thank you, Naoki.
But I'm the only one who knows...
that his real dream is...
to become a doctor.
He finally found his dream,
but does he have to give it up now?
Subtitles by DramaFever
[Mischievous Kiss]
[Love in Tokyo]
[Episode 13: A Mischief of Fate]
Irie is working in his father's place?
Yeah, he officially told the school
that he's taking a temporary leave.
He will be focusing on the company
until Mr. Irie gets better.
I see.
It sounds very serious.
But Irie will have no problem
doing it, right?
- He is a genius after all!
- That's right.
And I'm sure he was raised to
take over the company someday.
And how is Mr. Irie?
Kotoko?
He will stay at the hospital for a while and
take an absolute rest.
Irie-kun will come back to
live with us again.
- I'm sure he is relieved.
- I see.
But a time like this, the distance between
you and Irie might become closer.
What?
You see, when you are sick or
when you are in a hospital...
because you feel weak,
it's easier to fall in love.
But it's Mr. Irie who is in the hospital.
But Irie is also anxious.
If Irie-kun is feeling uneasy
and needs help...
if there is something that I can do,
I would do anything.
Way to go, Kotoko.
But I don't want to think about the
relationship between us right now...
Because, Mr. Irie is sick
and his company is in trouble.
I'm happy that Irie-kun is coming back
to the house, but...
If Mr. Irie gets better and
Irie-kun starts going to school again...
and studies what he wants to...
I'm okay with him living away from me.
Oh you, I know that's not
what you really want.
No...
You said it.
That's what I expect from Kotoko.
Kin-chan.
What do you mean by 'you said it'?
You simply don't want Kotoko
and Irie to get closer.
Stop it!
This is no time to joke around.
His family has a big problem.
It's Irie... I can see him
pretending to be tough.
But I'm sure he feels lonely
and anxious.
If there is something that you can do,
you should do it, Kotoko.
You are right.
If there is something that I can do,
I will help you with that.
So don't hesitate...
just ask me anytime.
Thank you, Kin-chan.
It's about that time.
I have to go.
Bye.
- See you.
- Bye, bye.
Hey, Kin-chan.
What was that all about?
What do you mean 'what?'
Could it be that you gave up
on Kotoko?
- Are you stepping aside for Irie?
- Don't be ridiculous.
I'm not talking about
something so low-level.
It's like I'm sending
support to my enemy.
Irie's family is in trouble...
If I take advantage of this situation
and take Kotoko from them...
it would make me less of a man.
After all, you and Kotoko are so similar.
Because what you just said is
the same as what Kotoko said.
'I don't care about myself, but
I want the person I love to be happy.'
That's true. You are like her.
You and Kotoko are actually
a good couple.
But...
- Just kidding.
- What?
- Kotoko can't love anyone but Irie.
- Right.
Never mind.
What?
Please have some.
Tonight, we have stewed taro roots,
teriyaki yellowtail...
miso soup, kidney beans
with sesame seeds...
- and I guess you can call this boiled tofu.
- Ahh!
It's hot.
Too spicy.
- Too spicy?
- Yeah.
It can't be...
Why? Why is it?
Why is it hot?
It's too spicy.
Big Brother, it's too spicy.
You shouldn't eat it.
It's hot.
Big Brother, what was that sound?
The taro root.
Usually taro roots don't make that sound.
Undercooked!
Big Brother, hurry and spit it out!
Don't force yourself to eat it.
You shouldn't eat it.
- What?
Stop complaining and eat
your food, Yuki.
What?
Ah, Irie-kun.
Do you want me to make
some coffee for you?
Sure.
Um, Irie-kun...
Are you going to take over
Mr. Irie's company?
You told me before that
you wanted to become a doctor.
I don't want to run away.
I told you...
I've been undergoing so many
trials since I met you.
I never imagined that my father
would collapse.
But I decided that I wouldn't run away.
Irie-kun.
When his heart recovers,
I will go back to school.
It's not too late to do what
I want after that.
I don't think it's a bad idea
to learn the ropes now.
I see.
If there is something that I can do,
please let me know.
Oh right, coffee.
During the time the president is
in the hospital, I will be your aid.
My name is Kanamori.
Pleased to meet you.
Please.
Now then, let me explain the materials
that I gave to you the other day.
You don't need to.
I took a look at them all last night.
You read them all by yourself?
The company's performance declined
significantly from last year.
Yes.
This is the inventory list
of our most popular product.
The sales have dropped drastically.
Our rival company's similar product is
taking our customers away from us.
The president was also
concerned about this matter.
At this rate, Pandai may
have to go through with a merger.
We need an enormous amount
of financial support immediately.
No wonder his heart became weak.
Okay.
Irie-kun is working so hard.
I'm going to work hard making his
lunches and doing house chores.
Alright!
It feels... kind of like we're a
newlywed couple.
'Fight with love...'
Which one comes first, H or G?
Oh well, this is okay.
Heart, heart.
Love, love, heart.
G should come before H.
Welcome home.
Would you like to take a bath first
or would you like to eat first?
Oh, your jacket...
Breathe in, please.
Breathe out, please.
Hey, Irie-kun, Irie-kun.
Your bag.
Have a good day!
Good luck!
We will try to gain profit from
the copyrights of all the merchandise.
By producing an animation...
we will have the initiative
and obtain its copyrights.
Our unique business style is to take
a partnership with oversea companies.
Do you know that too much miso
makes the soup too salty?
So salty.
But today's taro roots are
pretty good.
I'm sorry, Sudo-san.
[Request to leave the club temporarily]
- I see...
Irie's father is still not doing well?
No.
That's why I can't spend
much time at school.
I understand.
You and Irie are both our
precious tennis club members.
When Mr. Irie gets better,
you have to come back.
We will be waiting for you.
Thank you very much, Sudo-san.
It's not only you, Aihara.
We are all worried about Irie.
There are girls who miss him...
Like Ayako Matsumoto...
Leader!
I'm sorry, I'm late.
- I am not coming to the practice today.
- Huh?
New members are not allow to miss
a practice without my permission!
That's why I'm here to tell you.
Today I have a date with
my boyfriend, Taketo-kun.
- Boyfriend?
- When did this happen?
- I'm sorry.
But I'm going to borrow Ayako.
Kotoko-san, I heard about
Naoki-san's father.
Please tell him that I'm rooting for him.
Well then...
W-w-what?
Didn't she declare that she
was going to win Irie's heart?
How can she change so quickly?
Oh, she must be a part of that new
breed of Japanese kids. She must be!
- What are you talking about?
- What?
Then do you know 'Now Young?'
'Now young?'
You've totally lost me.
I see.
Ouch.
Oh, I'm sorry, Kotoko-san.
Can we talk for a little?
And... how is Irie-kun?
He is busy working at the company.
He comes home after midnight everyday.
Well, I'm always up waiting for him.
So that means there is a
possibility that...
he will quit the school and
take over the company.
Um, he is only taking a leave
from school temporarily.
He will come back eventually.
I wonder.
There is no need for him to come back to school
if he is taking over his father's company.
Um, but...
When his heart recovers,
I will go back to school.
It's not too late to do what
I want after that.
I don't think it's a bad idea
to learn the ropes now.
Irie-kun... wants to come back to school.
What I'm saying is that even if...
he does want to come back,
reality doesn't allow him to do that.
Oh.
Hey, why don't you liberate him
from your lunch boxes?
You are turning
his lunch time into a hell.
H-how do you know that
I'm making him lunch boxes?
I know you two.
I'm pretty sure that nothing
happened between you two.
Oh well, well, well...
Well, well, well...
Goodbye.
I'm home.
Ah, welcome back!
Mom!
It's great to be at my own house!
There are checkups and visitors
all day at the hospital. It's so restless.
What? He can see visitors now?
The doctor recommended that he
take it easy.
But he would let work related
people see him.
But I have good news!
It seems like he can come
home next month.
Really?
I'm so glad.
It depends on the result of
the detailed exam...
but now his condition is stable,
so we will try to bring him home.
I think Daddy will be more relaxed at home
than he is at the hospital.
I'm sure.
We will cause you trouble
a little bit more, Kotoko-chan.
No problem.
You should take care
of yourself, Mrs. Irie.
Thank you.
Now I will get his clean clothes
and go back to the hospital.
Yes.
- Yuki, be a good boy, okay?
- Okay.
Good.
When Mr. Irie comes home from the hospital,
Irie-kun can go back to school.
He will be able to study and pursue
his dream of becoming a doctor.
Thanks to everyone's support,
he will be able to go home next month.
That's good to hear.
Well, but Naoki-san is amazing.
He has done well
with taking his father's place.
It's hard to believe
that he is still in college.
You are so dependable, Naoki.
Naoki?
Strange. I don't think there are
any visitors besides us today.
- I see. I see.
- Dad.
You should be resting.
Chairman Oizumi.
I was in the neighborhood,
so I decided to stop by.
Naoki-san.
This is Hokueisha Chairman Oizumi
and his secretary Mr. Yokoyama.
I'm sorry for not
introducing myself sooner.
I am Naoki Irie.
Irie?
Oh, Chairman,
I'm sorry for being rude.
This is my son, Naoki. Currently he is
getting trained at my company.
I see. He seems like a very
dependable young man.
Thank you.
Chairman, since everyone is here,
we should talk about the plan.
President Irie...
We would like to discuss
investing in your company.
Yokoyama, we are at the hospital.
Oh, I'm sorry for being rude.
But I thought his son and Mr. Kanamori
should know about this too.
Yes, of course.
Honey, could you pass me
those papers over there?
But...
I hate to be rude...
but I have to ask you to
leave for today.
Naoki.
Chairman Oizumi came
all the way to see me.
I am really sorry,
but my father needs to rest.
He is not in the condition
to be working.
Chairman.
In that case, I suggest we
reconsider the investment plan.
Chairman.
On behalf of my father, I would like to
discuss the investment plan with you.
You have been very rude.
- A young fellow like you...
- I am the acting president now.
I would like to visit your
company tomorrow.
So I would like to ask you to
leave today.
It's not good for my father's health.
Hey, Naoki.
Please leave everything to me
while you are in the hospital.
I came to wish you a speedy recovery, but
it seems like I was being a nuisance.
Well then, please excuse us, Irie-kun.
You took time to come visit me.
I am sorry that you have to leave.
Yokoyama.
What is my schedule tomorrow?
Yes?
I am asking you when I'm
available tomorrow.
Well, before lunch with the minister,
you are available from 11 am to noon.
That's how it is.
What do you say?
Thank you very much. I will definitely
be there at 11 o'clock.
He made Chairman Oizumi
make time for him.
Naoki-san is incredible.
Indeed.
This never happens.
For these reasons, I can promise quite
enough profit for your company.
What do you think, Yokoyama?
For a student who has no experience
but learned management from lectures...
the presentation was well done.
Excuse me, but I am in the science
and engineering department.
I taught myself management.
I see.
But aren't you planning to become
the successor of Pandai?
Why are you in the science
and engineering department?
It's because I wanted to have a broad
and diverse range of knowledge.
I don't think a person with a narrow range
of knowledge can survive in this society.
Excuse me.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Please be careful.
Oh Naoki, I know you're busy.
I'm sorry for asking you to leave work.
More importantly... you said there is
something urgent to tell me?
Because I didn't want Yuki
to hear this...
Welcome home.
You are late again.
I will heat up dinner right away.
You don't need to.
What? Did you have dinner already?
I don't have an appetite.
Irie-kun.
Here is your lunch box.
Oh.
You seem very tired.
Are you okay?
Irie-kun?
I was thinking about something.
I'm going.
Have a good day.
Big Brother... I hope he's okay.
Here.
Wow, looks so delicious.
It's from Boss.
He said it must be hard
for you to cook everyday.
Thank you. This helps me a lot.
You should thank Boss.
Hey Kotoko, you aren't
going to school lately, are you?
No.
Are you okay with that?
I decided to go to college on my own,
so I will definitely try to graduate.
But right now, I want
to help the Irie family.
Not the Irie family...
You mean Irie, right?
I know what's in your mind.
Well, sometimes I wish I didn't know.
Kin-chan.
Anyway, no matter what happens,
I'm on your side.
Don't carry everything by yourself.
Let me know if you need my help.
Not only cooking, but anything else
like attending a class for you.
Thank you, Kin-chan.
Except...
I won't write a paper for you.
If I do that,
you are going to fail your class.
Geez.
Don't you think tonight's
dinner is delicious?
Your father made this, right?
You knew?
How could you think I wouldn't know?
It's way better than your food.
Excuse me, I am trying
my best too, you know.
Can you appreciate what
I do for once?
Thank you.
You are always saying mean things to me.
What?
You've improved a lot.
Thank you for the food.
Irie-kun is late.
Irie-kun!
Oh, it's Sudo-san.
Hello.
Oh, Aihara.
There is a big problem.
What happened?
To tell Matsumoto that I love her...
What?
Did you finally tell her
that you love her?
No, I was going to...
Oh, okay.
Please don't call me just to tell
me such a trifling thing!
No, no, no. And then she said
there was someone she loved.
I'm sure she would say that.
We all know that she loves Irie-kun,
I thought you knew...
No, that's not what I'm saying!
I know she loves him already.
She said she was going
to tell Irie she loves him.
Of course if she loves someone,
she would want to tell him her feelings...
What?
Matsumoto-san is going to tell
Irie-kun that she loves him?
When... when is she going to do it?
Tonight.
Tonight?
Where and when is Matsumoto-san
going to tell Irie-kun?
Don't tell me that she's
already told him?
No!
I'm sorry that I was waiting
for you here.
You must have waited for a long time.
If you wanted to tell me something,
you could've waited at my house.
I didn't want to do that.
I wanted to tell you alone.
I know I am being selfish.
You are in a difficult situation right now.
But...
What is it?
I love you, Irie-kun.
You see? I said it to you straight.
So I want you to tell me how
you feel about me straight, too.
What do you think about me?
Sorry.
I can't think of you as more than a friend.
I really love you, Irie-kun.
I've never felt like this before.
So...
I can't give up.
Huh?
Do you feel better now?
I'm sorry, but I don't want to do
something like that with you.
Why don't you want it with me?
Then whom would you kiss?
I've kissed someone.
I kissed Kotoko.
I feel so insulted by this.
My pride is torn apart.
I pray for your father to
get better soon.
The kiss we had...
it happened more than a year ago.
Why did he say that now?
Hey.
Stop eavesdropping on my love life.
Sorry.
I was worried because you were late.
Irie-kun?
My father is actually not doing well.
What?
Today I went to listen to
the doctor with my mother.
It seems like his condition
is stable now.
But according to the results
of the detailed exam...
he has a heart disease.
As soon as they are ready,
he is going to have an operation.
Is it a difficult operation?
It's his heart.
Even if the operation is successful,
he won't go back to work for a while.
I see.
I think the disease is caused
by stress and anxiety.
Because of this depression,
the company's performance has gotten worse.
That's why he wanted me to take over
the company as soon as possible.
I'm thinking of you as my
company's official successor.
At this rate, Pandai may
have to go through with a merger.
If I take over the company,
all of the problems will be solved.
But your dream is to
become a doctor, isn't it?
It's hasn't been long
since I had that dream.
I... want to become a doctor.
I'm not sure if I'm suited for it...
but I want to study properly.
So you are going to give up?
Irie-kun.
Becoming a doctor was...
the first job that has
interested me in my life.
Irie-kun looked so sad...
Before I knew it, I was hugging Irie-kun.
But he didn't take my hands away.
At that moment...
I felt like our hearts were connected.
Irie-kun, here is your lunch box.
I'm confident with today's rolled egg.
And there is sauteed leek.
I've heard that leek makes you smart.
Then why don't you eat it?
Have a good day!
Despite that...
I'm delighted that you paid
a visit to our company, Chairman.
- Thank you very much for coming.
- Well, well...
I had something to do
in this area today.
You are by yourself today?
I came here to talk to you
about a personal matter, Naoki-kun.
Talk to me?
Naoki-kun, would you like to have
an arranged marriage meeting?
I know it's not the best time
since Irie-kun is in the hospital...
I have a granddaughter.
She is your age and goes to
Seishin Women's College.
It's a real prestigious school.
What do you think, Naoki-kun?
Would you at least like to meet her?
You are young.
I'm sure you need time to
think about it.
After discussing it with your parents...
please give me your answer in
the next few days.
We will talk about the
investment plan afterward.
I'm sorry for visiting you
without notice.
Please don't apologize.
Well then, Naoki-kun.
Please consider this carefully.
Yes.
Thank you very much.
Naoki-san.
This meeting is...
going to be a great
advantage for the company.
Our fate was about to
start moving significantly...
Subtitles by DramaFever
Starring
Honoko Miki
Yuki Furukawa
Starring
Yuki Yamada
Original Comic
"Itazurana Kiss" by Kaoru Tada
Executive Producers
Katuski Yoshiharu (SPO Entertainment Inc)
Kenji Nishibuchi (Fuji Television Network, Inc.)
Executive Producers
Yoshikuni Murata (Hakuhodo DY Media Partners Incorporated)
Takeshi Moriya (Atmovie Inc.)
Planning
Yuki Sakurai (SPO Entertainment Inc.)
Opening Song
'Update' by Sabão
Ending Song
'Takaramono (Thanks for All)' by Sabão
Script
Uiko Miura
Producer
Takeshi Moriya
Director
Koji Kawano
Production by
Atmovie Inc.
Presented by
"Itazurana Kiss-Love in TOKYO" Partners
Is it true that you will have
an arranged marriage meeting?
Yes, I like her.
Do you remember me?
I especially don't forget a
beautiful woman.
I have a good idea.
You are going to ruin the meeting?
For only this time,
I will join your plan.
This is not like what you had before.
An arranged meeting
is between families.
I will take Kotoko away from you.
Do whatever you want.
The girl you love is Kotoko,
right, Big Brother?
I'm sure everything will work out.