Thought I told you not to run
them sheep on my land!
It's my land, Garrett.
It became mine when
we signed that lease.
He's right, Mr. Garrett.
I'm paying you off when we get back,
and I'm breaking that goddamn lease.
- I don't allow the law would agree to that.
- What law is that?
Santa Fe Ring law?
Shit.
- Goddamn law is ruining the country.
- Ain't you still a part of that law?
Something wrong with that harness.
I believe they elected you and paid you
good wages for killing the Kid, huh?
You rotten son of a bitch.
- You try your luck, Eno.
- You miss more than anybody else does.
I'll bet on it.
You want the breast or the thigh?
What he always gets.
I want a breast and a thigh.
Jesus Christ!
- Who is it?
- Get down!
Goddamn, that's Garrett.
Hello, Bill.
- It's fair shooting for an old married man.
- Lucky, I guess. How are you, Kid?
- Good to see you.
- Good seeing you.
- Hey, Billy!
- Who's this you got with you?
- Looking good.
- Having some kind of fiesta? Hello, Black.
We always live like this.
You ought to visit us more often.
I reckon the whole damn territory’s
gonna be one big open jug for us now.
- Is that right, Pat?
- Ain’t that right, Pat?
Take a two-day ride from Lincoln just to pay
me back the 2 dollars you owe me, Pat?
You'd better collect it now, Black.
We ain't gonna be seeing much
of Pat these days.
Say, I understand those Mexican señoritas
are still pretty as ever down there.
Yeah?
I know one's waiting on you, hoss,
with a knife.
- Remember them sisters?
- No. Which ones were they?
That one you got up and asked
how much you owed.
And she said,
"Whatever you think it's worth."
You threw a dime on her pillow.
Girl said, " If that's all it's worth,
I might as well sew it up."
Son of a bitch.
Come on, I'll buy you a drink.
You don't figure he's too good
to drink with us, do you?
Maybe it's the other way around.
Jesus, don't you get stale
around here, Bill?
Maybe a year or so down in Mexico
will do you some good.
I didn't figure you'd bother
to make a ride out here.
Shit, you know me better than that.
You heard about Eben?
He drowned in the Rio Grande.
Trying to get to that old Mex
you're talking about.
He took two of the posse with him.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I always liked old Eben.
At least he knew when it was
the right time to leave.
We did have some times, didn’t we?
It's gotta be pretty hard
to turn your back on all that.
You want it straight?
If that's what you're here for.
The electorate...
...wants you gone.
Out of the country.
But are they telling me,
or are they asking me?
I'm asking you.
But in five days, I'm making you.
Because I might take over sheriff
of Lincoln County.
Old Pat.
Sheriff Pat Garrett.
Sold out to the Santa Fe Ring.
How does it feel?
It...
...feels like times have changed.
Times maybe.
Not me.
Hey, why don't you stick around.
We got a few days left, ain’t we?
No, I gotta get back.
Adiós, Pat.
Adiós, Bill.
Don't press your luck.
I ain’t worried about my luck.
Why don't you kill him.
Why?
He's my friend.
Get on up, Billy.
You hear what I'm saying?
I ain't making no money
watching you boys sleep.
You like to waste the best part
of the damn day.
Let that squirrel loose!
You'll shake it to death.
- I'm just scratching.
- Chisum's cattle is waiting.
Oh, let them wait.
I hate a son of a bitch that gets up
noisy and full of himself.
I ain’t in this for my health, hateful.
That's awful.
- Pat ain’t gonna like this.
- What?
Coming down hard on him
the day after he got his new badge.
Hell, there ain’t no way
he's gonna know.
I ain’t afraid of Pat Garrett.
Well, all right, a little bit.
Bastards.
I'd best go get them horses watered.
Goddamn Chisum.
How'd he know we was here?
- Hell, that's Garrett.
- Goddamn him too.
Now he's got Bell and half the town
of Lincoln out there with him.
Help me up.
Sweet Mary's ass!
Don't let me go down.
They killed me. I'm gut-shot for sure.
Hold your fire!
Hold it!
Bill!
Come on out!
You don't have a chance!
What are you taking me in for?
Which one was that?
Buckshot Roberts.
For the killing of Buckshot Roberts!
Hell, that was a year ago.
I shot him straight up.
Come on in, Pat!
I'll warm your breakfast!
Guess he ate.
They're closing down
the store on us for sure.
Maybe it's time you took a walk.
Hell, yes.
Why not?
I can still hold a gun.
We gotta move. I'm going fast.
Kid.
Sweet Mary's ass!
I'm going now, so, by God,
let's get on with it.
Hey.
I ain’t afraid of him now.
Hold your fire! We're coming out!
Hold it!
- You go left. I'll go right.
- Might be they ain’t circled us.
Might be the dog would've caught
the rabbit if he hadn't thought to shit.
Where are the goddamn horses?
- That's enough!
- Hold it! Hold it!
All right, Kid!
Come on out if you're still alive!
Game's over!
Coming out, Pat!
You're in poor company, Pat.
Yeah, I'm alive, though.
So am I.
I never figured to hear you brag
on being a working man.
Well, I never figured you
for the law either.
It's just a way of staying alive.
No matter what side you're on,
you're always right.
And I aim to live to be rich,
old and gray.
That's a fine ambition, Pat.
You keep thinking like that.
I'll think on how I'll spend your money.
Only thing you've got
to think about...
...Is when you stand before
the highest court there is.
May it sit in judgment
on your rotten soul.
Now, you listen. Listen to me good.
Before that rope snaps,
it'll hit you like a bolt of lightning...
...that what I've been telling you
is the truth!
You'll learn to believe
before I'm finished.
That's 3 to you.
What do you believe in, Bell?
I do believe I'm gonna
have to see that bet...
...and raise you 5.
- Billy...
...somewhere in the Good Book,
it says there's a time for everything.
A time to love, a time to hate...
...a time to kill.
But now it's time
you got close to God, boy.
I heard God's fast...
...but I have to go up in front of him
myself before I'd bet on it.
You will.
Well, that puts me on my way.
I got to go collect a few more taxes.
He's all yours.
Two days, boys.
I count eight days till dawn, Billy.
You'd best be on your knees and making
the acquaintance of your Lord and master.
Pat, keep that mule's asshole away from me
before I have to break him.
I surely wish you'd try, son.
I got my shotgun full of 16 thin dimes.
Enough to spread you out
like a crazy woman's quilt.
- Bob.
- Why don't you sing a song of Jesus...
...while there's still a way.
- Bob. Bob.
Damn it.
You mess around with him one more time,
I'll send your ass back to Texas.
Don't.
I think I'd like to keep him here a while.
I fold, Billy.
Folding three queens, now, are you?
You must be afraid
I'll go out a loser, Bell.
- I guess I just ain’t seeing them.
- Well, I'll tell you what...
...as long as I'm breathing,
let's play it straight.
I ain’t sold my saddle like you
and the rest of the town boys, Bell.
Or it's just Bob that smells
like street shit over there.
On your knees!
Kiss my ass.
Bob!
Repent, you son of a bitch!
Sweet Jesus, I repent.
Leave off, Bob! You've gone loco!
I'm going across the street
and have a drink.
I'm thirsty as hell.
I wanna tell you one last thing
personal, Kid.
It's gonna be a loose rope
and a long drop.
That last thump got my guts going.
I need to go to the outhouse.
My horse locoed on me once
coming back from Pacheco.
I cut the second bar in his mouth
and bleed him.
He died on me,
and I ended up walking 40 miles.
I never was much for walking.
Well, I ain’t never walked a mile since.
Fell in with a bunch of Mescaleros.
They was just off the reservation,
and I was "suspicioned" of them.
But I had some biscuit on me.
I give it to them, and they just rode off.
That's a hell of a story, Bell.
You know, I believe old Pat's
lost his sand.
He won't come on a man.
You ought not to talk about him that way.
You and him used to be pretty close.
He ain’t the same man.
He signed himself over to Chisum
and every other landowner...
...that's trying to put a fence
around this country.
That's what you been doing, ain’t it?
Selling us out and getting fat.
Ain't that easy, Billy.
You was a friend of Carlyle's,
wasn't you, Bell?
You know I was.
I don't mean to be contrary,
but did I ever tell you how he died?
I shot him three times in the back,
blew his goddamn head off.
I don't wanna kill you, Bell.
Well, I sure hope you don't, Billy.
Then just move toward me.
Don't. Don't do it, please.
You wouldn't shoot me in the back, Billy.
- What the hell was that?
- There's been a shooting.
Get in the house!
- My God, he's got a shotgun.
- Somebody get the sheriff!
How does Jesus look to you now, Bob?
Bonney's killed Bell!
Yeah, and he's killed me too.
Keep the change, Bob.
Bring me an ax.
Get back, I don't wanna kill you.
Go over to that livery stable,
get me the best horse you've got.
Caught your horse, Billy.
Try him again.
By God, I think I'm just gonna trade you
that fine brown horse for your buckskin.
What the hell, Billy?
I'll thrown in about $1.60 worth of change
if you can dig it out of old Bob there.
Would some of you people
get him up off the ground and into it?
Anything you say, sheriff.
Hell of a mess, Pat.
Shot Bell and Ollinger and rode on out.
Yeah. Do me up good this time, Zeppy.
And leave the mustache on it.
- Is the boy around?
- Boy.
Speak to Mr. Garrett.
Yes, sir?
I want you to run all the way down
to my house.
Tell Mrs. Garrett that I'm gonna
be home for dinner.
And then I want you to stampede
over to the courthouse...
...find John Neully and the others
standing around there...
...and tell them to come over here
and pay me a visit. Got that?
John Neully, courthouse. Yes, sir.
Who are you?
That's a good question.
I believe you know of me.
Bill Kermit.
Wanted for horse-thieving
down in Seven Rivers, ain’t you?
That'd be me, sheriff.
Killed old C.B. Denning last year
at Silver City...
...for calling you at cheating at monte.
That'd be me. Alamosa Bill.
Well, Bill, I'm gonna make you
my deputy.
Listen, Bill, why don't you go out back...
...tingfind us a couple of steaks
and a mess of eggs.
And get one of them good bottles
they got behind the bar there.
I wanna have me a bath.
It should take you about two weeks
to make the circle.
Yeah.
- They say William Bonney's escaped.
- He has.
And he's in Mexico, I hope.
Where we should be If I had any sense.
If not...
...I'll go after him.
Got too much riding on it not to.
I figure that's why they elected me.
Anyways, I don't give a damn.
Brought him in once, I can do it again...
...lf I have to.
You might say that
you are glad to see me.
It's been over a week you've been gone.
I'm sorry.
I gotta go down to the saloon,
there's a...
...drunk down there causing a lot of trouble.
Goes by the name of Alamosa Bill.
Said he rode with the Kid
down in west Texas.
Will you be blessing this house
with your presence for dinner?
Looks like it's gonna be a long night.
- It's been a long year.
- Not now.
My people don't talk to me.
They say you are getting to be too much
of a gringo since you've been sheriff.
That you make deals with Chisum.
You don't touch me.
You are dead inside.
- I wish you'd never put on that badge.
- Not now.
Or I won't be here when you get back!
We'll deal with this...
...when it's over.
I hope he gets away.
Well, he won't.
There's too much play in him.
And not enough in you.
You're late, Pat.
More cognac, please.
- Good of you to come, sheriff.
- Thank you, Your Honor.
- It's a pleasure to see you.
- Thank you, sir.
May I offer you some supper?
Oh, no. No, I think I might have
a little of that brandy, though.
Of course. Some brandy.
I do hope you enjoy
these rainy New Mexican evenings.
They have a fabulous melancholy
to them.
They bring us closer
to some greater design.
At least I hope so.
Allow me to introduce
Mr. Lewellyn Howland.
And this man is Norris.
These gentlemen are very concerned
about the escape of William Bonney.
- A concern I'm sure you also share.
- He escaped from my jail.
Exactly.
This territory is vast and primitive.
There is money here, growing investments
and political interests.
We must protect these investments...
...so that the area can continue
to prosper and grow.
- I believe you rode with the Kid, didn’t you?
- I did.
- Then you must be aware of his moves.
- Well, I know Billy.
- And he ain’t exactly predictable.
- Oh, come now, sheriff.
For a man who's half outlaw himself
and still smart enough...
...to be elected sheriff by Chisum and
the big ranchers, I expect better than that.
Can you bring him in,
or should we look elsewhere?
Oh, I can bring him in.
If you and the big peckerheads don't mess
things up by startling another cattle war.
I assure you, Chisum and the others have
been advised to recognize their position.
And in this particular game,
there are only a few plays left.
I'd advise you to grab on to a winning hand
while you have a chance.
We're offering a reward of $1000
for the Kid's capture.
You can have 500 now.
Well, I aim to bring the Kid in.
But until I do...
...better take your $500
and shove it up your ass and set fire to it.
Commendable notion, sheriff.
Eno.
Well, now.
I'm gonna blow the top of your
cow-humping head off, you son of a bitch.
How's it going, Luke?
You are a son of a bitch.
I thought they's getting ready
to trim you.
There's a whole bunch of us
just fixing to ride in.
Well, I saved you all a trip.
Or somebody did.
I figured I'd lay back a few days.
Maybe more.
Well, it sure is pleasurable
seeing you back again, Kid.
- You glad I'm back?
- Welcome home, Billy.
And did you miss me?
So much you had to take up
with that low-down piece, old Hyatt.
Cómo estás, Silva?
Buenos dias, Billy.
Now, you're uglier than me.
How's it going, Beaver?
Eno, I thought you boys would be out
In the Nueces or Colorado by now.
Well, I figured to watch you get stretched
but might have knowed you'd show up.
Good thing somebody did.
These four rode in here this morning.
What's your name, boy?
- Alias.
- Alias what?
Alias anything you please.
What do we call you?
Alias.
- Hell, let's call him Alias.
- That's what I'd do.
Alias it is.
Thank you.
My, my.
You boys hungry?
- I didn’t catch your name.
- I didn’t give it out.
Well, I guess that's why I didn’t catch it.
But I know yours.
And that's enough.
Hey, Silva. Do you remember that meeting
with John Jones...
...and that old man they called
U.S. Christmas, down near El Rito?
- That old man they called U.S. Christmas?
- Right. See?
Seems John stepped on one of U.S.'s
boots one night they was both in town.
Old U.S., he'd been out hunting buffalo
for six months.
Now, he was mean and testy
and damn near blind drunk.
He had on a pair of these flat-heeled,
about half-length Wellington boots.
Them boots was the only thing he owned
he put any store in.
And John stepped on one of them.
That old man just stepped back and said:
"Let's get to it."
So John said to U. S:
"If you're gonna get that riled...
...over a pair of foreign,
lady-looking boots...
...we just might as well
get the ball rolling."
So they went in the middle
of the street.
And they took the 10 steps.
And John put three holes
right through that old man's chest.
I must have known them
from somewhere.
It's too soon for bounty hunters.
Alias?
What the hell?
Garrett?
I thought you was in Lincoln.
- What the hell you doing?
- You get your ass over there, Gate.
Howdy, Cullen.
How do you do, yourself?
What are you doing
with that piece of sheep dip?
I'd like to blow his thieving head off
just for riding through my town.
I ain’t paid nobody no never mind.
Been staying in my own good hole.
Fact is, I'm thinking about
going to Texas.
Kid broke out.
Killed Ollinger and Bell.
I thought maybe Gate and some of the boys
might have a sign on him.
Well, I still want him for that train robbery
up at Springer.
Gate's been holed up outside of town here
with Black Harris and Sut Cole, that bunch.
Been meaning to roust them
out of here...
...but somehow or other
I just can't get around to it.
I don't know nothing about the boys,
I don't know nothing about the Kid.
Understand you've been riding for Chisum.
I'd rather be on the outside of the law...
...than packing a badge for that town of
Lincoln and them that's a-running it.
It's a job.
Comes an age in a man's life when...
...he don't wanna spend time
figuring what comes next.
Well, it's gonna cost you some change.
I got to the point where
I don't do nothing for nobody...
...unless there's a piece of gold
attached to it.
One of these days,
when I get my boat built...
...I'm gonna drift out of
this damn territory.
This town's got no hat size nohow.
Mama?
Where'd you put my badge?
I don't like it, Cullen.
This town is not worth it.
Tell you the truth, Mama,
I don't take a shine to it myself.
Anytime you're ready.
Company's coming.
Sheriff Baker.
Hey, Black Harris!
I wanna talk to you!
Whoa, boys.
Black.
I ain’t seen the Kid,
If that's what you're sniffling after.
But if it's straight-up one-to-one you want,
then I'm your man.
I'm looking for sign, Black.
Us old boys ought not to be doing this
to each other.
Ain’t that many of us left.
Remember?
You and me rode into this county together.
How long ago was that, Pat?
Oh, hell, about 15 years ago.
Pat, I know where the Kid’s at.
I'll tell you...
...when you're lying proper
on the ground.
It'll be the last words you ever hear.