Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Episode 7
What is this?
- All right!
- Oh...
Hey!
- What?
- Hey!
Don't touch that.
I'm giving it to Madame Shin.
Geez, you give this measly
thing to your little sister.
But, you sure are looking out
for the Director.
What happened with the glass mask?
I didn't bring it back.
I didn't bring it back or
you couldn't bring it back?
Someone else is going to bring it.
Don't worry.
That person will bring it for sure.
That person?
Did you meet a guy in Japan?
Hey, aren't you going to school?
Go, so I can go to work too.
Hurry, go.
Unni, the landlady called again.
Just pay her the rent, will you?
All right. Go to school.
[Shim Gun Wook]
Is it too early?
Oh?
Geez, what is this?
Now what?
[Shim Gun Wook]
I'm in Seoul.
Welcome.
Did Hong Tae Seong come with you?
Did you come alone?
No. There are two of us.
What? So, Hong Tae Seong came too.
Seon Young...
I feel it was my fault
you fell in the water.
Where shall I take you?
We're going to the police station.
So, you're saying the glass mask is
now in Seoul, but it's not in your hand?
Yes.
There's someone who went and
got the glass mask before me,
but it will be in Korea shortly.
Someone got to it first?
Who is it?
Well, that's...
I'm going to meet with him soon.
And I'll make sure that there won't
be any impediment to the exhibit.
But you said...
that the glass mask made by Ryuu-sensei
is the only piece of its kind in the world.
And the reason I chose you
was to find a piece like that.
And I trusted you had the skill
to acquire it.
You know I trust you, right?
Of course.
I will acquire it for your exhibit;
without fail.
Aren't you coming?
I'll wait for you here.
It's me.
What's happening regarding what I requested?
Yes.
- You can't park here, sir. Please move it.
- I'll contact you again later.
You have Choi Seon Young's belongings
safely in custody, don't you?
Yes.
Detective Lee, bring some coffee.
- Yes!
- Hurry, hurry.
About Seon Young,
wasn't it a suicide?
Yes, well...
A new witness surfaced
on the day of her death.
Who is this?
My personal assistant.
Ah... hello.
A new witness?
After analyzing the witness' statement,
we suspect the man whom Choi Seon
Young fought with outside your apartment
might possibly be the person
who was briefly adopted
then given up for adoption
before you entered Haeshin Group.
Seon Young knew the guy
who moved in instead of me?
We've confirmed that they
both stayed at the same orphanage.
Choi Seon Young never mentioned this to you?
About the other Hong Tae Seong?
Anyhow, we're wondering
if you might be able to find out
the real name or address of the boy
who was given up for adoption,
or any sort of lead.
Is it really true that she met with him?
She knew I was the son of the Haeshin Group
family and she never mentioned it to me.
My name... She did say she
liked my name Hong Tae Seong.
She said it was a name she liked.
Tae Seong,
his name is Tae Seong too.
I haven't seen you in a long time.
What are you so busy with?
Hey!
Are you listening to me?
Yeah.
Sorry, Noona.
What is it?
Haeshin Group document?
Let's eat.
It's been a long time since
I got to eat your cooking.
Tae Seong...
Call me Gun Wook now.
It's him.
The man I'm seeing...
Choi Seon Young?
Yes.
Oh!
What are you doing here again?
I heard you got probation.
Did you already get into trouble?
This is like your second home.
Keep up the good work.
I'll be going now.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Have you read Seon Young's diary?
Diary?
Yes.
Seon Young always carried around a diary.
She carried it around like a wallet,
and was always writing things down.
- Detective Lee,
- Yes?
Was there a diary at Choi Seon Young's
house?
No.
It wasn't there?
That's strange.
She was never without it.
If you need my help,
call me anytime.
- What are you doing?!
- Eh?
Tae Seong, what are you doing?
Yes, Father.
Haven't you taken him away yet?
Tae Seong.
Yes?
Hong Tae Seong.
Find out about the guy who
was called Hong Tae Seong.
Why don't you answer?
I understand.
From what I remember,
he was bad news.
Seon Young was seeing him?
The reason she said she
liked the name Tae Seong,
was it all because of that guy?
What the hell happened?
Unni.
Let me go to Japan.
Gun Wook oppa doesn't even answer his phone.
What if something happened?
Mo Ne, listen to me carefully.
If someone doesn't call very often,
and never tells you when
they're coming or going,
that person doesn't have feelings for you.
That person is using you.
I like him and that's enough.
What does all that matter?
Mo Ne...
Have you tried on some clothes?
She's bringing some right out.
She's coming now.
What's that?
That's not our style.
It's a new brand.
It's a promotional gift for our VVIP's.
You don't like it?
It doesn't look too good.
Customers like you
probably wouldn't shop for it.
It's also in a different price range.
I was pondering
whether or not to bring it out...
Still the design is new and fresh.
I'll just take it out.
No, put it in a separate bag.
Why do you want it,
if you aren't even going to wear it?
There's someone who would like that
sort of thing. Someone who'd be grateful.
[Mobile Banking Service]
Ah, yes.
I've made the payment online for
the two months’ rent that was past due.
Yes, I'm sorry that it's late.
Have a good day.
[Account Total 171,155,
Available for Withdrawal 171,155]
170,000 Won.
(~about US$170)
I have to make it to pay day.
- Are you alone?
- Yeah. You've come?
I was at the department store today,
and I thought this would suit you.
Director, thank you.
You didn't even bring me the
glass mask and I'm ticked at you,
but I saw these pretty clothes
and still thought of you.
I'll wear it well.
It will suit you.
You know I have a good eye.
You know this has another purpose too,
right?
Don't worry about the glass mask.
Wow.
It's beautiful.
You think I'd pick just anything?
I thought it was because of the glass mask.
The reason you returned to Korea...
I felt heavy.
But if it wasn't my fault she died,
then the load will be lifted.
There are women's things in the apartment.
Clothes, cosmetics...
get rid of all of them.
Get rid of all of them means...
You don't know what it means
to get rid of something?
Throw it all away.
Wasn't it...
someone you loved?
What?
If it was someone you loved, shouldn't you
keep at least some small remembrance?
Hey.
Your meddling is really strange.
You normally don't show any interest in
anything other than what I tell you to do.
I'm just concerned
you might look for them later.
I don't need it.
Throw it all away.
I confess this to you.
Please listen carefully
to what I'm about to say.
That you and I ever loved...
Any memory of our love,
forget it happened at all.
Seon Young.
They say you might not have died
because of me.
Is that true?
But, why does that make me less happy?
Never again, the two of us.
Whatever chance may bring...
Gun Wook, I love him.
So, please, stop.
Please just stop!
Gun Wook, please.
Love?
When he won't miss these memories
even if they're thrown in the trash?
Love...
What's not my fault?
I know it's all my fault.
But Seon Young,
If...
If that punk...
had any connection to your death,
I won't let him be.
Noona,
I'm sorry.
I'm not going to stop.
Haeshin Group and those people...
I'll let them know of the consequences
they brought upon themselves.
When the time comes
and everything is over,
then I'll take my punishment.
Watch me, Noona.
It will be difficult without a receipt.
But there was a different
girl when I came last time.
I'm sure she'd remember me.
You can't just refund it for me?
Really?
Just a moment.
"I'm in Seoul!"
[Shim Gun Wook]
Yeah.
Oh, you answered.
Where are you?
Are you in Seoul?
Yeah.
I'm headed for Hong Tae Seong's house.
Where?
I'm going to Hong Tae Seong's house.
Hey, is he going to his house too?
It's his house,
so probably yeah.
Why do you ask?
Oh, no reason.
Okay, bye.
Excuse me, Unni,
I'll take those back.
I'll look for the receipt and come back.
Okay then.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
What's this about a diary?
We found everything near Choi Seon Young
that could possibly serve as a clue.
And her house has also been searched.
So, where else are we supposed to look?
Detective Lee.
Yes?
That guy earlier...
Who, Hong Tae Seong?
No, no.
The guy with him...
Ah, the assistant?
The wealthy are indeed a different breed;
dragging around an assistant.
There's a really...
strange air about him.
Who are you?!
I've returned.
Oh, it's you.
Let's go inside.
Yes, sir.
Dad! Mom!
Dad!
- Tae Seong, let's go inside.
- I don't want to!
- Dad! Dad!
- That's right, I'm your dad.
I don't want to!
Young Master!
Don't do that.
You'll get hurt.
Young Master Tae Seong!
Chairman, you've come home.
Mmm.
Come in.
Yes, sir.
You know the tea that was sent from China?
Yes.
- Bring some of that.
- Yes, sir.
When did you come back?
You wouldn't have come back
on your own, right?
We came back together.
But, that kid didn't even call?
When is he going to grow up?
Oh, drink up.
So, you brought Tae Seong home.
But, the key is to settle him
down and keep him in Korea.
Do you have any good ideas?
What if you put him to work?
Work?
He'd probably do well.
He's smarter than one would think,
he has a quick judgment,
and he has remarkable determination.
Who? Our Tae Seong?
That has been my observation.
It sounds good to hear my son praised.
- You're home early.
- Yeah...
But what are you so happy about?
Hello.
Who's this?
Oh, I guess you wouldn't know.
He's the guy Mo Ne was talking about.
Shim Gun Wook.
How could you bring strangers into the house?
- What about Mo Ne?
- She stepped out a little earlier.
That's a relief.
I'm sorry, but could you
leave before Mo Ne gets home?
No matter what anyone says,
don't forget you're Hong Tae Seong.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
If Mo Ne comes home,
it will get loud.
And I don't like it when it gets loud.
Yes, I completely understand.
She's so high strung.
All right, then go.
Don't let Tae Seong know we met.
What's the matter with you?
Why do you let people like that in our home?
Can't you tell from the way he seduced
an innocent girl and made trouble?
A paltry good-for-nothing who
doesn't even know the basics.
Whether he's a good-for-nothing or not,
we'll just have to wait and see.
Where's Hong Tae Seong?
He didn't come.
What is this?
Weren't you coming with Hong Tae Seong?
Jae In, where are you?
I've got to go.
Young Master,
do you still want to go home?
Yes.
Don't tell Madame Shin,
because she'll say you'll get cavities.
Okay.
What is it?
Does it taste good?
Yes.
It tastes good.
How did you...
I'm sorry.
I noticed the box.
Excuse me...
No, it's nothing.
I heard there was a child
who briefly lived here.
Hong Tae Seong has asked me to find him.
Who should I ask?
Why is the Young Master looking for him?
I'm not sure.
Do you know anything, by any chance?
I don't know.
I see.
All right, then...
What do you think of that man?
I don't really know.
Are there so few men in the world,
that she has to pick such a low-life?
But, he's not a low-life.
I'm saying all sorts of things to you.
Anyhow, you're still working
on the glass mask, right?
Ah, of course.
Then, I'll be going.
So, who on earth is the person
who has the glass mask?
What am I going to do about the glass mask?
I'm going crazy.
Oh... You haven't left yet?
No.
You left a while ago.
Were you waiting for me?
What about transportation?
I came with the Director from the gallery.
Hop on.
Hey. You expect me to ride this thing?
Never mind, I'll just go.
Get on.
How can I ride that?
I'm wearing a skirt.
It's okay if I ride?
It'll be cold. Put this on.
Just a second.
Hold on tight.
Or you might fall.
Just a second. Stop the car!
Oppa!
I'm sure that's Gun Wook oppa's motorcycle.
Forget the hurt you got from love.
I hope that all of your tears dry now,
basking in the sun after the rain.
Even though I try not to love you,
My heart keeps on racing so fast like this...
But why did you go there earlier?
You're on tea-drinking
terms with the Chairman?
It's because of Mo Ne, I guess.
Ahh... Mo Ne.
That house is pretty nice, huh?
Yeah.
The first time I saw that house,
I really thought I was going to faint.
Wow, I thought, there are really
houses like that in the world.
There are really people who
live in houses like this.
I thought it would just be nice,
to have a 33 pyeong* apartment.
(*unit of measuring area)
But there is a completely different world.
A different world... whatever!
Hey, is your house better?
That's right.
Now you're even making up stuff.
Thanks for pretending
not to know me earlier.
It's the same for me, anyhow.
What are we doing?
It's really funny.
Hong Tae Seong is here.
Yeah, I heard earlier.
Well, you want me to arrange a meeting?
Frankly speaking,
Hong Tae Seong isn't the issue.
The glass mask,
that's the issue.
I kind of talked a big game to the Director.
I told her I'd get it for her without
fail and show it at the gallery opening.
Meet him and ask him.
Who knows?
No. If I ask him, he'll want
to tease me with it even more.
He says his goal is to irritate his mother.
Would you give it to me
if you were him?
I guess you know
Hong Tae Seong better than me.
Is that true?
Really. Now that I think about it,
I don't know anything about you.
Tell me about you.
Me?
What are you curious about?
Let's see.
What your parents do,
what you like,
what your dream is,
what kind of person you are...
Are you really curious?
Just focus on your target.
Hong Tae Seong.
Do you always have to talk like...
I'm going.
What about the glass mask?
I told you I needed it.
I'm going.
My dream...
Who told you
you could report that I came back?
I'm sorry.
I'm not liking you these days.
I don't have a pass.
You've come, sir?
Why don't you block me like last time?
Please go on in.
So, you know who I am now?
I'm sorry about last time.
Tae Seong, sit over there.
- When did you come?
- A few days ago.
You should have called and let us know.
It's not like you care whether
I come or go. Why bother?
So twisted as always...
Tae Seong, starting tomorrow,
come work at Haeshin Construction.
Haeshin has embarked on
building a robot theme park.
You take it and run it.
You liked robots.
I liked playing with them...
What did you say?
You're placing a business in his hands?
What does he know how to do
that would make you bring him in?
To this age, all the kid knows
how to do is sleep and play.
Oh, that's right,
he occasionally gets into trouble.
What kind of humiliation are you asking
for by bringing him into the business?!
Mom...
I'm against it.
What does he know?
You sent him to study in the States
and Japan, but did he study?
Did he even live like a person?
What are you doing over there?
Is this a place you should be?
My apologies.
I told him to come.
Why?
This is an important conversation.
Who is he to be here?
Step outside.
You said my dad was coming to get me.
Mom!
Why are you so persistent?!
You're just a kid!
Soon, your mom and dad
are going to pick you up.
Excuse me.
I have something to ask.
Remember the teachings of
philosopher Dasan, Jeong Yak Yong.
If you don't have a solid foundation,
before the paint on the building dries,
the cornerstone will collapse.
You recklessly put a kid who
knows nothing in that position,
and how are you going to clean up
the mess later?
You do the things you want.
And don't concern yourself over the company.
No, I'll start tomorrow.
I was slowly starting to
get sick of playing around.
I'll just come and play in the company.
Are you in your right mind?
Do you want me to be in my right mind?
What?
You like it
when I live like I'm out of my mind.
Who knows?
Maybe I'll create some major disaster,
and ruin Haeshin Construction.
Unbelievable.
Are you really going
to keep acting like this?
That's enough.
Tae Ra, you take over the department store.
And Tae Seong, you take over Construction.
I can go now, right?
Information on the child
given up for adoption?
Why, all of a sudden?
Hong Tae Seong has asked me to look into it.
I don't know
if there are any documents left,
but I'll contact you if I find anything.
Thank you.
What's the matter?
You said your name was Shim Gun Wook?
Yes.
There wasn't a lot of information
on Shim Gun Wook's childhood either.
The job of a personal assistant,
requires having no qualms about
digging into people's backgrounds.
It sounds like it came naturally;
that question...
Because you are seeing Mo Ne,
so of course...
What are you curious about?
- Where are you going?
- You don't need to go.
Car key.
Hello.
I'm pressing the lobby.
Hey, hey, what is this?
Madame Shin gave it to me as a gift.
You've never gotten a gift?
Hey, you have to remove the price tag.
Hey, don't.
What is this?
You're not going to pretend this is brand
new and try to get a refund, are you?
Hey, what are you talking about?
She gave it to me.
I'm joking.
Ah, girl, it must be nice.
Hey, but were you able to
get the glass mask?
Yeah.
It's me.
You know what I told you the other day?
About the glass mask?
Did you talk to Hong Tae Seong?
Hong Tae Seong is at Haeshin right now.
Huh? Really?
Hey, I'll call you back.
What are you doing?
Are you going somewhere?
Yeah. The person who has the
glass mask is at Haeshin right now.
I'm going to try to see him.
I'm on my way up.
Where can I see him?
He just left.
Come up the escalator for now.
I don't see you.
Yeah, behind you.
- Behind me?
- No, to your right.
Yeah, here.
Hey, Gun Wook.
If you haven't eaten yet,
let's go eat.
Huh?
Then is he waiting for us?
Hmm?
You should have just told me where
and I could have gone there.
So, do I look okay?
Yeah.
But, Hong Tae Seong just left.
Hey.
He just charged out, so what was
I supposed to do? What do I say?
Should I have told him to wait?
Are you playing games with me right now?
I told you, didn't I?
That I needed the glass mask.
That I had to get it.
I asked you to help me meet him.
And you're playing games with me?
I told you multiple times I needed it!
If it was so important,
why did you leave Japan without it?
If it was that urgent, you should
have taken it, stolen it, or whatever.
Are you asking me why I left it there
because you really don't know?
Why?
So that Hong Tae Seong
would bring it back to Korea...
I mean, back directly to you?
Is that what you hoped for?
That's right.
That's what I hoped.
So you're saying that you know all this
and you're still playing games with me.
I don't have much time before the
exhibit, Madame Shin is waiting,
and it's a headache even without this.
Never mind, then.
Never mind.
What can I even say to you?
You know my situation and you're
always playing these games!
All right. I'll get it.
I'll go and get it myself!
I don't need your help.
I'm going to have to return you.
What now?
Yeah, let me drive you.
Forget it.
Come to the parking lot.
I don't want to!
I'll wait.
That Shim Gun Wook, where is he?
That Shim Gun Wook, really.
Excuse me.
Oh, Tae Seong.
What are you doing here?
Well...
I was supposed to meet someone.
So, you came to Seoul.
Yes, well...
Have you been well?
Yes.
You brought the glass mask with you,
didn't you?
No.
You didn't bring it with you?
I don't have it with me.
Please don't joke.
You brought it from Japan, didn't you?
Didn't you tell me to rebel
in front of that person?
I did leave that note,
but I'm kind of in an urgent bind.
I'm really sorry,
but can't you just sell it to me?
But I don't want to.
I haven't even had a chance to rebel.
I haven't had a chance to think of
how to play with it,
and you want me to hand it over already?
But, an art piece isn't even a toy,
so how could you play with it?
But to me,
it's not that different from a toy.
Please don't talk like that.
And, rebelling for no reason
isn't necessarily a good thing.
If you are good to the person,
that person might be moved.
And that means you win, doesn't it?
Moved.
I don't think that person is someone
who would feel moved by anything I do.
I'm curious about something.
What is it?
Why did you just leave it?
You said you needed the glass mask,
and you seemed so desperate in the snow.
Could it be that you hoped
I would bring it to you?
No,
I just wanted to buy it in a proper manner.
How much do you want for it?
The current market...
I don't need money.
Then, shall we go on a date?
Excuse me?
It was a joke.
Well,
if you change your mind or
your rebellion ends, call me.
Excuse me.
I'll deliver it shortly.
Really?
It's a promise, right?
Then, I'll be waiting.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Young Master is moving in,
so send some people over.
Ah, yes.
Manager ahjumma,
Tae Seong oppa is back?
Ah, yes.
Then you should have told me earlier!
Gun Wook oppa probably
came back with him.
Agassi!
[Life-saving Rope]
I knew he'd do this.
Is there something wrong with his phone?
It looks like it's been worn.
I just tried it on at home.
Everyone does that.
I tried it on and it didn't really
seem to suit me and the size was off.
Wait just a moment.
We'll refund it, but next time,
you must bring a receipt.
Ah, yes.
But that outfit...
It was part of a new collection that
was given as a promotion to VVIPs,
but you're saying another
employee truly sold it to you, yes?
It was a promotional
collection given out to VVIP's?
No, I bought it.
Then, have a good day.
Hey, one for me too.
Give me some money then.
I guess you got a little money today.
It looks that way.
I got a little money today.
I'm going.
Hey kid.
You can have this.
Hey!
No way...
What, you don't like it?
It seems you guys have the same taste.
Where did you get this?
What do you want to know for?
Ahjussi.
Huh?
Do you have a girlfriend?
Do you make good money?
Ah, that's right,
you're unemployed.
Still, do you happen to have a house?
Why are you asking all of a sudden?
See, I just had a really good idea.
Why are there so many
people curious about me?
I'm going now.
You are?
See you later.
Okay.
He looked kinda like he's got some.
You have a message.
I met with Hong Tae Seong.
He says he'll give me the glass mask.
But if you play games with me again,
you're dead!
Oh, yes.
A package came for the director.
Ah, thank you.
Mmm, come in.
Director.
Someone has sent a gift.
Yeah?
Leave it and go.
Jae In,
how's the glass mask going?
You'll be able to see it shortly.
Open it.
Is this it?
Yes.
You look at it on your own.
I'll be outside.
All right.
Don't you need to go into the office?
If I go in now,
it will just be time to leave work.
It must be nice for you, since you
don't have specific office hours.
I wonder if she has opened it by now.
Did you call me?
Did you see it?
What is this?!
Were these all that were in there?
Was the person who took the glass mask him?
Yes.
You lose the glass mask to someone like him.
Is that all you measure up to, Moon Jae In?!
You amateur!
You lose a piece to a guy who
doesn't even know how to look at art?!
What the hell kind of work is this?!
Please control your temper at work.
It's possible that someone else
could buy it first.
But is it any reason to get so angry?
A high-bred person like you...
You, did you do this
on purpose to annoy me?
You're bored, aren't you?
It was fun, wasn't it?
It's not something for you to play with.
Hand it over.
Shall I give it to her or not?
What should I do?
You dare... you dare...
It's mine.
I can do what I want with it, right?
Yours?
How can there be anything that's yours?
Was there anything that was yours
from the start?
Whatever you lay your hands on,
things, women, you ruin them.
You break them, and ultimately lose them!
Do you have anyone left beside you?
And you say it's yours?!
Do you want to destroy that too?
Go ahead and break it!
I was just going to.
I'm the one who breaks whatever
I lay my hands on, things, women...
This measly little mask?
I'll break it for you.
The glass mask you wanted,
I leave it here for you.
That was a piece that Ryuu-sensei created.
It's not a piece
which should be so casually broken.
I don't know how great
you think you are,
but that's not something
you can treat so carelessly!
How could you break it so easily?!
Do you know what you just did?!
Miss Moon Jae In.
You impertinent thing.
How dare you overstep your bounds
and interfere?
Is this a place for you to step in?
There are lines that people
are not to cross.
Lines that fit your position.
How dare a thing like you...
try to slap my son's face?
A thing like you...
and in front of my eyes!
That old glass mask.
He can break 10 like it.
If we need to, we can just
pay money and buy another one.
But over something like this,
you dare to belittle my son?!
What the hell
do you think you are?!
Get out of my office immediately.
Jae In.
Let go.
I want to be alone.
I'm touched.
Why, all of a sudden,
are you acting like a mother?
After all these years...
What you just said right now...
Did you mean it?
I'm saying this, just in case.
Make no mistake.
I didn't do it to play mother
to you after all these years.
I just wanted to make that girl realize,
not to take Haeshin Group
or me so lightly.
And another thing,
I just can't tolerate those who
overstep the bounds of their position.
Do you get it?
So, stop humiliating our Haeshin.
It's embarrassing.
You should have just not said anything.
"Ah, she really is my mother."
"Inside, she really does love me
just a little bit."
I almost mistakenly thought those things.
I was almost grateful.
Clean up in here.
You...
I...
I'll be Hong Tae Seong.
I'm Hong Tae Seong right now,
so get angry with me.
Get angry with me just like
the first time you met me.
You won't be able to say anything
to the real Hong Tae Seong anyway.
Do it.
Hong Tae Seong.
You... do you think I gave
up the glass mask for this?
This is the first time since I started
this work that I've ever let a piece go.
I did it for you.
I did it so that you'd come back.
If you came back,
I wanted to get close to you somehow.
But, what is this?
The mask is broken.
And Madame Shin's goodwill
towards me is broken.
I've learned once again what happens
when I mess with guys like you.
Someday... suddenly,
even if your thoughts should fall on me,
I pray you don't sadly cry
Some far away day...
Some far away day,
I pray we don't meet again...
I pray we don't meet again.
Someday, the two of us...
Someday, the two of us,
whatever chance may bring,
I pray we don't meet again.
I pray.
This, I confess to you.
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
Translator: meju
Timer: casajuve
Editor/QC: aaachec
Final QC: ay_link
Coordinators: mily2, ay_link
I'm always near, wandering near your side.
Because my thorn causes you such pain,
I try my best to hide away the tears...
Who the hell are you?
Are you the Shim Gun Wook I know?
What's your relationship?
If you lie, you're dead.
Tell me the truth!
The child who was adopted
into Chairman Hong's house
and then put up for adoption.
Whatever the reason,
I won't fall for you.
What if I were to get close to you?
I won't let you be.
That place really makes a person
feel strange.
Being angry, being happy or sad,
feelings I like and don't like,
all become meaningless.
What's the use of being good to me?
I may see you for a while like this,
and then I'll throw you away.
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Watch dramas legally at
dramafever.com | crunchyroll.com