First, you need to know
something about them.
The beautiful ones.
The flawless four.
Everyone wanted to be them.
You know them.
They went to your school too.
They totally ruled.
The one in green, that's Courtney.
She was the leader.
She was like Satan in heels.
The blonde, Marcie Fox,
a legend in her own little mind.
Known to herself as Foxy.
The leggy one with the pigtails
is Julie, doomed to be popular
because of that face
and because she was best friends
with the one in the pink.
That's Liz Purr.
She was special.
Everybody loved Liz,
not just because she was beautiful
and popular and rich and smart.
She was all of those things,
but more than anything,
she was sweet.
Courtney ruled with terror,
but Liz ruled with kindness.
She was like the Princess Di
of Reagan High,
and that pissed Courtney off.
Liz Purr was just...
Well, she was perfect.
I used to dream about what
it would be like to be her:
Elizabeth Purr.
It's a shame about
what happened to Liz.
That was no way to wake up
on your 17th birthday.
Ah!
She is gonna die!
It's so much better than last year.
I wish my friends did that for me.
Yeah, right. You'd have us killed.
Brutally maimed, my dear.
What're we gonna do to her?
We'll stuff her pretty face
with pancakes,
then tie her to the flagpole
in her bra and undies
and watch the fun begin.
Whoo!
She is gonna die! Ha, ha, ha.
Polaroid.
Hey, birthday girl, rise and shine!
Who's doing the honors?
Me.
Aren't we anxious?
One is for witch,
two is for bitch...
Pop it, Marcie!
Surprise!
Oh, my God.
What happened to her?
What's in her throat?
Courtney?
Oh, my God.
This is a joke, right?
This is a total joke.
Say it's a joke.
- It was supposed to be for fun.
- Oh, my God!
This isn't happening.
I just didn't want her to scream.
Oh, God.
Oh, God, Liz!
I thought a jawbreaker
would be funny.
You gagged her
with a jawbreaker?
We have to call someone
right now.
No way.
Why not? It was an accident.
Oh, my God,
did you hear that?
I think I'm gonna be sick.
Sick?
That's it. Liz is sick.
Courtney, she is dead.
Does school know that? Don't think so.
What? You cannot just call
in sick for her.
We have to tell somebody.
Liz is--
Dead. Liz is dead.
Do you have any idea
what that means?
You're a shoo-in for prom queen?
That is so not funny.
Our best friend is dead.
People won't be pleased.
But they'll understand.
No. You understand.
I am not getting fucked
because I was sweet enough
to play a clever prank
for my friend's birthday.
Just give me the phone.
Okay, who's got
the motherly voice?
No. No way.
I want nothing
to do with this.
Okay.
Wait, Courtney--
Shh.
Ms. Sherwood, please.
Hi, Ms. Sherwood,
this is Mrs. Purr,
Elizabeth's mother.
I'm sorry, but Elizabeth
won't be to school today.
Oh, I know,
she's had a lot of absences,
but the poor dear woke up
with a blistering fever.
Can you send one of her friends
with her assignments?
Thank you ever so much.
Have a nice day. Bye.
That was really good.
What do you mean?
The way you imitated Liz's mom.
I'm just saying you're in control.
Oh. I know.
Okay, reality check.
Liz is in the trunk
of this car, and she is dead.
That is a sad,
fucked up thing.
But you will walk into
that school and strut
your shit down the hallway
like everything is
peachy fucking keen.
Get it?
Julie?
Whatever.
All right, bitches, out.
Move it, move it!
That means you too, gusher.
Come on.
Hi, Julie.
Oh. Hi, Fern.
No, no, no,
space cadet.
Drinking fountain
down the hall.
I don't think I can
do this.
It's just a day,
like any other day.
Now, what would we do
on any other day?
Pre-lunch touchups?
That's right, Marcie.
Take a long, hard look
in the mirror, girls.
It's beauty time.
Hello, girls. Having a smoke?
A toke? Some dope?
No loitering in the
girl's room.
Trouble brews in this room.
Not so fast.
Elizabeth is out today.
Which one of you will stop by
my office to pick up
her assignments for her?
Miss Shane?
With pleasure, Ms. Sherwood.
Excellent. Make it by 3.
I have a pet to groom.
Okay.
And Miss Shane,
please cover your bosoms.
This is a learning institution,
not a brothel.
Do it yourself.
Be nice, girls.
"Be nice, girls."
Nice is not enough.
lf I was friends with
every Pam, Beth and Sherry
because they're nice,
I'd have Noah's fucking Ark
in my phone book.
Oh.
Remember, everything
is peachy keen.
Peachy fucking keen.
I know this a bit out of our realm
of comprehension.
The delusion, the derangement,
the descent into madness.
She says it herself,
"What's done cannot be undone."
I know this may be hard to understand.
It's not like your lives today, what with
your acne mask and corn dogs.
Planet head.
It's nothing to laugh about.
There was nothing fun and fancy free
for Shakespeare's tragic characters.
In the Dark Ages,
knowledge of female anatomy
was divulged through autopsy
and execution.
Women deemed
Hey, baby.
criminal or demented were
put to death,
both on and off their menstrual flow.
Then we crack the egg ever so gently,
but with ample force.
Cool, you got a stillborn.
Oh, nasty.
I say we just put her back in bed.
We can't put her back in bed.
Why not?
She's got a jawbreaker in her throat.
Ah. We can get it out.
I've got eyelash curlers.
It's perfect. She was up late,
watching TV, sucking on a jawbreaker.
Maybe she was practicing,
if you know what I mean,
ha-ha, and swallowed.
Wait a minute.
What?
Rape.
They'll check to see if she was raped.
Maybe Liz had a friend over.
You know,
mummy and Daddy's last night away.
Maybe he's from school, maybe not.
But definitely into kink.
He got a little rough, went too far.
There's a fine line
between pleasure and pain.
She screamed for help,
but her screams were muffled
by the huge candy ball.
She tried, but there was nothing.
Only sugary, sweet death.
Oh, my God. That, like,
totally gave me the chills.
Nobody's gonna believe that.
There is no proof.
They will because
it's their worst nightmare.
Elizabeth Purr,
the very picture of teenage
perfection, obliterated by perversion?
You are sick, Courtney.
Shit! I was supposed
to pick up Liz's homework.
What if Ms. Sherwood took it?
We kill her.
Heh. Did you see her face?
It doesn't matter
that I have to get there.
Yes? Yes?
Ms. Sherwood?
Oh. Hello, Fern.
I wanted to know
if you were gonna chaperone
the botany club's garden party.
Yes, I am. Of course,
I wouldn't miss that for the world.
Ahem. You know, Fern, do you know
a senior named Elizabeth Purr?
You mean the meow?
Excuse me?
Liz is the cat's meow.
Heh. I'm sure she is. In any case,
the poor thing is sick with the flu.
Somebody has to take her
her assignments
and Miss Shane tardy.
I could do it.
You will?
It'd be an honor.
Oh, thank you so much.
Thank you.
Fern! Uh-- Ahem.
I didn't give her the address.
Ms. Sherwood, wait!
Ms. Sherwood.
Miss Shane.
I forgot to pick up Liz's homework.
Right, you were tardy.
But, thankfully, Fern Mayo
stopped by my office.
She's on her way right now.
Mayonnaise?
Liz hates her.
Hate is a very ugly word, Miss Fox.
Fern Mayo is a dependable
young woman.
She may not be pretty like you,
but she gives as well as receives.
We could learn a thing or two
from the Fern Mayos of the world,
couldn't we?
We have to get there before Mayo.
That is no 1 05 pounds.
God, she's so stiff.
No more aerobics for this girl. Ugh!
Panties on or off?
Rip them.
Let's see. lf I were being choked,
I'd claw the sheets to smithereens.
Should we shred them?
No time.
Hi, Liz.
Hi, Liz. My name's Fern Mayo.
Like hold the mayo?
You don't know me,
but I know you.
Help me get her legs. Ugh!
What're you doing to me?
Oh, my God.
I'm so sorry.
It's from last year's prank.
It's one of those cards.
You push a button, record a greeting.
You open it--
What're you doing to me?
Oh, my God. Stop it!
It's like she's in here with us. Alive.
Don't touch anything.
Let's just do this and get out.
I love your hair.
I love the way it shines.
What?
She looked at me.
I swear to God,
she looked at me.
Her eyes are open.
She has to look somewhere.
My God, Marcie, she's dead. Relax.
Liz?
How's that?
Very natural.
Thank you.
Liz?
Jules?
I need your seal
of approval here.
Now come over here
and check it out.
- Does it look real?
- I can't do this. No!
Liz?
Did you hear that?
You're being paranoid.
Will you relax?
I killed Liz, the teen dream.
Deal with it.
I have to get out of here.
What?
What's wrong?
You don't understand.
I'm not doing this.
- I don't want anything to do with this.
- It's a little late for that.
Courtney, please. I want to go to the
police, tell them it was an accident.
We didn't mean to kill her.
The police will come
when her parents find the body.
She was raped.
You can't just say that
because she's in bed
with her legs spread.
I can't believe this!
I am looking after us.
I am saving your ass,
and you shit on me.
Go to hell, Courtney.
Fern?
You're Fern Mayo, right?
I'm Courtney.
I don't think we've officially met,
what with the cruel politics
of high school and all.
Hi.
May I introduce Marcie Fox?
Foxy.
Fern, I need you to be
completely honest with us.
And I know you will be, because
you're an honest kind of gal.
Tell us, did you hear anything?
And let's not lie.
I have this gift. I can smell a lie.
Leave her alone,
Courtney.
Fern is a big girl, Julie.
She can speak for herself.
Fern, come on,
I'm gonna take you home.
Homework.
What?
I was sent with Liz's homework.
Isn't that nice? Heh, heh.
And you heard us?
It's okay.
Fern.
No one's gonna hurt you.
I don't know.
She doesn't know.
We're all girlfriends here.
It's just between us.
What do you know?
She doesn't know anything.
Come on, Fern.
Say what you heard.
Come on, Fern. Say it!
What did you hear?
Marcie, get her!
Let her go.
- Have a little scare, dear?
- Boo!
I'll come clean with you, Fern,
because once our bloated boo-boo
floats to the surface,
it'll all become clear
in that little head of yours, anyway.
And we wouldn't want you
to do anything rash, would we?
No. Uh-uh.
You knew Liz Purr, right?
I know of her.
Knew of her. Past tense.
She's dead, Fern. She died.
But we've got a bit of a problem
because you know we did it.
You heard us. That gives you
a little something called power.
The power to tell. And you're
the kind of girl that tells.
A tattletale.
A rat.
I know you.
I know all about you.
You're the one in the corner
that the geeks won't dance with
because they're at home
fucking old pervs in cyberspace,
thinking they're doing some hot babe.
There's nothing to hide, Fern.
You're nothing.
We're everything.
You're the shadow, we're the sun.
But I'm here to offer you
something you never dreamed of.
Something that you were
never meant to be, but will be.
Because today, Fern, my dear,
fate has decided that you are cool.
We're gonna make you...
one of us.
Beautiful, popular,
loved, feared.
All you've ever dreamed of.
lf, and only if, you never,
ever tell anyone what you heard.
Think of it.
This is sick, Courtney.
You don't own someone
by making them beautiful.
A makeover can't hide the truth.
Liz is gone, Fern.
Take her place.
You know you want it.
Think about boys.
Think about prom.
They'll be lining up
for you.
Not with oil.
But with drive.
- Watch the eyes come alive.
- You as me, as us.
A dash of magenta.
Lashes bold, black.
- X-rated gloss.
- Lips full.
- Hair frames the portrait.
- Some gilded.
Color, the secret to not growing old.
We cut, layer and curl.
- For a look that is you.
- For the hair of a dead girl.
We use model glue.
- Lips full and dark.
- Lush.
A fine line that traces
a deep, crimson heart.
- Rest now, sweetness.
- Till the day all shall see
the beauty we molded
from sheer misery.
Elizabeth!
Honey, we're home.
Stand straight.
- Stop shaking.
- I'm sorry.
I still can't get over myself.
Oh, fresh meat!
To think, my 2nd-grade teacher said
I had no artistic potential.
It's like a dream.
I made you and I'm God.
That's all you need to know.
No.
Oh, my God, Julie is sitting
with the body-art rejects.
- Is she tweaking?
- It's a beautiful thing.
To make someone fall so far, so fast.
Look what the kitty dragged in.
Meow.
You look really great, Fern.
Thank you.
I thought you should know
that Liz's parents came home
this morning.
So?
So I think we should
tell someone
what happened.
There's nothing to tell.
I made cocksure of that last night.
What does that mean?
Girls, why don't you run ahead?
Listen, bitch, one word
and you're over. I mean that.
I'm not scared of you anymore.
We saw you.
We all know you did it.
No one will ever believe you.
Ask Fern.
Ask Marcie.
We saw everything.
Fucking liar.
One word and you perish.
I promise you that.
Toodles.
Fern, no!
What are you doing?
God. Tuna munch?
But my mom always--
We never eat at lunch.
Do you understand me?
For some damn good reason we did,
we would never, ever eat
out of a brown paper bag.
I don't care if there's
a four-star culinary masterpiece in it.
Get rid of it.
Sorry.
lf I get a zit because of this--
I'm sorry.
I'd better never have kids.
I have zero patience. Ha, ha, ha.
Don't think we're anorexic, we're not.
That's for the Karen Carpenter table.
We're not stupid. We eat.
And we eat well.
We just don't eat in public.
Well, at school, at least.
We don't want people
judging us by what we eat.
It gives them ammo,
and the only ones with ammo are us.
Food's cool and all.
You need it to live.
But the mere act of eating
invokes thoughts of digestion,
flatulation, defecation, even,
shall we say, complexion defection.
I wouldn't be caught dead
eating a greasy pizza.
Not even in front of the
uItra-special students,
the deaf, dumb and the blind.
because they're associating that
greasy pizza with your shiny face.
A zit, a blackhead,
a cluster of pores.
It's another vexing stress
we don't need.
Life is hard enough
without added anxiety.
So are introductions
in order?
Dane, this is--
Violette.
Hm. Pretty name.
You're a transfer or what?
Dane, let's not perplex her.
She's had a trying morning
with the trauma of
changing schools and all.
Reagan's a whole new battlefield,
and we were on the subject of...
strategy.
But come by a little later.
I don't know about you,
but I could do with some kink.
You got it, baby.
Nice meeting you--
Violette.
Yeah, that. See you, Foxy.
Sit on it, Dane.
Heh, heh, heh.
Violette?
Mm-hm.
I like it.
It's called thinking on your toes,
a must if you're going
to rule the school.
I was thinking, Fern.
It's a plant, right?
I don't know about you,
but I would much rather be a flower.
A rose? Too obvious.
Never send a rose unless
dyed black as a warning.
And if one is sent to you,
destroy it, along with the sender.
Emotionally, of course.
It's not like we kill people.
On purpose.
Anyway,
you're extra fancy. You're Violette.
My Violette.
May I help you?
I'm Detective Vera Cruz.
I need some information
about one of your students:
Elizabeth Purr.
Oh, my.
Julie!
What are you doing
waiting for the bus?
Don't ask.
What happened to your friends?
I don't want to talk about it, Zach.
Well, can I give you a lift?
Okay.
Cool car.
Thanks.
You shined today.
You've got the look,
the walk.
But popularity is fleeting.
Trends change.
People change.
It's all about details.
Pay attention to details.
Look at my nails.
In junior high, I wore
only pink. Now it makes
me puke. So I change.
See? It's called Demented.
Seriously, the color's
called Demented.
Mine? Decayed.
Like Julie. Our friendship
with her is decayed. Rot.
Julie is over.
Done, null and void.
In two weeks, no one will know her.
Including you.
From now on, you don't know her.
Never knew her.
She's like Fern Mayo. A bad dream.
Get it?
Well, thanks for the lift.
It's no problem.
Okay.
So do you wanna, maybe,
call me sometime?
Yeah. I would love to.
Yeah?
Well, bye.
Okay.
Mayo, please. It's a residence.
Hello?
Fern? Hi, it's me, Julie.
Oh, hi, Julie.
I know you're not
supposed to talk to me.
No, no. It's okay.
This must be really weird for you.
Yeah.
I mean, knowing about
what happened to Liz
and everything else.
Yeah.
Fern, do you remember 4th grade?
Fourth grade?
Yeah, we used to have sleepovers.
Remember my Holly Hobbie oven?
Your parents wouldn't
let you have one.
They were afraid you were gonna
electrocute yourself.
We used to bake cakes together.
God, they were the worst cakes.
I'm scared, Fern.
I'm really scared.
It's just weird
how time erases things.
Time doesn't erase things.
People erase things.
Yeah.
People erase people.
Can you hold on for a second?
Hello?
Never answer after one ring.
What were you thinking, Violette?
Hi, Courtney.
Are you on the other line?
No.
Good. When I call, you listen.
I don't care if your little sister
locks herself in the kitchen freezer,
Courtney Shane is priority one.
Get it?
I brought you something sweet.
Hm.
What is it?
It's called a Big Stick.
A Big Stick?
Uh-huh.
You want it?
I want you.
And I want you to suck
the Big Stick.
God, you're a little sick.
I said I could do with a little kink.
Now suck it and see
or get the hell out.
Do you like it?
It's okay.
Okay? There's nothing kinky
about "okay," now, is there?
Now I said, do you like it?
Yeah. Yeah, I like it.
Heh, heh, heh.
You're good at that.
I'm good at a lot of things.
I should have known.
You are on the wrestling team.
Hey, fuck you.
Hey.
Now, right about now,
I could get really hot.
Oh, yeah.
And I mean...
hot.
You know what I like to do
when I get hot?
Oh, yeah, baby.
I want to, Dane.
I want to real bad.
The problem is
I've forgotten how.
What?
But if you could just show me...
Oh. Mm.
How's that?
That's good.
I better get that.
Don't go.
Don't come.
Are you Courtney Shane?
Maybe.
Dad, don't be a dick.
What did you say?
You gonna launch
into another lecture
on the ugliness of profanity?
I just wish
you could hear yourself.
You sound uneducated.
Dad.
And you know what?
It reflects on your parents.
Parent.
That's right.
I've gotta be the mom and the dad.
Whatever.
I was watching Oprah today.
That must be the mom in you.
You know what the topic was?
Let me guess. "Club Kids"?
No, it was "Is Your Child a Follower?"
I'm done. Can I go?
And you know what?
I was deeply concerned because,
yes, Oprah, my child is a follower.
You are so lame.
You don't even have any friends.
Whatever happened to
my sweet little Brownie?
Don't.
My Girl Scout?
You remember the Tiffany concert?
Ho-ho-ho.
You loved Tiffany.
Oh, my God.
Thank God!
Nice to meet you, Courtney.
I'm Detective Cruz.
You can call me Vera.
Okay. Vera.
So you're Liz's best bud, huh?
Yes.
You went to school that day?
Of course.
Did you try calling her?
Why?
lf your close friend is not at school,
she should be.
Depends.
Okay. Let me ask you this.
Did you call in sick for Liz?
Did I what?
Of course not.
Did it shock you?
What?
Her death.
Not personally.
What, trying to get used to the idea?
Yeah. I guess you could say that.
Do you know who was
with Liz that night?
Uh-uh.
Come on, who was the lucky guy?
What do you mean?
Who was she fucking?!
No one.
You ever seen
one of these before?
No.
Yes.
Take a lot of licks
to get one of these down.
Wanna give it a whirl?
No, thank you.
Mm.
It's hard.
Like a rock.
T minus ten, nine, eight...
Jawbreaker.
The name says it all.
It'll break your jaw.
Pretty fucked up name for candy,
don't you think?
Good morning, Reagan High.
It is with deep dismay
and sincere regret
that I inform you
that Elizabeth Purr
a well-known senior
at Reagan High School
was found dead in her home,
apparently suffering
from acute asphyxiation.
There will be a memorial service
held for Elizabeth
tomorrow at 2:00
at Cloverdale Lawn Rest Home.
And students,
Mr. Murk, our guidance counselor,
will be available
for those of you
suffering from distress.
My thoughts are with you.
Just tragic.
A beautiful, charismatic
girl like Elizabeth Purr
just struck down
by the hand of fate.
I still can't believe it.
You said her mama
called in sick for her.
Yes, sick.
She said Elizabeth had the flu.
Her mama said she
didn't make that call.
Oh, no.
It could have been anybody.
It could've been a sex-crazed maniac.
lf I had anything to do with her demise,
I don't know what I'll do.
It'll be all right.
A neighbor said she saw
a girl with schoolbooks come up
to the house at 3:30 that day.
Yes. Miss Shane.
I sent Miss Shane home
with her assignments.
Was it Courtney Shane?
Yes. No.
Miss Shane was tardy, as usual,
and Fern Mayo was in my office,
so I sent Miss Mayo home
with the assignments.
She is such a nice girl.
Mayo?
Yes.
Is that M-A-Y-O?
Fern Mayo.
Come to think of it,
Miss Mayo has been
absent for several days.
You don't think that
Miss Mayo could have...?
No. Miss Mayo is as sweet
as the days are long.
It's a crazy world, Ms. Sherwood.
Some of the sweetest candies
are as sour as death inside.
- Hey! You're Violette, right?
- Mm-hm.
I'm Brenda,
Chad's girlfriend.
I don't think we've met.
Oh, God,
I just love your hair!
Mm, hi.
We heard
you were the last person
to see Liz Purr alive.
That is so cool.
Heh, heh.
Well, bye.
Oh, look, you have groupies.
I know. Aren't they cute?
Now about boys. You need one.
Only one?
One's enough to start.
We don't want to baffle her.
So what turns
you on?
Marcie likes a nice,
round ass, don't you, Marcie?
Good morning, Vera.
Miss Shane.
I like cheekbones. You know,
a boy with a little Bowie going on.
What do you like?
I've always been partial to--
Darling, spare us the details.
Meet your teen dream.
Violette, this is Zach Tartak.
That's him?
You don't think he's cute?
Most girls go crazy over him.
He's in drama so we can't
guarantee hetero status.
But it doesn't matter.
He is beyond fine.
l.e., uItra-pretty.
Unapproachable. Always in rehearsal.
When he's not rehearsing,
he's with the drama crowd.
Can you say "freak"? Ha, ha, ha.
Freak.
So the only sure way to meet him
is to star in the school play.
No. No, no, no.
Relax.
It's high school, not Broadway.
Do you
smell something?
Hi, Fern.
I don't know a Fern.
There is no Fern.
It's Violette.
What?
My name's Violette.
Learn it.
Live it.
Love it.
Ladies.
Hey.
Sorry I'm late.
It's okay.
This just hasn't been my day,
you know?
Yeah, I know. lf you want to be
alone tonight, I understand.
I know that's what I would want.
No, it's okay.
Liz was the only one
that meant anything to me.
With Courtney and Marcie,
it was all games.
It was total bullshit.
Imagine what it looked like
from the outside.
God.
It was a total sideshow, Zach.
You ever get the feeling that
maybe this is one of those things
that shouldn't even be happening?
What do you mean?
It just seemed to me
like you were the kind of girl
that didn't give the time
of day to anybody.
But when I saw you that day
waiting for the bus,
it was like I knew.
You were alone and weren't
with them anymore.
I mean, I would've never thought
to approach you.
I've seen you.
I've seen you see me.
Heh, heh, heh.
I just wouldn't have gone there.
There's no way.
Why not?
I mean, I liked you.
Yeah?
Come on.
I want to show you something.
It's so beautiful up here.
This is where I come when
I don't want anyone to find me.
Now I can find you.
It's really hard to track you down, Fern.
Violette.
My name's Violette.
Fern was a childhood name,
but now, as a senior,
Violette seems more appropriate.
Can we keep that between us?
Of course.
Now, Ms. Sherwood says you took
Liz's assignments to her home.
Would you tell me about that?
Liz and I never officially met.
Well, we kind of met.
I had a term paper due.
And I was late for class.
It was the nicest thing
anyone's ever done for me.
So you two
became friends?
We had a class together.
Algebra. I sat behind her.
She's got this shiny hair, you know?
It smells like apples.
I'd sit there,
staring at her from behind.
She has this cluster of beauty marks
on the back of her neck.
And I know this sounds weird,
but they were in
the most fascinating patterns.
Like a puzzle waiting
to be solved, a Rubik's cube,
an uncharted constellation.
So that's what I'd do. I'd sit there,
stare at the back of her neck,
playing connect-the-dots.
I've found salmon swimming upstream
on the back of that neck.
Spider webs,
sea monkeys even.
And the bell would ring
and she'd be the first one out.
And I'd be stuck there,
sitting with all these
salmon and sea monkeys
dancing in my head. Heh.
Very interesting.
So I guess Liz
was a hero to you, huh?
I mean, wouldn't it bother you
to lose such a close friend?
This is high school, Detective Cruz.
What is a friend, anyway?
A friend is someone who tells
the truth no matter what.
A true friend never lies.
Look. Liz was sweet.
I did her a favor.
Can I go now, please?
Sure, Violette.
This is high school, Detective Cruz.
What is a friend, anyway?
Liz is the cat's meow. Meow!
I killed Liz.
I killed the teen dream.
Deal with it.
We're gonna make you one of us.
You're Violette.
My Violette.
A friend is someone who tells
the truth, no matter what.
Detective Cruz?
I don't know if I should be
talking about this.
About what?
Liz was a private person, you know?
But I want to help.
Well, that's why I'm here.
I just don't know how to say this.
Liz had this craving.
Craving for what?
For men.
Strange men.
No one knew,
not even Marcie or Julie.
It was her thing. I respected that.
And what was her thing?
Sex.
Sex?
Yeah. With strangers.
She wasn't into the boys at school.
It wasn't about boys.
She liked the real thing.
Real, live, strange men.
She'd have her way with them.
They'd be gone by dawn.
In and out.
Never to be heard from again.
That's the way she liked it.
It wasn't like in high school
where you sleep with a guy and
the entire school knows the trim
of your bikini wax the next day.
You know which bars
she frequented?
Yeah.
I have a pretty good idea.
Hi, Brenda.
That seat's saved.
But I always sit here.
You do?
I'm sorry. This stall is reserved.
What?
Haven't you met Violette?
It's all about Violette.
Have you guys seen the new girl?
Who is she, anyway?
- I don't know.
- No one does.
She have a last name?
She's doing the Madonna thing.
I heard she toured with Madonna.
Supposedly she's a model.
Totally bicoastal.
Or just plain bi.
Hot. Heh, heh.
I know. Right?
Zach?
Hi.
Nice to meet you. I'm Violette.
Yeah, I know.
I saw you in Grease,
twice.
You did, huh?
What can I say?
You rocked my world.
I rocked your world?
It beats football.
Not that I have a problem with football.
I mean, I am head cheerleader.
Head cheerleader
and star of the school play.
Well, that's a first.
Is it?
Yeah, it is.
Let me tell you something.
Sports and drama,
it's like plaids and stripes.
They don't mix.
Well, the rules have been changed,
haven't they?
Your ass is much
too precious for vinyl.
Thank you.
Hi, girls.
What's wrong with this picture?
Is this spot mine? Heh, heh, heh.
Yeah.
I really like it here.
Yep.
It's really great to have someone
to disappear with.
Yeah.
Someplace to go.
You know a girl named Violette?
Yeah.
Yeah? She just got cast in the play.
What?
Well, you know, she's new.
I guess.
It's weird, though. She told me
she saw me twice in Grease.
She said that I rocked her world.
It doesn't quite
all add up to me though.
Do you know a girl named Fern?
Fern Mayo?
Uh-uh.
Come on.
The girl, she's a little geeky?
She does errands for Ms. Sherwood.
Okay. I think I know.
Well, Fern Mayo is Violette.
What do you mean?
She's Courtney's creation.
Why would Courtney give her
the time of day?
You don't want to know.
I do. Please tell me.
Liz Purr is part of it.
Jesus, Julie. What is it?
Okay.
Do you know how girls
sometimes kidnap their girlfriends
on their birthdays?
Well, we do that.
Okay.
Well, Courtney had
a stroke of genius.
It was totally disgusting.
Courtney put her back
in the bed
and tried to make it
like she was raped.
Well, tried to.
That's when Fern showed up.
Fern?
Take her place.
So what're you gonna do?
I don't know.
You gotta do something.
I know.
You can't pretend nothing happened--
I know that.
You gotta tell somebody.
I'm taking Dane to the prom.
Surprise.
Aren't we cocky? Too bad
you don't have the cock part down.
Well, at least
I'm not jocking it. Heh.
Dane may be a jock,
but let's face it.
He was born to be prom king.
What he does after prom
is his problem.
He could get married, coach
Little League. I could give a shit.
He's a yearbook photo,
a piece of nostalgia that
won't stand the test of time.
So where's the cherry bomb?
Rehearsal.
Ah. Good. Julie can kiss
drama boy goodbye.
I think Violette is out of control.
I mean, the car, the parking place.
Oh, honey. It's like when
people first get money.
They're called nouveau riche.
They drape themselves
in fur and jewels.
They're pathetic,
but they don't know any better.
Yeah, but Violette--
Violette is the same.
For once in her pathetic life,
people are giving her the time of day.
The little whore is milking it
for all she's worth.
What the hell?
- You stupid cow!
- What?
- Courtney!
- Get off.
Who the heck do you think you are?
Angelyne?
What the fuck
are you doing?
Exactly what you taught me.
I taught you
to disrespect us?
You taught me to rule.
That's right. Rule, bitch!
But don't forget who made you.
I'm sorry. Sometimes I'm
at the mercy of the crowd.
I can't help it, Courtney.
They love to hate me.
Don't fool yourself. Deep down,
they know who you are, Fern.
I'm Violette.
You're whatever the fuck
I want you to be.
Courtney.
Pretty little Courtney.
Let's stop pretending, shall we?
You once spoke of ammo.
Ammunition, if I'm correct.
I don't know why,
but it really struck me.
In the last few weeks,
it's all come clear.
And on a clear day, baby,
you can see tomorrow.
Excuse me?
I've got the power.
Her name's sweet Liz, remember?
Your bloated boo-boo?
I'll fucking shred you, you whore!
And I'll tell a secret.
Do tell. But don't be surprised
when they laugh in your face.
Cruz has a suspect in custody.
It ain't me.
I know the truth. I know
what really happened, Courtney.
I made you, and I can
break you just as easily.
Good idea.
Kill me like you did Liz.
Courtney?
Julie, you're doing
the right thing.
I know, I know.
Everything's gonna be
okay, right?
Right.
But I'm guiIty too.
Courtney will say I was there.
I didn't stop them or tell the police.
That's why we need evidence.
That would be great.
But Courtney destroyed everything.
There's nothing.
What about the Polaroid?
Didn't you say there
was a camera?
Yes. She took a picture.
Yeah? And who has it?
I don't know.
What do you mean?
I don't know! It was chaos.
We popped the trunk.
She dropped it.
She dropped the camera.
Okay, it was right about here.
It's gone.
Look, Julie,
is there anything else?
There's nothing.
At this point,
it's my word against hers.
Looks like that's gonna
have to be good enough.
I understand you have something
about the Liz Purr murder.
I wanted to tell you
that we have a suspect
in custody.
We found the man leaving
Liz's house that morning.
lf his semen matches--
What're you talking about?
Julie, Liz wasn't as innocent
as she appeared to be.
Bullshit! It's not true.
I know it's difficult
for you to understand--
Excuse me.
This isn't happening.
Liz was a virgin.
Someone had sex in that bed
after Liz died.
It was just the four of you, right?
Yeah.
Wait a minute.
Unless someone went back.
Oh, my God.
What?
She said it herself.
They'll believe it because
it's their worst nightmare.
Elizabeth Purr, the picture
of teenage perfection
obliterated by perversion.
What are you saying?
Courtney found some poor guy
to have sex in Liz's bed
to make it look like murder.
What?
Come on.
We gotta get out of here.
Where are we going?
We are gonna bring that bitch down.
Violette?
Oh, my God.
What the hell is this?
Well, there you are.
You had quite a fall, my dear.
What happened?
You fainted out in the quad.
I want you to take it easy, Fern.
What did you say?
Your name is Fern Mayo, correct?
No. No, it's not.
Well, that's what it says right here.
Get me out of here.
There she is!
This is crazy.
Fern Mayo! Fern fucking Mayo!
I thought you looked familiar!
Take off your mask, Fern!
Shut up!
It's over, bitch.
What the hell is this?
Fern?
Oh, my God.
Fern, are you okay?
Fern, it's me, Julie.
I'm not Fern.
Oh, my God.
It's okay, Fern.
Go away. Please just go away.
It's okay.
How can you look at me?
I'm shit.
I'm reprehensible.
No, you're not.
I'm nothing.
Before all this, I was something.
Not much, but something.
You were a good person, Fern.
A lot of good that did me.
I'm nothing. I'm shit.
I'm a nobody.
I don't blame you
for what you did.
I know what it's like to be scared.
That day at Liz's house,
we were terrified.
It's not like you had a choice.
I'm so sorry, Julie. I'm so sorry.
It's okay. I know.
What a fucking tearjerker!
Look. It's like
Terms of Endearment,
part three.
Only this time, the boyfriend's gay.
Yeah. And the rest of the cast sucks!
Who the fuck are you?
What?
They charged some poor guy
with murder?
What have you done, Courtney?
What have you done?
Just what I had to do, dear.
What?
Destroy another life, Courtney?
Life's a bitch, then you die.
No, honey, you're the bitch.
Oh. So aggressive, Julie.
It kind of turns me on.
I'm sure Fern likes it.
Come on, Marce.
This train wreck's getting old.
It's over, Courtney.
I am petrified.
See you at prom tonight, Julie.
Some poor, nameless son of a bitch
thought he got lucky.
Boy, was he wrong, huh?
How could she do that?
She's so evil.
And she's only in high school.
What are we gonna do?
We make her pay for what she did.
We could go to prom.
You're not serious, are you?
Gee, great idea. And on the way,
let's pick up some pig's blood.
- That's real cute.
- Can you take me home?
It's a shame Julie
couldn't make it tonight.
Isnt her boyfriend
in drama?
I bet they couldn't decide
who got to wear the dress.
Ha, ha, ha.
You are evil.
Oh, listen to the queen
of the damned over here.
Come in.
Hi, honey.
Hi, Mom.
Mrs. Purr came by today
and brought some things over
of Liz's that she thought
you might like to have.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Good night, babe.
Good night, Mom.
I killed Liz. I killed the teen dream.
Deal with it.
To prom queens.
Heh, heh, heh.
Oh, my God!
How original.
Nothing like a little girlfriend
to spice up an evening.
How about some
public affection, girls?
It's like, how low
could you possibly get?
Heh, heh, heh.
Carpet munchers!
Ha, ha, ha.
Do you hear something?
No. Do you hear something?
No, I don't.
Well, if it isn't
the beautiful people.
Courtney, I've been
meaning to tell you.
You are to die. To die!
Thank you.
I am so bored tonight.
I think it's time
for a little room service.
Marcie.
Reality check. There's a certain
announcement that needs to be made.
Give it up for
the prom queen.
Oh, my God, Courtney.
I am so sorry.
It's okay. We can't all
be up to speed, can we, girls?
I'm sorry. I'm very sorry.
Ahem. That was wonderful, wasn't it?
Welcome to Reagan High's
senior prom!
You always were such
a spirited group.
Eat me!
All right, all right then.
The moment that we have
all been waiting for.
The announcement
of Reagan High's
prom king and queen!
I love this part.
This is my most exciting part.
I'm nervous. Heh, heh.
Our prom king this year is...
Dane Sanders!
Yeah! Yeah, baby!
Dane was always
the most spirited of the bunch.
All right.
Now the cherry on the cake
of a delicious year.
I'm so pleased to announce
that the prom queen
to reign over our kingdom
this year is...
You'll be pleased.
Courtney Shane!
Reagan High's queen!
We love you, Courtney!
Thank you so much, Ms. Sherwood.
Ha, ha, ha.
Thank you, senior class.
You don't know how much it means
to me. It's a dream come true.
Thank you, everyone.
I love you--
I killed Liz.
I killed the teen dream. Deal with it.
I killed Liz. I killed the teen dream.
Deal with it.
What?
Heh, heh.
I killed Liz. I killed
the teen dream. Deal with it.
Thank you so--
Ms. Sherwood, fix it.
What is going on here? I do not
appreciate a prank at a time like this!
That's her voice.
That's her!
I killed Liz.
Dane?
Dane!
I've been a very,
very naughty boy.
Have you?
Would you like
to do the honors?
That bitch!
- It's gotta be true.
- She'll pay for this.
Eat shit.
- Skanky slut!
- You should be ashamed.
Get off the stage!
Off the stage!
Do you hear me? You are dead!
Motherfucker!
Julie!
Smile pretty, Courtney.
Eh.
This is high school, Detective Cruz.
What is a friend, anyway?