Fitted to 2 CDs by azeroth
I am not a bum.
I'm a jerk.
I once had wealth...
...power...
...and the love of a beautiful woman.
Now l only have two things...
...my friends...
...and...
...my thermos.
My story?
Okay.
It was never easy for me.
I was born a poor black child.
I remember the days...
...sitting on the porch with my family...
...singing and dancing...
...down in Mississippi.
-"Oh, lordy
-"Pick a bale of cotton
-"Pick a bale a day
-"Oh, lordy
-"Pick a bale of cotton
-"Pick a bale a day
-"Gonna jump down, turn around
-"Pick a bale of cotton
-"Pick a bale a day
-"Jump down, turn around
-"Pick a bale of cotton
-"Pick a bale a day
-"Me and my buddy gonna
-"Pick a bale of cotton
-"Pick a bale a day
-"Me and my buddy gonna
-"Pick a bale of cotton
-"Pick a bale a day
-"Oh, lordy
-"Pick a bale of cotton
-"Pick a bale a day
-"Oh, lordy
-"Pick a bale of cotton
-"Pick a bale a day
-"Gonna get on my knees
-"Pick a bale of cotton
-"Pick a bale a day
-"Gonna move all around
-"Pick a bale of cotton
-"Pick a bale a day
-"You want a barebacked man
-"Pick a bale of cotton
-"Pick a bale a day
-"Jump down, turn around
-"Pick a bale of cotton
-"Pick a bale a day"
Boy, l hope everybody's good and hungry.
-I know l am.
-And l'm ready for that.
Here's corn bread.
Collard greens.
And l cooked up those hog maws you like.
Mother, dear,
ain't we forgetting something?
No, l'm not. Today is Navin's birthday.
Happy birthday!.
It's Navin's birthday!.
And l cooked you up your favorite meal.
Tuna fish salad on white bread
with mayonnaise...
...a Tab and a couple of Twinkies.
-Here, darling.
-Mom, thanks.
You're gonna like that shit, man.
I got you a present.
-Gee, Elvira.
-I made it myself.
We got you something, too. A half bottle
of lilac vegetal. It's from both of us.
I drew you this picture.
-Here.
-Thank you.
I want you to have my Zippo.
Dad, you had this since the war.
Thanks.
Thanks, everybody.
God bless us...
...everyone.
Navin!.
Will you pass me the potatoes
and the collard greens?
-Navin, darling.
-I'm sorry l spoiled the party, Mom.
You didn't spoil the party.
I brought you a Twinkie.
I'm not hungry right now.
Feeling different again?
It's like l don't fit in.
It's like l don't belong here.
It's your birthday, and it's time you knew.
You're not our natural-born child.
I'm not?
You were left on our doorstep...
...but we raised you
like you were one of us.
You mean l'm going to stay this color?
I'd love you if you were the color
of a baboon's ass. Come here.
Navin, l wrapped your sandwich
in cellophane, just like you like it.
You want to come in and sing some blues?
No, thanks, Taj.
There's something about those songs.
They depress me.
Come here, darling.
That's it, darling.
You're getting the rhythm. See?
And that concludes
this Sunday night Gospel Hour...
...live from the
Four Square Gospel Church...
...at the Divine Salvation
in St. Louis, Missouri.
The Reverend Willard Willman, Pastor.
And now, music throughout the night.
Music in a mellow mood.
-Grandma!.
-What happened?
-Look!.
Don't touch that radio!. Don't touch it!.
Turn it up!. Turn it up!.
I've never heard music like this before!.
It speaks to me!. Taj!. Dad!.
This is unbelievable. Now watch.
Yeah?
Well, if this is out there,
think how much more is out there!.
This is the kind of music that tells me
to go out there and be somebody!.
-But Navin--
-Let him go.
Now that you're going out into the world...
...there's something you should know.
-You see that?
-Yeah.
That's shit.
And this is Shinola.
Shit.
Shinola.
Son, you're gonna be all right.
Now, what town
are you gonna try for first?
I thought l'd go to St. Louis 'cause
that's where that radio show was from.
And remember,
the Lord loves a working man.
-"Lord loves a working man."
-And son...
...don't never, ever trust Whitey.
"Don't trust Whitey. Lord loves
a working man, don't trust Whitey."
Baby.
Daddy.
Pierre. Come here.
Don't you forget to grow up now.
-Good luck, brother.
-Send me a picture postcard.
Okay, let the boy go.
-Bye.
-We got work to do.
And l hope you find
whatever it is you're looking for.
I will, Ma. I know it's out there.
It's out there, all right. If you catch it,
see a doctor and get rid of it.
-"See a doctor and get rid of it."
-Good luck.
"Lord loves a working man.
Don't trust Whitey.
"See a doctor and get rid of it."
Bye, Grandma!.
I sure do miss Navin.
Is he ever coming back?
Take away his place setting.
It's making us too goddamn sad.
I wonder if he's doing all right?
Navin!. How you doing?
Don't worry about me.
I think l see a car coming.
No, wait. It's a truck!.
Lord...
...take care of our little boy.
-I'm hitchhiking.
-How far you going?
St. Louis. How far are you going?
To the end of this fence.
Okay.
I'm Navin Johnson. What's your name, sir?
-Here we are.
-Okay.
Thanks for the company.
I hope l can repay you someday.
Well, what is it, boy? Are you lost?
Do you want to play? ls it trouble?
Trouble?
Is it an accident?
A drowning?
A fire?
Fire!.
We've got to warn everybody!.
I've heard about dogs like you.
You're going to be famous!.
You're going to get your picture taken,
and they'll put it in the paper!.
This is exciting!.
You saved my life!.
Come on, let's warn everybody!.
Fire!. It's a fire!. Fire!. There's a fire!.
Everybody!. Up!. Wake up!. It's a fire!.
It's a fire!.
This dog, he's saving everybody's life!.
He's unbelievable!. He's some dog!.
He's a lifesaver!.
That's what l'll call him, too!.
Ol' Lifesaver!. That will be your name!.
Folks!. False alarm. There's no fire.
Mister, don't call that dog "Lifesaver."
-No?
-Call him "Shithead."
Good. "Shithead."
It's exciting.
It's just exciting to have
this kind of life on the road.
A guy and his dog.
St. Louis?
No. Navin Johnson.
No, do you want a lift to St. Louis?
-Okay, thanks.
-Hop in.
This'll be fine right here.
Thank you.
-Where you going?
-To the bathroom.
-Got to have a key.
-Can l get one?
My key is for customers who buy gas.
I'm buying gas.
I don't see no car.
I just need enough for my lighter.
Look at this!.
And my wife wanted me to stay home.
Look what l would've missed.
A complete fill-up for a whole lighter?
-It's on that wall.
-Thank you.
-And don't walk away with it.
-I won't.
Pop-top.
Silver Bird, l'm talking to you!.
Listen, you want to be
president of Texaco Oil?
-Sure!.
-Then clean up the sink in there.
Then l'll be president of Texaco Oil?
Whatever happened
to working your way up?
Working for me 10 minutes, and already
he wants to be president. The nerve.
Get to work in there!.
But, sir, l don't work here.
Not even for $1 .10 an hour?
"Dear Folks, l got this greatjob
in a gas station.
"l don't want to say
how much l'm getting...
"...but let'sjust say it's a lot!
"l'm enclosing $2!"
That's a good boy!.
"lt's a lot of fun working,
and Mr. Hartounian is really nice.
"He's teaching me how to be impatient.
"Well, l've got to go now. What do you
think l do, write letters all day?"
-You actually sleep here?
-Yes. Is that okay?
Come with me.
I got a beautiful little place for you.
Put the light on.
You're going to like it here.
Like it? l love it!. This is fabulous!.
You got the toilet here!.
This must be the kitchen. No.
You know what l could do...
...is take this wall
and just turn it this way...
...so l've got a larger living space...
...plus it'll create a flow into
the main living area. It'll be incredible.
No, l'll just elevate this about six inches...
...create the illusion of two rooms,
and yet still have that flow.
Then l can take bookshelves
and put it here.
No, l'll put the books right over here.
That way l can be relaxing over here...
...the customers can use the urinal. I won't
disturb them, they won't disturb me.
Take it easy. It's not here. It's in here.
I couldn't afford this anyway.
Well, this is it.
It's perfect!.
I won't have to change this at all!.
Take a look.
No kitchen, no windows,
no chairs, no tables.
It's a masterpiece of understatement.
I'll put a bed down here, get a bigger bulb.
I'll bring some sheets from the house.
You'll be set for life.
How much is this gonna cost me?
Nothing. When you're rich and famous,
you'll send me a postcard.
A postcard?
Okay!. It's a deal.
It's a deal.
What are those?
Step outside for a second, darling.
Navin, this is my wife Lenore.
Lenore, this is Navin.
Pleased to meet you.
Do you know why a woman
of such pulchritude is married to me?
'Cause l make a comfortable living.
This is the first time
l'm leaving you alone on a Sunday.
If anything should happen to this station,
this woman would leave me like a--
In other words, there would be no more....
-Do you know what l'm talking about?
-Yes, sir. No more....
So remember,
guard this station with your life...
...because my sex life is in your hands.
I can fix those shocks.
No. We just want some gas, muchacho.
Okay. But it's Sunday.
We've got to have a credit card.
And all the cash is locked up?
No, not locked up. We got a lot of cash.
Just that the banks are closed...
...and l'm not allowed to have cash
coming in or out.
I'm alone for the first time.
I don't want anything to happen.
You flash this kind of wad in front
of some people, they'll kill you for it.
So, we've got to have a credit card.
Have we got a credit card in there?
Credit card.
No, thanks. I don't smoke.
-What kind of cigarette is that?
-Joint.
Joint?
They don't make 'em very good.
-MasterCharge do?
-That's fine. We take MasterCharge.
You want a fill-up, Mrs. Nussbaum?
I'm Mr. Nussbaum.
Yeah, that's his wife's card.
-His wife's card?
-Yeah, l'll vouch for him.
Okay, as long as we got a voucher.
Stolen!.
I got it!. Just send a police car over.
Mrs. Nussbaum's credit card!.
I got the guys who stole it.
Hold on, they're calling me!.
I'll be right back!.
-Yes?
-Yeah, throw a couple of tires in the trunk.
Put it on the card. Radials.
-Make them whitewalls.
-Yes, sir, Mr. Nussbaum.
I'm back, only it's worse than l thought.
They're not only sticking us for gas,
but grabbing tires and everything.
They're really socking it to us.
Yeah, it's Hartounian's Gas Station
at the corner--
Hang on a second.
I don't want to get 'em suspicious.
Don't worry, l can keep 'em here.
I saw this trick in a movie.
-Got your tires!.
-Yeah, good.
-Anything else?
-Yeah.
We'll take that money
you got in your pocket.
Sure. I'll just put it on the card.
Guess what!.
You're our eighth customer today!.
You won a free oven mitt!.
I'll go get it for you.
Yeah, l'm back.
Yeah, they're gonna be here for a while.
Don't worry. I've rigged it.
You guys want to stick around
for an oven mitt?
Hang on just a second.
They might not be here
exactly when you get back but...
...it's a blue Chevy two-door.
And it'd be going south on Hertado Street.
No, l can't make out
the license number, but...
...it'd be pulling a small church.
Any blue Chevy pulling a small church
l figure that'd be the one, yeah.
Believe me, l'm not mad at you.
What's the matter with you?
What did l lose, a couple of tires?
Look at the bright side.
We also lost a church.
Mr. Hartounian.
Oh, my God!.
Thank you.
The new phone book's here!.
I wish l could get that excited
about nothing.
Nothing? Are you kidding? Page 73!.
"Johnson, Navin R."
I'm somebody now!. Millions of people
look at this book every day!.
This is the kind of spontaneous publicity...
...your name in print, that makes people!.
I'm in print!.
Things are going to start happening
to me now.
"Johnson, Navin R."
Sounds like a typical bastard.
Die, Navin R. Johnson.
Bastard!.
Random son of a bitch,
typical run-of-the-mill bastard.
-Fill 'er up?
-Fill 'er up and a little bit extra.
-Stan Fox, buying gas.
-Navin R. Johnson selling it, sir!.
Gotcha, you average...
...typical blocking-the-view-
of-a-goddamn-average-victim bastard!.
-Check your oil?
-Check away, Navin R. Johnson.
Oil rag at the ready, sir!.
-Let's check the oil together.
-Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Son-of-a-blocking bastard!.
Looks good to me, sir,
but l'd like your opinion.
Damn these glasses.
It looks good to me, too.
Hurry up. Time's a wasting.
I'm going to the john. Don't forget
to check those tires. Damn these glasses.
Yes, sir!. I damn thee!.
Damn!.
Damn these glasses!.
-I can fix those glasses.
-You can?
Well, here, fix those suckers!.
Shit!.
Guess what? l fixed 'em.
I was back there thinking...
..."What causes glasses to slip on and off?. "
And it's because
when you take them on and off...
...you're putting pressure on the frames.
It causes them to spread.
So l put a little handle
right here in the center...
...that puts the pressure on the bridge.
Just like the tie rods on a '72 Buick.
Plus, l put a little nose brake on here
to prevent slippage. Try it.
Use the handle.
Well, l'll be.
It works.
I make a pretty good living
selling shit like this. I'll tell you what.
If l can develop this gizmo,
l'll split it with you fifty-fifty.
How much for the gas?
l got a load of shit to sell.
-$26.41 .
-Here's a triple dix. Keep the change.
Thanks!.
Dead center!. Say your prayers, half-breed!.
Harry!. Look at this!.
What's the matter with these cans?
Die, milk-face!.
These cans are defective.
They're springing leaks.
Come and look at this.
You better run for cover
or you'll spring a leak.
We don't have defective cans.
We have a defective person!.
He hates these cans.
Stay away from the cans!.
Die, gas pumper!.
I've got to get away from those cans!.
There's cans in there, too!.
Run!. Run!.
More cans!.
Die, you bastard!.
He doesn't want to put holes in cans.
He wants to put holes in you.
What?
Milk-faced bastard!.
Oh, my God!. I'm endangering your life!.
-Cover me!.
-You're covered.
Suck my toes!.
You stay here!. I'll distract him!.
Shithead!. Come on!.
Come on, boy!. Good boy!.
"Carnival personnel only." Damn!.
Shithead, come on!.
You're not carnival personnel!.
He's not carnival personnel!.
Okay, move it out!.
"So, Mom, when l told Mr. Hartounian
l'd come back, he said:
"'Don't be a putz.
"'See the world. Me you've seen already.'
"l took his advice and got a job with
SJM Fiesta Shows as a weight guesser.
"Frosty, my boss, told me
there's a big future in weight guessing.
"Enclosed is $4.75 for my loving family.
"P.S. Is grandma still farting?"
For $1, l'll guess your weight,
your height or your sex.
The most exciting thing on the midway.
Imagine the thrill of getting
your weight guessed by a professional.
You can blow up your cheeks,
you can stick out your chest...
...but you're not going to fool the guesser!.
How 'bout you, sir? Step right up!.
Honey, let's see how good this guy is.
Now, what do l win?
Anything in this general area right in here.
Anything below the stereo and
on this side of the bicentennial glasses.
Anything between the ashtrays
and the thimble.
Anything in this three inches
right in here, in this area.
That includes the Chiclets,
but not the erasers.
No, sir!. Come on, honey.
He thought he had himself a rube.
Frosty, l'm no good at this.
Come on. You're doing fine.
I've already given away eight pencils,
two hula dolls and an ashtray...
...and l've only taken in $15.
Navin, you have taken in $15...
...and given away 50 cents worth of crap!.
Which gives us a net profit of $14.50.
It's a profit deal.
Takes the pressure off.
Get your weight guessed right here!.
Only a buck!.
Actual weight guessing!. Take a chance,
win some crap. Step right up--
Ladies and gentlemen...
...l draw your attention now
to the left side ofthe midway.
Presenting the amazing Patti Bernstein...
...doing her special ride...
...through the Flaming Wall of Death!
Want to guess my weight, Greenie?
I saw you last night. You were great.
Yeah, right. Turn around.
What?
Turn around.
Go like this.
You're okay.
Give me a bite of that corn dog.
What about germs?
Put a rubber on it.
Get on.
Don't you wear him out!.
He's got to work tonight.
What a great place!.
You know, you can tell so much
about a person from the way they live.
Just looking around here, l can tell...
...you're a genuinely dirty person.
What do l do with this?
You keep it there.
Where's your garbage?
There.
-Do you know what l'd like to do?
-What?
Guess your weight.
That would be interesting for me.
No one has tried to guess my weight.
-I guess their weight so it would be sort--
-Put your arms up.
This will give me
a whole different perspective on this.
You're really trying to be accurate.
Is it getting hot in here?
Wait a minute!.
What's happening to my special purpose?
What's your special purpose?
When l was a kid, my mom told me
that was my special purpose...
...and someday l'd find out
what that special purpose was!.
Today's the day!.
This is like a ride!.
"My dear family, guess what?
"Today l found out
what my special purpose is for.
"Gosh, what a great time l had.
"l wish the whole family
could have been here with me.
"Maybe some other time...
"...as l intend to do this a lot...
"...every chance l get.
"l think next week
l'll be able to send more money...
"...as l may have extra work.
"My friend Patti promised me a blow job.
"Your loving son, Navin."
And he's got the kisses here.
-That Patti must be a sweet girl.
-God bless her.
Do you think we'll get to know each other
well enough to kiss?
We don't have to. You're my man.
It's like we're married. Look at my ass.
You have my last name tattooed
right there under the J's.
First l get my name in the phone book,
and now l'm on your ass.
You know, l'll bet more people
see that than the phone book.
End of the line.
This is Engineer Fred.
Come back and visit me again.
Billy!.
Have you seen a 5-year-old boy, blond hair,
wearing a T-shirt that says "bullshit" on it?
No, there was just one kid had a T-shirt
that said "life sucks" on it.
We got off the Round-Up,
and he said he wanted to go on the train.
There he is!. Billy!.
-Come back here!.
-Get off the train.
Pull that lever!. Pull the lever!.
Here, hold that!. And these!.
Take my keys. And hold my wallet. Okay.
Don't touch the Johnson bar,
you'll explode the fuel casing!.
And if the Wolfe and Smith
indicator gets above 160...
-...turn that off there.
-I can't take you here anymore.
There's a screwdriver.
Put it in, turn it one quarter.
Listen, we're going into a tunnel.
Don't stand up.
The clearance is only 4 foot--
-No.
-I'm okay.
I was protected by the bill
of my Engineer Fred cap.
Thanks for pulling my cap down.
You scared me half to death.
Thank you so much.
It would've been so embarrassing
to go home without Billy.
Here's your gloves
and your oil can and your wallet.
And this fell out.
Those guys!.
Listen, what you did just now
was very brave.
Is there some way l could repay you?
Repay me?
I could never accept anything from you
for saving your child.
He's not my child.
I'm just baby-sitting for a friend.
-Would it be too much if l asked for a kiss?
-No.
He's a real little dickens.
Thank you.
Miss?
I was just standing here right now,
and l was...
...wondering, if you weren't
doing anything tomorrow...
...maybe you might want to go out with....
What?
I thought maybe you might
want to go out with me.
Are you trying to ask me for a date?
Once for no, twice for yes.
Okay.
You're so cute.
How about 3:30 tomorrow
at the Round-Up?
Okay.
Do you have any boyfriends?
Not really.
Are they crazy? lf l was a fella,
l'd be around all the time.
Well, see if you can work it out.
We have a date tomorrow.
What's your name?
Marie.
What's yours?
I'll tell you tomorrow. It'll give us
something interesting to talk about.
Hi!.
What's up, hubby?
I got these for you.
Thanks.
Navin, you know the other day
when l showed you the tattoo?
Yeah.
Well, l forgot to tell you something.
-Really? What?
-This.
That's what's going to happen to you if
l ever catch you looking at another broad.
I'm glad you told me.
And remember, l did this without anger.
And l stayed away from your crotch.
Bye, sweetie.
-Hi!.
-What happened?
It was unbelievable.
These guys jumped me.
They tried to get these flowers.
I got 'em for you.
It's kind of a traditional date deal.
Yeah, l've heard of that. What were they?
Couple of dozen roses.
Look like daisy stems.
What? That guy gypped me.
Put daisy stems on my roses.
Look, these hoodlums are dangerous.
I think we ought to get out of here
before she sees us.
-"She"?
-What?
-You said "she."
-No!.
I always call a gang "she."
It's like when you call a boat "she"
or a hurricane "she."
Or a girl?
You can call a girl "she." That's just one
of the many things you can call "she."
Why are you smiling?
You're the fiirst person
l've ever had at my place.
Do you live here?
It's nice.
Did you decorate it?
I got this from the old Cup O' Pizza place
before they tore it down.
That was really good pizza.
This is the best pizza in a cup ever.
This guy's unbelievable. He ran the old
Cup O' Pizza guy out of business.
People come from all over to get this.
You know, you have beautiful skin.
May l?
So smooth and flexible.
I take after my mother's side of the family.
It's amazing the way it
just snaps back like that. Amazing.
-Are you a model?
-No.
I'm a cosmetologist.
Really? A cosmetologist?
That's unbelievable.
That's impressive.
It must be tough
to handle the weightlessness.
Can l ask you a personal question?
What is it?
Now be totally honest.
You do have a boyfriend, don't you?
Kind of.
I know this is our first date, but...
...do you think the next time
you make love to your boyfriend...
...you could think of me?
-I haven't made love to him yet.
-That's too bad.
Do you think it's possible that...
...someday...
...you could make love with me
and think of him?
Who knows?
Maybe you and he can make love
and you could think of me.
I'd just be happy to be in there somewhere.
Do you have a girlfriend?
-Does it matter?
-I'd like to think you were available.
I'm available.
Did you forget about my ass?
No, l've been thinking about it.
She tattooed my name on her ass.
Not just my name. A lot of names!.
And funny things, too. She's got one
up here that says "Slippery when wet."
-How do you know that?
-What is she, some great piece of ass?
She's no great piece of ass!.
I mean, wait a minute.
We're all adults here.
Let's reason this out.
Marie's the type of person that if you got--
If this gash doesn't get out of here...
...l am gonna drive this bike up her butt!.
While Patti tends to be more direct.
As for you, farm boy....
We're married!.
And as for you, kewpie doll--
You protected me.
You must really like me.