Behold the handmaiden
of the Lord,
may you be done unto me
according to your word.
The savior has been born.
This is my world!
I will not share it with an infant!
There is no room for two kings here!
Like a newborn scorpion under foot!
Kill them all!
Kill! Kill them all!
The slaughter of the innocents
was in vain.
In the village of Nazareth,
the child Jesus, grew to manhood.
In Galilee, John the Baptist,
preached against the sinns sins
of Herod's successor.
I'm not afraid of your power
on earth, Herod Antipas!
If I do not warn you,
you will die in sin.
And the Lord will ask me
to account for your life!
Arrest the prophet.
I demand that you arrest him!
Demand?
That's a strong word, my heart.
You must remember...
...John is right.
By the laws of Moses,
we have sinned.
I am the voice of one
crying in the wilderness,
make straight
the way of the Lord.
Though the dust will returneth
to the earth as it must,
the spirit returneth unto God, David.
Mary, you'll be left alone.
They will run the shop.
Jesus, we have always known.
It was not for us
that Jesus came to earth.
If only I could've stayed
a little longer.
God's will be done.
Peace, Joseph.
To thine end, I command my spirit.
Out of my distress,
I cried to the Lord and He answered me.
I cried and He heard my voice.
I went down into the cities
underneath the earth,
to the peoples of the past,
but He lifted my life from the grave.
Hear, O Israel, the Lord thy God,
the Lord is one.
Hear, O Israel, the Lord, our God,
You are born into a new light
through your repentance...
...and the Lord forwards
His blessings on you!
The Lord rejoices in repented hearts.
Go in peace.
He will forgive you,
if you truly mean it in your heart.
Open up your eyes,
be ready for the coming of the kingdom.
Let your heart now be cleansed.
Forgive me, I have sinned.
Help me to be strong.
Be strong.
It is I who need baptism from you...
...and yet you come to me.
Let it be so.
We must fulfill all righteousness.
Lord, Eternal Father,
I hear your voice.
"This is my beloved Son,
in whom I am well pleased."
You are born into a new life,
true to your repentance,
and the Lord pours His blessings on you.
The Lord rejoices in repented hearts.
This water cleanses you.
Andrew. Philip.
Behold, the lamb of God,
who takes unto Himself
the sins of the world.
It is Him you must follow now, not me.
He must increase as I must decrease.
He has come to take us,
come with us please!
My time is over.
Mary! Mary!
- Mary! Mary! Mary!
- Mary!
Mary, your son is back!
He's at the synagogue.
He went straight
to the synagogue! I saw him!
And now our reading from the prophets.
The prophet Isaiah.
Now, who is... who is our reader?
It is my turn today, Rabbi.
Isn't that Joseph's son?
- Yes, Joseph the carpenter.
- The carpenter, God rest his soul.
The spirit of the Lord is upon me,
because He hath anointed me to give
good tidings to the poor.
He has sent me to heal
the broken hearted,
to preach deliverance to the captives,
to give sight to the blind,
and to set at liberty
them that are bruised.
To proclaim the acceptable
year of the Lord.
- Amen.
Today, in your hearing,
the scriptures are fulfilled.
The scriptures are fulfilled?
- Did he say fulfilled?
- How can he dare to say such a thing?
What do you mean?
The prophecy you have read can only
be fulfilled by the coming of the Messiah.
- Yes, he's right.
- By the coming of the kingdom of God.
The kingdom of God comes not
in a way foreseen by men.
Repent and believe the good news.
The kingdom of heaven, behold,
is suddenly upon you.
What?
Rabbi, take the scriptures
away from him!
He is a blasphemer!
He shouldn't touch them
with his unclean hands!
I've heard things about you.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
A prophet is never accepted
in his own country!
Who do you think you are?
John the Prophet?
You should be thrown
out of this holy place!
Blessed is he who is not ashamed of me!
- Take this man out of here!
- Don't let him touch the holy scriptures!
Today, in our hearing,
the scriptures are fulfilled.
What... What's happened
inside the synagogue?
Let's go see!
Rabbi! You must stop them!
You cannot let this happen!
Rabbi! They don't understand
who this man is! Andrew!
Go away, go away!
Never come back to Nazareth!
- Don't let him go!
- Blasphemer!
Stone him to death!
Blasphemer!
That's what he deserves!
Don't let him go!
Master! Master!
Master!
We were told to make
ourselves known to you.
I am Andrew of Capernaum,
a fisherman by trade,
but your follower now,
if you'll take me.
This is Philip.
We were sent by John
the prophet, the Baptist.
He has just been imprisoned
by King Herod Antipas.
Andrew.
Philip.
Come with me.
Come on!
- Tell me, when was John arrested?
- As soon as he returned to Galilee.
He had to return. Too many people
were waiting for him...
There it is. The sea of Galilee
and Capernaum, where I was born.
It's a town of fishermen, but it also has
the greatest synagogue in Israel.
You can stay at my brother's house.
He's a good man, Simon Peter.
The commandments God gave
to Moses so long ago...
...must not remain dead stone
for the reverence of unthinking minds.
Dead stone? The tablets
of the law, dead stone?
- What do you mean, Rabbi?
- Stone is what the law is written on...
...but the law itself is alive!
And living things
are constantly changing.
But the law is eternal.
- You cannot change law of Moses.
- That's right, the law is here.
The man is made
of flesh and blood, and he changes.
Doesn't he remain the same man?
God wants to write
the law on your hearts.
Rabbi, you said you have come
here to give us the good news.
Is this it the good news?
That the law is living like a man?
The good news I bring you is this:
Your captivity is over.
But what does that mean,
our captivity is over? What captivity?
Captivity in sin!
God fulfills the promise
He made to our people Israel,
and reconciles Himself to man.
God is coming to you.
To all of you,
even the most wretched.
Do not shut the door in His face.
Rabbi! The demon has always
tried to throw him...
...into fire and into water
to destroy him!
If you can do anything,
have mercy, help my poor faith!
Satan!
Leave him!
My son! My son!
Praise be the Lord!
Yes, we're all fishermen in our family.
Andrew here knows us well,
but I was sent off to learn.
All you were fit for, perhaps.
And what have you learned?
Well, hat two and two
make four, sometimes.
But most people seem
to be here to be pushed about,
that getting on is a fine thing,
that birth is the beginning of death.
But there must be something more
for man between birth and death.
Today, when I heard you preaching,
I began to understand, and it gave me hope.
Through your words,
the old scriptures seems to become alive!
That's all we want.
We want the Lord to be alive,
written in our hearts,
not carved in stone.
What is your name?
John, son of Zebedee.
John...
...stay with us.
Back, back! This way, you idiots!
That's my brother now, Simon Peter.
And there's my brother, James.
He's shouting again, angry as usual.
If anyone's drunk, it's you!
He doesn't mean it. He's a good man.
- What's the matter, brother? Poor catch?
- Poor catch? Nothing!
The only things we catch
these days are Roman taxes!
And while we are out sweating,
working our hands raw on the nets,
the stinking tax gatherers
take half and give it to the Romans!
Bloodsuckers!
Go brother. Go and tell that leach,
that two-face
tax collector of ours, Matthew,
that if he wants more money out of me,
to put some fish in the lake.
Simon, this is the man
I told you about.
The man John spoke of.
John the Baptist.
What? Another holy man?
Are you another of those
that tell us to be patient,
and promise us
better times will be ahead?
What about now?
What about our children?
Who will fill their bellies?
A lot of talk these days
while we all starve!
Find a holy man who can put an end to that.
Then maybe I'll listen.
Go out again.
I shall come with you.
We've just pulled in!
Get the nets off the boat!
Please Simon, do as he says.
Why do you always listen to these people.
Who knows the lake better than I?
Please!
What are you staring at?
Come. You can preach to the fish.
Cast off! We're going out again.
We've been out all day
and we caught nothing!
He send us out again
and we catch all these fish!
It's a miracle!
It's not a miracle!
Only God can work miracles.
They speak these profanities,
they believe it!
We must go and speak to him!
My house cannot hold
anymore people!
Please! Please! Please!
Help me out! I can't get up!
It was amazing!
I've been fishing for four years,
I've never seen a catch so big.
More.
So, there were miracles were they?
And a big catch inspired by a prophet,
what's his name, Jesus? Get out!
He's staying with Simon Peter.
You know him? The fisherman?
Yes. He owes me back taxes,
doesn't he?
Move!
Well, well, well...
Well, if there's been a big catch,
he can pay, can't he?
The kingdom of heaven is like
a treasure hidden in a field.
A man finds it, and in his joy spends
everything he has to buy that field.
It's like a merchant
in search of fine pearls.
He finds one pearl of great value,
and sells everything to have that pearl.
You, you're all fisherman.
Well, the kingdom of heaven is like a net.
A great net thrown into the sea.
Suddenly it is filled!
It's almost bursting!
You have to call to the other
boats to come and help!
Everybody is working
together, happy, excited!
It's a time for joy.
For rejoicing in what God
has freely given.
But one day...
...God will ask you to account
for the gift he has given.
Be prepared.
The kingdom of heaven is at hand.
Rabbi. You say the kingdom
of heaven is at hand,
but when exactly will it come?
When you see the clouds
moving from the East,
you say the rain
is coming, and so it is.
When the desert wind blows,
you say it will be hot, and it is.
All of you can read the signs
of the earth and the sky.
How is it you can't read
the signs of the times?
The kingdom of heaven is here, now.
What's he doing here?
That's Matthew,
the tax collector! Get him out!
- Peter, your friend Matthew is here!
- Get out!
- Bloodsucking tax collector!
- There's no place for you here!
Out of my house! You scum! Filth!
- No Simon, don't! Simon, look!
- I will not have it defiled by you!
I hear you've had a big catch Simon!
We'll talk about it later, shall we?
But what about this friend of yours?
This new preacher
or teacher or whatever he is.
Am I not allowed to speak with him?
Not in my house!
You seem to be most unwelcome here.
I don't know your name,
but I know what you do.
Levi, or Matthew,
I'm known by both names.
And by others.
I see you and I must meet in a place
where both of us are welcome.
Is your own house far?
Why do you ask?
I should like to have
supper with you tonight.
You would enter
the house of a sinner?
I would enter any house
where I am welcome.
Wait! What are you doing?
Be careful, this is my property!
Help me. I've been this way
for 20 years.
It is the curse of God, punishment
for my sins and for my parents' sins.
Your sins are forgiven you.
Rabbi, you must not speak so!
That's blasphemy.
Only God can forgive sins.
Which of these is easier,
to say your sins are forgiven you,
or rise up and walk home?
The Son of Man
has the power to forgive sins.
Rise and walk home.
He doesn't seem to realize the scandal
it would cause! Peter, you tell him!
I've told him.
Well, tell him again!
The whole place is talking about it!
- Meeting some Pharisees, I suppose.
- Well, they know the law!
Tax collectors cannot even
enter the synagogue,
and anyone who associates
with them is as defiled as they are.
- Yes, according to the Pharisees!
- But yes.
Well, that's their argument.
- Peter, tell him again.
- I've told him! What do you want from me?
I said Matthew is my
bloodsucking enemy. I hate Matthew!
But all Jesus would say was,
"Well, why don't you join us as well?"
Andrew...
Andrew, I'm not like you.
I'm not a follower
of priests and prophets.
I'm a fisherman.
I have my family to think of.
You followed the Baptist,
now follow this one.
- Peter!
- Just leave me alone!
Why did you bring him here to me?
This is my life.
My nets.
My boat.
Go on! Follow him...
...but leave me!
Come on. You can't talk to him
when he's like this.
Come on, Philip.
This is where I belong.
Master!
It's a scandal for you
to eat with these people!
Don't you know who they are?
We've lived our lives honorably.
Made sacrifices to keep the law.
They are thieves, whores, usurers.
Violent and godless people.
And now you sit
and eat with such people,
who spend their lives
in orgies and perversions!
I've not come to call the virtuous
to repentance, but the sinners,
and they might enter the kingdom
of heaven even before you.
Listen, Master! If you go and eat with
these people they will contaminate you.
The whole town will abandon you!
James, the heart of the Lord is mercy.
He's here.
Quiet!
Peace be with you.
Thank you...
...coming to my house.
Rabbi, you are welcome.
Welcome Rabbi.
- Move!
- No, no, no, don't move. I'll sit there.
Wine.
This is my brother James.
He's in the same business as I am.
I drink to you in the name of all here.
Rabbi, we want to hear your words.
- Please speak to us!
- Yes!
No, no, no, no, no!
Let's eat first!
No! Let him decide.
No, no.
I'd like to tell you a story.
Sit down! Sit down!
A certain man had two sons.
And one day the younger
of these sons said to his father,
"Give me my share of your estate now."
So his father divided his wealth
between his two sons.
And a few days later,
this younger son
set off for a distant land,
and there he squandered
all the money he had on riotous living.
Now, not long after this,
a great famine swept over the land,
and the boy began to starve.
He persuaded a farmer
to hire him to feed his pigs,
but he was so hungry that even
the husks he was feeding the swine...
...began to look good to him.
And still, nobody gave him anything.
Finally, the boy came to his senses.
"At home...
...even my father's servants
have enough food, and to spare.
And here I am starving to death.
I will go home, and ask my father
to hire me as one of his servants."
And so, he set off.
Now he was still some
distance from his home...
...when his father saw him coming,
and he was so filled with compassion,
that he ran towards his son
and embraced him and kissed him.
The boy said, "Father! I have sinned
against Heaven and you.
I am not worthy
to be called your son."
But his father called
for the servants and said,
"Bring me the finest robe
in the house and put it on him.
Put rings on his hands
and shoes on his feet!
Kill the fatted calf,
we must celebrate with a feast.
My son was dead...
...and is alive again!"
Now, the older brother
at this time...
...was working in the fields,
and as he came back to the house,
he heard the noise of music and dancing.
He called for one of the servants
and asked what was happening,
and he was told.
At this, the older brother
became very angry,
and he refused to go into the house.
The father came out, tried to plead
with him, but he wouldn't listen.
"I have worked for you
all this time, all these years,
and never once have I disobeyed you!
And in all that time, you've never even
give me so much as a goat...
...so that I could have
a feast with my friends.
My younger brother comes back,
having spent all your money on harlots,
and for him you kill the fatted calf!"
"Please," said the father.
"Please, try to understand.
You are always with me,
everything I have is yours.
But it is right to celebrate.
Your brother was dead...
...and is alive again.
He was lost, and is found."
Forgive me master.
I am...
I'm just a stupid man.
Free the man! He is innocent!
He's a man of God!
Free John the Prophet!
Free the man!
John!
John?
What is it you want from me?
Is it just a matter of my
violating the marriage vows?
Is that it?
Because I don't mind
to repent that, John.
Will that satisfy you?
You think it makes me happy
to see you rotting away...
...in the dark down there with
a howling gang outside the walls?
Why don't you listen to reason?
There's work for you here
in this wretched kingdom.
If it's power you want,
you can have power.
Power to build, not to break.
My task has been to prepare the way
for the one who shall wear the crown.
Who is this man? This prophet from Galilee?
Is he the one I ought to be talking to?
Do not fear the toppling
of your throne.
Before kingdoms change...
...men must change.
Ah, you say that, yes,
but I've been listening
to those fools outside.
What leaders intend
and what their followers are after...
...are not one and the same thing.
That crowd of yours needs
someone to control it.
John, if I set you free,
what would you do with your freedom?
I would follow the one
whose way I have prepared,
just like many others
who already follow Him.
But you will not set me free.
Herod...
...I was wrong.
Yes...
The curse of God is upon us.
Release John.
Yes, send him away. Send him away.
Send him to Egypt. You're right.
What harm can
he do us there, after all.
Yes, tomorrow.
Yes, tomorrow on your birthday.
What better present could you give
to yourself and your people?
A great gesture of clemency.
I see! I see!
Oh, what a remarkable woman you are!
How quickly your heart changes!
Once he was free,
and had gone to Egypt,
he just might meet with
some unfortunate accident.
What imagination, my king.
How fast your thoughts travel.
Imagination? You know
I can always read your mind.
Don't forget I can read
your mind too, my lord.
Herod...
...what present shall
I give you on your birthday?
What do you think I would like most?
Salome.
You see, I can read your mind.
- Welcome to our shores!
- Come save us!
Come save us!
Take her away. Back to Capernaum.
Do no think I have come
to bring peace on earth.
I've come not to bring peace...
...but a sword.
I have come to sow discord
between a man and his father,
between a daughter and her mother.
A man's enemies...
...will be members of his own family.
You may say, "We have left our belongings
to become your followers."
I tell you this:
Anyone who has left home,
or father, mother, wife,
children, land,
for the kingdom of God...
...shall be rewarded
a hundred times over... on earth,
and inherit
the kingdom of God.
Whoever wants
to save his life will lose it,
but if a man will lose
his life for my sake...
...and for the gospel
I bring you, he will save it.
For many that are first will be last,
and the last first.
So do not store up
for yourselves treasures on earth,
where it grows rusty and moth-eaten
and thieves break in to steal it.
Store up treasure in Heaven,
for where your treasure is,
there will your heart be also.
My name is Jairus. I am one
of the elders of the synagogue here.
My little daughter is dying.
I beg you, come and lay your hands
on her so that she may be cured and live.
Take me to her.
You're daughter is dead.
Do not weep.
The child is not dead.
Only sleeping.
Who are you to come
here with your jokes?
We've seen that
she's dead, you haven't!
Peace Thomas, peace.
Talitha kumi.
Rise, little girl.
Give her something to eat.
She's alive! She's alive! She's alive!
Rabbi, I want to apologize.
I didn't know who you were.
But I thought the child was dead.
Well, she was dead!
I saw her with my own eyes.
Can't you believe
without seeing, Thomas?
Sometimes I do.
Sometimes I think
I know what I believe, but...
...something happens,
my mind gets blurred and...
...I don't know.
To doubt so much,
you must want to be certain.
I do!
Then follow me.
You mean, give up my work and...
Yes.
Jairus, will you give me your servant
to be one of my disciples?
With gladness, master.
I am happy for him.
Do you have doubts
about following me, Thomas?
No.
I don't believe I have.
Women.
I ask you, why would they listen?
I told my wife
I won't be away for long.
In any case, the fishing
is hopeless why not go away.
I told her. I said,
I'll come back in the spring.
Don't lie to her, and to yourself.
Lie?
Yes. You know very well...
...you'll never go back.
I will.
No you won't.
Never.
You'll never fish again.
You'll never get drunk again.
And you'll never go back
to Capernaum again.
None of us will.
We'll never be the same.
And neither will the lives
of everyone in the whole world.
We know why, Simon.
We are the first to know.
The ruthless shall be no more!
The arrogant shall cease to be!
Remember the words
of the scriptures!
Vanity of vanities. All is vanity!
Woe unto them that seek to do evil!
Woe unto them that call
evil good, and good evil.
Woe unto them that
are wise in their own eyes!
Have you not known?
Have you not heard?
Hath it not been told you
from the beginning?
Have you not understood from
the foundations of the earth?
Music! Music! Music!
Go to him. Go. Remember.
Dance, Salome.
Dance.
When I've danced,
what will you give me?
Whatever thou shall ask of me,
I will give to thee,
unto the half of my kingdom.
My friends!
The princess is going to dance.
Was that anything?
Yes.
Anything.
I want the head of the Baptist.
Oh... no!
You promised.
Yes, you promised!
You promised, yes!
You swore, my Lord...
...before all your guests.
Shall it be said that king Herod
does not keep his promises?
King Herod, you said anything.
Yes, you promised! Yes, you promised!
A king will rule
in righteousness,
and princes
will rule in justice,
and the eyes of those that
will not see will not be closed,
and their works are
in the dark and they say,
"Who seeth us?
Who knoweth us?"
Oh, woe unto them!
Woe unto them!
His head, sheared off
like a rabbit's,
and given as a present
to the dancing girl.
Only by killing him could Herod
hope to silence his voice,
but I can still hear him.
We must avenge him.
Revenge, bad politics my friend.
Suppose we kill Herod,
who will replace him?
I'll tell you, another servant of Tiberius,
a Roman procurate like Pontius Pilate.
So what should we do then? Submit?
Or become soldiers of Rome like
the Syrians or the Greeks?
No, the Romans must know
they can never rule Galilee with ease.
Oh, I know but for the present
we strike in the dark.
The time will come when God
shall send us our leader.
Then we shall make open war.
You mean a real war?
The people of Israel, alone,
against the Roman empire?
Brothers, this is Judas Iscariot.
I've asked him to talk to you.
You should here what he has
to say about Jesus of Nazareth.
Jesus of Nazareth?
Do you know him?
Oh, I've heard him preach many times,
and I have seen
the kind of power that he has.
Is he the man to place our hopes on?
Why do you ask me this question?
John answered it.
Remember what the Baptist said?
I bear witness that this is the man.
Tell all my friends
and disciples to follow him,
and proclaim in His name
the kingdom of heaven.
We know that, we know that.
But could he be the one, priest and king,
who will lead our people Israel?
Could he be the Messiah
promised by our Lord?
I believe that if one day the people
of Israel do find a Messiah...
...oh, yes, it will be him.
But, no, I beg of you,
let him fulfill his mission.
That is my advice.
I intend to follow him,
and I hope, if he will accept me,
become a disciple.
Very well, Judas.
Will you keep in touch with us?
If you wish.
Peace be on you, John.
Though your blood cries out for revenge,
may your soul find rest
in the glory of the righteous.
May peace be with you John.
Eternal peace, John.
Eternal peace on your soul, John.
May your soul find eternal peace.
We shall not forget you, John.
Peace be on you, John.
You stupid idiots! Go on, go away!
You mind your mother's business
crazy... and your sister's!
Get out of here! Get out!
- Get away! Get out of here.
- Can't I come in for a minute?
Can I come in for a minute, too?
Come.
You pigs! Don't you come
near me anymore! I'll kill you!
What is it? What's going on?
Ask your pigs over there,
those big, brave sons of yours.
Amon!
There's no peace in this neighborhood
since you came here. Noise and filth.
The curse of God is on you.
Don't worry, Mary.
They're only boys' games.
Ah, boys, they would only burn
my house down. The fathers...
...they're all against me.
Not all, Mary. There's a friend
of yours in town today.
- I have no friends.
- Oh, yes, you have!
Jesus, the prophet!
Friend of our God, forgiver of sins.
Hey, according to him,
the sins of the flesh are nothing
compared to the sins of the soul.
A man will always forgive a man,
but a woman's sin, that's another story.
For most people, but not for him.
I've never seen anybody like him.
Have you seen him often?
If you go around on business like me,
you can't help seeing him.
Turn a corner, cross a square,
go into a camp, there he is!
Come on.
He might be here for another year.
I'm sure you'll come across him.
Oh, I sleep during
the daytime, don't I?
Sorry, I forgot.
Well, a big crowd
is following him in everywhere.
Sometimes so big
he has to sleep in the field.
He thinks nothing of eating
and drinking with thieves and whores.
Any scum of the earth
is good enough for him, eh?
One of his disciples,
as they call themselves, was a...
...a tax collector, devious one.
But this Jesus,
well, he says it's not the righteous
that need him, it's the sinners.
So you see, you have got a friend.
- What about next week?
- Go on.
Look!
There's Joseph of Arimathea.
One of the leading Pharisees in Jerusalem.
Which of you, for all his worrying,
can add one day to his life,
one inch to his stature.
So don't concern yourselves
so much with the means of life,
what you shall eat and drink,
or with your bodies
and how they should be clothed.
Life is more than clothing.
Consider the birds of the air,
they do not sow, or reap,
or gather into bonds,
but our Heavenly Father feeds them.
Will He all the more feed you?
Are you not worth more than they?
Consider the lilies of the field.
They do not spin,
they do not weave,
but not even Solomon, in all his glory,
was so arrayed as one of these.
Now if God so clothe
the grass of the field,
which is here today and tomorrow
thrown into the fire,
will he not
all the more clothe you...
...who have so little faith?
Therefore do not ask,
"What should we eat?
What should we drink?
How should we dress ourselves?"
It is only the faithless
who set their hearts on these things.
You must first seek the kingdom
of God and His righteousness,
and everything will be
added freely unto to you.
So do not be anxious about tomorrow.
Tomorrow will be anxious for itself.
Let the day's own trouble
be sufficient for the day.
Extraordinary.
But isn't that taking it too far?
Well, surely our religion
isn't opposed to honest hard work.
Imagine what he says has been said
by the prophets, but not like this.
I agree with you.
But we can't be sure until
we meet with him face to face.
Why not invite him to eat with us?
- Would he come?
- I'm sure he would.
Such a man must be willing
to discuss his ideas with...
...people who are open-minded.
Good master!
Please, tell me, master,
what must I do to have eternal life?
Go and sell all you have
and give it to the poor,
and you shall have treasure in Heaven.
Then, come and follow me.
Sell Everything? Everything I own?
Everything my father slaved for?
Everything. You cannot serve
two masters, God and money.
You see...
...it is easier for a camel
to go through the eye of a needle,
than for a rich man
to enter the Kingdom of God.
Master, may I speak with you?
What is your name, my son?
My name is Judas Iscariot.
Or call me a scholar.
The State finds use for...
...I read and write...
Hebrew, Greek, Latin. I...
I translate documents.
This has become
a country of many tongues.
Now I have never beaten copper,
nor carved wood nor caught
fish as your men have, but...
...I know your men.
My father was
a prosperous builder who said,
"My son must never have calluses
on his hands, nor brick dust in his hair.
My money must make
my son into a scholar."
Well, behold, a scholar
who wishes to serve you.
But do you need a man like me?
The tree is known by it's fruit.
Come...
...stay with us.
And now some scenes
from Jesus of Nazareth Part III...
...which shall be presented
tomorrow night.
I can see! I can see!
Jesus of Nazareth, he cured the blind man!
Jesus of Nazareth...
Your faith has saved you.
Go, and sin no more.
But the Romans have butchered
hundreds of innocent people,
young people, old people,
lives ended without mercy,
without trial.
We must meet
the sword with the sword!
All who take up the sword
shall perish by the sword!
Jerusalem, the faithful city,
she that was full of justice,
has become a harlot!