- Da, da, da, ♪ da, da, da-ba-da,
da, da ♪ ba-let's go! Ba ♪
♪ we'll be there ♪
♪ a wink and a smile
and a great old time ♪
♪ yeah, we'll be there ♪
♪ wherever we are,
there's fun to be found ♪
♪ we'll be there
when you turn that corner ♪
♪ when you jump out the bush ♪
♪ with a big bear smile ♪
♪ we'll be there ♪
Okay, I need two men
on that aerial ladder.
Get the life net,
in case the animal falls.
Hey, we almost there?
Says that it's right here.
Wup, wup, we passed it.
Back up, back up.
There it is.
I see it!
Welcome to purrito, gentlemen.
What can I get for you today?
- Um, I'll have the veggie tacos,
please, and some extra salsa.
Okay.
- Ice bear
will have more free chips.
And what about you, sir?
-What can you tell me about
this?! ♪
- Ah, yes, our famous
burrito challenge.
Succeed in eating our whole
array of burritos in one hour,
and you'll get your photo
up on our wall.
It can be pretty hard, though.
I'd be lying if I told you
there weren't gonna be
tears involved.
So, I understand if you
don't want to do it anymore.
Oh, that's cute.
Oh, I'll do your
precious challenge.
And I'll do it in half an hour.
-Ice bear wants separate checks.
Okay. Ready... Start!
First up,
the fajita steak burrito.
Omm!
Another!
-Jalapeño chicken burrito.
Omm!
-Baja Halibut burrito.
Avocado delight. Pork wasabi.
Veggie party. Bacon and egg.
Crazy meat.
Cilantro overload.
Omm! Finished!
Finished!
Finished.
Wow. 15 minutes.
That's a new record!
But there's still
one last burrito.
Are you sure you want to do...
That one?
We have no choice.
Do it.
Tortilla warmers!
Faster!
Get 'em off the stove!
We need them over here,
- laid out.
- Cilantro, hot sauce.
Okay, spread 'em
with sour cream.
-Tortillas! Tortillas!
Spread them all the way.
We want every corner covered.
- Meat, meat!
Tortillas, then meat!
Tortillas!
Tortillas! Tortillas!
This contest is a breeze!
What's one more burrito
gonna do?
Uh, grizz.
Hmm?
Oooooh!
Gimme, gimme, gimme.
Ooh-eh.
Mmm.
Um... You doing okay
there, grizz?
Yeah, it's just this burrito,
it's... So comforting.
Nice and warm.
Safe.
Safe burrito.
-Well? Eat it.
N-no!
It's too perfect to eat!
I will eat it!
Stay away!
You stay away from burrito.
Let's get outta here, guys.
-Cash only.
Uh... Are we really
gonna keep that thing?
Of course, silly.
What else would we do with
such a magnificent burrito?
Uh... Not keep it?
Hey, a theater!
We should watch a movie.
Come on, come on, come on.
It's your turn to pay, panda.
Ahem, three ticke...
Hello! Can you hear me?
- Yes.
Great! Three tickets,
please.
-You got four people there.
Uh, no, we have three.
- You'll have to pay
for that thing, as well.
Uh, there must be
a misunderstanding here.
You see, that's just a burrito.
It can't watch movies.
Hey, watch what you say, man.
Burrito's gonna enjoy
this movie.
Don't listen
to that silly panda.
It's okay.
Um, any discounts
for the burrito?
Fine.
♪ Whoo-hoo! All right! ♪
- what the...?
♪ I think we gon' be chillin' ♪
♪ whoo-hoo! All right! ♪
♪ We took a tour
down to market street ♪
♪ ♪
♪ then rode a cable car
and got a receipt ♪
♪ -so, we're sitting
outside of a studio and then,
somebody comes to me
and asks me for a quarter
and I looked at burrito.
♪ I said right on, my brother ♪
♪ have a nice day ♪
- ahem.
♪ Hey-ey! ♪
♪ I think we're
gon' be chillin' ♪
Whee-ee-ee!
♪ I think we're
gon' be chillin' ♪
♪ ♪
♪ we're gon' be chillin' ♪
♪ I think we're gonna be,
we're gonna be chillin' ♪
♪ Whoo! All right ♪
♪ I think we gon' be chillin' ♪
♪ whoo-hoo! All right! ♪
- huh?
♪ I think we gon' be chillin' ♪
♪ I think we're gonna be,
we're gonna be chillin' ♪
♪
Ooh, shortcut.
Hey, grizz, we're back!
We got your...
Ohh!
What is that smell?
Uh...
Ice bear feels nauseous.
Grizz, this is disgusting.
Your burrito smells horrible!
[Gasp] How could you
say that about burrito,
and right in front of him?
Panda, I'm shocked.
You're shocked?
I'm the one who
should be shocked!
You never want to go
out with us anymore.
You're never two feet
away from that burrito!
It's creepy, man!
Ice bear forced to agree.
You guys just don't understand.
Also, it's not "that burrito,"
it's just burrito.
You've changed, grizz.
You're wrong!
Burrito's the best thing
that ever happened to me,
so just leave us alone!
I think it's worse
than we thought.
I found this website
about people
who get too attached
to their food.
Look at all of these.
This lady in Idaho
became obsessed
with a bag of chips,
someone in Japan married
their bowl of ramen,
and this guy adopted
a jar of pickles.
It just goes on and on!
They forget about
their families and friends
and sometimes just
become total hermits.
I think one thing is certain.
Ice bear sees
where this is going.
We have to do something
about that burrito.
Uh...
burrito!
Ah.
Huh?
What the...?
Uh...
burrito?
Hey, come back here!
Kidnappers!
Don't hate us, please!
Oh, it smells so bad!
Ah! My hand
has juices on it!
Ahh! Oh!
Ow!
We're just trying
to help you, grizz!
This burrito
is driving you insane!
Grizz...
Needs... Burrito.
Uh, up the tower!
Whoa-oa!
Dudes, why are you doing this?
I need to be with burrito.
Burrito completes me!
Grizz, please!
It's wrong to be
dependent on something
so unnatural.
We are doing this for you!
Let me cradle burrito.
We're concerned
because we love...
Dude, stop it.
Not right now.
Grizz, you need to understan...
What?
Ah-aah!
Huh?
Grizz! I'm sorry.
I'm so... wha-ah-oh!
I'm so sorry!
Uh-whoa!
Grizz are you okay?!
Oh, oh, my gosh! We...
We didn't mean to...
We didn't think it would...
We could still fix it.
Put this right there and...
There. See, grizz?
It's not so bad.
We could just put it
back togeth... whoa-oa!
Oh! That was
so unpleasant.
Whoa!
Ha!
Oh!
Ooh!
Ah, I am sorry if I was
acting weird, you guys.
We were really worried there.
Oh, don't worry about it.
I feel good as new.
Come on, let's head home.
Ice bear demands
everyone showers.
Hm, I wonder why I was
so obsessed with that burrito.
Ah, I guess it doesn't matter.
All cars, immediately.
Affirmative,
we've secured the area
and fire and rescue is
on the scene.
Okay, I need two men
on that aerial ladder.
Get the life net,
in case the animal falls.
It's okay, little guy.
Grab on.
You're safe now.
♪ Please take me there ♪
♪ I'm ready ♪
I'm not sure how this
little fella got up there.
He's holding my arm so tight.
Cute little guy.
I hope he doesn't get
too attached, heh.