No one is allowed
into the palace,
by order of the captain
of the imperial guards.
Do you not know who this is?
This is Military
Envoy Jang Bogo. Stand back!
We can't let you pass
without orders from the captain.
Stand back!
We have blockaded the palace.
Do not let anyone into
the palace without orders from me.
- Understand?
- Yes, sir.
Captain.
What is it?
Military Envoy
Jang Bogo is here.
What happened?
His Majesty seemed well
when I had an audience with him.
What was the cause
of his sudden death?
We do not know the cause.
Your Majesty...
it is I, Jang Bogo...
How could you have
left us so suddenly
before realizing
your grand cause?
Your Majesty...
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty...
What are you saying?
You must be mistaken.
He seemed to be in good
health when I last saw him.
It can't be...
it can't be.
The arrow has
already left the bow.
No conflict or hesitation
will be tolerated.
Unless the arrow
hits the target,
you and I will
both be finished.
I will announce
the king's death,
and prepare for
an imperial funeral.
You must get rid of any evidence
that could cause trouble.
We have seen it
with our own eyes,
but I still can't believe it.
According to
the royal physician,
His Majesty's heart condition
was the cause of death.
But his condition had been
cured during his stay in Chunghae.
He was in perfect health
when I saw him
just a few days ago.
You mean there is suspicion
concerning his sudden death?
There are many
questions concerning his death.
We must delay the funeral
and find some answers.
Call a meeting of the captains
of the Kuseo division.
Yes, sir.
- My lord.
- What is it?
Jang Bogo has exercised
his authority as military envoy
and ordered a delay
of the imperial funeral.
What are you saying?
He said he'd uncover the truth
behind His Majesty's death.
He has used his authority
to station troops in the palace.
He has also summoned the court
officials to the palace.
Who is he to
summon court officials?
He has the authority
as military envoy.
Your failure to kill Jang Bogo
will be shackles that bind us.
What is the purpose
of this meeting?
I wish to delay
His Majesty's funeral.
Delay the funeral?
Do you not realize
that stability will return
to the imperial court
only when the funeral is held,
and the crown prince
succeeds to the throne?
I can't accept
His Majesty's sudden death.
People will also find
it hard to accept.
We must resolve
any suspicion in order
to restore the stability and
authority of the imperial court.
Suspicion?
Are you saying someone
has assassinated the king?
There will be more
commotion among the people
if the funeral is delayed.
Are you able to accept
the sudden death of His Majesty
when he was in good health?
I thought you would be
the first to investigate his death.
What did you find?
There is no trace of poison.
Inspect the body again.
There would be traces
of poison in his body
if he had been poisoned.
But there are none,
as you can see.
Are you still suspicious
of His Majesty's death?
You have let
an unfounded suspicion
delay the imperial funeral and
upset the officials of the court.
How will you take
responsibility for that?
A lowly slave summoned
a meeting of the nobles,
and ordered the imperial family
to come and go.
Jang Bogo will soon face
strong hostility from the nobles.
He has dug his own grave.
Consul Jang is not
leaving His Majesty's side.
A dead man can't talk.
What is there to worry about?
The royal physician has said
that traces of the poison
will surface after five days.
Traces of poison will
surface in three days.
Don't worry.
We just need to hold
the funeral before that.
My lord.
I told you not
to show yourself before me
until the funeral is over.
The military envoy
is not leaving...
I know.
I will take care of everything.
Put your worries
to rest and leave me.
- Leave me at once!
- Yes, sir.
We must silence him.
What brings you here?
I have so many questions,
but I am frustrated
to find no answers.
Do you believe His Majesty has
died from his chronic illness?
If His Majesty was murdered,
who do you believe did it?
I know there are many nobles
who oppose His Majesty's
ideas for reform.
I'm certain
they couldn't tolerate
his relationship with me.
You will confront the
imperial family knowing that?
The more you assert yourself,
the more enemies you will make.
It could also
put you in danger.
I can't back down like this.
I must uncover the truth.
You are the captain
of the imperial guards.
You are in a position to know
all the goings-on of the palace.
Just what happened?
Please tell me.
You already know
everything I know.
I know nothing more.
I have a few questions regarding
His Majesty's sudden death.
We even performed an autopsy,
but there was
no sign of foul play.
I hear that there are poisons
that do not leave traces.
Is that true?
I have heard of an herb
called Chinese foxglove
used by Chinese physicians
that has such properties.
But I have never seen it.
What is this?
I do... not know.
A royal physician doesn't
know the contents
of his own
medicine warehouse?
I will tell you.
It is a poison known
as Chinese foxglove.
When a person is
poisoned with this,
traces of poison will not appear
until five days after death.
Am I wrong?
I predict that traces
of poison will appear
in His Majesty's body
in two days.
Who put you up to this?
Please do not kill me.
I was forced
to commit a grave wrong.
Tell me who put you up to this.
Lord Kim Yang and the captain
of the imperial guards.
Consul.
What is it?
Master Chang-gyum...
has passed away.
Is it true you're
returning to Chunghae?
Yes.
Get ready.
You will return when there
are unresolved suspicions
regarding the deaths of
His Majesty and Master Chang-gyum?
My presence in the
imperial city is arousing
hostile feelings
in Kim Yang and the nobles.
I will return to Chunghae,
and think about
what I can do for the new king.
There is nothing
to think about.
We could summon our army
and wipe out the nobles.
I know reform is difficult
as long as there are nobles
who have enjoyed
privileges for generations.
But we can't kill them all.
For the sake of the people
who have suffered through wars
and conflict in the court,
we must not cause more trouble.
Be prepared to return.
I don't know
how I will face
Lady Jung-hwa's father
when I die...
...for even Master Chang-gyum
has died such a violent death.
Haven't they found
out who killed him yet?
No.
I'm worried sick
about Lady Jung-hwa.
She has lost His Majesty,
who was her pillar of support...
and now Master Chang-gyum...
What a sad fate she has.
I can't stay here.
I must go to the imperial city.
You stay and
take care of business.
I must go and take
care of Lady Jung-hwa.
- There is no need for that.
- What do you mean?
Lady Jung-hwa will
enter the palace
to take care of the young king.
Forgive me for leaving
after placing such a great
burden on your shoulders.
I believe you made
a wise decision
to avoid confrontation
with the nobles now.
I will serve His Majesty.
Put your worries
to rest and return to Chunghae.
If you detect
any danger to His Majesty,
send a message
to Chunghae right away.
I will come back
to the imperial city.
The nobles' and imperial family's
hostility toward you
will grow stronger
in the future.
Please...
Please be safe.
My lady.
If I could see...
...you live happily...
I would...
I would have forced
myself to forget you.
When you were going
to be so lonely...
why?
...why did you push me away?
I'm returning
to Chunghae now.
I have a favor to ask
of you before I leave.
Take care of Lady Jung-hwa.
She has lost her brother
even before getting over the
sorrow of the late king's death.
The pain must be unbearable,
but she is not
even crying out loud.
I will find a way to protect
His Majesty when I return,
but I'm thousands
of miles away,
and the power that threatens His
Majesty is in the imperial city.
They will not even allow
Lady Jung-hwa to stay by his side.
You must take
care of Lady Jung-hwa.
Since you have
loved her for many years...
I believe
you will protect her
even without my asking.
- Welcome, Master.
- Yes.
- My lord.
- What are they?
It's profit earned
by our merchant group.
Good work.
I don't mean
to toot my own horn,
but the reason I led
such a mediocre life was
because I never had the chance
to apply my talents.
I will repay your kindness
by bringing you large profits.
I will be watching your back.
Build a merchant group
that will surpass Chunghae Base.
Yes, sir.
What is it?
Jang Bogo has
returned to Chunghae.
Trading is taking
place without a hitch.
We will soon have to increase
the number of ships to China
to accommodate the increasing
quantity of trade.
Since I have you to run
Chunghae Base in my absence,
I feel most relieved.
Lady Jung-hwa must
be upset over her loss.
Is she well?
Yes.
Ill fortune continues
to plague Lady Jung-hwa.
My heart goes out to her.
Consul.
- What happened?
- Everyone is here.
They are middle-class nobles
from all over Shilla
who have answered your summons.
Please be seated.
I have asked you here
to recommend you
to His Majesty.
All of you possess
extraordinary talents,
but you have not had
the chance to use them,
and you have lived in rural areas
because of corrupt nobles
or because of the limitations
of your status.
But His Majesty urgently
needs your talents and support.
You must go to
the imperial city,
reform the imperial court,
and put the confusion
in the imperial court to rest.
I am sick of politics
in the imperial city.
I do not wish
to go to the imperial city.
You can't bring reform
to the imperial court
with your will alone.
The imperial city
will find no peace
unless you wipe out
all the corrupt nobles.
I understand the despair
you must have suffered until now.
But if you give up
in the face of reality,
Shilla will come to ruin.
Corrupt nobles who have enjoyed
privileges for generations
surround the young king,
indulging in acts of tyranny.
You must go to the imperial
city to protect the king
and support him
so that he may govern wisely.
How many days will it
take to travel to Chunghae Base?
It will be a journey of three
to four days by ship.
Do you wish to
go to Chunghae Base?
There is no place
in Shilla you can't go.
But it wouldn't be too late
to go after you have
become an adult
and restored authority
to the imperial court.
The military envoy
is not coming back?
He will come anytime
if you command him.
Your Majesty, it is time
to meet with the court.
You must endure it even
if you find it difficult to do.
People can trust you and
follow you when you are strong.
Please be strong.
Escort His Majesty.
I'm relieved to have you by
His Majesty's side at all times.
It is my duty.
You have grown frail.
Are you feeling unwell?
No.
My lady.
What is it?
If I hadn't met you...
...my life would have
taken a very different shape.
You said you wished
me to be happy.
Come to think of it,
the happiest days in my life
were the days
I taught you business in Mujinju.
Back then you learned business
from me without any caution.
Those days seem
like a dream to me.
Since then, you were
always by my side,
but you were also
the farthest from me.
Even when you said
you would marry me...
Even when you said...
you'd stay by my side
in Yi Sa-do's camp,
you were the farthest from me.
You said you wished
me to be happy...
You said to forget you...
It is painful
to keep you in my heart...
but because it would
be more painful to forget you,
because I'm afraid
of that pain...
I don't believe I'll be able
to forget you until the day I die.
If I should be happy,
it will not be
from forgetting you,
but because my life
of loving you...
will have come to an end.
My lady.
What is it?
Kim Yang is planning to make
his daughter the king's consort.
He has boldly unveiled his
ambition to dominate the court.
If Kim Yang's daughter
should become a consort,
he will become
the king's father-in-law,
and control His Majesty.
I can't just stand
by and watch it happen.
He must be
stopped at all costs.
Must you make your
daughter the king's consort?
It is the imperial family's wish.
They want to use me
to keep Jang Bogo in check.
It is a chance for me
to gain great power
as the king's father-in-law.
I have no reason
to turn it down.
If I become the
king's father-in-law,
you will also
gain even more power.
I will give you the power
to slay Jang Bogo in an instant.
Assuming that you are
willing to kill Jang Bogo.
Is there bad news?
Kim Yang is trying to make
his daughter the king's consort.
The imperial family and the nobles
are in cahoots with him,
ignoring the king, and
indulging in acts of tyranny.
We must take our army
to the imperial city
and slay Kim Yang.
You can't get agitated.
If we raise the army, Lady
Jung-hwa and Master Jo will also
be in danger
along with the king.
It is most regrettable,
but the nobles' tyranny was
to be expected since His Majesty
is of so tender an age.
But for now, it is my duty
to send talented men
who can stay by His Majesty's
side to protect and support him.
Your Majesty, they are men
recommended by the military envoy.
They are excellent scholars
who once served in the court,
but have left the court
to avoid conflict there.
But they have returned
to the imperial city to serve you.
If you are recommended
by the military envoy,
I will bestow official posts
on you and keep you nearby.
Your grace is immeasurable.
Your Majesty, I heard
that you bestowed official posts
on the men sent by Jang Bogo.
That's true.
That is not to be!
Please withdraw your command.
It is Jang Bogo's
intention to control the court.
You must ignore his attempt.
They are distinguished scholars
who were already acknowledged
by the imperial court.
What is to keep them
from serving His Majesty?
Silence!
How dare a woman assert
herself in the court?
Your insolence in His Majesty's
presence is unforgivable.
You wench!
Do you have a death wish?
Your Majesty, you must not let
Jang Bogo control you any longer.
Please withdraw your command
to bestow official posts on
the men sent by Jang Bogo.
You must go to Chunghae.
Deliver this letter
to Consul Jang.
Yes.
You have to be discreet.
Kim Yang's men
mustn't find out.
- Be most careful.
- Yes.
Kill him.
You called for me?
I shall go to Chunghae
and draw a clear line
so that Jang Bogo can't interfere
in the politics of the court.
Be prepared
to leave for Chunghae.
I will not go.
I am the captain
of the imperial guards.
My duty is
to protect the king.
Do so,
if that is your wish.
You mean to place
your men in the imperial court
under the guise of recommending
talented young men to the king.
It seems it is your intention
to control the king...
- Am I wrong?
- Shut up!
How dare you
utter such nonsense!
Consul, ban this man
from Chunghae at once,
and never give him
the time of day again!
Captain Jung!
So what is this warning
you have for me?
Do not ever
act in haste again.
Since you have
given me a warning,
I will give
you one as well.
I heard you have joined
forces with nobles
to oppress the young king
and indulge in acts of tyranny.
The reason I honored
Lord Kim Woo-jing as commander
of the Pyong Dong army, and
marched to the imperial city
was to reform
the corrupt court
and look after
the welfare of Shilla people.
But if you disrupt the court
for the sake
of your personal ambitions,
I will not overlook it.
Are you saying you
are willing to go to war?
I have refrained
from raising an army
for the sake of the people
who have already suffered so much.
But if His Majesty's
safety is threatened,
I will take my army
to the imperial city at once.
As of this moment,
Chunghae Base is on a war footing.
Captains, inspect
your troops and weapons.
Be ready to
deploy at any time.
Yes, sir.
Unless Jang Bogo ceases
to provoke the imperial court,
we will go
to war with Chunghae Base.
- Captain.
- Yes.
Shut down
the king's private quarters,
and allow no audience
with court officials.
- Chief Jang.
- Yes.
Put Jung-hwa and Jo Jang-gil
under house arrest.
Yes, sir.
Let me go, you wretches.
Who sent you here?
Did Kim Yang send you here?
Let go of me.
You must be prepared for
a surprise attack from the enemy.
Yes, sir.
May I have a word with you?
What is it?
I will go to Chunghae
and negotiate with Jang Bogo.
Going to war with Chunghae Base
now is a reckless act
that will not bring any good
to the imperial court
or to the people of Shilla.
I will negotiate
with Jang Bogo, and avoid war.
He will not listen to you.
I will stop this war even
if I have to kill Jang Bogo.
How can I trust you?
You have already put aside
your grudge against Jang Bogo.
I am putting my life
at stake by going to Chunghae,
when we are on the brink
of war with Chunghae Base.
If any harm should
come to His Majesty
before I reach an
agreement with Jang Bogo,
I will not forgive you.
You're worried about the safety
of Jung-hwa, not the king.
Fine, I can grant you any wish
if you will kill Jang Bogo.
I'm sorry I can't
be of any help to you.
I'm leaving the imperial city.
- Baek-kyung.
- Yes, sir.
You will serve
Lady Jung-hwa from now.
- Yes, sir.
- Leave us.
I do not believe
I will see you again.
Where are you going?
It seems I might finally be
freed from my long suffering,
and find happiness.
You said you wished
me to be happy...
You said to forget you...
It is painful
to keep you in my heart...
but because it would
be more painful to forget you,
because I'm afraid
of that pain...
I don't believe I'll be able
to forget you until the day I die.
If I should be happy,
it will not be
from forgetting you,
but because my life
of loving you...
will have come to an end.
It seems I might finally be
freed from my long suffering,
and find happiness.
Where has
the head chief gone?
Where has he gone?
He's gone to Chunghae Base.
I must go to Chunghae.
I need your help.
Station the Noh and Kuseo
divisions outside of Chunghae.
You will go to war
with Chunghae Base?
When Yum Jang kills Jang Bogo,
we must take the opportunity
to wipe out Chunghae Base.
Let's go.
Who goes there?
Captain.
Consul.
Yum Moon showed up in Chunghae.
Chunghae Base is on the brink
of war with the imperial court.
We can't allow entry to the
captain of the imperial guards.
Leave at once.
I must speak to the consul.
Allow me to see him.
Consul.
Bring Yum Moon.
Consul!
Bring him.