[ Horn honks ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ scattered cheers and
applause ]
[ Rock music plays ]
fuck.
[ Speaking indistinctly ]
[ laughs ]
ladies and gentlemen, this
[ Laughs ]
is your cue to start clapping,
Ladies and gentlemen, this
start cheering, start whooping,
Is your cue to start clapping,
and welcome to the stage
Start cheering, start whooping,
jim jefferies!
And welcome to the stage
[ Cheers and applause ]
Hello.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you for coming to my show,
"alcoholocaust."
[ Laughing ] fucking look at
"Alcoholocaust."
this big theater, man.
[ Laughing ] fucking look at
I appreciate you coming out.
This big theater, man.
People who are watching this at
I appreciate you coming out.
home might know that this is a
People who are watching this at
fucking monday night, so i
Home might know that this is a
appreciate how many people have
Fucking monday night, so i
come.
Appreciate how many people have
I realize that in this economy,
Come.
tickets for things such as
I realize that in this economy,
comedy shows aren't that cheap
Tickets for things such as
for men.
Comedy shows aren't that cheap
For women, same price they've
For men.
always fucking been, aren't
For women, same price they've
they?
Always fucking been, aren't
Women don't pay for things like
They?
this.
Women don't pay for things like
There's women in this room have
This.
no fucking idea how much the
There's women in this room have
ticket for this show cost.
No fucking idea how much the
No fucking idea!
Ticket for this show cost.
Your husband came home, said,
No fucking idea!
"remember, we're seeing
Your husband came home, said,
jim jefferies," you said, "who?"
"Remember, we're seeing
And now you're fucking here.
Jim jefferies," you said, "who?"
Women don't pay.
And now you're fucking here.
Basically, women are a bunch of
Women don't pay.
cunts.
Basically, women are a bunch of
To summarize, women are cunts.
Cunts.
See, and i don't know if women
To summarize, women are cunts.
even know that drinks cost
See, and i don't know if women
money, you know?
Even know that drinks cost
Ugly chicks know.
Money, you know?
If you know that drinks cost
Ugly chicks know.
money, you're a fucking ugly
If you know that drinks cost
bitch, but otherwise, you're a
Money, you're a fucking ugly
good-Looking girl.
Bitch, but otherwise, you're a
Good luck to you.
Good-Looking girl.
See, my birthday's on
Good luck to you.
valentine's day, so even on my
See, my birthday's on
fucking birthday i'm buying some
Valentine's day, so even on my
bitch dinner.
Fucking birthday i'm buying some
If i meet a nice girl and i'm in
Bitch dinner.
a restaurant and the check comes
If i meet a nice girl and i'm in
and i put the credit card
A restaurant and the check comes
down -- And she's a nice girl --
And i put the credit card
She'll do the purse grab.
Down -- And she's a nice girl --
And if i go, "no, no, no, it's
She'll do the purse grab.
okay," she's very quick to give
And if i go, "no, no, no, it's
up on that argument.
Okay," she's very quick to give
Other arguments, she can keep
Up on that argument.
going for fucking years, but
Other arguments, she can keep
that one she's ever so gracious
Going for fucking years, but
about.
That one she's ever so gracious
This is why i think i'd like
About.
to be gay.
This is why i think i'd like
I think gay would be a good move
To be gay.
for me.
I think gay would be a good move
I wouldn't enjoy the sex.
For me.
I'd have to get through the sex.
I wouldn't enjoy the sex.
I would have a cock in my mouth,
I'd have to get through the sex.
with tears streaming down my
I would have a cock in my mouth,
face.
With tears streaming down my
And as the jizz hit the back of
Face.
my throat, i'd be thinking of my
And as the jizz hit the back of
happy place, but it'd be
My throat, i'd be thinking of my
worthwhile just so i could split
Happy place, but it'd be
the occasional bill.
Worthwhile just so i could split
[ Cheers and applause ]
The occasional bill.
that's why gay guys are happy,
[ Cheers and applause ]
and that's why lesbians are
That's why gay guys are happy,
fucking miserable.
And that's why lesbians are
Lesbians are fucking miserable
Fucking miserable.
people 'cause they have to hang
Lesbians are fucking miserable
out with women all day.
People 'cause they have to hang
It must be fucking horrible.
Out with women all day.
They must just be sitting there
It must be fucking horrible.
at dinner, going, "i'm not gonna
They must just be sitting there
pay for this bitch.
At dinner, going, "i'm not gonna
I've just worn my best plaid
Pay for this bitch.
shirt and shaved my head.
I've just worn my best plaid
She better treat me like a
Shirt and shaved my head.
princess."
She better treat me like a
Now, if there's any lesbians in
Princess."
the room -- And i assume there's
Now, if there's any lesbians in
not, because laughter's not your
The room -- And i assume there's
thing -- But if there is, i'd
Not, because laughter's not your
like to apologize for that last
Thing -- But if there is, i'd
joke.
Like to apologize for that last
But if you hate men so much,
Joke.
stop trying to look like them.
But if you hate men so much,
You never see a jew dressed as
Stop trying to look like them.
a nazi.
You never see a jew dressed as
[ Cheers and applause ]
See, i did that joke in america.
I said lesbians have no sense of
humor and they're not fun or
whatever.
Humor and they're not fun or
And these two lesbians stood up
Whatever.
and stormed out of the room as
And these two lesbians stood up
if to prove my point.
And stormed out of the room as
They're just not fun people.
If to prove my point.
Gay guys are fun.
They're just not fun people.
I don't care how homophobic you
Gay guys are fun.
are.
I don't care how homophobic you
If you're holding a dinner party
Are.
and a gay guy shows up, you get
If you're holding a dinner party
a little bit excited, don't you?
And a gay guy shows up, you get
You're like, "oh, fucking a
A little bit excited, don't you?
gay guy.
You're like, "oh, fucking a
Oh, strap yourself in, love, eh?
Gay guy.
We got a live one."
Oh, strap yourself in, love, eh?
Right?
We got a live one."
But if you're holding a dinner
Right?
party and a lesbian shows up,
But if you're holding a dinner
you're just like, "aw, fuck me.
Party and a lesbian shows up,
All i wanted to do was relax and
You're just like, "aw, fuck me.
play pictionary.
All i wanted to do was relax and
She's drawing something
Play pictionary.
political."
She's drawing something
[ Chuckles ]
Political."
you can't even point lesbians
[ Chuckles ]
out, and they're so fucking
You can't even point lesbians
obvious.
Out, and they're so fucking
They're so obvi-- But you can't
Obvious.
point them out.
They're so obvi-- But you can't
If you saw, like, fucking --
Point them out.
If i see like two lesbians in
If you saw, like, fucking --
the audience and go, "excuse me,
If i see like two lesbians in
are you lesbians?" They'll be
The audience and go, "excuse me,
like, "what?
Are you lesbians?" They'll be
What the fuck? What?
Like, "what?
What do you mean by that?"
What the fuck? What?
Right?
What do you mean by that?"
But if i see two gay guys in the
Right?
audience and go, "excuse me --
But if i see two gay guys in the
Are you gay guys?" They'll go
Audience and go, "excuse me --
[ singsong voice ] "guilty!"
Are you gay guys?" They'll go
[ Normal voice ] 'cause gay guys
[ Singsong voice ] "guilty!"
fucking love being gay.
[ Normal voice ] 'cause gay guys
The word "gay" comes from
Fucking love being gay.
"happy."
The word "gay" comes from
They like fucking men in the ass
"Happy."
so much, they've called it
They like fucking men in the ass
"happy."
So much, they've called it
I-I have been a heterosexual my
"Happy."
whole life.
I-I have been a heterosexual my
I would not call the experience
Whole life.
"happy."
I would not call the experience
I would call it a struggle, at
"Happy."
best.
I would call it a struggle, at
I'll tell you another reason why
Best.
it must be awesome to be a gay
I'll tell you another reason why
guy.
It must be awesome to be a gay
It must be wonderful to be in a
Guy.
relationship where, if you're
It must be wonderful to be in a
partner's being a dickhead, you
Relationship where, if you're
can punch him in the head.
Partner's being a dickhead, you
Hasn't that got to give your
Can punch him in the head.
relationship a whole new
Hasn't that got to give your
dimension?
Relationship a whole new
I can't tell you the amount of
Dimension?
arguments i've had with women
I can't tell you the amount of
that could have been sorted out
Arguments i've had with women
quicker with a punch.
That could have been sorted out
And while we're on the subject
Quicker with a punch.
of domestic violence --
And while we're on the subject
It's a horrible thing.
Of domestic violence --
Of course it is, and...
It's a horrible thing.
now, you ever met a woman who's,
Of course it is, and...
like, been married like four
Now, you ever met a woman who's,
times and she's like, "i guess i
Like, been married like four
just choose the wrong type of
Times and she's like, "i guess i
men"?
Just choose the wrong type of
"I've been married four times,
Men"?
and all my husbands beat me."
"I've been married four times,
And you're like, "all of them?
And all my husbands beat me."
All four?
And you're like, "all of them?
One, two, three, fucking four?
All four?
They all beat you?
One, two, three, fucking four?
Someone doesn't know when to
They all beat you?
shut the fuck up, now, do they?"
Someone doesn't know when to
'Cause i'm a tolerant man.
Shut the fuck up, now, do they?"
I'll give anyone three, but
'Cause i'm a tolerant man.
four?
I'll give anyone three, but
You're a fucking button-Pusher.
Four?
Come on.
You're a fucking button-Pusher.
That's a nice, cheery way to
Come on.
start the show.
That's a nice, cheery way to
I do a lot of gigs -- Well, not
Start the show.
a lot -- I do some gigs out in
I do a lot of gigs -- Well, not
iraq and afghanistan and stuff
A lot -- I do some gigs out in
like that, which, if i was in an
Iraq and afghanistan and stuff
american crowd right now, they'd
Like that, which, if i was in an
go, "whoo! Yeah, yeah, yeah!"
American crowd right now, they'd
But i'm not, so i can be honest
Go, "whoo! Yeah, yeah, yeah!"
with you.
But i'm not, so i can be honest
I do it for money.
With you.
Um, the first time --
I do it for money.
Over there it's like i'm king.
Um, the first time --
The first time i go do a gig in
Over there it's like i'm king.
iraq, they fly me and my manager
The first time i go do a gig in
in a passenger plane into
Iraq, they fly me and my manager
kuwait.
In a passenger plane into
Now, it turns out that kuwait is
Kuwait.
a regular country that anyone
Now, it turns out that kuwait is
can visit.
A regular country that anyone
Then a military truck gets me
Can visit.
and my manager and drives us
Then a military truck gets me
over the border into iraq and
And my manager and drives us
drops us off.
Over the border into iraq and
And we're standing in the middle
Drops us off.
of the desert of a war-Torn
And we're standing in the middle
country.
Of the desert of a war-Torn
We can't see anything on the
Country.
horizon.
We can't see anything on the
And i turn to my manager and go,
Horizon.
"good booking, fuckface."
And i turn to my manager and go,
And then this helicopter comes
"Good booking, fuckface."
in over the horizon and lands in
And then this helicopter comes
front of us, and the blades are
In over the horizon and lands in
still going.
Front of us, and the blades are
And this soldier runs off and
Still going.
goes, "excuse me!
And this soldier runs off and
Are you jim jefferies?"
Goes, "excuse me!
And i went, "what other white
Are you jim jefferies?"
cunt were you looking for in the
And i went, "what other white
desert at this exact location?"
Cunt were you looking for in the
Then he hands me my bulletproof
Desert at this exact location?"
vest and my helmet.
Then he hands me my bulletproof
He's obviously wearing his
Vest and my helmet.
bulletproof vest and his helmet.
He's obviously wearing his
His are camouflaged.
Bulletproof vest and his helmet.
Mine?
His are camouflaged.
Fucking blue.
Mine?
And i said, "why do i have a
Fucking blue.
blue vest and helmet?"
And i said, "why do i have a
He said, "that's so the enemy
Blue vest and helmet?"
know you're a civilian."
He said, "that's so the enemy
I'm like, "does the enemy give
Know you're a civilian."
a shit?
I'm like, "does the enemy give
That's my main concern, because
A shit?
i've never been a sniper."
That's my main concern, because
But every time i got off the
I've never been a sniper."
helicopter, i was surrounded by
But every time i got off the
soldiers protecting me.
Helicopter, i was surrounded by
If i was a sniper, i'd be like,
Soldiers protecting me.
"the cunt in blue looks
If i was a sniper, i'd be like,
important."
"The cunt in blue looks
Right?
Important."
So...we got in this helicopter.
Right?
[ Laughs ]
So...we got in this helicopter.
and we're sitting in this
[ Laughs ]
chopper.
And we're sitting in this
That's what we call them in the
Chopper.
biz -- "Chopper."
That's what we call them in the
And i'm sitting here.
Biz -- "Chopper."
And i got two soldiers sitting
And i'm sitting here.
next to me there, my manager,
And i got two soldiers sitting
brett, sitting there.
Next to me there, my manager,
He's got two soldiers sitting
Brett, sitting there.
next to him.
He's got two soldiers sitting
There's two soldiers in the
Next to him.
cockpit.
There's two soldiers in the
There's a great big door open
Cockpit.
next to me there, and there's
There's a great big door open
another door open there, and at
Next to me there, and there's
that door is a soldier with a
Another door open there, and at
great big gun on a hinge, with
That door is a soldier with a
bullets coming out of it like
Great big gun on a hinge, with
that thing that chewbacca wears.
Bullets coming out of it like
And we take off, and off we go
That thing that chewbacca wears.
to baghdad.
And we take off, and off we go
And as we hit the border of the
To baghdad.
city, i hear a great big "bang!"
And as we hit the border of the
And these two small flares shoot
City, i hear a great big "bang!"
out from the small wings of the
And these two small flares shoot
helicopter, followed by a trail
Out from the small wings of the
of smoke.
Helicopter, followed by a trail
And the helicopter goes,
Of smoke.
"fwwhhh! Fwwhhh! Fwwhhh!"
And the helicopter goes,
Now, the reason they do this is,
"Fwwhhh! Fwwhhh! Fwwhhh!"
when they get over the danger
Now, the reason they do this is,
area, if there's a heat-Seeking
When they get over the danger
missile, it'll be distracted by
Area, if there's a heat-Seeking
the flares, and then the
Missile, it'll be distracted by
helicopter will fly out of
The flares, and then the
range -- Very clever.
Helicopter will fly out of
Now...
Range -- Very clever.
they never told me this was
Now...
happening.
They never told me this was
As far as i'm concerned, the
Happening.
wings have just exploded and
As far as i'm concerned, the
we're now plummeting to our
Wings have just exploded and
death, but it's nice to know how
We're now plummeting to our
you react under pressure,
Death, but it's nice to know how
because i reacted thusly -- By
You react under pressure,
vomiting over my lovely blue
Because i reacted thusly -- By
vest, ironically making it more
Vomiting over my lovely blue
camouflage than it was before,
Vest, ironically making it more
and yelling out, "we're going
Camouflage than it was before,
down!"
And yelling out, "we're going
The two pilots, the sergeants,
Down!"
the gunner -- They all start
The two pilots, the sergeants,
pissing themselves, laughing.
The gunner -- They all start
They're reaching through.
Pissing themselves, laughing.
They're high-Fiving each other.
They're reaching through.
They're tearing it down.
They're high-Fiving each other.
They've been waiting for this
They're tearing it down.
joke for months.
They've been waiting for this
I'm cleaning vomit off myself,
Joke for months.
going, "oh, you, that was a good
I'm cleaning vomit off myself,
one.
Going, "oh, you, that was a good
Thank you for defending my
One.
freedom."
Thank you for defending my
Right?
Freedom."
So, i sit back down, covered in
Right?
vomit in the helicopter --
So, i sit back down, covered in
"Ugh."
Vomit in the helicopter --
And so i'm trying to look out
"Ugh."
the door to try to un-Quease
And so i'm trying to look out
myself.
The door to try to un-Quease
And i'm looking out over the
Myself.
ground, over baghdad -- By the
And i'm looking out over the
way, baghdad, beautiful city,
Ground, over baghdad -- By the
untouched -- And i look out on
Way, baghdad, beautiful city,
the ground, and i see a little
Untouched -- And i look out on
arab fellow with a handgun
The ground, and i see a little
shooting up at the helicopter,
Arab fellow with a handgun
just -- [ Imitates gunshots ]
Shooting up at the helicopter,
once again, i freak out.
Just -- [ Imitates gunshots ]
"We're being fired on!"
Once again, i freak out.
The gunner now is laughing so
"We're being fired on!"
fucking hard.
The gunner now is laughing so
He's laughing even harder than
Fucking hard.
he was before.
He's laughing even harder than
He's laughing so hard, he's
He was before.
keeled over.
He's laughing so hard, he's
The gun's just dangling out in
Keeled over.
the hinge.
The gun's just dangling out in
And i'm like, "what's your
The hinge.
fucking problem, man?"
And i'm like, "what's your
And he's like, "jim, you're
Fucking problem, man?"
gonna have to calm down, mate.
And he's like, "jim, you're
We're in a military helicopter
Gonna have to calm down, mate.
with a bulletproof bottom.
We're in a military helicopter
That's a handgun.
With a bulletproof bottom.
We're so high up, the bullets
That's a handgun.
can't even reach us.
We're so high up, the bullets
They just sort of go --
Can't even reach us.
[ Whistles ]"
They just sort of go --
and then i jokingly said,
[ Whistles ]"
"[ chuckles ] i bet our bullets
And then i jokingly said,
can reach him."
"[ Chuckles ] i bet our bullets
And he went, "oh, yeah."
Can reach him."
[ Imitates gunfire ]
And the little cunt died.
And -- And i was like,
"[ sighs ]
i was just saying, mate.
"[ Sighs ]
I was just saying.
I was just saying, mate.
I didn't want to ruin anyone's
I was just saying.
day."
I didn't want to ruin anyone's
[ Laughs ]
Day."
isn't that a fun story about a
[ Laughs ]
man dying?
Isn't that a fun story about a
It's funny, though.
Man dying?
My limited time in a war zone,
It's funny, though.
i really, you know, didn't see
My limited time in a war zone,
what all the bad stuff was.
I really, you know, didn't see
They were very nice to me.
What all the bad stuff was.
But this was kind of crazy to
They were very nice to me.
me 'cause i don't know,
But this was kind of crazy to
historically, how we're gonna
Me 'cause i don't know,
talk about it.
Historically, how we're gonna
See, like, my grandfather --
Talk about it.
He fought during the second
See, like, my grandfather --
world war, for the japs, weirdly
He fought during the second
enough.
World war, for the japs, weirdly
No, no, for the australians.
Enough.
He killed a lot of japanese --
No, no, for the australians.
Hated them till he died.
He killed a lot of japanese --
"Love the food, hate the
Hated them till he died.
people," he used to say.
"Love the food, hate the
What a complex man.
People," he used to say.
And...
What a complex man.
i used to love listening -- When
And...
i was a kid, listening to him
I used to love listening -- When
tell stories about killing
I was a kid, listening to him
nazis.
Tell stories about killing
There was always something
Nazis.
exciting about it, you know?
There was always something
I just don't know what i would
Exciting about it, you know?
tell my grandson about what's
I just don't know what i would
happening in history now.
Tell my grandson about what's
I imagine i'll be 80 years old,
Happening in history now.
i'll be sitting in my chair, and
I imagine i'll be 80 years old,
my grandson will be on the
I'll be sitting in my chair, and
floor, looking up at me
My grandson will be on the
adoringly.
Floor, looking up at me
And i'll go, "now, there used to
Adoringly.
be these people called arabs.
And i'll go, "now, there used to
And they lived in the
Be these people called arabs.
middle east, or, as you call it,
And they lived in the
the radiation zone.
Middle east, or, as you call it,
In 2020,
The radiation zone.
president macaulay culkin got
In 2020,
really upset with the arabs, and
President macaulay culkin got
he nuked them all.
Really upset with the arabs, and
But what macaulay culkin and the
He nuked them all.
rest of the americans hadn't
But what macaulay culkin and the
realized was that china had
Rest of the americans hadn't
slowly but surely become the
Realized was that china had
superpower of the world.
Slowly but surely become the
So, while the americans were
Superpower of the world.
nuking the arabs, the chinese
So, while the americans were
nuked the americans, and that's
Nuking the arabs, the chinese
why we have no americans and no
Nuked the americans, and that's
arabs."
Why we have no americans and no
And then my grandson will look
Arabs."
up at me and go...
And then my grandson will look
"mashaba awa."
[ Applause ]
[ laughs ]
you know what i like about that
[ Laughs ]
joke?
You know what i like about that
It has the feel of racism, but
Joke?
you can't pick the exact moment.
It has the feel of racism, but
Like, you know it is.
You can't pick the exact moment.
It's definitely racist.
Like, you know it is.
So, let's change the subject
It's definitely racist.
quickly.
So, let's change the subject
How do blind people wipe their
Quickly.
asses?
How do blind people wipe their
I know you're thinking, "the
Asses?
same as us," but you're not
I know you're thinking, "the
thinking outside the box, 'cause
Same as us," but you're not
wiping your ass is a very visual
Thinking outside the box, 'cause
activity.
Wiping your ass is a very visual
No one's ever just leant up,
Activity.
wiped, then dropped into the
No one's ever just leant up,
bowl.
Wiped, then dropped into the
You wipe. You check.
Bowl.
"There's a lot of poo there.
You wipe. You check.
I'm gonna wipe again.
"There's a lot of poo there.
There's still a lot of poo.
I'm gonna wipe again.
It feels dry, but there's
There's still a lot of poo.
still poo.
It feels dry, but there's
I think i left one up there."
Still poo.
I bet that's where the dog comes
I think i left one up there."
in handy.
I bet that's where the dog comes
[ Audience groans ]
In handy.
ohh!
[ Audience groans ]
No!
Ohh!
No, don't --
No!
I'm not saying the dog licks
No, don't --
the blind person's ass!
I'm not saying the dog licks
I'm saying these are very
The blind person's ass!
intelligent dogs.
I'm saying these are very
They would have worked out some
Intelligent dogs.
form of barking system.
They would have worked out some
So, the blind guy would have the
Form of barking system.
dog, like, sit in front of him.
So, the blind guy would have the
"Woof woof woof."
Dog, like, sit in front of him.
"Woof woof."
"Woof woof woof."
"Woof."
And they'd probably work out
some special morse code-Y bark
for when there's blood in the
Some special morse code-Y bark
poo.
For when there's blood in the
No, 'cause they've already been
Poo.
through a rough time.
No, 'cause they've already been
They're blind.
Through a rough time.
No need for ass cancer.
They're blind.
Not that blood always means
No need for ass cancer.
ass cancer.
Not that blood always means
I suffer from hemorrhoids, have
Ass cancer.
done since i was 22 years old.
I suffer from hemorrhoids, have
And it's a very young age to get
Done since i was 22 years old.
hemorrhoids, but there's a lot
And it's a very young age to get
of blood involved.
Hemorrhoids, but there's a lot
If you've never had one, there's
Of blood involved.
a lot of blood involved in a bad
If you've never had one, there's
hemorrhoid.
A lot of blood involved in a bad
I've had toilet bowls that look
Hemorrhoid.
like abortions.
I've had toilet bowls that look
Now, i'm not -- It's not good.
Like abortions.
And the first time, when you're
Now, i'm not -- It's not good.
22 and you get one, your brain
And the first time, when you're
goes to ass cancer.
22 and you get one, your brain
You're like, "oh, i got ass
Goes to ass cancer.
cancer," because no one ever
You're like, "oh, i got ass
told you about hemorrhoids when
Cancer," because no one ever
you're young.
Told you about hemorrhoids when
Your dad never sits you down and
You're young.
goes, "when you get a bit older,
Your dad never sits you down and
you'll be pushing a poo a little
Goes, "when you get a bit older,
bit hard, and a small portion of
You'll be pushing a poo a little
your asshole will fall out.
Bit hard, and a small portion of
Now, it's nothing to be alarmed
Your asshole will fall out.
about.
Now, it's nothing to be alarmed
It's just part of becoming a
About.
[chuckling] man."
It's just part of becoming a
So, the first time i got a
[Chuckling] man."
hemorrhoid, i didn't tell anyone
So, the first time i got a
'cause i thought i was dying,
Hemorrhoid, i didn't tell anyone
obviously.
'Cause i thought i was dying,
And i go to see my doctor, the
Obviously.
same doctor that i've had my
And i go to see my doctor, the
whole life, and he makes me --
Same doctor that i've had my
I go, "i got ass cancer."
Whole life, and he makes me --
And he makes me bend over a
I go, "i got ass cancer."
chair.
And he makes me bend over a
And then he gets a rubber glove
Chair.
on, and he sort of prods around
And then he gets a rubber glove
my ass a little bit.
On, and he sort of prods around
And he goes, "oh, you've just
My ass a little bit.
got hemorrhoids there."
And he goes, "oh, you've just
And i said, "i thought that only
Got hemorrhoids there."
happens to old people and
And i said, "i thought that only
pregnant women."
Happens to old people and
And he went, "and you."
So, i live in america now, and
i --
[ Cheers and applause ]
I --
[ chuckles ]
[ Cheers and applause ]
people get so entertained by
[ Chuckles ]
that, but where else am i gonna
People get so entertained by
put them?
That, but where else am i gonna
We'll put that away for
Put them?
continuity, in case they cut
We'll put that away for
the jokes up differently.
Continuity, in case they cut
There we go.
The jokes up differently.
That's a bit of a --
There we go.
'Cause i know there's people
That's a bit of a --
that are sitting at home, going,
'Cause i know there's people
"[ laughs ] that beer went like
That are sitting at home, going,
that, then it it went like that,
"[ Laughs ] that beer went like
then it went like that."
That, then it it went like that,
Fucking nerds.
Then it went like that."
So, i live in america, and it
Fucking nerds.
fucking blows my mind i live in
So, i live in america, and it
america now, man.
Fucking blows my mind i live in
I -- Coming from australia and
America now, man.
everything, i never thought i'd
I -- Coming from australia and
sort of go this far with my
Everything, i never thought i'd
career or anything.
Sort of go this far with my
And i find myself -- Now i'm out
Career or anything.
there auditioning for major
And i find myself -- Now i'm out
movies and shit, man.
There auditioning for major
And i still feel retarded every
Movies and shit, man.
time i go in there.
And i still feel retarded every
Now, the first time i went for
Time i go in there.
an audition, i'd been in l.A.
Now, the first time i went for
For like a couple days.
An audition, i'd been in l.A.
And my agency sent me to this
For like a couple days.
audition and i went along and i
And my agency sent me to this
met this girl in the corridor
Audition and i went along and i
called carla.
Met this girl in the corridor
And i was really nervous, and
Called carla.
she could tell i was nervous.
And i was really nervous, and
And she sort of calmed me down
She could tell i was nervous.
and we had a little bit of a
And she sort of calmed me down
chat and she was really cute,
And we had a little bit of a
and we flirted together and
Chat and she was really cute,
stuff.
And we flirted together and
And then i went and read the
Stuff.
little bit, and then i went
And then i went and read the
home.
Little bit, and then i went
And then i got a call later on
Home.
that afternoon, going, "they
And then i got a call later on
loved you.
That afternoon, going, "they
You're gonna come back for a
Loved you.
callback."
You're gonna come back for a
So i'm like, "excellent.
Callback."
That's good.
So i'm like, "excellent.
So, i go back for the callback,
That's good.
and when you do callbacks, often
So, i go back for the callback,
they have you reading with
And when you do callbacks, often
another person.
They have you reading with
So, i'm in the room, reading
Another person.
with this girl, and it's the
So, i'm in the room, reading
same girl from the corridor.
With this girl, and it's the
It's carla, right?
Same girl from the corridor.
And we're sort of flirting,
It's carla, right?
going, "hey, from the thing
And we're sort of flirting,
before -- Ahh."
Going, "hey, from the thing
And so we're reading.
Before -- Ahh."
We have great on-Screen
And so we're reading.
chemistry and all that type of
We have great on-Screen
stuff.
Chemistry and all that type of
Then after the audition, i said,
Stuff.
"carla, do you have any taxicab
Then after the audition, i said,
numbers?
"Carla, do you have any taxicab
I got to get to my next
Numbers?
audition."
I got to get to my next
She said, "where are you trying
Audition."
to get to?"
She said, "where are you trying
And i went, "santa monica."
To get to?"
And she said, "that's where i'm
And i went, "santa monica."
going.
And she said, "that's where i'm
I'll give you a lift."
Going.
Now, please note at this stage
I'll give you a lift."
of the story i didn't ask for
Now, please note at this stage
the lift.
Of the story i didn't ask for
We go down to the car.
The lift.
She gets in.
We go down to the car.
She unwinds my window.
She gets in.
She looks out and goes, "jim,
She unwinds my window.
what's your full name?"
She looks out and goes, "jim,
And i went, "jim jefferies."
What's your full name?"
And she went, "wait there."
And i went, "jim jefferies."
Then she called her mom up and
And she went, "wait there."
said, "hi, mom. It's carla."
Then she called her mom up and
I just met a very nice boy at
Said, "hi, mom. It's carla."
the audition today, and i'm
I just met a very nice boy at
going to give him a lift.
The audition today, and i'm
But in case i get raped or
Going to give him a lift.
murdered, his name's
But in case i get raped or
jim jefferies.
Murdered, his name's
So if you don't hear from me in
Jim jefferies.
an hour, assume something bad
So if you don't hear from me in
has happened and call the cops.
An hour, assume something bad
Get it, jim!"
Has happened and call the cops.
So i get in.
Get it, jim!"
We got like a 15-Mile drive.
So i get in.
I say fucking nothing for the
We got like a 15-Mile drive.
first 5 miles.
I say fucking nothing for the
I just look forward.
First 5 miles.
And eventually i turn to her and
I just look forward.
go, "you've just made this rape
And eventually i turn to her and
really awkward."
Go, "you've just made this rape
She fucking freaks out!
Really awkward."
She slams her foot on the
She fucking freaks out!
brakes.
She slams her foot on the
She skids off the highway.
Brakes.
She starts slapping at me.
She skids off the highway.
I'm grabbing her wrists.
She starts slapping at me.
Now i feel kind of rapey, and
I'm grabbing her wrists.
i didn't want to.
Now i feel kind of rapey, and
And it's like, "you offered the
I didn't want to.
lift!
And it's like, "you offered the
I didn't ask for the fucking
Lift!
lift!
I didn't ask for the fucking
You seem more concerned in
Lift!
solving this crime than
You seem more concerned in
preventing it."
Solving this crime than
So, i raped her to teach her a
Preventing it."
lesson, 'cause...
So, i raped her to teach her a
[ applause ]
Lesson, 'cause...
...how else would she learn?
[ Applause ]
We're trying to sell this show
...how else would she learn?
to the americans.
We're trying to sell this show
I don't like our chances.
To the americans.
So, let's do something we can
I don't like our chances.
all enjoy.
So, let's do something we can
Sometimes when i'm fucking a
All enjoy.
chick, i go to fuck them again
Sometimes when i'm fucking a
in the morning, and they'll say
Chick, i go to fuck them again
something like this --
In the morning, and they'll say
"No.
Something like this --
When we fucked last night, it
"No.
was a little bit dry, and now
When we fucked last night, it
i'm sore."
Was a little bit dry, and now
Now, to any woman who's said
I'm sore."
something similar to this, may i
Now, to any woman who's said
say, "your problem.
Something similar to this, may i
My job was to get an erection.
Say, "your problem.
Your job was to get your hole
My job was to get an erection.
wet.
Your job was to get your hole
Didn't you get your hole wet?
Wet.
We both had things to do"?
Didn't you get your hole wet?
See...
We both had things to do"?
if i don't get an erection
See...
during sex, i'm called impotent.
If i don't get an erection
But a dry hole is the same as a
During sex, i'm called impotent.
flaccid penis.
But a dry hole is the same as a
A dry hole is an impotent hole
Flaccid penis.
and you're not a complete woman
A dry hole is an impotent hole
and you should be ashamed of
And you're not a complete woman
yourself.
And you should be ashamed of
[ Cheers and applause ]
Yourself.
but women don't take
[ Cheers and applause ]
responsibility for the dry hole.
But women don't take
If i go to fuck a chick tonight
Responsibility for the dry hole.
and i get too drunk, which i
If i go to fuck a chick tonight
will -- And i go to fuck a chick
And i get too drunk, which i
and i don't get an erection,
Will -- And i go to fuck a chick
she'll go back to her friends
And i don't get an erection,
and go, "oh, i went to fuck that
She'll go back to her friends
jim jefferies.
And go, "oh, i went to fuck that
He couldn't get an erection."
Jim jefferies.
But if i go to fuck a chick and
He couldn't get an erection."
she doesn't get wet, she'll go
But if i go to fuck a chick and
back to her friends and go,
She doesn't get wet, she'll go
"i fucked jim jefferies.
Back to her friends and go,
He didn't even get me wet."
"I fucked jim jefferies.
Do you see the problem there?
He didn't even get me wet."
I'm in charge of everything.
Do you see the problem there?
It's like -- I used to fuck this
I'm in charge of everything.
chick for a while.
It's like -- I used to fuck this
I start fucking her, and she
Chick for a while.
sent me a text -- Well, you
I start fucking her, and she
know, i just stopped calling
Sent me a text -- Well, you
her, you know, just ignored her.
Know, i just stopped calling
And she sent me a text message
Her, you know, just ignored her.
a month later that went, "oh,
And she sent me a text message
by the way, you never made me
A month later that went, "oh,
come."
By the way, you never made me
And i was like, "pfft, really?
Come."
You think you're the one who
And i was like, "pfft, really?
makes me come?
You think you're the one who
Do you want to know who makes
Makes me come?
me come?
Do you want to know who makes
I make me come!
Me come?
All the horrible thoughts i
I make me come!
have in my fucking head makes
All the horrible thoughts i
me come!
Have in my fucking head makes
You have very little to do
Me come!
with it.
You have very little to do
You're just the container i
With it.
shoot it into."
You're just the container i
[ Applause ]
Shoot it into."
but let's go back to the dry
[ Applause ]
cunt.
But let's go back to the dry
There are women in the room who
Cunt.
are thinking, "maybe i wouldn't
There are women in the room who
be dry if there was a bit of
Are thinking, "maybe i wouldn't
foreplay."
Be dry if there was a bit of
Let's explain foreplay.
Foreplay."
Foreplay is what we do to each
Let's explain foreplay.
other to get each other ready
Foreplay is what we do to each
for sex.
Other to get each other ready
If i have an erection, that
For sex.
means i'm ready for sex and
If i have an erection, that
i'm all foreplayed out.
Means i'm ready for sex and
Now, the foreplay that's
I'm all foreplayed out.
necessary for a woman goes like
Now, the foreplay that's
this -- You got to start by
Necessary for a woman goes like
kissing them.
This -- You got to start by
Women love kissing.
Kissing them.
Men don't give a shit about
Women love kissing.
kissing.
Men don't give a shit about
We kiss you because we like you
Kissing.
and -- Let's be honest -- We
We kiss you because we like you
spoil you.
And -- Let's be honest -- We
Men don't give a fuck about
Spoil you.
kissing.
Men don't give a fuck about
Used to like kissing when we
Kissing.
were in our early teens.
Used to like kissing when we
Then someone sucked our dick.
Were in our early teens.
And then, "what's this kissing
Then someone sucked our dick.
thing?
And then, "what's this kissing
Why am i kissing this person?
Thing?
Why would i ride on the swings?
Why am i kissing this person?
I've already been to
Why would i ride on the swings?
disneyland."
I've already been to
But we kiss you 'cause we like
Disneyland."
you and we're a charitable
But we kiss you 'cause we like
bunch.
You and we're a charitable
Then you start kissing down the
Bunch.
neck.
Then you start kissing down the
Now, the whole time you're doing
Neck.
this, you're working downwards,
Now, the whole time you're doing
towards the cunt.
This, you're working downwards,
Now, you know you're going to
Towards the cunt.
the cunt.
Now, you know you're going to
She knows you're going to the
The cunt.
cunt.
She knows you're going to the
Everybody knows...you're going
Cunt.
to the cunt.
Everybody knows...you're going
But for some unbeknown reason,
To the cunt.
you have to act like you're not
But for some unbeknown reason,
going to the cunt and that
You have to act like you're not
you're enjoying the journey of
Going to the cunt and that
this creature.
You're enjoying the journey of
Women -- You got to give them a
This creature.
journey.
Women -- You got to give them a
Men don't give a shit about a
Journey.
journey.
Men don't give a shit about a
If a man's driving from point
Journey.
"a" to point "b," we fill the
If a man's driving from point
tank, we get on the motorway,
"A" to point "b," we fill the
we make good time, right?
Tank, we get on the motorway,
With women, you got to give them
We make good time, right?
a fucking journey.
With women, you got to give them
You got to take them by the
A fucking journey.
water or antiquing or some shit.
You got to take them by the
[ Chuckles ]
Water or antiquing or some shit.
see, the thing is women read so
[ Chuckles ]
many magazines about how to send
See, the thing is women read so
your man wild and how to
Many magazines about how to send
titillate your man and all these
Your man wild and how to
25 steps to do all the --
Titillate your man and all these
It's a lot of fucking bullshit.
25 steps to do all the --
Oh, "get a feather."
It's a lot of fucking bullshit.
"Involve food in the
Oh, "get a feather."
relationship."
"Involve food in the
This is all bullshit.
Relationship."
"Play with his nipples."
This is all bullshit.
These things are fucking dead!
"Play with his nipples."
They're dead to me!
These things are fucking dead!
These mean nothing!
They're dead to me!
You could cut these off and
These mean nothing!
donate them to some poor african
You could cut these off and
child without nipples!
Donate them to some poor african
I wouldn't give a fuck.
Child without nipples!
This is what we want you to
I wouldn't give a fuck.
do -- Fucking suck our cock and
This is what we want you to
cup our balls.
Do -- Fucking suck our cock and
And when you're sucking our
Cup our balls.
cock, look like you're in a bit
And when you're sucking our
of pain because we enjoy it if
Cock, look like you're in a bit
you look uncomfortable.
Of pain because we enjoy it if
[ Cheers and applause ]
You look uncomfortable.
anyway, but back to the lady --
[ Cheers and applause ]
You keep kissing down.
Anyway, but back to the lady --
Now you're at the tits.
You keep kissing down.
Now, tits are a mixed bag.
Now you're at the tits.
Some tits you got to be firm
Now, tits are a mixed bag.
with.
Some tits you got to be firm
Some tits you got to be soft
With.
with.
Some tits you got to be soft
Some tits, you can bite the
With.
nipple.
Some tits, you can bite the
Some tits, don't even go near
Nipple.
the nipple.
Some tits, don't even go near
Tits are like golf -- You play
The nipple.
the course you're on.
Tits are like golf -- You play
Then...you keep kissing down.
The course you're on.
Now you're at the cunt.
Then...you keep kissing down.
But even when you get to the
Now you're at the cunt.
cunt, you have to act like
But even when you get to the
you're not at the cunt.
Cunt, you have to act like
You have to act like you've
You're not at the cunt.
stumbled upon the cunt by
You have to act like you've
accident.
Stumbled upon the cunt by
So, you'll be kissing, like, a
Accident.
dimple-Y bit of thigh here, and
So, you'll be kissing, like, a
the cunt's there.
Dimple-Y bit of thigh here, and
And you have to sort of almost,
The cunt's there.
"oh, hello!
And you have to sort of almost,
I was visiting dimple-Y thigh.
"Oh, hello!
I forgot you lived down here.
I was visiting dimple-Y thigh.
No, always a pleasure, never a
I forgot you lived down here.
chore.
No, always a pleasure, never a
Do you mind if i pop in?"
Chore.
Then you lick the whole general
Do you mind if i pop in?"
cunt area.
Then you lick the whole general
Then there's a bit at the top of
Cunt area.
the cunt -- If you lick that,
Then there's a bit at the top of
they seem to enjoy it.
The cunt -- If you lick that,
This all takes between 10 and 40
They seem to enjoy it.
minutes.
This all takes between 10 and 40
And she might be wet.
Minutes.
And that's the foreplay that's
And she might be wet.
necessary for a woman.
And that's the foreplay that's
Now, the foreplay that's
Necessary for a woman.
necessary for a man -- We just
Now, the foreplay that's
need to see you naked.
Necessary for a man -- We just
Maybe you need kisses, caresses,
Need to see you naked.
compliments, and licks, when all
Maybe you need kisses, caresses,
we need is you.
Compliments, and licks, when all
Maybe we take our relationships
We need is you.
seriously.
Maybe we take our relationships
[ Cheers and applause ]
how many more do you reckon
there is behind there?
How many more do you reckon
There's a dwarf behind there
There is behind there?
mixing me a cocktail.
There's a dwarf behind there
I am fucking drunk, though.
Mixing me a cocktail.
All right.
I am fucking drunk, though.
I'm gonna tell you a story.
All right.
This story's very long.
I'm gonna tell you a story.
The first three minutes of this
This story's very long.
story are very depressing.
The first three minutes of this
Just hitching up my pants.
Story are very depressing.
The first three minutes of this
Just hitching up my pants.
story are very depressing, but
The first three minutes of this
there is a moment where this
Story are very depressing, but
story takes flight.
There is a moment where this
And you have to hang in there
Story takes flight.
with me until this moment and
And you have to hang in there
trust me that the story's gonna
With me until this moment and
get good.
Trust me that the story's gonna
I grew up at number 3
Get good.
turramurra street.
I grew up at number 3
At number 5 was my two best
Turramurra street.
childhood friends, andrew and
At number 5 was my two best
daniel connor.
Childhood friends, andrew and
Daniel was born with a disease
Daniel connor.
called muscular dystrophy.
Daniel was born with a disease
If you don't know what muscular
Called muscular dystrophy.
dystrophy is, it's a horrible
If you don't know what muscular
disease that wastes away at your
Dystrophy is, it's a horrible
muscles.
Disease that wastes away at your
It's the same as lou gehrig's
Muscles.
disease or motor neuron disease,
It's the same as lou gehrig's
except you're born with it.
Disease or motor neuron disease,
You get diagnosed when you're
Except you're born with it.
about 6 years old, when you're
You get diagnosed when you're
not walking right and they put
About 6 years old, when you're
you on crutches.
Not walking right and they put
By the time you're 10, you're in
You on crutches.
a wheelchair.
By the time you're 10, you're in
By the time you're 20, you're in
A wheelchair.
a completely vegetative state.
By the time you're 20, you're in
Most people die before their
A completely vegetative state.
25th birthday.
Most people die before their
Dan's lived to be 33 years old,
25th birthday.
still alive and kicking.
Dan's lived to be 33 years old,
Let me rephrase that --
Still alive and kicking.
Still alive.
Let me rephrase that --
[ Scattered applause ]
Still alive.
he's actually died seven times
[ Scattered applause ]
in his life and been
He's actually died seven times
resuscitated -- Seven.
In his life and been
And i once asked him -- I said,
Resuscitated -- Seven.
"dan, what happens after you
And i once asked him -- I said,
die?"
"Dan, what happens after you
And he said, "nothing."
Die?"
So, good luck with your religion
And he said, "nothing."
and your faith.
So, good luck with your religion
I'll take an actual statistic.
And your faith.
Now, his family had since moved
I'll take an actual statistic.
to melbourne.
Now, his family had since moved
I had moved to great britain.
To melbourne.
I went to do the
I had moved to great britain.
melbourne comedy festival.
I went to do the
This was about a year ago.
Melbourne comedy festival.
I hadn't seen him in all that
This was about a year ago.
time.
I hadn't seen him in all that
His brother andrew came to see
Time.
my show, and then andrew took me
His brother andrew came to see
to see dan.
My show, and then andrew took me
And i went in to see him, and
To see dan.
i'd never seen anyone live this
And i went in to see him, and
long with this disease.
I'd never seen anyone live this
And he's laying on a bed.
Long with this disease.
His eyelids are a muscle that he
And he's laying on a bed.
can't keep open anymore, and
His eyelids are a muscle that he
he's just squinting through
Can't keep open anymore, and
these little things and has a
He's just squinting through
breathing mask on him to keep
These little things and has a
his lungs working because the
Breathing mask on him to keep
lungs are a muscle that he can't
His lungs working because the
keep pumping.
Lungs are a muscle that he can't
He has a heart-Monitoring
Keep pumping.
machine in case he flatlines in
He has a heart-Monitoring
the middle of the night and
Machine in case he flatlines in
someone has to resuscitate him.
The middle of the night and
And as soon as i walked in and
Someone has to resuscitate him.
saw this guy that i used to run
And as soon as i walked in and
around with as a child, i burst
Saw this guy that i used to run
into tears.
Around with as a child, i burst
There's nothing worse you can
Into tears.
give anyone in this world than
There's nothing worse you can
pity, you know?
Give anyone in this world than
I went in the corridor.
Pity, you know?
I felt like a right prick.
I went in the corridor.
And i was fucking wiping my eyes
I felt like a right prick.
off.
And i was fucking wiping my eyes
And i went back in and i sat
Off.
with dan, and his brother andrew
And i went back in and i sat
went off to work.
With dan, and his brother andrew
And me and dan chatted for
Went off to work.
a while.
And me and dan chatted for
20 minutes into the
A while.
conversation, dan says to me,
20 minutes into the
"jim, i'm 32 years old.
Conversation, dan says to me,
I've never been with a woman.
"Jim, i'm 32 years old.
Will you take me to a
I've never been with a woman.
prostitute?"
Will you take me to a
And that's where the story picks
Prostitute?"
up, ladies and gentlemen, 'cause
And that's where the story picks
i went, "fuck, yeah!"
Up, ladies and gentlemen, 'cause
And he went, "but don't tell my
I went, "fuck, yeah!"
brother.
And he went, "but don't tell my
He wouldn't understand."
Brother.
And i said, "that's where you're
He wouldn't understand."
wrong.
And i said, "that's where you're
I've known your brother my
Wrong.
entire life.
I've known your brother my
Trust me -- He will understand."
Entire life.
And against dan's will, when
Trust me -- He will understand."
andrew came home from work, i
And against dan's will, when
pulled andrew aside and said,
Andrew came home from work, i
"andrew, look, here's the deal.
Pulled andrew aside and said,
Dan's asked me to take him to
"Andrew, look, here's the deal.
a prostitute.
Dan's asked me to take him to
I'm gonna do it whether you like
A prostitute.
it or not, but i think, as his
I'm gonna do it whether you like
brother, you should come along
It or not, but i think, as his
and help out."
Brother, you should come along
And andrew went, "we're not
And help out."
doing it."
And andrew went, "we're not
And i went, "why?"
Doing it."
And he went, "it'll kill him."
And i went, "why?"
And i went --
And he went, "it'll kill him."
[ Exhales heavily ]
And i went --
"he's gonna die soon anyway.
[ Exhales heavily ]
This is a good way for him to
"He's gonna die soon anyway.
go.
This is a good way for him to
Like, sure, we'll have to answer
Go.
a few questions."
Like, sure, we'll have to answer
And he said, "we're not doing
A few questions."
it."
And he said, "we're not doing
And i said, "why?"
It."
And he goes, "'cause mom doesn't
And i said, "why?"
like you already!"
And he goes, "'cause mom doesn't
And i went, "your mom's never
Like you already!"
liked me!
And i went, "your mom's never
That's why i'm the right guy to
Liked me!
kill your brother!"
That's why i'm the right guy to
And he said, "all right, we'll
Kill your brother!"
do it, but he can't have full
And he said, "all right, we'll
sex.
Do it, but he can't have full
Full sex will kill him.
Sex.
He can only have a blowjob."
Full sex will kill him.
And i thought that was fairly
He can only have a blowjob."
reasonable.
And i thought that was fairly
So, we went back in and saw dan.
Reasonable.
He was where we left him.
So, we went back in and saw dan.
And we said...
He was where we left him.
"dan, here's the deal -- I know
And we said...
you told me not to tell your
"Dan, here's the deal -- I know
brother, but i told your
You told me not to tell your
brother.
Brother, but i told your
Me and him are both gonna take
Brother.
you to the knock shop tomorrow,
Me and him are both gonna take
mate, but you can't have full
You to the knock shop tomorrow,
sex.
Mate, but you can't have full
You can only have a blowjob."
Sex.
And dan went, "i want full sex."
You can only have a blowjob."
And his brother andrew went,
And dan went, "i want full sex."
"dan, you're in no position to
And his brother andrew went,
argue with anyone, ever."
"Dan, you're in no position to
Then dan reluctantly agreed.
Argue with anyone, ever."
Now, prostitution in australia
Then dan reluctantly agreed.
is legal, so i spent the rest of
Now, prostitution in australia
the afternoon going through the
Is legal, so i spent the rest of
phonebook, trying to find a
The afternoon going through the
brothel with wheelchair access.
Phonebook, trying to find a
Best afternoon ever!
Brothel with wheelchair access.
[ Scattered applause ]
Best afternoon ever!
eventually, i found one, the
[ Scattered applause ]
biggest brothel in the southern
Eventually, i found one, the
hemisphere, the daily planet,
Biggest brothel in the southern
or, as the australians call it,
Hemisphere, the daily planet,
"four floors of whores."
Or, as the australians call it,
It's a 24-Hour brothel because
"Four floors of whores."
australia's a go-Ahead country.
It's a 24-Hour brothel because
So, we decided we were gonna go
Australia's a go-Ahead country.
early in the morning, like
So, we decided we were gonna go
really early, like 6:00 a.M.
Early in the morning, like
We wanted to go in when the
Really early, like 6:00 a.M.
place was quiet and we weren't
We wanted to go in when the
gonna cause a scene.
Place was quiet and we weren't
So, we wake him up at 6:00 in
Gonna cause a scene.
the morning.
So, we wake him up at 6:00 in
It's hard to tell if he's awake.
The morning.
And we get him in his chair.
It's hard to tell if he's awake.
Now, he hasn't got your
And we get him in his chair.
bog-Standard fucking wheelchair.
Now, he hasn't got your
He's got one of those big sort
Bog-Standard fucking wheelchair.
of silver-Looking things with
He's got one of those big sort
the truck tires on it.
Of silver-Looking things with
I think the model's called a
The truck tires on it.
hawking.
I think the model's called a
And even though his muscles
Hawking.
don't work, they get sore.
And even though his muscles
So, this thing can move him from
Don't work, they get sore.
side to side and back to front
So, this thing can move him from
and even into a full bed.
Side to side and back to front
So, we get him in the chair.
And even into a full bed.
Then we order a taxi.
So, we get him in the chair.
And then -- It's not like you
Then we order a taxi.
have black cabs out there.
And then -- It's not like you
It's like a normal car, but
Have black cabs out there.
they've modified the back to go
It's like a normal car, but
higher, and they drive him up
They've modified the back to go
through the boot and they strap
Higher, and they drive him up
him in there and he sits up
Through the boot and they strap
high, with windows all around
Him in there and he sits up
him, like a big, retarded
High, with windows all around
pope...
Him, like a big, retarded
or, as the catholics would say,
Pope...
the pope.
Or, as the catholics would say,
[ Applause ]
The pope.
and we drive up to the brothel.
[ Applause ]
Now, when we get to the brothel,
And we drive up to the brothel.
it takes 10 minutes to get him
Now, when we get to the brothel,
off the taxi.
It takes 10 minutes to get him
I see this as my window of
Off the taxi.
opportunity, so while they're
I see this as my window of
getting him off the taxi, i run
Opportunity, so while they're
into the brothel.
Getting him off the taxi, i run
Now, there's two ways that
Into the brothel.
brothels work.
Now, there's two ways that
Either the prostitutes will
Brothels work.
stand in a row in their lingerie
Either the prostitutes will
and you just pick the one that
Stand in a row in their lingerie
you want, or they'll stand
And you just pick the one that
around in a bar in evening gowns
You want, or they'll stand
and high heels and you walk up
Around in a bar in evening gowns
to the one that you like the
And high heels and you walk up
look of, chat to her for a bit,
To the one that you like the
act like you've got some type of
Look of, chat to her for a bit,
connection with an eastern
Act like you've got some type of
european woman, then take her
Connection with an eastern
upstairs and fuck her if you
European woman, then take her
need your life to be this
Upstairs and fuck her if you
delusional.
Need your life to be this
This is one of these situations.
Delusional.
So, while they're getting dan
This is one of these situations.
out of the cab, i run into the
So, while they're getting dan
brothel and go, "everyone,
Out of the cab, i run into the
quickly, gather 'round!
Brothel and go, "everyone,
I haven't got much time!"
Quickly, gather 'round!
And these 14 bemused hookers
I haven't got much time!"
shuffle over, and i went,
And these 14 bemused hookers
"look -- Here's the deal.
Shuffle over, and i went,
I have a severely disabled
"Look -- Here's the deal.
friend with me.
I have a severely disabled
If you're not up for it, speak
Friend with me.
now or forever hold your peace."
If you're not up for it, speak
And one of them went, "how bad
Now or forever hold your peace."
is he?"
And one of them went, "how bad
And i went, "[ chuckles ]
Is he?"
pretty fucking bad."
And i went, "[ chuckles ]
And 10 of them said they
Pretty fucking bad."
wouldn't do it, and i said,
And 10 of them said they
"well, i respect that, but can
Wouldn't do it, and i said,
you please go and hide?
"Well, i respect that, but can
Because i don't want him to be
You please go and hide?
rejected by hookers."
Because i don't want him to be
And these 10 girls shuffle away
Rejected by hookers."
in their evening gowns and their
And these 10 girls shuffle away
high heels, with gonorrhea
In their evening gowns and their
falling out of them.
High heels, with gonorrhea
I am now left with four girls.
Falling out of them.
The best-Looking one by a mile
I am now left with four girls.
stays.
The best-Looking one by a mile
Dan wheels in, looking like
Stays.
jabba the hut, breathing like
Dan wheels in, looking like
darth vader.
Jabba the hut, breathing like
Two of the girls run away, and
Darth vader.
i'm like, "are you fucking
Two of the girls run away, and
kidding, you sluts?
I'm like, "are you fucking
I just asked you nicely."
Kidding, you sluts?
So we're now left with two
I just asked you nicely."
girls.
So we're now left with two
The best-Looking one's there.
Girls.
The other one's a fucking troll.
The best-Looking one's there.
Now, out of respect for the ugly
The other one's a fucking troll.
one, i go to dan -- I go, "dan,
Now, out of respect for the ugly
there's only two girls working
One, i go to dan -- I go, "dan,
today, mate.
There's only two girls working
Which one do you want?"
Today, mate.
And he said, "the one in the
Which one do you want?"
green dress."
And he said, "the one in the
Now, neither of them had a
Green dress."
green dress.
Now, neither of them had a
I stand up and look at andrew
Green dress.
and went, "what the fuck is all
I stand up and look at andrew
this about?"
And went, "what the fuck is all
And andrew went, "oh, yeah, his
This about?"
eyes are fucked, as well."
And andrew went, "oh, yeah, his
Now, it turns out that dan's
Eyes are fucked, as well."
colorblind.
Now, it turns out that dan's
It's not part of the condition.
Colorblind.
It's just unfortunate.
It's not part of the condition.
So...i sat with the hooker.
It's just unfortunate.
Now, i'm gonna pay for
So...i sat with the hooker.
everything.
Now, i'm gonna pay for
Now, the reason i'm gonna pay
Everything.
for everything is simple.
Now, the reason i'm gonna pay
I told dan and andrew that i
For everything is simple.
would pay for everything, as
I told dan and andrew that i
long as i got to tell this story
Would pay for everything, as
to hundreds of thousands of
Long as i got to tell this story
people in the future.
To hundreds of thousands of
And they said, "of course you
People in the future.
can, jim, but be respectful and
And they said, "of course you
change our names," which sounds
Can, jim, but be respectful and
like the right thing to do, now,
Change our names," which sounds
doesn't it?
Like the right thing to do, now,
Now, i haven't changed their
Doesn't it?
names.
Now, i haven't changed their
Their names are andrew and
Names.
daniel connor from st kilda,
Their names are andrew and
melbourne, australia.
Daniel connor from st kilda,
I would have liked to have
Melbourne, australia.
changed their names.
I would have liked to have
It is the right thing to do.
Changed their names.
But i look at this way -- Even
It is the right thing to do.
if i changed their names and
But i look at this way -- Even
their parents started watching
If i changed their names and
my comedy, they'd be like, "my
Their parents started watching
word, doesn't 'randy' and
My comedy, they'd be like, "my
'steve' sound like our kids?
Word, doesn't 'randy' and
Didn't jim grow up with a lot of
'Steve' sound like our kids?
people with muscular dystrophy?"
Didn't jim grow up with a lot of
So, i sat there with the hooker,
People with muscular dystrophy?"
and i said, "how much for the
So, i sat there with the hooker,
half-Hour?"
And i said, "how much for the
And she said, "$180."
Half-Hour?"
And i said, "i'll give you $250
And she said, "$180."
'cause i realize this is a
And i said, "i'll give you $250
specialty thing you're doing."
'Cause i realize this is a
And she goes, "i got one
Specialty thing you're doing."
question for you," and i said,
And she goes, "i got one
"shoot," and she went...
Question for you," and i said,
"is he mentally retarded?"
"Shoot," and she went...
And i went...
"Is he mentally retarded?"
"oh, yeah.
And i went...
That's what i do.
"Oh, yeah.
I find mentally retarded people
That's what i do.
and take them to prostitutes.
I find mentally retarded people
I'll be masturbating in the
And take them to prostitutes.
corner.
I'll be masturbating in the
He doesn't even know he's here."
Corner.
And she went, "okay, then, but
He doesn't even know he's here."
if there's two of you --"
And she went, "okay, then, but
"No, he's not mentally retarded!
If there's two of you --"
It's his choice to come here!
"No, he's not mentally retarded!
There's a good chance he'll
It's his choice to come here!
die!"
There's a good chance he'll
And she went, "what am i meant
Die!"
to do with him?"
And she went, "what am i meant
And i went, "i don't know.
To do with him?"
I've never been a hooker.
And i went, "i don't know.
But i'm thinking give him a bit
I've never been a hooker.
of a show.
But i'm thinking give him a bit
Dance it around a bit.
Of a show.
Rub your tits in his face.
Dance it around a bit.
Then suck him off.
Rub your tits in his face.
But don't sit on him or fuck
Then suck him off.
him.
But don't sit on him or fuck
It'll kill him."
Him.
So, we go up to the room, which,
It'll kill him."
thank god, was on the first
So, we go up to the room, which,
floor.
Thank god, was on the first
And me and andrew look at dan
Floor.
like two proud parents, watching
And me and andrew look at dan
our child go to school for the
Like two proud parents, watching
first time.
Our child go to school for the
And then we leave.
First time.
And as we proceed to leave, i
And then we leave.
pat andrew on the back, and i
And as we proceed to leave, i
said, "andrew, you've been a
Pat andrew on the back, and i
good brother today."
Said, "andrew, you've been a
He said, "thanks, mate."
Good brother today."
Then we had a hug.
He said, "thanks, mate."
And then we had that moment
Then we had a hug.
after our hug that australian
And then we had that moment
men have, where we go, "ah, get
After our hug that australian
out of here.
Men have, where we go, "ah, get
What's wrong with ya?"
Out of here.
And then i said, "hey, andrew,
What's wrong with ya?"
how does dan get his clothes
And then i said, "hey, andrew,
off?"
How does dan get his clothes
And andrew went...
Off?"
"fuck!"
And andrew went...
And we went back in.
"Fuck!"
Andrew looks him up and down,
And we went back in.
and he turns to me and goes,
Andrew looks him up and down,
"look -- He's very fragile.
And he turns to me and goes,
I know how he likes to be
"Look -- He's very fragile.
picked up.
I know how he likes to be
I'll lift him up.
Picked up.
You take his pants off."
I'll lift him up.
Andrew gets behind, lifts him up
You take his pants off."
by his armpits -- Like i
Andrew gets behind, lifts him up
couldn't have figured out their
By his armpits -- Like i
magical hold.
Couldn't have figured out their
I'm on my knees taking dan's
Magical hold.
track-Suit pants off.
I'm on my knees taking dan's
He always wore track-Suit pants,
Track-Suit pants off.
never got into fashion.
He always wore track-Suit pants,
And as i'm taking his track-Suit
Never got into fashion.
pants off, what many of you are
And as i'm taking his track-Suit
wondering is, "can dan get an
Pants off, what many of you are
erection?"
Wondering is, "can dan get an
And the answer is, "yes."
Erection?"
Even though none of the muscles
And the answer is, "yes."
in his body work, the cock is
Even though none of the muscles
not a muscle.
In his body work, the cock is
The cock is a bit of skin that
Not a muscle.
fills with blood.
The cock is a bit of skin that
If he gets aroused up here,
Fills with blood.
blood will rush to there.
If he gets aroused up here,
Now, what nobody knew about this
Blood will rush to there.
32-Year-Old virgin is that dan's
Now, what nobody knew about this
packing heat!
32-Year-Old virgin is that dan's
I'm talking 9 1/2 inches of
Packing heat!
disabled misery.
I'm talking 9 1/2 inches of
This cock's so fucking big, i
Disabled misery.
think that's why the rest of his
This cock's so fucking big, i
muscles didn't work.
Think that's why the rest of his
I take the pants off.
Muscles didn't work.
This thing springs up and hits
I take the pants off.
me in the mouth.
Then the hooker goes, "let's do
the light."
Let's explain the light.
The light."
When they legalized prostitution
Let's explain the light.
in australia, they didn't
When they legalized prostitution
legalize it in all forms.
In australia, they didn't
For instance, you cannot get a
Legalize it in all forms.
street-Walking hooker.
For instance, you cannot get a
You cannot get a prostitute to
Street-Walking hooker.
your hotel room.
You cannot get a prostitute to
You can only go to a brothel, in
Your hotel room.
a safe environment, where they
You can only go to a brothel, in
have security for the girls in
A safe environment, where they
case a man shows up being a
Have security for the girls in
drunken dickhead or whatever.
Case a man shows up being a
And also it's safer for the
Drunken dickhead or whatever.
people that go to brothels
And also it's safer for the
because the girls get tested for
People that go to brothels
stds every month.
Because the girls get tested for
So, arguably, you're better off
Stds every month.
in australia fucking a
So, arguably, you're better off
prostitute than picking up a
In australia fucking a
girl in a bar.
Prostitute than picking up a
But i'm not gonna have that
Girl in a bar.
conversation again.
But i'm not gonna have that
All my -- You try explaining
Conversation again.
that to a girlfriend.
All my -- You try explaining
It's a fucking minefield.
That to a girlfriend.
But also they make it safe for
It's a fucking minefield.
the girls.
But also they make it safe for
If you're a guy who goes to a
The girls.
prostitute, you have to undergo
If you're a guy who goes to a
the light.
Prostitute, you have to undergo
Let's explain the light.
The light.
It's very simple.
Let's explain the light.
It sounds like what it is.
It's very simple.
You put your cock under a very
It sounds like what it is.
bright light, and they look
You put your cock under a very
around the shaft to see if
Bright light, and they look
there's anything untoward.
Around the shaft to see if
Then they get a magnifying glass
There's anything untoward.
out, go through your pubes to
Then they get a magnifying glass
make sure nothing's running
Out, go through your pubes to
around.
Make sure nothing's running
It's not a big deal.
Around.
I've been rejected heaps of
It's not a big deal.
times.
I've been rejected heaps of
Now, the chair's here.
Times.
There's a bed here.
Now, the chair's here.
There's a hot tub there.
There's a bed here.
The light's over there.
There's a hot tub there.
Now, we try to get the chair
The light's over there.
past the bed and the hot tub,
Now, we try to get the chair
but we can't get it through.
Past the bed and the hot tub,
So, me and andrew walk over to
But we can't get it through.
the hooker, and we're whispering
So, me and andrew walk over to
'cause we don't want dan to
The hooker, and we're whispering
hear.
'Cause we don't want dan to
We're like, "um...we can't do
Hear.
the light thing."
We're like, "um...we can't do
And she goes, "if you don't do
The light thing."
the light, i'm not doing it."
And she goes, "if you don't do
And me and andrew went, "aw.
The light, i'm not doing it."
Come on.
And me and andrew went, "aw.
He's a virgin.
Come on.
What's the worst that could
He's a virgin.
happen?"
What's the worst that could
And she whispered, "actually,
Happen?"
i'm more concerned about his
And she whispered, "actually,
cleanliness."
I'm more concerned about his
And then his brother andrew said
Cleanliness."
loudly and proudly, "i washed it
And then his brother andrew said
before we came out!"
Loudly and proudly, "i washed it
Now, you may think you're a good
Before we came out!"
brother, good sister, good
Now, you may think you're a good
mother, good daughter, whatever
Brother, good sister, good
the fuck you think you are in
Mother, good daughter, whatever
this world, but you're nothing
The fuck you think you are in
until you've washed your
This world, but you're nothing
disabled brother's cock to take
Until you've washed your
him to a prostitute!
Disabled brother's cock to take
That is love, ladies and
Him to a prostitute!
gentlemen -- Tangible fucking
That is love, ladies and
love.
Gentlemen -- Tangible fucking
So, we looked at dan.
Love.
Everyone agreed it was time to
So, we looked at dan.
go.
Everyone agreed it was time to
We looked at dan.
Go.
Me and andrew looked at him and
We looked at dan.
went, "we're going now, mate.
Me and andrew looked at him and
If you got anything you want to
Went, "we're going now, mate.
say to us, say it now, 'cause,
If you got anything you want to
uh, we're gonna leave, mate."
Say to us, say it now, 'cause,
And this is what dan did.
[ Imitates wheelchair whirring ]
"Leave!"
So, me and andrew went back down
to the bar, and we hanged out
with the hookers.
To the bar, and we hanged out
There was like 10 of them sort
With the hookers.
of mulling around there.
There was like 10 of them sort
We're standing there.
Of mulling around there.
We don't know what dan's up to,
We're standing there.
but we're standing around the
We don't know what dan's up to,
bar with all the hookers.
But we're standing around the
And then five guys from london
Bar with all the hookers.
walk into the bar, who are
And then five guys from london
obviously out of their fucking
Walk into the bar, who are
skulls on coke.
Obviously out of their fucking
Now, if you've never taken a
Skulls on coke.
lot of coke, and i've --
Now, if you've never taken a
[ Mumbles ]
Lot of coke, and i've --
if anyone's got any...
[ Mumbles ]
[ mumbles ]
If anyone's got any...
no, if you've never taken coke,
[ Mumbles ]
you don't -- When like five or
No, if you've never taken coke,
six guys get together and take
You don't -- When like five or
coke on, like, a tuesday, there
Six guys get together and take
comes a point at about 6:00 in
Coke on, like, a tuesday, there
the morning when they go, "we
Comes a point at about 6:00 in
better call up some chicks,
The morning when they go, "we
maybe --"
Better call up some chicks,
And you call up ex-Girlfriends,
Maybe --"
like, "bring some friends, bring
And you call up ex-Girlfriends,
some friends."
Like, "bring some friends, bring
And it's like -- I don't know
Some friends."
what you're expecting.
And it's like -- I don't know
So, basically, this --
What you're expecting.
I think it was a wednesday we
So, basically, this --
did this, and i think these guys
I think it was a wednesday we
had been on coke all night.
Did this, and i think these guys
And they've obviously gone, "all
Had been on coke all night.
right, let's go down the
And they've obviously gone, "all
brothel.
Right, let's go down the
We'll go down the brothel.
Brothel.
It'll be fun.
We'll go down the brothel.
We'll go down the brothel."
It'll be fun.
And i'm standing at the bar,
We'll go down the brothel."
chatting with all the hookers,
And i'm standing at the bar,
and these five guys from london
Chatting with all the hookers,
walk in, and one of them
And these five guys from london
recognizes me and goes,
Walk in, and one of them
"jim fucking jefferies,
Recognizes me and goes,
jim fucking jefferies.
"Jim fucking jefferies,
I know you, mate. I know you.
Jim fucking jefferies.
You're the comedian -- The
I know you, mate. I know you.
'spaz approved' guy, australian
You're the comedian -- The
comedian."
'Spaz approved' guy, australian
And i went, "hey, how you doing,
Comedian."
man?"
And i went, "hey, how you doing,
He goes, "hey, jim, jim, jim,
Man?"
jim, jim, jim...
He goes, "hey, jim, jim, jim,
want a line of coke?"
Jim, jim, jim...
And i went, "yes."
Want a line of coke?"
And i went up to the toilet
And i went, "yes."
and did a line of coke.
And i went up to the toilet
And i come back out, and,
And did a line of coke.
obviously, i've left andrew
And i come back out, and,
alone for too long, and he's
Obviously, i've left andrew
sort of panicking all by
Alone for too long, and he's
himself.
Sort of panicking all by
And i sort of walk in, like...
Himself.
"what's wrong?"
And i sort of walk in, like...
And he goes, "what if we've done
"What's wrong?"
the wrong thing here?
And he goes, "what if we've done
What if he's in there dying
The wrong thing here?
right now?
What if he's in there dying
What if he stopped fucking
Right now?
breathing or -- What the fuck --
What if he stopped fucking
Or his heart stopped?
Breathing or -- What the fuck --
What the fuck are we meant to
Or his heart stopped?
do?"
What the fuck are we meant to
I said, "uh, not a problem,
Do?"
not a problem.
I said, "uh, not a problem,
Um...
Not a problem.
i'll resuscitate him."
Um...
And he said, "do you know how to
I'll resuscitate him."
do that?"
And he said, "do you know how to
And i said, "no, i don't, but
Do that?"
how hard could it be?
And i said, "no, i don't, but
Push, push, blow, blow."
How hard could it be?
[ Chuckles ]
Push, push, blow, blow."
i haven't embellished that in
[ Chuckles ]
the slightest.
I haven't embellished that in
That's the exact thing i said
The slightest.
to him -- "Push, push, blow,
That's the exact thing i said
blow."
To him -- "Push, push, blow,
Then the prostitute walks back
Blow."
in the room, who was with dan.
Then the prostitute walks back
So, i'm standing with the 5 coke
In the room, who was with dan.
fiends, 10 prostitutes.
So, i'm standing with the 5 coke
She walks in the room.
Fiends, 10 prostitutes.
It's like that moment in a movie
She walks in the room.
where the needle on the record
It's like that moment in a movie
just sort of goes...
Where the needle on the record
[ imitates record scratching ]
Just sort of goes...
and everything stopped.
[ Imitates record scratching ]
And she walked in, and she said,
And everything stopped.
"well...it's over."
And she walked in, and she said,
And me and andrew, in unison,
"Well...it's over."
went...
And me and andrew, in unison,
"is he dead?"
And her exact words were,
"oh, i didn't check that."
So, me, andrew, the 5 coke
"Oh, i didn't check that."
fiends, the 10 hookers -- We
So, me, andrew, the 5 coke
all run to the room.
Fiends, the 10 hookers -- We
No, he's not dead!
All run to the room.
His chair's back in the upright
No, he's not dead!
position.
His chair's back in the upright
His cock is still sitting up,
Position.
majestically, covered in jizz
His cock is still sitting up,
and spit.
Majestically, covered in jizz
But for a man who an hour ago
And spit.
couldn't lift his eyelids, he
But for a man who an hour ago
was sitting there like this.
Couldn't lift his eyelids, he
[ Applause ]
Was sitting there like this.
now, you might be wondering why
[ Applause ]
his eyelids were up like that.
Now, you might be wondering why
Let me explain something.
His eyelids were up like that.
It wasn't through happiness.
Let me explain something.
Tell you something about myself.
It wasn't through happiness.
I'm 33 years old.
Tell you something about myself.
I've been masturbating since i
I'm 33 years old.
was 10 years old.
I've been masturbating since i
And in that time, i have not
Was 10 years old.
missed a day.
And in that time, i have not
Every single day, i masturbate.
Missed a day.
Haven't missed a fucking day.
Every single day, i masturbate.
Every day, i'm in a hotel room
Haven't missed a fucking day.
with a laptop way high up on my
Every day, i'm in a hotel room
chest here, so i don't have to
With a laptop way high up on my
look at the filth i'm doing to
Chest here, so i don't have to
myself.
Look at the filth i'm doing to
So, i'm watching porn here.
Myself.
And 9 times out of 10, i hit the
So, i'm watching porn here.
apple sign, right?
And 9 times out of 10, i hit the
[ Applause ]
Apple sign, right?
and i do this every single
[ Applause ]
fucking day.
And i do this every single
Yet i would be mortified if any
Fucking day.
one of you was to ever see me
Yet i would be mortified if any
doing this.
One of you was to ever see me
I would want to fucking kill
Doing this.
myself.
I would want to fucking kill
And i do this every single
Myself.
fucking day.
And i do this every single
Now, imagine if you've never
Fucking day.
ejaculated through the power of
Now, imagine if you've never
yourself, you've never had
Ejaculated through the power of
another person do it, you're
Yourself, you've never had
32 years old, and for the first
Another person do it, you're
time you've shot a load of
32 years old, and for the first
fucking stale jizz all over the
Time you've shot a load of
fucking room and you're sitting
Fucking stale jizz all over the
there with your cock out and 15
Fucking room and you're sitting
strangers walks in and you do
There with your cock out and 15
not possess the power to put
Strangers walks in and you do
your cock away.
Not possess the power to put
Can you see how that might be a
Your cock away.
bit unhinging?
Can you see how that might be a
So, we had to get him dressed
Bit unhinging?
quickly.
So, we had to get him dressed
But there's come everywhere.
Quickly.
And this time, i look him up and
But there's come everywhere.
down.
And this time, i look him up and
And i turned to andrew and said,
Down.
"andrew, i don't give a fuck how
And i turned to andrew and said,
fragile he is.
"Andrew, i don't give a fuck how
I'm taking the top half this
Fragile he is.
time."
I'm taking the top half this
And we lifted him up...
Time."
and we put his pants on and we
And we lifted him up...
proceeded to leave the brothel.
And we put his pants on and we
Now, as we left the brothel, i
Proceeded to leave the brothel.
turned to dan.
Now, as we left the brothel, i
I said, "dan, i paid for a
Turned to dan.
story.
I said, "dan, i paid for a
Please tell me what happened."
Story.
And he said, "well, she danced
Please tell me what happened."
around a bit, rubbed her tits in
And he said, "well, she danced
my face, and sucked me off,"
Around a bit, rubbed her tits in
which is what i asked her to do.
My face, and sucked me off,"
It's so nice to be a disabled
Which is what i asked her to do.
sex puppeteer.
It's so nice to be a disabled
But even nicer than that --
Sex puppeteer.
I used to have a preconceived
But even nicer than that --
notion on what i thought about
I used to have a preconceived
people such as prostitutes, man,
Notion on what i thought about
but i was wrong.
People such as prostitutes, man,
That woman treated him with
But i was wrong.
dignity and respect and made him
That woman treated him with
feel like a sexual being for the
Dignity and respect and made him
only time in his life.
Feel like a sexual being for the
And you can't put a price on
Only time in his life.
that, all right?
And you can't put a price on
Well, $180 is the -- The
That, all right?
exact -- The exact figure.
Then we go out front, and we go
to call a taxi, and the taxi
driver who drove us there is
To call a taxi, and the taxi
still sitting out the front in
Driver who drove us there is
his car.
Still sitting out the front in
And he winds his window down and
His car.
looks out and goes, "i'll drive
And he winds his window down and
you home for free.
Looks out and goes, "i'll drive
I just need to know what
You home for free.
happened."
I just need to know what
Thank you very much, ladies and
Happened."
gentlemen.
Thank you very much, ladies and
Good night.
Gentlemen.
[ Cheers and applause ]
[ Rock music plays ]
[ Speaking indistinctly ]
Hey!
she's an natural mover
ah
does it like a hoover
ah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah