I'm truly sorry,
but it's just that this is a really important opportunity for me.
Can you be understanding just once more?
All right.
Really? Really?
You're not upset, are you?
No, I'm not upset.
You're not lying, are you? Are you really okay?
Yes, I'm really fine.
Thank you Seo Jin. I really appreciate it.
Then I'll see you at home later. Okay?
I'm all right.
Really.
I'm really all right.
What? You're making a contract with YS entertainment?
Yes.
That's great news! It's a big company with famous celebrities.
People are finally realizing my talents as an actor now.
Really?
Right. Seo Jin.
I'm sorry for bailing on you today.
No, It's fine.
It was for work.
And you had to go through so much trouble without management.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Jun Ki, you might really become famous now.
Maybe I should get your signature in advance.
I've been practicing my new sign. Do you want one?
Sure.
Okay. In that case,
I'll give you my first signature.
Lee...
Gosh, I fell asleep.
Jun Ki, isn't it finished yet?
Just wait a bit longer.
- Then I'll go to my room now. - What?
I need to study to get my baking certificate.
Really?
When I'm done with this, I'll take it to your room.
Okay.
Now that the "Lee" part is over...
Jun...
(The Dancer in the Dark)
Yes, Father.
I'm going to sign the contract.
Don't worry. I've read the contract in detail.
Yes. I'll call you afterwards. Okay.
What did he say? Is he happy?
Yes. He doesn't show it,
but I can feel how happy he is.
I didn't expect this day to come.
You've finally turned your life around, right?
Right.
I went through a lot for 10 years while working as a nameless actor.
Well, you did go through a lot.
- You're going to act like that? - Tell me, you scum.
I got fired again.
With ink like this...
Gosh, even thinking about that is horrible.
- I'm going now. - Bye.
Where did Soo Ah go after making me answer...
all these inquiries on the shopping mall?
Du Shik! Du Shik!
- Look at this. - Why the fuss?
- What is it? - I designed it myself.
If we only resell products, we won't be able to go further.
So you want to sell clothes that you've designed?
Yes. Do you want to see it?
Look.
It's Soorgio Armhany 2018 SS vintage collection,
Ultra-V-Neck Sweater. What do you think?
Well, but why is the chest part so exposed?
Normal V-necks are so normal, and they're not sexy.
This one has the V-neck line further down just above the navel.
It emphasizes sexiness.
What do you think? Isn't it cool?
It's cool, but I think...
it's too exposed.
No, it's fine.
People like unconventional designs nowadays.
But why aren't you wearing it?
What?
You want me to wear it? Why?
You're the model. We should take a picture and upload it.
What? Me?
When, where, what, how, and why?
You should just do it if your boss says so.
- Be quiet, and follow me. - Why me?
I'm busy, you bad boss.
- Follow me! - No, it will show my naval.
What do you think? Do you like the conditions?
Yes, it's all good.
In that case, sign it.
Should I?
Lee...
Jun...
- Isn't it done yet? - Jun...
Ki...
It's done now.
Really?
I look forward to working with you.
Thank you. I look forward to it too.
So... See here.
The baby tiger and the daddy tiger...
lived together happily ever after.
The end.
Sol, what do you think the point of this story is?
The point of this story is "daddy".
Say "daddy".
Gosh, you're not easy, are you?
Sol, please say "daddy".
Just once? Please?
- Say "daddy". - What are you doing?
Nothing. I was reading a book for Sol.
What is that? It looks like something a cool beggar would wear.
What? A cool beggar?
It looks like it'd be really cool if you wore it.
Where did you buy that?
I didn't buy this.
Soo Ah designed this herself.
What? Soo Ah makes clothes now?
Yes.
That's not the end. She wants me to wear it around for publicity.
Gosh, Min Soo Ah is definitely crazy.
- I'm home. - Hello.
Hello. How was the contract?
It was okay.
What is that? It looks like something a cool beggar would wear.
He says Soo Ah designed it.
Isn't it funny?
It's so funny. I can see your naval.
You're so open-minded. Gosh.
Seriously. Stop.
What is this? Why did you stop talking when I arrived?
You were saying bad things about me, weren't you?
No.
We were complimenting your clothes.
He's right.
It's great. It makes Du Shik look so much better.
Really? Do you like it that much?
- What? - What?
Now, look at you two.
Be quiet.
What is this?
You guys look like three cool beggar brothers.
- Don't they? - They do.
You look cool and sexy, Dong Gu.
Why are you doing that, Yoon Ah? It's so embarrassing.
What is this?
But why is Soo Ah suddenly into designing?
I don't know. She's so passionate,
so I can't tell her it's weird. Gosh, it's driving me crazy.
But still, what is this? Gosh.
- Right, Yoon Ah? - Exactly.
It's a bit too extreme, right?
- It's... - Stop.
Hey, you were all here.
What is this? Why are you all quiet again?
You've been saying bad things about me, haven't you?
Of course not.
We were saying...
the sweater you designed looked awesome.
That's right. They look so sophisticated.
It's so pretty.
Really? You like it that much?
What is this?
The sleeves are...
just too long.
Oh, it's...
a part of Soorgio Armhany's 2018 SS Cutie Collection.
It's called Bongsan Number Five.
It was inspired by the Bongsan mask dance.
I see.
But aren't the sleeves a bit too long?
That's the point.
Existing hoodies look so boring.
By adding extremely long sleeves,
I gave the hoodie a cute look.
What do you think? Isn't it so cute?
It is. Thank you.
You're welcome.
Just wear it every day...
so people can see it, okay?
- Okay. - Okay.
- We will. - Of course.
Hello.
Yes.
What?
Me?
Okay.
Who was it?
It was the director of my agency.
Choi Min Sik was supposed to throw the first pitch,
but he caught the flu.
So the director wants me to do it instead.
- You'll throw the first pitch? - For a professional game?
- Yes. - Congratulations.
Only real celebrities get to do that.
I know.
I guess this is a perk of having an agency.
- I'll throw the first pitch. - I can't believe it.
Congratulations.
Let's go over first pitches that attracted a lot of attention.
Clara's leggings.
Cheng Xiao's 360° turn.
Shin Soo Ji's acrobatic first pitch.
After their first pitches,
their images improved by 13-fold.
And the awareness increased by 20-fold.
Really?
They hold a meeting for the first pitch?
A big company sure is different.
We need something new and different.
Do you have any ideas?
Jun Ki is playing an anchor in the drama.
He could dress like Sohn Suk Hee...
and throw a ball that looks like a microphone.
That sounds boring.
Do you have any other ideas?
No?
There are so many of us. How can we have no other ideas?
Honey.
What?
You want to learn pole dancing?
Sure. Do whatever you want.
Okay.
Hold on.
Pole dance?
Well...
You want me to practice pole dancing here?
The director doesn't want it to leak to the press.
Confidentiality is everything.
But a pole dancing first pitch just sounds weird.
I can't throw a ball while pole dancing.
It doesn't make sense.
What can we do? It's the director's idea.
Gosh, it's driving me crazy.
Should we start practicing?
I'll demonstrate for you. Watch carefully.
Okay.
Gosh.
What do you think? Doesn't it look easy?
No. I can't do this.
Please excuse me.
Come on. Practice makes perfect.
Let's start from hanging.
Hanging?
Be serious.
Use your arms. Try again.
It's hot. Hey.
Again.
Ma'am!
Help me! Ma'am!
Gosh, it's killing me.
Gosh.
After spending all day on the pole, my whole body aches.
Is this really necessary?
What can I do? It's the director's idea.
I'm worried you'll hurt yourself.
It's okay. This is such a great opportunity.
I... Gosh.
I'll work hard and become successful...
so that I can give you...
anything you want.
I'm so touched I want to cry.
Bacca.
I don't think pain-relieving patches are enough.
I need something else too.
What do you mean?
Gosh.
Why did you hit me?
If you have to hit me, do it with your lips.
Forget it.
- Don't be like that. - Stop.
We're not getting any orders.
Look at that.
I knew no one would want that sweater.
I hope no one I know sees this.
I'll have to ask Soo Ah to take down these pictures.
Soo Ah. By the way...
She seems pretty serious.
Did she fall asleep like this?
Gosh, it stinks.
What did she eat?
What?
Hey. What are you doing here?
I just came by.
What is it? Why are you laughing?
Well...
I just farted in my dream.
It felt so real.
Of course.
I'm sure it did.
Director Bong.
Have we gotten any orders for the sweater I designed?
Not yet.
Really?
Why isn't anyone buying it?
Is my design that bad?
It hasn't been exposed a lot yet.
Cheer up.
- You think so? - Yes.
Should we try to expose it more?
I have an idea.
What's that?
This is Soorgio Armhany's new product,
Ultra-V-Neck Sweater. Take a look.
Here.
Take a look.
It's so pretty, right? It looks amazing. It's so sexy.
Girls, take a look.
Thank you.
Come take a look.
Hey.
Thank you. We're Soorgio Armhany.
- Soo Ah, I can't believe you. - It was designed by me.
- This is just too much. - Soorgio Armhany...
- It's so embarrassing. - Ultra-V-Neck Sweater.
- You're getting the hang of it. - Right?
I became a lot better after practicing all night.
But I'm not sure if I can throw a ball while dancing.
Is that so? Do you want me to help?
I'm free today.
Really? That'd be great.
You're an angel.
- Let's have fun at the playground. - Okay.
Chae Rin, let's go to another playground.
- Jun Ki. - Yes?
Should we start?
Will you be all right?
You've never played baseball.
Don't worry. I'll be fine.
Throw the ball.
Are you sure? Then I'll throw it.
Seo Jin!
Seo Jin! Are you okay?
I'm okay. Try again.
- I'll try again. - Okay.
I'm sorry.
Hold on.
- I'm sorry. - You're doing great.
Do you want to try?
Designing clothes is not easy.
How long do we have to wear these?
It's so embarrassing.
Don't say that in front of Soo Ah.
She's working hard.
Still, this is just not okay.
No one would want this rag. Don't you think?
Maybe we should tell her the truth and make her give up...
for her sake.
We shouldn't just play along with her.
- I'd rather go naked... - Gosh.
Soo Ah.
I get it. That's what you thought.
- Soo Ah, it's not what you think. - I'm sorry...
for forcing you to wear rags.
Soo Ah. That's not what I mean.
- Soo Ah. - Listen, Soo Ah.
- Soo Ah. - Soo Ah.
I'm sorry, Soo Ah.
I didn't mean that you weren't talented.
Your clothes are so unconventional.
It's hard for me to look good in them.
He's right. Your clothes are pretty.
They don't look good because our bodies are ugly.
Forget it. You're right.
I can't be a designer.
- What's that sound? - There must be an order.
That's great.
- What? - What's wrong?
Look at this.
I have orders for the v-neck sweater.
- Someone ordered 5. - 5?
What? Someone also ordered the hoodie.
Some people buy them after all.
Didn't I tell you that unconventional styles were popular?
You know nothing about fashion.
I'm sorry. I didn't have an eye for it.
Right.
We should be honored to wear such amazing clothes.
Really? I have some clothes that I recently designed.
- Do you want them? - What?
What?
- Soo Ah. - Yes?
What kind of shorts are these?
They are a part of Soorgio Armhany's 2018 SS Sexy Collection.
They're called Ultra Fire Shorts.
I shortened the length of the shorts...
to focus on sexiness.
- What do you think? - They're nice.
They're sexy and cool.
They're embarrassing.
Soo Ah.
Aren't these too short though?
Come on, that's the charm.
I'm giving them to you as a special gift.
Wear it every day so people can see it, okay?
- Okay. - Of course.
They look great.
You'll do well today, right?
Of course. You helped me so much.
I have to do well.
If you came and cheered for me,
I would do better.
I'm sorry, but I have work today.
It's okay. Work can't be helped.
Instead...
- Ta-da. - What's that?
- Is it a mustache? - It's a lucky charm.
Give me your hand.
Even if I'm not with you, take a look at it.
Think that I'm always beside you, okay?
Thank you.
You know that I'm your number one fan, right?
Don't forget that I'm always cheering for you.
I won't.
I have another present.
What is it?
You can do it, Jun Ki. See you later.
I can do it.
- Have a good time. - Bye.
You can do it.
My goodness.
I have to go to the office.
How can I go while looking like this?
I should get changed and leave from the window.
Du Shik, may I borrow your laptop?
What are you doing?
Are you taking it off?
No, I was putting it on.
I really like your clothes.
Really? Where's Du Shik?
He went out to meet a friend for a while.
Yes, director...
I'm on my way.
I'll hurry. I'm sorry.
Are you going to the office? See you.
Thanks.
You should go. Make sure many people see it.
Okay.
- What is it? - I have something to take out.
See you later.
Where is the laptop?
What's this?
These are the clothes that you asked for.
Thank you.
What's Soorgio Armhany anyway?
Why do you ask me to order clothes for you?
I have my reason. I'm sorry for bothering you.
Are you wearing boxers? You look embarrassing.
Everyone is looking at you.
What? They look cute.
Unconventional style is popular these days.
Hey.
Do you want to try it on? Try it on.
If you like it, recommend it to other people.
Go on and try it.
- Are you embarrassed? Try it. - Stop it!
- Come on. - Keep it!
You can start over now.
You still have time.
Find work that will make you happy all your life.
- Will I make it if I try? - I'll help you with studying.
- You can do it, Soo Ah. - I can do it.
I'll start an online shopping mall.
It's Armhany.
- Shopping Mall Soorgio Armhany - Soorgio Armhany
How can I go home first when you're out here?
- Soo Ah, what are you doing here? - What?
- Nothing. Why? - Why are you annoyed?
I borrowed a game from a friend. Want to play and bet on noodles?
No, thanks. I'm tired, so I'll rest.
You're a pig.
What? Wait.
Pig? Where did that come from?
She's crazy.
Did you practice a lot?
Yes, I did my best.
Good job. I guarantee you.
If it gets aired, you'll become popular.
- Do a good job. - Yes, sir.
- Where's the outfit? - Yes, sir.
They're here.
Wait, why do you have this?
It's a great outfit. It's perfect for pole dancing.
Where did you buy this?
There's a shopping mall that's popular among the stylists.
- It's called Soorgio Armhany Mall. - What?
Is Soorgio Armhany Mall popular?
Yes, the owner is now selling clothes of her own brand.
The designs are amazing.
Isn't it unconventional and sexy?
Yes, I guess.
Good job on the interview.
Since work is finished,
shall we go somewhere to eat?
- Sorry? Actually... - Yes?
If there isn't more work to do, may I go somewhere?
- I have something to do. - Well... All right.
Thank you. See you tomorrow.
Goodbye.
You gave a shocking pole dancing performance today.
The viewer response is already amazing.
Where did you get the idea?
The president of my agency came up with the idea.
Many other people helped me...
so that I could give a better performance.
Seo Jin.
- Hello, sir. - What brings you here?
I was in the neighborhood, so I stopped by.
Pole dancing couldn't have been easy.
Wasn't it difficult?
Of course, it was, but many people helped me.
There's someone who helped me practice every day.
As I stand here,
I'd like to thank her very much.
Is the person your girlfriend?
It is, isn't it?
Pardon? Girlfriend?
No, I don't have a girlfriend.
Really? What's your ideal type?
I'm not sure.
Please support pole dancing.
Jun Ki is still the most searched.
"Pole dancing 1st pitch" is the 2nd most searched.
"I took a dump," is the third.
You got so popular.
Pole dancing worked, didn't it?
I had no idea that the response would be so positive.
Life is full of surprises.
There's one thing that makes me uncomfortable.
- What? - You don't have a girlfriend?
Do you not want to be alive any longer?
It's because the president...
told me not to tell anyone that I have a girlfriend.
He was so adamant about it, so I couldn't help it.
Seo Jin, I'm really sorry.
I should have told you beforehand.
It's okay.
It can't be helped.
Thank you for understanding.
Jun Ki. Why did you wear that outfit?
Aren't those the pieces Soo Ah made?
Actually, my stylist brought that outfit.
Apparently, Soo Ah's online shopping mall is really popular...
among stylists these days.
- What? Really? - I'm telling you.
Stylists are praising her and saying that she'll become...
the next Coco Chanel.
- Coco Chanel? Really? - Yes.
Gosh. I saw you do the ceremonial first pitch the other day.
I noticed you received a huge response. It was amazing.
Thank you.
I should be the one thanking you.
Thanks to you, our drama got promoted.
I was meaning to ask you. You saw the script, right?
Yes, of course.
How does it feel to play the opposing role of Cindy...
who's receiving unconditional love from middle-aged men?
It's an honor, of course.
By the way, who are all those people?
They're Cindy's fans.
So they're the middle-aged male fans I've been hearing about.
She really must be popular.
- Look. Cindy's here. - It's Cindy. She's coming in.
- Cindy. - Cindy.
- Stop them. - Cindy. Cindy.
- Cindy. - Cindy. Look over here.
(My Love, Cindy, Beautiful Cindy, I love you)
- Cindy. - Cindy.
- Cindy. - I'll love you forever, Cindy.
Now, this will be the next scene.
Hae Na, a rookie reporter, meets her first love, Song Jun Seok.
Hae Na notices her first love and runs to Jun Seok...
and throws herself into his arms.
- All right? - Yes.
Let's start shooting right away then.
We'll be starting the shoot now.
Ready and action.
Jun Seok?
Jun Seok.
What do you think you're doing?
Hae Na?
It's you, isn't it?
Jun Seok. It's been a long time.
Cut. All right. That was great.
- We'll move onto the bus scene. - Yes, sir.
I must've gotten lipstick on your clothes. I'm sorry.
It could happen.
Don't worry about it.
(May your career be filled with glory, Cindy.)
[VIU Ver] jTBC E19 Eulachacha Waikiki
"Terrifying Fans and Shocking Designs"
-♥ Ruo Xi ♥-
Why are they looking at me like that?
They're scaring me.
(Baking and Confectionery License Performance Test)
Almighty. Almighty.
Please help Yoon Ah pass the test.
Bring her luck.
I beg you. Please.
Gosh. That startled me.
Yoon Ah. Yoon Ah. I'm over here.
Did you finish the test? Did you do well?
What's wrong? You didn't do well?
No.
I think I made a lot of mistakes.
I get the feeling that I'm going to fail.
The results haven't even come out.
I'm sure you'll pass.
I really worked hard for this.
For Sol's sake, I really wanted to pass this test.
Why are you crying?
Don't worry. You'll pass.
Stop crying. Stop.
Dong Gu.
Gosh. Come here.
You'll be all right.
It's all right.
(Misfortune Always Comes)
Jun Seok.
What do you think you're doing?
Gosh. Jun Ki hugged Korea's sweetheart, Cindy.
Who would've thought this could happen?
Don't make a fuss. We were just acting.
Anyway, Seo Jin, it must bother you.
You must be jealous.
Why would I be jealous of that? It's just acting.
She's right.
Bacca's not that narrow-minded.
Right.
Let's eat at that restaurant...
we couldn't go to last time this Sunday.
That's all right. I know you're busy these days.
No. It's not just any other day. It's your birthday.
How could we possibly not celebrate?
I'll make it this time no matter what,
so make sure to keep your schedule open, okay?
All right. I will.
It's your birthday?
How can you not know your one and only sister's birthday?
That would be expecting too much from you, right?
I'm going to do some grocery shopping.
Hey. What's wrong with Yoon Ah?
I don't think she did too well on the license test.
She's been gloomy the past several days.
Then why don't you take her out and cheer her up?
I've tried, but nothing works.
Do you know any way I could cheer her up?
In that case, what's most important is...
for you to find a way yourself.
- I have a shoot to do. Bye. - Bye.
That jerk.
Jun Ki. I'm sorry.
I was on my way to pick you up when the car broke down.
It's all right. I can grab a taxi.
Don't worry about it. I'll see you at the set.
Taxi.
My goodness. Gosh.
What was that?
I'm sorry. Are you all right?
I dropped it by mistake while watering my plants.
You should've been more careful.
I could've gotten hurt!
I'm truly sorry. Please forgive me. I'm sorry.
Never mind. It's all right.
That scared me to death.
Taxi.
Welcome, sir.
Where would you like me to take you?
JBC broadcasting station, please.
I think I've seen you somewhere.
You recognize me.
You must've seen my pole dancing during the ceremonial first pitch.
Pole dancing first pitch? What is that?
Do you not know?
Then you must watch the drama "Newsroom".
"Newsroom"?
That's right. You're Song Jun Seok.
There was a scene where you hugged Cindy.
You even remember specific scenes.
You're right. That was me.
Would you like my autograph?
No, thank you.
I'll be going now then.
How could you get carsick from a taxi ride?
I don't even want to talk about it.
You wouldn't imagine how fast the driver was driving.
I thought I was going to die.
Come to think of it, it's strange.
Earlier on, a flower pot fell toward my head.
I could've almost died.
Today must be an unlucky day.
I guess so.
Hold on.
That taxi driver...
looked familiar.
There was a scene where you hugged Cindy.
Cindy. Milky-white Cindy.
That's right. It was him. He's one of Cindy's middle-aged fans.
What? The taxi driver was one of Cindy's middle-aged fans?
Yes.
He was one of the fans that came to root for Cindy on set.
Wait.
My goodness.
Are you all right?
Cindy!
Wait. That guy that dropped the flower pot was also Cindy's fan.
That can't be. You must've mistaken them.
No. I'm positive.
You don't think they're getting back at me...
for hugging Cindy in that scene, do you?
Gosh. That's nonsense.
I don't think the fans would harass you for hugging her.
Right?
Why would I? Why would I like Du Shik?
He's not good-looking and doesn't even have a good body.
But...
he is cute in his own way.
What am I saying? I'm crazy.
I must've lost my mind.
Get a hold of yourself. This isn't like you. What's wrong with you?
What are you doing?
Why are you looking at a picture of me?
I wasn't looking at it at all.
I was just erasing your pictures because you're so ugly.
What? You brat.
Never mind. Be quiet. Get out.
You're so ugly. I don't want to look at you. Get out, you pig.
What? Pig?
Hey. Why do you keep calling me a pig? Are you crazy?
I don't want to talk to you, so get out, you pig.
All right. I'll leave you, you fool.
Go on farting.
See? He's ugly and even has a bad temper.
But he is kind of tough.
He's sexy.
Wait. What am I saying? I've gone crazy.
No. This isn't me. This isn't me.
He's amazing.
(Song Jun Seok of "Newsroom" Pole Dances During the First Pitch.)
Good job.
(Actor Lee Jun Ki Is Currently Single!)
What do you think you're doing? You should be working.
It's Lee Jun Ki.
This guy is really popular these days.
You were a fan of Lee Jun Ki too?
Yes.
- You see, Jun Ki's my... - Yes?
No. I mean he's my brother's friend.
Really?
That's great.
Then I'll ask you for help if I need an interview.
- Sure. - Okay.
Anyway, I'm going on a date soon. What should I wear?
Is this the workroom of the rapper who's in charge of our soundtrack?
Yes, he's called MC Dacopy.
He's on the rise these days.
His raps are great.
Dacopy.
He's here. Hello.
What's up?
Long time no see.
Who's he?
He's Kang Dong Gu, the production assistant.
- Hello. - Nice to meet you.
- Put your fist up. - All right.
- Nice to meet you. - Let's get it.
How's the music going?
It's okay.
I heard that it's a spy movie in Dubai.
I've prepared some samples that fit the concept.
Do you want to hear them?
- Shall we? - Okay, let's get it.
Okay, let's get it.
Dubai, Dubai, Dubai, Dubai
How do you like it?
Isn't this Psy's "Champion"?
I think you just changed the lyrics.
What the... What did you say?
Are you suggesting that I plagiarized?
No, I just think it's similar.
Oh, my gosh.
Do you think it sounds like Psy's "Champion", Director?
No, it's totally different.
He doesn't know music.
Don't mind him.
Then I'll show you the next song.
Okay.
I never knew, but I knew
Dubai
I didn't know well
But don't send me to Dubai
Why's your expression like that?
Well,
I think this one sounds a lot like Big Bang's "Lie".
What are you talking about? It's totally different.
- What's wrong with you? - Well,
I thought that the rhythms were similar.
You're pickier than I thought. All right.
I'll give you something you've never heard of.
I wanted to change my style from traditional rapping.
I'll let you listen to it.
What? Have you heard of this too?
Well, no. No.
It's nice and new.
Yes, it's good.
We'll use this one.
- Okay, let's get it. - All right.
I'll work on it a bit more, and we'll discuss it more later.
Okay.
I went to Dubai
I already memorized it.
In this scene, Hae Na suddenly visits Jun Seok's house.
You need to look at him for a few seconds...
with watery eyes and then kiss him suddenly.
- Do you understand? - Yes.
We'll start shooting then.
- Let's make it as real as possible. - Okay.
We're shooting.
Get ready. Action!
Who is it?
Hae Na, what brings you here?
Jun Seok.
Come inside. We can talk inside.
- Oh, my. - Gosh.
Are you all right?
What are you doing?
I'm sorry, sir.
- Are you all right, Jun Ki? - I'm okay.
Cindy?
What's that? Cindy? Is he...
We'll start the kissing scene again.
All right.
Get ready. Action!
- Are you all right? - Gosh!
Cut. What's wrong?
- Jun Ki. Jun Ki, are you all right? - Yes.
Are you out of your minds?
What's wrong with everyone today?
Gosh, what's wrong so suddenly?
I'm sorry, Jun Ki.
It's okay.
Cindy?
Is he also...
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine.
We'll take a break until we have the light set up again.
- Take a break, Jun Ki. - Yes.
Something's not right. Something's going wrong.
Jun Ki, are you all right?
Something's wrong.
I think all the staff members are Cindy's fans.
Gosh, are you talking about that again?
It's not like that. I'm sure there's something.
Calm down and drink this.
Thanks.
What's wrong with this?
Hey, the expiry date was a year ago.
Really? I'm sorry.
I just bought it from the shop.
Gosh, it's fine.
Hey, I don't have anything to do on Sunday, right?
I have an important appointment.
- Sunday? - Yes.
Just wait a moment.
Sunday.
(My Love Cindy)
Cindy? My manager is... He's also...
- What's wrong? - It's nothing.
Are you all right? Do you want some coffee to wake you up?
No! I'll never drink that!
Why are you getting angry?
Jun Ki!
This is it.
Park Seo Jun is my style,
not Du Shik.
How can he be?
He's so handsome.
What's wrong?
You're out of your mind. Gosh.
Min Soo Ah, you must be crazy.
- What are you doing? - Gosh.
Why do you care what I do, you pig?
You're calling me pig again. Hey!
Why am I a pig?
You stupid, dumb sea animal!
She must be a psychopath. She's crazy.
Gosh, Jun Ki.
Why are you so pale?
Du Shik, I'm so scared.
She must be a psychopath.
Gosh, Jun Ki.
Why are you so pale?
Du Shik, I'm so scared.
What are you afraid of?
What? You think Cindy's fans are terrorizing you?
Yes. Every time something weird happens,
it involves her fans.
I think they're revenging on me...
now that we are in love.
Does that make sense?
You're paranoid.
It's not that! I'm certain something's going on!
You should just go to bed and get some sleep.
- You're just tired. - Really?
Maybe that's it.
- It's get better when I rest. - You should go and rest.
All right.
Gosh, it's so dangerous. It's dangerous outside this room.
It's dangerous.
(I'll kill you, Jun Ki. Cindy is mine. Get away from her.)
Jun Ki, what's wrong?
Look at this. Cindy's fans are blackmailing me.
Someone must have been in here.
I can't be safe even in my own bed.
Jun Ki, where are you going?
What's with him?
(Stay away from Cindy, or you'll be dead meat.)
(My Love, Cindy)
What are you doing?
I bought some sundae for you.
Thank you.
Are you still depressed about the exam?
No.
You have a lot of work these days, right?
Yes. I'm leaving for Dubai in a week.
I have a lot to prepare.
You'll be away for a month, right?
Yes.
I'll miss you and Sol so much.
Should I just not go?
Don't be silly.
I hope you'll have a safe trip.
I mean,
I'm worried I'll fall for another girl.
I'm just joking to make you laugh.
I'm sorry.
I met someone really funny today. Do you want to hear?
Who did you meet?
I met the rapper who is working on our sound track.
But all his songs sounded so familiar.
He copied Psy, Big Bang, and iKon's songs.
All he did was change lyrics.
Really?
What was his name?
MC Dacopy?
Oh, is he called Dacopy...
because he copies songs?
MC Dacopy?
What? You've heard of him?
Of course. He's my favorite rapper.
He's the one who inspired me to dream of becoming a rapper.
Really?
It's my dream to meet him.
Do you want me to introduce you to him?
Really? That'd be so fantastic.
My goodness. You're finally smiling.
Are you that happy?
Yes, I'm so happy.
Thank you so much. I appreciate it.
My goodness.
I can't believe it.
- Hi. - Hi.
Hi.
Jun Ki, you're here.
You must be tired. Do you want some coffee?
Sure. Thanks.
I don't want to drink it. No!
Why are you eating alone?
Let me join you.
I'm okay.
You have rice on your face.
Give it to me.
I'm saving it for when I'm drunk later.
Don't touch it!
Gosh.
Cindy...
You startled me.
Are you angry with me for something?
No.
Then why are you avoiding me?
You don't talk to me, and you ignore me when I say hi.
Did I do something wrong?
No, that's not it.
Tell me if I did something wrong.
I'll try to change. Please.
Are you crying?
The thing is...
What's wrong?
I think something went in my eye.
Really? Let me see.
Done. I've updated all our new products.
I'm so tired.
What is Soo Ah doing? Why are you doing all the work?
I don't know. She's so mean.
She never does any work, and she calls me a pig.
She's weird.
She's never been normal.
That's right.
Now that I'm finished,
I'll play with the number of viewers...
for "President Is Bruce Lee" a bit.
Hold on. "Lee Jun Ki" is the most searched word right now.
Do you think it's the Lee Jun Ki we know?
What's that?
"Cindy and Lee Jun Ki are dating."
"A secret date"?
What? What are you talking about?
Well...
(Cindy And Lee Jun Ki's Secret Date)
What's that?
I don't know. What's going on?
I'm back.
What are you guys doing?
Did you find something interesting? I want to see it too.
I want to see it.
Wait. What is this?
What's going on?
Did you kiss Cindy?
No. What are you talking about?
It's not true.
It's just a misunderstanding.
What's this picture then?
Well... She had something in her eye,
so I was blowing it out.
It's true.
Seo Jin, you trust me, don't you?
Is that right?
I knew it.
Gosh.
Who wrote this article?
Seo Jin, don't worry.
I'll make sure a correction is published right away.
Okay.
(CEO)
Hello. Have you seen the article?
It's a misunderstanding.
Nothing is going on between Cindy and me.
We should publish a correction right away.
"A correction"?
Why? Just leave it.
What? What are you...
Jun Ki. Who is Cindy?
She's the nation's little sister.
A scandal with Cindy will make you famous...
and bring you a ton of media coverage.
Still...
Stay quiet for the time being.
I'll make a comment at an appropriate time. Okay?
Well...
Sir?
It's driving me crazy.
Well...
(Lee Jun Ki and Cindy dating)
He's still on top.
More articles are coming out every second.
What did he say? Will they publish a correction?
Well...
The CEO wants to wait.
- What? - Well...
He thinks the rumor will make me famous.
He wants me to stay quiet.
Gosh, it's driving me crazy.
Is that so?
What can you do?
I'm okay. Don't worry.
Jun Ki, this is not okay.
How would Seo Jin feel?
She can't tell people you're his boyfriend,
and she even has to put up with your dating rumors.
Isn't that too much?
Seo Jin, I'm sorry.
I really am.
Don't worry.
It's not your fault.
By the way, when you hugged Cindy in the drama,
her fans went crazy.
With the rumors spreading, won't they try to...
kill you?
Right. I'm in trouble.
And we're celebrating Seo Jin's birthday tomorrow.
We can celebrate at home.
I've already booked a place.
And we can't just stay home on your birthday.
I'll figure it out.
We are going on a date tomorrow, okay?
Okay.
Unbelievable.
Let's get it.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Thank you for making time.
You're welcome.
I had no idea your girlfriend...
was my fan.
Neither did I.
Your music inspired me to dream of...
becoming a rapper.
But I've given up.
Really?
You dreamed of becoming a rapper?
Let's get it.
Now that you're here,
why don't you try recording something?
- Really? - Of course.
Give it a try.
It'll be a good time. It would be memorable.
Which song would you like to sing?
Your main song...
"Mapo Bridge" is my favorite. May I sing it once?
Sure, why not?
Go to the recording room. Let's get it.
Okay.
Yoon Ah, let's get started.
- Don't be nervous. - Okay.
Okay, let's get it.
It's the same as "Yanghwa Bridge" by Zion.T.
I can't believe this. Unbelievable.
I was always alone at my home
Mother was a bus driver
When I asked her where she was
It was always Mapo Bridge
Let's be happy
Don't be sad
Wait, Yoon Ah.
Yes, what is it?
Your singing reminds me...
of Zion.T.
You seem confused with "Yanghwa Bridge" by Zion.T.
This is my song, "Mapo Bridge".
It's not "Yanghwa Bridge". You know what I'm saying?
Yes, I'm sorry.
Don't ever sing like Zion.T, okay?
- Okay. - Let's start again.
Let's get it.
I was always alone at my home
Mother was a bus driver
When I asked her where she was
It was always Mapo Bridge
Let's be happy
Stop it, stop it.
You sound like Zion.T again.
This song is completely different.
Why do you keep getting confused?
Yanghwa Bridge and Mapo Bridge...
are at least over 1km apart.
There's Seogang Bridge in between. How are you confused? I mean...
Be happy... No.
Let's be happy
Is this so hard?
I'm sorry.
Let's do it one last time.
Okay.
Gosh, Bacca.
- You look so pretty today. - Really?
We haven't gone on a date in a while, so I dressed up.
- Do I look okay? - Yes, you look beautiful.
- Shall we go? - Okay.
I almost forgot. Wait.
- What are you doing? - In case reporters catch me,
the president told me to go outside like this.
Really?
Okay, let's go.
Let's go.
Welcome.
Do you have reservations?
- Chewbacca. - Please go that way.
Wait just a moment.
Here.
The chair is going in.
Thank you.
Anyway, will you keep those on?
What do you mean?
Oh, I should take these off.
You should order, Seo Jin.
I'll buy you everything that you want today.
Really? I'm so excited.
What shall I eat?
Yes, I just arrived.
The interview just ended. Yes.
Which room was it?
On the right? Okay.
Gosh, I'm sorry. I made a mistake.
It's okay.
What shall we eat? How about this?
Let's see.
Sirloin? Tenderloin?
Seo Jin, decide what you want.
- I'm going to the restroom. - Okay, go ahead.
Sirloin?
Pardon me.
You're Lee Jun Ki, right?
No, you're mistaken.
Come on, you are Lee Jun Ki.
I saw you sitting in the room.
Mr. Lee, could you say something about your romantic life?
Do you admit it?
- I'm not Lee Jun Ki. - Come on.
Then why don't you lower your mask a bit?
I'll let you go if you aren't him. Show me a little.
- Lower it a little. - Goodness.
- Wait, Mr. Lee Jun Ki. - Gosh.
Wait, Mr. Lee Jun Ki!
Why isn't he back yet?
(Jun Ki)
It's him. What's going on?
Jun Ki, why aren't you back yet?
Seo Jin, a reporter is chasing me.
I can't go back to the restaurant. What should I do?
What?
I'm really sorry.
Gosh, she's still chasing me.
See you later at home. I'm sorry.
Seo Jin, you're home.
I'm sorry about what happened.
A reporter was waiting for me in the hallway.
She asked me if the rumor was true. I couldn't help but run away.
I'm really sorry.
Seo Jin, I'm really sorry.
I have something to say.
You do? What is it?
Let's take some time to think.
What?
"Take some time to think"?
What do you mean by that?
I mean...
we should reconsider our relationship.
What?
What's wrong with him?
"Yanghwa Bridge" and "Mapo Bridge" sound the same.
He's the one who copied the song. Why did he take it out on you?
Yoon Ah, cheer up.
He was the one who was acting strange.
It's okay.
I gave up on being a rapper anyway.
Dong Gu.
Why can't I do anything well?
I can neither bake nor rap.
Come on.
Don't think so negatively.
I'm sorry.
I know that you're trying to cheer me up,
but I can't cheer up.
You can't do this anymore.
Yoon Ah, I prepared something for you.
What is it?
Yes, get it
The first wound stays in the heart, the tears fall
Even if you're lonely or sad
Don't cry
My dear Yoon Ah
What are you doing, Dong Gu?
Look at my eyes
Forget about MC Dacopy
Erase everything, and run
Run toward your dream, just go
Where?
Let me start over. Again.
Just Go
You're laughing, right?
Then you're feeling better, right?
It sure is hard to cheer you up.
Gosh. That was embarrassing.
Why? You're a good rapper.
I could never be as good as you.
Gosh, Sol. What do you think about my rap skills?
(Ms. Han Yoon Ah, Congratulations. You've passed the test.)
Why? What is it?
I passed the test.
I passed the baking license test.
Really?
You see? What did I tell you? I told you you'd pass the test.
Congratulations, Yoon Ah.
Thank you.
Wait a minute.
We should celebrate on a day like this.
Let's have a party.
Wait here for a minute. I'll go buy a cake, all right?
Dong Gu.
Yoon Ah.
(Welcome to Waikiki)
What? Sol's father's here?
Why are you here?
Daddy.
Blood really must be thicker than water.
I'd like to take care of Yoon Ah and Sol.
After all this time, you want to take care of them now?
I still love Yoon Ah.
This won't change anything.
But it won't change the fact that I'm Sol's father.
I want to ask you for your forgiveness. Is that wrong?
Why do I keep thinking of Du Shik? Why?
You're crazy, Soo Ah.
You've completely lost your mind.
- My stomach. - What's wrong? Are you sick?
Is there a Bong Du Shik here?
I have something to say to you.
I think I...
I thought I was a strong person, but I guess I'm not.
You mean you're going to let go of a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity?
You should move out of there first.
- So? - I'm breaking up with Seo Jin.
I'd like to tell you all the truth...
about the romance rumor between Cindy and myself.