Hey, Kevin, time to get up, buddy.
- Gotta roll.
KEVIN: I know.
- What time is it?
- Can you get up?
- Four-thirty, man.
- Okay.
- How long do we have?
- Five minutes. Living the dream, baby.
- Nick. What's up, buddy? Gotta roll.
- Ugh.
- Four-thirty, man. Get up. All right?
- I know.
One more minute.
All right, I'm up.
Hey, Joe. Gotta get up, brother.
You gotta move.
- Dude, go away, man.
- Gotta go.
- No, I'm sleeping. I'm sleeping...
- Let's go.
- Why did you hit me, man?
- Get up. Time to go.
Okay, so here's today's schedule.
At 7 AM., you...
Earthquake. Just kidding.
- Ugh.
- Aftershock.
- I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry. Thank you. Yes.
Do you have any peach jelly?
- Um, seven-thirty, we...
SERVER: Yes.
- Ah, didn't see that.
... are leaving for rehearsals.
At 8:12, "Burnin' Up"
with the anchors onstage.
- Hey, Joe, are you listening?
- Yes. Pancakes, please.
KEVIN:
Nine AM., post-show taping.
Nine-fifteen, finish
Good Morning, America.
Then we depart for Central Park
to finish our music video.
We film it in 3-D.
Three-thirty PM., CD listening party
at the Highland Ballroom.
Psst. Hey.
KEVIN: Perform about three songs.
And then 5 PM., interviews.
How long was she standing there?
Five seconds.
She was... Joe, she was standing
there because you're like:
"Can I have the jelly, please?
Like, do...?
Do you have any waffles?"
KEVIN
"Pancakes will do. "
Dude, did you see her buy
the quake joke?
That works every time.
You've been doing
the earthquake thing since, like, third grade.
Stop playing.
- What's wrong with earthquake?
Sorry, Big Rob. Okay.
- Stop doing that.
It's awesome.
Guys, you're gonna play with
more earthquake games again.
Three to 4, Kevin picks
up some new pajamas. Oh!
You got... You showed him.
"Whoo-hoo.
Aftershock. Can I have your number?"
- What are you wearing?
- Yo, guys, we got to go.
Are we late?
- Yes, let's move.
- Where are we going?
- Thank you.
KEVIN: Joe, just follow.
- Which way?
This way, assuming?
KEVIN: Living the dream.
- Let's go.
This is a mess. Do you see this?
This goes all the way
down to Broadway.
- Unbelievable.
- Yes, I just beat my high score.
We're gonna be late.
Big Rob, this traffic's killing us.
We're on in another hour, guys.
- There's nothing we can do.
- Helicopter?
- Already on it.
Nice.
- Big Rob.
KEVIN: Nicely done.
- Yes, sir. Tenth and Broadway.
- That's so close.
Yeah, but we're gonna
have to leave the car here.
Guys, I put this car on my credit card,
and why are there fans here?
We got trouble.
KEVIN: How did they find it was us?
- Big Rob!
- No!
Earthquake!
KEVIN: Not now, Joe.
We have to get out of here.
- Look, I can't get out, Big Rob.
Stay inside.
Where's Big Rob going?
I'm trying to get out of the car.
Stand back.
KEVIN: Let's go through the roof.
Let's try it. Ready?
Kevin!
It's Nick.
Come on.
- Big Rob, come on.
- Go, go. Save yourselves.
Oh, my God.
Go, go.
Oh, no!
Nick. Kevin.
Open.
I love you.
KEVIN: Joe.
- How did you get here so fast?
- Don't worry about it. Get in.
Jonas! Jonas! Jonas!
Joe, I love you!
Sing it out.
Come on.
Sing it!
How's everybody doing tonight?
Welcome to the Burning Up Tour,
everybody.
We are the Jonas Brothers.
And I think it's time
that we get this party started.
Listen, girl.
You gotta be good.
You see, I don't wanna hurt you.
I wanna kiss you.
Come on. Come on.
Come on, Kev.
Come on, come on.
I'm gonna need your help.
Sing it out with us, okay?
Here we go.
How about just you?
Come on.
One more time.
- Come on.
Yeah!
There are a lot of fans down there.
Oh, my God. That's so crazy.
- In back.
Look how far they're over there, guys.
There's even more there.
But go fresh.
I really wanna accentuate
the eyes on Big Rob tonight.
Uh-oh.
Still coming in too. It's crazy.
KEVIN:
Look, they're waving up here. See?
From the early days of Beatlemania,
to the overnight sensations
of the '70s,
to the choreographed
boy bands of the '90s.
As long as there have been teen idols,
there have been teen-idol fanatics.
But the Big Apple has never seen
dedication quite like this.
Twenty-four hours.
Can I borrow this?
Oh, my God!
I can't believe it.
Can you tell your mom you're okay?
- I'm okay, Mom.
See? Everything is fine.
Touching Joe was just, like, ahh!
That's not fair. I didn't get to touch him.
He missed me.
Okay. It's okay. It's okay.
I was shaking the entire time.
Oh, my God.
Ready?
They're bodacious.
Seriously, I don't know what I'm
gonna do. I'm gonna throw up.
Like, I've dreamt about this day
so many times.
Oh, my God.
Joe. Joe. Joe.
Kevin. Kevin.
Kevin.
We flew from Florida, just to see them.
This used to say, "Florida. "
- I love you, Joe! I love you!
- I love you!
We love you.
If the Jonas Brothers are gonna see this,
we really wanna meet you.
I love you, Joseph!
KEVIN:
What's going on, everybody?
We are so happy to be with you tonight.
Are you having fun so far?
All right. You know what?
I think I like that. Let's clap our hands.
Are you with me?
Okay. Joe, take it away, bro.
Now, we're gonna have
a little drum competition right now.
Between the two drummers up top.
We're gonna see how many drumsticks
Jack Lawless,
over here on drums, can catch.
And Nick J's gonna throw them.
But we're gonna need
your guys' help.
I love you!
All right?
So on the count of three
he's gonna throw them.
We're gonna need your help.
One, two, three.
Oh! So close.
I think I need you to scream
a little louder than that. Come on.
One, two, three.
There you go.
Madison square Garden.
Greatest city in the world.
The Jonas Brothers fans
never get to touch the Jonas Brothers.
- We're the next best thing.
- We're the Fake Jonas Brothers.
If you can't meet the real ones,
- why not meet the fake ones?
- They're usually pretty pleased.
Jonas Brothers are living the dream.
And we're dreaming the life.
Jonas! Jonas! Jonas!
- How are you, guys?
- I'm Fake Joe.
- Hi.
- Hi, I'm Fake Nick.
- Hi, Fake Nick.
- Nice to see you. All right.
I'm Fake Kevin.
Look, it's Zac Efron.
Yeah, I can't believe
you came to the show.
Fake Zac.
- It's so good to see you, man.
- Fake Efron.
You were so awesome
in the Shanghai...
No, not Shanghai.
What's it called with Jackie Chan?
FAKE KEVIN: Rush Hour.
Rush Hour, man.
That was tight.
- That wasn't me.
Kelly Clarkson doesn't even have
a Fake Kelly Clarkson.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, well done.
He's our fake dad.
- Yeah. Whoo!
- Yeah.
- Fake Kevin senior.
- He had Nick hair.
You're from spain, huh?
Are the Jonas Brothers popular in spain?
A little, a little.
Could you say, "I love the Jonas Brothers
more than my wife" in spanish?
Yes, I love.
What?
One, two, three.
All right, now it's your turn.
Come on, everybody!
Ladies and gentlemen,
give it up for our friend Demi Lovato.
Come on, girl.
Ladies and gentlemen, Demi Lovato.
AsslsTANT:
Come on, guys, come on.
KEVIN:
Come on, guys, hurry up.
Jonas! Jonas! Jonas!
KEVIN:
Okay, guys, we have 30 seconds.
- It's stuck in my hair.
- Whoa!
- Hey.
AsslsTANT: Oh, man.
Two, three.
This song
is for every broken heart,
for every lost dream.
For every high,
and for every low.
And for every person
who's ever felt alone.
And tonight,
this song...
This song's for you.
Now, here's what I want you to do.
Want you to clap your hands...
There you go.
- And I want you to sing this out with me
as loud as you can.
With all of your heart,
with all of your soul.
Ryan, would you join me?
Sing it.
Just you.
Two, three.
I'm Joe Jonas.
- One, two, three. Showtime.
All right.
Thank you.
I need to see you clap your hands
like this, come on.
All the way to the top.
- Are you ready?
- Yeah!
Here we go! Yeah!
Hey, Joe?
You think they're ready?
Here we go. We're about to leave
for Times square. Tsk, tsk, tsk.
Whoo!
This is gonna be real out of control.
Do what we gotta do.
Walk out. And that's...
You know what I mean?
- Just stick to us like white on rice.
I will.
- Oh, my gosh.
- It goes all the way.
Oh, my goodness.
DENlsE: I can't believe this.
Oh, my gosh.
It's New Year's Eve.
I've never seen anything like this.
Oh, my gosh.
It's the Jonas Brothers New Year.
This is incredible. Oh, my gosh,
there are so many people here.
Excuse me.
I love you, I'm here for you.
I love you, Joe.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Yeah, you can't go back there.
Anytime, guys.
Here, have another one.
Kevin.
First copy.
This is madness.
Yeah!
Thank you!
Thank you, everybody!
Thank you very much.
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
Ladies and gentlemen,
please give it up for our friend
Taylor swift, everybody!
Come on, sing it with us!
Ladies and gentlemen, Taylor swift!
Thank you very much!
Hot dogs.
SOs.
All right, keep clapping
those hands. Come on. Come on.
One, two, three, yeah.
Thank you!
Oh, my gosh.
That's enough. Let him go, please.
Guys, move back.
Move that truck!
Move that truck! Move that truck!
I gotta move.
Move that truck!
Clear the street. Clear the street.
Behind the barricade, please.
Get behind the barricade.
You, back. You can't be there.
All right, everybody clap their hands
like this. Come on.
Keep it up, all the way to the top.
Come on, girl.
Give it up for Big Rob!
Ladies and gentlemen, Big Rob.
We're gonna take this time
to introduce
these amazing people behind us,
everybody,
starting with my main man
Jack Lawless on drums.
Jack, show them what's up.
Come on.
Everybody, give it up
for Greg Garbowsky on the bass.
KEVIN: I got Ryan Liestman
on keyboards.
Give it up for my main man
John Taylor,
our musical director, on guitar.
Give it up one more time for our beautiful
and talented string section.
Everybody, Big Rob one more time.
Come on.
Thank you so much.
My name is Kevin Jonas.
Thank you for having me tonight.
One last time, my name is Nick Jonas.
Thank you so much for having us.
Thank you, everybody. I am Joe Jonas.
And we are the Jonas Brothers.
One, two, three.
KEVIN:
Hey, watch it, Joe, hey.
Watch it, Brad. Hey. Hey.
That was so cool.
Let's watch it again.
This 3-D's amazing.
I can almost touch the audience.
Big Rob,
do you have any more popcorn?
- All gone.
- Oh, man.
Hey, you in the red shirt, I see you.
Can you...? Can you give me
a little popcorn, please?
By BackFire