(Episode 21)
-Completed Episode-
www.facebook.com/IKSubs
I will
accept our breakup.
You don't have to come back to me.
But be a father to Saebyeol.
You must tell Sejin.
Tell her about Saebyeol
and get Sejin to accept her.
And openly be there
for Saebyeol as her dad.
I came here to tell you that.
Do I have a twin sister?
You hid my twin sister
somewhere out there in this world, right?
Why are you overreacting?
I was just joking.
I mean, someone insisted he met a woman
who looked exactly like me.
Okay.
Okay, I won't make jokes like that again.
I'll see you soon.
What is it? Your mother got angry?
She did, and now I feel even more suspicious.
What if there's a secret behind my birth?
Maybe there is.
What?
There are lots of people with secrets like that.
That's why so many TV dramas and movies
use birth secrets as a plot device.
I have a secret behind my birth, too.
What is it?
Oh, no...
You should've been more careful.
You'll cut yourself. Move.
You never make mistakes like this, so what's wrong?
I know.
Would you like some tea?
No, I'm fine.
Dohui hasn't come home yet?
She's on her way.
I...
I really don't like him.
Mr. Park's son, I mean.
With all the rumors about him,
I don't want him as Dohui's husband.
You're her mom, so you'd say that about any man.
Leave it up to Dohui.
I'm going to bed.
You should, too.
Mom.
Did you meet up with her?
You weren't late?
You weren't rude?
Why didn't you drive her home?
You must have been dying to call me.
I fought the urge,
since I didn't want you to complain.
I'll answer your questions now,
so pay attention.
I wasn't late. I showed up on time
and met with her.
I don't remember doing anything rude.
I was going to drive her home,
but she declined, so I didn't.
Happy now?
How was the girl?
You're going to see her again?
I was just doing it for father's sake.
There's nothing more to it,
so don't get your hopes up.
Your father will be suspicious,
so meet her a few more times, okay?
Oh, I'm hungry.
I'm hungry. Can you fix me something?
You didn't even have dinner?
You should've had a delicious meal together.
The chicken feet didn't have much meat.
Let me go get changed.
At your age, you should be eating your wife's food,
not your mom's food.
Oh, don't say that.
Mom's cooking is the best.
This is getting hard for me.
Do you know how many years your father's been sick?
If I didn't have to worry about you, I could relax.
I'm not a kid. Why worry about me?
How can I not?
You're such a softie
that you can't even take what's rightfully yours.
Sejin is tough,
but her future husband seems really ambitious, too.
That's great.
I'm afraid of them pushing you out.
Your big sister
is dying to get rid of you,
so if your father passes away, what will you do?
Don't worry.
I won't let you starve.
It may not be an extravagant life,
but I won't make you suffer. So relax.
You think I'm afraid of starving?
I wouldn't be acting this way
if there was another person in the world
who was on your side, other than me.
Wouldn't it be great if you had powerful in-laws
who could help you when you needed it?
Oh, this is terrible!
What does she do to her chicken?
There are fried chicken places everywhere,
so why do I only like Yang Malsuk's chicken?
Hello?
Well, who might this be?
You're still alive and breathing?
I didn't heard from you for so long,
I thought you were dead and buried.
What? Who?
Why are you asking me about him?
You didn't let me see him for the last 20 years.
You said he'd be better off without a mom like me.
What did you do to him
to make him leave his dad and never call?
Whatever! Bye!
Oh, I'm so upset.
If he took after me,
he must be pretty handsome.
Manjeong, you've had a wretched life.
You don't even know your own kid's face.
Did he really meet her?
Are you sure?
Your son never tells lies.
And from now on,
you can't lie, either.
He went on a blind date,
so you want me to change his position at work?
Of course.
What's with that face?
That's your stubborn face!
What is that?
Not every blind date leads to marriage.
Set the wedding date.
And if the woman agrees to wear a wedding gown,
Hwigyeong can move to a different position.
Honey!
And have Dr. Ju
prepare to discharge me from the hospital.
Is today the Day of Stubbornness or what?
It's too early!
I know my body best.
So go and tell him.
I can't skimp on onions for Onion Chicken,
but onions are expensive these days,
so I won't make any profit.
Who put a newspaper in here?
(Baekdo Group's chairman's granddaughter...)
If Taejun didn't work there,
I'd be praying every day
for that company to go bankrupt.
Of all places, why did he get a job at Baekdo?
(Her fiancé is a Baekdo employee, Kang Taejun)
Ms. Yang.
Why are you acting like this? What have you heard?
Nothing's been decided yet.
Aren't all marriages the same way?
We're not like other families,
so we don't know until the ceremony...
Oh Manjeong,
you've been deceiving us up till now?
That woman... Today I'm going to get her!
Oh Manjeong!
Right, if you want to stay alive,
you can't show your face.
You have to hide and avoid my calls
if you want to live.
Your call is being forwarded to...
(Moving Company)
Right, if I do this,
you'll have to come and see me.
What? What is mom doing?
Why are we all meeting here?
What have I done wrong recently?
No, I haven't been out drinking lately,
because I'm on a diet.
Did you two get into trouble?
Are you stupid? Must you ask?
Oh, no...
Mom's seen the article, right?
The article about Taejun? Right?
Did you think you could keep it from me forever?
Mom...
We didn't.
We didn't keep anything from you.
Nayeon, tell me the truth.
If you don't want me to go crazy,
tell me the truth.
Why is Taejun
marrying that Baekdo woman?
His wife and child are right here!
So why is he marrying another woman? Why?
Mom.
It's not like that. It's a misunderstanding.
I'm a reporter, too,
and sometimes we make mistakes.
So ignore it, mom. Just ignore it.
You think I can trust you girls?
When you all got together
and deceived me?
You tell me.
That it's not true.
That it's not happening! Tell me!
It's true.
It's all true, mom.
That cursed company Baekdo...
After getting my children's father killed,
they're taking Taejun from you?
I'm going to go there and...
Mom, please don't do this.
Mom, reacting this way won't help!
Mom, please calm down.
Getting upset won't help!
Go. You go
and bring Taejun back,
or go to that woman's house and resolve this!
Tell them you're Taejun's wife,
and that he has a daughter,
and bring Taejun back! Hurry!
Mom, please.
Taejun has his reasons.
He needs time, too.
Saebyeol...
What about Saebyeol?
He'll turn his back on his child?
I'm going to protect Saebyeol.
I'm going to get Saebyeol's dad back.
I'm going to do that, mom.
You gave him
everything you had
and the best years of your life,
and look at what happened...
All you have left are tears...
How will I face your mom in the afterlife?
How?
Mom...
Mom, I'm sorry.
Mom, I'm so sorry...
Nayeon...
- That jerk... / - Don't cry.
It's okay.
This is the list of companies
Baekdo is looking at for mergers and acquisitions.
And these companies are not on the list,
but I'd like you to review them.
You've been interested in tourism?
I think it's one area
where Baekdo's combined power
would yield the greatest effect.
Okay. I'll review it.
Thank you.
Have you met your child?
I saw her for a bit.
That must have affected you.
Do you see the mother sometimes?
I'm sorry.
She must be in a state of shock.
She'll need time to process it.
Refrain from meeting her.
And keep it a secret from Sejin for now.
This would be such a big shock for her.
I'm sorry.
It's "Yes, sir," not "I'm sorry."
That's the answer I want.
Wow!
Mr. Kang, you've become a big star.
Everyone is talking about you in management.
What are you talking about?
The material you presented at the last meeting
was distributed to everyone!
About selling AP Foods,
which the president and chairman are opposed to.
Right.
Everyone's been walking on eggshells,
but you said what needed to be said,
so imagine how happy they must be.
You're being too kind.
I just did what needed to be done.
If the article is true,
your wedding must be coming up soon.
Have you told Sejin about Saebyeol yet?
Saebyeol is your daughter,
and she comes first.
Don't keep her a secret.
If you can't tell Sejin, I will.
(Delete message)
Which bed will make us happier
when we wake up every morning?
Wouldn't this smaller bed
keep us closer together?
I want this one, mom.
The color's not too flashy,
and the size and height are what I wanted.
And it's not too hard or soft.
You never use that many words.
What? What are you talking about?
You always had a big bed
so you could sleep like a queen.
So why are you going for the shabby one?
You find this kind of color boring,
and you think the frame is old-fashioned.
Why has your taste changed overnight?
You're acting like a total stranger, Sejin.
This kind of simple style works well
in a newlywed bedroom.
It's the harmony that's important.
It might work well for Taejun,
but it doesn't work well for you!
Why are you tainted?
Why must your taste be spoiled
because of that jerk? Why?
Mom!
"Tainted"? "That jerk"? How can you say that?
We're shopping for me and my future husband.
You've given me permission to marry him,
and now we're planning the wedding together.
So why are you doing this again?
Just get the one I picked!
I have better taste than you!
It's mine, so I'll decide.
The bed is for me and Taejun,
so I'll choose it.
Excuse me.
Can I buy this bed right now?
Of course, ma'am.
- How many do you have? / - Excuse me?
How many do you have available?
Outside the display model, we have one in storage
and one at the factory.
Then I'll buy all three.
I'll buy them all, so let me pay.
And take all of them apart
and throw them away.
Mom!
Hello?
It's me. Sejin's mom.
Hello, mother.
I need to see you, so I'm coming to your area.
Don't tell Sejin about this.
Yes, mother.
I'm sorry for making you wait.
Have you waited long?
I didn't interrupt your work, did I?
No, I've finished all urgent business.
I ordered tea while I was waiting.
You should order something.
It's okay. I've already had some.
What did you want to tell me?
Open it.
I'm not paying you to break up with Sejin,
so don't get nervous.
I'm so relieved.
I'm not giving that to you because I like you.
I don't want Sejin
to be affected by your cheap taste,
so I want you to fill up your wallet.
Do you know why I said no to you?
Because of your eyes.
Others might say they see
spunk, spirit and ambition in your eyes,
but I don't.
It's an inferiority complex
and greed from wanting to overcome it.
That's all it is.
And Sejin fell into that trap.
You have a keen eye, mother.
You're correct.
I grew up so poor
that I always feel inferior.
I've worked very hard
to get over my inferiority complex,
but it's not easy.
Actually,
I've been getting over it after meeting Sejin.
When I'm with her,
I'm so full of confidence.
So I was even more determined not to lose her.
You're really something.
Sejin is your daughter.
I know I can get along with you
considering how much I love Sejin.
And I don't need this.
My taste led me to choose Sejin.
And that proves
that I have pretty good taste.
Don't make excuses,
and just put it in your empty pocket.
What a sly jerk.
Sejin fell for him because she's so naive.
Then again,
he's better than someone stupid.
You should try smiling.
When did you get here?
Just now.
I wanted to have dinner with you,
so I got some food.
I worried that you'd say you were too busy to eat.
I went to a department store today with my mom
to look at beds and had an argument.
Why? Why didn't you humor her?
It's true that couples develop similar taste.
Your taste has become mine.
Don't mind me, and go with what your mother wants.
Okay.
Go get washed up. I'm hungry.
Okay, I'll do that.
(Mother)
Well...
Is this Taejun?
I can't believe
how heartless she is!
This is crazy!
What kind of life is this?
Why is every day worse than the one before?
Do you know what Yang Malsuk did to me?
She used the measly deposit money
on the rooftop apartment to kick me out!
Come here and do something about it!
Your mom's going to freeze to death!
Hello? Taejun?
Are you listening?
I'm sorry.
Taejun can't take your call right now.
Oh, my!
Who is this?
Hello, I'm Jang Sejin.
I'm sorry I have to say hello on the phone.
Oh!
Are you the young lady
who's going to marry my Taejun?
Yes. I'm sorry I haven't been able to see you .
It's okay.
You have such a pretty voice.
I'll tell Taejun to call you back.
Okay. Good night.
(Missed call from Nayeon)
What are you doing?
Nothing.
What is it? Your morning sickness?
It's okay. I can handle it.
Oh, no...
Did you break up with that woman?
Almost.
Almost? It hasn't happened yet?
Why is she so persistent and pathetic?
Why can't she play it cool?
She needs time to process it.
I know it's hard on you, but please give me time.
But I'm worried.
What if she tries to hold onto you
and ends up ruining our wedding?
The reporters are dying to find trouble,
so what if they find out?
I'm so worried and afraid.
I'm on pins and needles!
Why can't you understand? Why not?
Mom, it's because bears have thick fur.
What are you talking about?
Bears have such thick fur
that when it's too warm,
they feel hot and get angry.
My teacher told me that.
Daddy Bear might be angry
because you're too warm to him, mom.
Bears are like that?
I didn't know.
I should study harder, right?
Now you know, so it's okay.
Hello?
Who is this?
I don't know how to introduce myself.
You can just say it like it is.
I'm Kang Taejun's fiancée.
Our wedding is coming up soon,
and I want to meet you before that.
Can we?
There's no reason why we can't meet.
Right.
There's no reason.
Then let's meet now. Right now.
There's no reason for us to stall.
Right. There's no reason for that.
Yes, I know that place.
I'll see you in an hour.
Yes? Saebyeol?
Hello?
Yes.
Who is this again?
Hello.
I'm the person you called earlier.
My prediction was wrong.
I thought that
you'd be shocked and scared to hear from me.
I was worried for no reason.
Are you upset because
I'm not scared or shocked?
I see why Taejun's having trouble letting you go.
This is actually great.
You seem gutsy enough for a decent conversation.
Don't worry about your child.
We will take full responsibility.
Responsibility?
How will you do that?
Tell me what you want.
You can take your child abroad.
That would be smartest thing for everyone.
But if you don't want that,
you can give the child to us
and make a fresh start.
I'm sorry,
but that's not what I want.
What I want
is for my child to get her one and only dad back.
That's all.
You're saying that
you want to steal Taejun from my daughter.
But I'm not the one who stole him.
If someone has to get hurt,
it won't be my daughter,
because I will stop it.
You must love your daughter so much.
I never felt like this before.
I am so angry at my dad,
whom I never met.
I envy Sejin
for having a father.
You are
nothing I like expected, either.
When I first got your call,
I had a glimmer of hope.
I thought that you of all people
would understand my situation
and make the right decision.
Because you were like that 20 years ago.
20 years ago?
It's natural for you not to recognize me.
The girl
who was sent to an orphanage
for stealing your wife's jewelry 20 years ago
is all grown up.
It's natural that you wouldn't recognize me.
Are you...
Nayeon?
Please help me.
Stop this wedding.
If you bother Sejin and give her a hard time,
you won't get away with it.
She asked you to meet up?
She wants to see you?
You have to keep hiding,
so I can have fun looking for you.
Compared to how I feel about you,
it's cheap.
Thanks.
The owners of this company
are going to be my in-laws.
I'm not really attracted to you.
So let's focus on our deal.
I'm confident that I won't fall for a man.
Taejun isn't coming back.
He's not the Taejun we used to know!
Taejun.