2017, New Year's special.
This is the second part of Zero Base, Three No's.
Survival without power.
The Tribe faces an obstacle from the beginning.
They must cross the ocean using only manpower.
And the Tribe does not give up.
They remove a part of the tambak ikan and make a raft out of it.
They finally arrive on land after much difficulty.
We're on land.
However, their happiness doesn't last long.
The darkness surrounds the Tribe and they're terrified.
Didn't they say they'll give us light if we catch something?
The only way for them to get some light...
is to catch a living creature.
Would the jungle family manage to catch something...
in the dark?
Hold on.
(The Chief looks determined.)
I'll go in the water.
Really?
(He's planning to go in the water when it's this dark?)
Make sure you leave this on.
- I have to know where I am. - Okay.
Can you see?
It's blurry. I can't really see.
The night ocean is pitch black.
The Chief sets out to find a prey.
Meanwhile, what are the rest of the members doing on land?
Shouldn't you go this way?
(They're also busy looking for something to catch.)
- There's something here. - It's a crab.
(Crab?)
I just saw something.
If we catch this,
would you turn on the light for us?
(He's obsessed about getting the light.)
(It runs away.)
It went in.
It went in the hole.
(Their only light of hope disappears.)
These guys are so small. We can't catch them.
- It's a mini crab. - They're too tiny.
I'm hungry.
(They had taken power for granted in the city.)
We have no power so we can't do anything.
(They have to keep working to get some light.)
- Gong Myoung. - Yes.
Did you catch anything?
No.
- You have nothing? - No.
They caught something. Come here.
(They caught something.)
(Is it a prey?)
They caught something. Hurry up.
They'll give us electricity.
(Chief's flashlight shines through...)
(the rocking waves.)
Did you catch something?
What did you catch?
(Chief is their hope.)
I caught something unique.
(His net looks heavy.)
Did you catch something?
What's that?
(Swinging)
I think we should ask though.
- Is this fish? - What is it?
(The Chief is persistent.)
- What's that? - It's edible.
What is it?
(He takes it out of the net.)
- What's that? - What's that?
(It's a bizarre looking creature that resembles a stone.)
- Is this alive? - It is.
(They're on full alert.)
For goodness' sake.
- These are the eyes. - This is the mouth.
- It looks sad. - It looks like a person's face.
(it's almost arguing that it's alive.)
It looks like a stone.
How did you find it?
It's a fish.
I don't know if it was poisonous...
or felt confident in itself. It wasn't moving at all.
I hit it a few times and it flinched.
That's when I knew it was alive.
My goodness.
We caught a living creature so are you going to turn on the light?
- Turn on the light. - Turn on the light.
(Give us light.)
We approve.
(It's a successful hunt.)
(They turn on the light as promised.)
(They haven't seen light for a while.)
(That's too bright for my eyes.)
(It feels like they can finally live again.)
(Thank you for your patience, viewers.)
Is this how we looked?
I...
couldn't handle being in the dark.
We have light.
(The light shines on Cheng Xiao.)
- We caught a unique creature. - What is it?
I wonder how the inside looks like.
(We call it the stonefish.)
- Stonefish? - Stonefish.
(Why is the Chief surprised to hear that?)
Aren't stonefish venomous?
Yes, they are.
- They're venomous. - Imagine if you got stung.
What is this strange creature...
that shocked the entire jungle family?
They're difficult to tell underwater.
They look like stones so they're called stonefish.
This is the first time we've come across them on the show.
It has 14 venomous spikes on its back.
It's the deadliest venom of all fish, and...
it is also known as scorpionfish.
It also sheds its skin every 50 days.
It sure has a strange ability.
It looks like a coral underwater...
and lives hidden in it.
Be careful, jungle family.
Imagine if I got stung by it.
I'm getting scared.
(She takes a step back.)
The venom is deadly.
(Good thing he handled it with caution.)
Let's not eat it.
(It starts dancing at the news.)
(Chief puts it back in the net.)
Thank you. Bye.
- Bye. - Bye.
(They're still sad to let it go.)
- The stonefish gave us light. - Bye.
- I won't see you off. - See you again.
(They're thankful.)
Give a round of applause to our Little Aunt.
Thank you.
(They give him a round of applause.)
(Chief is tonight's hero along with the stonefish.)
Thanks to the Chief, who caught the stonefish in the dark,
the light finally comes on.
They can now make out the various features of the island.
Before it's too late, they must secure a shelter.
I'm hungry.
Let's go.
(The coconuts are way up high.)
It's too high.
Would you be okay?
I'm okay.
Locals have carved holes in the tree so it's okay.
Go slowly.
(He reaches the top in no time.)
Move away.
Move.
(When did he reach the top?)
(Twisting)
Hey, take it.
(He starts throwing coconuts down.)
My gosh.
- He has regular shoes on, right? - Yes.
How did he get up there?
(Chief drops them...)
(and Gong Myoung picks them up.)
(Cracking)
(Five coconuts)
That's six.
(Seven coconuts)
He's incredible.
Be careful.
(Chief moved all day from making the raft and hunting underwater.)
(Gasping)
(He must be getting tired.)
- You can stop. - Come down.
Okay. How many was that?
- There are 8. - There are 8.
(He picks a total of nine coconuts.)
Be careful. Slow down.
(He finally climbs down the tree.)
(Sliding)
But...
(He's exhausted.)
I'm starving.
- He must be tired. - You're the best.
Let's gather them.
Wash them and take one each.
How do we carry them?
- It's heavy. - It's no joke.
It's different from the ones before.
I want to try carrying it.
- We're good, right? - Let's go.
Can we put them down here?
Put it down here.
- I'm thankful. - Da Hoon, put it in the middle.
Should we make a table?
How?
(They bring the big stones to the center.)
- Lift it. - Turn it around.
- Like this? - It looks so nice.
(It goes on top of the stones.)
(We need chairs for the table.)
(Here are more chairs.)
- Here? - You're so strong, Gong Myoung.
- It looks amazing. - Doesn't it look good?
(They try to make it as cozy as possible.)
(They decorate the house with antiques.)
- It looks like a perfect table. - It's perfect.
This is worth 5,000 dollars in Gangnam.
I want to take it home.
Can I take it home?
We'll light the fire.
- Me too. - Go ahead.
(They're hoping that the weather will be warm tonight.)
Blaze it up.
(This is going to be a new Sol Bi.)
(She tried to look smart yesterday by lighting a fire.)
(She wants to be like Wonder Woman.)
Why wouldn't it work?
I did it at home.
(Big Aunt was being mean to her after her continued failures.)
(She ended up being humiliated.)
Seriously.
(Nothing worked out as she had hoped.)
(I'll show you today.)
I want to look different and be like Wonder Woman.
I want to do everything.
(Sol Bi is about to transform.)
(Sparkling)
(She looks so cool.)
(Her eyes are on fire.)
(She's fully concentrated.)
Give it to me.
(He comes out of nowhere.)
- Let me try. - I want to try it.
(Sleepy thought it looked cool.)
(Don't touch me.)
Don't light it.
(She's not fazed.)
Let me try it.
(He has no idea what's going on.)
Is there paper?
(Sleepy's ambitious trial begins.)
(Sparkling)
(Here I go.)
(He slows down.)
(Here you go.)
(Sorry for annoying you.)
My hands. My hands hurt.
(Sol Bi goes at it again.)
Why is it not lighting up?
It's not easy.
It took 30 minutes to an hour yesterday.
(He's on her side.)
All right.
(He blows on the flame for her.)
What's wrong?
(He even puts his hand by the fire.)
All right. Keep going.
(Sol Bi earned herself a good assistant.)
(I'm the leader today.)
- It worked. - Turn it around.
Don't blow too hard.
(Da Hoon cheers them on.)
It goes out so quickly.
No way.
Don't you have a notebook?
(That's what everybody wanted to ask.)
Did you use it up?
(They were all gone yesterday.)
Where's her notebook?
Should I try?
No, I'll do it.
She won't give up the notebook.
(Will she become the Wonder Woman today?)
I'll teach you something. Look.
Let's learn from him.
(Chief's field trip lesson)
This is how it hangs from the tree.
Since it hangs like this,
the meat is near the bottom.
You shouldn't be cutting the top. When you buy it from a stand,
they cut the top off to make it look nice.
But if you cut the bottom, the meat comes out easily.
If you just want the coconut water,
cut here...
(He puts it to practice.)
(The meat shows itself as soon as he strikes down.)
It's different.
(He's fascinated.)
It's soft.
If you poke at it, it'll spurt out.
(Spurting)
(It's just as the Chief said.)
What was that?
Cut around it.
(He did as he was told.)
(The senior student discovers his love for learning.)
It should taste better than water.
(All they had this morning...)
(was squid.)
(They thought they were going to turn into squids themselves.)
(They longed for fruits.)
Drink all the water first...
and cut it in half.
(He gulps it down.)
Split it.
(It's soft to swallow. A sense of refreshment rushes over him.)
(Let me taste it, too.)
(My goodness.)
(The drink liberates him. A sense of refreshment rushes over him.)
I was so hungry. It's nice to drink something sweet.
(Everyone's interested in drinking it.)
- Here you go. - How did you do that?
(Pupil Gong Myoung wants to learn.)
(Master Byung Man wants to teach.)
Watch your hand.
(The inside is covered by the endocarp.)
(It escapes.)
- You can eat that. - What is it?
- This is... - You're throwing it out?
No. This is edible as well.
Every part of this fruit tastes different.
Coconut milk is made with this part.
(He stores this information as well.)
(We need something to chew.)
This tastes different.
(He recommends it.)
(How delicious will this taste?)
Try it.
(He wrinkles his face.)
I don't like this.
(They start spitting out.)
I agree.
(Byung Man wouldn't give it to us if it wasn't delicious.)
How does it taste?
It tastes weird. Have you tried it?
(He's puzzled.)
- Is it tasty? - It's spoiled.
Give me some.
- Sleepy, this is really delicious. - I'm hungry.
- What is it? - Try it.
(He doesn't hesitate to try.)
(It's yucky.)
(He won't accept any returns.)
Everyone should taste this at least once.
We should taste two or three times.
(He forces himself to eat.)
(Sol Bi is still struggling with the fire.)
I will succeed by all means.
(I will dedicate my everything for this moment.)
(I've risked my body and spirit to keep this fire.)
(I will get rid of my former reputation and make a new one.)
(I yearned for...)
(a fire.)
- You did it. You did it at last. - I lit the fire.
(Sol Bi finally manages to start a fire.)
You did it at last.
(What a surprise.)
Sol Bi and Cheng Xiao are good at making a fire.
It's hard without the wax droppings.
(What a victory for Sol Bi.)
Before the fire goes out,
let's make it big.
(Let her reputation to be changed.)
The fire got onto the wood. It's amazing. It caught onto the wood.
- You did it at the end. - Cheng Xiao.
Forget her reputation as a dummy.
She devoted herself to make a fire.
(Sol Bi started this fire with perseverance.)
It will keep them warm and chase away bugs.
Her preparation is at last paid off.
This is so beautiful and the coconut...
I guess you come here for that.
(Sol Bi also drinks it.)
My gosh. This tastes so good.
It's delicious.
It's filling me up a bit.
No matter where we are, being on the land is the best.
Of course, it is.
- We can make a big fire. - This is...
the plainest meal in the jungle.
(It's the plainest meal.)
However, I'm so happy.
- Land is the best. - It is, right?
We all have a fickle mind.
Look. Look at this.
Look at this.
(She seems to have found something.)
What is it?
(Everyone focuses as she calls them.)
(It moves very quickly.)
- Is it a crab? - No, it's not.
- A lizard? - It's a lizard?
Do you want to eat it?
(Look!)
It went to the stomach.
(Let me inspect it.)
- It climbed. - I got it.
- She's amazing. - It's too fast.
- How can she catch with her hands? - I know, right?
You're great. Don't bring it near me.
(He refused to be introduced.)
- Stop it. Please don't. - She sure is brave.
- Give it to Sleepy. - Jin, this is a gift for you.
I don't need that sort of gift.
Stop it. I'm really scared of it. It really scares me.
- Jin, you are my senior. - I'm not your senior.
- The tide is rising. - It's coming near us.
Shouldn't we unpack?
(What kind of tact will the Chief take?)
Da Hoon.
Let's only get the bottom.
Okay.
Do you want that?
(What is 'the bottom' the Chief referred to?)
(They bring the barrels from the shore.)
Bring these barrels.
He plans to use the raft that they brought...
as a wooden bench.
(They stick in the barrels to lift the bench from the ground.)
Their efforts...
to cut and bring the raft has finally paid off.
I had no idea...
that we would be dragging this raft along.
We don't know what will happen tomorrow. Let's hunt.
- Okay. - Let's do it.
(They are about to hunt putting confident Sol Bi in the lead.)
Is it out of battery?
I kept spinning it.
(It takes labor to survive. Surviving without power is a labor.)
- Should we get going? - Where are you going?
Join us.
I searched online, and...
- My goodness. - Gosh.
- What a surprise. - My goodness.
(Did they find something to hunt already as they just set out?)
(Wobbling)
(A snake-looking creature is on the branch.)
- It's my bag. - What is it?
- It's my bag. - You scared me.
I was startled to see it on the branch.
Why did you hit me in the stomach?
I should've brought the straw cutter.
(He's saying anything.)
- Wait. I meant the knife. - I agree. We're blocked.
- My goodness. - What? What is it?
- Why? - What's wrong?
- It's a snake. - Really?
(Sleepy gets away at an incredible speed.)
(He's terrified.)
(An unwelcome guest shows up.)
- Be quiet. - I'm so scared.
- It's a real snake. - Let me see.
- Come here. Don't go near it. - Snakes are really fast.
(Reticulated pythons are one of the few snakes that prey on humans.)
Where is it? Where?
- Stop. - Don't go near it.
- It's amazing. - It is not venomous.
(Goodness)
(It splits its mouth open to mark its boundary.)
I'm terrified.
We must catch it or do something. It might come to us when we sleep.
Gong Myoung, you are too brave.
It's disappointing if we don't continue. We came this far.
Something is moving.
- What is it? - What is this?
Birds lay eggs on the ground.
- Birds? - On the ground?
There are eggs on the ground. Since there are eggs,
- be careful. - There are a lot of bird eggs.
- There are so many. Look. - They do it in groups.
If eggs are here,
then snakes must be here as well.
- They might be here. - Right.
What if there are snakes here?
- What? - What is it?
(They are a tall coward and a good-looking coward.)
(They are in perfect unison.)
- What's the matter with you? - It's so scary here.
- I want to go home now. - So do I.
Since they are scared,
they decided to go back for the night.
Can all of us sleep here?
Two of us will have to sleep on this side.
We're lucky to have this wooden bench.
- Yes, we are. - We certainly are.
(He's spinning the generator at this hour?)
(To save is to live well?)
Since it's the end of the day, we can use the speaker.
(The speaker?)
We can listen to music.
(Last night, for his family members who were all tired...)
(Hey guys, I have music.)
(He played music with a portable speaker and acted as a DJ.)
(Thanks to music, they felt better and it relieved their stress.)
(In order to listen to music, he must charge the battery first.)
(Will it work?)
(Perseverance and patience are needed.)
(They start to lose interest.)
(My gosh. It will strengthen my muscles.)
(Music starts.)
- It's starting. - My gosh.
Da Hoon. Thank you. Please continue spinning.
- Thank you. - Spin it all night long.
(Isn't good to listen to music?)
Can you hold this?
(He pairs up with Cheng Xiao.)
It's charging. The light is red.
- It's charging. - The red light is gone. It's back.
(Spinning)
When the light turned blue, the lyrics matched.
- Lower the volume. - The volume?
If it's loud,
- wouldn't it take more energy? - Would it?
- Should we try it? - Okay. Let's turn up the volume.
(It stops.)
Let's turn up the volume as high as it can go.
(It only lasts for a moment.)
What happened?
(What's the matter with this?)
Spin it.
- Give it to us. - Let's take turns.
- We can't even rest for a moment. - Then, it will stop.
Let's switch every 15 minutes.
It's like keeping a night watch.
We should listen to music at the end of the day.
- It's starting again. - Where did you go, Seung Hun.
Should I do it now?
If we spin it slow, will it stop?
(He's trying his best.)
If we keep this up...
I want to listen to just one song. Don't stop.
It's so different from yesterday.
(Do we have to listen to this song?)
You can do it.
(As they try to listen to a song,)
(they get exhausted.)
This is...
The battery's out.
Let's just sing. There are so many singers here.
Let's listen to it live.
(He's disappointed.)
No, stop it. Don't do it.
I'm hungry again.
We still managed to listen to it for a bit.
We did it without any power.
Good night.
- Good night. - Good night.
(Tonight's music stops here.)
You can put your head there.
(They are getting ready to sleep.)
- It's cold. - You'll sleep there?
(Little Aunt decides to sleep on the ground.)
(The sisters lie down side by side.)
(Buzzing)
(A mosquito shows up around Sleepy.)
(Exhaling)
Are there a lot of mosquitoes?
(A mosquito might've gone into her mouth.)
(As they acquired land, they also acquired mosquitoes.)
We have to still fight with bugs here...
even though I'm fully covered.
(Even her feet are covered.)
I covered myself completely.
(She covers Cheng Xiao's face for her.)
(The veteran, Byung Man, is covering himself.)
(Meanwhile...)
Mosquitoes must survive as well.
I think of it as the mosquitoes having their meals.
(Gong Myoung is a philanthropist.)
I want to sleep and I will.
I will sleep as I become the mosquitoes' prey.
(He has an extreme environment-friendly attitude.)
(Since they were exhausted, they fall asleep quickly.)
(At that moment when he's about to fall into a deep sleep,)
(he moves.)
(He scratches.)
(He takes turns scratching his right and left foot.)
(He's bitten by a mosquito again.)
(It's itchy.)
(I can't endure it anymore.)
(All the mosquitoes must die.)
(Please let me sleep.)
(Is Sleepy scratching again?)
(This time, it's Gong Myoung.)
(Did the mosquitoes change their target since he asked for it?)
(They attack Sleepy, Gong Myoung, and Sol Bi at the same time.)
(Everyone's scratching as they sleep.)
(Even Byung Man is scratching.)
(Who do you think I am?)
(He starts to hunt the mosquitoes.)
(In the meantime, Da Hoon is soundly asleep.)
(Byung Man gets up at last.)
(He's moving his mouth.)
Are there a lot of mosquitoes?
Yes, a lot of mosquitoes are here. It bit my lip.
(His upper lip is swollen and bulging.)
(Gong Myoung and Cheng Xiao are tortured constantly.)
It bit me on my lip.
(Byung Man tells Gong Myoung about the mosquito bite.)
(I have a lot to say as well.)
(I have so many mosquito bites.)
(He's about to cry.)
He had an interview before he went to sleep.
He said confidently that he will donate his blood to the mosquitoes.
Mosquitoes must survive as well.
(He looked confident a few hours ago.)
I can't sleep.
(Byung Man scratches his lip and Gong Myoung scratches his ankle.)
(These two can't sleep for a while.)
(I can't let this happen.)
(The Chief moves his sleeping spot.)
(He's fully prepared next to the fire.)
(Okay, then I will prepare myself as well.)
(Hopefully, you will sleep well.)
After a long battle with mosquitoes,
(They are bound to sleep somehow.)
their first morning on land has come.
(A new day has started again.)
(He gets up.)
(Da Hoon gets up first.)
Why did you get up so early?
(Sol Bi is the second one to wake up.)
I usually wake up early.
(The early bird...)
Most of the time...
(The early bird spins the generator?)
I wake up early even at home.
(He spins it unconsciously.)
Did you get bitten during the night?
I don't have a single bite. Not even one.
(He slept well.)
I guess I belong on land.
I didn't get bitten at all.
(Groaning)
(Jin gets up, covering his face.)
(I'm so worried about my face.)
Can I see the mirror?
(He looks at his face, reflected in the camera.)
Why would they bite my lip?
(His upper lip is swollen.)
- It's swollen, right? - Yes.
(He's at a loss.)
The mosquito knew my lips are attractive. It's why it bit my lip.
(He sure loves himself.)
This is unbelievable. How can I not get any bite?
I feel like they ignored me.
(Are you mad now?)
Does the bite itch?
(You win, Da Hoon.)
Mosquitoes must survive as well.
The mosquitoes are...
(I talked without thinking at that time.)
There were so many of them.
(He can't think straight because of them.)
I must hunt the best I can.
(Mosquitoes ruined everything.)
I didn't sleep a wink.
(I hate mosquitoes. I can't hunt now. I didn't sleep at all.)
What's the hardest part?
(What is the hardest part?)
Not being able to eat.
(He can't give up his food even in the jungle.)
(Cheng Xiao gets up.)
(She's half asleep and half awake.)
(Meanwhile,)
(she takes something out.)
(What will she do?)
(She's rolling her bangs.)
(What is that?)
This? When I roll it like this,
my bangs look nice like this.
(Like this. Isn't it pretty?)
I have to have my bangs.
I always had bangs ever since I was a baby.
(She can't give up her bangs even in the jungle.)
You didn't do this yesterday.
That's why I looked so ugly.
(Sol Bi is eating.)
Thank you.
(Jin also has a bite.)
(Everyone is awake and eating coconuts.)
I feel like I am a bird now.
(Is this person still sleeping?)
Did Sleepy sleep late last night?
He said he will wake up at 11:40am. So we are not to wake him up.
(Sleepy is in a deep sleep again today.)
He said he had a lot to ponder on.
He said he will reflect about his day.
(Last night, he said he will reflect about his day.)
At some point, he stopped talking and fell asleep.
(He stopped talking and fell asleep.)
(Until this moment, he slept well.)
This...
(Little Aunt, also known as the owner of the general store)
My teacher who's instructing me these days made this.
I'm learning how to sew.
(He only sewed, but it looks amazing.)
- Are you learning leather crafts? - Yes.
(The Chief is planning to create his own hunting tools.)
(You can see the products he's producing now in Kota Manado.)
It's too tight. My chest is bulging out.
(Da Hoon gets an upgrade.)
This looks a bit awkward.
You can tighten it up if it's loose.
- No, it's perfect. - Is it?
(Where did he get the sunglasses?)
This...
(With the equipment, he gets confident.)
(I'm completely ready.)
(Yoon Da Hoon, the Big Aunt, can defeat the mosquitoes the best.)
- Cheng Xiao. - Put this on.
Doesn't she look like a warrior?
Put it on.
(It's customized just for her. It's for a female warrior.)
(He opens his eyes wide.)
(Aren't I scary?)
(Cheng Xiao, the youngest daughter, is fixing her bangs.)
(Sol Bi gets a customized gear as well.)
As I put this gear on,
I feel like I can hunt.
I can also be a female warrior.
(Swinging)
You don't look like one.
You're not a female warrior. A lady died in a battle.
When you swung, you are as good as dead.
"As good as dead"?
Since your dagger is small,
you need to swing it with only one hand.
Don't do it with both your hands.
- With only one hand? - Yes.
Do it with only one hand.
- It looks weird. - Use your arm, not your body.
Hold your body and swing.
(Don't forget to use your arm.)
There you go. You look strong.
No, that's not how you should do it.
(His eyes, nose, and mouth are open wide.)
Don't do this. Don't open your mouth.
- Right. Don't do that. - When you swing hard...
- Should I try again? - Yes.
(Try again.)
(She swings with all her might.)
(Sol Bi, the cousin, can make her eyes very big.)
(We agree.)
Having this weapon gives me courage.
(Everyone can see she's courageous now.)
What if you see a snake?
A snake?
When you see a snake, you can't use your dagger.
You need to press its neck with your fingers making a Y.
You have to press it down.
- Press its neck? - Yes.
- But what if... - Don't worry. I can catch it.
- it turns its neck and bites me? - I'll take care of it. Don't worry.
Look. Let's pretend you are the snake.
I made Y-shape with my fingers.
- I'm pressing you down. - Okay.
Try to bite me now.
(Trying)
Try to bite me.
(She tries her best.)
(Snake Sol Bi fails to attack him.)
This is what happens.
(She tries with all her might.)
- This is what happens. - Really?
- However, look. - I see.
Let's pretend I hold this part. Try to bite me now.
You can bite me, then.
That's why you can't grab its body.
- Its head won't turn. - That's right.
Press the back of the snake's head.
It's similar to how you grab a person.
I will go hunting today.
Sleepy, who finally woke up,
and the trio of Jungle Rangers head to the jungle.
The ace members, Gong Myoung and Jin,
follow Chief Byung Man to the sea.
(Look forward to the family's hunt.)
Let's go.
Let's go hunting.
- Let's go. - We haven't gone this way.
Let's go somewhere we haven't gone.
Let's catch something.
Here is an important thing...
you should remember.
(Da Hoon stops the members prior to the hunt.)
A jungle is not an easy place.
Be careful at all times.
Tell the others when you find something.
Snakes often rest on trees.
- That's why... - Are we allowed to pick plants?
Before you pick plants, check with the government...
to see if they are in a nature reserve.
- Da Hoon, let's go. - Don't make rash decisions.
(Sol Bi starts before the guide.)
You should listen to the guide.
They don't concentrate.
Da Hoon, this place is...
- Why are there concave areas? - I can explain.
- Birds come here to lay eggs. - They lay eggs.
Birds lay eggs here...
and snakes appear to eat the eggs.
These are bird tracks,
right?
- These are bird tracks. - You are right.
Look.
I will dig deep.
I have no strength in my arms.
(It's hard to dig the earth on an empty stomach.)
I didn't eat a meal.
I know.
I don't think bird eggs would be at a place that is too sunny.
The sun is too bright.
Don't you think they would have laid eggs in the shade...
to keep them cool?
There would be eggs in the shade.
(They keep repeating same words.)
There are tracks here as well.
There are tracks.
Don't they look like an animal's?
I found animal tracks.
We will find something if we follow the tracks.
Did this animal come to steal the eggs?
It's possible. This tells us...
there are animals on this island.
I don't think it's this way.
Let's not go this way.
Wait a minute.
(The hunter in a male menopause searches the area.)
It's a bit scary.
Get out of the way.
Get out of the way. I will go.
(He is a brave hunter.)
(He boldly walks into the forest.)
- The ground... - My goodness.
(My goodness.)
Ants built a house inside this rotten log.
There are holes.
This log has rotted.
There is a path.
Guys, there are a lot of insects.
There are insects like mosquitoes.
This place is a swamp.
(He stops searching for an animal and becomes a tour guide.)
That's right. My feet are sinking.
Look at this.
This place...
is a swamp.
(I will go before the guide.)
It's wet over there, too.
It's a wetland.
I think we can go this way.
There are animals roaming around.
(There are animals on this island.)
Let's have a meeting.
Come here, Cheng Xiao.
(The family gathers around for a meeting.)
(Squealing)
What was that sound?
- My goodness. - Everyone heard it, right?
It sounded like a boar.
(A boar?)
- It's the sound of a boar. - Really?
It's the sound of a boar.
It came from that way.
It's a boar. I know what a boar sounds like.
(There were animals.)
It's a boar.
It's the sound of a boar.
Boars are very loud.
(I will catch you.)
(Everyone follows Da Hoon.)
(However, their pace is slow since the road is rough.)
(Screaming)
- Be careful. - There are a lot of snakes.
Be careful.
It was the sound of a boar.
(I certainly heard it.)
(Where did it go?)
Is there a boar?
You heard the sound, right?
Yes.
Wouldn't it be a smaller animal than a boar?
It could be a small boar.
It didn't sound like...
a big animal.
It could be a goat.
No, it was the sound of a pig.
Shall we keep on going?
Let's go this way.
(Actually,)
(Sleepy has been running ever since he woke up.)
(Dizzy)
(He feels faint.)
It's exhausting.
That's because our stomachs are empty.
I have no energy left.
(Squealing)
(The sound came from the back this time.)
Run quickly.
(Running on an instant)
What is it?
Do you see anything moving?
(It's in the forest.)
Come this way.
- Where is it? - Come on.
(What could it be?)
(It's a wild goat.)
- It's too far away. - It really is a goat.
Where is it?
(He runs at full speed.)
(Running)
(Sleepy's adrenaline surges.)
(Disappearing)
(The wild goat disappears into the forest.)
(As the musician has guessed, it was a goat.)
(Screaming)
- What was that? - It will run away.
Don't scream.
Did you see it?
I saw it go that way.
It went that way.
However, I don't know which path it took.
From here, it could have gone that way.
(Sleepy tries to predict which way the goat went.)
Hey.
(The goat won't come just because he is calling for it.)
I feel like there would be something up there.
(The fragile man decides to climb a mountain.)
(My goodness.)
(Shaking)
(It had better be a very slow goat.)
No, it went this way.
I am 100 percent certain.
We will go to the mountain.
That's because...
there is a lot of grass in the mountain.
Goats eat grass.
The mountain has their food.
- Shall we go up? - Let's do that.
Are we going up that mountain?
Yes, we are. The goat will be up there.
Goats live on a high mountain.
Be careful.
(Sleepy and the group will trap the goat from both sides.)
Stay here. I will go up and look.
I will go up to that point.
Goat.
(Bleating)
Goat!
Where are you?
(No matter how much she calls,)
(the goat doesn't respond.)
I don't think it came this far.
The scenery is really pretty.
The sea is beautiful.
It's really pretty.
(They get a bird's-eye view.)
I want to go snorkeling.
It's really nice.
The team that chased after a goat...
is entranced by the beautiful scenery.
What is the team of ace members doing...
- right now? - Chief Byung Man.
- Yes? - Let's go.
Wait a second. There is something I want to take.
- Okay. - I really wanted to do this.
I saw it on the internet.
You use a pump...
and inject air with manual labor.
To follow the theme of the survival,
they will hunt in the water without electric power.
A rubber hose will be attached to a water container.
Then air will be pumped into it...
so that they can hunt...
without coming up for air.
Byung Man borrowed the necessary items from the crew.
I am going to use this.
Then he got to making a tool without electric power.
I wanted to try it.
Do we put it over our head and stay in water?
Yes, you walk around like that.
(He cuts the base of the water container.)
(Concentrating)
You are meticulous.
You're like the son of a divine being.
(A divine being?)
(Embarrassed)
- I am not that great. - Do you think that?
Do you know what a divine baby is called?
- Was it a joke? - I am telling you a joke.
(Jin is thorough.)
(Thinking)
(I really want to get it right.)
Well...
A newborn.
(The answer is "A newborn".)
That's what you are, Chief Byung Man.
You are good at telling jokes. There isn't anything you can't do.
I can't dance very well.
(Jin is the best idol singer.)
Jin's dad jokes kept the team entertained.
They focus on making the air container.
That's right.
So that the buoyant water container...
can sink,
they attach a heavy hammer to it.
The air container is complete.
It's time for a test drive.
The team tests its effectiveness.
(How will the handmade air container turn out?)
We will use it.
We spent a few hours to make it.
Chief Byung Man will put it on.
- Pump the air into it. - Okay.
(Pump the air into it.)
(You can trust us.)
It will be dangerous for the Chief if we take a break.
That's right.
We should begin pumping.
(Jin pumps air before Byung Man goes into the water.)
(It's his first time.)
All right.
(It's on his head.)
(He's a bit nervous.)
All right. I am going in.
Okay.
(Splashing)
(He jumps into the water.)
(A handmade air container is like something from a comic book.)
(Will it work?)
What is happening?
(He went in the water.)
(Is Chief Byung Man breathing?)
It works.
(Does it really work?)
- Does it work? - Yes.
I was breathing the whole time.
My goodness. Really?
(He enters the water again.)
(The water only comes up to his chin.)
(He is breathing with his mouth.)
(It really works.)
I am breathing.
(Laughing)
(He is excited.)
This is funny.
(Jin is getting exhausted.)
This is interesting.
That's good. Pull the hose.
(He is satisfied with his creation.)
(The person who is pumping air is exhausted.)
I am exhausted.
(Someone help me.)
(Unaware of what is happening, Byung Man is excited.)
If you rest,
Chief Byung Man won't be able to breathe.
(Chief Byung Man's fate lies in my hand.)
You need to come out.
(You need to come out if you want to live.)
(Otherwise, I will die.)
You need to come out.
(Chief Byung Man comes out of the water.)
(I am saved.)
- We can't hear you. - Can you hear me?
We can't hear you.
Please pump the air well.
- You can trust me. - Okay.
(Gong Myoung tries on the handmade air container.)
Go into the water.
(He enters the water without hesitating.)
(He is the ace member.)
(Pumping began anew.)
(Relaxed)
This is fascinating.
Can you hear me?
I am breathing well.
I will give my line from "Drinking Solo".
Shall we begin dating from today on?
I can see the bottom of the sea.
Can you hear me?
There is a current.
(He keeps rising to the surface.)
This is fascinating.
(The hammer isn't heavy enough to fight the buoyancy.)
(Moreover,)
(pumping air is exhausting.)
Let's put on snorkeling masks.
(Byung Man's invention was a big success.)
This is fascinating.
I could breathe and look at the bottom.
Really? We should still wear snorkeling masks.
(Jin's arms will be too exhausted if they use the air container.)
The water is coming in...
in this area.
Let's go someplace else.
I am hungry.
- We must hunt. - Let's dive.
Meanwhile, the team that was chasing after a goat...
travel deeper into the jungle.
(Screaming)
What is it? Is it a snake?
No. Look at this.
- It's really long. - Hold on!
- What is that? - What is it?
- It's a centipede. - A centipede?
- This centipede is really big. - Be careful.
It looks like a pill bug.
I feel like there would be snakes, too.
I am scared of insects. I am really scared of them.
- Be careful. - I don't think it will be here.
Be careful.
- Move to the side. - There is nothing here.
- Be careful. - I am...
looking for a goat.
(He only cares about the goat.)
I really want to catch it.
- It will be nice if we have fruits. - You can...
look for fruits.
I will look for the goat.
What is that?
- What is that green thing? - That one?
- Isn't it a young coconut tree? - What is that?
- What is that? - Where is it?
- Over there. - It's over there.
- What is that? - On the bottom,
- there are bigger ones. - What are those?
I know.
- Are those mangoes? - No.
- Aren't those mangoes? - Aren't those mangoes?
I only know its Chinese name.
Those are papayas. That's incredible.
Wait a minute. How do we get them?
- How do we get them? - Move out of the way.
(Sleepy is excited to hear the familiar name.)
Move out of the way.
- They are up too high. - They are inedible.
(Are they inedible?)
Why not?
They are green. You eat them when they are yellow.
Will they become yellow if we wait?
Why don't we take them and wait?
Pick the lower one.
I love fruits.
I ate a lot of papayas when I was in China.
I eat fruits every day.
That's what a papaya looks like.
They look edible.
They will be sweet, right?
(How will we pick them?)
What should we do?
(They can only look.)
I see bananas.
(I see bananas.)
- What? - Where?
- Where? - Where?
- There they are. They are green. - Where?
I see bananas.
(I came and saw...)
(bananas in the jungle.)
- There are so many bananas. - Should we go over there?
Wait a minute.
Let's go after we pick these.
- I will climb the tree. - Don't do that.
Step over here. It's the middle.
That's right.
(Taking a big step)
There we go.
(He reaches the papayas in one step.)
They will be sweet.
(The jobless brother helped.)
That one looks nice.
(Sleepy picks the papaya Cheng Xiao pointed out.)
- There you go. - Pick the bottom one.
(Sleepy is Cheng Xiao's avatar.)
Cheng Xiao, you are speaking well.
Your Korean improved all of a sudden.
(Her Korean became fluent at the sight of her favorite fruit.)
- Go left. - No, pick the one on the right.
It's the biggest one.
Stop picking them. They won't be edible.
(Cheng Xiao is speaking Korean like a native.)
Okay. Good job.
How do we cut it? Do we cut it like an apple?
You can cut it in half.
It looks edible.
- It's edible. - Give me a piece.
Give me a piece.
(They judge that it's ripe.)
The color is nice.
Does it taste good?
(How does it taste?)
How is it?
It's sweet.
My goodness.
- Is it edible? - Yes.
- It's sweet. - It's perfect.
It's edible.
It's nice.
(The papaya expert approves of the taste.)
All right. Eat this.
(Sleepy played a big role and acquiring the papayas.)
(He broke out in sweats.)
- It's tasty. - It's really tasty.
It's like a mix between persimmon and peach.
It's a million times tastier than coconuts.
Really?
It will be better to discard the seeds.
Try it.
That one is fully ripe.
(Sol Bi has a taste.)
My goodness.
It's really tasty in the middle.
All right. Then I will...
(The soft and sweet fruit makes her shudder.)
My goodness.
These seeds are edible,
but inconvenient.
Will papaya trees grow if I plant these seeds?
It will take forever for them to germinate.
They won't germinate before we leave.
(Sleepy gnaws on an unripe papaya.)
Leave some behind.
That one is inedible.
(She feels bad.)
(He tries hard to eat a papaya.)
(Da Hoon, here is a goat.)
(It's tasty.)
I took out the seeds.
You did a good job, but it sounded like a swear word.
I feel a bit uncomfortable.
- I took out the seeds. - Make sure you enunciate.
Shall we pick bananas this time?
We forgot about bananas.
- Be careful. - Go, go, go.
Look at those bananas.
We will be able to eat them until tomorrow.
(There is a bunch of bananas.)
(They march towards the bananas.)
How will we pick them?
They are up too high. What should we do?
Let's use a rod.
(The tree is very tall.)
They are up too high.
Would it be possible to climb the tree?
(They only stare.)
(Da Hoon shakes the banana leaves.)
- My goodness. - What should we do?
There are too many.
There's no way up.
Nothing is easy.
There are red ants everywhere.
- There are. - Look.
Of course, there are. There's food up here.
I've got ants on me, too.
(There are red ants on the ground, too.)
How do we get the bananas?
Let's have a meeting.
Let's use bamboo.
(They're addicted to meetings.)
How about we tie a piece...
to the saw and saw the tree down?
(No reaction)
From there.
(You don't like that idea.)
Cheng Xiao's a gymnast. Why don't you jump?
- Me, jump up there? - I'll crouch underneath.
(Jump up in one fluid movement...)
(like a woman in a martial arts movie.)
(I didn't train at the Shaolin Monastery.)
Do you see the thing hanging beneath the bananas?
Shall we try using that?
We could pull it down.
Let's use this.
(Sol Bi jumps into action.)
(It's time to prove that she's smart.)
(Using a branch with a curved tip...)
(she'll pull the flower.)
How do we get that?
Give me that.
You do it. You hook it up.
(Sleepy steps up yet again.)
(This is my day!)
(We're coming for you, bananas.)
Hook it right there.
(They got the flower.)
(Slipping)
(How dare you!)
Give me just one.
Just one banana.
I think you have it.
- Wait. - Can you lift him up?
Let's have a meeting.
(Obsessed with meetings)
What? Now?
Cheng Xiao, you climb up.
- Me? - Yes, you're the lightest.
How much do you weigh?
(Pardon?)
Don't ask things like that.
Let's have a meeting. Is this really the right way?
Give me that belt.
- Give me that. - Let's try.
Let's see.
(Using Byung Man's belt)
Think about this.
What if the belt remains hanging?
The falling knife could hurt someone.
- We took it out. - It's here.
Good.
Let's give it a go.
(The wooden hook got an upgrade.)
(Now it has a leather belt noose.)
(It's hooked.)
Pull.
Twist it a few times.
(He twists the belt to keep it tight.)
Make it tight.
(Spinning)
Yes, that's it.
(Carefully and lightly)
He may wake up late but he does his worth.
(He makes himself useful.)
- That's it. - You did it.
Now pull.
- You did it. - Now pull.
(Will Sleepy's noose do the trick?)
(Please)
We'll just get the flower. See?
(The belt came off.)
You tried, at least.
- Well done. - Well done.
I bet you'll sleep all day tomorrow.
(He's already sickly.)
You'll wake up at 2:30pm.
I'll need to sleep until 3pm.
(Da Hoon decides to cut down that one branch.)
(Big Aunt is going full steam ahead.)
(Will it work?)
Stay away from that area.
I'm halfway through.
(Banana trees live for many years and branches are cut regularly.)
It's going over!
- Move, move! - It's going!
(It's going down.)
(The bananas seemed out of reach.)
(Crashing down)
- Unbelievable. - No way.
(That was hard work.)
- How did you do that? - The ants are going crazy.
These ants are huge.
(They're in a frenzy.)
Let's take some.
(They check the condition the bananas are in.)
It's not ripe at all.
(Not ripe at all)
We should let them grow.
Is there a way to ripen them?
- In the skin? - Put them in the sun.
- They ripen right away. - You're right.
- This much? - That's perfect.
Let's take that much.
(They scored!)
It's so happy.
It's sucking the sap.
As if the tree's like sugar cane.
It's a long-headed grasshopper.
(I'm just a grasshopper.)
It's having a drink.
(He grabs it.)
Look at how fat it is.
Isn't this edible?
- This is huge. - It's massive.
It was gulping the sap.
It's huge.
Let's take it.
- Let's go. - Take this.
Nothing is impossible when the family works together.
The Land Team returns with fruit...
and a huge grasshopper...
that will provide the family with some protein.
They return light-heartedly.
That was quite productive.
How is the Sea Team faring?
(Deep-sea hunting class)
(Shall we begin?)
(Byung Man's camera)
(Scanning for prey)
(He sees something and dives straight down.)
(What is the Chief's first target?)
(A giant clam)
(He plucks it easily.)
(Where's Gong Myoung, his star pupil?)
(He can't find any prey and is...)
(floating on the surface.)
(Jin grabs his nose to dive.)
(But he surfaces right away with nothing.)
(Flapping around)
(Did you get anything?)
I can't see properly. I can't see.
(I should teach them what to do.)
Come over here! Come here.
Come to where I am.
(The lesson commences.)
(Byung Man's camera)
(Calmly scan the ocean floor.)
(Prey spotted)
(There's something!)
(Locate the prey.)
(Gong Myoung, go!)
(Yes, Sir.)
(Diving gracefully)
(It was an easy success.)
(I got it.)
(Byung Man's lesson was a success.)
(This time...)
(Jin, you go.)
(On Byung Man's signal, he dives right down.)
(Swimming close to the ocean floor)
(Jin found a conch.)
(The lesson yields results right away.)
- Do you have something? - This.
What is it?
- A conch? - A conch.
(Byung Man's proud.)
They're good. They're quick learners.
(He puts his catch in his bag.)
(The next target...)
(was an easy one.)
Byung Man was a great leader.
He's an amazing guy.
It was so fascinating and such a great experience.
He taught me step by step and I managed to keep up.
I saw that it's actually possible.
(Aunt Byung Man's pleased with the boys' success.)
Do you have something?
(Each dive yields a result.)
(Byung Man's awesome.)
If Byung Man teaches them one thing, Jin and Gong Myoung...
master 10 on their own.
Byung Man leaves them...
to catch clams and conchs while he looks...
between the coral and rocks.
(He saw something!)
(He tries shoving the net in.)
(There's a lot of dust.)
(What's hiding between the rocks?)
(Gasping)
(A stingray)
(This is a huge find!)
(Hang on)
(The stingray got away!)
(It slipped out of the net.)
(It's really fast!)
(It's here in just one second!)
(Gong Myoung heard the scream and rushed over.)
(He lost a stingray.)
(The stingray's nowhere to be seen.)
(Byung Man searches between the rocks just in case,)
(but the sea is too wide for them to meet again.)
That was so close and such a pity.
They lost a stingray,
but Byung Man and his two sidekicks...
found a few clams and conchs.
On today's menu is Kota Manado-style shellfish soup.
It should be good.
- Once it opens up... - Clean it?
That's right.
(The clam and conchs slowly open up.)
(Grumbling stomachs)
This one opened up.
(An open clam)
(Remove the flesh from the shell.)
- Is it an oyster? - It looks like one, doesn't it?
(Pulling)
Tear the adductor muscle.
- Do we tear it all up? - Yes.
(Add water.)
It's done.
(Bring to the boil and eat.)
- Leave it like this. - To boil?
Yes. So the flavor seeps out.
(While they wait for the soup to cook...)
- Welcome back. - You're back.
We just finished cooking something.
- They found something. - Not much.
- Ta-da. - What's that?
- Papayas. - You found papayas?
Yes. We plucked them from over there.
Cheng Xiao.
Bananas.
(The bananas make an entrance.)
Give me your hand.
(This is for you.)
- For you. - Thank you.
There's something else.
(The grasshopper)
(Scared out of his wits)
(Gong Myoung's calm)
- What's that? A locust? - Isn't it cute?
Eat it.
(He runs away.)
- Come back here. - Go away!
- Sorry. - I'm tired.
(Still alert)
What do you have, Sleepy?
- Stop hiding things. - That's all we have.
(He smiles all of a sudden.)
(A huge bunch of bananas)
(Gaping)
Are you a monkey?
- Taste this. - How?
It's really good. Take a bite.
You'll be shocked. It's really sweet.
It's good. It tastes a bit like a squash.
The unripe ones taste like persimmons and the ripe ones...
- taste like peaches and persimmons. - Really?
Eat it all up.
(Da Hoon cares for the young ones.)
It's really good.
- Isn't it sweet? - It's really sweet.
(Cheng Xiao's working on something.)
Is it too big?
(She's communicating with the grasshopper.)
What do you eat?
Look at this.
(She's feeding it like it's a pet.)
What is it eating?
A piece of wood.
I named it "Bana".
I called it that because we caught it...
while it was feeding off the banana tree.
Say hello.
(She treats it like a puppy.)
It might escape.
It's really strong. Hello.
(I'm so tired.)
We should cook that.
How do we cook it?
(And that is how...)
(Bana ended up in the fire.)
It's a banana feast.
(The family waits for the food to cook.)
(Gong Myoung drifts off to sleep.)
(Dozing off)
How many are there?
(His head slowly dips.)
I've never seen this insect before.
(Look at him.)
(Glancing over)
(He must be so tired.)
He's asleep.
It's heartbreaking.
He was like this on the boat, too.
Really?
You didn't sleep much.
- Did you? - Were you praying?
He slept in the water.
He slept while floating around.
Shouldn't we take it out?
We have to wait until the stomach puffs up.
- Are you cooking the grasshopper? - Yes.
It's cooked.
(The grasshopper's cooked.)
(He can't wait to eat it.)
Aren't there a lot of these in China?
These?
There are a lot but I've never seen one this huge.
(It's a massive grasshopper.)
- What's this? - A leg.
I'll try a leg.
It's nice.
- Me, too. - It's like chicken jerky.
It's hot.
(She holds a twig-like leg...)
(and smacks her lips.)
I'll eat it because I'm hungry.
It's got a nutty flavor.
I saw this alive just a while ago.
But now I can't help but eat it.
(How does the grasshopper taste?)
It's really good. Why is this?
(Shocked by the unexpected taste)
Why does this taste good?
(What's this flavor?)
I'm shocked.
(Everyone rushes in for a taste.)
- It's good. - The older generation ate these.
Even I used to. They were sold deep-fried.
Why is it salty?
(It's salted.)
It's like dried fish.
A squid's spine.
Right?
(That's the taste of the jungle.)
Can I eat this part?
(Sol Bi's fallen in love.)
(She might want it whole.)
- You must like it. - Wait, I'll tear it off.
I didn't know it's this good.
It's tasty and high in protein.
Can we get these in Korea?
Not in Seoul.
(A new horizon is opened.)
Do you want some?
Who wants half?
It tastes just like the leg.
(Staring)
I ate one as a kid.
Do you see all this flesh?
I'm going to eat the head.
- Isn't that the good part? - You eat it, then.
- No. - It's just meat.
- It tastes good. - Do you want it?
(Do you want the body?)
(He goes for it.)
It'll taste just like the leg.
(Da Hoon savors it as if he's used to the taste.)
(Jin may be afraid...)
(but hunger fuels him.)
Well done.
(Gasping)
(What's wrong, Jin?)
(Trembling lips)
I saw inside his mouth. Something burst.
There's nothing to burst but the head.
Something burst.
- Something burst. - The guts, right?
I ate all the guts.
I plucked it out of the belly when I separated the head.
It's just the head.
What does it taste like?
Like a grasshopper...
jumped into my mouth and...
I bit it by accident.
- A bit like death, then. - Yes.
Death?
(Yes. Something like that.)
(The sound stimulates your appetite.)
Chief, shall we take the soup off the fire?
Yes.
(The soup's ready.)
- What's this? - Shellfish soup.
I don't want it all but I'd love to taste the broth.
(Their first soup)
I'm so excited.
(Everyone's gulping)
Just a bit.
That must be good.
(The eldest gets to taste first.)
(Gulping)
It's really rich.
The flavor's all there.
It's slightly salty...
but not too much.
I taste more kelp than shellfish.
- Right? - Yes.
I love the smell of the shellfish.
(The smell of shellfish)
You had too much.
(Glaring)
(Making a snide remark because he wants some.)
(She just laughs.)
Shellfish soup.
(It washes all the fatigue away.)
(Is it good, Cheng Xiao?)
(Nodding)
- How is it? - Good.
(It's Sleepy's turn at last.)
It's like soju.
Try some shellfish. It's good.
(Open wide, Gong Myoung.)
That's the tasty bit.
- Did you doze off? - Yes.
(The tired boy deserves a large piece.)
(Staring open-mouthed)
(Nice and chewy)
This isn't something...
we can buy at a market.
That's what's important.
(It's amazing.)
It's delicious.
That's incredible.
On a rainy day...
a bowl of this by the sea with waves crashing in the back.
That would be nice.
(Yummy)
(Cute moans)
It's so good.
What does it taste like?
Is it that good?
I can't describe it.
You can't describe it?
Thank you.
(Sleepy gets his share.)
It's very rich.
Everything here is just so fresh.
(There's not much but everything's flavorful.)
It's such a pity I have to swallow it.
Is that it?
There's still a lot left.
(They try to fill their stomachs with grilled bananas.)
We Koreans need soup.
(The weather suddenly changes for the worse.)
(It begins to pour.)
- It's raining. - It's raining.
It's raining.
What about the fire?
(Everyone rushes around.)
(Where is Da Hoon going?)
(He relishes the rain.)
I'm getting soaked. I love rain.
(He suddenly got sentimental.)
I love the sound.
The raindrops are really strong.
("Like Rain and Music" by Kim Hyun Sik)
It's great.
This is what rain should be like.
When would I get to be drenched like this?
I'm really enjoying this.
(It's now or never.)
(Our aunt has the sentimentality of a girl.)
(Search for song, singer)
(Search by country)
(For the weather)
(BTS, Lee Moon Sae)
("It's Raining")
(Play now)
Where is it?
Bring the sheet of plastic.
Hold it up.
(Collecting rainwater)
Hold it up higher.
Let's collect the rain.
We need to fill our bottles!
(Overflowing)
Hold this edge.
Hold the end.
Hold it with your fingers.
(They collect rain water in the water bottle.)
Okay, okay.
(There is plenty of water.)
- That's good. Next. - Me.
- I don't have water. - Hold it open.
(They get ready to fill up Gong Myoung's water bottle.)
(What?)
(Glancing)
(What's with the stare?)
It's not raining anymore.
(No way.)
It doesn't matter whose water bottle it is. We can share.
(He's saying this because he filled up his bottle.)
(I don't know what to do.)
- Oh, dear. - I thought it was the rainy season.
My goodness.
Should I drink this?
- Sure. - Go ahead.
Don't spill it.
(Sleepy drinks the remaining water.)
(Choking)
Why did you spit it out?
(We can only do this in Sunda.)
- It's sweet. - When is it going to rain again?
It's sweet.
It didn't rain too long...
so I survived.
Look.
It rained a little bit and we filled up this much.
(The water bottle is almost full.)
- Really? - Yes.
Hurry up.
As soon as it started showering, they didn't panic...
and collected rain to obtain drinking water.
No wonder the Chief is a jungle veteran of six years.
(Everybody loves the Little Aunt.)
It's almost time for the end of survival without power.
- In 5, 4, - In 5, 4,
- 3, 2, 1. - 3, 2, 1.
Success.
(They survived without power.)
We did it.
- I'm scared about the next one. - What are you going to take away?
Zero Base, Three No's.
Here's the third topic.
(They're anxious.)
Live without food?
(Live without food?)
We're already doing that.
Live without fire?
- Live without light. - It's fire.
- What if it's no clothes? - Live without clothes?
- Live fleetingly. - "Live fleetingly"?
(That's Sleepy's lifestyle.)
Live without sleep.
Zero Base, Three No's.
The third and last rule...
(They're anxious and nervous.)
(What?)
See?
(They're shocked and terrified.)
- That makes no sense. - That's...
- nonsense. - You're telling us to starve.
- All of a sudden? - This is ridiculous.
(It's the worst rule you can imagine.)
What have I done wrong?
Next week.
(This is the last of Zero Base, Three No's.)
(They're in chaos and confusion. They can't let their guards down.)
(Groaning)
(Weather is awful.)
I'm cold.
(It pours in Kota Manado due to the rainy season.)
(They're exhausted.)
(Even their ace member goes down.)
(Is there a conflict amongst the members?)
(The Law of Jungle in Kota Manado, Friday at 10pm)