[ALARM CLOCK SOUNDS]
[♪]
♪ It was just another
Saturday night ♪
♪ I was jamming with the guys ♪
♪ Hanging out on the corner ♪
♪ Just a-watching
the girls go by ♪
♪ Suddenly, I noticed
They were staring back at me ♪
♪ And when I took a closer look
I couldn't help but see ♪
♪ Girls got something ♪
♪ Boys ain't got ♪
♪ Drives 'em crazy ♪
♪ Gets 'em hot ♪
♪ Girls got something ♪
♪ Boys ain't got ♪
♪ They just ain't got ♪
♪ Whoo-hoo... ♪
♪ Like a bee
That needs its honey ♪
♪ Like a moth
drawn to a flame ♪
♪ Girl, is just a
fact of life ♪
♪ They're captured
by the game ♪
♪ That's the way
It's always been ♪
♪ Since Adam fell for Eve ♪
♪ Just one taste
Is all it takes ♪
♪ To make a boy believe ♪
♪ Girls got something  ♪
♪ Boys ain't got ♪
♪ Drives 'em crazy ♪
♪ Gets 'em hot ♪
♪ Girls got something ♪
♪ Boys ain't got ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh... ♪
Terry...
Denise, why aren't you
in science?
They're showing
a film strip.
Everyone left.
I have to talk to you.
Denise, I'm really into
this article.
I know, but I need
your advice,
and you are
my best friend.
and I tried to deal
with this myself, okay,
and I'm really
stressed out!
Three guys want to take
me out Saturday night,
and I'm not too thrilled
about any of them,
but I think I should
go out with someone
in case I don't
have a real boyfriend
by the prom.
Okay, who are the guys?
If I give you names,
you cannot laugh.
I know.
You have the perfect
college boyfriend.
You think Kevin's perfect?
He's a god, okay?
Can we talk
about me now?
Where was I?
Bruce Schulman,
Edward Zink,
and Roger Gibbler.
This is serious.
I know.
All right.
On a scale of lame to cute,
who rates
the least low?
They're all lame.
Put Roger
in a Rent-A-Tux,
he might move up
to semi-lame.
Okay, forget looks.
Who's got
the hottest car?
A Pinto,
dad's Skylark,
and a Schwinn.
Looks like you're going to have
to skip the prom.
Hey, hey, everybody...
Listen up. Hey.
A lot of you have been
giving me a lot of grief
about this Sun-Tribune
journalism competition.
Well, I finally got
all of your submissions ready.
Now, during my
planning period,
I picked
the best two,
and then from those,
and from those submitted
by all of your pals
over at Sturgis-Wilder...
[BOOING AND HISSING]
Thank you.
...the Trib will pick one,
and award somebody
a summer internship, okay?
So I'll post the names
of the winners
in the main
trophy case
right after
I finish my lunch.
Tuna salad on whole wheat.
A summer job at the Sun-Tribune.
Think about it.
I'll think about that.
You think about me at the prom
with a lizard.
I think
you're exaggerating.
Hi, Denise.
A-are you busy
Saturday night?
Sorry.
Mr. Raymaker, Mr. Vino,
the driver's ed teacher,
just ran over a dog.
Should I take a photographer
over?
No.
What's up, Terry?
How's it
going, Terry?
- Hi, guys.
Bye... guys.
Am I invisible?
They were
in a hurry.
You are so hot.
Buddy...
I just ate.
Thanks for stopping by, Bud.
Any time, sis.
Our parents are gone
for two weeks.
You know what
that means?
Their king-size bed
is empty.
What do you think?
I think if you and I
were the last man
and woman on earth,
the human race
would die out.
You want time
to think it over.
I understand.
I have two words
for you.
Slumber party.
We'll invite every
girl you know.
Tall, short,
loose, easy.
I'll be
the bartender.
They can use
my bedroom,
they can use my body.
I want to help.
You want to molest my friends.
Forget it.
Why?
You'll have a party,
and I'll...
Uh, uh, uh!
Oh, God.
Does he do this
at the dinner table?
Don't get me wrong.
It's not like I've
never had sex before.
I've had lots
of sex.
It's just that now
I'd like to try it
with a partner.
We really have to get back
to school.
Yes, we must
get back.
I want to make sure my article's
in the trophy case.
Yes, we really
must get going.
You have
to get going?
I'm 15 years old.
In two years,
I reach the peak
of my sexual powers.
The clock is ticking.
I have to get jamming.
Can't you hear
what you're saying?
Aren't you a little
embarrassed?
Nope. I'm horny.
Horny will kick
embarrassment's ass
every time.
Budster,
listen to me.
Don't you want your first time
to be with someone you love?
I guarantee it,
I'll be in love.
There's Lisa MacAdoo.
I'll hear she'll do
anything with anybody.
She looks pretty
cheap to me.
Me too.
Denise, I am
so excited.
You know this job
means,
everything in
life to me.
I know. Just make sure you work
in the Sports section
That way we can interview
all the cute jocks.
You are going to be
so proud of me.
I am going to make
such a great reporter.
I'm not there.
Why aren't
you there?
Neal Perlow
and Joseph Dreyer?
And then I had
Terry Griffith,
fourth period civics.
Did you see
what she's wearing?
The legs
do not stop.
I say
we flunk her.
Keep her here
for another year.
You better
be careful, George.
You could lose
your job.
Be worth it.
It's not that
great a job.
Terry...
What's wrong with my article?
Well, there isn't anything
wrong with it, per se.
It's just not outstanding work.
Well, I think it is.
What do you give me
straight A's for, my wardrobe?
I give you the A's
because of your hard work,
and you write well,
but this contest,
it's a completely different
ball game.
When I read those articles,
I have to ask myself,
"Does this person
have a nose for the news?"
"Do they dig out
the most interesting
angle on a story?"
Oh, so I see,
what you're trying to tell me
is that the nutritional content
of our school lunches
isn't interesting.
Now, Terry, I know
that you're disappointed,
but I had to pick kids
who've got a real shot
at becoming journalists.
I am going to be a reporter.
I like
that attitude,
but don't you think
that it would be nice
to have something
to fall back on?
Like what?
Uh, well, you're a pretty girl,
you could be a model.
Be a model?
Why? Because a pretty girl
can't possibly have a brain?
Look, what I meant was--
I know what
you meant!
This is a great article,
and it belongs
at the Sun-Tribune,
and you are so clueless
to, like...
It is really pathetic.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Terry, it's Mr. Wonderful.
Always when I'm busy.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
She's in the pool.
- What took you so long?
- I knew it was you.
I keep forgetting
how young you are.
What a waste of a sports car.
Listen, everything's
going to be all right
How'd this get in here?
Why do you always tie
these double knots?
Kevin, please
forget the knot.
What I need
is a little sympathy.
I had my heart set
on that summer job.
Oh, Terry.
I know exactly
how you feel.
Can I tell you a little story?
When I was a kid,
I was obsessed
with being a fireman.
I set little fires
in the backyard,
and I practiced
putting them out.
Then one day,
when... I was 12,
I learned I could
never be a fireman.
Why, what happened?
I found out how much
money they make.
Pitiful.
Don't you understand
that I don't care
what reporters make?
I can't remember a time
when the was anything else
I wanted to do,
and it's pretty
discouraging
when Raymaker tells me
that I should
become a model.
Why not?
You're a knockout.
Besides, models make
some pretty nice bucks.
You don't think
I can do it, either.
Well, no, that's not exactly
what I said...
Exactly.
Yeah, well, itas close enough.
You know,
it's lucky for you
I'm in love with you,
I think,
or I'd probably never
speak to you again.
I'd like to be
alone, please.
Now?
Can't you be alone when your
parents are home?
Since you haven't listened
to one word I've said,
why don't you try
reading my lips.
Goodbye, Kevin.
Would you rather spend the night
at the frat house?
[♪]
All men care about is sex.
I resent that.
Big improvement, huh?
The room
needed something.
Your room is why
my life is totally
screwed up.
You guys think beautiful women
are nothing but decoration,
total airheads.
Hey, not me.
These women have
my deepest respect.
For showing
their boobs?
And for their minds.
It just so happens
that Kim here
reads Vonnegut
in her bubble bath,
and Louann has
dedicated her centerfold
to help clean up
toxic waste,
and the only reason
Barbara does her physics
homework buck-naked
is 'cause that
library's hot.
Come on, Buddy
admit it.
You would love to
spend your entire life
just using
women's bodies.
Yeah, all but
the last 60 seconds.
I'd like a little time
to reminisce.
Can't you think of anything
more profound than getting laid?
A blowjob?
I'm sorry.
This is the perfect end
to my day.
I mean, it's as if
women's lib never existed.
Today's woman has the freedom
to be just as sick and perverted
as us guys.
Oh, that's wonderful.
I mean, I write
an excellent article,
and just because I'm... cute,
no one takes me seriously.
It's not fair.
And yet somehow you find
the courage to go on living.
You got guts.
Sometimes I just wish
I were a guy.
No, you don't.
The male body needs
sex at all times.
It's a living hell.
I bet if a guy turned in
the same exact article,
it would be at
the Sun-Tribune right now.
Yeah, no kidding.
Hey, does Miss April
look straight?
[DOORBELL RINGS]
What are the odds of this being
a homeless nymphomaniac?
Is your sister home?
Yeah.
Hey, Terry,
you got company.
Terry?
Why am I
brain-damaged?
I just fooled
my own brother.
Hey, I wasn't
paying attention.
Now I am.
Hello, Terry.
I think I can
pull this off.
This morning
I knew her.
I talked to her.
She screamed at me.
Everything was great.
Now she's wearing my clothes.
Hey, who do you think you are,
Tootsie?
No.
Okay, Yentl?
What do you
want to be, a rabbi?
Just tell me what's wrong.
Really?
Okay. Well, uh...
Look how you're
standing.
I mean, drop
your hands.
Okay, now stick
your hip in.
All right, now move
your feet apart.
Hey... Guys
take up space.
All right, now, you've
got to look tougher.
Very crucial.
Something
every guy does.
Let me see you
scratch your balls.
Come on, try it.
Wait a minute.
Watch the master.
Now, first, there's
your basic shift...
But that's not
always enough.
Sometimes, you've
got to get inside,
dig a little,
let some air in,
move things around.
Yeah, well,
maybe my balls don't itch.
All balls itch. It's a fact.
Well, maybe this would help.
Not bad.
Shit. Maybe I
should try that.
Okay.
Let's see you walk.
Hold it.
Look, you got
balls now.
Use them.
Say, baby, what's happening?
I'm a lean, mean, sex machine,
and that be the way it is.
Say, baby,
what's happening?
I'm a lean, mean,
sex machine.
and that be
the way it is.
I think you'll pass
as long as you don't move.
I'm going to do it.
I'm going to take
that article
to Sturgis-Wilder,
and I'm going to submit it
as a guy.
It makes perfect sense.
You got a problem,
you get in drag.
You don't think I can do it,
do you?
No way...
But d love
to see you try.
Hey, how you doing?
We'll talk more later.
Once you're into
power blitzing,
doing super sets is
like jerking off.
The key is to work out
every possible minute.
Like, say you don't
have any weights?
You use freshmen.
I'm serious.
Excuse me! This'll
just take a minute.
Okay, get
a good grip,
bend your knees
and lift.
One, two. One, two...
[GRUNTING]
Hey, no pain,
no gain.
This is great
for the deltoids.
Thanks, kid.
Happy to help.
Who invited you?
Uh... I'm new here.
Just what we need,
another pussy.
Strong as an ox,
and almost as smart.
- Ooh...
Another good exercise
for upper body strength...
The pussy toss, for distance.
Hey, get off me!
Get off me right now!
Ow! Watch the prickers.
Damn!
Great bunch of guys.
I see you met
Greg Tolan.
He kind of
runs the school.
I'm Rick Morehouse.
Try not to
get us confused.
Willy, give us a synopsis
of Catcher In The Rye.
[MAKING ALIEN NOISES]
Catcher In The Rye...
A novel written by
the earthling Salinger
that every adolescent
Homo sapiens in America
is forced to read.
You didn't read it,
did you?
Our mission
on your planet
is to study human
behavioral patterns.
Last night, we simulated
a daily teenage ritual,
homework avoidance.
We consumed
large quantities
of fermented hops,
and were transformed
into degenerate
party animal headbangers.
[SILLY ALIEN LAUGHTER]
Can I go
to the restroom please?
Three minutes.
I don't care what galaxy
you two are from.
You've been pulling
this routine
for three years.
You'll be here
another year
if you don't
straighten up.
I want that homework now.
The earth woman seems
so tense, irritable.
Too much coffee.
Not enough sex.
[SPEAKING ALIEN]
[♪]
♪ On the streets people talk ♪
♪ All the strangers
That you meet ♪
♪ Watch you move,
how you walk ♪
♪ Little secrets ♪
♪ Take it out face to face ♪
♪ Cross that line of fantasy ♪
♪ If you want
You can come along with me ♪
♪ One of the guys ♪
♪ Stick together ♪
♪ Reputation's
Out on the street ♪
♪ One of the guys ♪
♪ Hard to measure ♪
♪ When the love
is to start... ♪
Just finished.
I care.
♪ No one knows what's inside ♪
♪ Girl, you're hungry
For the dream ♪
♪ If you want
You can come along with me ♪
♪ One of the guys ♪
Yo, punch it, punch it!
♪ Reputation's
Out on the streets ♪
♪ One of the guys... ♪
Way to go, Big Ter.
♪ They stick together ♪
♪ Reputation's
Out on the streets ♪
♪ One of the guys... ♪
Table pressing.
Good for strength
and definition.
Full extension
is very important.
No pain, no gain.
Gotcha!
Uh, Coach Morrison?
One moment, son.
Bowling, uh... Great game.
The greatest,
but it's more than a game.
It's the ultimate challenge.
One man, one ball, 10 pins.
10 frames too.
Exactly!
Uh, you see, coach, um,
I just transferred here
from another school,
so I don't have
my gym clothes yet,
so I guess I'll just go
to Study Hall.
Hold it.
Everyone dresses
for my gym class.
Everyone.
Great.
I have surprise jock inspections
three times a week.
A word to the wise...
Wear it.
[GEEKS MOANING]
Hey, Yo, Mark!
Throw me a towel.
I hate gym.
I really hate
gym a lot.
I really
hate gym.
I don't like
the smell in here.
Excuse me.
Oh, it's spreading.
Have you ever seen
anything like this?
Never.
All right,
shower squad!
Get the new kid!
[SHOUTING]
[FIRE ALARM RINGING]
Everybody out!
Fire!
Take only essential
materials!
Hey, out
of my way!
We have a saboteur
in our gym class.
A real scum!
A nimrod!
Whoever started that fire...
Is a human gutterball.
A zero!
Sherpico...
how many times
have I told you
no creatures
in my gym class.
I couldn't
help it, coach.
If I left him
in the locker,
The alligators
would eat him.
You get rid of it,
or I'll get rid of it.
Shh.
It's all right.
It's okay.
He's just a little upset.
Don't worry about it.
Sit. Sit. Stay. Good boy.
I'll be back soon.
I'll take Willie
if you take Phil.
Okay,
come on, guys.
- Ahh!
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
Okay, shirts! Skins!
Shirts! Skins!
Ahh! Agh!
Got a problem,
son?
Oh, stomach... Shooting pains.
I ate in the cafeteria.
Come on, tough it out.
When life rolls you
a 7-10 split,
what do you do?
Go to the nurse?
No! Hell, no!
You aim for that seven pin,
and let her rip!
[SCREAMS]
All right, all right.
The rest of you
pinheads, play ball.
This is good work.
I knew it.
Thanks, Mr. Mendosa.
But I can't send it
to the Sun-Tribune.
What'd you say?
I can't send it.
Your writing skills are fine,
but, man, this stuff
is really boring.
You've got to
grab the reader.
Goose them
a little.
Right. Goose them.
Just because you're a guy
doesn't mean you can't write
with sensitivity,
with feeling,
with heart,
but you do show promise.
Look, I'm not going
to choose the winners
until a week from Monday.
So think of something exciting.
Try again.
Yeah, well, uh... Thanks.
DENISE: Terry, I hate
when you're depressed.
I mean, if you're this
upset over your life,
I should
be suicidal.
I mean, look what
Kevin sent you.
I'd do anything
to come home
and find roses.
Can we define the word
"anything"?
Maybe Raymaker
was right
about my article,
but I know
I can do better.
I'm just confused.
Of course, you're confused.
You're wearing my underwear.
Terry, forget it.
Come back to Pearl.
So you got
a bad haircut.
I mean, you've
got a great life
and a fabulous
boyfriend.
I can't give up.
And today was a disaster,
and I was a major geek,
but they all thought
I was a guy.
I was in the boys'
locker room!
You were?
Yes.
And they were?
Can I be your
younger brother?
There's a story here.
I don't know what it is,
but I've got
until a week from Monday
to find it.
Hey, what about
"Girl Gets in Locker Room,
Turns Stupid."
I can still
win that job.
I'm going to go
to Sturgis-Wilder,
and I'm going to start
making friends...
Any friends I can find.
What if Kevin finds out
you were in
the boys' locker room?
Denise...
Would Woodward and Bernstein
worry about their girlfriends?
No.
Anyway,
Kevin will never find out.
Unless I tell him,
which I would never do...
As long as Denise
cooperates.
Denise?
When pigs fly.
Never hurts to ask.
It's driving
me crazy.
I looked
everywhere.
I can't find the back
of my earring.
What am I
supposed to do,
walk around all day
with one earring?
That is so punk.
Listen, all
you've got to do
is break the eraser
off a pencil.
and you can use it
to hold your earring on.
Should get you
through the day.
Oh, thanks.
I have sisters.
We're in
the cafeteria.
Everything eats
and is eaten by something.
Don't take it
personally.
Remember when I--
Hi. Uh, I'm Terry Griffith.
Oh, hi.
I'm Harold "Reptile" Sherpico.
It's time to feed Snowball
his lunch.
Oh, Snowball. He's cute.
Oh, that's not
Snowball.
This is Snowball.
That's lunch.
They don't make
Snake Chow.
It was very nice meeting you.
Nice meeting
you too.
Want some company?
Want some
company?
Want some company?
Uh, yeah, sure.
I'm Terry Griffith.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I forgot your name.
Rick Morehouse.
Oh, yeah. That's it.
Last time we met,
I was in some bushes.
Right. Big fun
being the new kid, huh?
Are you new?
Two months ago.
Actually, I'm a professional
new kid.
Seven schools
in three years.
I really know
how to register.
Excuse me!
Hi! Thanks.
It worked great.
He knew how to
fix my earring.
That's because
he's a little tulip.
You know
Deborah Strowbridge?
Not really.
But, I mean,
she talked to you.
Deborah Strowbridge
is perfection.
Well, seems to me
like she's got a boyfriend.
Yeah, well, there's
no accounting for taste.
So are you a senior?
Yeah.
You going to college?
Well, I like music,
and d like to do something  i,
but I'm not too sure you have
to go to school to do it.
I dig music a lot too.
I like, um, The Clash,
The Talking Heads,
and Springsteen and Prince.
Oh yeah?
That's pretty cool.
Listen to this.
Look. What a fox.
Dresses like
Elvis Costello,
looks like
the Karate Kid.
I'm going to get him.
Severe intestinal disorder?
What's the matter?
You having a little
tummy ache?
What are you, a pussy?
Uh... My doctor said
that I should be okay
by a week from Monday.
So I guess I'll just
go to Study Hall--
No, you won't.
I have a little
job for you, son.
Here you go.
Hey, knock yourself out.
Hey, you look
like you could use two.
Dragon coming through.
Watch your toes.
Come on, Fifi.
Don't dawdle. Come on.
What are you
looking at?
Nothing.
Tulip.
Nice to see you.
Hi. I'm Sandy.
Terry.
Yeah, I know.
That's an incredible tie.
Where'd you get it?
At a store.
Bitchen.
So I guess
if you're new here,
you don't have
a girlfriend.
Yeah, well, I got one
back home.
Long-distance relationship?
Good luck.
Yo, Rick!
You want a ride home?
Uh... Sure.
Yeah, well, got to go, Sandy,
so I guess I'll see you around.
Yeah, you will.
She's pretty nice.
Yeah, but I got this one rule--
I never go out with girls
who say "bitchen."
Pull up right here.
This is fine.
Thanks for the ride.
Well, uh... What are
you doing now?
I don't know. Nothing.
Did you want to come in?
Well, I was
just going to--
I was going to tune up my car,
maybe play a little football,
but, yeah, I got time.
Okay.
Um, if my mom comes
home from work,
and she asks you
about my girlfriend...
Just so you know,
her name is Alice,
and she looks a lot
like Chris Evert Lloyd.
I just don't want her to worry,
you know, about my social life.
Yeah, but Chris Evert Lloyd?
It was Wimbledon Week.
Do you want a beer?
Yeah, I'll take a brewski.
So you don't really
have a girlfriend.
You guessed it.
What about
the prom?
What about it?
Well, yoknow,
it sounds all right,
Passion in Paradise,
you're renting out
that big surf place.
Don't you
want to go?
Yeah, but it's kind of
a romantic night.
I'd rather not
go with my mom.
Well, did you ask anyone?
Well, you'd better get going!
Come on,
who's your
first choice?
You ask a lot
of questions.
Rick, we're rapping
man to man about chicks
and shit like that.
You know, like, uh,
still a virgin?
I don't know.
You don't know?
Weren't you
paying attention?
Are you a virgin?
No.
Have you slept with
a lot of girls?
No.
Have you ever
slept with a girl?
Yeah.
Well, all right,
let's hear the story.
It's no big deal.
Um, just after
my dad died,
this friend of my mom's...
I think she wanted
to cheer me up.
She did.
Hey, is that your
room over there?
Wait a minute,
don't go in there.
It's kind of messy.
This is different.
I'm kind of into James Brown.
I guess so.
You know Prince,
Michael Jackson?
It all goes back
to James Brown,
the godfather of soul.
Not to mention,
Mr. Humanitarian, Mr. Dynamite,
and the hardest working man
in show business.
Ah, New York City, live,
Apollo Theater, 1962.
This man was king.
Well, let's hear some sounds.
I don't think so.
Stereo broken?
No, it's just
something I do by myself.
Huh?
Well, when I
hear James,
I have to dance...
You know, like James.
Go crazy. I can't help it.
And I'm usually
alone when I do it.
That's cool, man.
I can respect that.
How about another
brewski, okay?
Okay.
Budster...
The refrigerator
gives new meaning
to the word "empty."
Hey, don't worry
about breakfast.
This stuff tastes
great cold.
You agreed to do
half the shopping
around here
while Mom and Dad
were gone.
Yeah, that's right,
the second half.
Now, I'll tell you what.
I'll do the dishes.
Thank you.
I can see myself.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
I'll get it.
Hello.
Hey, yo, scumbag.
Hey, suck your own.
Eat me.
Hey, same to you, buttface.
Mom says hi.
Yo, Rick. How they hanging?
It's Terry.
Listen, I want you
to wear something really hip
to school tomorrow.
We're going to get you a date
for the prom.
Just do what I say.
Okay.
Yeah.
Bye-bye... Uh, scumbag.
Shit. He hung up.
[GROWLING]
This is your idea
of hip?
A guy who
is into James Brown?
Could we please just
forget the whole thing?
Now, there
is no reason
why you should
miss that prom.
A girl would bcrazy
to turn you down.
So come on.
Who is she?
Red sweater.
Cute shoes.
Huh?
Go for it.
Just waltz right up there
and ask her out?
No, you've got to...
say something nice,
like how pretty
her eyes are.
Girls eat up
that crap.
Come on.
Hi, Jeanine.
Hi.
I keep forgetting
your name.
Rick... Morehouse.
You know, I sit
right next to you
in civics class?
You have
beautiful eyes.
I'll bet.
Do you have a--
a date for the prom?
Of course.
It's next week. Why?
Official
prom committee survey.
Thank you very much.
Terry...
TERRY: This has got
to be the one.
You know why?
Because I've asked
everybody else.
No. Because I've
got this feeling.
True, I've had
this feeling before,
but this time...
Uh... Beth.
Doing anything, uh, prom night?
I'm going to the prom.
What about Saturday?
I'm busy.
Night?
How about Sunday?
I'm busy.
How about any
night in 1987?
I'm busy.
How about yesterday?
You busy yesterday?
I think so,
but you can
ask me out again.
Hi, Terry.
Oh, hey, Sandy.
Hey, word's out your friend's
desperate for a prom date.
He would love
my cousin Jill.
She's cute.
How cute?
Extremely.
She's got, like,
Joan Collins' eyes,
Christie Brinkley's
teeth.
Uh, well, what about
the rest of her?
Dynamite.
Rick has to meet her.
How about you and me,
and Rick and Jill
all meet up at the cave tonight?
We'll have
a picnic.
Uh...
Come on.
We'll have fun.
This Jill better be some girl.
♪ I want a lover
With a slow hand ♪
With an easy touch ♪
♪ I want a lover
Who will spend some time ♪
♪ Not come and go-- ♪
Buddy, can I borrow
your army jacket?
♪ I want somebody
Who will... ♪
What are you doing?
Just cleaning
the house.
Budster,
are you all right?
Huh... I am awesome.
Linda is on her way over.
Huh, huh, huh, huh!
Excuse me, Mr. Romance,
just out of curiosity,
does this girl
have any idea
she's coming over here
to, uh,
light up your life?
Well, technically
speaking, not really.
We'll probably start off
with some algebra,
but once I turn on the charm,
she's mine.
Hand me that massage
book, please.
Bud, why don't you
take the subtle approach?
You know, maybe hang
a couple of salamis
from the ceiling.
Hey, at least my date
is someone of the opposite sex.
I'm just seeing Sandy for Rick.
For Rick?
What happened
to research?
Well, that's
what I meant.
So for research,
you're willing to toy
with this poor girl's emotions?
All you transvestites
are alike.
You disgust me,
but of course, that isn't
the real problem here.
Oh really? What is?
Well, this Sandy
woman's hot for you.
What if she suddenly goes nuts
and tears all your clothes off?
That's what Craig Garfield said
Roxanne Doyle did.
Yeah...
What do I do then?
Call me.
I could be there in 15 minutes.
Wait, you can't call me.
In fact, you
can't come home.
You'll have to sleep
in the cave.
The cave.
Oh, God.
I want to toast
my good friend Rick,
a guy with a great
sense of humor.
And here's to summer.
I swear, sixth grade
is so bogus.
It's a joke.
Want to take a walk?
I think they need
some privacy.
Jill...
You animal, you.
Come on.
Hey, wait!
Where you going?
Hey, man, don't leave me now.
♪ I think I'm in trouble ♪
You kids have fun, huh?
They left me.
It's okay.
I'm still here.
Sandy... You tricked me bad.
Uh-uh.
You know,
in five years,
Jill's going to make
him very happy.
Yeah, I'm sure.
Nice fire.
Sandy,
this is really--
Shh. Don't talk.
Sandy, this is
a big mistake.
Maybe, maybe not.
There's only one
way to find out.
Sandy!
Sandy, really.
Sandy,
get out of there!
There really is a very
good explanation
for that.
I'm flattered.
You are?
But you don't
have to do this
to impress me.
I don't?
No. I like you a lot.
I think I'll take
one of those beers now.
It's okay.
I mean, how
small can it be?
Don't ask.
More Cold Duck?
Sure.
Hit me again.
If I give you
five bucks,
would you go
see a movie?
Lien,
you little squirt,
Terry promised
she'd be home tonight,
and I'm not leaving
till I see her.
If I give you
10 bucks,
would you go wait
in your car?
We're on number 22.
Let's keep going.
Bummer.
If the coefficient
of X
is greater
than that of Y,
and the coefficient
of Y
is greater
than that C,
then by the transit
of property,
what can be said about
the coefficient of X
in relation to
the coefficient of C?
Hold it!
It's time Kevin
knew the truth.
Terry moved to Oregon
to join a religious cult
that she saw on 60 Minutes.
It's all in the letter.
You should go home
and wait for it, Kevin.
Wait.
Two more problems.
If the coefficient--
Hi, Kevin.
Terry!
Back from the cult!
Where the hell have you been?
You're going to laugh.
I was upstairs
looking for this skirt,
and I fell asleep
in the closet.
What did you do to your hair?
Oh, I cut it.
Isn't it cute?
Cute? It's gone.
What are you,
drunk?
You are. You're drunk.
Now, what's
going on here?
We're supposed
to get together.
Kevin, honey, angel.
I'll make it up to you.
I promise.
When? Tonight?
Let me tuck you in.
I can't tonight.
I'm working very hard
on my article,
but I'll tell you what...
I'll walk you out
to the car, okay?
Gee, a walk
to the car?
Ta about
your wild nights, hmm?
Don't feel bad. It's okay,
because while you were up
in the closet getting drunk,
I got to do algebra.
Oh, that's wonderful.
Crazy kids.
Well, alone at last.
Why are you
smiling like that?
Because it's party time.
Let's dance. Let's get crazy.
Let's get drunk.
Let's get naked.
Buddy, I love
a good party,
but something about you
worries me.
Linda, you're a nut.
What do you like,
skinny dip in the pool?
Back rub in the bedroom?
Pick a sin. Any sin.
It's getting kind of late.
NoIt's early.
Bye.
Linda, wait! For God's
sake, I vacuumed, Linda.
Buddy, you're a nice guy.
No, not a "nice guy."
That's the kiss of death.
I'll see you in algebra.
Thanks for your help.
Linda, wait.
Would it make
any difference at all
if I said
I was hung like a bear?
It might. Are you?
No.
Just checking.
Goodbye, Buddy.
I like your hair.
That girl had incredible
self-control.
Kevin hates me.
Rick hates me.
Everybody hates me
except Sandy.
Oh, yeah, how'd it go?
Did you get laid?
I bet I came closer
than you did.
Years from now,
Linda'll look back on this night
and be very sorry.
Good night, Buddy.
Sorry, Spike.
Nothing much has
been happening, Ma.
Yeah, I did pretty good
on my history test.
Terry's become
a transsexual.
Yeah, she's starting to
grow hair on her chest.
Yeah, just a second.
Hey, Mom wants
to talk to you.
No, no.
Uh, she can't
talk, Mom.
The doctors
have advised her
not to speak.
Something hormonal
and vocal.
Besides,
she's hung over.
Yeah, she was out
drinking with the guys.
Okay, see you
in a week.
We miss you too.
Okay. Bye.
She thought
I was kidding.
Yo, Rick!
Hi, Terry.
Good morning,
Mrs. Morehouse.
Rick, your friend
Terry's here.
Sorry about
last night.
Hey, that's okay.
If I was in the sixth grade,
I think I would've
had a big night.
- Come on, we're going out.
- Let me guess.
You got me a hot date
with Sandy's grandmother.
No, no, no, listen,
I figured the whole thing out.
There is nothing wrong with you
except for the way you dress.
Terry, it took me an hour
to put this look together.
Yeah, so don't try so hard
next time.
Come on.
I don't have
any money.
I got plastic.
You can pay me back.
I just feel kind of weird.
That's because your
body's not used to style.
You'll adjust.
Hey, Deborah,
what's shaking?
Hi, Terry.
Hi...
Rick.
Yeah, I know.
You look a little
different.
The kid went
shopping,
got a haircut.
Welcome
to the '80s.
Very sharp.
Thanks.
Deb, what
are you doing
hanging around
these chumpstains?
Come on.
Let's go.
I'll be
right there.
Now, Deborah.
Just
a second.
Greg just likes
to act tough.
He doesn't really
hate y guys.
Oh, that's no act.
He truly hates us.
Deep down,
he's insecure.
Yeah, well, upfront,
he's an asshole.
Take it easy,
Deborah.
What was that,
a pity stop?
[SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE]
...pizza!
[LAUGHING]
Those guys are...
It's just about
showtime, boys.
[MAKING WHIRRING NOISE]
I'm picking up
curious life readings.
Is it human?
Unknown.
It seems to be
some sort
of carbon-based
douchebag.
Whoop! Whoop!
Whoop!
Not again.
Gentlemen, relax.
Sit down.
Too much stress,
it's not good
for your muscles.
Have a nice lunch.
Hey, how you doing?
Nice jacket.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Spaghetti, too.
I think it stains.
Did I miss
something?
Why didn't you slug
that asshole anyway?
He said he was sorry.
And you
believe him?
Benefit of the doubt.
Besides, the guy
can lift cars.
What are you doing?
What's it look like I'm doing?
Well, do you have to do that
in here?
It felt like
the right time,
certainly
the right place.
Terry, is this
a problem for you?
No, no problem at all.
I was just kidding.
It's just that you
looked so nice today.
You were perfect.
Hey, isn't
this great?
Isn't what great?
Well... You know, here we are,
a couple of guys
hanging out in the men's room,
leaning up against the urinals,
talking about
broads and fights.
Just like a couple
of guys, you know.
This is what you call
typical male bonding.
You know, like Butch Cassidy
and the Sundance Kid.
Oh, so that's what it is.
Yes, it's great.
I'm glad you told me.
I just wish that Greg Tolan
would join the gang.
Oh, man, I've had it
with that jerk.
You want to know
about Greg Tolan?
I'll tell you about Greg Tolan.
Greg Tolan is toast.
He can't get away
with this.
We've got
to get him back.
We and what army?
No violence.
No need to sink to his level.
You see, we have something
that Greg Tolan
will never have.
Intelligence.
You know, you're right.
I mean, we're smart.
Okay, Terry.
What do we do?
I don't know.
Me neither.
Hey, man, this
stuff'll kill you.
Try this.
You'll live longer.
Thanks.
Looks good.
I made it myself.
Can I finish
those fries?
Buddy?
Thanks.
What are you
doing here?
Looking for you.
Uh, Rick, this is
my younger brother, Buddy.
How you doing?
So. This is Rick.
I've heard a lot about you.
A lot.
Bud, what
do you want?
Guess who came by to pick you up
for school this morning?
Your true love...
Kevina.
Kevina was
very upset
that you left
without her.
You know how she worships
your rippling muscles
and your hairy chest.
Terry's such
a stallion.
Go on.
Show him your hairy chest.
Buddy!
Anyway, Kevina made me
promise to tell you
that she's going to
be picking you up
for dinner
7:30 sharp,
so you should look
your handsomest.
Thanks for
the message, Bud.
My pleasure.
Well...
I'm going to scope out
the local babes.
Hey, Rick,
stay real.
Take it easy.
You have a girlfriend
named Kevina?
Rather exotic,
isn't it?
Stallion.
Hi.
Can I be totally
honest with you?
Your touch
is the reason
why I went
through puberty.
Sit down.
Guys, I just
want to apologize
about neglecting you
yesterday.
I felt terrible,
and I just
want you to know
you're still my favorite people.
Sit down.
Man, Terry, this crap
has got to stop.
What are you
going to do?
Um... Excuse me.
Could I have
your attention please?
Your attention?
Every day at lunch,
we get a very
special treat
from a very
special guy.
A guy who has
dedicated his life
to building his body,
pushing his muscles to the very
limits of human endurance.
Why, you ask?
Why?
Well, to be strong enough
to lift tables and spill food.
Greg Tolan!
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
Whoa. Wait.
Let's take
a moment now
to find out
a little bit
about the man
behind the mess.
Greg! May I call you Greg?
Now, tell us, Greg,
how did you first
get into spilling food, huh?
Were you
a messy baby?
[LAUGHTER]
Did you hate your strained peas?
[CHUCKLING]
Well, you know,
most psychologists
tell us that guys,
well, they get into
body building
to compensate
for either a lack of IQ
or a small weenie.
Which is it, Greg?
Well...
those of us in Greg's gym class
certainly know the answer
to that one.
[LAUGHTER]
I'm going to beat the shit
out of you, Morehouse!
Greg, please!
Hey, isn't he great?
Muscles and a sense of humor.
[LAUGHTER AND MURMURING]
Well, let's
all thank Greg
for the many lunchtime
thrills and spills
he's given us.
All right,
everybody, up!
Come on,
everybody up!
Grab the end
of your table.
A tribute to you, Greg.
Lift!
We love you, Greg!
Everybody out!
Go on outside!
Now!
Hold it, clown!
Come on, Greg.
Greg.
Lighten up.
It was a joke.
People laughed.
Let it slide.
Stay out
of this, Deborah.
I am getting
real bored
watching you
push people around.
Yeah? Well,
stick around,
because it's going
to get real exciting.
You know,
Terry was right.
You are an asshole.
That asshole called
me an asshole?
Oh, now you want
to beat him up too, right?
No, I want to buy him
an ice cream.
[SINGING IN ALIEN LANGUAGE]
Can't you ever
just be man enough
to walk away?
Watch. I'll show you
how it's done.
Uh, you've got some
pudding on your shoes.
TERRY: You were
outstanding. Phenomenal!
So who are you going
to ask?
Don't start this.
You're practically
a celebrity.
I'm having
a really great day.
Please, Terry,
don't spoil it.
We've gone too far to stop now.
Just ask one more person.
Anybody.
And then I swear
I'll shut up.
Anybody?
Anybody.
Um...
This is, uh...
This is going
to sound crazy...
But what the heck,
you know,
it's been
a crazy day.
Would you like to go
with me to the prom?
Yeah. I'd love to.
Deborah,
I don't think
you understood
the question.
The prom?
I'd love to
be your date.
Hi, Terry.
I'm going
with Deborah.
I'm going with Deborah.
Yow! Huh!
That's really wonderful.
See, what did I tell you?
You're a great guy.
It's about time
some lucky girl
figured it out.
We've got to double.
Who are you
going with?
Oh, I don't know if I'm going.
You got to. Come on.
Sandy.
Oh, no way, man.
That chick is dangerous.
I don't need to go.
Yes, you do.
After all you've
done for me,
we've got to get you a date,
because, uh, Terry,
I'm not going
unless you're going too.
I mean it.
I'll tell Deborah right now.
I think I know
who to ask.
Okay!
I was wondering, do you have
plans yet for Saturday night?
I'm not sure.
Either I'm jetting
to Paris
or watching
The Love Boat.
Denise...
Will you be my date at the prom?
You are so sexually confused.
Please, just say
you'll go with me.
Why would you
want to go?
Because I promised Rick,
and if I don't go,
he won't go with Deborah.
Deborah...
I am such a jerk.
I thought the whole point
was to get Rick a date.
Yeah, but not her.
I mean, what could he possibly
see in her?
She's totally
wrong for him.
Too pretty?
No. She's trouble.
I guess Rick needs someone
a lot more sensitive.
More like you,
right?
Why would I want Rick
when I have Kevin?
Good question, but...
Do you like him?
Rick's not my type at all.
Sure, with my help,
he's come a long way.
He stopped buying his clothes
at Nerds 'R' Us.
I know you, Terry,
and you like him.
He's research.
My article's due Monday.
I've got a lot
of good stuff,
but I still need something
to tie it all together.
Yeah. You like him.
Denise...
Just say you'll go
to the prom with me.
I'll go to the prom with you.
Oh, thank you.
I want a limo.
And you can't
tell anyone,
not my friends,
not my parents, no one.
Deal?
Look, I'm not proud
of this either.
God. Look how low
I've sunk,
and you know
what's really sad is,
you're the best date
I've had in weeks.
How do I look?
Beautiful.
Kevin really loves
this outfit.
I want to look
really nice for him.
I guess you two haven't
had much time together
since the sex change.
That's cute.
Hey, Denise.
What's your rush?
We're young. We're wild.
Let's be young
and wild together.
I'd rather
get the phone book
and pick a name
at random.
Hi. Is Terry home?
Yeah. Come on in.
Hey, Terry,
you've got company!
Come on up,
I'm almost ready!
Hey, we can go
to your place.
It's cool.
I'm very flexible.
Oh, shit.
Terry?
Uh, don't come in.
I'm dressing.
Ter?
I'll be right out.
Hey, Sandy. What
a nice surprise.
These are for you.
They're kissing fish,
to say sorry
about the cave.
Yeah. I'm
sorry too.
[WHISTLING]
Hey, how'd you know
where I lived?
I followed you.
Why don't you go to Pearl?
Oh, I hate
that school,
bunch of snotty
rich kids.
Anyway, thanks
for the fish.
I'll put them
by my bed.
Oh, that's perfect.
Is that your room?
Oh, no, no. It's my brother's.
That's my room
over there.
Well, let's see how they look.
Help me.
I think they'll look
good over here.
Wow. Like,
this is where you sleep?
Do your homework?
Yeah, well, uh...
I like pictures of people.
Terry loves tits and ass.
These women
just aren't tits and ass.
Kim reads Vonnegut,
and Louann...
Louann despises toxic waste.
Don't let him
fool you.
Hardcore sex maniac.
Well, Terry treated me
with nothing but respect.
Very special.
Yeah.
He's one of
a kind, my bro.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Hey, I wonder if that
could be your pal, Kevin.
Yeah, Kevin.
Why don't you
go downstairs
and tell Kevin
I'm not quite ready,
and could he please
wait for me in the car?
I tried that once.
He doesn't like
waiting in cars.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Thanks for stopping by,
but as you can see,
I really am in a rush.
First, there's
something else
I have
to give you.
Oh, nothing could top
these fish.
Don't be
so sure.
Oh, my God, the fish.
Did you
feed them today?
Look at those
hungry little eyes.
They're kissing.
They're turning
cannibal.
Here, feed them this,
and I'll see what
I have in the kitchen.
Do you guys like pizza?
Buddy...
Kevin!
Ah, here she is.
What are you
doing here so early?
It's 7:30.
I'm right on time.
7:30...
I could've sworn
you said 8:30.
I'll tell you what,
I'll go get ready, and you can
come back for me in an hour.
Terry, you know
damn well I said 7:30.
You said you'd be ready
and dressed to kill.
So why do you
look like hell?
I don't know.
Buddy, can I see you
for a minute?
"I don't know?"
You're so great
under pressure.
Listen, there's
a half-naked woman
feeding pizza to some fish,
she's all yours.
Sounds too kinky
for me.
Budster, I need you.
She needs you.
You need her.
She really
half-naked?
Maybe more by now.
What if you're lying?
What if I'm not?
Good point.
If I'm not back in a week,
forward my mail.
Kevin, darling.
Hello.
Where's Terry?
Gone.
This isn't
the first time
that androgynous
sleaze bucket
has broken a beautiful
girl's heart.
I'm so embarrassed.
Why?
The room's full
of naked women.
Wait. Would you feel
more comfortable
if I took my shirt off?
What a nice girl.
Well, we can't
go to Giovanni's
with you being
dressed like that.
Sure we can.
We'll get it to go.
A long time ago,
I knew this girl named Terry.
She wore dresses and make-up.
e was hot...
And then, one day,
she disappeared.
Do you know
where did she went?
She's right here.
You know,
I'm still the same person,
and is that all you
care about, that I'm hot?
No, that's not all I care about.
Look, I'm under pressure.
My article's due Monday.
Terry, what is it
with this article?
I mean, it's nice
to have a hobby,
but let's
get serious.
A hobby?
I didn't-- I didn't mean...
Hobby, like, just a hobby.
I, uh... I meant hobby,
like, an important hobby.
Well, how do I look?
Dashing.
My zipper's open.
That was the dashing part.
Budmeister, are you okay?
No, Terry,
I'm not.
Mom and Dad come home Monday.
I've had two weeks
of total freedom.
The closest I've come to sex
was a girl who took her top off
to seduce my sister.
What's wrong with me?
Not a thing.
Listen, sex is not
that big a deal.
I'd like to form my own opinion.
It'll happen.
I know this place
that delivers.
Massage Delight or something.
Can I borrow $200?
Buddy, why don't you just
call the guys
and go to the mall?
I'd rather wallow
in my virginity.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
Buddy, you know
I can't answer it.
Please? This
is almost over.
Yeah.
Yeah, Terry's here.
I'll see if it can talk.
It's Mr. Wonderful.
Hi, Kevin.
No. I can't tonight.
Listen, we have to have
a serious talk.
Yes. It's about us.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
Listen, can we talk
about this later?
I got to g--
Bye, Kevin.
Mr. Wonderful
is Mr. History?
All right!
♪ Street-wise, tough guy
Born wild, don't try ♪
♪ Don't know if I asked ♪
♪ I knew it couldn't last ♪
♪ Warm crowd, small town
Wised up, pulled down ♪
♪ Just spinning my wheels
I guess you know how it feels ♪
♪ I feel a change coming on ♪
♪ Suddenly
Some love's not far away ♪
♪ Ooh, I had to learn
The hard way ♪
♪ From now on
Things are going my way ♪
♪ Ooh, I always learn
The hard way ♪
♪ From now on
We're doing things my way ♪
♪ Boathouse bar scene
Back room sleaze queen ♪
♪ I was just a boy
With a brand-new toy ♪
♪ She knew my mind
She seemed my kind ♪
♪ And she named her price
It was 20 twice... ♪
I'm having such
a good time.
No one here knows
I used to be fat.
Tell me again
how Rick and Deborah
belong together.
Rick and Deborah
What a crock.
♪ ...The hard way ♪
♪ From now on... ♪
He's doing it again.
He keeps giving me looks.
♪ Ooh, I had to learn
The hard way ♪
♪ From now on
Things are going my way ♪
♪ My way ♪
[♪]
Thank you. You're very special.
We'll be right back.
He wants to talk to me.
Do you mind if I go?
No. Really.
Go ahead.
You're a great date.
Hey, Sandy.
About the other
night...
I feel like a visitor
from the Planet of the Sluts.
Hey, that's okay.
We all make mistakes.
Hi, Deb.
Greg...
Can I help you?
Yeah, parsley
for eight, please.
Ooh, they're
so cute!
Yeah.
You know, I don't think
they're hungry.
Hi.
They really do prefer
mealworms or flies.
How could she
do that to you?
We don't have
a real commitment.
She can date
whoever she wants.
In the middle
of the prom?
[CROAKING]
Oh, there you are.
He's so excited.
It's his first prom.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Terry!
All right,
where is she?
It's that darn
cult again.
They have her
totally brainwashed.
Want to split
her records?
Look, you can
tell me now,
or you can tell me
in the hospital.
I'm suddenly
remembering.
If I tell you
where she is,
you got to
take me with you.
I don't want
to miss this.
Let's go.
Wait.
It's kind of formal.
I got to change.
Thank you. Thank you.
Well, as chairwoman
of the prom committee,
it's now my pleasure to announce
your prom king and queen.
The envelopes, please.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen...
this year's prom queen is--
[GASPS]
uh... Deborah Strowbridge.
Aw, fix!
Fix!
Hey, I swear to God
I'm not lying.
Okay, all right,
and, uh, this year's
prom king is...
It's Greg Tolan.
Yeah!
All right, Greg!
Way to go, Greg!
Congratulations, Greg.
Thank you, Deborah.
You know, now that I
take a good look,
they really do make
a nice couple.
Normally, we'd have
the traditional
king and queen's
dance,
however, as chairwoman
of the prom committee,
I've decided that
that's a stupid tradition.
So everybody dance!
[SLOW DANCE MUSIC PLAYING]
Come on, Rick!
♪ If I travel in the night ♪
♪ Can't find the way ♪
♪ Without a light ♪
♪ And the thought of you ♪
♪ The hardest thing
I'll have to do ♪
♪ I must be
Doing something right ♪
May I cut in?
Tolan,
you're a creep!
You son of a bitch!
I'm going to scratch
your eyes out!
Oh...
TERRY: Help!
You dumb ox!
You're in trouble!
Stop it!
Put me down!
Yah! Wo-aah!
Shit, where'd these
guys learn to fight?
Okay, tough guy.
You want a piece of me now, huh?
My back's not turned
the other way.
Nice tux.
You'll look good buried in it.
No pain, no gain.
[APPLAUSE]
Hey, Ter.
Buddy?
I missed you.
Terry, are you
all right?
Kevin?
Hey, Sandy!
What are you
doing here...
In a tuxedo?
Please go home.
I'll call you tonight.
Who is this guy?
Terry's boyfriend.
Who are you?
Just a friend.
Terry, we can
work this out.
I know you still
love me.
No, I don't.
I love someone else.
Whoa, uh, thanks,
but no, thanks--
Look, Terry,
we belong together.
You're my g--
Hold that thought.
Can I talk to you
for one brief moment?
I'll be right back.
What's going on?
Wait. It gets better.
Yeah. Big night, huh?
I bet
you're a little confused.
I think I understand.
I know I should've
told you sooner,
but, uh... I didn't.
Um... I'm a g--
Terry...
I know.
You're gay.
I'm not gay.
Wait a minute.
Now I'm confused.
I'm a girl.
I'm a woman.
Right,
and I'm
Cyndi Lauper.
Could we please
go back to
the prom now?
I'm a female, I swear.
Rick...
Wait a minute,
are those what I think they are?
I'm sorry.
Where do you get off
having tits?
There was this contest,
and I needed to prove it,
but then I stayed,
and I met you,
and you're so wonderful that...
Shit...
I can't believe this.
Rick, I know
you're mad,
but I think you're terrific,
and your friendship
means so much to me
that I just--
Then this whole thing
was bullshit.
Major bullshit.
Rick, wait!
You've got to understand
how much you mean to me.
You've got to believe me.
Right, Terrence,
because you've been so honest
up till now.
So how's the fish?
They're great. I put a frogman
in the bowl,
and you know what?
They really do
love pizza.
Rick, can't you
just forgive me?
No, I can't.
Rick...
[CROWN GASPS LOUDLY]
It's okay, everybody.
It's all right.
He has tits.
What?
Come on, Deb.
Let's go.
No, I don't
believe it.
Tits?
Whoa! 9:15 already.
Well... Gotta go.
Had a lovely time.
Have a nice prom.
Hi.
You're probably
here with a date.
Yeah.
[♪]
Night, son.
Buddy, why'd you bring Kevin?
Good evening.
Whoops.
Hey, no problem.
Just a couple of nice,
clean, all-American kids
experimenting with sex.
You remember Sandy,
the fish girl?
Hi.
Hello.
TERRY: You know,
my voyage of
self-discovery...
Has ended in despair.
Hey, that's
so interesting.
Really.
Could you shut
the light off, please?
I'm seeing Julian
again this weekend.
He is so cool.
I can't believe
I finally lucked out.
Denise, he is
the lucky one.
Hey, Terry,
is it true
you broke up
with that
college guy?
It's true.
You want to go out
Saturday night?
Oh, I'm sorry,
but I'm really not ready.
Well, what
about Sunday?
You think that's
enough time?
No. Thanks.
Terry, you have
to snap out of this.
I will.
It just may take me
a couple of years.
Terry?
I really liked
your article.
Especially the part
about how
you can be cool
even though if you don't
dress cool and stuff.
I feel the same way.
You want to go out
sometime?
Oh... I'm really
not ready yet,
but thanks anyway.
Shelley,
wait up.
Terry!
Can you come
in here, please?
Mr. Raymaker...
Come on
into my office.
I read your article
in the Sun-Tribune.
Congratulations
on winning.
Thanks.
It was real good,
and I'm sorry I misjudged you.
You don't have
to apologize.
I wouldn't have this job
if it weren't for you.
I mean, you forced me to fight
for what I wanted,
and I will never forget you
for that.
Thank you.
I learned a lot too.
What about that kid
you wrote the article about...
Rick?
He hates me.
Well, that's too bad.
You really like him, don't you?
Why do you say that?
I read your article.
Don't worry.
I'm a stunt driver.
I do this for a living.
Swift parking
job, Bud,
and you're late.
Yeah, I ran out
of gas,
but don't worry,
I put a buck's worth in...
on me.
Terry, it's summer.
Smile.
My face hurts
when I smile.
Listen to me,
oh, sister of my loins,
I've got
a driver's license
and a sex life.
You've got the job
of your dreams
and a chauffeur.
Life is sweet.
Let's get
an ice cream.
Uh, it's, uh,
for you.
You look very good in a dress...
Very good.
I thought you hated me.
I missed you.
I read your article.
Do you, uh...
still feel the same way
about me?
Yeah, I guess I do.
Well, hey, why don't we go out
and have some fun?
You know, like, maybe
we could go dancing
Friday night.
Wait a minute.
I'm the guy here.
Let me just
try this, okay?
Why don't we go out
dancing Friday night?
What an original idea.
Hey, you want
to go for a ride?
Yeah.
Come on.
As long as
I get to drive.
Come on, Buddy!
[♪]
♪ They say we're worlds apart ♪
♪ We don't belong together ♪
♪ But I've got this
Need in my heart ♪
♪ That careless talk
Can't sever ♪
♪ Now we're alone ♪
♪ And no one
Can take that away ♪
♪ You're safe in my arms ♪
♪ Safe in my arms ♪
♪ Don't go away ♪
♪ Say you'll stay ♪
♪ Tonight you're
Mine, baby ♪
♪ I'm going to love you ♪
♪ Don't worry
'Bout tomorrow ♪
♪ Oh, baby ♪
♪ Tonight you're
Mine, baby ♪
♪ Make it forever ♪
♪ Let's make it
Last forever ♪
♪ Oh, baby ♪
♪ Tonight you're
Mine, baby ♪
♪ I'm going to love you ♪
♪ Don't worry
'Bout tomorrow ♪
♪ Oh, baby ♪
♪ Tonight you're
Mine, baby ♪
♪ I'm going to love you ♪
♪ Let's make it
Last forever ♪
♪ou live your life
On the run ♪
♪ And I see you just a little ♪
♪ But as long
As I need someone ♪
♪ I'll keep a light
In my window ♪
♪ So promise one thing ♪
♪ Promise
One thing ♪
♪ You'll keep me
Inside of your dreams ♪
♪ 'Cause after tonight ♪
♪ After tonight ♪
♪ If I set you free ♪
♪ Set you free ♪
♪ Whoa oh oh oh oh ♪
♪ Tonight you're
Mine, baby ♪
♪ I'm going to love you ♪
♪ Don't worry
'Bout tomorrow ♪
♪ Oh, baby ♪
♪ Tonight you're
Mine, baby ♪
♪ Make it forever ♪
♪ Let's make it
Last forever ♪
♪ Oh, baby ♪
♪ Tonight you're
Mine, baby ♪
♪ I'm going to love you ♪
♪ Don't worry
'Bout tomorrow ♪
♪ I'm going to love you ♪
♪ Tonight you're
Mine, baby ♪
♪ Let's make it
Last forever ♪
[♪]
♪ Say you'll stay ♪
♪ Stay ♪
♪ Tonight you're
Mine, baby ♪
♪ I'm going to love you ♪
♪ Don't worry
'Bout tomorrow ♪
♪ Oh, baby ♪
♪ Tonight you're
Mine, baby ♪
♪ Make it forever ♪
♪ Let's make it
Last forever ♪
♪ I'm going to love you ♪