Sync and corrected by Elderfel
www.addic7ed.com
Fuck! Look at this thing.
- It's huge!
- (Laughs)
- I'm so excited.
- Yeah.
I didn't think I was
gonna be this excited.
I'm so glad we are done with
that fucking game, right?
Yes. Congratulations, by the way.
You too. Look at that view!
- Now that is impressive.
- This is amazing!
- Oh.
- Ohh.
- Ahoy.
- Hello there.
You know what? I'm gonna put the
whole Richie thing behind me.
I'm just gonna
have fun and geek out.
We should get
totally drunk in this.
Oh my God!
This is incredible!
Oh, it's my perfect utopia.
- Sailors giving out free drinks.
- (Laughs)
Hello, sir. Thank you so much.
You've made my night.
- Cheers.
- We fucking deserve this.
- Abso-fucking-lutely.
ANNOUNCER:
Welcome to "Naval Destroyer"!
(Cheering)
Congratulations.
But they keep telling us
that we have to expand
our demographic,
and then they force us
to make a game
where you can't even
play as a female.
And I'm a guy
and I always play as a female.
- But that's...
- And before you say it,
- it's not because I'm gay.
- Okay.
- There's nothing to be ashamed of, buddy.
- I'm not ashamed.
And FYI, this is the gayest game
in the history of the world.
(Laughing)
Right?
I mean, first of all,
there's a lot of seamen in it.
And from over here,
the title of the poster
looks like "Anal Destroyer."
Now you guys made it,
so it's not...
So why do you play as the woman?
Well...
maybe it is because I'm gay,
but not for the reason
you might think.
Women are the outsiders in games,
and I relate to that.
Gay people get it.
Does that answer your question?
(Mock British accent)
"Why do you play as a woman?"
(Laughs)
- British people are awful.
- The worst.
(Dance music playing)
Okay, move a little to the left.
- You're blocking my view.
- All right, jeez.
What should we talk about,
all right?
We want to seem nonchalant.
Let's talk about the Middle East.
No, he can't even hear us anyway.
Oh, shit. Okay.
What?
He has got a very gay laugh.
- Very gay laugh.
- You can't have a gay laugh.
Yes, you can. Believe me.
No no! You have to be subtle.
Shit.
- Less teeth.
- Okay. All right, bring it down.
(Clears throat)
Oh my God.
He is so gay.
He is gay gay gay.
The gayest thing
I've ever seen on two legs,
I'm sure of it.
How much you want to bet?
Two dollars.
- Two dollars?
- Yeah.
I'll bet you a thousand dollars
that man is gay.
- All right, deal.
- Okay.
All right. Oh shit.
Fuck. He's on the move.
He's on the move.
I'm gonna go get him.
- Calm down. Deep breaths.
- Okay.
- Keep it together.
- (Exhales) All right.
Cheers. You're about to
owe me a thousand dollars.
All right.
(Sighs)
(Militaristic drumming)
You gonna try it out?
Yeah.
- Do you want to play?
- Sure.
Whoa.
Are these things real?
Yeah, I think so.
That's cool, right?
Real torpedoes.
Ooh! It's cold.
(Chuckles)
(Clear throat)
Comfy?
Let's do this.
(Punching, grunting on TV)
You... are... seriously good.
Well, I fucking should be.
We have mandatory
play day every Friday.
- Ah!
- Uh-huh.
Didn't see that coming.
Good... fucking move.
Thank you.
So...
did you buy my theory from earlier?
Oh, about who plays who?
Sure.
Okay.
So, um...
who do you...
you know...
Oh, play as?
Yeah.
Do you play as the...
Fuck you.
- Do you play as the...
- As the woman?
Well, you know, the lady.
(Mock British accent) Do you play
as the British lady or the bloke?
Which one is it?
(Chuckles)
You're asking if I'm gay,
aren't you?
- Yes.
- Uh-huh.
I am.
I am... gay.
Okay.
That's cool.
(Chuckles)
Cool? Okay. Is that what it is?
(Laughs)
Yeah.
You know, we never have
any gay guys around here.
Not that I'm suggesting that
we're gonna hook up, of course.
Of course.
Unless, you know,
I let you win a couple more games...
Well, I have a boyfriend.
Right.
I was just trying
to be funny anyway.
Fuck you, fuck you.
So you're based in Seattle, yeah?
- Was.
- Okay.
Live here now.
I'm setting up a new team
now that you guys have launched.
At MDG?
Yeah.
I start tomorrow.
As in you could be my new boss?
(Grunting on TV)
(Sighs)
Well, that sounds very formal.
But... yeah.
I suppose.
It's true. Dean just told me.
He starts tomorrow, and he's picking
his team for "The Infinite."
Oh, fuck.
Owen, you have no idea.
I'm sure you were fine.
No, I asked out my boss
while straddling a torpedo.
(Laughs)
And he said no.
I don't know why you're laughing.
If I don't get on his team,
neither do you.
(Seriously)
You need to apologize.
(Sighs)
(Distant laughter)
Fuck.
(Trolley bell dings)
DORIS:
Okay, you are freaking me out.
- Seriously.
- Why, because I'm in a good mood?
Yes. I don't think
I've seen you this perky
since you dragged me
to see "Miss Congeniality,"
and that was a very long time ago.
What can I say?
I'm in a good mood.
Oh, stop it.
(Laughs)
You know what?
(Humming)
In some weird fucked up way,
I think seeing Ethan has kind of...
not helped me, because I don't want
to give that motherfucker credit.
- Yeah, exactly. And you shouldn't.
- Yeah, but it has,
and you're just gonna
have to embrace that.
Oh, I will. I will.
It's like a lunar eclipse.
I'm gonna get my shades
and a picnic.
I'm gonna take this in.
It's gonna make me go blind.
Why the picnic?
I don't understand.
(Dance music playing)
I think I'm finally gonna do it.
Do what?
You know.
Peri-peri?
Yep.
The restaurant?
Where are you, really?
Yeah, and don't say I'm crazy.
No, I wasn't gonna say that.
I think that's a great idea. I do.
I think it sounds amazing.
But... and I hate to say this, but...
How?
I have my plans.
She's killing me.
Where'd you get these placemats?
I stole them... from Target.
In Oakland a week and
she's already a hood rat.
Well, you know, I gots
to take care of my man.
So, uh, I want to skip work today
and stay home and practice.
You want to hang out?
I want to play you something.
I can't. After spending three weeks
putting up Stina's piece of shit,
now I gotta take it
back down again.
Mmm! I was, um...
talking to Pauline
about her gallery space,
and she... What?
Don't even think about it, Franklin.
No no.
She was just asking if you had
anything you wanted to show,
so I just thought I'd ask.
Come on. There's no way
she asked you that.
She did. I'm asking you.
If you don't have anything to
show, it's not a big deal.
- Well, I don't. You know that I don't.
- I know you don't.
But maybe you could.
We could clear out the shed.
I never use that
stupid weight bench.
Yeah, maybe you should.
Yeah.
I need to work out more.
(People chattering)
(Knocks)
KEVIN:
...by your department.
So I'm...
I'm doing that right now.
Uh, so...
When it comes to the...
Do you know what?
Do you have an extension?
I need to call you back.
Great. I will call you back later.
Thank you so much.
Okay, bye-bye.
- Hello, Patrick.
- Hi.
Um...
- Good morning.
Listen, I hope you don't mind.
I just wanted to come in
and apologize for last night.
For what?
Well, you know,
I was a little drunk,
and I hope that I
didn't come across as...
As...?
Well, as you know,
one of those guys
that...
(Inhales sharply)
Yeah, it's fine. It's fine.
I should have told you
I was starting here
before you went too far.
Thank you.
Listen, I would also love it
if you could consider me
and my lead artist Owen
for the new game.
I know you guys are just getting started...
Yeah, it's not early days,
unfortunately.
We've got a very short
development window.
That's perfect.
- Then I'm your man.
- Yeah?
Well, it will be 24/7.
Would you be okay with that?
- Absolutely.
- Are you sure?
Yes.
Because I was checking out
your performance earlier.
- Well then you'll see...
- Do you realize we log
all of your internet activity here?
- What?
- And it seems
you've been visiting
certain websites... a lot.
Uh, OKCupid...
and... what is it?
Is it ManCunt?
Uh, ManHunt, actually.
I was just showing Owen.
It was just educational.
Sorry about that.
I read that wrong.
Uh, no, that's fine.
I mean, I wouldn't
worry about it too much.
Just... just be careful
what you look at during work hours.
Sends a certain message.
(Cellphone ringing)
- Shit.
- Take it. I've got to make a call anyway.
It was good to see you again.
(Stammers)
Okay, that was really bad timing.
No, not today.
No, I can't. Today's not good.
(Sighs)
Okay, I'll be there.
(Drill whirring)
STINA: You've got to be
more careful with this.
I was careful.
Seriously,
I don't want to get to London
and find that nothing fits
and it all looks like shit.
(Scoffs)
(Drill whirrs)
If you have something
to say about the work,
you should just say it.
Come on, Stina. There's no point in
commenting on a finished piece.
It's not your best work.
If I'm really being honest,
I don't like it.
STINA:
Why?
(Sighs)
Look at it.
It's a bunch of
furniture stacked up.
It's got no meaning,
it has no perspective.
It's like a chair apocalypse.
Four days before I show.
Thank you for that.
I'm sorry.
I was just trying to be honest.
I really look forward to seeing
some of your work in the future.
Oh wait, that would mean you would
have to make something, wouldn't it?
Fuck off, Stina, really.
Actually, yeah.
We're done.
Done? What do you mean
"we're done"?
I mean we're done.
I need somebody working for me
who actually wants to work for me.
Fine. Good luck in London.
I'm sure they'll love
your fucking chairs.
(Drill clatters)
Oh, then you have
a serious misunderstanding
- of the word "flattery."
- He took the time to search through
- your internet records.
- I know. Hasn't that been banned?
I know I signed some Facebook campaign
having something to do with privacy.
And what's wrong with having
a life outside of work?
This is San Francisco.
That's why I live here.
If I didn't want to have a life,
I'd move to LA.
Yeah, then you could
hang out with Ethan
and use Eastern Philosophy
to justify being a dick.
I just wish I could
control my stupid mouth.
Um, wasn't this lunch
supposed to be about me?
Oh my God, yes.
I'm so sorry, I'm so sorry.
I think it's an amazing idea.
- Really?
- Of course I do!
I'm excited for you.
It's about fucking time.
It's what you've always wanted.
- Yeah.
- Right?
Tell me how much you love chicken.
Oh my God.
I fucking love chicken.
- Right?
- It's the queen of meats.
- It is the queen of meats.
- It's the meat to beat.
(Laughs)
It's the meat to beat.
I gotta get to work.
Will you walk me?
- Sure.
- All right.
(Cellphone buzzes)
(Sighs)
Crappy day?
I got fired, so...
Would you like a job?
(Scoffs)
No.
Then it's a good day.
(Cellphone ringing)
Hi.
Yep.
I can do that.
Just text me your address.
It's 220.
An hour.
Great. I'll see you later.
That's a healthy hourly rate.
Well, people are into beards.
You should consider a career move.
I'd lose the icing though.
Oh.
(Chuckles)
So, um...
you're a...?
Sex worker?
You can say it.
Do you want my card?
I just got new ones
printed in matte finish.
Oh my God.
That's so professional.
Well, some people
are good with numbers,
they become accountants.
I'm useless with numbers
but very good at sex.
So...
You just... you put it out there.
You got no qualms
about telling strangers?
This is what I do.
If I was embarrassed about it,
I wouldn't do it.
TAJ:
It's a hard fucking sell, Dom.
Does anyone even know
what Portuguese chicken is?
- It's a peri-peri.
- I know that.
- Does anyone else?
- That's what Twitter's for.
Look what happened to Todd,
and he already had a restaurant.
And that one lasted, what,
for like three months?
That's because nobody
even likes meatballs.
Who wants to go out to dinner
and eat fucking meatballs?
I'm not saying yours
is not a good idea.
Taj, I get we need investors.
All right? I do.
But that's why
I need you on board.
Come on.
This is our moment.
We talked about this.
Dom.
I'm sorry, buddy.
I just can't risk it.
If they find out that
I'm leaving, I'm screwed.
But if you come up with the money...
Yeah, I get it. I get it.
I get it. It's okay.
(Sighs)
We need to figure that shit out.
You know, I heard
he already hired Joseph?
B.O. Joe?
- Yeah.
- Oh, God.
All right. You know what?
If we don't make it
on Kevin's game,
then we'll just look
at it as an opportunity.
Maybe this corporate environment
is choking our creativity anyway.
This could be our opportunity
to take control of our lives.
Are you talking about
being unemployed?
Are you crazy?
I'm Asian, all right?
Our DNA rends itself apart
when we lose our jobs.
It's scary and ugly.
We should avoid it.
Well...
We'll figure something out.
(Typing)
(Sighs)
(Lock clicks)
(Silverware clinking)
Hello?
(Indistinct chatter)
(Chuckles)
Hey.
What the fuck are you doing here?
I had a bad fucking day.
Oh, good.
Me too.
Want to get drunk?
No, I had too much
to drink last night.
You want to get Thai food?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
Your feet smell.
- No, please. Stop.
- (Laughs)
- I'm gonna order.
- Okay.
PATRICK:
Kevin Matheson.
Oh, I can't believe
he has a Wikipedia page.
I found him. Here he is.
This is kind of
a really good picture of him.
He doesn't normally
look this good, but yeah.
- What do you think?
- You want to fuck him?
No, I do not want to fuck him.
He's an asshole
and he made me feel stupid.
'Cause he wouldn't fuck you?
No, because he's an asshole
and he made me feel stupid.
And more than that, he's got
the wrong impression of me,
and I fucking hate that.
It seems like all I do lately
is give people the wrong impression.
I got fired today.
Really?
How is that not
the first thing you told me?
What are you gonna do?
Okay, stop asking so many questions.
Okay. It's just...
major news. Jesus.
I don't know.
Would you have sex with him?
- Yeah.
- Really?
With those ears?
I mean, those ears are big.
Yeah, he's like the white Will Smith.
(Pop music playing)
(Showers running)
AGUSTIN:
I mean, he owned what he does.
Oh, so you want to be
a prostitute now?
It doesn't seem like
a very smart career move.
It'd be nice to make
some money though.
Yeah, that's true.
Hey, do you think that
people fetishize thick thighs?
If I was a prostitute,
that could be my thing.
He was proud of what he does.
If I'm being honest, it made
me totally fucking jealous.
I'm good.
Jealous because people
pay him for sex?
When was the last time you heard
me call myself an artist?
Oh my God.
You say it all the time.
No, I don't. I don't ever say it.
I mean, not out loud.
I don't think that really matters.
When's the last time
you heard me say out loud
that I'm a level designer?
Yeah, but that's different.
You don't want to be known
as a level designer,
because you want to
be more than that.
True.
I can't call myself an artist,
'cause I don't do shit.
(Sighs)
- You know what?
- What?
I don't know if either of us are...
very good at being
who we think we are.
Maybe we need to
try a little harder.
(Pop music playing)
LYNN:
Is that to keep the energy up?
It's been a long day.
Sorry.
For what?
No one really likes to talk in
these places anymore, do they?
Did they ever?
Sure, they used to.
They had bands sometimes.
Food.
Still had sex,
but it was friendlier.
(Chuckles)
You always lived in the city?
Well, I wasn't born here, of course,
but... I heard the siren,
and west I came.
(Laughs)
I bet it was cool back then.
"Back then."
Suddenly feel like I'm 103.
- Oh, I'm sorry. (Both laugh)
- No.
No, but it was. It really was.
And then it wasn't.
I'm Lynn.
Dom.
Very formal, isn't it?
(Chuckles)
Seeing as how we're both
naked underneath these towels.
Yeah.
I have the florist shop on Castro.
Oh, shit. "Buds"?
Yeah, that's me.
Oh, man, you're like an institution.
That makes me sound like
the Gay Man's Chorus.
Everyone likes them in principle,
but no one wants to
hear them actually sing.
We use your flowers at Zuni.
- I work there.
- I know.
- I recognized you.
- Really?
Yeah, you're somewhat
of an institution too.
(Sighs)
Well, he's looking very determined.
Yes, he is.
You should go for it.
(Exhales)
I think I will.
(Chuckles)
We should grab lunch
or something sometime.
LYNN:
You know where I am.
(Sighs)
(Mouse clicks)
(Exhales)
(Train rattling)
- Hey.
- Can I talk to you for a minute?
- Yeah.
I want you to know that I
do care about this job.
A lot.
This is all I've ever wanted to do.
Okay, good.
But I also want to have a life,
and I'm pretty sure
that I can do both
and not let you down.
What's this?
It's a new build
for "Naval Destroyer"...
- Mm-hmm?
- ...with a playable female character.
Okay.
Take a seat.
Um...
You do know I was kind of
fucking with you before?
What do you mean?
You were always gonna
be on my team.
- Really?
- Yeah.
But commitment looks good on you.
All right.
(Keyboard clicking)
Let's play.
Sync and corrected by Elderfel
www.addic7ed.com