[Previously]Don't you feel like that new transfer student is kind of weird?
[Previously]There's been a lot of violence at school lately.
[Previously]That piece of trash disappeared! I'm sure that the current Ri Yin Wang
[Previously]isn't himself.
[Previously]Nobody dares to steal my things away from me.
[Previously]I saved the strawberry for last because I couldn't bear to eat it so early on.
"Angel and Devil" - by A’N’D
♫ Just because my heartbeat is tamed by you, it doesn’t mean I’m not proud. ♫
♫ Don’t be fooled by my gentle appearance, I can eat you in one bite. ♫
♫ Don’t be delighted too soon and plan your scheme. ♫
♫ Take it slow, we’ll make the world flow in my way. Hey, girls! ♫
♫ Squad, attention! Stand up straight.I want you to follow my style. ♫
♫ Telepathy, what is that? Girls, don’t believe in those. ♫
♫ Your performance is okay, but it’s still far from success. ♫
♫ Follow me. Raise your hands up! na na na na ♫
♫ Angel and Devil in town, ♫
♫ Angel, angel, angel, angel. Devil, devil, devil, devil. ♫
♫ If you don’t treat me well, then I’ll throw you away. ♫
♫ If you treat me too well, then I’ll eat you up. ♫
♫ I want more action, action. I want less show-off, show-off. ♫
♫ Don’t try to patronize us. We are angels. ♫
♫ I want more action, action. I want less complaints, complaints. ♫
♫ Then I want you to change,change for us, for we are devils. ♫
Angel 'n' Devil
Task Code 025
There's more!
This person isn't my dad!
That's weird. Why did I put it to vibrate?
[Gou Zhui]
[Da Wei Wang]
Hello? Zhui, what's wrong?
You called me and you're asking me what's wrong?
Only my dad and I are at home right now. Why?
Okay, I'll go wait for you outside my house.
Wait for me?
Okay, fine. I'll go right out. Wait for me.
You're home alone with your dad...
Ri Yue Wang!
Da Wei, where are you going?
Weren't you going to wait for Gou Zhui outside?
Aren't you afraid that he'll never be able to find you again by coming here?
You're not my dad!
Where did you hide him?
How old are you?
Still yelling for your daddy.
Hurry and hand my dad over!
Your capabilities
are even worse than my two daughters who like to play pretend all day.
You want to become the king of the Pure-Blooded Day-Walkers
and dominate the whole Copper Dimension?
Zhui!
Da Wei, are you okay?
Didn't you tell me that you were going to wait for me outside? Why did you run off?
I wanted to keep my promise,
but I was thinking that you would want to see me alive more,
so I made a run for it to buy some time.
Zhui, be careful.
He's Ri Yue Wang.
I know.
Your abilities aren't bad for a member of the Gou family,
but why are you with Da Wei as a loyal puppy who comes only when called?
Why not come with me?
I can give you double what he could give you. No,
I could give you a hundred times what he could give you.
You can't afford what he has to give.
Since that's how it is,
then don't blame me for doing things old-school style.
People can't have the things that I can't have.
Zhui, are you okay?
Run.
You're so heavy. I can't carry you.
Leave by yourself. Hurry!
You want to escape? Could it be that simple?
But if you could obediently hand over the Some Spirit Some Soul,
I could spare your friend's life.
What Some Spirit Some Soul? I don't understand what you're talking about!
You don't understand?
Do you really have to be punished before you tell me?
Zhui!
I already told you that I really don't understand what you're talking about!
Since you're so persistent, I'll just have to end his life first.
Who is it?
Me, A Tian Wang.
Zhui!
I used to think that that piece of trash was already ugly enough.
Who would have thought that you're even uglier than he is?
Let's be fair, okay?
We're clearly identical twins, but you could tell who looks uglier and who doesn't?
If I, A Tian Wang, didn't have that ability, how would I have survived as a mafia leader for so long?
We meet again, little friend Ming Wang.
The Ri Yin Wang whom I met was you, right?
Bingo.
Did you know that
your father wasn't really as strong as people said he was?
- Because I easily killed him!- You!
You liar! If you hadn't used tricks back then,
you wouldn't even have been able to touch You Wang.
So what if I used tricks?
The winner is the king, and the loser is the servant. I was the one who survived.
Who cares if you're the king or the servant?
I just want to ask you why you had to kill Xiao Yang.
Oh, her.
My daughter returned Xiao Yang to you, didn't she?
Don't you know what you're talking about?
Because of you, Xiao Yang will never be able to come back!
- Dad! - Boss!
That's enough.
Since things turned out like this today,
I'm bored. I'll come back
another day.
Be patient. You two are no match for him.
Come help bring the Dimension Leader's soldier back.
Dimension Leader?
Uncle, Zhui--
It's okay. His chi is just temporarily locked up.
We'll just give him an "A Tian Wang's Pill for Replenishing Chi",
and he'll be as good as new by tomorrow.
Take him away.
♫ I want more action, action. I want less complaints, complaints. Then I want you to change, change for us, for we are devils. ♫
[A Tian Wang's Pill for Replenishing Chi][Impressive]
Gou Zhui, are you okay?
I'm fine,
as long as this guy doesn't come bother me again.
My uncle must have captured my dad. What do I do?
Even if he's been taken by Ri Yue Wang,
I don't think he'll do anything to Ri Yin Wang yet.
Gou Zhui, did you say anything to Xiao Xiong before he left?
I just told him to pay more attention to your boss, Gabriel.
So the reason why we can't be in contact with Xiao Xiong is Gabriel?
Aren't you curious of who Gabriel really is?
How could he fulfill your wishes? Is he really a good person?
If he is a good guy, then why did he have to make contracts with you,
and make you guys risk your lives to collect seeds?
What are you trying to say?
If my guess is correct, then Gabriel is Ri Yue Wang.
So my uncle didn't only capture my dad,
but he also took Classmate Xiong Ya?
What exactly does he want?
No matter what it is, it can't be good.
If that's how it is, we have to hurry.
We have to find Ri Yue Wang's secret base.
But how will we find such a mysterious person?
We need everybody's help to try and find him.
The more people we have helping, the stronger we'll be.
That stupid Ji An.
He randomly appears when we don't need him,
but when we really need him, he disappears.
[Tell?][Not tell?]
Ding Dang,
are you hiding something?
God!
Why? Why?
Why do I have to face something so difficult?
For the sake of world peace,
would I have to sacrifice my love? Oh, my god!
Ding Dang! What are you screaming about?
- Actually, I do have a way to find Teacher Ji An. - Really?
Really?
Yeah, because
I put Teacher Ji An under a black magic spell of love, [Black Magic of Love?]
- so whenever I call him, no matter where he is, - Black magic?
he'll immediately come back to my side.
My god, you put a black magic spell on Teacher Ji An?
That's so evil.
Hey, Zhui. Do people from Thai all know how to use black magic?
People from Thai really do know how to do these useless things, don't they?
Hey, it's not "black magic".
Listen clearly. It's "delivered like this", [Delivered Like This: correct]
not "black magic". ("Delivered like this" and "black magic" sound alike)
They sound the same when you say them.
Aiya, let's not worry about what they sound like.
Ding Dang, what are you worried about? Would there be a problem?
There is a big problem.
Forced love is prone to failure.
Once I use the Love is Delivered Like This,
and force Teacher Ji An to come back,
Teacher Ji An will always hate me,
and he'll never like me back.
Ding Dang, even if you used the Love is Delivered Like This,
it's not like Teacher Ji An will like you.
Hey, Xiao Yan! How could you say that?
You completely murdered my fragile, female heart, understand?
Ding Dang, we have to do things for the greater good.
That's right. For world peace, there must be some sacrifice.
(Thai) You guys said it yourselves.
(Thai) You have to do it, okay? Don't try to escape.
You guys said it yourselves, okay?
Come! Come! Come!
Hurry up. Come here!
Come!
Whoa, I don't want to.
Hey, didn't you just say that it was for the greater good?
I-- I'm dropping out of K.O. Bad Girls.
Hey, for world peace, you have to make sacrifices.
I promised my brother that I would go visit my dad.
Hey, what time is it right now?
It's far from the end of school.
O-Okay.
That's how it's settled, then.
Let's start.
Music!
♫ I'm so lonely, so lonely, so lonely. I'm so annoying! ♫
♫ I'm so lonely, so lonely. Hurry and come save me. ♫
♫ You are the one whom I trust with my love.♫
♫ I'm so lonely, so lonely. Hurry and come hug me.♫
♫ You are the cause of my reckless love. ♫
Hey, I think it's working.
Dropping from the sky? That's so cool.
What kind of inexperienced person called me here?
Why was the location of the call in midair?
- Teacher Ji An! - Hey!
Please let him be.
Also, please don't tell him
that you called him here, okay?
What? My first love hasn't even started and it's about to end.
- Teacher Ji An! - No!
- Teacher Ji An! - Calm down!
Love is Delivered Like This.
It's too tragic.
Why is it you again? You still dare to come?
- What are you doing?  - Forgive me.
W-What are you doing?
Let me go! What do you really want?
Let me go! What do you want? Let go! Let go!
What are you doing? I'm going to call the police!
Sister! What happened?
Hu Po?
Xiang Ning, call the police right now!
Why are you doing this?
It's not what you think it is. Let me explain.
You guys...
I'm sorry. I surrender.
You're laughing?
No, it's because you two are really so similar.
Why are you at my house?
Isn't bullying me enough? Now you want to bully my sister, too.
Xiang Qing, I'm really sorry.
I had to use you to let Xiang Ning come out.
If you're still mad, let me explain myself.
I'll let you beat me up later, okay?
Xiang Ning,
you finally came outside.
Do you how much trouble you caused me these few days?
Sister, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry...
You dummy!
Do you know how worried I was about you?
Sister, I'm sorry.
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Minions Of The Devils Team @ Viki
Stay there! Don't run away!
What is happening?
Stop!
They are my prey.
You're a Pure-Blooded Day-Walker, right?
I don't care what you do outside,
but this is school, which is also my territory.
I won't allow you to hurt my students!
Why can't I? They only know to bully weaker people.
What's the point of their existence?
You purposely made them bully you
to arose hatred form them.
Stop acting like a hero.
Unless you want a share, too?
It's fine. I can share some.
I already told you to stop!
You're a high-ranked Pure-Blooded Day-Walker? Why are you helping these humans?
Because they are my students.
Stop testing my patience.
You're the one who's testing my patience!
Based on your skills,
normal humans wouldn't be able to hurt you like this.
Who created these scars on you?
None of your business.
Listen up.
Don't let me see this happening again. Next time,
I won't let you go so easily.
♫ I want more action, action. I want less complaints, complaints. Then I want you to change, change for us, for we are devils. ♫
I wonder what's going on outside.
This should be the only exit to this cell,
but what should we do to release Ri Yue Wang's lock?
That's right. What can we do
to release that cloud and that fog?
Impossible.
Could it be...
Shao Hui! (Name of a song)
T-This... This...
♫ That cloud. That fog. That cloud. That fog. ♫ (Lyrics to Shao Hui)
♫ Take the sword of victory, break the chains, ♫
- ♫ and break all of the implications! ♫ - Together now!
♫  Break, break, break, break, break! ♫
That's how simple it is?
I don't even know what goes on inside Ri Yue Wang's brain.
Let's hurry and leave this place.
But-- This--
See? See?
I told you. I don't even know what goes on inside his brain. Boring!
Since Ri Yue Wang locked us up,
then this lock could only be opened by him,
but there's no lock on here. Could it be voice recognition?
Impossible. That's too old-schooled.
I don't think that Ri Yue Wang would be so uncreative.
How would we know if we haven't tried?
Since Ri Yue Wang has been unconscious for fifty years, he still might be living in the past.
You two are twins. You can try to imitate his voice.
I don't want to.
That's dumb.
It's okay. There's only us two in here.
No one will laugh at you.
You--
I--
Fine,
I'll try it, but if it doesn't work or if I don't sound like him,
don't ask me to do it again, okay?
I'm going to start now.
I say--
I say,
open the door.
See? It doesn't work.
Wait,
could it be another one of Ri Yue Wang's tricks?
Let's try it.
- You go. - Me?
Please.
Classmate Xiong Ya, wait for me.
[Mystery Forest]
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Minions Of The Devils Team @ Viki
Aiya.
Principal, there's no road there.
What--
What kind of crooked road is this?
Human beings are supposed to face forward and go straight ahead.
Listen to me.
As long as we find the north star, we'll be able to leave this forest by following it.
Believe me.
Principal, I think we've already been there.
Classmate Xiong Ya, haven't you noticed that
we're lost in this forest?
Principal, we're lost in here because
you keep insisting on going in straight lines and turning at right angles.
That's not how it is. Let me tell you,
this is definitely a maze created by my brother,
so that we'll never be able to leave this forest.
Principal, I really think that if we followed the mountain path,
we'll be able to leave this forest.
Is that so?
Definitely.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know that that's how things were. I misunderstood you for so long.
No, I'm at fault, too.
If I had explained myself to you back then, you wouldn't have had to bear so much pain,
but why did you have to lie to me?
If I hadn't thought that you were dead, I would have found you earlier.
Because nobody liked that ugly Xiang Ning.
I thought that as long as I turn pretty,
I'll be able to hide that ugly Xiang Ning.
That way, people will like me, but turns out,
I still couldn't deceive you.
No, I was clearly tricked by you many times,
but no matter what you turn into next time,
I'll always be able to recognize you.
Oh.
You randomly disappeared for so long.
I wish that other than playing, you didn't forget to accomplish some things.
Don't mix me with people like you, who play around while accomplishing missions.
Of course I left to take care of business.
Get back on topic. Tell us your plan.
There's a solution, but we'll need some help.
Right now, we could only wait.
Charlie Wang!
I finally found you.
What do you want?
I need to figure out something first.
What is it? Explain yourself.
There's no time. Come with me!
Hey! Hey!
But this isn't fair at all.
How come I, who wanted to die could live, but Xiang Ming, who wanted to live had to die?
Is Brother Xiang Ming's friend still at this hospital?
Are you talking about Jack? She's already discharged from the hospital.
The person whom Brother Xiang Ming said would be very, very sad for him
is actually Jack.
What in the world?
Allie! What are you doing? Don't do anything stupid!
Please.
Don't worry, I wasn't going to jump.
I promised Brother Xiang Ming
that I wouldn't do dumb and stupid things anymore.
Xiang Ming? Are you talking about Xiang Ming?
Are you saying that
because Jack was able to live, Xiang Ming had to die?
How is that possible?
If it was through the Concluding Contract, then it's possible.
That explains why Jack would rather die
than stay in the K.O. Bad Girls.
How could he? How could Ri Yue Wang do that?
He's a devil!
Xiao Feng, if he's the devil,
then what does that make the ones who made the Concluding Contract with him?
Allie!
How could you disappear without a trace?
Don't do that again, okay?
I'm sorry. I made you guys worry.
You'd better not scare us like this again, understand?
That's right. Who cares about that dumb contract? Who cares if it gets canceled?
I believe that as long as we're all together, with our combined willpower,
we'll be able to solve every problem.
That's right, Allie. Even if you can't walk again,
I'll carry you to and from school, right?
My legs are really sore. Do you want to carry me first?
- Come on. - Try it. See if she can do it.
You have to remember that in this world,
somebody would be upset because of the dumb and wrong choices you've made.
- Wait! Wait! Carry Allie first! - Brother Xiang Ming,
I think I've found that person,
and there's more than one.
And she went like this!
[Still in the forest~]
Seriously.
I, Ri Yin Wang, at this age,
have always fought against my urge to suck human blood,
but turns out, I'm being sucked of blood from mosquito right now.
I didn't think that my healing abilities would be used for this, either.
Oh.
Who would have known that that would work? Thank you.
What should we do? If we keep walking around, it'll turn nighttime.
Classmate Xiong Ya, come behind me.
I sense something unusual.
That's weird. This feeling
feels like deja vu.
♫ I want more action, action. I want less complaints, complaints. Then I want you to change, change for us, for we are devils.
An, have you been well these days?
Okay,
I, A Tian Wang, take responsibility of my actions.
I apologize to you. It was all my fault.
I shouldn't have blamed you for everything.
What's worse, I always called you a piece of trash,
but I'm so used to calling you trash,
so it's kind of hard to change.
Also, I was ignorant when I was young,
but lately, after a lot of investigation,
I figured out that turns out,
you have a twin brother.
The bad things that I thought you did before were actually all done by him,
so I apologize to you.
That's right. You were wrong. You were very wrong.
Growing up, I always thought that you were my best friend whom I could trust,
but how do you treat me? Huh? You--
You covered me with a bag!
Hey, l-listen to me explain myself.
Desperate times call for desperate measures.
You know about your OCD. You can't walk in those crooked paths on the mountains. That's why I had to--
- Stop! - I--
That's not the point, my friend. Wait, you--
Are you even my friend? Do you know
how dirty that bag was?
Don't you know that the germs on that bag could take my life?
You-- You-- Be fair, okay?
I did that to save you!
My god, there are hundreds of ways to save people.
As a mafia leader, couldn't you at least have bought a new bag?
You-- You-- That's murder, okay? You cheapo.
I should have just left you on the mountains to feed mosquitoes! Why did I rescue you?
You shouldn't have saved me, then. Why did you rescue me?
Don't rescue me. Don't rescue me. Don't rescue me.
I said it three times because it's very important.
Would this work, Brother Wei Yi? Are you sure?
No matter what, this is our only solution so far.
I'm looking forward to it, since...
Da Wei Wang, what happened?
I don't know. I just suddenly
feel like throwing up.
Hey, shouldn't you go to the hospital for a checkup?
Is it morning sickness? Who's baby is it?
Why are you guys looking at me like that?
Hey!
As a man, you should have been responsible.
Why are you trying to act cool? Explain yourself!
Also, you! Why didn't you help me explain?
Why were you looking at me along with them?
Da Wei, my son!
Who are you?
I'm your dad.
Don't try to trick me again. I won't be tricked!
You're a fake!
What could I do to make you believe me?
How about this, you name it and I'll cooperate.
Okay. If you're Uncle, no matter how well you understand my dad,
you wouldn't understand me, so
I'm going to ask you a few questions. If you get them all right,
then you're my dad.
No problem. Let's go.
Number one, what's my record of the highest number of hamburgers that I've eaten in one sitting?
[Time's up]It depends on how much money you have and how many you could buy.
Number two, do I eat the strawberry on strawberry cakes
first or last?
Y-You stuff everything in. If you stuff it in, there's no order.
[Time's up]Y-You stuff everything in. If you stuff it in, there's no order.
Number three, do I add sugar in my millet congee?
Millet congee... You don't like millet congee. You said that it's not filling.
[Time's up]Millet congee... You don't like millet congee. You said that it's not filling.
- Dad. Dad!  - It's me, my son!
[It's really my dad]
[It's really my dad]What is this?
How about it? Dad understands you the best, don't I?
I got all the questions right, didn't I?
No,
dad, you didn't get any of them right. You had 0 points.
How could I have 0 points? I graduated as a student of the Ivy League.
But dad, your habit of having to answer each question within three seconds
hasn't changed at all.
It's really my dad.
Dad,
good thing you're okay, or else... I have to throw up.
You child... Throw up?
Da Wei, what's wrong?
I don't know, either. I keep having to throw up these days.
Have you been eating the vitamins that I gave you?
Yeah, but you haven't been here these days, so I ran out and I didn't know where to go buy more.
Oh, no. The Some Spirit Some Soul can't be suppressed any longer.
Dad, what are you doing?
Oh, it's nothing.
Don't worry, I'll go buy some more vitamins for you.
You'll get better after you've replenish your nutrients.
I found it, didn't I?
Dad, is that why you purposely let Ri Yin Wang escape?
My dear brother, you want to fight with me? You're still lacking too much.
The smoke has already risen.
Do you know what to do now?
Yes, I won't disappoint you.
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Minions of the Devils Team @ Viki
You're really gone.
I can't sense you anymore.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't protect you.
Xiao Xiong.
We heard that you and Principal were captured by the devil.
Good thing you're okay.
I'm sorry. I made you guys worry.
Aiyo, it's okay. We're glad you're back.
Let's go eat and celebrate now.
Yay!
Yeah, it's about time we celebrate. We're all back together.
K.O. Bad Girls, I have something to tell you guys.
Xiao Xiong, so many things happened lately.
We have a lot of things to tell you, too.
Let me go first.
K.O. Bad Girls,
I'm going to give you guys one last command.
Why is it the last one?
The K.O. Bad Girls,
from this moment onward,
will disband.
What?
Disband?
Xiao Xiong, why are you saying that?
Because I made the Concluding Contract with a demon.
I caused you guys to become used by demons.
Our so-called justice
was actually just helping the evil.
Xiao Xiong, we've already known that.
Even if that were true, we don't have to disband.
Also, we need to unite the most right now to defeat Ri Yue Wang.
I won't let you guys risk your lives for me again.
I brought all this pain unto you guys.
I'll bring everything back to its original position.
Please accept my last act of selfishness.
I'm sorry. I want you guys to return to the peaceful lives that once belonged to you,
away from the demons that Gabriel and I brought to you.
Welcome back.
Please let the K.O. Bad Girls return to their original, peaceful lives.
What did Xiao Xiong mean by that?
Why did he say that he could promise
to return our original lives to us?
Do you not want to return to your original life, then?
It's you.
I'm here to return your shoes.
I already told you that you could keep those shoes.
I won't use them.
You'll use it very soon.
Hey, wait.
Name.
I still don't know your name.
Why do you want to know my name?
Aren't we friends?
Isn't it very weird for friends not to know each others' names?
I'm Allie. What's your name?
Are we friends?
Of course.
This is my first time
hearing that somebody wants to be my friend.
My name is Tu Mi. Tu Mi as in the blackberry roses.
It represents that all good things end when they reach me.
You can't trick me.
Don't judge me by what I'm like right now. I actually skipped a lot of grades.
Blackberry roses are flowers grown in heaven.
The people who have seen these flowers are removed of all evils,
just like the feeling that you give off.
Removed of all evils?
How is that possible?
Hey, where are you going? I wasn't done talking!
My legs...
Why don't they hurt at all?
[Preview]You're still hiding yourself? Show yourself, Ri Yue Wang.
[Preview]Classmate Xiong Ya?
[Preview]Tu Mi?
[Preview]Sorry, but I won't have mercy.
[Preview] Your death is coming.
[Preview]If we keep this up, we'll all die.
[Preview]Enough! Stop hurting everybody here!
[Preview]Da Wei, you can't!
"Just Lose It (Hurt So Much)" - by Pets Tseng
♫ My dear one, I really miss you. ♫
♫ I really want to embrace you. ♫
♫ I’ve already changed into the thousand wisps of the breeze. ♫
♫ I’m flying towards the limitless and boundless blue sky. ♫
♫ I’ve only lost a little, tiny bit, ♫
♫ yet my wound won’t stop festering and hurting. ♫
♫ Watching you sleeping soundly, I sit there all night, staring as my tears flow. ♫
♫ I really wish I could wrap you in my embrace and comfort each other. ♫
♫ I’ve already lost all of my dignity, ♫
♫ so I can no longer meet you, face to face. ♫
♫ But I still beg God to have pity on me, and let me return to your side. ♫
♫ Just once, I want to enter into my dreams and hold you ♫
♫ and cry. ♫