Love scene no. 1
Here I lie.
The rain is falling on my face.
But I feel nothing.
In a moment they'll bring white tape
to mark out my profile.
A good shot:
The victim in the rain.
Direct flash. Razor sharp.
The woman.
There always has to be a woman.
There she is.
Dear Mette...
...I don't know where I am going.
Only that I've got my back
against the planet...
...and I'm on my way away.
Love scene no. 2
We could go to Polynesia.
Have we won the lottery?
If we forgot about a new car?
I am not driving another foot
in that old wreck.
New car, new flat, new lamps,
new paint. Everything is new.
The Paracetamols.
This new stuff makes us old.
Do you know where they are?
Yes. Near the Equator.
Uh?!
Here.
How many times have we made love?
If we say the first five years
about five times a week.
The next five, maybe twice.
2000 times?
It's not enough, damn it.
What are you doing?
Love scene no. 3
I am afraid.
No, no, no...
Here.
Or I won't be able to see you.
I love you.
JUST ANOTHER LO VE STORY
Tibetan monks think
that sexual abstinence
gives absolute insight.
- Mette, are you asleep?
- Yes.
Shall we go into the living room?
Why?
All I could see was darkness.
But from bed height
I could see a long way.
My agents reported back
on everything...
The secretive coasts of Polynesia.
The deserts of Arizona.
The reefs of the Dead Sea.
I was king of the world,
and my throne stood far
to the north in a tiny country
that called itself Denmark.
In a new flat that smelled
of fresh paint
in a faceless new part of town,
mortgaged up to the hilt,
and with a battered old car
in the car park downstairs.
Two lovely children,
Klara and Frederik.
And my beautiful wife Mette.
And a job that was slightly unusual.
Daddy, what's your job?
I work for the police.
Daddy photographs
dead bodies, Klara.
Here.
You can photograph dolly, then.
Yes.
Hold her steady.
She certainly resisted.
Joking helps you to survive.
"Manicure from hell. "
But Poul just wasn't funny.
Frank often wondered
which was the scarier:
Poul or the crimes.
He beat her unconscious
and then he pushed the skewer in.
And then he kicked it.
Where is he?
Upstairs with the children.
The children?
They didn't mention any children.
"I love Malthe, Tulle and Charlotte,
so we are going away together. "
"Up yours. "
Four spelling mistakes
in three sentences.
I had always wanted
to be a photographer,
ever since I was 14.
I wanted to photograph
the beauty of the world.
To fly across the world
in a helicopter,
and photograph downwards.
Landscapes.
Not dead children.
I didn't know a thing about Julia.
But I'd end up loving her.
With unbridled passion.
That was how you loved Julia.
Like in a movie. Dramatically.
Exaggerated.
A chance meeting.
A moment of madness...
...and the world
as you know it vanishes.
Julia was on the run.
Not from a grey humdrum existence,
but from a sharp, black shadow
that had drilled into her neck.
Hello, Mommy. It's me.
No, we're fine.
We're still in Hanoi.
But...
I am coming home.
Yes.
No, I'll be on my own.
Sebastian has some business.
So he'll be coming later.
It's a little silly,
but there's so much going on.
Mom, I miss you.
Julia was on the run.
Julia wanted to get away.
Julia was definitely getting away.
All the way away.
Unlike me.
I never went away.
I was always on my way home.
We're going to be late again.
Why do I get this feeling of déjà-vu?
- It's a pile of crap.
- Yes. That's what I keep telling you.
You mustn't swear.
Yes, you may swear
at crappy old cars.
It's a pisspot.
- Yes, it's a pisspot.
- Come on, Dad!
There's nothing wrong with it.
- It's just...
- That's the fourth time this week.
- It's just what?
- It's just...
- It's stubborn.
- Yes. It runs in the family.
Crappy, lousy, stupid car...
Now, now, young lady!
There.
Will you do the shopping?
We need black bread,
yogurt, vegetables.
Klara needs a new drinks bottle.
- Hasn't she just had one?
- I chucked it out.
Why?
I read about plastic and cancer.
- Was that what it was made of?
- You never know.
Buy a metal one.
Okay.
Phthalates.
Honestly!
Oh, come on!
No...
Duck!
Don't look!
Close your eyes, Frederik!
Sebastian?
Everything is going to be okay.
I can't see.
I don't want to die.
I don't want to die, Sebastian.
It will be okay.
Get a blanket!
Easy now.
I can't see anything.
I don't want to die.
I don't want to die, Sebastian.
Here...
I'm a doctor.
Are they...?
Oh, God!
She went into a coma.
Did you check out her ID?
I don't have access.
I'll phone Bundgaard.
Am I a criminal?
No matter what, drivers approaching
from behind must ensure at all times
that it is possible to brake
if a preceding vehicle
finds itself in trouble.
But I still feel...
You were driving
an irresponsible heap of junk.
You nearly took it in the rear, Jonas!
Hi.
Poul, go get a nasty pastry.
I can't. I'm off to forensics.
She's Julia Castlund.
- Castlund?
- The art dealer.
Her dad owns the biggest
publishing house in Scandinavia.
She must be his daughter.
Her mother is Swedish.
She flew from Hanoi to Frankfurt
and rented a car.
I'm going to see her.
Jonas.
I'm partly to blame.
I want to see how she is.
Is she a looker?
Why?
Beautiful women and a mystery.
Isn't that how all film noirs begin?
I am looking for a patient
in Intensive Care:
Julia, Julia Castlund.
Are you family?
No.
Sorry, we can't disclose anything.
She was...
Didn't you hear me?
I can't help you.
Yes?
Julia Castlund?
- Are you family?
- Yes.
I am her boyfriend.
Hello.
I'm Magnus Castlund.
Should I wait outside?
I'm not sure I...
It's him.
Sebastian!
You're Sebastian?
We haven't heard
a word from you?
Frankfurt?
Did you fly via Frankfurt?
Or via London?
Why didn't you answer our calls?
We left thousands of messages!
You had business in Hanoi?
You came straight from Kampuchea?
Sebastian!
You've heard of mobile phones?
He's not as bad as I thought.
Angkor Wat...
The night you both phoned.
It was your first night...
Julia seemed transformed.
I'm sorry.
This is quite difficult.
It's difficult?
- Quite difficult?
- Yes.
He finds it quite difficult.
And this is...
Sebastian.
He's getting cold feet.
Now, then, Monica!
What were you thinking?!
Why didn't you tell the truth?
Listen, their daughter
was all smashed up.
They were all in tears.
It was fucking embarrassing.
It was only for five minutes.
And when the real Sebastian
shows up?
We'll take it from there, all right?
I just don't get
what you were doing there.
That wasn't even the worst of it.
You should've heard the doctor
when I was on my own with him.
The girl you knew was full of life.
This girl may be on a respirator
for the rest of her life.
"I see lots of people run away. "
I see lots of people run away
because they don't want
to be saddled with it.
"It's a matter of life and death. "
It's a matter of life and death.
"Will you help or will you not?
Don't break now. "
Don't break now.
"Do you understand?"
Sit down.
Do you understand?
Julia...
I am here.
We are together again.
I won't leave you.
But you've got to come back to us.
Kiss her.
Maybe...
Maybe she'll feel it.
- Kiss her.
- Yes.
Thank you, Sebastian.
Where are you staying?
At a friend's place.
Why not stay with us?
I'll be fine at Frank's, so...
But thanks anyway.
Call us.
Yes.
What did you do
while you were alone with that
defenseless woman in the dark?
What did I do?
Hold her hand?
Or... Where did you hold her?
That's so sick, Frank!
Hello, Sebastian.
My name is Irma.
I've come to wash Julia.
But you can wash her.
It's her armpits and between her legs.
And anywhere you can feel
she's burning.
Call me if you need me.
Sebastian?
Julia.
Sebastian.
Are you mine?
I have searched for you for ages.
Where have you been?
Round about.
Have you come home now?
Yes.
Till death us do part.
No. Nothing will part us.
Not even death.
Julia, who are you?
Where have you come from?
Why didn't I leave Julia right there?
Perhaps because my life
was just too real.
And Julia's was mysterious.
Beautiful women and mystery.
I expect that's what it was.
I was curious.
I was just curious.
What are you doing?
- I'm from the scientific support unit.
- Ah, okay.
You find loads of weird things
in people's cars.
I once found a pair of shoes.
And I found a Teddy bear.
And I once found
a whole tin of Coca Cola
nobody had drunk from.
I once found a dead cat in the trunk.
That was disgusting.
Did you find anything
in the trunk of this one?
Listen, it's important.
Yes.
- You did?
- Yes.
What?
What did you say his name was?
Sebastian. Christersson.
Sebastian Christersson.
You'll have to go back to tell them.
I... I'll just keep out of it.
And bump into the whole bunch
of them one day?
With Mette and the kids?
What do you reckon Mette
will say to that?
No.
I'd better go back, hand them the case
and tell them the truth.
Good thinking.
Dear Mr. And Mrs. Castlund.
I have committed a crime.
I came stomping in on you
like some clown in oversized shoes.
You were in shock, and I hadn't
the guts to tell you the truth.
I am not Sebastian.
I saw Julia's crash.
I wanted to see
how she was doing.
I am a photographer
with the scientific support unit,
and I found this case in her car.
Forgive this stupid misunderstanding.
I wish you all the best
at this difficult time.
Yours truly, a friend.
Sebastian?
Sebastian!
Have you talked to the staff in IC?
- No.
- You'll be so pleased.
You'll be so, so pleased.
Julia has come round.
But the chances of it returning
are pretty good.
Sebastian has arrived.
Sebastian?
Your Sebastian.
What are you talking about?
I don't know anyone
called Sebastian.
Julia, have you a boyfriend?
Sebastian...
Julia...
We'll take it slowly one more time.
Let's try again.
This is Sebastian.
Your boyfriend.
You met him in Asia.
You spent nine months there.
Oh, God!
I'm sorry.
I don't remember a thing.
Julia, Julia, Julia...
How are you feeling?
I think it'd be best for us
to talk about this.
- This is too stupid.
- Yes.
I know what you're thinking.
I talked to Dichmann.
Julia may be in a wheelchair forever.
Listen...
...this is all...
...a big misunderstanding.
Here. I've signed it.
Put any figure you want.
- Money doesn't matter.
- Precisely.
What matters is helping Julia.
I'm employing you to help
my daughter.
I'm buying a bit of your time.
What happens later is of no concern.
Give her a bit of love,
for God's sake.
Look at her!
My daughter is a wreck.
You can't back out now
when she needs your help.
You can at least pretend.
Write 100,000.
A million. Whatever.
I have known women who can
pretend to love for much less.
If I told you I wasn't Sebastian...
I'd call you a damned coward.
I beg you!
Sebastian?
Julia wants to talk to you.
Dichmann says
you're my best medicine.
Oh?
Have we known each other long?
A few months.
Dad says we phoned
from Cambodia.
Angkor Wat.
What happened there?
What happened?
How did we meet?
There was a bonfire.
It was evening.
Huddles of people
gathering in the twilight
getting to know each other.
People from all over.
Was I alone?
Yes.
And so were you?
What do you look like?
Ordinary.
Tall or short?
Dark or fair?
Dark.
Ordinary.
I blend into the wall.
What happened?
You were on your own.
With a Danish flag
on your backpack.
I offered you a bottle of Chang.
Chang?
Yes, it's the local gnat piss.
Two Danes in Angkor Wat.
Some coincidence!
Love at first sight.
If you believe in that.
What do you do?
I'm a photographer.
I travel around.
I take photographs.
For what?
National Geographic.
Features. Bits and pieces.
Do you love me?
Of course I love you.
You hesitated for too long.
I don't love you.
No.
I don't fall in love.
That's sad.
I have always been terrified
of a life of habit, appointments,
regular meals.
I hate rituals.
I don't want to be tied down.
Can you imagine such a life?
What life?
Husband, wife, a home.
Two screaming brats
and a miserable job.
Television.
Friends round for supper
on Saturdays.
Regular days for sex
once the kids are in bed.
No.
I can't imagine it.
It must be dreadful.
Or absolutely wonderful.
Everything so predictable.
Still no Other Half, Frank?
As far as I know.
What was our secret?
Can I surprise you with a rum
and Cola or a gin and tonic?
We could...
I'll have a rum and Coke
without the Coke.
We could see.
See?
Feel things.
We were refugees
from a tiny country.
We wanted to see a world far bigger
than coffee, herring and chatter.
And you provoked me.
And I provoked you.
We kept surprising each other.
Always another experiment.
And always...
...always love.
Sex?
Several times a day.
Liar!
No.
Did I come?
What?
I can never come.
You always came.
Are you full of yourself of what?
Pardon?
Nice to see you.
Good of you to come.
We've just said that!
Thanks for asking us.
Did you sleep well?
Well, it is nice to see you.
Where did we go after Angkor Wat?
At the rate I am going, I reckon
we are soon going to run out of wine.
Where are the other bottles?
Polynesia.
What?
- Polynesia?
- That's a long way to go.
Yes.
I always wanted to see Polynesia.
Are you ill?
Had you heard that Carsten
and Henriette are splitting up too?
He found a Pole. The bastard.
Did she come cheap?
Marriage is like a new car.
You're thrilled when you drive it
off the forecourt; it's all shiny.
Slowly you lose interest.
You don't wash it.
You don't vacuum the mats.
We're thinking about a new car.
You leave an empty bottle
under a seat.
The only thing you want
is a new one.
If only you'd been regular.
Just once a week.
1) Wash the car.
2) Vacuum.
3) Run a damp cloth
round the interior.
4) Wash the hubs.
You'd always have a new car.
He's down there all day long.
Someone must have poisoned
my apple.
You kissed me, and I woke up.
Want to try again?
My face is a wreck, isn't it?
You are beautiful.
I think you're feverish.
I'm going out for a bit.
What?
I need some air.
We've got visitors, darling.
Julia, there is something
I have to tell you.
It's hard for me to say this.
I know what it is.
Go now.
I don't know
what it was like out there,
but it's all different now.
You don't need me,
and I don't need you.
Okay.
- What did you think I wanted to say?
- Go. Just go.
What is happening?
What happened last week
is happening this week
and will happen next week.
I am dying, Frank.
Who isn't?
I feel...
Feel what?
Limp.
Join the Marines.
Grow a moustache.
What's worse?
The caves of Afghanistan
or screaming kids and a wife
who's always got a headache?
I don't know!
But maybe you've struck lucky.
You and Mette and all your friends
who have seen the light!
If there is any?
Hey, is anyone breathing out there?
Can you hear me?
Have you seen the light?
Listen.
If you need to stretch your legs,
buy a blow job off a Lithuanian.
Get it over with.
They're dirt cheap.
Julia needs me.
"Julia needs me. "
Julia needs you, does she?
Jonas, you are not Sebastian, okay?
You're Jonas, Jonas.
I don't know
if they're breathing, Frank.
I fucking don't know.
They're not.
I am Jonas.
Yes, you are Jonas.
He'll show up tomorrow,
and all hell will break loose.
- Who?
- Sebastian.
Sebastian Christersson is dead.
What?
Murdered. I circulated his name
round Interpol.
I heard from Hanoi yesterday.
They found him in his hotel room.
He'd been shot at point blank range.
I'm going to see her.
Damn it, Jonas.
Am I mad?
Yes! You're in love!
Is there anybody there?
Who's that?
Sebastian?
Is that you?
Were you asleep?
I don't know.
Are you okay?
I thought I heard you just now.
Maybe I was dreaming.
Have you been drinking?
A lot.
I'm happy you're here.
Yes.
Aren't you going to answer it?
Never mind that.
It might be urgent.
Take me.
Do you want to make love?
No, thanks.
Are you playing away?
Mette...
I want to know.
Will you tell me the truth?
Stop it.
Yes.
I'll tell you the truth.
Turn me over.
Is there somebody else?
No, Mette.
Where did you go?
I needed to stretch my legs.
Because I get the feeling
we may be needing two cars.
And so you bought one.
Spending money helps
when one's frustrated.
That much shopping?
I'm that frustrated.
Sit down.
- What the hell's going on?
- What do you mean?
These aren't my fucking size!
My butt is too big
after having two kids.
I had no idea that dirty panties
turned you on!
Where did you get them?
From here.
Well done, Mette.
Do you know what that is?
Evidence from a crime scene.
Goodness!
And you've mauled it.
For the last forth night
you've been out of here, Jonas.
You don't talk to me.
You don't touch me.
You've gone.
What's happening?
Where are you?
Is that your hotline?
Mette speaking.
Hello?
No, I am not Julia.
I don't know if this is her phone.
Wait a second.
Is that her name? Julia?
Someone wants to talk to her.
Hang up, Mette.
I guess this is her phone,
but she's not here at the moment.
I think she is busy
fucking my husband.
Please try again later.
- Where are you going?
- To work.
What's going on?
Nothing.
It's a fantastic house.
From the beach you can see
all the way across to Kullen.
And all the time
there's the sound of the sea.
You feel the sun on your back.
It sounds lovely.
As soon as I'm discharged, we'll go.
For a month or two.
I'll need help, after all.
There is nothing I'd rather do.
Something fantastic has happened.
You've got me pregnant.
It's amazing.
Yes... But when?
Before or after?
What do you mean?
Here or in Asia?
Here. Right here.
That's fantastic.
An amazing recovery.
I've seldom seen the like.
A couple of weeks ago
she was close to dying.
And now we can send her home.
With some help, of course.
Julia has told you she's pregnant?
Yes.
It's fantastic.
Sebastian?
I don't know how to put this.
Though, maybe it is very simple.
You may be the biggest bastard
I have ever met.
You disgust me.
What?
How dare you?
You pervert.
Where are you going?
I can explain.
What is there to explain?
It all just happened.
The misunderstanding.
But what has happened
between us...
...the feeling is real.
- The feeling is real?
- Yes.
I don't know what happened in Hanoi
or what she went through.
But we'll figure it all out together.
And I'll tell her who I really am.
What the hell are you on about?
Screwing your girlfriend
while she's in a coma!
That's disgusting!
What?
We test her urine every day.
We know precisely when it happened.
She was in a coma, damn it!
Perhaps you should check
on who's been running around...
Are you insinuating that we go round
shagging the patients?
I'm trying to tell you...
Forget it!
I am only covering up
for you for her sake.
I insist that you see a psychiatrist.
Here's a phone number.
Give them my regards
and tell them it is urgent.
- Dichmann!
- Shut up.
- Shut up!
Hey!
You want a search of the hospital
for a man in bandages?
- Yes, something is not right.
- Yes, you shagged her.
Not till later.
So somebody
must have mixed up the samples.
How can you be sure
Sebastian is dead?
They found the corpse,
brought him in,
and filled in a death certificate.
Here it is.
- Where did you get it?
- They faxed it.
I wanted to be sure.
If you're running around
with his name,
you don't want anyone
after your head, do you?
There's a short translation
on the back.
He was shot in the chest.
And transported to hospital
where he was declared
dead on arrival.
Keep it. It's a present.
He seems to have been
one of those losers
who goes backpacking
to get off with girls.
He gets a job at a bar in Pattaya,
runs out of cash, needs money
for coke or what's even worse.
He meets some low-life Chinese
and makes a buck ferrying suitcases
for them from Beijing to Sydney.
Does Hanoi know that?
Maybe that's what Julia did too?
She had money.
Maybe she was getting
her own back on her dad.
The Hearst syndrome?
They want to talk to her.
Maybe it was them who phoned?
Why? She doesn't know anything.
How's Mette feeling?
Hellish.
Remember back at school?
Those leather bracelets?
We wrote the names of the girls
we wanted to get off with.
Yes, you had Lise.
I had Joan.
Until we swapped.
They never knew.
- We just swapped.
- Yes.
Everything was simpler then.
If you don't want Mette,
I'll have Mette.
- Are you threatening me?
- With what?
Mette is my wife.
That's right. Fuck feelings.
- Make up your mind.
- Fuck you!
Whom do you have feelings for?
Fuck you back, Jonas.
I'll tell you whom I feel for.
For the poor sods I see
in silly dead positions every day
due to something in their love lives.
Hurt, hatred, cheating, rage.
You know why that jerk took out
his whole family the other day?
His wife kicked him out.
Then she got custody of the kids.
And then she shagged his best mate.
Is he mad or is she?
I don't know.
I do not know, Jonas.
I believe in the Muslim way.
Do it for practical reasons.
Do it to have children.
Do it for a camel.
Draw up a contract.
Fuck the love bit.
- Are we feeling cynical today?
- And you're a pathetic romantic.
Like this stupid cow.
She left a note.
"Tell everyone
that if Johnny hadn't left me
I'd still be dancing
among the living. "
Nine spelling mistakes
in one sentence.
Couldn't you at least
have got the spelling right?
Are dyslexia
and unrequited love infectious?
- Henriques?
- What?
Where is love actually located?
Know what?
It's right here.
In the area where pleasure
meets association.
There.
That's where desire, a progressive
instinct, crosses harmony,
its opposite, the need for peace.
Two completely
irreconcilable commodities.
That's why the result is always hell.
Unfortunately, it can't be excised
without inflicting greater handicaps.
Your two lovely kids...
What will become of them?
Know what?
I make myself sick.
But must life go on hold?
Until one's kids have left home?
Is that the kind
of father Klara and Frederik
will have to grow up with?
Hey, are you two
coming down for lunch?
It's heart casserole today.
Go on ahead.
I'll be right with you.
Where do they get the hearts from?
Just asking.
We've run out of everything.
What?
Practically everything.
Do you remember
if we're short of toilet paper?
Wake up! Toilet paper!
Jonas!
Please!
Don't spoil our morning.
Make an effort.
Mette...
Where did you get to?
I can't do it.
Do what?
This.
Would you rather shop elsewhere?
I'm sorry.
Is that alcohol I smell?
We're good together in many ways,
but it's not enough.
What are you saying?
I can't take it anymore.
One day we'll die.
One day we'll have gone from here.
What are you on about?
This.
You can't take what?
Everything, Mette, everything.
Are you leaving me?
Is this a good place for it?
No place is good for it.
- Are you crazy?
- Everything is no more than so-so.
But life is more
than Saturday shopping.
- Pull yourself together!
- I want more than that.
Is it her?
You are destroying our lives.
Destroying our lives!
And finally one day you announced
with steely determination,
"I'll never find a husband
in this poky little country. "
"I'll have to get out there
and look for one. "
Because, of course, you wanted
to find a man.
Obviously.
You'd made up your mind.
And what kind of man?
Not just any man: A normal man!
The first time we saw Sebastian
we thought, "This can't be Sebastian. "
He wasn't a rock climber
or a drug dealer or crazy in any way.
No, he was completely normal.
Thank you, Sebastian.
For being so wonderfully courteous,
kind, ordinary, and normal.
Thanks, Sebastian.
Cheers!
The setting might have been false,
but the feeling was real.
Reality was far off.
I doubted
if it would ever come back.
Every day postponed the day
I would tell Julia the truth.
And finally it no longer mattered,
for Sebastian's face took hold
and Jonas disappeared.
You didn't cash that bank check.
What check?
You are silly.
This must be the day God created
as the prototype for all good days.
How about we make a baby today?
We've known each other for...
Forever.
Only forever?
Hey?
You'll enjoy the cottage.
You are in no state to go anywhere.
Whether it's a cottage or not.
I don't think you should go yet.
We'll cope.
There's a lot to cope with.
It's nice and peaceful.
And you can phone.
It's only an hour away.
Quite so. Just an hour.
Julia...
I love you.
Nothing can part us.
Not even death.
I had a weird dream last night.
I was having a swim.
A whale came along.
It opened its mouth to swallow me.
But standing on its tongue
was an old man
with a Ho Chí Minh beard,
shouting, "Look out! Look out!"
But it wasn't Ho Chí Minh.
Because his T-shirt
had his name on: Jonah.
I thought, why is Jonas
in the whale called Jonah?
I don't know any Jonases.
And why Ho Chí Minh?
Yes, why?
"Jonah" backwards spells "Hanoi".
Have you ever hit me?
No.
Have we ever had a fight?
No. No.
I'll get a rug. And some tea.
You have six new messages.
The first new message:
Hi, it's me.
Call me. Now.
Where are you?
Call me.
Jonas, goddamn it!
This is bad.
I've got to talk to you.
I fingerprinted that wheelchair,
the one you said
the Bandaged Man was in.
The prints belong
to Sebastian Christersson.
Call me!
I am dead.
Do you understand?
I got onto Hanoi.
I traced him to an apartment hotel
in Copenhagen.
I'm going to pull him in and find out
what the heck is going on.
You have no new messages.
- Hi.
Is Julia in?
What do you want?
I am her boyfriend.
Sebastian.
Is she in?
No.
Doesn't the sign say Castlund?
There's no Julia here.
Sebastian!
Julia?
Where is she?
We were down by the water.
And you are...?
When did you get here?
It's a long story.
Sebastian?
Did you walk all the way?
A visitor?
Who is it?
You must be Julia.
Hi.
My name is...
...Jonas.
Jonas?
I just had a dream about you.
You did?
Did you come by whale?
No, by car.
On my way to the mainland.
Sebastian told me you were here,
so I dropped in.
He's talked so much about you.
Are you in a rush?
No, not really.
Stay for supper, then.
- I don't want to bother you.
- Of course you must.
Sebastian? Right?
How can I refuse?
I've got some treats in the car.
How lovely!
Is there a car?
Yes.
So there was a Jonas.
Swallow!
Did you feel it?
Disgusting!
Do you always carry them
round in your trunk?
To be quite honest,
I actually had them in my trunk
to seduce an old girlfriend with.
And now we're eating her oysters
and drinking her champagne.
Aren't we lucky?
Oh, I bet you eat them every day.
Sebastian says your family is rich.
Does he? Hm?
Are you completely blind?
I can sometimes make out shadows.
A penny for them, Sebastian?
This is sick.
What's your game?
What do you mean?
Spit it out.
What?
The truth.
I am disappointed...
...that you haven't told Julia
about us.
Told me what?
We were lovers.
Come off it...
Scout's honor.
Sebastian and I were together
for three years.
Oh, we weren't gay gays,
we also loved women.
Really close friends, shall we say?
Who cuddled.
Jesus, Sebastian!
Oh, Sebastian shagged
anything that moved.
Isn't that so, Sebastian?
What a pig!
I don't know a thing about you.
Exactly what do you want?
Hey, I'm sorry, I just thought
you seemed so good together.
I didn't think you'd have secrets.
What is it that I don't know?
I'm so sorry.
I do apologize.
You don't have to say sorry.
No, I know.
I'm to blame.
Sorry.
Sorry, Jonas.
It's just so long
since we last saw each other.
With good reason, of course.
But it's great that the six years
didn't wear you down completely.
Yes, I can tell.
Prison would be hard on anyone.
The violence.
No love.
And love from the other prisoners
is not real love, is it?
Just rape?
What did you go to prison for?
Drugs.
Jonas was a drugs runner.
Bumming about South East Asia
with casual jobs
from Beijing to Sydney.
Always with someone after him.
Always with a suitcase.
Jonas was always on the run.
Dear God.
Where did you fuck up?
Eh?
What went wrong?
Why are you telling her this?
Have I insulted you?
Why are you telling her I did time?
Sebastian, what is this?
I'm sorry if I spoke out of turn.
I could tell immediately
that I wasn't especially
welcome today.
It was only because Julia insisted.
I'd better go.
Sebastian, what is going on?
Just what do you want?
Julia, I'm going.
Sebastian and I have had
a few issues...
Sit down.
What do you want?
Have you heard from Frank?
Frank?
I don't know who Frank is.
What happened in Hanoi?
I don't know...
You want to know?
Yes, I'd very much like
to hear about it.
I have no idea, and I have no idea
what we are talking about.
Tell us what happened
in Hanoi, right!
Stop it!
Go for a walk.
Buy some cigarettes, anything.
Yes.
Yes, a breath of air might be
a good idea
when you're in such a state.
To cool you down.
Know what, if you drive,
you'd better take my car.
It's blocking the driveway.
If you can be bothered to drive
such an old wreck.
Will you be all right?
I'll be fine.
Frank here.
Leave a message,
and I'll call you back.
Frank, it's me. He's here.
It's absolutely crazy.
I don't know what he wants.
I am by the phone.
Call me.
That was stupid of me.
You told the truth.
Me and my big mouth.
You know how he loses his temper.
But he's changed incredibly.
Has he?
Sebastian has so many emotions.
I think he is the most
sensitive person I have ever met.
But sometimes things
get too much for him.
His love turns to...
...madness.
Do you know anything
about his exes?
To be perfectly honest with you,
I don't feel comfortable with this.
I don't like it,
but I'd rather tell the truth.
Do you ever feel Sebastian
is concealing stuff?
Yes.
You don't remember a thing?
No.
He claims Asia was fantastic
when you were out there.
Wasn't it?
Julia...
...I was not on my way anywhere.
I rushed up here the moment I heard
you were back with Sebastian.
Go on.
He was off his head
when he called me from Hanoi.
I don't know whether it was the acid,
but he was desperate.
Julia, Sebastian was the one carrying
a suitcase round Southeast Asia.
He worked for some
really vicious people.
He was smuggling diamonds,
but it went wrong.
And you only cheat the triads once.
This is Frank's
answering machine.
Why didn't we escape?
He was doomed.
His only way out was as a corpse.
What happened?
You were going to die together.
You've got to get us out of here.
Do you mean that?
I am with the man I got away from!
Yes.
You've got to help me.
Calling Frank
This is Frank...
This is Frank's answering machine.
Leave a message.
I don't get it.
Did he tell you about Hanoi?
You were at a hotel.
You left him there.
I keep seeing a door.
I am walking towards it.
- I mustn't go through it!
- You've got to go back.
Through that door.
You've got to go into the room.
They'll kill us!
- Give them what they want.
- It's too late.
It's too late, too late.
Let me go!
At least we are together.
No, no, no!
What are you doing?
Don't you love me?
I want you to tell me you love me.
I love you. I love you.
Orpheus loves you, Eurydice.
We'll get away from all this.
But I mustn't turn round.
He just wants to see
it is her following him.
And so she ends up back
in the Kingdom of Death.
And that's why they can only
be together in death.
Listen!
Orpheus must die first.
If they're to be reunited.
Look at me. Look at me.
Look at me.
I love you, Orpheus.
If you enter the Kingdom of Death,
I will follow you.
I promise.
You know I love you.
You promise you'll follow?
I promise.
Orpheus should never
have looked back.
You didn't want him.
Can you imagine how that felt?
Orpheus fought like fury
to reach Eurydice,
and when he finally made it,
there they all were, laughing.
"Eurydice? No, she isn't here.
She has found someone else. "
Come on.
Let's go outside and finish this.
Sebastian!
What are you playing at, Jonas?
You can see?
Who are you?
Have you started smoking again?
What about the children?
I only smoke under the hood.
I'm very careful.
- May I have one?
- Yes.
- How's the new car?
- Perfect.
I told you we'd need two cars.
I am really sorry.
I don't know how it got to be
such a mess.
It just happened.
The earth vanished
beneath my feet.
I'm not moaning.
But I landed very hard.
You always did dream of flying.
Yes.
Who doesn't?
I miss Frank.
Maybe he was mad,
but you could see his madness.
Yes.
Do you want to see the children?
Wait.
Take this damned suitcase
with you.
Bad karma.
When will you be back?
I'll call you.
I was on my way away,
but nevertheless on my way home.
It was a good evening.
Not a Hollywood ending,
but it would do.
Like the place we live.
Not much goes on there.
But what happens
happened yesterday,
and luckily
it will happen tomorrow too.
Sebastian!
Cozy.
And nice.
Here I lie.
The rain is falling on my face.
But I don't feel a thing.
In a moment they'll bring white tape
to mark out my profile.
A good shot:
The victim in the rain.
Direct flash.
Razor sharp.
The woman.
There always has to be a woman.