Yes, ma'am, how ya doin'?
Is this Rose Hill?
Good.
This is Ed Couch.
I'm Vesta Adcock's nephew.
I need to get up there
and see her,
but I'm gonna be late
'cause I'm lost out here.
We're off the Alabama interstate
but I don't know where.
Did you hear that?
What?
The train.
No, I didn't hear no train.
Oh, nothin', I guess.
Where's "Whistle Stop" on
the map? I can't find it.
Why did you tell me to
turn right 10 miles back there?
God, you got a negative
sense of direction, hon.
I'm sorry.
Oh, Ed, your aunt's gonna be
so disappointed we're late.
I know she's been looking forward
to this visit all week long.
Bless her sweet,
little ol' heart.
Hey, how's my sweet Auntie V
this afternoon?
Remember us?
Don't you look pretty!
We brought you something.
Let me look at
you.
Don't you know Evelyn loves you?
Well, honey, I guess it'd be
better if you wait out here for me.
I'll get all this stuff.
Well, if you think it's best.
Yeah, I do this time.
Okay?
Have a nice day, Aunt Vesta.
Don't you pitch a fit like that!
Did you know
they took my gallbladder out?
No, I didn't.
Oh, yes. Still
in the hospital in a jar.
I guess that's where
they keep 'em.
I guess.
When I was in the hospital,
the nurse gave me one of them
Fleet enemas they're so fond of.
Mrs. Cleo Threadgoode,
82 year old widow,
imagine that.
Actually,
everybody calls me Ninny.
'Course I'm just visitin' here.
Did you ever have
one of them Fleet enemas?
Um, well?
No.
You'd remember it.
Me and my friend, Mrs. Otis,
come from Whistle Stop.
You ever been to Whistle Stop?
Why, yes. I just
passed by there today.
She's lived down the street
from me for 30 years or more.
After her son died,
her daughter-in-law had a fit for
her to come live at the nursing home.
They asked me to come
and be her roommate.
Mrs. Otis don't know it, but I'm going
home just soon as she gets settled in good.
Does the name "Idgie
Threadgoode" ring a bell?
Um, no, ma'am.
I don't think so.
You'd remember her.
You see, I was practically
adopted by the Threadgoode family.
I married her brother,
Cleo. Oh, uh-huh.
Idgie  and her friend, Ruth,
ran the Whistle Stop Cafe.
Oh.
Idgie  was a character,
all right.
But how anybody
could've thought...
she murdered that man
is beyond me.
I beg your pardon?
You sit and relax a while.
I'll tell you all about it.
Oh, now, let's see.
I 'member the day they pulled
that truck up out of the river.
That same rainy, summer day...
Idgie Threadgoode was arrested for
the murder of the owner of that truck,
Frank Bennett.
I guess, to understand ldgie,
you'd have to start way back
with her brother, Buddy.
Idgie  was Buddy's pet
from the day she was born.
I 'member the day we was all
gettin'ready for Leona's weddin'.
The war had just ended,
the Great one,
you know.
And another one was about to
begin in the Threadgoode house.
Sipsey, honey, is that finished?
Buddy, get dressed, honey. Mama?
Leona, what is it?
Idgie 's upstairs in her room...
And says she won't come out
as long as she lives.
She is gonna ruin my weddin'! Shh.
Leona, you're gonna be
the most beautiful bride.
Of course she is, Papa.
Your papa has spent every last
nickel he has just to make you happy.
Now, you try to act
a little grateful, young lady.
Imogene Louise Threadgoode!
This is your mama!
You come down here right now.
Do you hear me?
Buddy, fetch her. She'll listen
to you. Come on down, little bit.
There's no firin'
squad waitin' for you.
Ohh! Come on,
honey. Let us see you.
You look so pretty.
I see London, I see... Hush!
Julian, hush.
Come ahead, sweetheart.
You look awful nice in that.
Mama!
You look fine.
She looks like a monkey.
Julian, stop it
right this second!
Take it back!
Take it back! Idgie , hey!
I told you she
was gonna ruin my weddin'!
Idgie , get up.
Take it back!
I'll get you for this.
No, Buddy.
We have to be careful
when she's dressing up.
She's just a pain!
Leona, will you
stop shrieking!
This is your
weddin'day!
Looks like you got
yourself up a tree, little bit.
I'm sick of
people makin' fun of me.
So you're gonna stay up here
all day long.
Yep.
The hell with them.
Who wants to wear
that stupid ol' dress anyway?
I ever tell you about
the oysters? Oysters?
I tell you about the oysters? No.
Think about the millions
of oysters lyin'around the ocean.
Then one day...
God comes along and sees one
and he says,
"I think I'm gonna make
that one different."
You know what he does?
He puts a little
piece of sand in it.
Guess what it can do that
the others can't. What?
It can make a beautiful pearl.
What if God made a mistake?
Well, the way I figure it,
he never makes mistakes.
I mean, he made sure
we got together.
He made sure you got
the best looking,
most charmin' brother
in the world...
Who's gonna beat you to the
chocolate cake. You will not.
Got you out of the tree,
didn't I?
Did not!
Into this estate,
these two come now to be joined.
If any man present
can show cause...
why they may not lawfully
be joined together,
let him speak now or
forever after hold his peace.
Please be seated.
If either of you
know any reason...
why you may not justly be joined
together in holy matrimony,
do you now confess it?
It is then your will
to proceed.
Do you,
Charles Osgood Justice...
Thank you. I don't know what
we'd do without your generosity.
Sipsey, especially you.
Look what you've done!
Thank you, Mrs.
Threadgoode. Gimme that, you rascal!
Ohh!
Jump on my back.
I don't think there ever was
a sweeter boy than Buddy Threadgoode.
You look beautiful, Lily.
Yes, Lily, you sure do.
I had the biggest crush on him.
He was a terrible flirt!
But his heart belonged
to Ruth Jamison.
She was the daughter of
a friend of his mama's...
who was visitin'
that summer.
Ruth Jamison, you're just
the one I've been lookin' for.
Are you thirsty? Let's
go visit someplace else.
A little nest
that's nestled
Think that's a big lake, you should've
seen the one next to our house.
We used to swim in it and fish.
I sure do miss it.
Sure do.
What happened to it?
Did it dry up?
No, worse than that.
Last fall, a flock of ducks,
40 or 50 of'em, landed right
smack in the middle of it.
This fluke thing happened.
The temperature dropped so fast
that the whole lake froze...
In three seconds,
just like that!
Those poor little ducks.
Did it kill them?
No, they flew off
and took the lake with 'em.
To this very day, that lake
is somewhere over in Georgia.
Buddy Threadgoode.
Come a little closer.
I wanna give you something.
Come here.
Whoop!
You'll see
a smiling face
Come back here, hat.
Where do you think you're goin'?
Whoa!
I got it. Hold on, Ruth.
Hold on, little bit.
It's all right.
I got it.
Come here, you damn hat. Got it!
Oh, I meant to do that.
I... got it!
Ta-da!
All right.
Damn!
Come on.
Come on. Get out.
Get out.
Buddy!
- Buddy!
- Buddy Threadgoode!
Come on, Buddy!
Get out.
Get out of there.
Buddy!
- Come on, Buddy!
- Buddy!
Buddy!
No-o-o!
Buddy, no!
No!
No! Buddy!
No-o-o!
Let me go!
- No!
- Buddy!
You got to go back
to the house.
Come on.
We're gonna go home.
- Buddy!
- You have to be strong.
It'll be okay.
Buddy!
"The Lord is my Shepherd,
I shall not want. "
Oh, it like
to have killed us all.
But nary a one took it
as hard as ldgie,
everyone thought she'd die
right along with him.
Night after night,
she stayed by the river.
Big George was the only soul
she'd let near her,
and he watched over her
night and day.
You know,
a heart can be broken,
but it still keeps a-beatin'
Just the same.
Miss ldgie, you'll have
to keep this blanket on...
Or you'll catch your death
of cold, you hear me now?
That's so sad.
Ah.
Would you like one of these?
Oh, thank ya, honey.
Evelyn?
Honey, we gotta get goin'.
The Braves' game's
fixin' to start...
And you're gonna miss
your... thing.
Excuse me.
That's my husband, Ed.
Hi, ma'am.
How you doin'?
Um,
I can't believe Buddy died.
Neither could I.
Oh, well, I enjoyed
talkin' to you, honey.
What's your name?
Evelyn...
Evelyn Couch.
I've got to go. You come
back and see me, you hear?
Okay.
Bye-bye.
First of all, I want you...
to truly
dedicate yourselves...
to finding little ways to
putting that magic, that spark...
back into your marriage.
When we think of
romance and marriage,
what is the first thought that
comes into your mind? Divorce!
Remember when counselors used to tell
you to wrap yourself in cellophane...
To put a little charge
into your marriage?
Do we really pay
for these lectures?
You can see,
it is truly up to you...
to put romance back
into your relationship.
Oh, yeah
Da-na-na
da-na-na-na
As I walk this land
of broken dreams
I have visions
of many things
Happiness
Hi, honey.
Is just an illusion
Evelyn, have you gone insane?
My God,
people can see you!
What if I had been
the paperboy?
Get in there!
What are you
thinking about?
Evelyn?
Evelyn!
Oh.
You know, what we really need
instead of this baloney...
Is an assertiveness training
class for Southern women.
But that's a contradiction
in terms, isn't it?
Especially you, sweetheart.
You're livin' in the Dark Ages.
The roots of love
grow all around
But the leaves
they come tumblin'down
Every day, heartaches
grow a little stronger
I can't stand this pain
much longer
Hi, honey. I need one of those. Hi!
Mmm, you smell good too.
I need one of these.
Oh, this looks good! Uh-huh.
Yes, indeedy.
Always movin'
but goin'nowhere
[Indistinct]
Ed.
Why don't you come in
and sit down at the table...
and have dinner with me? I'm
sorry. The game's almost over.
I just want to see a little bit
of it. Why you so dressed up?
Honey, don't get in the way.
Scoot over a bit.
Ed?
If I'd answered the door
wearing only cellophane,
would you still be
watching the baseball game?
No, honey. I'd probably be
checking you into a looney bin.
Hi, sugar.
How's my dumplin'?
Trick or treat!
You're not gonna throw
them hissy-fits, are you?
Happy Halloween!
Oh, no. No, no, no!
You're meaner than a damn snake.
I'm glad you're feeling better.
Get back in bed. Good thing
your eyesight's failing.
Hey!
Mmm. Oh.
Hey. I was hopin' you'd be here.
My roommate, Mrs. Otis,
said I could visit her family,
but I said, "Thank you kindly,
but I think I might have
my own visitor."
And here you are.
Well, sit down.
Thank you.
And doughnuts to boot!
You can't beat that.
Well, help yourself, Mrs.
Threadgoode. Thank you.
How's your friend?
Mrs. Otis?
Uh-huh.
Well, not so good.
Oh.
Looks like I won't be
gettin' home for quite a while,
and I sure miss it.
Funny what you miss
when you're away from home.
I miss the smell of coffee...
And bacon fryin'.
Oh, what I wouldn't give for a
plate of fried green tomatoes...
Like we used to have
at the cafe.
Ooh!
I never told you about the cafe, did I?
No, ma'am.
Oh, well...
now let me back up a bit.
You see, ldgie never
quite got over losing Buddy.
She hardly
ever come home.
Only Big George
knew how to find her.
She just didn't seem to care
about anythin'anymore.
Then, one summer day,
her mama sent for her.
Like they say,
God never shuts one door
without opening another.
That was also the day ldgie
met Frank Bennett, Mama!
The man whose murder
got her arrested.
Well, hello there, miss.
And who might you be?
Towanda to you.
Who are you?
Oh, Frank Bennett's
the name, Miss Towanda.
I must say you are lookin'
mighty fine today.
You a politician...
Or does lying
just run in your family?
Mama!
Well, there you are!
Well, it's about time,
ldgie.
If you don't look like
the wild man of Borneo.
Here you go. Well, thank you.
Guess who's here?
Who?
Ruth. She's stayin'
with us this summer...
And will be in charge of all the young
people's activities at the church.
Is that why you wanted to see me?
We have so many things planned.
Ruth?
You remember my youngest
child? Of course I do.
Hi, ldgie.
Hi.
Maybe this isn't
such a good idea.
Oh, it's got to work.
Somebody's got to help her. I can't.
Are you sure you want
to go to this river club, Miss Ruth?
These ain't no
churchgoing folks.
I'll do just
fine, George, thank you.
Oh, excuse me.
Is ldgie Threadgoode here
by any chance?
Come on in, honey.
She's right down here.
Here? Okay.
Uh-huh.
I'll see you, Grady Kilgore,
and I'll raise you twenty.
You ain't got nothin'!
Maybe I do and maybe I don't.
Put your money where
your mouth is, Mr. Sheriff.
Well, look what
the cat drug in!
I came to talk to you.
You're gonna have to wait.
I'm busy.
Come on, Grady, this is your
big chance. You in or out?
I'll make you
a rich man.
You just bluffin'again as usual.
I'm afraid you're gonna have to excuse
ldgie. She's goin' home for dinner.
Say good-bye, ldgie.
Where you goin'?
Where the hell you goin' with
my money? We're goin' home!
- Who are you to boss me around?
- The one holdin' your money!
Give it back.
Now, get in the car.
All right, I'll get in the car.
You win!
Come on.
Sucker!
I'll leave when I want!
I don't know how you can break
your mother's heart like you do.
I'm not doin' anything
to my mother.
Oh, no? Why do you think
I'm here for the summer?
Your mother was so worried, she thought I
might be able to talk some sense into you.
But you're too busy
being selfish!
What are you talkin' about?
You're not the only one
who lost Buddy.
We all miss him...
But turning your back on
your family is not gonna help.
What's he got to do
with anything?
Looks like you're the one with
the problem forgetting my brother.
Why, just ten miles away...
down by the river,
there lurks
a den of the devil...
where liquor
and gamblin'...
and sin abide!
Snakes and serpents...
Hey, Scroggins!
You're finally preachin' about
somethin' you're kin to... snakes!
As I said,
snakes and serpents
take many disguises.
Let's turn to page 53
in our hymnal.
Yoo-hoo!
Big George thought
I might find you here.
If you give me a chance,
a chance to get to know you,
maybe it'll be fun!
Fun?
Idgie , just spend
some time with me.
Please?
Suit yourself.
You sure you
don't wanna back out?
It's not too late.
I'm sure.
Here, hold this.
Tell me now, you like trains?
Yes.
Good.
We'll get along just fine!
Boy, did we luck out tonight.
Hop in.
Hop?
Oh. Give me
your hand.
Put your foot up there.
Hold that.
Ooo-ooo!
Look at all this!
Don't you think we should get off
the train? It's startin' to move.
No. The fun
just started!
You all right?
Well, sometimes I get
a little dizzy lookin' down.
Don't look down.
What are you doin'?
Come on. Look.
They're throwin'
away food!
You talk about
"give unto others."
Yes, but this food
isn't yours to give.
That's church talk.
I've seen those same people
over at church on Sunday...
Over at the river club every
other night of the week,
doin' anything
but pray. Come on.
More!
Give me some.
Okay, time to get off.
We gotta jump.
Jump?
Yeah, jump. The next stop's
five miles down the tracks.
I don't wanna walk
that far back.
Are you crazy?
You're not kiddin'.
Well...
I give up. Jump.
I'll tell Mama I'm not
a good influence on you...
You'll never jump, will you?
Don't say "never" to me.
Towanda!
You all right?
I'm fine.
I'm all right.
Ow!
Does this hurt?
Guess so.
We better get you to
a doc... doctor. Shit!
Which way is it?
About two miles
down the tracks.
All right, let's go.
You'll never be able
to carry me that far.
I know.
Never say never.
I'm not carryin' you.
You're walkin'.
Thank you,
Julian. I owe you one.
Uh. Ow.
Aren't you ready yet?
What?
This doesn't have anything
to do with trains, does it?
You like honey?
Yeah, I like honey.
Fresh honey?
Yeah.
Me too.
There it is.
There what... is?
You'll see soon enough.
Now... stay here.
No matter what happens,
don't move.
What are you gonna do?
Ah.
Here you are, madam.
This is for you.
Why did you do that?
You could have been killed.
I'm sorry.
Don't you want the honey?
I got it just for you.
It's all right.
I do it all the time.
I never get stung, honest.
Don't be mad at me, Ruth.
Idgie , I'm not mad at you.
No foolin'?
Is it bad, what I did?
No.
I thought I might
be crazy or somethin'.
No, no.
I've heard there were people
who could charm bees.
I've just never seen
it done... before today.
You're just a bee charmer,
ldgie Threadgoode.
That's what you are,
a bee charmer.
Here, you want to taste it?
"Satan started to
laugh at Job's devotion.
"He bet God that Job would
never have so much faith...
"if he didn't have
so many blessings.
"He went on and on so long and
so much that God finally agreed...
"to let Satan
put Job to a test.
"Suddenly, from bein'
on top of the world,
Job was plunged down into
the deepest pits of misery. "
Surprise!
Idgie  Threadgoode!
Tonight we're gonna have
a real party.
Drink this... and then,
we're gonna play some poker.
I don't know how to play
poker and I never drink...
But thank you anyway.
Oh,
my darlin' Oh, my darlin'
Here comes the windup.
Burn that ball in here.
Burn 'em in here!
Right in the pocket. I
don't know how to bat.
And you don't drink, either.
It's gonna be a spitter.
Hold the bat and swing.
Spitter?
- She gonna spit at me?
- She's gonna spit on the ball.
Swing that bat!
Take another crack at it.
I'm gonna take
another crack at it.
Get 'em in here.
Now run, Ruth.
Run!
Come on around the bases!
Don't kiss everybody.
Run!
I have never had so much fun...
In my whole life.
I even got a home run.
A clean one at that!
A straight beats
three of a kind.
You know, poker isn't half bad.
What's your mother gonna say...
When she sees us both...
drunk?
You gotta stop worrying about
what people think. I know.
You've always done
the right thing.
You took care of your daddy,
the preacher, when he took sick.
You take care of all the kids
over at the church school.
You're gonna
take care of your mama.
And I'm gonna marry
the man I'm supposed to.
You gettin' married?
As soon as the summer's over.
Oh, am I gonna miss you.
This is the best birthday...
I ever had.
Ruth invited
ldgie to the weddin',
but ldgie never did
write back.
No, but she did drive all night
to Valdosta, Georgia,
to watch from afar.
Oh, here we go!
And she swore
she'd never see Ruth again.
No sir! Whew!
Now, Mama Jamison,
you put that down.
Oh, my Lord!
During these next few weeks,
we will be learning to reclaim
our own power as women!
Hallelujah!
And tonight, we're gonna
begin to explore...
our own femaleness...
by examining the source
of our strength...
and our separateness.
Our vaginae.
So if y'all will just
slip off your panties...
and straddle your mirrors.
Ms. Couch!
Um, I need to be excused
for a minute.
Um, Missy, could you come
with me to the ladies' room?
- Do you find this threatening?
- Uh, well, um...
do you have a problem with
your sexuality? No, ma'am.
But I do have a problem
with my girdle.
Cherish is the word
I use to describe
Hi, baby. All the
feelings that I have...
All right, fried chicken!
My favorite.
I don't know how many times
I wish that I had told you
Ed?
Those classes I've been taking
aren't helpin' us one bit.
Let's go to Florida...
Like when we got married.
Kyle's gone,
busy with his own life.
It'd be just the two of us.
Well, honey, it's just
the two of us here now.
Boy, you got a good scald
on that chicken!
I'm tellin' you, that's
really good. Thank you.
We could rent a boat...
And drift around
in the hot sun.
What do you think about it?
I'm just gettin' used to it
being quiet around here.
Honey, if those classes
aren't doin' you any good,
then don't go to 'em.
Everyone needs a
miracle in their life.
Damn, game's blacked out!
Yoo-hoo,
Mrs. Threadgoode?
Hey, Evelyn!
Do you like it?
Oooh! Well,
who did it for ya,
darlin'? Believe it or not,
it was a student,
a little bitty thing,
no bigger than a midget
from the beauty college.
Sometimes they come out here
and do our hair for free...
Just for the practice,
you know.
Is Ed with ya?
No, ma'am.
His aunt said she didn't want
visitors anymore, especially us.
It's a shame.
I know he feels bad,
but Lord if he'll
talk to me about it.
Oh, thank you.
Merry Christmas.
Mrs. Threadgoode...
How about tellin' me
some more... about ldgie?
Oh, well, now, let me see.
Where were we? Ruth had just
gotten married to Frank Bennett?
Wasn't that the man ldgie
was arrested for murderin'?
That's right.
After Ruth left, ldgie
went back to her old ways,
Hangin'out with Grady
and the boys at the river club.
But after a few years,
temptation got the better of her.
I don't wanna wake you, Miss ldgie,
but it's an all-day drive to Valdosta.
Your mama said if you're goin', she
wants you to take this pie to Miss Ruth.
How does she know where
I'm going? I told her.
Don't you go stirrin' up
no trouble for Miss Ruth now.
Yes, ma'am.
Don't "yes, ma'am" me.
You can stay in my house
as long as you want,
but don't treat me
like you treat your mama.
Grandma!
Yes, ma'am.
Hi there.
Yes?
Uh, is Ruth at home?
Who's callin'?
You just tell her it's the
bee charmer from Alabama.
Ruth,
there's some bee person
here to see you.
Idgie .
Hi.
You got a real nice home,
real nice things and all.
Mm-hmm,
thank you.
Mama said to give you this pie.
So...
Idgie  Threadgoode, how are ya?
You look so...
so grown up.
All the guys
must be wild about you.
Tell me,
do you have a fella yet?
A... couple.
I haven't decided on any.
Grady's the most
persistent, but...
Grady Kilgore? Don't say it so loud.
Ruth, honey, who's down there?
Hey...
Well...
What happened to you?
Nothin'.
Nothin'!
Where'd you get the shiner?
Well, l... Who's down there?
You'd better leave now. Did he hit you?
Did he beat you? Somebody's
got to talk to him. Idgie .
You're not gonna do
anything. I'm gonna kill him.
I'm gonna have a
conversation with him about...
You're not gonna do anything.
...pickin' on somebody his own size.
You're not gonna do
anything, understand?
If you care about me,
if you really do,
you'll turn around and leave
this minute. You understand?
Well, what'd she want?
Nothin'.
Ruth's a grown woman, and
she knows what's best for her.
Mmm, I'm not so sure
about that.
Idgie ?
Grady.
Hi.
Idgie , will you dance with me? No.
Come on.
It's only a dance.
Miss ldgie Threadgoode...
Get your butt off the floor.
Will you dance with me?
I will not dance with you,
and I will not marry you.
Go marry Gladys Moats.
She just adores you.
But she did fall on her
head when she was a child.
You're just a goofy girl,
ldgie, a goofy girl.
Who're you callin'
a goof? Ow-ow-ow!
Who you callin' a goof? Stop
that before I get mad and hurt ya.
Oh, yeah.
You try it.
Grady! There now, you give up?
No, I'll never give up!
Grady finally
got dizzy and give up.
Try as they might, none of them
fellas could tame ldgie.
Now,
a little while later,
a letter
come from Ruth.
Oh, it's an obituary.
Oh, no, honey,
Ruth's mother died.
Oh.
And this is from the Bible.
It's from
the book of Ruth.
"And Ruth said,
whither thou goest, I will go;
"where thou lodgest,
I will lodge;
Thy people
shall be my people."
All right, Julian,
you and Big George wait here.
Mama died.
I know.
And I'm pregnant.
Julian, I got another
box here when you're done!
I never seen
anybody with so many hats.
Why don't we put
three in one box?
I don't think we can fit
all these in the car.
We're gonna need a separate
truck for all your stuff.
What the hell is going on here?
Looks like your wife's
leavin' you, mister.
Sure she is. Don't
you touch her! Let go.
You bastard!
Put her down!
Bastard!
Whoooo!
Stop it!
Don't you hurt her!
Frank!
I wouldn't do that
if I was you, mister.
See, the thing is,
you might upset Big George.
And he's crazy.
There's no tellin'
what he might do.
Go on, get outta here.
Hey!
Come on!
Hey, hey! Come on now!
Let's go. Come on.
You okay?
Let's get Miss
Ruth and get outta here.
Come on, Miss Ruth.
Come on.
If you ever touch her again,
I'll kill you.
Well, I sure as
hell scared him, didn't I?
Yeah, you sure scared him.
Towanda, the
amazing Amazon woman!
Towanda?
Towanda! Towanda!
Evelyn?
Evelyn!
Oh!
I'm sorry.
I was just lookin'
at the pictures, Missy.
They have the greatest stories
in that magazine, don't they?
Will I see you
in group tonight?
We'll be talking about
masturbation.
No, I don't think so. I think I've
had enough learnin' for the time bein'.
Thank you.
Oh!
Excuse me.
Screw you!
Excuse me, young man.
There was no reason for you
to be so rude to me.
Get away from me, you fat
cow. What did you call me?
Beat it, you old bitch.
Why are you being
so mean to me?
What did I ever do to you...
I don't understand!
Look at my Stove Top!
Boo!
Oh, honey, what in the world
is the matter?
I don't know.
Come on.
I need some exercise.
Now, you tell me what's
botherin' you, sugar.
I just...
I just feel so useless.
So...
So powerless.
Everybody goes through that.
But I can't stop eatin'.
Every day I try and try
and every day I go off.
I hide candy bars
all over the house.
A candy bar ain't
gonna hurt ya none.
One, no.
But 10 or 11?
I can't even look
at my own vagina.
I can't help ya on that one.
I wish I had the courage to get
it over with and get really fat.
Oh, Mrs. Threadgoode,
I just...
I'm too young to be old
and I'm too old to be young.
Maybe I'm just goin' crazy.
You get hot flashes?
Sometimes.
You get the sweats and your
hearts starts a-poundin'?
- How did you know?
- Simple, honey.
You're going through
the change.
I used to burst
into tears for no reason at all.
You need some hormones. Hmm?
Maybe some Stresstabs
number 4 for good measure.
- Really? Is that all?
- Sure, honey.
You get yourself some hormones.
Then you get outta
the house and get a job.
With your pretty complexion...
I'll bet you'll be
great with cosmetics.
I know how you feel.
I was about your age
when I had my child.
Then I went through
the change of life.
I didn't know you had
a child. Yes, I did.
Albert.
When he was born, the doctor said
it would be best if I didn't see him.
He said his mind would never
develop past the age of five,
and I should just put him
in an institution...
Because the burden of raisin' a
child like that would be too great.
Well, I thought about Ruth.
She always said...
There was a separate
God for children.
So I smiled at him and
I asked for the baby.
Oh, how could anybody think
that sweet, precious baby...
Could ever be a burden?
Why, from the minute he was born,
Albert was the joy of my life,
the Lord's greatest gift.
I don't believe there was a purer
soul ever lived on this earth.
I had him with me
till he was 30.
Then he went to sleep
and didn't wake up.
Sometimes I can't wait to get
to heaven to see him again.
Whoo!
Shit!
It's a boy!
I think a prayer of
thanksgivin' would be in order.
Goddamn it to hell, son-of-a-bitch,
she did it! Here's to Ruth!
Idgie  always did have a
way with words around the reverend.
Well, Ruth had a baby.
She named him Buddy...
Buddy Junior.
Papa went out and borrowed money so
Ruth and ldgie could start a cafe,
the Whistle Stop Cafe.
When you come by my house
come down behind the jail
I've got a sign
on my door
Barbecue for sale
I'm talkin'
about barbecue
Only thing I crave
And a good-doin' meat
Will carry me
to my grave
I'm sellin' it for cheap
'cause I got good stuff
Miss ldgie,
can you get the door?
Yes.
Big George.
Miss Ruth, me and the
missus want to thank you...
for sendin' that soup
over last night.
I'll pay you when I get
ahead. You don't owe me, Ocie.
Thank you. I'm just glad they're better.
How is this, by the way?
It's good, very good.
I'm not happy
till I see clean plates.
Can't go on, ldgie.
I'm talking to you as a friend.
There's people in this town, paying
customers too... There you go.
But some people
don't like you...
sellin' to coloreds.
Here you go.
Tell you what. Next time
those "some people" come here,
I'm gonna ask if they
don't want anybody to know...
Who they are
under those sheets...
When they go marchin'
in those stupid parades,
how come they don't have
sense to change their shoes?
Hold on there.
Y'all ain't foolin' anybody.
I'd recognize those size 14
clodhoppers you got anywhere.
- Just a minute, ldgie.
- More pie, Grady?
No, thank you, Ruth.
Idgie , I'll talk to the boys.
You just keep them
on out back there, ya hear?
Bye, Ruth.
Bye, Grady.
You're gonna get yourself
in a heap of trouble.
What, Grady?
He's harmless.
You shoulda seen that
big ox down by the river.
Three solid days, drunk as
a dog, cryin' like a baby...
'cause Joe, that ol' colored
man that raised him, died.
Remember that, Sipsey? Yes'm.
He sure ain't jokin' now,
is he, son? No, ma'am.
He won't even sit in the same
room and have a meal today.
Don't make no sense. Big ox like Grady
won't sit next to a colored child,
but he eats eggs... Shoot
right out of a chicken's ass.
Now some like it hot
some like it cold
Some take it any way
any way it's sold
I'm talkin' about
barbecue
All these things I pray
Come on, Smokey,
let's go for a walk.
I'm sorry about
spillin' my food, ma'am.
I'll just head on.
See that piece
of land over there?
See it?
That used to be a lake.
Yeah.
This one November,
all these ducks come by...
and they landed
on that lake.
Then the temperature dropped so
fast, the whole lake just froze.
Then the ducks took off
and took the lake with 'em.
Now that lake's somewhere
in Georgia, the way I hear it.
Go on now.
God bless you, ma'am.
Cool down, down
down by the bank
Banks of Jordan
Cool down by
the banks of Jordan
down by the bank
Here, try this.
So what do you think? They're okay.
The truth.
Well...
They're terrible.
Oh, well, don't be shy.
Tell me how you feel.
I will.
What'd you go and do that for?
I just thought you needed
a little coolin' off.
You're right.
Try these.
I think we need
to make a little paste.
What in the name of
Christmas are you two doing?
She's tryin' to teach me how to cook.
Look at those
fried green tomatoes.
You better stop this. I'm gonna have
to arrest you for disorderly conduct.
Arrest us then.
Let me handle this.
All right.
Grady.
Ha-ha-ha!
Arrest us.
Go ahead, arrest us.
Ruth, I have to say it. I believe
ldgie's been a bad influence on ya.
I agree.
I, I, I
I, I, I don't wanna
Hear you weep no more
when I'm gone
Don't wanna hear you weep
when I'm gone in my grave
In my grave
I'll be back in a minute.
Y'all keep the show
going till then.
We ain't goin'
nowhere.
...down again.
She's still poorly.
- Where's the baby?
- Who are you?
What do you want?
Frank!
Get outta here.
Get on outta here! Go on, get
outta here and leave us alone.
Come on now, Ruth.
You wouldn't deny a father the
right to see his son, would ya?
You git, I say. Scat you!
Damn! Gimme that. Let it go!
Well, that's my boy, isn't it?
Everything all right, ma'am?
Our guest is just leavin'.
Come on, Frank, let's go.
I'll be back.
In the end, you and
the baby gonna be back.
I ain't scared
of you! No, sir!
You should be.
Mind your manners, boy!
Grady,
what does Gladys think
of you stayin' out late...
And losin' your money to me
in poker night after night?
She likes it just fine.
They got Big George. Idgie !
- Let go of him!
- Let me handle this!
We seen how you treat your niggers
around here and we don't like it.
I'm the law in these parts. I don't
care what you like or don't like.
Turn him loose.
Don't get riled up,
nigger lover.
You deaf or somethin'?
I said, let him go!
Before you get yourselves in a
whole lot of trouble! Calm down.
We wanted to have
a little get-together...
and make sure we see
eye to eye on some things.
You hear me now?
Let's let him go, boys.
We've had enough fun
for one night.
Turn him loose.
Come on.
No, you're gonna
get in trouble.
Well, now, that's more like it.
Seems I don't recognize
any of you boys.
Y'all ain't from Whistle Stop,
are you?
This ought to do it.
I want to thank you,
Miss ldgie.
Forget it. You'd have
done the same for me.
Try to get some sleep.
Who the hell
were those assholes?
They's just some old boys from Georgia
come over here to put a scare in you.
Well, it worked.
One of'em was here
the other day for something,
seen you sellin' food
to coloreds.
They decided to come back,
shake you up a bit.
I told 'em we don't need anybody
from Georgia comin' over here...
Tellin' us what
we can or cannot do.
They won't be back. I
guaran-gol-damn-tee you that.
One other thing,
little Miss Smarty-pants,
I do not wear a size 14 shoe...
And I don't
much care for parades,
bedsheets or otherwise.
Hey. What's the matter?
It was Frank.
He saw the baby.
You sure it was him?
Yes, I'm sure.
So that's why those
Kluxers were here.
Let me take him.
Don't worry. I mean, if he's
dumb enough to come back here,
Grady and the Alabama boys
will take care of him.
If they don't,
I'll think of somethin'.
Don't take any chances.
Promise me you won't do
anythin' crazy, no matter what.
Me?
Not me.
I'm gonna put him down.
Hey, little Buddy.
That was the last
anyone saw of Frank Bennett...
until the night
of the town follies.
Ruth was away at one of the
Reverend Scroggins' many revivals.
One thing a woman
expects when she gets married...
Is sympathy.
Haven't you got that
since you married me?
I sure have...
from the whole town.
Hey there! You got to come quick.
Well, the show
has hardly begun.
You got to come quick now.
You hear me?
Run, get help! Run,
quick! Where's the baby?
Never mind.
Excuse me, sir. I don't believe
you should be goin' anywhere...
With Ruth's baby.
Thank you.
Hi there. What can I do for you boys?
Idgie .
Grady.
This here is Sheriff
Curtis Smoote. Hi there.
He's over here from Georgia.
He's lookin' for a fella. Oh.
You recognize him?
No.
That's my husband, but I
haven't seen him in months.
I heard he got run over
by a Brinks armored truck.
What's he done?
Nothin' that we know of. We're tryin'
to find out what's been did to him.
He told his hired man he was
comin' to see his wife and baby,
but he ain't never
showed up back home.
Hell, I told him
if he showed up in this town,
we'd all have known.
Looks a little sissified to me.
From what I hear,
most you boys in Georgia...
are a little light
on your feet.
That's the way I heard it.
Could I interest you
in some pie?
No, ma'am, but that
barbecue sure smells good.
Best damn barbecue
in the state of Alabama.
Here you go.
That's your 4th one today.
I swear you're about
to eat up all my barbecue.
Sit down.
You ain't foolin' me,
girlie girl.
I know who you are.
I heard from Bennett's hired hand
that you threatened to kill Frank.
He ain't showed up
dead yet.
But if he does, you in a whole
mess of trouble. You understand?
What we talkin'about
is murder here.
Runnin'a foul of the law
and nobody gets away with that,
not even a bunch
of Alabama smart alecks.
If I find so much
as a hair of his head,
I'll arrest you faster
than you can slap a tick,
'cause I'm the law,
and you can't beat the law.
Hey there.
Tell me what he said.
Smoote's? I told you.
He said...
That was the best damn
barbecue he ever had.
That's all?
No.
What else? He said the
pie was pretty good too.
You sure you ain't
never seen this man, boy?
Yes, sir, and I already
told ya, I ain't never seen him.
You'd do anything for
Miss ldgie, wouldn't ya, boy?
Yes, sir.
Would ya kill for her?
Did ya kill for her?
No, sir.
Well, now, maybe one of these
days you'll tell the truth.
Just remember, we hang
lyin' niggers in Georgia...
Just as fast as
they do in Alabama.
Yes, sir, I remember.
Sorry.
What are ya doin' in
here? No milk in the house.
Where were you?
Takin' care of business,
havin' a good time.
I've been thinkin'
maybe I should move on...
because of Frank
and all.
I just don't want
you to feel like...
You have to look out for us.
I just...
don't want to be selfish,
that's all.
Maybe if I wasn't here,
you'd settle down.
I'm as settled
as I ever hope to be.
Then... why can't you
tell me where you were?
I had a dream...
the other night.
I dreamt that Buddy was gone.
I ran to his crib and there
he was, sleepin' like an angel.
You know, I thanked God...
For lettin' me
still have Buddy.
And I remembered...
Havin' the same reaction
after Frank would beat me,
thankin' the Lord for givin' me
the strength to take it.
And I remembered...
Thankin' the Lord
for each day my mother lived,
even when she was
spittin' up blood...
And prayin' for me to kill her.
I looked in my mother's eyes
pleadin'for me to help her...
and all I could do was pray.
While you were gone,
as I was holdin' Buddy,
I thought if that bastard,
Frank Bennett...
Ever tries to take my child,
I won't pray.
I'll break his neck.
Ruth, you don't have to worry
about Frank Bennett anymore.
How can you say that?
It's his child too.
He won't give up on his blood.
I'm only gonna
tell you this one time.
Frank Bennett won't
be bothering you no more.
Understand?
You killed him,
didn't you?
No!
You don't believe me.
Right now, I don't know
what to believe.
Believe me when I tell ya
I don't want ya to move out.
If I can help
Somebody
As I go
Finally.
Thanks, I've been
out here all day.
If I can show
Somebody
That they're travelin'
Travelin'wrong
Then my livin'
Hey...
Shall not
shall not be in vain
Excuse me.
I was waiting for that space.
Yeah? Tough! Face it, lady,
we're younger and faster.
Towanda.
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
Yeah!
Whooo!
Towanda!
Yes, ma'am.
Whoooo!
Help, someone! What are
you doing? Are you crazy?
Face it, girls. I'm older,
and I have more insurance.
I never get mad, Mrs.
Threadgoode. Never!
The way I was raised
it was bad manners.
Well, I got mad
and it felt terrific.
I felt like I could beat
the shit outta all those punks!
Excuse my language.
Just beat 'em to a pulp!
Beat 'em till
they begged for mercy.
Towanda, the avenger!
After I wipe out
all the punks of this world,
I'll take on the wife beaters,
like Frank Bennett,
and machine gun their genitals.
Towanda will go on the rampage.
I'll put tiny bombs
in Penthouse and Playboy...
so they'll explode
when you open 'em.
I'll ban all fashion models
who weigh less than 130 pounds.
I'll give half the military
budget to people over 65...
And declare wrinkles
sexually desirable.
Towanda, righter of wrongs,
queen beyond compare!
How many of them
hormones you takin', honey?
Oh, when you give more
than you get
You're in danger
Well, honey,
what I can't understand is...
How in the hell
you can hit someone...
Six times by accident.
Oh, Ed, don't make
such a big deal about it.
Who knows what evil lurks
within the hearts of men
When you find
that you're losin'
- What the hell is this?
- A low cholesterol meal.
Happy Valentine's.
That's danger and
heartbreak dead ahead
My God!
Are you tryin'to kill me?
If I was gonna kill ya,
I'd use my hands.
Stop in the name of love
Before you break my heart
Think it over
I'm worried about
my little friend Evelyn.
She said her husband...
Will just be watching
his sports on TV...
And she has an urge to hit him
in the head with a baseball bat.
Hell, that seems normal to me.
Hi, Janeen.
Mm-hmm.
Mrs. Threadgoode, would
you like some crudites?
Thank you, but this raw stuff
don't sit good with me.
Mrs. Threadgoode, you
have to tell me something.
Did ldgie murder Frank Bennett
or not? Hold your horses, honey.
Where were we?
You didn't kill Ed, did ya?
Not yet.
Oh, good.
Anyway, five years had passed
since Frank Bennett disappeared.
And Smokey Lonesome been
missin'ever since that same terrible night.
I 'member the day
when he showed up again.
My God, son,
you're the spittin'
image of Ruth.
Buddy Threadgoode, Jr.
Nice to meet you, sir.
Well, sir, Smokey Lonesome.
Curtis Smoote was making one
of his visits to Whistle Stop, Alabama,
still huntin'and peckin'
for any scrap of evidence...
about Frank Bennett's
whereabouts.
Who wants to begin? Oh, I do.
I do, Miss Ruth.
Thank you.
We'll begin on page five.
Life has a funny
way of working things out.
Well, hey there!
Smokey!
Idgie ?
Smokey Lonesome!
If it isn't old home week.
How are you? Well, I'm
rattlin' but I'm rollin'.
What brings you to these
parts? Smell of good cookin'.
Hey, Smokey.
Sipsey. Let me fix you some lunch.
You know just about everybody
except Curtis Smoote.
He's the officer from
over at Valdosta, Georgia.
He's been lookin' for the same man for
almost 5 years. Very stubborn fella.
He loves our barbecue.
Mommy! Mommy!
Buddy.
Everybody outta the way.
Give him here.
Let him go. I've got him.
Come on. You're
gonna be all right.
Open the door!
Put him in the
car. It's all right, honey.
I can understand...
having a funeral for an arm.
I just don't know why she
insists on callin' him "Stump."
She say everybody
else gonna be callin'him that...
so we might just as well
be the first.
Okay, ice cream
and cake for everybody.
Go on.
My daddy always used to say there
was a separate God for children.
The good Lord was
watchin' over stump that day.
But then it started to rain
that month.
It rained and rained, and it
flooded parts of Whistle Stop.
That's why Grady's deputies stumbled
onto Frank Bennett's pickup truck,
and I just knew ldgie'd
never get out of this mess.
Now, you in or out? Remember,
I didn't take any cards.
Look at me and
let me see your face.
Idgie , I have to talk
to you. You're bluffin'.
Why don't you sit in? I'll deal
you a new hand. Gladys won't mind.
In private, ldgie.
Excuse us, Ruth.
A-ha. I'm just tryin' to teach
you not to fall for any tricks.
You're doin' a great job.
What's your hurry?
And what is so important?
What's that?
Somebody found Frank
Bennett's truck in the river.
What's that got to do with me?
Officially, you and Big George
are under arrest for murder.
You're in my custody
until tomorrow.
I'm supposed to take you to
Georgia first thing in the morning.
Unless, of course...
Well, some people have
been known to pack up...
And sneak out of town
in the middle of the night.
What about Big George?
Well, the way I figure it,
they'd be satisfied
if they had him.
Idgie , this is serious.
We're talkin'
murder of a white man.
Someone's gonna have to pay.
Nobody wants to hang a woman.
No deal.
Idgie , I know how you feel
about Big George.
Hell, we all do.
But these just
the facts of life.
I can't do that.
Take me to jail if you have to.
Well, that's what
I thought you'd say...
'cause you're absolutely,
unconditionally,
positively the most stubborn
person I've known in my life.
Idgie  and Big George went
to the county jail in Valdosta...
to await trial for
the murder of Frank Bennett.
They didn't have
to wait too long.
Did you know Frank Bennett? No, sir.
You mean, you
never met the man...
whose wife, Ruth, is your
business partner? That's right.
You never threatened to kill
Frank Bennett at his home...
In front of his hired man
in June of 1932?
The same Frank Bennett you did not
know. Oh, that was me, all right.
I thought you wanted to know if we'd
ever met... and the answer is no.
Um, I threatened
to kill him,
but we were never, what you
might say, properly introduced.
Is it not true that in September
of 1932 you came to Valdosta...
and took Frank Bennett's wife and
child back to Alabama with you?
Um... just the wife.
The child came later.
How much later? The usual. Nine months.
I suggest that you bribed...
this poor, weak woman with
promises of liquor and money,
and she lost control
of her senses momentarily.
When her husband came back
to get her and take her home,
you and your colored man
murdered him in cold blood.
No, sir.
Well, where were you on the
night of September 30, 1933?
I was at the town hall
doing a show.
And after that? I was
at my mother's house.
Oh, yeah?
Who was with you?
Just Big George and myself. What about
your mother? Can she confirm that?
No, sir.
She died a year ago.
I'm sorry to hear that.
But do you expect 12 intelligent
men to believe you,
although one witness is dead and
the other is a colored man,
known to be a worthless,
no-good, lying nigger?
You expect these men
to take your word for it...
Just because
you say so?
That's right, you gump-faced,
blown-up, baboon-assed bastard!
One more outburst like that...
and I'll hold you in contempt
of court. You understand?
Yes, sir.
Oh, Lord.
Next witness.
Did you know
that you were pregnant...
at the time
you left Valdosta?
Yes.
And yet, you tell us
over and over...
that you went with this
woman... willingly?
Yes. I wouldn't raise
my child with Frank Bennett.
But why?
Did this woman promise you money? No.
A bigger home?
No. No.
Then tell us,
Mrs. Bennett,
why would a respectable
Christian woman...
go anywhere with this ldgie
Threadgoode... I object.
Whose reputation
is known far and wide...
as a notorious liar
and drunkard?
- Objection!
- Sustained!
Why did you leave...
with ldgie Threadgoode
that day?
Answer the
question, Mrs. Bennett.
Because she...
She's the best friend
I ever had,
and I love her.
Thank you, Mrs.
Bennett. That will be all.
The defense
calls as its last witness...
the Rev.
Herbert Scroggins.
Place your right hand
on the Bible, please.
I brought my own,
if you don't mind.
You swear to tell the whole
truth and nothing but the truth?
I do.
You have
information about the whereabouts...
of ldgie Threadgoode and her
colored man, known as Big George,
on the night
of September 30, 1933?
Yes, sir, I do.
It has been
suggested here...
that she and her colored man
were at her mother's house.
Can you confirm that?
No, sir. That is a lie.
Oh, shit.
It has been my
habit to write all the dates...
of the activities of
the church in my Bible.
I show that the night
of September 30, 1933...
was the start of our
annual revival...
Down at the Baptist campground.
Sister Threadgoode was there...
along with her hired man,
George Pullman,
who was in charge of the
barbecue as he has been...
for the last ten years.
Objection.
That doesn't mean anything. Murder could've
taken place any time the next couple of days.
Have you ever been to one of
our revivals, sir? Well, no.
Do you attend church
regularly, sir?
'Course I do.
Good. Well, maybe if you
attended one of our revivals,
you'd know
they last three days...
and three nights, Your Honor.
Approach the bench.
Percy, it don't look like
you got a case at all.
In the first place,
there's no body.
Second, we got us a preacher
nobody's gonna dispute.
But, Your Honor... I'm tellin' you.
What you got is a lot of nothing.
I say Frank
Bennett got himself drunk,
drove into the river and
was long ago eaten up...
and I don't give
a good goddamn!
What we got here is a
case of accidental death.
Case dismissed.
Whoo!
See you in church, Sister?
Reverend.
I can't believe he
actually swore on a Bible.
Well, not really.
If that judge
had looked closer,
he'd have seen it was really
a copy of Moby Dick.
But why did he do it? For the sheer
joy of seeing you in church again...
Which I suggested to him
might be your penance.
You didn't promise him,
did you? Yes, ma'am, I did.
And I never break my word.
If I live 1,000 years,
I will never forgive you.
I don't know what's worse,
church or jail.
There now.
Don't you look pretty?
Oh, yes, honey.
You'll have me lookin' like
Ginger Rogers before you're done.
Don't let Mr. Dunaway see me.
He's liable to go wild.
I'm glad to see
you're in a good mood.
You've slimmed down quite a bit
in the last few weeks.
I'm just so happy Big George
and ldgie got off.
I would have killed Frank
Bennett if I could've.
Did anybody really
think she did it?
Some said yes, some said no.
'Course the only one who really
knew was Frank Bennett.
And you know what they say.
Dead men tell no tales.
Towanda-a-a!
Evelyn, what in the hell
are you doing?
I need some light and air.
Why don't you take one of
your walks or your jog...
Or whatever it is you do?
There's no dinner either!
Ed, you have any idea why I've
been goin' to all these classes?
No. I've been trying
to save our marriage.
What's the point
of my tryin'...
If you're gonna sit on
your butt drinking beer...
And watching baseball,
basketball, football...
Bowling and hockey and golf...
and Challenge
of the Gladiators?
Mrs. Couch, I'm Sue,
Mrs. Otis'daughter-in-law.
How are you? I've heard about
you from Mrs. Threadgoode.
She is so sweet. She's been
lookin' after my mother-in-law.
Now, how is Mrs. Otis doin', by the way?
Much better, thank you. It takes
time getting used to a strange place.
I'm glad to hear it. Mrs.
Threadgoode's been anxious to get home.
Mrs. Couch, Mrs. Threadgoode
doesn't have a house anymore.
They tore that down. What?
They had to. It was falling
apart, and it was condemned.
Oh, no.
Does she know that? No, well, we
didn't see any point in telling her.
It would just break her heart,
poor old thing.
But I am so glad
I got a chance to meet you.
You take care of yourself now.
Bye-bye.
Oh, Evelyn, hey!
Hey.
Do you like my roses?
Since I can't get home
to look at my own roses...
I made myself a paper garden.
Got everything but the
bugs. They're lovely.
You been here long?
Happy birthday!
Oh! I shouldn't have woken you up.
'Course you should've. Don't you never let
me sleep through a visitor's day, honey.
I look forward to them all
week. So do I, Mrs. Threadgoode.
Oh! I can't
believe you remembered.
You made me
fried green tomatoes!
Mmm!
They're delicious.
It's your recipe. Are they
cold? No. They're just the way...
We used to have 'em at
the Whistle Stop Cafe. Mmm!
You couldn't be sweeter to me
if you was my own daughter.
Here's your napkin.
And wait-wait-wait.
Queen, queen.
You know, I don't feel 83.
It sorta slipped up on me.
I never expected
to live this long.
'Course, the Lord takes us home
when he wants us.
Are you all right?
I was thinking about Ruth.
After the trial was over,
everything went back
to normal...
till that fall
when Ruth lost her appetite.
By the time Doc Hadley
looked at her,
he said the cancer was so bad
she only had a couple of weeks.
Well, we moved her
to the Threadgoode house...
and put her downstairs
so she'd be more comfortable.
Sipsey moved in with her
and never left her side.
Hold on, baby. I'm right here.
Idgie  just prayed for a miracle.
Now, listen to me.
Make sure he graduates.
And don't... let him
come to the funeral.
I don't want him going
through that mess.
Would you quit talkin'
like that?
What funeral?
You're gonna be back on
your feet feelin' just fine...
in just a few days.
Just you wait.
Oh, what's the matter, son?
Well, let's go for a walk.
Did you get into a fight?
I got punched in the nose.
I can't play
like everyone else.
Did I ever tell you the
story about... the oysters?
All the millions of'em
just lying around...
And God put sand in one of'em,
and it makes a pearl. Oh.
Did I ever tell you about
Eva's three-legged dog?
How it never felt sorry
for itself...
And how I ought to be smarter than a
dumb dog and not feel sorry for myself.
You listen to everything
I say, don't you?
You get real mad at me
when I don't.
Well,
you know about your mama.
She's sick.
Mm-hmm.
See, now is the time
for courage.
I guess you already know
that there are...
angels masqueradin' as people
walkin' around this planet,
and your mom's
the bravest one of those.
Come here.
Mama, I can hit!
You should see me.
Idgie , she hit me in
the back with a curveball.
I didn't duck,
and I hardly cried.
She hit you?
Well, she did that
to me once too,
but I think I did cry.
Mama, I'm sorry
if you're sad.
Well,
give me a big kiss then,
and I'll never be sad again.
And you best not be sad
neither.
You understand?
You promise?
Promise.
Attaboy.
You go and wash up.
Sweet baby.
You two be alone now.
Hey, girl.
No.
That's nice.
Will you do one thing for me?
Yeah, anything.
Be good to yourself.
Even...
Settle down if
you can find someone...
Who can beat you in poker.
There's so many things
I want to say to you.
No.
I love your stories.
Tell me a story, ldgie.
Oh, God.
Go on,
you old bee charmer.
Tell me
a good tall tale.
Tell me the one about the lake.
What lake? The one...
that used to be here.
Oh.
Well, that was just a lie.
I know that, fool.
Tell me anyway.
Tell me the story.
Well...
One time...
There was this lake.
And, uh, it was
right outside of town.
We used to go fishin' and
swimmin' and canoein' in it.
And see, one November...
This big flock of ducks...
Came in and landed
on that lake and, uh,
and then the temperature dropped so fast
that the lake just froze right there.
And the, uh,
the ducks, they...
Flew off, you see,
and took that lake with 'em.
And, uh,
now they say that lake is
somewhere over in Georgia.
Can you imagine?
It's all right, honey.
Let her go.
You know, Miss Ruth was a lady.
And a lady always knows...
When to leave.
When I think on
our departed sister, Ruth Jamison,
I'm reminded of our
Lord's Sermon on the Mount...
and how his teachings...
It's funny how
strong Ruth affected everyone,
even Smokey Lonesome.
When he died
a few years back...
he had one possession
on him,
a picture of Ruth.
He was in love with her
from the first time he saw her.
We all were.
I shouldn't
a-told you this.
I hate death.
It scares me so.
Death is nothin'
to be afraid of!
Look at me. I'm at
the jumpin'-off place,
and I ain't afraid
one bit.
Oh, Ninny, you're so brave.
Ruth and ldgie were brave,
not me.
I wouldn't be afraid
of death if I was you.
I'd be more afraid of driving
in rush-hour traffic.
Oh-oh-oh
Just listen to that rain
A-rainin' in the north
A-rainin' in the south
A-rainin' in the east
A-rainin' in the west
Ooh-ooh
Tell me didn't it rain children
Rain all night long
Didn't it
you know it did
I said, o my good Lord
didn't it rain
Hey, it rained 40 days and
40 nights without stoppin'
Noah got worried
and the rain kept a-droppin'
He sent out a raven
Sent out a dove
The water, good God
came down from above
They tell me my God
went and sent the rain
The women and the children
did begin to scream
They knocked on the windows
and they batted at the doors
While they... Hoo, hoo
Take on more
Noah said
No, no, my friend
God said
I can't let you in
Hoo, hoo
Listen to the rain
Uh-oh
Just listen to the rain
Listen to the rain
Just listen to the rain Oh, oh
Listen, a-listen to the rain
Oh, oh, listen
Listen to the rain
Yeah, yeah, listen
Uh-oh, listen
Listen to the rain
Yeah, yeah, listen
Last chance
Listen to the rain now
And then drip, drop
drip, drop
Drip, drop drip,
drip, a-drop drip, drop
Yeah, drip, drip, a-drop
Now, drip, drop
Drip, drip, a-drop
Hi, honey.
Look what I got you.
Ah...
Ed, how sweet!
Lilies! My favorite. Yeah.
I know.
Sometimes I even amaze myself.
What's the occasion?
Oh, honey, I just...
Feel sorry about
the past few months.
I don't know what you're really
up to and what's going on with you,
but I guess I could've been more helpful
with your job and everything, you know.
Well, why are you...
Puttin' up this wall
where you just tore one down?
Well...
I changed my mind.
I don't mean to seem
dense or anything,
but what's changed?
The air and the light.
Ed...
Hmm?
You remember how
you used to tell me...
You always wanted
two women in your house?
Oh, God.
Yeah.
Well...
What if I was
the younger of the two?
I don't believe
I get your drift.
I want something more than I've
ever wanted anything before.
I want to bring
Mrs. Threadgoode...
To our home.
I want her
to live here with us.
I want to give her the love
she's given me.
You're kiddin' me,
aren't you? I'm absolutely serious.
That's why I'm puttin' the
wall to Kyle's room back up.
Well, honey, this isn't
something you're just go and do.
I mean, she's an old woman.
What if she got sick?
Who's gonna take care of her?
I will!
I can't leave her
in that place.
She's not a stray cat.
Hell, she isn't even family.
She's family to me.
Now, Evelyn.
Evelyn?
Honey?
Ah, look...
have you mentioned this
harebrained idea to her?
Not yet.
Well, good!
Then we'll just pretend
it never happened.
I'm making my own money.
I'll pay for everything.
You don't have to do a thing.
Evelyn...
It's never gonna happen.
So just forget about it.
Don't you ever
say "never" to me.
Someone helped put a mirror
up in front of my face,
and I didn't like
what I saw one bit.
You know what I did?
I changed.
And that someone...
was Mrs. Threadgoode.
She needs my love and care,
and I'm gonna give it to her.
If you'll excuse me,
I have to go to the gym.
And if you won't listen
to reason...
There's always Towanda.
Hey, Nin...
What are you doing?
Those are her things,
Mrs. Threadgoode's things!
What are you doing in here?
Where's Mrs. Threadgoode? Who?
Mrs. Threadgoode! The woman
who lives here. Are you deaf?
I'm sorry, miss.
All they told me...
Was that the woman who lived
in here died this morning.
Oh, my God!
Wha... What
are you sayin'?
She died early
this morning.
They were shorthanded so they asked
me to take all this stuff down.
That's all I know.
Stop that!
What is the matter
with you people?
Can't you wait a goddamn day,
for Chrissake?
Do you have no respect?
These are her things!
I'm sorry, but they told me to get
this room ready for another patient.
She may be just
another patient to you,
but she was my friend,
and I loved her. I'm sorry.
I'm just following orders.
What is going on? Why
didn't you call me?
You could've called me before
you sent that idiot... I'm sorry.
It never occurred to me that
you would take it this hard.
I didn't even get to tell
her good-bye. Oh, I know.
These things are difficult, but
she died peacefully in her sleep.
To tell you the truth, I thought
you'd be happy for Mrs. Threadgoode.
Happy? Why, yes! This
is what she wanted.
What?
To be dead?
No, to go home.
You just missed her.
She left in a yellow cab
about a half hour ago.
I don't understand.
What? A cab?
She said there wasn't no reason for
her to stay now that Mrs. Otis had died.
Mrs...
Otis is dead?
Oh, Mrs. Otis died.
Mrs. Otis died!
Mrs. Otis!
Oh, God!
Not that... I'm glad that
Mrs. Otis died, it's just...
Oh, God, I've gotta stop her.
Hey, Evelyn,
somebody stole my house.
It was right here when I left.
Unless... Oh, Evelyn, you
don't reckon I'm crazy, do you?
It was here when I left.
No, honey, you're not crazy.
This is the place.
Why would anyone want to
steal an old lady's home?
Wasn't worth nothin'.
Oh, honey, nobody stole it.
They had to tear it down.
It was condemned.
I'm sorry.
I shoulda told you.
Well, somebody shoulda told me.
I'm old. I'm not a child. I'm sorry.
My husband Cleo and I
lived in this house...
For more than 40 years.
Now, it's... it's gone.
83 years worth of livin'
and all that's left of me...
Is what's in this box, a
bunch of old cards and pictures.
Come on.
I'll take you home.
This is my home!
And now it's gone.
And Mrs. Otis
is gone.
I...
I don't quite know what to do.
This is the first time I can remember
when I don't have a soul to look after.
You can come
look after me and Ed.
Oh, you're sweet,
but I think you're doin'
just fine on your own.
Don't you know you'd be
like a gift for us?
You're the reason
I get up every morning...
And that Mary Kay's
havin' such a good year...
And I don't look like some
blob from a horror movie.
Well, with a little help
from ldgie and Ruth.
Come on. I've got
your room all ready.
What does Ed say
about all this?
He'll learn to love it.
Did I ever tell you that Mrs.
Otis was Sipsey's baby sister?
No, ma'am.
Yes, she was.
Mrs. Otis was with Sipsey
and me the night Sipsey died.
Sipsey told me a story that night
I've never told a living soul, Evelyn.
A story about
what really happened...
the night Frank Bennett
disappeared.
Hey there! You got to come quick.
The show has hardly begun. You
got to come quick. You hear me?
Run, get help! Run,
quick! Where's the baby?
Never mind.
Excuse me, sir.
I don't believe you should be
goin' anywhere with Ruth's baby.
Like I said,
you ain't goin' nowhere.
Damn, you a thickheaded
son-of-a-bitch, ain't you?
I told you...
you ain't goin' nowheres
with Miss Ruth's baby.
Come on, angel.
Come on.
Come on, sweetheart.
It's all right.
Come on.
It's all right, baby.
It was self-defense.
I don't know why any white
jury would care why I did it.
Well, I saw it, and I can
testify. Excuse me here.
I don't mean no offense here,
but I don't know who's less
likely to convince a jury,
my mama...
or Mr. Smokey.
No offense taken.
You're a good man,
Mr. Smokey.
You did good.
The sun's almost up.
George?
Mm-hmm?
I think...
It's hog-boiling time.
No, ma'am. It
ain't cold enough.
It's hog-boiling time.
Big George?
Uh-huh? When is that
barbecue gonna be ready?
It's gonna be ready
any time now.
Smells so damn good I just
can't wait to get me some.
Now, don't you forget to call
me when that's ready. All right.
Here you go.
Miss ldgie? Smokey left town. Yeah?
I thought it'd be best
under the circumstances.
He asked that
you tell Ruth good-bye.
Shame he had to go.
Hold on! I'm comin'.
What you want?
We want some barbecue.
Not today you don't.
Go on.
Why, this is about the
best barbecue I ever ate!
The secret's in the sauce.
Sipsey?
My God!
That fryin' pan did more
than fry chicken that night.
Did ldgie really barbecue Frank
Bennett? Are you pullin' my leg?
Secret's in the sauce,
or so I've been told.
Now you know why
ldgie had to go on trial.
She knew the law would never
believe Sipsey. No!
Sipsey or Big George
or anyone else of color...
Would've been hangin'
from the nearest tree.
To this day,
I'm still not sure...
Whether Ruth ever believed...
That ldgie didn't kill
Frank Bennett.
Truth's a funny thing
sometimes.
I feel better now.
Good.
I feel better 'cause
all these people'll live...
As long as you remember 'em.
You reminded me...
About what the most
important thing in life is.
Do you know what I
think it is? No, ma'am.
Friends.
Best friends.
Oh, Ninny!
Look.
Oh!
Idgie ?
Idgie 's alive?
Oh, yes!
She's still out and about
charmin' bees and selling honey.
Sometimes I think
I catch a glimpse of her.
Maybe we'll see her today.
Maybe.
Let's go.
After Ruth died and
the railroad stopped runnin',
the cafe shut down, and everybody
Just scattered to the winds.
It was never more than just
a little knockabout place.
But now that
I look back on it,
when that cafe closed...
the heart of the town
Just stopped beating.
It's funny how
a little place like this...
brought so
many people together.
I'll remember you
When I've forgotten
all the rest
You to me were true
You to me were the best
When there is no more
You cut to the core
Quicker than anyone
that I knew
Now when the roses fade
I'm in the shade baby
I'll remember you
Now listen didn't I
Didn't I love you
Didn't I didn't I care
Didn't I sleep
and didn't I weep beside you
With the rain that
was blowing in your hair
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh
I'll remember you
When the wind blows
On through
the piney wood
It was you who came
right through for me, baby
It was you
who understood
Though I'd never say
That I turned the way
That you have led me to
Darling, in the end
My dear sweet friend
I'll remember you
Yes, I will now
I'll remember, remember
I'll remember
I will remember you
Yes, I will
Time ain't gonna
change nothin', baby
We can be halfway across
the world from each other
Don't make no difference
I'll remember
Every hour, every second
Every moment that we had
We do it, we do it
We do it don't do it
Gonna do it, do it
do it, do it, do it
I'll remember,
I'll remember
Oh, I'll remember you
I'll remember you
Yes, I will