Kevin Gable,
please see the manager.
You, uh --
you wanted to see me, Owen?
"Owen"?
Sorry. Mr. Durning.
Exactly. Like the name
on the sign out front.
That's right --
my dad owns the place.
You've mentioned that
a couple times.
Here's the sitch.
I noticed on the security
monitor that you popped
a cube of cheese from Rose,
the sample lady.
It was a free --
Don't deny it, chief.
I see everything.
I'm not denying it.
She asked me to try it.
I don't know --
Is there a problem with that?
Would there be a problem
if Homeless Joe came in here
and started peeing
on the apricots?
I didn't pee
on the cheese.
Now, one more screw-up,
and it's your keys.
The whole ring, chief.
You feel me?
I do.
I-I feel you.
Then why are you
still here?
I don't --
I don't know.
Hey.
Sorry I'm late.
Did you know All American Burger
is right across the street?
I pulled in there by mistake.
It's like muscle memory.
My body was like --
just wanted to go there.
Yeah. Well, I'm glad
you made it here.
And I know your policy
on foreign food --
If you can't read it,
you don't eat it.
That's right.
What's the, uh --
what's the deal here?
Do I got to take off my shoes?
Do I got to bow to anybody?
It's Vietnamese.
No.
Okay, well,
just so you know,
I'm not eating anything raw --
anything, okay?
And I don't want to cook
my own food, you know,
where they put the hot rock
in the middle there
and they're like, you know,
"Get to work."
I'm like, "You get to work.
That's what I'm paying you for."
Honey, I know
all your food rules, okay?
There's no rocks.
There's no raw food.
There's
no sourdough bread.
Why would I want my bread sour,
by the way? Seriously, I mean...
You're gonna love it,
all right?
Oh, great.
Look at this.
What?
I can see the sign
from All American.
It says "urger."
It says "urger," but I know
what they mean, and I know --
We got to switch.
Switch with me.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Switch. Switch.
It's like a lighthouse
calling you home.
There we go.
Well, I got to admit,
it was a nice surprise
to get your call.
I thought you were gonna be
at the supermarket till 8:00.
Oh, yeah, uh, cute story.
Um...
There might have been
a little dustup
involving
some cubes of cheese --
that were complimentary,
by the way.
Mm-hmm.
You quit?
Yeah, I did.
I also kissed Rose,
the sample lady --
just to make a point.
Wasn't sexy.
Her teeth shifted.
It was weird.
I'm telling you.
Should I be worried
about this?
No! Trust me --
she's not gonna sue.
She lit up like a candle.
I'm telling you.
That's not what I mean.
That's, like,
the fifth job
you've walked out on
in two months.
Honey, what's going on?
I know we need extra money,
all right?
But I just can't take these kids
bossing me around anymore.
Okay, well,
don't worry about the money.
We'll figure that out.
But you need to find something
that you like,
something
you're passionate about.
Yeah, I would love that.
That's awesome.
Oh.
Thank you.
What am I
looking at here?
It's pho.
It's what?
Pho.
Well, pho looks like
a clogged sink.
What are those chunks floating
around in there? What is that?
It's chicken.
You love chicken.
Did he make this outside?
What is this?
Okay, babe,
it's seasoning!
Just try it!
Okay.
Good?
Hold the pho-one.
Yeah!
This is insane.
This existed
this whole time,
and you don't
tell me about it?
Yeah, and wait
till you try the beef.
This comes in beef?!
Oh, hey, babe.
Ugh. Never be
a school nurse.
I had to send two kids home
with chicken pox,
and I'm so paranoid
that I have it.
I'm, like, itchy.
Will you look at my back?
Your back is fine.
Where do you keep
peanut worm?
Um...
Hey, hon,
where's our peanut worm?
What...is happening?
Let me get you caught up
to speed.
Yeah.
Remember that soup
that I loved last night?
Yeah.
Well, Mr. Chu here,
he made it.
Oh. Oh, Mr. Chu,
hi.
We -- I showed him my back.
I'll tell you later.
All right, anyway,
I went down
to the restaurant today
and...
Well, long story short,
Mr. Chu works for me now.
Uh, with you.
This guy's got no filter.
He's crazy.
Um...
Wait.
Working with you?
What -- so you're opening
a Vietnamese restaurant?
Well, that was
my first impulse,
but then I cooled my jets
and put my business cap on.
Chale, hit me up with it!
90% of all new restaurants
go belly-up within a year.
You know
what doesn't go belly-up?
Food trucks.
That feels like
it can't be true.
Chale.
A-Actually,
you're both right.
But food trucks have
a much higher rate of success.
And currently, there are none
on Long Island that sell pho.
Thank you, Chale.
However,
in my opinion --
Okay, you know what? I will
point to you when I need you.
So, yesterday,
you didn't know what pho was,
and now we're in
the pho business?
You told me to find something
I'm passionate about.
Well, with this, I can be
my own boss, thanks to you.
Okay, well,
that's great.
But how much
is this gonna cost us?
It's just 25 grand.
What?!
Honey!
We don't have 25 grand!
No, no, but we can swing 5,
and for the rest,
I brought in
some investors.
Let's meet...the Sharks.
Three retired
police officers
searching for their slice
of the American dream.
And my brother.
So, they're
all into this?
Not yet --
I got to pitch them.
But if we get four yeses,
we're in business.
Pho ready.
Oh! Pho ready.
Let's do this.
What? What?!
Showtime.
Showtime!
Oh, Chale,
please don't encourage him.
I just want him
to like me.
Gentlemen, good afternoon.
I'd like to talk to you about
a little place called Vietnam.
Country of mystery.
Once our enemy,
now our friend.
And at last, we can enjoy
one of their finest
achievements -- pho.
Pho?
Yes. Don't let
the weird name scare you.
Think of it
as a warm blanket
from our friends
from the Far East.
What's all this green stuff?
This guy's like a caveman,
I swear.
It's seasoning.
Give it a shot.
Man, this is
actually really good.
Right?
I love the hunks of meat
at the bottom.
It's like a --
a treasure hunt.
Yeah.
It's like a reward for pushing
away all the green stuff.
You know what? I don't
really mind the green stuff.
Minty -- like a cross between
lettuce and brushing my teeth.
Okay, well, guys,
that's great,
but is there even
a business plan?
Because you can't have
a business without a plan.
I couldn't agree more.
You know what?
Chale,
slap the math on her!
The food-service industry
generates $782 billion
a year.
If you were to make
just 1% of 1% of that,
you would all
be quite wealthy.
Do you hear that? Okay?
This is not soup.
This is a ticket
to happiness!
And what does
that ticket cost?
Just $5,000.
$5,000.
Per man.
I don't know --
that's a lot of bacon.
Mott,
can I ask you a question?
Are you happy?
I am.
Mott, are you happy?
Yeah, I'm -- I am.
He's happy! He said he's happy.
Leave him alone.
I'm just saying
I don't think he's happy.
What?!
Mott. Look at me.
I want you to focus now.
Are...you...happy?
I'm not happy?
Thank you
for admitting that.
That was big, okay?
Now, Duffy, please,
let's be honest.
We know you're financially
dependent on your mom.
Don't you want
to break free of that?
Yes, I do.
Then you got to do it.
You know what? You're right.
I'm gonna do it.
I'll do it right now.
No, no, no, wait.
You got to get the 5 grand
from Mommy first, and then...
Kyle.
Yeah. What?
What's 5 grand
between brothers?
I'll just pull it
from my fireman's pension fund.
Smart move.
Actually, it's not.
There's, uh, crazy penalties
for early withdrawal.
No, no, no, man, this whole deal
sounds too risky.
'Cause it's a lot of risk.
It's a lot of risk.
Yeah, but you know what?
We're betting on ourselves.
That's
the difference here.
You know what?
I just ran the numbers.
I'm gonna have to take out
at least $7,000 to --
Kyle,
nobody gives a crap.
You know what --
I'm gonna take out $8,000,
just to give myself
a little walking-around money.
You know
what I'm saying?
Duffy's in, right?
Kyle's in.
Goody, it's up to you.
Oh, man.
I'm in, too.
Can't watch these guys
get rich without me.
Yes!
I'm in.
All right, Mott,
you are the missing piece.
What am I doing?
I'll just take out the full
$10,000 and treat myself.
Look,
I got seven kids.
Yeah, and that's
seven mouths to feed.
But...I want to be happy.
I'm in.
No!
We got
our four investors.
Come on, honey.
I can't do this without you.
Are we in?
I -- Uh...
Okay, fine! We're in.
Awesome! 'Cause I already put
the down payment on the truck.
Hey, folks.
Kevin Gable -- CEO/founder.
I'd ask you how the soup is,
but that electric smile
tells me everything
I need to know.
Once again, Kevin Gable --
CEO/founder.
Hey. There you go.
Enjoy.
We have been so busy all day.
You're a hit, Dad.
I told you.
You having fun, sweetheart?
Yeah. Slinging soup in a hotbox
for no pay?
Living the dream.
That's my girl.
Hey, Mr. CEO, you want
to chop some onions?
Sorry, Mr. Chu,
but I'm a little busy out here
putting a face
with the brand, okay?
No, you come in here,
take out the trash.
This guy
knows nothing about branding.
You know what I'm saying?
Anyway, Kevin Gable --
CEO and founder.
Wow! Honey,
look at all these people!
It's working.
Okay,
you sound surprised.
I am. I mean,
I'm not gonna lie.
I went
and got more insurance
in case we had to
torch this puppy.
That's funny.
No, I'm serious. I went and saw
Jeannie on the way over here.
Okay.
In the future,
next time I get a feeling,
you might
want to ride with it.
Okay, you're right,
you're right.
So, what's a girl got to do
to get some pho around here?
Oh, well, for you...
Yeah?
...you got to wait in line
and pay.
'Cause it's -- it's a business.
I'm running a business.
Mm-hmm.
All right,
you're cute, kid.
I'm gonna get you one.
Chicken or beef?
Surprise me.
Okay.
With chicken.
You got it.
Hey, sweetheart, just take one
of these out to your mom, okay?
Okay, yeah,
um, Dad, this lady
wanted hers
with no scallions, so...
Oh. Okay. Uh...
Whoop! Sorry.
Mr. Chu, uh,
this customer right here,
she wanted this one
without scallions.
No special orders.
This is
my grandmother's recipe.
No offense to your grandma,
but she's not here right now,
and this customer is.
So let's just --
let's make an exception.
Okay.
Ahh.
Scallions gone.
Okay.
Clearly, this is not
about the scallions, okay?
Obviously,
you're on a power trip.
Without me, you're just
a thick man in a rusty truck.
Now you don't
like the truck?
I like the truck.
I don't like you.
You don't have to like me.
Just make the soup, okay?
Otherwise,
I'll do it myself.
You make the pho?
It's not
that difficult, okay?
It's basically Cup O' Noodles
with some meat floating around.
Sorry, Grandma Chu.
I don't need this!
Oh!
I quit!
Oh, fine.
No scallions, right, you said?
No scallions.
Okay, uh, we will be
right with you.
The secret's in
the slow cooking.
Dad, we need it now!
It's ready. Here we go,
just like Chu's.
Tell me what you think.
Okay.
I called the investors meeting
a little early this month.
Oh, and I know why.
I drove by.
I saw the line.
Ka-ching, ka-ching!
Yes, and we are gonna continue
having those lines
when we introduce
Kyle's Firehouse Chili!
What?
I thought we were here
to divvy up the profits.
Yeah,
I want to be happy.
You're gonna be happy --
with Kyle's Firehouse Chili!
Something wrong with you?
We sell pho.
We used to. We're pivoting.
Pivoting?
Chale.
"Pivoting" is a business term
to describe
when a company changes
its strategic direction.
Why are we changing anything?
We're doing great.
Yeah.
Hey, where's Mr. Chu.
Chale?
Mr. Chu has pivoted
away from the organization.
So we'll get
a new pho guy.
Uh, we tried that,
but, uh, apparently,
we have been blackballed
by the entire pho community.
What was it
they called me?
Xe tai khi,
which is Vietnamese
for "truck monkey."
Yes.
But don't worry,
because...
No, no, don't point at him
and say "chili" again.
I wasn't
gonna point at him.
I was gonna point at you --
'cause everybody loves
Goody's world-famous
egg salad sandwiches!
Have you lost
your mind?
Okay,
I want my money back.
We got to sell the truck.
Sell the truck.
Yes.
Whoa.
Wait a second.
That is a decision
only the CEO can make,
and that's me,
and I say we're pivoting.
Well, wait a minute --
We are the investors,
so technically,
you work for us.
Mm.
I don't think
it works that way. Chale?
It works
exactly that way.
What did you think
being a boss was?
Just walking around
giving people orders?
Kinda, yeah.
You have to sell the truck.
Now you're on the side
of the investors?
Honey,
it's the only side!
And, by the way,
we are the investors.
We could lose
a lot of money.
Who's gonna be stupid enough
to buy a used pho truck?
You! You bought
a used pho truck!
Look, I called the guy
who sold it to me.
I tried to sell it to him.
He laughed at me.
Yeah, I figured.
But we do know a guy
who would want to buy it,
who's already
in the pho business.
Mr. Chu? No way.
No, he said
he liked the truck.
He knows
you guys were killing it.
He called me a truck monkey!
He hates me!
I know! I know,
but you can talk him into it.
Honey,
when you want something,
you are the most persuasive
person I know.
Okay, that's not true.
Oh, really?
Night we met --
Mulcahy's.
You're out
with your dumb friends,
You're making noise,
and you walk up to me
with your badge out,
and you say, "Excuse me,
I'm gonna have to arrest you
for being too beautiful."
I was pretty smooth, huh?
No, no! Smooth?
No, it wasn't smooth.
You tripped
on the way over.
You were eating a gyro,
and then
when you introduced yourself,
you spit on me -- here.
But you won me over
because you're so charming
and persuasive.
Wow. I got to say, we remember
things completely different.
What?!
Yes!
Okay.
I was at the bar.
I was hanging out,
minding my own business, right?
Mm-hmm.
I notice you
and your girlfriends
are all checking me out.
Oh!
Yeah.
You know how I know?
'Cause the temperature's rising.
The back of my neck
feels like a --
like a tater tot
under a heat lamp.
Oooooh.
And then I turned to you guys --
I remember.
And I looked,
and I said,
"That girl right there,
I'm going to marry her."
And then I thought,
"You know what? Nah.
I'm going for the tall,
skinny one instead."
Best decision
I ever made.
Bet your life.
Okay, there he is.
Remember -- Mulcahy's.
Yeah.
But don't spit on him.
Gotcha.
Mr. Chewbacca!
What up?
I am busy.
I thought about it,
and I just feel terrible
about messing
with your grandmother's recipe.
You know, and if --
if she found out,
I figured she'd be
spinning in her grave.
She's not in a grave.
She's in the kitchen.
You keep her
in the kitchen?
In an urn or something
like that?
That would be disgusting,
right?
Like in a chair,
eating lunch.
She's not dead!
Oh.
How old is she?
I don't know.
She's very old.
Truck. The truck.
Anyway, the point is,
I have to place you
under arrest
for having
some crazy-dreamy eyes.
You know
what I'm talking about?
Honestly, I just --
I just want to swim in them.
I just want
to swim in them.
But you're right -- I'm not cut
out for the food truck business.
But you --
you have a gift.
And all I'm here to do
is try to help you out
and sell you my truck.
I mean, come on.
It's good business.
You know that.
You know,
it already says "pho" on it,
so we're gonna
give you that for free.
That's right.
You know,
you're right.
It's a very good
business.
Mm-hmm.
And that is why I bought
my own food truck today.
See you in the streets.
Okay. Well, I guess
we're stuck with the truck.
Unless you know some other idiot
who's sitting around
with a ton of money
burning a whole in his pocket.
Hey, chief.
What brings you back?
Let me ask you
a question, Owen.
Are you happy?
Wow.
I got to say,
for an old guy,
you're still able to make
a few good decisions.
You're gonna love the truck.
Just make that out to "Gable."
It's G-A-B-L-E.
There you go.
Thanks, bud.
All right.
Yes!
Hey, Mr. Gable.
Uh, did you want
to be alone?
No, no, grab a beer.
Sit down.
I just wanted to say,
um...
I know things didn't turn out
exactly as you expected,
but, um,
I really admire you.
You started a business.
You made something
from nothing,
and that is
a very hard thing to do.
Well, you know,
I had a business for a day.
You know,
I had some customers.
For a moment,
it was pretty sweet.
Oh.
You've been bitten by the bug.
Entrepreneurs like you and me,
Mr. Gable,
we dream big dreams
and we take big risks,
and sometimes,
they don't work out.
But we never give up.
We just regroup
and come back stronger.
Thank you, Chale.
I-I hope so.
I speak from experience.
I once had a business that I was
very passionate about.
It --
it was a great idea.
I put everything I had
into it.
Didn't work out.
What did you do?
Well...
Ohhh.
I, uh...
You moved in my garage,
didn't you?
Yeah.
Yes.
And you live there rent-free
so you could "regroup."
I probably should've
thought this all through
before I started talking.
Yeah.
Um...
I will leave you
to your thoughts.
Okay.
And leave the beer
to my thoughts, as well.