KEVIN IS NEEDED TO TALK ABOUT
If the ball about ...
they must learn to dance
like a princess, right?
1, 2, 3 ...
- 1, 2, 3 ...
- Yes!
to wear what I do today?
- I'll wear ...
- I will wear ...
- A bucket on his head.
- No!
- 1, 2, 3 ... Not?
- one on the barrel.
- No!
- and taking cloth bags to shoes?
- No.
1, 2, 3 ...
Welcome.
Oh, boy!
Want to eat anything?
No. I do not feel hungry.
Yes, it does.
Yes.
Franklin?
As you well. I want
leave a message for him.
I think we can talk,
only two of us without kids do not?
I want to overcome it.
Is not?
I really miss you.
Eva Khatchadourian!
She has done a lot here.
Listen, Eva.
I does not matter
that she was,
or she has done. If you know
typing and clerical
I would hire her.
How about something with.
Thank you.
I will not disappoint you.
I promise you. Thank you.
- Thank you very much.
- Nothing.
Come on Monday.
Well, thank you.
Looks like someone is there
must be a happy day?
You're pleased you?
Sorry?
I hope you washed crushed
Hell, old whore!
Oh God, what?
She all right?
Nothing.
I'm alright.
- Let me call an ambulance.
- Self-causing me there.
- But she has ...
- No, I'm fine.
Eva, when you home?
I missed you.
I love you.
Promise  he is going
not to leave again okay?
I will never, never.
I promise okay? Promise okay?
I promise.
On safe?
Where not.
The real you?
Are you sure?
It really happen?
I can see, see it squirming ...
He made  here.
I needed her placement this
today, Eva.
But today my afternoon break.
You remember? I told then that.
Really dead, that's right.
- Give these to Massughi.
- Yes.
- Hi Eva.
- Hey, Al.
No, leave me out!
Please leave me alone!
- Put me out!
- Continue to go.
She Oi! She Oi!
Please help me!
Put me out!
Eva, do not hold your breath.
Do not hold your breath, Eva.
Eva!
And know.
Do not sleep anymore, Eva.
On nearly finished.
- Welcome!
- No, do not wake it.
I just finished it sleep, Franklin.
Hi baby.
World instead. I want to play?
I want to play the game?
You all right?
Do not do more than that.
You think I do too why?
Just swing it is a ty.
Just swing it a ty is given,
How that time.
He your father's small!
My God! All 12 results?
- They are why I still get.
- No need to ...
I was still taking off!
I am a pretty boy boyfriend.
We would love  daughter headline.
You know it. Do not wake up.
Do not wake up.
I say "mother" go?
"Me mother seriously," "mother," Kevin?
I said, "shadow", go? "Bong ... excellent ...
"Shadows"?
Not? OK.
She will be throwing it for me,
I threw it to me, the house?
Do.
Throw it to me.
Now, go throw it to me.
No stars, no stars.
Throw back okay?
Cho is to be rolled.
So ...
When I was last birth,
it does not stop crying.
I used to think that
will damage your hearing.
No, it's very good hearing.
But it must be said, right?
I once read somewhere that
without saying that ...
Early symptoms of autism.
It did not manifest
other symptoms.
Do not worry too
about it.
It is not
baby against children?
But how well it's all right.
Thank you.
Got it.
Roll it to me lightly.
Very good. Any rolling again.
This is done, Kev.
Got it. Making light.
Is not?
This is elephant gray,
it's as big as houses,
very big, not baby
the same mouse.
I say "elephant" to go, Kevin?
"Elephant"?
"Elephant."
Kevin?
I say "mother" your mother go?
No!
- "Mother"?
- No!
- Say "mother" to go.
- No.
Hoax or kind?
I got you know someone.
I do not like it.
I do not like that!
Mother been happy before
with Kevin, you know?
I now had to wake up every morning ...
and wish I was in France!
The elevator is
deadly traps here.
It needs a garden,
a place to play,
a swimming pool.
But I love New York.
Come on!
Slogan of someone by it.
This is the priority, Eva.
It only children
once it has.
He clung to "the things he wanted to," go.
I will not leave this city where.
Kevin, come on, there's enough.
Mother and father are talking.
Kevin, stop immediately!
large room here.
Bedrooms  homeowners in the following,
and two large dressing rooms.
Park after the great .
We arrive then, the whole family.
Our castles!
I seek food preparation,
anyone want anything?
Wait! Ms. K!
I'm here.
Soweto.
Good evening.
I just want to know
This stroll at it.
She was healthy, thank you.
She looks good here.
Yes. The doctors said it was still
opportunity for me to walk again.
So good.
Keep healthy light and K.
Me too.
Come on, come on!
Die! Die!
No! No! No!
- This Death!
- I jumped What kind?
This death!
Come on! Come on!
Kev, you on it you?
Kevin?
Kevin, you heard?
Dad is pee on the toilet.
I can also do that.
Sister, click here.
See that? She clicked the connector
then it will open.
If not ...
We'll try again.
- Press left his cell. Want to try?
- Yes.
- No, no.
- I'm sorry.
- Place it, then.
- Right.
See that? Open it here.
Right. Thank you.
Sure I understand.
Thank you for help.
The extrusion and diarrhea.
Welcome, old, star?
The extrusion à diarrhea?
No problem. Dad will help you.
No problem.
I went to his room, he'll be to soon.
Do I wake up.
Go away, cu.
All square sheets of paper
lem painted trash, stupid.
Everyone should have
a corner of their own.
I have my room.
This is the mother's room.
Mother can help make your room
so special, if you prefer.
"Special" mean?
This means that it reflects
of human personality.
What is personality?
I thought I knew there and then.
It's absurd.
No, no, good.
I do not need it you?
And him?
Got it.
I mean if you have to take care of all ...
I can.
Really?
Both which are great.
Okay, John.
Be mild. I'll tell you later.
Goodbye.
Kevin?
Nothing to say anymore?
Go wash your face!
It just said sorry.
And it's just trying to help children
so special.
Remember why you have that?
What is really most
mother did.
You know how people
teach a cat?
Tuck them into your nose
Department of faeces.
We do not like that.
And from there they discharge into the box.
Now, let's work
with numbers.
- Number of 3's behind?
- 9.
- Number 7's behind?
- 71.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5,
6, 7, 8, 9, 10,
11, 12, 13, 14, 15,
16, 17, 18, 19, 20,
21, 22, 23, 24, 25,
26, 27, 28, 29, 30,
31, 32, 33, 34, 35,
36, 37, 38, 39, 40,
41, 42, 43, 44, 45,
46, 47, 48, 49, 50.
Now we stop now?
Hold off.
The community they go,
because you are too intelligent.
I do not ...
I felt good to do you?
I can see
doctors alone.
I have to tell her this, Eva.
She is very energetic boy.
- Thank you.
- Nothing.
What did your mother,
it is wrong.
And she very apologetically.
Kev? Kev, wait minute!
Kev?
Kevin?
Kev, why is this?
I broke my hand.
Why do you break your hand?
The extrusion diarrhea in diapers.
Mother had to go for a new diaper.
And I fell down from the table
truck toys at changing diapers.
Mother took me to
Goldbutt doctor.
It's all in me.
No, I do not think cycle.
Where can I look after it
any time of day was.
Franklin ...
Unbelievable.
What style do it?
Anyway, also progressive.
Unfinished.
Got it.
I love you.
I do not like this.
Turn it off.
Department of pet, you mind
if the supermarket where she parked?
I want to go home.
As the mother should buy ...
Well we go home.
Hi all!
Dad! What now?
Dad took the beautiful photos you?
Eva, it was just a boy.
A very good boy.
Like every other boy.
Fat mom out!
Ever ...
I never new him to say?
Soon. The time now.
Why do arbitrarily decide
without him?
Now I know I say?
Then he planted the seed bears little
Bear in the womb, then it
become an egg.
18 + games is that right?
I understand that it is?
Is this guy put the "pee spot"
the "primary site" of the other.
Hug ...
I do not want anyone
play with me?
No.
You might like here.
What if I do not like?
Then only you will become familiar.
Just because she was familiar
with something ...
does not mean she likes it.
Familiar with the child and that parent only.
Oh yeah ...
In the few months we
will have to get used to new people.
Linda.
Kev, I went to see my sister.
This is his son, Kevin.
This is his child.
Yes, that's right.
This is Kevin.
Yes, yes ...
Kevin! Do not do that ...
No, Kevin, where so wise.
No problem dear.
I went shopping for food?
Come on.
to Ecuador? In 2 months?
Why not send someone else to go?
I really want to do this.
Initially it  cried a lot,
then complete silence.
Translated by Sangeras @ A4AS
It  create a separate language,
and this is worrying.
It looks very silly,
that is not normal.
Could we see here
is not a type of hatred?
So it's not good for .
Franklin, go pick up the phone!
Pick up the phone  go.
... 13, 14, 15,
16, 17, 18, 19 ...
... 20, 21, 21, 22,
23, 24, 25, 26, 27 ...
Give me some water,
please!
Kevin?
Kevin!
Department of honey?
I all right?
I'm sorry mom.
Do not worry, dear.
Now I support it.
"With all our hearts," Gilbert exclaimed.
"He is a devil in disguise,
good but why watch it? "
"No," Robin said, laughing.
"I believe I do not promote the sort."
"Then he took an arrow other ..."
I okay, Department of honey?
"Then he took an arrow other
and placed on the cord. "
Once again, he fired.
Again, he withdrew the arrow and
release into the stele near the middle.
The third time, he stretched cord
and release the arrow on
next two steles,
at the center of attention,
The plumes of birds
the three arrows stuck
come together as one big bundle.
Then the excited whispers
appeared in the crowd ...
Hi warrior, child stars then?
I better yet?
Dad went away. I'm tired.
Alright.
Yeah, boy.
I need sleeping?
Read on to her.
He released the arrow into the target 280,
with speed and accuracy horrible.
All were shot on target
back of a porcupine ...
detector when hunting dogs arrive.
Hello, ma'am.
I hope not to disturb her.
Actually there is.
We just have some questions for her only.
Regarding what?
She will go after death?
Ah yes, I know but.
I will go straight to hell.
Are doomed forever.
Thanks for asking.
Yet?
Department of honey, to me, please help her.
I know how self-dressing.
Mother was not going out?
Be.
Mother was glad I was better.
I want to eat soup
no lunch?
Whatever.
- With cheese or bread?
- I do not care.
Thanks Dad, this is amazing.
What where cu.
So, looking into the middle.
Nearly hit by then. Take.
Play again.
Try lightly.
Use your finger ...
Keep your eyes looking arrows.
You do, Kev.
I have genius here.
Perfect.
Thanks Dad.
Okay.
Hey  It's like this.
Getting up .
then watch TV.
In the car, then turn the radio up hear.
Then we come to work,
or go to school,
but we never hear about that
on the 6pm news item.
Why?
Because nothing really
is happening at all.
Then you go home and watch TV again.
Or, sometimes, that fun night
and we go out
and moviegoer.
Really bad is very often
the guys on TV,
inside the TV program,
they also watch TV.
And what do we see?
Those who like children.
And now she is doing what?
watching her children.
Mother  believe they will immediately change the channel
if you are "A"
geometry does not?
Kevin and his children are playing
game "Kidnapping Christmas."
Kevin!
Kevin, he is your friend!
He is your friend.
Come on, Celia.
Get his soda.
Not that, you stupid.
Root Beer cans marry.
Why?
Thank you, Celia.
He thirsty.
Hey, I want to know
a secret?
Again recently.
I know everyone is not thirsty?
Not you?
Beast in a vacuum.
Stop Now!
- Hi all!
- Dad!
See What brought about this announcement!
Kev, get him back here.
Well, of course.
- Want to dance?
- No, thank you.
- Take that, once.
- Where I do not dance.
The something new her pleasure,
pride that went there?
She also thought that madman
She now wants you?
Stay away. Drink extra billion more.
Why?
- The fun?
- Yes.
I could not believe it too!
- Too great discretion?
- Yes.
Kevin!
Looks like the mother that children in
bookstores today, right?
No.
The delicate, she vowed always.
By the way, you can do
on Friday?
Why?
I thought the house could
do something together.
That we are family.
Do what?
It is possible to restaurants.
Or go out on a
yard mini-golf place?
Got it.
Why do not you bring
jacket on?
I always do everything to
not comfortable enough?
Uncomfortable?
With his mother?
Every time I see fat people,
is that they are eating.
Not due to poor digestion
or item which is hardly trivial.
It's food.
They are fat because food lying around.
Eat more and eat his lips dripping.
Sometimes a mother is enough.
I was talking too.
Well, yes.
The children who inherit it from?
Good, I won.
What happens next here, mama?
I will go home, I'll wear
something more serious.
Then she take me to dinner.
Or.
We eat of that preparation.
I feel hungry.
You're that big.
I choose salads,
re-steak and a bottle of wine.
Got it.
How about at school?
The world.
Every school schedule.
What about teachers?
Some have ...
Mother asked the listening
music groups you?
Then she asked what is the pro-
is making me insane.
And we can always say mouth
everything depends on you,
but before the goods can opener,
make sure you are ready.
By the time dessert,
she'll talk about drugs,
Be careful,
she did not want to intimidate the
Where am drunk on drugs.
Then she tells me
what she experienced.
And when she stopped gulping
This wine,
she looked gently ...
and to say to you is great
when spending time together,
her arms on the shoulders of children,
I clutched at a time.
Too bad!
- Computer and damaged mother.
- Yeah, that's right.
The job data as well.
I thought I deserved that.
- Why do you have things like this?
- The collection here.
The craziest is worth collecting stars?
I do not like the postage stamp.
What is the purpose here?
There is no purpose at all.
That is the aim here.
No, really does not matter where.
As Sam. I gotta go.
Wish her a good day.
Bye.
Merry Christmas.
Okay, Kev,
I now turn.
Guess what?
Series 7 here. Vendor
said that the best ones in the shop.
- Sun. Thanks Dad much.
- Merry Christmas.
What do you want any breakfast?
You're doing good, Snuffles?
I heard a noise in there?
Sounds great discretion?
Celia!
Any child. Go to bed now and then.
Stand up.
I thought I
but closed it.
Kevin said I was stupid,
and he was right.
Where I am not stupid.
Do not worry, parents will find.
Now go to bed.
Uncomfortable?
I now make are Snuffles
pet shop in the sky then.
- Do not say that! Do not say that!
- It's the truth!
O you,
We focus here
Snuffles pray for ...
Come on!
Who died ... a tragedy ...
Then mother and father have found it all night,
and know why that child
not find it?
Because Snuffles is out
to live in the garden then.
Now it is living in my garden,
with so many new animals.
Celia.
Okay, put her spoon.
We will have a big party tonight
with small raccoon and squirrels, cats and bears ...
they will eat nuts with fruit,
very much the same ...
Why do water bottles to
cleaning out?
I did not.
- I had taken so long.
- So why is he out?
As Kevin.
Kevin did.
You should see a psychiatrist come.
Kev, mother to have
want to say to you here.
I want ...
Thank you for calling an ambulance.
And?
And ...
Mother worried that children might feel
I take responsibility.
Why?
Because you have to look after his brother.
I have nothing to blame myself at all.
No. I did not
Where self-blame.
I assume it will have to use your eyes, Kevin.
Should parents expect children
good will for his brother
institutions rather than a name ...
Dad did not remember that
I was a child star?
Celia not only to overcome.
Mother thought I hated the fabric.
Not so at all.
Now for the ...
I like to eat them.
I'm very sorry.
Do.
Got it.
Thank you.
- His son. Set next to you?
- Yes yes.
- Celia, who wishes to pick a name?
- No!
So ...
Are you trying to do?
Let's wait for the school year ends,
and prepared for anything this summer.
At least the guardianship
is also easy decision.
What?
He decided already?
Eva, what else to decide where.
What happened then.
- I need a drink of water.
- Hi, Kev.
Listen, son,
very misunderstood what the child
heard if the "external context" here.
Something that "out of context"?
The key is context.
- Appeals are free to kill.
- No.
She will lose everything.
Work, home.
I will pay by the house.
I always hated it.
What the hell die!
A package sent to
Kevin Khatchadourian.
- Careful, it's heavy.
- So you?
- Have a good day.
- Sister too.
It used to do?
Where can I use the bikes.
I saw it on the network
very cheap.
I will make a whole lotta
when sold at the school.
Just like Donald Trump.
He will lead you to your boat.
1, 2, 3.
Ready for the end yet?
Pleased to meet you, ma'am.
- No, not where.
- Do you instead.
Okay.
Hot forehead.
I all right?
Having never been better.
And third is that the 16th day there.
The should do something.
How about Sunday?
I do not know.
Perhaps your child then.
It's clean up this pile
I dressed to go?
I do not want to go to school.
You know, but it would take a bath
then we go.
Say "goodbye" What!
I think we can talk, only two of us,
without kids do not?
I want to overcome it.
Is Kevin studied in
School Glanston not?
Franklin ...
Pick up the phone  go!
My son is there.
Kevin?
Kevin!
Lauren!
Franklin?
Celia?
I do not seem happy.
I had a star?
The nearly 18 then, right?
Mean?
Prison makes you afraid?
Fear?
Do you know anything about the place
like this?
I have been calculated
satisfied with everything.
A minor child was
incapacitated by the drug Prozac say.
I'll be out of jail
after 2 years.
Know today is what?
I know my mother to
no visits on Mondays?
Knowing, the birthday child.
Two years.
Enough time to soak about it.
I want you to tell me why.
Before I thought I knew ...
Now I'm not sure anymore.
Time's visit then.