Subtitles by DramaFever
[The Bride of the Water God]
[Production of this work was supported
by the Korean Creative Content Agency.]
What do you see?
Are birds flying?
Yeah.
They're flying beyond the sun.
Where are they flying to?
I'm sure they're flying
to the world over yonder.
Can you see it?
Take a good look.
No, I can't see.
Want me to allow you to see it?
Yes.
Here. Take a good look.
The world we live in is composed of the
our world, and the world over yonder.
We live in this world,
and the gods live in that other world.
Gods?
The world that the gods live in
is composed of Water Country,
Sky Country, and Earth Country.
Those from the Realm of the Gods
send gods over to our world
in order to look after the environment
in the human world.
They don't look after
human beings, though?
Humans can take care of themselves.
The kings of Water Country,
Sky Country, and Earth Country
were fated to be kings from birth.
The king of Water Country, in particular
is also given the special power of being
the emperor of the Realm of the Gods.
The new emperor must bring the three
god stones together and make a royal seal
in order to become the next emperor.
However, the gods
who have those god stones
are the guardian gods
who reside in the human world.
So he has to come here
to find those stones
to become the emperor of the gods?
Yes.
What happens if the guardian gods
won't give up the stones?
Well, that's something that
only humans would do.
But there's something strange about this.
Why did they leave the god stones
in the human world?
[The Bride of the Water God]
[Episode 1]
[Whether it may be a
relationship with one's parent...]
[2018]
[One year ago]
High Priest.
It's about time that the red water came.
Looks like the Realm of the Gods will
welcome a new emperor after 3,200 years.
Where is Lord Habaek?
For my lowly self to be given this honor
truly is quite gracious of you, my lord!
To think that I'd be
painting a portrait of you...
I understand why the heavens chose you
to be the next in line for the throne!
It's time... for me to do your eyes, sir.
He's sleeping.
The... finishing touches...
Lord Habaek.
You have a call from the High Priest.
Tell him to stop calling me so much.
Why does he have to ask me so many
insignificant things every day?
The water of Water Country
has turned red.
So he said that you
should make preparations.
Does the king know about this, too?
He is quite happy.
He has been eagerly awaiting
the red water for a long time.
I understand how he could be exhausted,
seeing as how he was king for so long.
These are the locations of the
guardian gods who have the god stones.
These coordinates will lead you to them.
Lord Habaek.
Moo Ra will be the god
from Water Country
and Joo Dong will be the god
from Earth Country.
- Who is the god from Sky Country?
- Lord Bi Ryeom.
Bi Ryeom?
We must have the coronation by the
seventh time the red water flows
so all you have to do is get the
god stones and return before then.
I will return immediately.
Why, my lord? The  is
far more interesting than you'd think.
You will have quite a lot of time
before the seventh red tide
so enjoy yourself while you are there.
I have no interest in that.
Also, why do such archaic and
meaningless formalities still exist?
There is no such thing as a
meaningless thing in this world.
At any rate, the first thing
I will do as king
is get rid of these archaic
and meaningless rituals.
Yes, go ahead and do that
when you become king.
It sounds like you're implying that
I may not be able to become the king.
Of course not, my lord.
You were fated to become king
from the moment you were born.
You'd become king even if you
lay still and did nothing.
How could that possibly happen
unless your fate were twisted?
What relevance does becoming the emperor
of the Realm of the Gods have with humans
that the god stones
are kept in their realm?
What a nuisance.
Oh ho.
Since you've asked that question...
you may linger there and
find the answer for yourself.
It isn't a question.
Oh, you've heard of the
gods' servants, haven't you?
The humans who have promised
to become the gods' servants
generation after generation?
If you get into a tricky situation,
seek out a descendant from this family.
All you need to do is show them this
and exchange a few words with them
for them to accept you as a god.
I do not need it,
since I won't be seeking them out.
It is a woman.
Shall I show you her face?
She's not from the Shin family.
No thanks.
Nam Soo Ri will be serving you.
It may be difficult, but please
keep that with you at all times.
And don't just leave it
in your clothes somewhere!
Sky Country is doomed.
They've sent Bi Ryeom as
the guardian god of the skies.
There's no way he'll carry
out his duties properly.
Why do you hate
Lord Bi Ryeom so much, sir?
You were so close as children.
He has no decorum.
And... he's not trustworthy.
You'll have to study up on the
human world before you go, sir.
That's precisely why
I'm bring you with me.
I heard that you've
been to the human world.
Well, yes. I do know everything
there is to know about that place.
You'll feel a bit of a shock when
you pass through the Gate of the Gods.
It can actually be kind of addictive.
Prepare the finest human clothing for me.
And a present for Moo Ra, too.
Have you seen your servant's face?
I heard that it's a woman.
Is she pretty?
Yes, I see.
Aliens from the planet Intro-Q2544
delivered a divine message to me.
My leader is TF1004, but this
seemed to be quite an urgent matter.
I see. Anything else?
On Earth, there are Earth Partners like
me who carry out these divine messages.
There are people who belong to
our organization all over the world.
But the strange thing is...
why did they deliver this message to me,
instead of a partner in the States?
That's what baffles me.
Yes, I wonder why
it was delivered to you.
Oh, "Tell Obama that
world peace is at risk."
That's what this means, huh?
Doctor, are you...
What should I do,
since I don't know his address?
Do you know about the thing that
came out of the White House?
You don't believe me either,
do you, Doctor?
No, of course not. Patient--
Patient? Did you just call me a patient?
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
- Patient!
- Who's a patient here, huh?
Um, Ma Bong Yeol.
I'll try to find Obama's address
in any way I can, so--
Goodness!
Stop lying when you
don't even believe me!
Oh... Doctor. Doctor!
Nobody will believe me!
- World peace is at risk, here!
- Stop it!
Sir, sir!
Please let go of her before
you continue speaking!
It's true that world peace is at risk.
You... understand our language?
Of course. Nice to meet you.
Oh, it's nice to meet you!
All right, let's go. Let's go.
Let's go.
How did you learn his language?
I did some research.
His language has a rough system,
just like the alphabet.
Bong Yeol is quite
intelligent, after all.
He's better off than me.
His guardian wanted to
have him checked in here, right?
I can't do it. Schedule
another appointment with him.
How could you give up so easily, Doctor?
Give up easily?
Hey, I've been seeing him for a year now.
You think it's easy
for me to admit defeat?
Am I supposed to hold on to him
just because of my pride?
I'm worn out, too.
Yes, Doctor.
Here's half of the notices
to you from the banks.
The bank said that they can't
extend your payment due date
and they want you to
come in tomorrow.
What?
Why not?
Well, the psychiatric hospital
isn't doing too well
and you haven't been
paying the interest on time.
Are they telling me to
shut down my practice, then?
That's what it sounds like to me.
Leave.
Give me your coat.
I'll wash it for you by tomorrow.
No thanks.
Want me to have a drink with you?
Why would I have a drink with you?
Oh yeah, you forgot this before.
It's for your land in Gangwon-do.
[Land Tax Notice]
[Taxpayer name: Yoon So Ah]
You still haven't sold that land yet?
Who'd buy a useless field of gravel?
Why did they have to leave me
things like this behind?
The hospital is behind on
a lot of its bills, too.
I'm sure you've lost half of
the security deposit already.
So why are you sticking by my side?
Just leave!
Well, I'm trying to
repay my debts, of course!
- After all, you--
- That's enough!
I don't want to hear it.
Is that still your dream, Doctor?
- To leave Korea?
- Yeah.
As soon as my debts are repaid,
I'm going to go live in Vanuatu.
Just get yourself a man who
will take care of your debts for you.
And just live here.
No, I don't want to. I hate Korea.
Are you sure that it's
not just men that hate you?
Hey. I even once got a diamond ring
from a second-generation heir!
Oh, I found it!
Geez, why won't he believe me?
I definitely got one!
You were still here so that you could
become mine eventually, huh?
Also, what kind of name is An Bin?
How childish.
Take care of my bills and the
interest on my loans, okay?
Vanuatu, my love.
Now that's what I call living life.
I can't even see a single star properly
in this disgusting country, ugh.
Please, please let me get tons of money!
Hey, woman.
Woman!
I will grant you the honor of allowing
you to lend this to me for a bit.
Hey, woman.
Wake up!
You shouldn't be sleeping here, right?
What a bothersome woman.
What happened?
What's going on?
Ow.
Oh... ow!
Oh man.
Huh?
You damned thief!
"Thief"? Why, that insolent woman!
I'll see you next time.
What in the world happened?
Nam Soo Ri.
Where did Nam Soo Ri go?
Lord Habaek! Lord Habaek!
You're safe!
What happened?
I don't know. I fell over there.
Why do you look like this, sir?
And why are you wearing my clothes?
Pardon?
Oh... what's going on?
Trade outfits with me.
This is strange.
The location of the Gate of the Gods
is different than last time.
Take a good look around.
I heard that this place can change
a lot, even in 10 years' time.
No, the land used as the
Gate of the Gods never changes.
Then something must have gone wrong
while we were on our way here.
Where are the coordinates?
What? You don't have them?
Oh no!
Oh dear! Geez!
Use your divine powers to find them.
Did you find them, my lord?
What's wrong?
It's strange.
It feels as if...
something seeped out of my body.
How could this have happened?
How could you have lost
your divine powers?
First, let's return to Water Country.
Take me to another gate.
I can't, my lord.
A god who comes here can only return
once he finishes his duties.
I told you to study up...
First, let's look for the
descendant of the god's servant.
It's times like these
when we need their help.
You don't have it?
Oh no! What are we going to do?
I'll look for some clothes
to change into first.
- I'm all right.
- Well, I'm not.
Don't go anywhere. Stay here.
You can't just act haughty and confident
and give commands to just anyone, okay?
All right.
Oh, damn it!
No, there's no way.
I'm sure that this is only temporary.
I couldn't do as I wished when I
first went to Sky Country, either.
So how close are you, exactly?
How many times do I have to tell you?
I had my diamond ring stolen!
I'm not drunk, okay?
I am Habaek.
Why did I come to the park?
I told you, I came here
to find my diamond ring.
What? Delusional?
Hey.
Where are you now?
I am Habaek.
Just answer my question, okay?
Where are you, you idiot?
I am Habaek.
- Where?
- I am Habaek!
That surprised me.
See, I told you that I'm Habaek.
Yeah, it's working fine.
There aren't any issues with it.
Turn it off for now. Let's try turning
it on and off two more times or so.
It's that woman.
What's going on?
Is he walking toward me?
Do I know him?
No, I don't know him.
Woman.
You were mistaken.
I just borrowed it
for a bit, is all.
Pardon?
Are you talking to me?
If you tell me your name and residence,
I will have Nam Soo Ri compensate you.
What is it that you need?
Mental illness can strike anyone
regardless of their appearance, huh?
Your family must be quite
worried about you, so go home.
Don't decline. Just tell me.
It's all right.
You dare defy me?
I told you to tell me, not to leave!
Damn it all.
Maybe he's delusional?
I asked you what you needed.
Money?
What is that?
It's fine.
Please go home soon. Goodbye.
- Let go of me!
- Your name and place of residence.
I'll report you if you don't let go!
- I said let go!
- Doctor!
What are you doing?
I said let go! Ow!
- Ow!
- Whoa, let go, sir!
Don't be like this, sir!
How dare you defy me,
and then do this?
What's wrong with your forehead?
Did you hit her?
No. Let's go.
I am the god of the water,
to-be king of Water Country
and to-be emperor of
the Realm of the Gods!
I am Habaek.
I am the god of the water,
to-be king of Water Country
and to-be emperor of
the Realm of the Gods!
I am Habaek.
I knew it.
He has delusions of grandeur.
Here.
Our clinic isn't too far,
so stop by sometime.
Our doctor is great at treating patients.
Be sure to come by!
[Nurse Yoo Sang Yoo]
You know that your life's calling
was to be a psychiatrist, right?
People who need your help are
always finding you, day or night.
Shut it.
I bet you'll only meet people like that
at "Banana Boat" or wherever, too.
It'd be better for you not to go.
Still, isn't Korea better--
Where's the closest police station?
Why? Are you going to report him?
- Yeah.
- Take the high road. He's ill.
I'm going to file a report
for my diamond ring.
Are you still drunk?
They said they'll give you
a call after investigating.
Are you mad?
I feel like they don't believe me!
Okay, let's say you did bury a diamond
ring under a tree many years ago.
But you also said that
a shooting star stopped
and went back and forth three times!
And then a robber fell from the sky
and stole the ring from you?
And yet, they left your wallet behind?
I'm telling you, it's the truth!
Do you want a glass of cold water?
Oh wait, she doesn't like cold water.
How about some hot water, then?
Where were you?
I was collecting information from humans
and finding lodgings for tonight.
Let us go. I've found us an
adequate place for tonight.
- It's close to the water, too.
- There's no need.
- My powers came back.
- Really?
This water behind me heeded
my command and shot upward.
I knew it.
All right, then.
Please make that into gold.
This is the closest place to water,
so I'm sure you'll find it comfortable.
Here we are.
I already blew it up,
so it's too late.
A human male gave this to me
and told me to visit.
You spoke with humans?
Oh, I told you not to
say anything to them.
Happy Psychiatric Clinic,
Nurse Yoo Sang Yoo?
What?
Oh, I was just reading this.
You don't know how to read
the human language, do you?
Sleep well, my lord.
I will keep watch over you all night.
As for the coordinates,
I'll continue searching once day breaks.
Pretty much anything in the
human world can be solved with money.
I asked you what you need.
Money?
It's not "money,"
but "mo-ney," you idiot.
There was a call
from Happy Bank, too.
Did you borrow money from there, too?
I wasn't the one
who took out that loan.
Yeah.
I wouldn't have been able to take care
of this just by selling a diamond ring.
Money?
What is that?
Yeah, his mind must be at ease.
That's all you need in life.
Let us talk while taking
a walk around the resort.
You start, Food and Beverage Team.
We have 300 Chinese guests here today
for the construction of a harbor.
A Chinese heir named
Li Woi will be here.
Please go, CEO, and--
No need for me to go,
since this isn't an official state visit.
What about you,
Business Strategy Team?
Yes, sir.
This is a proposal from
Block Company from England
for the construction of Block World.
There haven't been any changes
to the land we inspected before.
It's not bad, as long as
the issue with the land is settled.
I'll take a look at it.
Is your report about
the bank, Intel Team?
Yes, there is a bank that says they will
lower their interest for several loans.
And they wish to have
a meal with you, CEO.
Must I really go?
I think it'd be good for you
to meet them once, sir.
Scientists have succeeded in detecting
a second wave of gravitational forces.
There may be a third or fourth wave
of gravitational forces coming at us
at this very moment.
The time-space continuum in Seoul
may have shifted without us knowing.
Today on "Fascinating Science,"
we'll talk about gravitational forces.
You're here, Doctor?
No calls from the police station?
None.
They say that the time-space continuum
in Seoul may have shifted yesterday.
Do you think that's when the
diamond ring disappeared?
I went to Dongdaemun Market
early this morning to buy it.
Just wear that for now.
You should've just gotten some sleep.
A doctor's coat is so
important to a doctor.
- Don't you feel sick?
- I didn't get drunk.
What about breakfast?
Again with your nagging.
There's nothing for you
to eat at home, right?
I'll have to go make
some side dishes for you.
Do you have a death wish?
Someone rear-ended
your car last month, right?
Named Park Sang Chul.
They called again.
I already took care of things
with my insurance company.
I don't know. They said they'd come
to meet you, then said never mind.
It's so confusing.
When are you going to go to the bank?
You won't be able to solve this
by pushing it aside it for later.
I know that.
Are there any appointments this morning?
Of course not.
You don't have any in the afternoon
either, so go whenever you want to.
You delayed payment on your
loan's interest many times.
And you haven't taken care of
your credit at all, Customer.
Your income for last month
was far too low.
Please look this over one more time.
I always paid my taxes properly.
I'm only going through
difficulties for the time being.
So many people go to
psychiatric hospitals now.
Then... we can start charging you
only seven percent interest
after you repay the first loan
but... I'm not sure if the
Examination Division will accept this.
Seven percent?
How can it go up from
four to seven percent?
Please look into this for me, then.
Where did that guy go now?
[Happy Psychiatric Clinic]
[June 24, 2017, 2:10 p.m.]
Gosh, why is it taking so long?
Excuse me! Excuse me? Excuse me...
How much longer will it take? I have
a patient waiting for me at the hospital.
Please wait a little bit longer.
Oh my, what do I do? What do I do?
President, did you enjoy your lunch?
Would you like a cup of
Ethiopian hand drip coffee?
If you borrow money from our bank,
we'll offer an interest of one percent...
What? One percent?
Excuse me.
- I told you to wait!
- For how much longer?
All I've done is wait
since early this morning.
All I want is an extension on my loan.
Is it really that hard to do?
Why are you going all over the place
with my personal information?
How about... how about you wait outside?
I'm not waiting!
And why do I get seven percent
when he gets one percent?
- Why are you discriminating?
- Well, that's because--
I know. I get it. But this is too much!
The difference between seven
and one percent is too much!
Please help her first.
We'll continue our talk
through my finance team later.
Wait, President. Don't go...
Apologize to the president!
What did you say?
He's upset because
of you rudely butting in!
I don't agree with that.
It's your fault for exposing
my interest rates to another client.
- I think you should apologize.
- Pardon?
I'll make a request to the bank
so you can get the loan that you want.
Why would you do that?
It was simply out of
the kindness of my heart.
Then stop harassing the employees
about the interest rates
and work harder to make more money.
Please visit our clinic. Please visit...
Please visit...
Hey, wait! Stop!
Why did you wipe off the bird crap
with our business card?
I mean, why?
- What's going on?
- It's nothing.
- What happened?
- Why did you wipe it with our card?
Don't do this.
If you contact me separately,
I'll resolve it.
This business card is our face,
and you wiped bird crap with it!
- Stop, let's just go.
- I mean...
What are these wipers for?
They're here to clean your windshield!
If your car is big,
is that all that matters?
I'm sorry...
Psychiatric clinic?
I'll contact you after I get a quote.
Sir!
What about the coordinates?
Did you find them?
No, I think I lost them
on the streets earlier today.
On the streets?
Then there's no hope of finding them.
I guess not. But why did you come out
when I told you to stay home?
Home?
I noticed you sleeping well last night.
I thought you were going to stand guard.
I couldn't help it because
I was sleepy and hungry.
- Are you hungry?
- Yes.
Newbies like me get hungry,
just like a human.
I'm sure a god like yourself
can't understand.
Do I... have to continue
listening to that?
No.
Are you really hungry?
I am.
I'm sorry.
This is all because I lost my powers.
I can't even take care of
a devoted servant like you
so I don't know how I can ever
be a good king in the future.
Excuse me? No, that's not true!
Did you really
expect me to tell you that?
- No.
- But what is that used for?
Oh, that is...
It's not food...
- Let's go there.
- Pardon? Where?
The land of the Gate of the Gods.
It's protected by my servant's descendant
so if we go there,
we'll know where to go.
Pardon? Are you going
to meet the descendant?
Giving my servant an
opportunity to fulfill a mission...
As a god, it's my generosity and my duty.
What do we do?
Don't those wipers cost millions of won?
I might have to move out
of my one-room apartment.
Then why did you go
into a raging fit like that?
Because he wiped bird crap
with our precious business card.
I didn't know you were so devoted.
But why did it have to be his car?
Are you calling Secretary Min?
Ask him for a discount.
I'm not calling him.
Gosh, why isn't the real estate agent
answering his phone again?
- I'm going to Gangwon-do.
- Right now?
If you're taking the expressway,
change your tires.
And the oil for your brakes,
and your navigation...
Wipers...
Gosh, why isn't it working?
Don't act like a used navigator, okay?
There.
Did you say you're going
to Chungbong Village?
Go straight that way. All the way down.
And when you feel
that it's right, turn left.
Then go straight, and when you
feel like it's right, turn right.
If you do that, you'll see it.
Do you understand?
What did that human just say?
Oh, he said we're close.
Don't worry. I've been here
multiple times already.
I didn't get a call
from anyone for five years.
That's why I made a request last time.
I asked you to post some advertisements
and take extra care of it.
Geez, I got it. I got it.
I came here today to lower
the price for an urgent sale.
No matter how cheap it is,
who will buy that useless piece of land?
Sir, you're not wrong, but you shouldn't
say that in front of the land owner.
Fine, are you going to
sell it for half the price?
Half...
We were supposed to enter through
that gate. Humans can't see it.
It looks quite shabby
for the Gate of the Gods.
But the descendant of your servant
doesn't know anything. What will we do?
We need to give her the crest
we lost to wake her up naturally.
Don't worry. There are other ways.
Like what?
She'll fall for my charms.
There's no way she won't listen to me.
And if that woman doesn't fall for it,
I'll use my last resort.
And what's that?
Pardon? No, not that, sir.
- Why not?
- That mustn't be used.
We can recover the crest
when we go back.
That way, she'll forget everything.
But not if you use that method.
That... will be too difficult
for a human to handle.
Ever since last night,
until this very moment...
you've continued to display foolish acts
so what is this foolish thing
you're saying now?
And, above all else,
you lost your powers.
- So will it work?
- Why does it matter?
If I don't have powers, am I not a god?
Then, why don't you act as my master?
How could you say that?
I didn't mean it like that.
Excuse me!
Excuse me, why are you here?
This is my land.
It was you.
Let go! Don't do this!
I am the god of the water,
to-be king of Water Country
and to-be emperor of
the Realm of the Gods!
I am Habaek.
Why is he here?
- Are you the land owner?
- Yes, I am.
- Are you thinking of buying it?
- Why would I buy my own land?
Pardon?
I've looked for you for a
very long time, my servant.
It's so very nice to meet you like this.
Be deeply touched...
that I'm happy to see you.
- What the heck are you doing?
- How dare you?
Don't you realize you were
destined to be a psychiatrist?
People who need your help
are always finding you.
I need to see Yeom Mi.
I think it's time to see Yeom Mi.
Sir.
I wish you'd give me a signal
before you did anything.
Hey, Yeom Mi! Do you have time tonight?
No, you need to make time.
Let's meet tonight.
I'm in Gangwon-do right now. Oh my gosh!
What? What happened?
Hey, I'll call you back later.
Are you all right? Let me see.
- Don't worry, I'm fine.
- No, you're not.
I don't think I'm okay.
I'm not fine.
Please enter the road
in the three o'clock direction.
I'll drop you off at a nearby hospital.
Let's call the insurance company there.
No, I will follow you
wherever you're going.
Excuse me, if he's hurt,
how will he make it to Seoul?
And why are you being informal?
I don't know what you mean,
but wake up so you can understand.
Everything will be easier
once you understand.
What did he say?
Excuse me, is there a hospital
you visit regularly?
If not, come to our hospital...
What am I saying?
Excuse me.
I'm a doctor, and your friend--
He's not my friend. He's my servant.
Then, your servant...
No, this man...
is completely fine in my opinion.
I'm just driving you because
I hit him, so let's cooperate.
I don't know what you're talking about.
This isn't the road I took earlier.
Please turn right.
I don't see a road to my right.
Please go straight.
It feels like we're driving
into the mountains.
Please turn right.
Please turn left.
Please drive straight.
Please make a U-turn.
Please enter the road
in the 11 o'clock direction.
- I'm going crazy.
- Please be careful of the curb.
Please go straight
in the 12 o'clock direction.
- The road is blocked!
- Please go straight.
- Where am I supposed to go?
Please drive safely.
- Are you tired?
- Yes.
What... should I do to help?
- Nothing.
- Should I drive?
Do you have a driver's license?
What's that?
No.
Doctors don't let their
patients drive the car.
Please turn right.
No!
What's the matter?
This? Her car stopped
because she ran out of gas.
Then give her some gas.
How?
Lend me your cell phone.
A cell phone. Don't you have one?
Fine, let's walk.
I'm sure we'll run into someone.
We'll borrow a phone and call
the insurance company or buy gas.
I don't know what you're saying,
but get some rest.
- Pardon?
- You're tired. Get some rest.
Nam Soo Ri will go by himself.
But, he's hurt.
- That's right, I'm hurt.
- No, you're not.
I don't think I'm hurt. I'm not hurt.
Go.
No, it'll be quicker if I go.
Oh my! Wait, excuse me!
I don't even know where anything is.
- Excuse me!
- Yes?
This is my license plate number
and insurance policy number.
And this is money for gas... Hold on.
This.
I almost forgot.
Okay.
Why...
am I so unlucky today?
Excuse me!
Wait in the car.
I'm fine out here, so get some rest.
My name is Habaek, not "Excuse me."
I am the god of water,
to-be king of Water Country
and to-be emperor of
the Realm of the Gods.
And I'm your owner...
Habaek.
Gosh, I keep forgetting he's a patient.
Excuse me, Patient...
I mean, Habaek.
Why do you think you're the water god?
What kind of question is that?
Then what about you?
Why do you think of yourself as human?
Fine.
Then, what is the god of water?
What are you trying to do with me?
As a human, do you want me
to teach you a lesson?
It seems like you want to talk about
the principles of the world.
Listen well.
The god of water, the god of the sky,
and the god of earth.
We're... nature.
I'm...
nature.
- A natural person?
- I'm nature.
A natural person?
I'm nature, and on top of that...
I'm the most natural of nature.
He looks totally normal on the outside.
Stop glancing over.
I can see it with my eyes closed.
I'm very used to getting looks like that.
Yes, I'm sure you are.
Do you... have a family?
I could say I do,
and I could say I don't.
We don't have the same family
relations that humans have.
- Then who was that friend--
- I told you, he's my servant.
He's like you. Nam Soo Ri is
my servant in the Realm of the Gods
and you're my servant in the human world.
- Look here, Servant.
- Yes?
- Excuse me!
- It's Habaek!
Do you really need money
more than anything else?
Why?
Why do humans need money so badly?
Because money means happiness.
- For you too?
- Yes, why do you ask?
I... think I can do that for you.
Not right away,
because of my current circumstances.
Why do I keep falling for it?
Hey, Servant.
If you need money
more than anything else
because money will make you happy
that means what you need is happiness.
What do you really know about me?
However, I have no interest
in the happiness of humans
so I'll reward you with money.
I think we should help him.
- Are we going the right way?
- No.
It looks like we're lost.
You're calmer than I expected.
Of course.
Right now, I'm your guardian.
- My guardian?
- Yes.
I might not look the part,
but I'm a doctor.
I hope that subordinate or colleague
of yours went the right way.
I don't think this is right.
We should go back.
- That's what I wanted to say.
- Excuse me, I'll take the lead.
Hey, Servant!
This is my last warning.
Listen carefully.
I'm Habaek, not "Excuse me."
I am the god of water,
to-be king of Water Country
and to-be emperor
of the Realm of the Gods.
Habaek.
Then listen to me.
My name is Yoon So Ah, not "Servant."
And since I'm your guardian,
I'd like you to call me Doctor Yoon
but if you don't like that,
call me Yoon So Ah.
Do you understand?
I see.
- What?
- Run!
Let's get in the car! Oh my!
The trunk!
Why do we have to be quiet?
I think it left.
- How are you?
- I'm very uncomfortable.
Pardon?
Don't move. That's even
more uncomfortable.
Okay.
I think it left, so let's open it.
What's... that?
Oh my!
That pig smiled at me!
That pig must be crazy!
Habaek!
- Can you move?
- I need to sit for a while.
What happened?
I was lost and ran into a hunter.
Good thing he was here.
- What about the hunter?
- He went after the pig.
Are you hurt?
Excuse me, I thought you couldn't drive.
- I couldn't.
- Then, what's this?
I'm good at it now.
This is my first time.
But driving is quite fun.
What?
Then, do you really not have a license--
What is this license that you speak of?
Excuse me! Let me drive!
Rest!
I'm in the middle of gracing you
with a divine blessing.
This is also my generosity
and duty as a god.
Excuse me!
Don't worry too much.
Habaek has abilities that
humans can't even imagine.
I don't care, so stop the car!
Stop the car!
Is this where you live?
- Did you trick me?
- Who tricked whom?
Anyway, thank you for
what you did for me today.
It happened a long time ago.
A god made a promise with your
ancestor, whose name I don't know.
He promised that your family
would forever live as my servants.
It doesn't matter that
you didn't make the promise.
If it's what the gods want,
as the descendant of my servant
you must assist me as promised.
Take me to your residence.
No, the hospital will assist you.
If you refuse,
it'll only get harder for you.
It's hard enough as it is,
so I don't care.
You were right. Happiness
might be what I need the most.
Because I'm exhausted.
So please... just go.
I'm begging you.
After explaining everything to you,
you haven't awakened.
How slow-witted you are.
Then I have no choice.
Nam Soo Ri, I wasn't going to use
this method because of what you said
but I have no choice.
Habaek, but your powers--
Hey, Servant!
I'll grace you with a divine blessing
so you may awaken.
Subtitles by DramaFever
[The Bride of the Water God]
She sneakily pinched my heart
as she entered...
Why did I close my eyes when he did that?
- It feels like a hit on your head.
- No!
- Hey, you dumb woman! Over here!
- He's crazy!
- It was fate.
- You're a god's person now.
- No!
- "God. God. God."
If you don't accept it,
you'll suffer everything.
When he said I'll suffer everything...
- No!
- You'll fall!
Servant!
Please... please save me.
- Are we leaving right away?
- Yes, my portrait was disrupted.
I know. He just need to dot your eyes.
Why are you punishing him?
Punishing him?
When is Habaek coming back?
I wish I had dotted his eyes
before he left!