[ Stops ]
[ Bell Rings ]
[ Radio DJ ] 1 03-5 is
the new KTU in Hollywood.
Hamilton, my main man'll be up.
Johnny, what's up ?
What's up, Hollywood?
It's a beautiful day out,
slick your hair back,
and get some sun.
Yeah,
easy on the mousse.
Yeah, way easy
on the mousse.
Hey, I just got off the phone
with somebody from the Bronx..
This one goes out to the boys
in the neighborhood.
- [ Tires Squeal ]
- Asshole!
A lovely girl
with a crooked smile
Now they gotta split
'cause the Bronx. ain't fit
For a kid
to grow up in
Fuck you!
With no Blacks, no Jews,
and no gays
- [ Horn Honks Impatiently ]
- Ho! Fuck off!
[ Tires Squeal ]
Yeah, but for
the grace of God
There go I
Yi-yi-yi-yi-yi
Pappy and the family
Left their dirty sheets
To find
a quiet place overseas
And year after year
the kid has to hear
The dos and don'ts
and the dids
And when she's
1 0 years old
She thinks
that rock and roll
Are two things
from the home
But for the grace
of God go I
Grace of God
Of God
How's it going?
Good.
It could be me,
it could be you
But for the grace
of God
Hey, Guido!
She turns out to be
a natural freak
Gaining weight
and losing sleep
And when she's sweet 1 6
She packs her things
and leaves
With a man she met
on the street
- She's hot.
- She's all right.
- She'll be good.
- For what?
- In bed.
- In bed?
All girls with no tits
are good in bed.
- What are you, whacking out ?
- No, it's true.
That's retarded.
Who told you that?
Your brother, Pino.
- [ Man ] What's up, Frankie?
- How you doin'?
-Joey Chips, what's going on?
- Gimme a slice.
- Hey, how many?
- A slice.
- No, I don't think so.
- Don't be a faggot. Eat a slice.
No. I'm supposed
to eat dinner now.
I've had your mother's cooking.
Eat a fuckin' slice.
What you gotta get on mothers for?
That shit ain't right.
Forget it.
Just give me one slice.
- I'll have a slice.
- Oh, now you want a slice.
Give my homo friend
a slice.
What you got
to start for?
Enough. Enough.
How many?
2 slices and a soda.
Want a soda?
- Diet soda.
- You gotta be fuckin'crazy.
[ Cash Register Rings ]
I know, but what
are you gonna do?
Hey, Frankie.
Give me a slice to go.
You talking to me?
Are you
talking to me?
- Yeah.
- [ Chuckling ]
Just kidding.
What do you want, a slice?
Uh-huh.
What's so funny?
Do I look like a clown?
You think I'm here
to amuse you?
Joe Pesci, Goodfellas.
Yeah, I don't think
that's funny, you.
Sorry. I'm doing a monologue
for acting class.
You're always practicing something.
Do something already, huh?
A commercial, a movie?
Something.
- Here, take these.
- What's this for?
My parents are staying
in Atlantic City tonight.
I want you to meet me
at my house.
- When?
- Tonight.
Be there when I get off from work.
It'll be like we're married.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
I'm fine. Fine.
I just wanna make sure
you're gonna be there, all right?
All right. All right.
Okay. See you later.
Yeah. I'll see
you tonight.
See you, Angie.
Pino, this thing real?
Hey... what the--
What do you think I am, huh?
It's just that
this thing is big.
Three grand
this thing goes for.
I got it for 600.
Thanks a lot, Pino. Appreciate it.
Want something to eat ?
Naw. I'm gonna go see
what Ma's cooking.
Naw, they went down to A.C.
No one's home.
I could have banged Janice
back at the house.
What happened
with you and Janice?
We broke up last night.
Broke up? I thought you went to
her father's funeral last night.
Yeah, that's
where we broke up.
I figured she was
already crying, right?
So what the fuck.
Ciao.
- Pino?
- What?
I gave Debbie keys to the house.
I told her to meet me there.
- So?
I was hoping
to be alone with her.
So if you had somewhere to go,
that'd be good for me, you know?
Listen. This girl Debbie, okay?
She's got a reputation.
I don't wanna hear it,
all right?
She doesn't belong in this
neighborhood. Either do I.
- It's just a matter of time.
- Frankie, listen.
I don't wanna hear it.
Just one night!
I wanna be alone with her.
I'm broke.
I got no cash.
Here.
How am I supposed
to get laid with 20 bucks?
Capri Motel don't do
one-hour stays no more.
If I find something,
I gotta do the full six.
What about your car?
What are you, a friggin'
wise guy now? Huh?
Yeah. Taking off
early tonight.
- [ Music Plays ]
- Do it.
Oh, my God.
That's it, baby.
Let it go, let it go.
Oh.
- Have you seen Meryl?
- I can't afford to stay there.
I have to find another apartment.
There's too many memories.
When's the last time you had
a man in your apartment?
- Couple of weeks, maybe.
- Try five months.
Okay, I'm in a dry spell.
It's not a dry spell.
It's a drought.
[ Horn Honks ]
[ Gasps ]
Look.
I just think there should be more
to a man than a washboard stomach.
- Like what?
- Date someone with a personality.
- Top or bottom?
- I don't care.
Men with little dicks
cannot be tops.
- Stop watching public access.
- It's true.
Now, me, I'm versatile.
I can be a top or a bottom.
You have bottom stamped
on your forehead.
I know where
my talents are.
- I could definitely be a top.
- With what?
Shh. He's coming!
Shut up.
[ Laughs ]
It's only--
- Oh, shit, is she coming?
- She's coming.
Shit.
Meryl, you look great.
How're you doing?
Cut the bullshit. I wanted
all the rent by last week.
I promise I'll have money
for you by next week.
You said the same
thing last week.
- Why don't you stay with Terry?
- He has a boyfriend.
Another one? It's like
a damn car wash up there.
Warren will bring you
your money tonight.
I promise.
I'm not kidding this time.
He's not kidding,
right?
I'll bring it
to you tonight.
I have a date, so I don't know
what time I'm gonna be home.
You have a date?
Who's the lucky guy?
Some guy from my therapy group.
Divorced, three times.
He's a Virgo, I'm Taurus.
What can you do?
At least he knows
what he's not looking for.
It's learning not to be dependent
on other people for your happiness.
That's what the therapy is for--
for people who give too much.
It's not like C.A.
or A.A.
It's for people who don't need that
in order to have relationships.
- You see, you have to learn--
- Look, Meryl? We gotta go.
Sure. Okay.
I'll see you later.
Okay. Bye.
I don't know what time
I'm gonna be home, though.
You know, maybe his place,
maybe my place?
I don't know.
It's our first date.
Do I look like
I'm retaining water?
Look, Meryl.
We really have to go.
Sure. Okay.
I'll see you later.
Oh, God.
She needs a muzzle.
She needs a vibrator.
So where am I supposed
to get this money?
Honey, your fairy
godmother's here.
You know I will pay you back
every cent, plus interest.
Are you crazy?
I'm not lending you money.
- What were you just saying?
- Sing to me.
[ Rewinding ]
- [ Man ] Hi. How are you?
- What are you doing?
I saw your ad in the paper.
I'd love to come check you out.
I'll give you
a call later. Bye.
Terrence, dear,
what did you do?
- Moi?
- Don't play with me.
I'm not.
I'm helping you.
- "SBF, mother of four--"
- I don't think so.
G WM?
You're gay, you're white,
you're male.
It's not like you have
an option, honey.
I'm not having a complete stranger
live in my apartment.
How do you think I met Todd? Or
Chandler, that Connecticut trash.
You didn't live with them,
you had sex with them.
Look. You need to
meet someone new.
If you don't like him, tell him
you're back with your boyfriend.
It's me, Dakota.
I'm in town.
- What?
- I'll talk to you later.
- [ Rewinding ]
- Oh, God!
I'm in town.
I'll talk to you later.
Okay. What did
he mean by that?
Warren, Dakota is
a 2-timing, ho-chasing bitch.
- I think he wants to get back--
- No!
Give me the tape!
Terry, I want you to--
I've just about had it!
Give me--
So you slept here
last night?
I don't wanna talk
about it.
I just thought you were supposed
to see Debbie, that's all.
I said I don't wanna
talk about it. Read this.
- So?
- So, I'm moving to Manhattan.
You're gonna move
to the city?
Yeah. I gotta get
outta the Bronx.
I'm dying over here.
Al Pacino,
Dog Day Afternoon.
I'm taking up acting full-time,
Joey. No bullshit.
Yeah, you could do movies.
You're good at movies.
I'll do TV, plays,
Broadway, anything.
Start with the small stuff,
work my way up.
- Stallone started like that.
- Somebody that knows the business.
You know, show me the ropes.
Read what it says.
"SBF, mother of four---"
Not that. That's a mother
with four kids.
Hey, you're right. You gotta
be careful with this stuff.
"TV. Seeks any kind,
race, or creed."
Big shit.
The guy's got a TV.
Not that one.
Above that.
" G WM. Little Italy,
seeking same.
"Non-smoker,
actor preferably,
"for share in spacious
fully-furnished apartment.
- Immediate occupancy a must."
- Sounds mint, right ?
Yeah. Little Italy, movies,
all those girls.
That's what
I'm thinking.
What, are you just
gonna call like that?
Joe, people in Manhattan
do this shit all the time.
[ Dialing ]
If only Debbie can see you
now as an actor, huh?
She had two years
to " see me now."
But she wanted to
see everybody else, so... fuck her.
- [ Terry ] Hello?
- Yeah, G WM, please.
- Who?
- You know I'd never do that.
- Do what?
- Fool around with Debbie.
You're calling about the ad.
Who is this?
- It's Frankie Zito.
- Terry, who is it?
You wanna talk
to Warren.
Some of the other guys
in the neighborhood--
Bobby No-Neck,
Jimmy Shoes.
- Never me, Frankie.
- What are you talking about?
Fuck Debbie.
I would never do that.
I know,Joey. It's just
a figure of speech.
- He sounds really cute. Come on.
- No!
- Tony Five-Belts.
- Enough.
- Be nice.
- Hello.
- Hey. How're you doing?
- Are you calling about the ad?
Yeah. You're G WM, right?
Come on!
Johnny's cousin Ralphie.
He did her.
Are you gonna stop?
Warren had to get something
out of the oven. Hold on a second.
- Get over here.
- I don't know!
Just tell him exactly
what you want.
Hi. I'm looking for
someone with money.
- A guy with money?
- Yes, a guy with money.
[ Chuckles ]
That's me, buddy.
[ Scoffs ]
"Buddy."
Come on, please!
- What happened, the oven again?
- How'd you guess?
I got the same
problem here.
- So how did it go ?
- Fine.
- Good.
- Hang up the phone.
- You wanna see the place?
- Yeah. Tell me when.
- Say around 1 :00?
- Hello!
GWM, give me
the address.
91 Mulberry Street,
third floor.
- Got it.
- You got it?
- I'll see you at 1 :00. Bye.
- I'll see you at 1 :00.
- Do you know what G WM means?
- Initials, right?
No. GWM stands for
"guy with money,"
and I got the cash
right here.
I'm gonna go get some stuff
from my mother's.
I want you to get some boxes.
Meet me downtown later, all right?
What happens when Debbie comes
looking for you? What do I say?
-Joey.
- What?
-Joey, did you fuck my wife?
You're giving me answers, but you
ain't giving me the right ones.
What are you
talking about ?
I'm gonna ask you one more time.
Don't lie to me.
Did you fuck my wife?
You gotta be kidding me.
I never touched her.
You don't believe me?
Robert De Niro,
Raging Bull.
Get the fuck outta here.
- What do you mean?
- Is something wrong ?
- No.
- Everything's all right?
Hey, Francis.
Francis, what happened?
What happened?
He is not working.
Something is wrong.
Go talk to him.
[ Speaking Italian ]
- Francis!
- I'm trying to tell you--
- Go get your brother.
- Aw!
- Pino!
- Pino's there?
- Um, I'm gonna come over.
- Go talk to him!
Josephina,
I'm gonna come over.
All right, Debbie.
You come downstairs, honey.
-All right.
- Ex.plain to me and then you eat.
I don't wanna eat.
[ Door Opens ]
I could see if you
knocked her up.
You know, that I understand.
You gotta do the right thing.
Frankie,
she was not for you.
You deserve better.
Hey, I'm sorry, all right?
But she was all over me.
What am I supposed
to do, say no?
I've been there.
Married three months,
three fuckin' months to Suzy.
Look what happened.
She goes back to college,
she starts taking
communications.
- What the fuck is that?
- Then she bangs her professor.
I don't want that
to happen to you.
I'm looking out
for you.
Frank!
- Francis, what happened?
- I don't wanna talk about it.
We had a little bit
of a problem.
I said I don't
wanna talk about it.
You wait right there!
What kind of a problem?
It's been hard,
Josephina.
We've been friends
for so long--
I thought of you as more
than just a friend.
I wanted to show you I was
different, not like everybody else.
But who told you to think that?
We're just friends.
Hey. Hold it!
What did you do to her?
- I didn't do nothing.
- Nothing.
Did you touch
this girl?
- No.
-All right.
Did you two ever--
Never,Josephina.
Never.
Never?
Never!
Oh, Dios Mio!
[ Speaking Italian ]
Bitch,
are you going crazy?
Just doing what you said. I'm
getting rid of all the reminders.
Honey,
it's your first.
Terry, just help me get rid
of some of this stuff, okay?
Did I just change my name
to Hazel?
Shirley Booth
never had your figure.
-Just a minute.
- [ Knock At Door ]
[ Gasps ]
I know him.
Give me that.
What, that ugly?
Terry, I'm here
to make peace.
- Then leave.
- Peace? For what?
Don't be silly.
It's old news.
Oh, I feel sick.
The place looks clean.
I'm impressed.
Yeah, well, I got rid
of most of the dirt.
Don't you have a date
in the sandbox?
No. Your dad couldn't get
away from the office.
So, what are you doing
in New York?
That's what I came
by to tell you.
There's this new thing out.
It's called a telephone.
I left a message. I didn't hear
anything, so I decided to come by.
So... what do you want?
Look, Warren,
I know how you...
feel about me.
But I need you.
Okay, wait, Dakota.
I don't know what
you're thinking here,
but... it's not gonna be
that easy.
- What isn't?
- Taking you back.
No, I'm not asking you
to take me back.
I wanna tell you
about my new play.
It's getting produced. I told
you about my new friend, right?
He's producing it,
and he's acting in it.
I told him if I could convince you,
you would be perfect for the lead.
Why don't you just stay
in the closet where you belong?
Terry, shut up.
Just meet him, okay?
He's waiting down at The Grill.
You know what?
Warren can't be in your play.
He's choreographing a show
for his new boyfriend.
- New boyfriend?
- Yeah.
Well,
it's about time.
[ Frankie ]
Yo! Warren!
You up there?
There he is now.
He's here?
Warren?
Frankie!
- How're you doing ? I--
- I'll explain later.
- There you go. It's off now.
- Pizza sauce, right?
I threw a slice down my throat
before I got here.
Shit sticks to your face
like glue.
Oh, don't worry
about that shit.
I'm Dakota. I'm sure Warren's
told you all about me.
- No, he never mentioned your name.
- Well, my work is done.
I'm sure you both have
some catching up to do.
We were just about to go out for
some coffee. You wanna join us?
Frankie just got in from out
of town. He must be very tired.
Naw, I could use
some bean.
Great, great.
So, how long have--
So many men
How can I lose
So little time
How can I choose
So many men
So little time
How can I lose
- So many men
- I just saw Dakota.
You better get that son of a bitch
to give you money.
I have a new roommate.
Don't worry. You'll get your money.
- I'm coming up for it tonight.
- I thought you had a date.
- He just canceled.
- What happened?
He's getting married.
Men! Gay, straight--
you're all
the fuckin' same.
You think with your dicks,
all of you.
I can do the same thing!
Wham, bam, thank you, Sam.
But I'm too special.
Well, this is
the last time.
This is the last time shit
like this is gonna happen to me.
You're all the fuckin' same!
- Acting is about passion.
- Right.
I mean-- Darling,
we need another chair over here.
How're you doing?
What's wrong?
Warren, Frankie,
this is--
How you doing?
Frankie
is an actor.
I'm sorry.
What was your name again?
So, this must be very
exciting for you.
Well, you must have pain
before art.
I'm tired of all
the existential proclivities...
circumventing
today's theater.
It's boring.
It's been done.
What is the play about?
- It's about the struggle--
- Life!
I want us to be like a woman
giving birth to something alive.
Can you imagine
what that is like?
I mean, the only way men can
think of that is to take a shit.
But it has to be the size
of a baby and alive.
That's what I want to do
with this play.
A piece
of live shit saying,
"Look at this shit,"
to the world.
- Wow.
- It's a love story.
It's about you and me
and all three...
growing from a tree.
That's theater.
Sort of Boys in the Band
for the '90s.
Oh, yeah? Maybe I could be
one of the boys, huh?
- What's the play called?
- Fire in the Hole.
It'd be a great role
for you, Warren.
You'd play a young man
confident in his sexuality,
dealing with the issues--
homophobia, AIDS.
A real tour de force
for the community.
You gonna have a bunch
of faggots in this play?
What's the matter?
Are you all right? Have some water.
What's the matter? Have some water.
Where are we going?
I had no idea you were
such a good actor.
Yeah, there's a lot
you don't know about me.
I'm new in the business
and everything.
Hey, you know people
who do movies, too?
[ Terry ] Take that boy
to your bedroom and--
- Did you see this movie?
- I was in it. Look, Frankie.
- We have a problem.
- You were in Mafia Kickbox.er III?
No fuckin' way.
How did you get in that?
Dakota directed it.
Look, this is not gonna work.
Dakota directed it?
I love that movie.
I saw it like five times.
Who were you?
I was the policewoman's
brother.
That's right! That was you!
You kicked that fat guy's ass.
I love that movie.
That's a great movie.
- You can't live here.
- What are you talking about?
You're straight, Frankie.
Yeah, but sometimes
I get drunk.
No, no, no. I'm talking
about me, my friends?
That guy Dakota
seems cool.
But that other guy--
Is he a whack job, or what?
You're right.
He is a whack job, isn't he?
He's gotta be kidding me
with those $40,000 words.
What is he on, crack?
Look, Frankie. You seem
to be a really nice guy.
Isn't there a girlfriend
you'd rather live with?
Fuck her. That was just
a figure of speech,
like plenty of fish
could swim.
In the sea-- there are plenty
of fish in the sea.
Yeah, whatever.
The point is,
I gotta start making new friends,
meet new people,
like that babe
in the restaurant.
- Wiggy?
- Yeah, Wiggy. You see her tits?
I never saw a skinny girl
with tits like that in my life.
- She's a friend of mine.
- That's what I'm thinking.
Introduce me to your friends,
I'll introduce you to my friends.
Work it out like that.
And you can forget about
your girlfriend just like that.
- Yeah, she's out.
- Out where?
Probably blowing somebody
in the back seat of some car.
- Sounds like my ex.
- Same thing, huh?
We were supposed
to get married.
I come home,
Ifind another man in my bed.
Big shit.
I caught my brother...
on top of the kitchen table
with my girlfriend.
- You did not. With your brother?
- Yeah.
Fast music, bodies pumping--
the whole nine yards.
- You weren't upset?
- Sure I was upset.
But if I don't laugh,
I go crazy, you know?
Wow. That's great
you could do that.
That's what I'm thinking,
you know?
Introduce me to your friends,
I'll introduce you to my friends.
What ?
What is it?
- That guy, your friend Terry.
- Mm-hmm.
You wanna get married
and everything, right?
Yes.
Don't take this personally, but
you're hanging with these guys.
I didn't know
if you were... you know.
What?
Come on.
A gay.
A gay?
I knew. I knew it.
Frankie, so you
thought that I was...
[ Lisping ]
homosexual?
You see?
You do that good.
Well, you know, Frankie,
the truth is,
I'm U.S. Grade " A"
1 00% fuckin' queer.
No!
Yeah?
Get the fuck outta here.
[ Knock At Door ]
You don't got a problem
with that, do you?
[ Knocking ]
Frankie Zito here?
[ Imitating Frankie ]
Come in. We're having a party.
- Hey, Frankie.
-Joe, what are you doing here?
I got your stuff.
Oh, you must be a friend
of Frankie's.
Chips, let's go.
What's your problem?
I just got here.
Me and your friend here,
we may not be living together.
- Why not? Place looks big enough.
- Let's go!
Joe,
I said let's go.
Oh, shit.
Mafia Kickbox.er III.
- You see that?
- [ Karate Cry ]
This is the guy.
Wong Gambino, right?
This guy's a movie star.
You movin' in with a movie star.
- Are you okay? Where we going?
- Yeah.
- Who's a fag?
- What?
What are you talking about?
I didn't call you a fag.
You gonna tell me
what's wrong, or what?
Frankie,
what's going on?
- I had to get outta there.
- What's the problem?
I couldn't stand it.
I couldn't breathe for shit.
- What, did he have a cat?
- A cat?
Yeah. I had an uncle who died
'cause he was allergic to cats.
What'd he do,
eat the fuckin' thing?
My aunt brought home a stray.
Kept it in the basement.
The smell went right
through the floor.
My uncle looked all over
for this cat. Couldn't find it.
Then that was it.
He had an asthma attack and died.
- They said it was the cat.
- Why didn't he check the basement?
Couldn't fit through the door.
Weighed over 400 pounds.
Those fuckin' cats.
Warren had three of those bastards.
- Couldn't breathe.
- Couldn't find them.
Oh, shit, Frank.
Check it out.
- Two queers. Look at this.
- Where?
There. They kissed. You believe
this shit, in broad daylight?
- Look.
- Come on.
Where you going?
Look. Fuck!
So? What do you think?
Top or bottom?
- Neither. He's straight.
- He is so fine.
Please. I'm sure
it's just a phase.
Closest he had to a gay ex.perience
was redecorating his locker.
- Oh, stop.
- Did you see what he was wearing?
- Yeah. He matched.
- I can't live with a Guido.
You can ring my bell
Ring my bell
My bell
You can ring my bell
Ring my bell
My bell
- How're you doing, gorgeous?
- Who are you?
Pino. I'm looking for my brother.
He in here?
- Who's your brother?
- Frankie Zito.
No, there's no
Frankie Zito here.
Oh, hold on, there, tiger.
Let me just ask you a question.
Ask!
Whoa! What's
your rush, Red?
What, you got a date
or something?
I don't date.
You don't date?
That's too bad.
Young, sexy woman
like you?
With a body like that?
Maron.
You should be dating
all the time.
You can ring my bell
Hi, how you doing?
I didn't order any pizza.
- This ain't pizza.
- I'm looking for an apartment.
I'm sorry.
How big?
Uh... one bedroom?
Sweet. How long
you two been together?
What do you think, Frank?
Since kindergarten, right?
Something small.
How much you looking
to spend?
- Couple hundred, maybe.
- $200?
Oh, 3, 400 tops.
Nothing fancy.
Oh,Jesus.
Pellegrino okay?
Yeah, sure.
I figured Pino Zito,
- you gotta be Italian, right?
- Sicilian.
Oh, you're Sicilian.
It's a beautiful island.
Very beautiful.
Hot as hell too.
You Sicilian men--
you're very continental.
Oh, very continental.
Are you Mafia?
I'm continental.
When's your birthday?
May the 1 0th.
- Taurus.
- The bull.
Taurus men--
strong, spontaneous.
Intelligent conversation
stimulates you.
Mmm. Definitely
stimulating.
Taurus: Stubborn, jealous,
hard-headed--
It's getting harder
right now.
A man with a sense of humor.
I like that.
Oh, I'm a man.
Men play games.
I don't.
That's why
I only date women.
Friday night
and it's the weekend
Everybody's speakin'
Let the party people
show you how
Ain't nobody
gonna stop us now
No, no
And we're doing
what we wanna
Everybody's gonna
Gonna party
till the break of dawn
And the DJ's jammin'
all night long
Oh, yeah
Can you feel it in the air
when the music's playing
This is it,Joey.
Manhattan girls,
me and you,
our own place.
We'll be getting laid
all the time.
But I can't move out of my house.
My father would kill me.
But that guy Warren
has a nice apartment.
Only if it wasn't
for those fuckin' cats.
I know. That last apartment
wasn't so bad.
You can take a shower
and cook dinner at the same time.
She only wants
two months' security.
Yeah, but where you
gonna get the money?
They're open tomorrow.
What am I gonna do today?
I'd let you stay at my house,
but my father-- you know how he is.
- He don't like people.
- Yeah, I know.
That was, uh--
Alleviating.
Yeah.
- All right. So I'll call you.
- Fine.
- I'll call you later then.
All right.
Can I ask you something?
- What?
- [ Neck Cracks ]
Think you could
loan me a 20?
- Fuck!
- [ Speaking Italian ]
I've been looking for you.
Where you been?
We just came back from
a pawn shop. It was closed.
A porn shop, for what?
Frankie, I got videos in the car.
Triple X, lesbian,
whatever you want.
Pawn shop! A pawn shop!
Joey, are you coming with me?
Ma's upset.
Come back home with me.
-Joey!
- Frankie, I can't. It's too late.
I gotta go home.
It's getting late.
Why don't you just come with us?
I'll sit in the back.
I'm not going anywhere with
this snake. Are you coming with me?
Forget you.
What about the cats?
How long you been waiting?
Long enough to bang this Jewish
broad in the building here.
These chicks in the city,
they're crazy, huh?
- You hungry?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, you wanna eat?
- All right.
- You got cash?
- Naw.
No cash?
Your stuff is here.
Look, uh...
I wanted to tell you
that I'm sorry...
if I acted stupid
and everything, you know?
I think
you're a cool guy,
and, you know,
I don't know what I was thinking.
I apologize,
I really do,
if I said something that was,
you know, not right.
I have faith in you.
You'll grow out of it.
Grow out of what?
You're bothered
that I'm gay.
Me?
I've hung out with
gay people before.
My friend Joey has a sister
who went to school...
with someone
who was gay.
- It doesn't bother me.
- Progressive.
Yeah, you know,
that's what I'm thinking.
Maybe I could-- Maybe I could
hang around temporarily maybe.
- No, no, no.
-Just for the night.
Frankie, if the fag police
found out...
I had a Guido in my apartment,
they would take away my tutu...
- Guido?
- and ban me from the club.
I'm not a Guido.
- No?
- No.
Let's see. Where are
you from, Brooklyn?
No, the Bronx.
Hmm, the Bronx. How many
gold chains do you own?
- A few. So?
- And who's your favorite actor?
De Niro's the better actor,
but I like Stallone.
- You are such a Guido!
- So, what's wrong with that?
I've hung out
with Guidos before.
My friend Terry has a sister who
works with someone who's a Guido.
- It doesn't bother me.
- [ Knock At Door ]
- Is he here?
- Who?
Pino's brother.
Hi. Ha.
You must be Frankie.
I'm Meryl.
You look just like
your brother.
Same eyes, same mouth...
very healthy.
Look at the feet.
Believe me,
we're not alike.
I know, silly.
So how'd you guys meet?
No, Meryl. Frankie
is not staying here.
I don't understand.
You got the money, right?
He has a few personal problems
he needs to work out first.
You haven't paid
your rent in five months.
If he has the money,
the place is his.
I've lived here
for almost six years.
Yeah, but you only
paid for 5 1 /2!
I can give you the money
for the rent,
as soon as my brother gives me
the money for this ring.
Whose ring is that?
Mine. I was gonna hock it, but I'm
gonna give it back to my brother.
What would your brother want
with an engagement ring?
I don't care,
as long as he gives me back--
As long as he puts it
to good use.
He called here.
He wants to hold on to it.
You talked to Pino?
[ Chuckling ]
You should have heard him!
He said he met someone, that she
is supposed to be unbelievable.
It gave him the chills.
Yeah, and he said that
they were multiplying,
and he's losing control.
He did lose control.
Twice. Ha ha!
- Was it electrifying?
- Mmm!
[ Whispering ] Honey, you have
to tell me all about it later.
Oh. Right.
You, Frankie;
me, Pino.
Not tonight. I understand.
Your first night together.
This must be very
exciting for you.
Okay. Okay!
Nice to meet you,
Frankie. Ha ha!
John Travolta, Grease.
You knew that!
I did that play
in high school, you know.
I love that play.
I got chills
All right, relax!
Frankie, Frankie, Frankie.
This is just
for the night.
[ Girl On TV]
The women look so beautiful.
[ Boy ]
I think they look ugly.
[ Girl ] You just say that
because you're scared of them.
[ Boy ] Silly, only grown-up men
are scared of women.
[ Girl ] I think
the men look beautiful.
[ Boy ]
How would you know?
[ Begins ]
[ Woman ] Nobody.
[ Girl ]
Oh, yes, you are.
[ Boy ]
May I have this dance?
[ Woman ]
I'd be delighted, young man.
[ Continues ]
[ Woman ] Why didn't you children
tell me you could dance?
[ Boy ] We were afraid you'd
make us all dance together.
Do you need anything?
Oh, no. I'm all right.
Thank you.
[ Girl ] What's that
they're playing?
- [ Woman ] An Austrian folk dance.
- [ Boy ] Show me.
[ Woman ] I haven't danced that
since I was a little girl.
[ Boy ] Oh, you remember.
Please?
That's how you're
gonna sleep?
Yeah. I always dress like this
before I go to sleep.
What are you watching?
- Sound of Music.
- Oh.
Who's in that?
Julie Andrews.
Right.
She did that before
Pretty Woman, right?
That's Julia Roberts.
Oh, right.
It's a good movie.
You like Pretty Woman?
Yeah.
It's very realistic,
you know?
I like those kind
of movies.
- [ Phone Rings ]
- Hello.
- What are you doing?
- I'm watching TV.
Look, I'm at The Zone.
Come down for a drink.
I don't know.
Oh, come on. I'm here
with Tino and Robbie.
Really? Hold on.
I'm gonna meet some friends for
a drink. Would you like to come?
Naw. I'm gonna watch
the rest of the movie.
- You sure?
- Yeah, go ahead. Have a good time.
Okay.
[ Dance ]
Good-bye
We drove out there
in a rented car.
It was worth it.
The armoire is stunning.
- And cheap.
- Never marry an accountant.
- Hey!
Hey!
Terry was just telling us
about your new roommate.
- Sounds adorable.
- Where is he?
He's watching The Sound of Music
in my apartment.
Oh!
Forget it.
It's just for the night.
He's gonna go live with
his friend Joey Chips.
-Joey Chips.
- What does he look like?
- Don't start.
- So, what are you gonna do?
Dakota called and is interested
in getting back together.
The guy is a two-timing William
Hurt wannabe. Reminds me of my ex.
- Which one?
- Sebastian.
I'm sorry, but Dakota has hair
and speaks English.
- Meouch.
- What's Tony Manero doing now?
He's waiting for Julie Andrews
to show off her tits.
Is he that straight?
Actually,
he's kind of funny.
You see?
That's a start.
Forget it! I am not
living with a breeder.
- So how was the movie?
- Good. Good.
A little
too much singing.
I'm pretty tired.
Think I'm gonna go to bed.
If you need anything,
I'm right--
[ Bell Rings ]
[ Phone Rings ]
Hello?
- Warren, let's do brunch.
- Dakota.
I just got up.
- Rough night?
- If you weren't such a slut, I'd--
Don't start. I wanna get you
a copy of the script.
I didn't say
I was doing it.
Forget it. Look, just meet me
down at The Grill.
If you want, you can
bring your friend.
- My friend?
- What do you do,
just love them
and leave them?
- I learned from the best.
- What did you say?
- Let him rest. I'll come by myself.
- Take your time.
I'm sitting here with...
you know who.
See you in a bit.
Get dressed.
We're going to brunch.
Naw, I can make
something here, you know?
I said let's go to brunch
because I wanna go to brunch.
The Yankees are playing
the Red Sox in ten minutes.
I don't care if they're playing
the Chippendale dancers.
- I have to meet Dakota. He's with--
- The whack job?
He's the producer
of the show.
I let you stay the night.
You owe me.
I'm gonna feel
uncomfortable.
Look, if you're gonna
be a goddamned actor,
you better start getting used to
talking to a few queers.
Now let's go.
- I'll punch out your lungs.
- Excuse me?
If you don't come with me,
I'm gonna punch out your lungs.
- Like that.
- Does that mean yes?
I'll make you a deal.
First you're Rocky,
now you're Monty Hall.
- Did that sound like Stallone?
- What's the deal?
[ Imitating Brando ] I want you
to go to this Hollywood big shot.
I want you to get Johnny the part.
Make him an offer he can't refuse.
Frankie, I'm serious.
I'm serious, too.
Get me a part in the play.
I don't think this
is your kind of play.
- Forget it.
- I'll try, I'll try.
You can't let Dakota know
you're straight.
He reminds me
of skim milk.
Shut up. We don't
have a choice.
Oh, man, Warren.
You got to hook me up.
- With what? Not now.
- This chick.
We were wondering
where you two were.
Sorry, sorry.
Worked up a sweat.
Had to take another shower.
You know what it's like.
- Of course.
- I'm glad you came to your senses.
I think you're gonna love it,
don't you agree?
Frankie, I've done a bit
of traveling,
and there's a tribe in southern
Malaysia called the Sonoi.
They talk about their performers
with the word gangchi.
That reminds me of you.
I think that you should
look over the role of Buck.
That sounds like an offer
I can't refuse.
- What kind of guy is this Buck?
- You know what.
Frankie's new in the business.
We'll see. We'll read it.
If Warren is as good
an actor as Dakota says,
you know, he can help you.
Show you, make you feel it.
We'll take it home.
[ Giggling ]
- [ Frankie ] Forty bucks!
- This isn't a diamond.
- What are you talking about?
- It's a CZ.
- CZ?
- Cubic zirconium.
No way!
No fuckin' way!
- Do you want the $40?
- Gimme back my ring.
Baby, do you
understand me now
Sometimes I feel
a little mad
But don't you know
that no one alive
Can always be an angel
When things go wrong
I seem to be bad
'Cause I'm just a soul
whose intentions are good
Oh, Lord, please don't let me
be misunderstood
[ Toilet Flushes ]
So how much did you get
for the ring?
Tell me some
of the play first.
I don't think
you're gonna get it.
Don't worry.
I saw Cats.
- Cats?
- Yeah. Did you see it?
Cats.
"When I close my eyes,
I feel your hands on my skin,
" your hot breath
on the back of my neck.
"When you flush me
with your love,
"holding my hard flesh in your
hands, I feel your strength,
" your waves of passion,
your thunderous joy.
Don't say a word.
You know we are perfect together."
I'd probably have to read it
from the beginning, you know?
Mm-hmm.
Hey, what do you say
I stick around a few days?
Help you out with the play?
What do you think?
I think you should be looking
for an apartment.
I have to speak
to my brother first.
Why? What happened
with the ring?
What did you do
Forty dollars!
You gotta get your money back.
I mean, go get it
from your brother.
- Forget it.
- I'll talk to him.
My brother washes out used condoms.
You're not getting money from him.
That's disgusting.
Okay, all right.
Let's get back to this.
Everything in me calls you. You know
exactly how to satisfy my desire.
When I close my eyes,
I feel your hands on my skin--
- Line.
- No, Warren, that's not it.
No, Frankie. When I say line,
you give me the next line.
All right.
When I close my eyes,
I feel your hands on my skin.
My--
- Line?
- Line.
Your hot breath
on the back--
on the back of my neck.
Oh! Line!
- "When you flush me...
- When you flush me...
- " with your love...
- with your love...
"holding my hard flesh
in your hands,
"I feel your strength, your waves
of passion, your thunderous joy.
Don't say a word.
You know we're perfect together."
I don't wanna do
this shit no more.
Okay, okay. Relax.
It's just acting.
I feel your strength, your waves
of passion, your thunderous joy.
Don't say a word.
You know we are perfect together.
Then, I move in,
and then the kiss.
All right.
That's it! No more.
-Acting isn't just memorizing lines.
-This is bugging me out!
Okay. Do you wanna
be an actor? Hmm?
Let's go.
I've lost you once,
but I'm ready--
I wanna come
and check you out.
- It's a small part. It's nothing.
- I don't care.
Forget it.
You're not coming.
What, are you too
good for me now?
What's up with you?
I'm sorry.
It's this part I got
in this play, you know?
It's not me,Joe.
- Like Travolta.
- Travolta?
John Travolta,
Pulp Fiction.
Remember, he's dancing with
that skinny chick in the diner.
He's doing that
bad dance bullshit.
People seen
Saturday Night Fever.
They know he's a better dancer
than that. He's just acting.
He's a good fuckin' dancer.
Stronger.
Stronger than the rays
of the sun.
Stronger than any earthquake
could move the earth.
I love you...
forever.
- That was-- That--
- See?
That was great.
Fuckin' gay guys.
- What are these guys looking at?
- Let it go.
- What, are they gonna kiss now?
- You talkin'to me?
- They're fuckin' making me sick.
- Yeah, you.
- Hey, faggot.
- You got a fuckin' problem?
- Fuck you, faggot!
- Yeah, what?
Come on, dick head.
Come on, motherfucker.
- What happened?
- My ankle.
- Why'd you do that?
- Do you always gotta start?
- You all right?
- Ow!
Hold on to me.
Pain killers
kick in yet?
I feel like
I'm on Pluto.
- That's a bad feeling, right?
- [ Knock At Door ]
- Who is it?
- Dakota.
- Nobody's home.
- Don't start.
You okay?
Where is he?
Okay, what happened?
What happened?
He's not feeling well.
I can see that. But I have a show
to put on that's sold out.
Maybe it's for the best. Give you
some time to work on that dialogue.
- It doesn't need any work.
- What's the matter with the play?
Nothing. It--
Dakota, I can't stand.
Get him a chair.
Anything for the movie star.
You know... you remind me
of an infection that I once had.
- Why do you exist?
- Eat me.
- I'd rather have a McMuffin.
- Who threw up on your shirt?
That's enough!
What are we gonna do
about my play?
Don't beg him.
If he cannot do it, that's fine.
We'll cancel the show.
No, we are not gonna
cancel anything!
Do not talk to me in front
of these people like that.
That's not nice.
Where are you going?
We need to talk...
alone.
You don't mind,
do you, Frankie?
Of course he minds.
- Yeah, of course I mind.
- Uh, I don't mind.
Then, I guess
it'll be all right.
Help me up.
- What's the matter?
- Lift me.
Are you okay?
- I'll be fine.
- Are you sure?
Okay.
Come on, Frankie.
So, where do
you wanna go?
I don't care.
Where do you wanna go?
You wanna go to the Anvil
and pick up a leather daddy?
No, let's go eat first.
I'm starving.
Okay.
I need you
on this, Warren.
It's a good play.
It's the type of play we always
talked about doing together.
How long have you
known about this show?
Why didn't you
come to me first?
I wanted to. But then we had
the fight and my hands were tied.
Do you love him,
Dakota?
His family is loaded. They're
putting up the money for the play.
But do I love him?
Give me a bottle of vermouth
and a case of vodka,
and I am madly
in love.
I miss you, Warren.
The play was an excuse
to see you, to tell you that.
I want to come back.
I don't know
if I could do it.
We open tomorrow!
I'm talking
about taking you back.
Oh. I thought, uh--
And besides, I told you,
it just hurts too much.
You're in love with him,
aren't you?
- Who?
- Frankie.
I'm talking about my ankle.
Oh, Dakota, please!
Okay. You know what?
I cannot do your play, okay?
And Frankie is not--
Frankie is not my first choice
to do Fire in the Hole.
- But I think he could do it.
- Frankie?
He knows all the lines.
He's been practicing with me.
He's not the queerest boy
in the world, Warren.
He's a little butch,
that's all.
You really think
he can do it?
I really think he can do it.
I could help him.
And then, maybe,
we could talk about us.
Yeah.
[ "Born To Be Alive" ]
Thank you, Miss Ross.
Remember,
be strong.
No, no, no.
You're like this, okay?
Get out of my way, man.
You really need to be
more like-- like me.
Like this. Like--
Where are you,
my precious man?
Terry.
You're at a parade.
You're looking over a sea of
people for the man that you love--
the woman
that you love.
- This isn't gonna work.
- Concentrate, okay?
You can do this.
Yes, you were born
Born, born to be alive
Born to be alive
Yes, you were born
Born
He's right.
This isn't gonna work.
- Relax.
- I am relaxed.
- Then be tense.
- I'll tell you what we're gonna do.
We're gonna take it
from the end of the play.
We'll start with...
" when you flush me
with your love."
We're all taking
a big breath.
When you flush me
with your love,
holding my hard
flesh in your hands,
I feel your strength,
the waves of passion,
the thunderous joy.
Don't say a word.
You know we're perfect together.
The kiss.
What about the kiss?
No big thrill for me
either, honey.
Frankie, you have
to do the kiss.
I'm not doin'
no fuckin' kiss.
You gotta do the kiss.
Al Pacino, Dog Day Afternoon.
- Did you see that movie?
- I'm dying here. I saw the movie.
- What about Cruising?
- He kissed a man in that movie.
- Did not.
- Tongue.
Now, come on.
Are you Al Pacino...
or Tony Danza?
[ Knock At Door ]
I'm sorry.
Am I disturbing something?
- Actually, we were just--
- Uh, you shut up!
Where's your brother?
What's he doing with that ring?
- Meryl--
- Son of a bitch.
He comes on like a freakin' dog
in heat. Now he's busy.
- Ha! Busy doin' who?
- Meryl.
I swear to you, if I see him,
I am gonna take his nuts...
and wrap them
around a pole.
Meryl, you have him
all wrong.
He hasn't called you
because, uh--
I can't tell you.
- What are you doing?
- I'm not asking you to cough.
- I just wanna know what's going on?
- Calm down!
- I'm calm.
- Could you let go of Frankie ?
I thought you'd be happy
about this, not upset.
Happy about what?
Frankie told me.
You... Pino...
getting engaged.
I think that's great.
Getting what?
You didn't tell her?
No.
Pino comes over here.
He's asking all sorts of questions.
The man is in love.
We just met.
He's nuts for you.
He said that
you were smart,
sweet, sexy, uh--
- Thin.
He's crazy like that.
Meryl... when he wants something,
- he grabs it, you know?
- Yeah.
That's the Taurus.
See, I'm a Taurus,
and we're like that.
Look, he wanted you
to have this.
[ Warren ] He wants to
make things perfect.
He doesn't have a lot of money,
so he's nervous.
How much does he need?
Give him time.
He will call you.
I think you're both
full of shit.
But this is
a beautiful ring.
And it just happens
to be my birthstone.
- I can tell him to call you.
- No!
He knows where I am.
Let him call me on his own.
That son of a bitch.
[ "Born To Be Alive" ]
[ Door Slams ]
You're Catholic,
right?
Yeah. So?
Don't worry.
It'll work.
I hope so.
- Hello.
- Hey, Pino.
Oh, Frankie boy!
I'm so glad you called.
- Listen, you're my blood.
- Pino!
- What, what? Talk to me.
- It's Meryl.
- Who's Meryl?
- The woman downtown?
Did you bang her?
You banged her, right?
Son of a bitch. Ma's been
thinking you were a finocchio.
I told her you ain't
no finocchio.
She's pregnant.
Frankie...
you gotta wear rubbers.
Especially with all this shit
floatin' around. Forget about it.
- I never touched her.
- So what are you worried about?
She says it was you.
Me? Hey, I was
only with her once.
Well, twice.
Cazzo.
What happened?
The second time,
the thing fuckin' broke.
- What's she gonna do?
- No, what are you gonna do?
She says
it's your baby.
Me? What am I
supposed to do?
I don't know, Pino.
Call her.
Talk to her.
But go easy.
She's thinking about not having it.
Not having it?
Disgraziato!
Don't she know I'm Catholic?
Ma's gonna kill me!
Do me a favor.
Get out of the car for a minute.
You think I could
borrow your phone?
You're an angel.
[ Ringing ]
- Hello.
- Yeah, Meryl. It's me, Pino.
- I just talked to my brother.
- He told you.
- Yeah, he told me.
- He told me he wasn't gonna tell.
Well, he told me.
So, uh... this is
pretty exciting, huh?
I gotta be honest with you, Meryl.
I don't know what to do.
What do you mean
you don't know what to do?
- I thought you were doing it.
- Doing what?
- Making plans.
- I wasn't making anything.
- What have you been doing?
- I don't know. Nothin'!
Nothing?
- What am I supposed to do?
- Terrific.
You don't have to do anything.
You got what you wanted.
I got what I wanted.
I'll get rid of it.
- You're gonna get rid of it?
- What do you want me to say?
I love it?
I want to keep it?
- You wanted me to have it.
- I do, you know, but--
Forget it!
If you don't want it, I'll sell it.
- I don't want it anymore.
- You're gonna sell it!
- [ Horns Honking ]
- [ Cursing In Italian ]
I can't believe
you're saying this.
If I can't sell it,
I'll give it to your brother.
What the hell's my brother
gonna do with it?
I don't know, throw it in
the garbage. I don't give a shit!
Madonna mi! Listen to me.
Don't move, you hear?
- I'm coming down to see you.
- Now?
- Yeah, now!
- I'm going to your brother's play.
My brother is
in a play?
[ Vomiting ]
Do you like my costume?
Could someone get me
a cold towel?
- Puke is not art.
- Is he gonna make it?
- Get me a cold towel.
-John, we need a cold towel!
What did you call me?
What did you just call me?
- I'm sorry.
- Yeah, I know you're sorry.
- We have an emergency.
- But I have a name!
Maybe that's John. But that's
not me. That's not my name!
- That's my name.
- Curtain in five!
My name is not John!
That's my name.
Forty-five minutes going
around the block.
Ma! It's supposed
to be off Broadway.
- This is nowhere near Broadway.
- Cocuzza!
Ma!
I don't like your car anyway.
It spoils my hair.
I don't believe this.
- Ah. Where is the stage?
- Your tickets, please.
Oh, I'm the mother
of the star of this play.
I'm afraid you're still
going to need tickets.
You...
little son of a bitch.
You did not go to Catholic school!
The nuns would have--
Hey, Frankie,
what's going on, buddy?
What are you
doing here,Joey?
I came to wish you luck.
Good luck.
You're supposed to say
"break a leg."
Break a leg, then. Guess who's
down here from the neighborhood?
- I don't have time for this.
- Vinny the Fish.
Vinny the Fish?
What the fuck is he doing here?
- I don't know.
- Who else?
Tony Five-Belts,
his cousin Johnny.
I can see the memories in my head
like an endless tape.
It was my heart I wanted to
give to you, you wouldn't take.
You are like a petal on a little
flower growing inside of me.
Touch me...
on my forehead right now.
Mother, Father,
I am a boy,
I am not a toy.
Hey, where do
I pick up the tickets?
You here
with Josephina Zito?
Yeah.
She's my mother.
She said that
you were paying for the tickets.
- Me?
- You're Pino? You owe me $88.
$88? $88? Are you
out of your fuckin' mind?
Your mother just came up in here
with three different people--
Watch what you say
about my mother, first of all.
Second of all, $88.00 for what?
You got no parking.
- Your mother called.
- What did she say?
Nothing.
Well, she never
has anything to say.
She does not
like me, does she?
- It's okay. I can accept that.
- [ Stomach Rumbling ]
But tell me, she does
not like me, does she?
No, she doesn't
like you!
I am so sick of this
whole society, who is angry.
And everyone is angry
at their own sexuality.
I am an artist.
Shut up.
I feel that our life
is going in circles.
We are in this apartment
on the east side.
We are stuck.
We are clowns!
We are toys for the society!
They are producers, directors!
But we are actors!
A strange calmness
is coming over me.
I can't sit. I cannot stand.
I must stay in the middle.
I must stay
right in the middle.
I'm a cocoon.
Please take me. Please take me.
Please take me.
Spank me harder.
Please, please. Please.
Please, please.
Please.
- I've grown up. I'm ready.
- [ Stomach Growling ]
What about Elizabeth?
What about the children?
Ha ha ha ha!
I don't care about Elizabeth,
and I don't care
about the children.
I care about you and I
right now.
Right now.
- I love you.
- I don't believe you.
Don't touch.
Don't touch me!
No!
[ Audience Clapping ]
Hey, Pop.
They're so damn
affectionate!
Where the hell have you been?
I've been waiting for you.
I-I had to come out
for some air.
- How-- How are you feeling?
- Like shit.
Why, you getting
sick already?
Listen. Pino,
we're kidding ourselves.
We don't have
a relationship.
We just met. I don't want
to force anything.
Who's forcing?
I'm not forcing anything.
Just take it.
You're givin' this
to me?
I don't want it anymore.
It doesn't mean anything to me.
Didn't you hear
what they said in there?
- I heard.
- I don't need a ring.
I don't need a man.
All I need is love.
I can't believe
you just said that.
What?
[ Speaking Italian ]
My mother says that
all the time.
She must
be some woman.
She's a saint.
Dakota.
Why aren't you
in costume?
I've lost
the motivation.
You better find the motivation.
It's the next fucking scene!
You're the writer.
Go cut and paste.
Don't do this.
Get-- Get back here!
Get back!
- Warren, you have to go on.
- I can't do it.
- It's the last scene.
- I cannot do it with my foot.
I've lost you once.
But I'm ready
to fight for your love,
and I'll fight
until the end.
When I close my eyes,
I feel your hands
on my skin,
your hot breath
on the back of my neck,
everything in me
calls you.
You know exactly
how to satisfy my desire.
When you flush me
with your love,
holding my hard flesh
in your hands,
I feel your strength,
your waves of passion,
your thunderous joy.
Don't say a word.
You know we're
perfect together.
[ Whispering ]
Kiss me, Guido.
[ Crashing ]
[ Farting ]
Thank you.
Ah.
Frankie,
you were great!
- I just wanted to tell you.
- Wiggy?
You were really,
really, really, really--
My uncle has a restaurant
down in the city,
and, uh, if I go
work there,
wait some tables,
in a couple of years,
- I could become head waiter.
- Head waiter?
I bet you'd give
great service.
The problem
with theater today...
is that there are
too many straight men.
I mean, the theater is about,
life, art, community,
not heterosexuals.
Your father told me not
to put plants in your room.
- Ma.
- You were too young.
There's some beautiful
broads here, huh?
Madonna!
Check out that one.
- She's a lesbian.
- Get the fuck outta here.
- You calling me a liar?
- Absolutely not.
Pop,
this is Warren.
- Nice to meet you, Mr. Zito.
- Yeah, I know you!
I just saw you
on video, right?
You were in
Mafia Kickbox.er III!
That's what it is!
I see you standing over here.
I said, "I know this guy!"
- Get the fuck out.
- Did I miss something?
You a lesbian?
No, I'm sorry. You like girls.
That's cool. Me too. Eh.
You have no desire
to do it with a guy?
- Do you?
- That's disgusting.
Exactly.
Yeah, closer is good.
Hey, Francis,
come take a picture!
You don't mind, do you?
Over here.
Mama's gonna love this.
Thank you.
So why do they
call you Joey Chips?
There's two moles
on the back of my ass.
They look like
chocolate chips.
Sometime,
I could show you.
Meryl, there's a lot of women up
there, but they're not like you.
- I gotta " aks" you something.
- Yes?
- Oh!
- Would you--
- Yes?
Would you...
convert for me?
Yes! Yes!
Oh, yes!
My good-bye song.
Good-bye!
It's finished, it's boring
and it's been done.
- Brrradada.
- I love it when you're feisty.
I was talking about us,
you and I. Bye-bye!
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
You're not going with him?
Ha ha ha.
You got a problem
with that?
I didn't think so.
Listen to me. If you wanna
come home, you come home.
You hear me?
Yeah.
Thanks, Pop.
Here.
Take this.
Don't tell your brother.
I think it's time
to talk about us.
- That's what you're thinking, huh?
- What's wrong?
I just saw you, Dakota.
I'm surprised you didn't
fall down the fucking stairs.
What is your problem? I told you
I'm moving back in with you.
- What about Frankie?
He can still do my play.
Good actor.
Better than I thought.
But he's not
the queer, Warren.
You are.
Fuck you, Dakota.
You're even starting
to sound like him now.
Don't tell me.
You're straight now too, right?
Fuck you!
You all right?
You should have seen his face
when he had to kiss me.
- He was gonna have a heart attack.
- You are such an asshole.
Nah, he just thinks
he's better than everybody else.
You don't bother me. Guys in my
neighborhood are just like you.
Maybe you should go back
and find them.
- Maybe he doesn't have to!
- Hey! Hey!
[ Needle Scratches Record,
Music Stops ]
[ Dakota ]
Get the fuck away from me.
Are you all right?
Is that who
I think it was?
Yeah, it's Wong Gambino. I saw
you do it in Mafia Kickbox.er III.
Okay. Rule number one:
No movies with "kickboxer" in the
title come into that apartment.
All right.
No Julie Andrews.
Fine.
"You know, Louie,
this could be the beginning...
of a beautiful
friendship."
-James Cagney?
- Oh, come on.James Cagney?
Maybe it was my impersonation.
You know who Liza Minnelli is?
Have you ever seen
New York, New York?
Telling me how girls in the Bronx,
they don't know how to serve a man.
I'm like, yeah,
sure you're right.
Then she starts unzipping my pants.
I'm going fuckin' nuts now.
I can't believe
this is happenin'.
Girls in the city
are whacked.
She went right down on me right
there like a fuckin' vacuum cleaner.
Yeah, but did
you fuck her?
I was drunk.
I passed out.
- See?
- We gotta go to the city, man.
I'm not drivin'
my car to the city.
Not even
for a blow job?
- What she look like,Joey?
- Like Marilyn Monroe.
Marilyn fuckin' Monroe.
Bobby, we gotta go to the city.
[ Phone Rings ]
Anthony's Pizza.
Hey, Frankie.
I was just telling
the guys about the party.
Tell him we're coming down
to the city.
These guys, they wanna come down to
the city, meet some of your friends.
Remember that
blonde-headed chick?
Yeah.
I never got her number.
You think you could
get her number for me?
I think I'm in love.
I am what I am
And what I am
needs no ex.cuses
I deal my own deck
Sometimes the ace
sometimes the deuces
It's one life and there's
no return and no deposit
One life, so it's time
to open up your closet
Life's not worth a damn
Till you can shout out
I am what I am
Ooh, I am
Throw your hands in the air
air, air, air
air, air, air, air
Throw your hands in the air
Everybody rise
Gonna put your hands
together tonight
Keep on
getting loose y'all
Let the drum
give you the news
I'm talking about bodies movin',
nonstop groovin'
Asses shakin'
Doors are breakin'
Queens are freakin'
Walls are creakin'
Fever's growin'
Everybody looks the same
Throw your hands
to the sky
Stand up, move on
- You got to stand up
- Throw your hands to the sky
Stand up, move on
You've got to stand up
Stand up
put your hands up high
High high high
Up high
Stand up
put your hands up high
High high high
high high high
There ain't no confusion
Confusion is what's
in the mind
There ain't no illusion
It's just taking
a little more time to find
'Cause my passion's
so strong
Strong enough
to take control
It's right here
where I belong
And it's burning
deep inside my soul
I'm gonna shout
for the whole world to see
- All about
- The love that's inside of me
- There's no doubt
- I'm ready to share it all
I'm gonna shout
There's no doubt, say it loud
Strong and proud
Gonna shout
- This love doesn't have to hide
- It's all about
- My passion is having pride
- There's no doubt
- I've finally found myself
- I'm gonna shout
- No doubt scream and shout
- About my
Life
Yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah
- Ooh
- I'm gonna shout
- For the whole world to see
- All about
The love
that's inside of me
- There's no doubt
- I'm ready to share it all
- I'm gonna shout
- There's no doubt, say it loud
Strong and proud
gonna shout
This love
doesn't have to hide
- It's all about
- My passion is having pride
- There's no doubt
- I finally found myself
- I'm gonna shout
- There's no doubt, say it loud
Strong and proud
gonna shout
Shout, shout,
shout, shout