Www.KoreanDramaX.com
Then I guess you won't care.
Gol Sa will die by my hand.
You must have heard the rumors about
the end of Seosumun's Six Ghost.
[Episode 13]
It was me who crushed Six Ghost.
Baek Dae Gil.
It was you.
You wore Scholar Baek Myun's mask.
And you broke down the gambling rooms
in the eight cities?
Why? Does that change your mind?
No, you're wasting your time.
No matter how hard you try,
you will never get to him.
Yi In Jwa is--
I know Yi In Jwa better than you do.
I've already fought him many times
and lost many times.
Then why do it again?
Because I have to face him.
If it is not me, nothing will change.
I know how you feel in wanting
to save your father.
But you won't be able to do that by
sitting there like that.
Just know this.
If you don't make a move,
nothing will change.
Nothing...
Oh, this is nice.
I had a good time.
Seol Im.
Baek Ho Dae Sal...
Of all the horoscopes,
it is the most atrocious one.
You have only two choices.
One is to leave here
and live your life out alone.
This is the easiest method since your
bad omen will not reach any others.
The other method is to
kill the person you love.
What is it? Did something happen?
No, not at all.
That child of his was a girl.
What?
It was a girl.
Gol Sa's child...
Oh.
Are you feeling unsure now that
you've met with Baek Dae Gil?
That is understandable.
Should I tell you a fun story?
The horoscope Baek Dae Gil was born with
has the calling of a monarch.
You have knowledge of horoscopes.
You must have no problem understanding
the meaning of my words.
What happened?
I tried to persuade her
but I cannot guarantee anything.
She became a hostage on her own
to protect her father.
I can understand
her devotion to her father--
No.
She was never a part of my plan
to get to Gol Sa.
I will go after Gol Sa, regardless.
We will get Gol Sa tomorrow.
He is quite powerful. It won't be easy.
That's true. Will you be okay?
It won't difficult with your help.
Me?
You said you wanted
something out of this.
I needed the accounting books because of
the license ban on the small merchants.
What? Did you think
you'd get it for free?
Well, how can I help?
Get the Office of the Inspector General
to take care of the troops under Gol Sa.
Then I can play a round with Gol Sa.
That... will be a problem.
After we got rid of Six Ghost,
I was removed from office.
As for position and rank...
my name has been removed.
But I have other methods.
Do you have confidence?
Tomorrow, 3 to 5 p.m. Don't be late.
I'll be going, then.
I will get going too.
Cutter will be waiting for me.
You'll come back, right?
Don't get hurt.
Tomorrow, 3 to 5 p.m.?
[Cutter]
Thank you for helping me
and keeping me safe all this time.
Will you be leaving?
It is very late now. Leave tomorrow.
Please help me!
If you help me, my life will be--
Your life!
Do not give it up so easily.
It is not worth so little.
Baek Dae Gil...
Baek Dae Gil met that girl.
South Goblin did come by
the gambling room today.
I did think it was a little odd.
He was probably looking for
Gol Sa's child.
So...
I got involved to make sure that
it would not impact you negatively.
She is a smart child,
so she will not be rash.
Moo Myung, you watch over her.
Yes, my lord.
What are you writing?
I will come for Gol Sa today
between 3 to 5 p.m., so wait for me...
Baek Dae Gil.
Once I have finished writing this,
put it up all over Hanyang.
Bukcheon, markets, streets,
Jongno, and Mapo too.
- Wow, What a bad guy!
- Baek Dae Gil?
[Choi Yi Seok]
He must be awful!
Isn't Gol Sa the gambler in Mapo?
He's not just a gambler.
He controls the waterways in Mapo.
He is also a craftsman for
Yi In Jwa and the other merchants.
If he is taken down,
it will be a blow to our Soron faction.
Bring in Yi In Jwa right now.
Oh my...
Here he is now.
My lord!
[Kim Chang Jib]
Your Highness, did you know what
this Baek Dae Gil was up to?
Regardless of what Baek Dae Gil does...
I am going after Yi In Jwa myself.
Yi In Jwa!
What about abolishing the license ban
on the small merchants?
Was that to get Yi In Jwa, as well?
Yes.
To stop Yi In Jwa, we must stop the
corruption with the large merchants.
And in order to do that,
I need that accounting book.
That accounting book is in
Gol Sa's hands at this moment.
You want to get that accounting book,
abolish the license ban
and cut off Yi In Jwa's money?
By any chance...
Even if you catch one gambler
do you think a rat like Yi In Jwa
would even blink?
No.
Gol Sa is not someone
you should overlook like that.
Is Mapo not the most prosperous place
in all of Joseon?
The master is passing by!
It is Gol Sa who controls all of the
rights of commerce to Mapo.
Products in Mapo cannot be shipped on a
boat without Gol Sa's permission.
However...
officials who should be controlling him
are too friendly with him.
So, we can do nothing but stand idly by.
Because of that...
I need you to help me.
I will get the help of
Hansung Regional Office.
However, I have a condition.
If I get aid from them,
give the accounting books to me.
I want you to step away from this,
Your Highness.
Leave the rest of the work to me.
It seems he has a
deep relationship with Yeoning.
Who is this Baek Dae Gil?
He is the pupil of former
military trainer Kim Chae Gun.
Do you all remember the assassination
plot the king set up two years ago?
That night the king gave him a sword.
But why is he going around
attacking the gambling rooms?
Also, why is Yeoning with him?
It is a long story so I cannot
tell you everything, but do not worry.
It is all in the palm of my hand.
[Choi Sukbin]
It is Baek Dae Gil.
It seems the two of them are gnashing
their teeth to get at Yi In Jwa.
It looks very dangerous to me.
I am asking you if it
seems all right to you.
What are you trying to say, Your Majesty?
The two of them do not even know
that they are brothers.
What will you do if something goes awry
and they draw swords at each other?
Untie the knot.
If you cannot untie it, cut it off.
This history came to be because you are
the mother of both these boys.
Your Highness! Your Highness!
[Hansung Regional Office]
I will get the help of
Hansung Regional Office.
How many personnel do you have here?
[Mapo]
Hey!
What time is it now?
I have an important appointment today.
- Get him!
- Arrest them all!
- Yes, sir!
What's the Hansung Regional Office
doing here?
Your Highness.
Are you not ashamed as an official
who gets paid by the nation?
Arrest these men.
Go to the shipping department
and seize all documents!
Yes, sir!
I've set up the game for you.
The rest is up to you.
Enter!
You're right on time.
I feel like a king
being welcomed like this.
What? This is nothing.
Hey, now. Why are you
treating a guest this way?
Dominoes.
Newly minted ones from the start?
I'm getting a taste.
I know you have some skills.
You know the rules, right?
I do know, but...
I'll letting you off
because it's the first game.
This side was made with iron.
This side was made with ivory.
The cost is double
and it feels different too.
You noticed it, did you?
This gambling room is interesting.
Three empress tree wood
and one oak tree wood.
And...
one that only comes out "yut."
A card with a wire in it.
What is this?
This entire place is rigged.
Well, should I reveal more?
That's enough now.
I've seen enough of your skills now.
Play for real.
Check it.
The weight is right,
the texture is right
and there are no marks on them.
They're good.
Then, let's play for real.
Why did you hang up those posters?
I did become famous thanks to you,
so it was nice.
Didn't you do that to catch me?
Why would I?
Are you playing innocent now?
So, it wasn't you
who put up those posters?
Let's go over the rules.
A pair of tens is the best hand.
And no tricks or
rigging cards allowed, of course.
There is one unique rule we have
in the Mapo gambling room.
Stealing a card.
Stealing a card?
Before players reveal their cards
they can switch one card
with their opponent.
You can switch cards with each other?
Best out of three rounds!
Deal the cards.
I won't switch.
I will...
I have a bad feeling about yours.
I'll just go with what I have too.
Then, let's show our cards.
What are you doing? Show your cards.
I lose. Deal the cards.
You'll lose that round to me. Is that it?
If it's best out of three rounds,
I only need to win one more.
Don't act so tough.
You don't know how life ends up
until the bell rings.
You don't know how a game will end
until you leave the table.
That's how Six Ghost acted
before he ended up in a fiery hell.
I'll deal this time.
Are you going to show me your skills now?
Switch well this time.
This one here smells like a 10.
You'll have to see it to know
if it's a 10 or crap.
It's your turn.
I'm fine. Let's show our cards.
Then, mine first.
This is the one I got from you.
I have a pair of twos!
What are you doing? Show yours.
He's not being shaken.
You have a zero.
I had a two and a seven.
Gol Sa had a two and a three.
How did he know?
This is the last game.
Have you ever lost playing cards before?
I've played for 30 years.
There was that one time.
To Cutter...
Then today is your second time.
Good thing I'm not late.
What brings you here again,
Scholar Baek Myun?
I wanted to give you strength,
so I brought you a gift.
Yeon Hwa!
Father.
What are you up to now?
I have to do this so that your
true abilities will come out.
What's your reason?
What's your reason for posting
my name all over town?
I'm sure you received some
hospitality thanks to me.
The game is just starting to get serious.
Go on and deal the cards.
I will deal the cards.
How can we be sure that Baek Dae Gil
will not use tricks?
What are you up to?
It makes sense that
she wants her father to win.
Go ahead.
Father.
10.
Five.
How did you know?
I don't think it's a trick.
It's the sound.
Every card has a different sound.
Sound? Is this game rigged?
Three.
Two.
Three. A pair of threes.
Seven.
Cards totaling nine.
Father has two threes.
That's a pair of threes.
Baek Dae Gil has a seven and two.
That totals nine.
If he chooses not to switch,
Father will win.
I don't want to switch.
You can switch if you want.
All right.
That's the seven.
Father has a pair of threes.
If they switch cards,
Baek Dae Gil will win.
Actually, I don't think I should.
Father has... won.
What are you doing?
Don't regret it. Why not switch it?
This is a game of fate,
so let's just do it.
All right.
Show your cards.
A seven and two.
That totals nine.
Then, mine...
Wait.
I want to make sure that you're betting
this gambling room on this round.
If I lose...
I will give you this gambling room.
If you lose...
I will get all the gambling rooms
you've taken from Scholar Baek Myun.
What is it?
Are you relieved that
you didn't bet your life?
Not my life, but let's say the loser
grants the winner one wish.
How's that?
If it's a wish that can be granted.
Show your cards, then.
What... how?
There's no way.
Why not? The sound trick?
That's such a old trick
and you're still using it?
I put a scratch on the card
and changed the sound.
Even so...
How could you do that in
such a short amount of time?
You have to be at this level
to be called a card shark.
Gol Sa...
You will need to
take responsibility for this.
No, you can't!
You still have that bad habit
of backstabbing people.
Your sword has become very fierce.
Put away your swords.
It is not over yet.
This is a note for 1,000 nyang.
Baek Dae Gil.
I will offer 1,000 nyang for his life.
What are you doing, Yi In Jwa?
2,000 nyang!
2,000 nyang?
This is the kind of money
you will never touch in your lifetime.
This is still not enough for you?
Then...
I will add 3,000 nyang more.
That's 5,000 nyang!
- 5,000 nyang?
- 5,000...
That is enough money for three
generations to live off of.
Stop!
Who are you?
Move.
Listen up.
[Baek Joong Ki (Union Member)]
Baek Dae Gil saved us.
He's the one who saved us from Six Ghost.
What we need isn't this 5,000 nyang.
Don't you see it's people like this
who think of our lives?
That's enough!
Put away the weapons!
Do you think this is the street?
How dare you come to my game
and play around with money?
Then, are you saying you're going
to end the game like this?
A win is a win.
A man should accept his losses.
Do you dare to lecture me?
Go on and bring out the accounting book.
Father!
From the looks of things,
there's no place for you here.
I'm sure you didn't expect
that I could get Gol Sa.
I am surprised.
Honestly, I didn't come here
for your game with Gol Sa.
I came here for another reason.
It is exciting.
That's right.
Whatever you see, hear, and experience,
make it entirely yours.
Baek Dae Gil, you will come to
a fork in the road soon.
Just remember this.
There is no eternal enemy or ally
in this world.
If you have many allies,
you will have that many enemies, as well.
And you, Gol Sa...
For being unable to protect
your gambling room...
you will pay a severe price.
Let's go.
Is this it?
Your Highness.
If this accounting book is revealed
both the Soron and Noron factions
will be up in arms.
Can you handle that?
Do you think I am standing here now
without preparing for that?
Prepare everything.
All of the rights of commerce of Mapo
and the gambling room.
I will take over tomorrow morning.
All right.
Also... you said you'd grant a wish.
Grandpa!
Gol Sa!
Gol Sa.
South Goblin...
Old man...
You know what happens
if you play tricks, don't you?
I do like your eyeball.
Sir...
It was a mistake from younger,
immature days.
Forgive me.
They say if a body is worth 1,000 nyang,
the eyes alone are worth 900 nyang.
I've been living with one left eye
worth 450 nyang!
I just want to rip you apart!
But what can I do?
That's enough.
So, stand up.
I'm Baek Joong Ki of the
Hanyang small merchants.
I'm a merchant in Mapo,
Moon Young In.
I'm Yi Woon Chang from the Sanha markets.
Oh my.
I'm Shin Yong Gol,
head merchant from Anyang.
I'm Bong Ki Chil.
I'm Seo Yang Hoon from Busan.
I'm Yoon Kang from Gongju.
You've become a hero.
Don't you have to say thank you?
Thank you.
Then... let us part here.
Baek Dae Gil!
Cheers to Baek Dae Gil!
Father, I cannot allow this.
How can give your gambling room to him?
You worked so hard to build it.
It's not like you built it!
Don't get attached and have regrets.
You just need to get married.
Get married to a good man.
I'm not going to get married.
What do you think of him?
You know... Baek Dae Gil?
Father!
He did save your life.
By looking at your expression,
I can tell you don't hate the idea.
Father!
Baek Dae Gil took down Seosomun's
Six Ghost and now Mapo's Gol Sa too?
And now Yeoning has the
accounting books in his hands.
How did something like this happen?
Didn't you say we should wait and watch?
It is tomorrow.
What would happen
if that accounting book were to...
fall into the king's hands?
We need to come up with a plan now.
This one has records of those who
paid bribes as well as the amounts.
And this one...
has the names, times, and dates
of who received the bribes and when.
It has the name of witnesses, as well.
I was relieved.
Your name was not in there.
Then step away from this now
as you promised.
I will take care of the rest.
Wow, I feel so proud and satisfied.
It's because I raised him.
He was raised a boy of Joseon.
Now, he has made such a name for himself.
This is so satisfying.
Okay, I'm paying for all this so drink
and eat to your heart's content.
In the end, isn't your money my money?
When it comes to money,
the person holding it is the owner.
I'll bring out more alcohol.
You were so great, Dae Gil.
Baek Dae Gil.
By tomorrow morning,
the world will have turned upside down.
Because of your name.
Gosh, how come you
do not even get drunk?
Are you curious about that too?
Your Highness.
Your Highness?
The palace officials call me that
over and over and it gets so tiresome.
But why is it so nice to hear
"Your Highness" now?
Here, have a drink.
Your Highness.
About that Baek Dae Gil...
What is your reason for continuing to
remain close to him?
At your position and status,
are you trying to make a friend?
Is it something like that?
My position and status...
I threw those aside.
I threw aside power.
I threw aside my self-interest.
It was then that my eyes were opened.
It was then that I recognized friendship
in someone I could not before.
And that I had turned away from
the misery I knew the people suffered.
But I finally began to see.
You saw friendship and the people.
That's all good.
Can you...
give up your life for that friend?
For the people...
can you give up this throne?
Just know this.
If you cannot do that,
then he is not your friend.
He is not one of your people either.
Therefore...
behave in a manner that suits
your status and position in life.
Dae Gil, what's your dream?
Dream? I don't know.
I don't know what my dream is.
I do think that I'd like to
become someone's dream.
Well, then...
Can you become my dream too?
Seol Im, don't you have a dream?
I don't want a dream that's
not even within my reach.
I want it to become
a reality that's always here.
I'm going to go to sleep now.
Okay.
Thank you.
What for?
Just... everything.
Go to bed.
Who's there?
You're stronger than I thought.
Six Ghost... and Gol Sa, too.
Cutter.
Why don't you show me your skills?
You're not bad.
What is it?
Were you too scared to come alone?
Seol Im...
What are you going to do with her?
She says she's leaving
from under your control.
Leaving, you say?
I have a request.
Don't die in a harsh place.
That was embarrassing.
I'm sorry.
Be careful.
What are you doing?
If you've come, you should enter.
Dae Gil.
Take care of yourself.
Okay.
You have only two choices.
One is to leave here
and live your life out alone.
I was told that I was
born with a bad omen.
I'm going to go far away.
Somewhere you won't be
and where I'll be alone.
Where did he go off to?
Dae Gil!
Seol Im...
Seol Im!
These are Seol Im's shoes.
Even if you're the master here,
don't think you can replace my father.
I cannot accept you... ever.
I will not replace him.
I will make good on the favor
that he asked of me.
Favor?
Stop!
What do you think you're doing?
Www.KoreanDramaX.com
Did you kill Gol Sa?
Would you believe me if I told you?
- Have you seen Seol Im?
- Seol Im?
Don't turn your back on me.
Arrest Baek Dae Gil.
Even without this sword,
I believe you.
How could you burn the documents
we worked so hard to get?
You promised to leave things in my hands.
It is time for us to all stand together.
I will kill him no matter
what I have to do.
Baek Dae Gil,
you are actually my brother?
I will arrest the culprit
before the bell is rung.
Now, I know who the real killer is.