Hold it, hold it, hold it. Georgia.
Sister Abernathy is singing
three times as loud as you...
and she just had her tonsils out, sugar.
- How you gonna account for that?
- I'm sorry, Reverend, I thought I was.
It's all right, baby. It's all right.
Now, as an incentive for us all
to be in full voice...
on Sunday, our very own
Senator Dillings will be here...
to help us kick off our Community
Redevelopment Program. Amen.
Amen!
Hi, ma'am.
Okay.
Okay, here we go.
Domino, Lean Cuisine.
You take the paper towel, right?
Oh, and mayonnaise.
That's it.
- That's it?
- Yes.
- Hey, little mama, that pretty.
- Check it out, man. Yeah.
Let me holla at you for a sec.
Don't you got no time for nobody?
Hey, Miss Byrd.
Hey. Any problems with the car today?
Some gunshots.
Nobody mess with the car, though.
Okay, Darius, so you come by
in exactly 75 minutes and I'll be ready.
Yes, ma'am. Me, too.
Yeah! Welcome back!
Welcome back to Emeril Live!
Emeril Lagasse here. We're
making chicken four ways tonight.
Wait till you see this dish
that I got coming up right now for you.
Poulet Tchoupitoulas.
Oh, yeah, baby!
You can't see this at home,
but he is happy, this chicken.
He's clapping for Doc Gibbs
and the Emeril Live Band!
He's just... Oh, yeah.
You gotta split him in half...
and then we're gonna make
what I call a paste.
This chicken, skin- side down...
Skin-side down.
Now, for this Poulet Tchoupitoulas...
maybe some of this fumé blanc
would work.
So, a little splash like this. Okay?
Or a big splash!
Like that!
Bread pudding with onions,
with sweet corn, and andouille sausage.
Okay? Oh, yeah.
'Cause the Poulet Tchoupitoulas with
the bread pudding.
Bam!
Look at that! That's looking good!
I don't suppose you're gonna have any?
Lord, no.
I don't eat nothing but my Lean Cuisine.
What is that book, anyway?
- How do you like them greens?
- Oh, man, it's the bomb!
Well, good.
I mixed them this time, you know.
Collard greens...
and of course, your favorite,
turnip greens.
- And I got plenty for your grandpa.
- Cool, thanks.
Sugar!
I just got these pants.
Always doing this.
Darius, what are you doing?
That is my private property.
- I was just looking. What is it?
- It's nothing.
It's just what it says, just possibilities.
Just things I'm interested in.
Including this guy?
- He your boyfriend?
- No.
He's just an idea.
I mean, he's a real guy...
Why are you snooping around
my stuff, anyway?
So, what's his name?
Who?
None of your business.
I'll tell you what his name is.
His name is lucky mother...
What?
I know you might as well
go ahead leave my house now...
if you're gonna be using
that kind of language.
I'm sorry,
but short of you telling me his name...
I don't know anything better to call him.
His name is Sean.
- Sean Williams.
- Sean Williams, huh?
And you better not say anything
to anybody.
I ain't.
There he is, there he is.
Okay, I'm not gonna say anything.
- You just talk to him.
- No, I'm not going to talk to him.
...just to say hello. All right?
Go and talk to him. Stop him.
- Good morning, Miss Byrd.
- Mr. Williams.
What was that? Was that power flirting?
I don't know.
Oh, my, my, my.
You could crack a walnut with that ass.
Girl, stop!
Don't you have somewhere to be?
You know what we need to do?
We need to get you out of these
frumpy clothes and into something...
- that shows off the real estate a little bit.
- No. Rochelle! This is a workplace.
Seriously. Then you need
to go down there...
and you need to talk to Mr. Big Stuff...
and you need to tell him
what you want for Christmas.
- You just sit in his lap...
- Hey! Rochelle, come on, now.
What? No...
What are you worried about?
That they're going to fire you
in this place?
Take your coffee and go!
You're the best damn worker they got
in this whole damn place.
They're not gonna fire you.
You're just scared.
You're scared of some man
getting a hold of all that booty of yours!
Would you stop?
He could hold my booty.
Sean!
Attention Kragen shoppers...
stop in our health clinic
on the second floor...
to make sure your holidays...
Right. This piece goes here.
There we go.
It's still crooked, but, yeah, that's good.
- It's good, huh?
- No, no, no.
"Lip of shelf to fit
between grill bottom and leg brace."
That was supposed to be put on last,
but that's all right.
Thank you.
- Miss Byrd.
- Georgia.
You had some light bulbs to change
or something, remember?
Yeah! Oh, yeah, yeah, light bulbs.
Light bulbs.
You know, they be relying on me...
Hey, I'll see you later.
Yeah. Sure. Yeah.
Is there something I can help you with?
That's quite a nice grill.
- Stainless steel, huh?
- Yeah. Durable.
- Easy to clean?
- You just hose it down.
Just hose it down, huh?
- Are you on your break?
- Yes.
Well, that's why I'm here.
I wanted to ask you something.
Ask me what?
Do you think I'll get my store discount
if I buy this thing?
Well, of course.
Of course you get your store discount.
But I just sold you a grill last week,
remember?
Yeah. But that was a hibachi.
That was for traveling.
I think somebody should've told you
when you got this thing...
that you're supposed to have a lawn
or a backyard or something.
Okay, how about a little more lifting
and a little less talking?
That looks good. Smells good, too.
All right, there you have it.
A simple Creole roasted duck hash
en croûte.
Now, what you can do with this here...
is you can take a little bit
of the parsley...
and onion if you like,
if that's what you like.
But here's what I like to do.
Now, this is only for the brave ones.
For those
who don't get a lot of heartburn.
I like to kick some of that hot sauce
on there, spice it up something.
Please, come on and enjoy some.
Excuse me.
Now, I made this special for you.
I left the pine nuts out...
'cause I know they get up
under your bridgework sometimes.
Aren't you sweet?
- Thank you.
- Excuse me.
Are you bucking for General
of the Salvation Army or what?
Stop feeding the moochers.
We always have...
our Wednesday morning
sales demonstration, Mr. Adamian.
No, no.
That's exactly the kind of thinking...
that put this store in Chapter 11
in the first place.
Now, Mr. Kragen, he's trying
to change the culture around here.
And by culture, I mean money.
Now, if you care about
your future here...
I suggest
you get with the program, Miss Byrd.
Have you read this? Kragen's awesome.
- Everybody got one.
- Read it again.
Yeah. Yup?
Yup. Yup.
Well, then, hire another Santa.
Of course, he has to be fat.
Attention Kragen shoppers...
today's pre- Christmas sales
are on the second level.
Georgia. I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to scare you. I'm sorry.
Oh, my God. I'm sorry.
No. I'm sorry.
I'm kind of in my own little world
up here.
What brings you to cookware?
It's that smell, to tell you the truth.
I can't help it.
It wafts down the escalator,
usually I can resist, but...
Oh.
Oh, well, please have some.
I'll probably get fired over this.
Did you ever have a smell
that triggers a memory?
This smells like my mama's house.
Thank you.
That's incredible. Incredible.
You know,
I'm just trying to sell the cookware.
Where did you become a chef?
France, or someplace European
or something?
Oh, no, I'm not a chef.
I've never been to France.
I ain't never been further north
than Mobile, Alabama.
You know, it's just a hobby.
Something I really enjoy doing.
- A hobby, huh?
- I never trained or anything.
- You gonna train?
- I don't know.
Someday. Maybe.
Look. I was wondering,
sometime, if you're free...
I thought maybe we could...
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- I'll get it. I'll get it.
You got...
Oh... Georgia!
Whoa! What happened? Is she okay?
She hit her head.
- Give me a hand, please.
- So what? It's just a bump.
Watch her head.
Don't hit her head again.
Miss Byrd, can you hear me?
Can you hear me, Miss Byrd?
Can you hear the words
that are coming out of my mouth?
How many fingers am I holding up?
Is it one, two, or more?
- What's going on here?
- Georgia, are you okay? Georgia?
Oh, man.
I think we should do a CAT scan.
What?
That's a big ticket number, isn't it?
I didn't think we did that kind of thing
around here.
Well, we got a new machine.
Used, but new to us.
Yeah, I don't know.
Sir, there could be
a huge workman's comp payout...
if we don't follow procedure.
All right,
only if it's absolutely necessary.
I knew you'd understand.
Paperwork. Follow me.
- Are you okay, Miss Byrd?
- Kind of nice to be off my feet.
Here we go.
Now, don't worry now, Miss Byrd.
Everything will be just fine.
What?
No, this can't be right.
Oh, my God.
We're just going to try
one more time, Miss Byrd.
This is not good.
This is not good at all.
What are we looking at?
Well, we're looking at the results
of a virus you have, ma'am.
- Virus?
- I believe it to be Lampington's disease.
It's very rare and it's very harmless,
in most cases.
- In most cases?
- Yes.
What about my case?
Well, I thought I'd misread
the first scan, so I did the second scan.
But that just confirmed it, you see?
- Okay, so I have Lampington's?
- Yes.
Well, which one do I have
if not the harmless one?
Ma'am, I'm very sorry to tell you...
But I...
You see,
in my opinion it's the kind that...
Ma'am, please! This is very, very
difficult for me. I'm just...
Oh, dear.
I need to lie down.
You see this area here?
- This is your mass.
- My mass?
Your tumor.
And this, and this, and this.
I'm sorry, Georgia,
but the virus has caused...
a very advanced case
of Lampington's lesions.
Okay, well, exactly what
does that mean, Lampington's lesions?
And Dr. Gupta hasn't told you anything
about this, right?
Well, I tried.
Thanks.
Without treatment, it's terminal.
What? Like I'm gonna die?
I'm very, very sorry.
But I feel fine.
I feel great.
I just finished a Fat Flush and...
No dizziness or fainting?
No. I got a tiny bump on my head,
that's all.
It's diabolical. Such a sneaky disease.
I'm afraid, in your condition,
you've got about three weeks to live.
What? I got three weeks to live?
Are you shitting me?
Four on the outside. I'm sorry.
You're sorry? Well, I'm sorry.
I can't accept that.
Then I think you should see
Katherine Lenz.
Okay. Fine.
That's what I'm talking about.
Katherine Lenz, okay.
- Is that the brain specialist?
- No.
She's your HMO administrator.
Let me just save you some time here,
Miss Byrd.
We won't cover you for this operation.
Well, what do you mean,
you won't cover me?
I'm covered through my HMO.
If you feel you're being treated unfairly,
these are our appeals procedures...
which you have every legal right
to pursue.
Well, what if I pay for it myself?
How much would that cost me?
The cost
of a median cranial debulking surgery...
is around $340,000.
That's without anesthesia.
You'll want that.
Check again,
make sure I'm not covered.
You wait and you wait
for something big to happen...
and then you find out you're gonna die.
I really wanted to meet you.
And I should've ate that.
I should've ate all that stuff.
Especially this.
Put my foot in that. Darius loved that.
Now I'll never get to Karlovy Vary.
Chef Didier.
- Hello?
- Hi.
Hiya, sis!
I was just getting ready to call you.
You know, there's this guy
that I met in this club...
and he said he's gonna introduce me
to some of his friends in Nashville...
I just need you
to take care of the kids for three days.
What you gonna do in Nashville?
Girl, I am finally going to be
a country western singer.
Isn't that great?
Tanya, ain't no such thing
as a black country singer.
You know, I am not asking you to
comment on the validity of my dreams.
Now can you...
Hold on. Anton, would you stop it?
- This child is going to kill himself!
- Listen, that's why I'm calling you...
What are you doing? Why can't you
watch the kids? What are you...
- I'm gonna have to call you back.
- But, I'm...
I told you to stop jumping.
Do it again and see what happens.
You think I'm playing?
Georgia, where have you been?
Adamian's been looking for you.
Good, 'cause I'm looking for him, too.
- Why?
- I'm gonna take your advice.
Huh?
Look, remember when you said
life was too short to live the way I do?
- Oh, I say a lot of things.
- Yeah, well, you were right.
What? What did I say?
What are you gonna do?
Georgia?
What did I say?
You don't knock?
You better have a hell of an excuse
for where you've been, Ms. Byrd.
I do, I do.
You see, Mr. Adamian...
Excuse me, would you mind?
This is very important.
- Actually, it's a matter of life and...
- What?
Just turn it off.
Yeah.
You're killing me
with the potato peelers.
Move them
or I'll shove them down your throat.
You got a problem?
Yes, I do.
That's a $400 phone.
Now I feel better.
That's company property.
That's going to come out
of your paycheck.
Take it. Take the whole thing, okay?
It's worth it.
This is not about you, okay?
It's not about me.
It's about business.
- It's about the company.
- Mr. Adamian.
I want you to hear this.
This man lives his philosophy.
Rule One:
Life is not a popularity contest...
but it is a contest.
Boo- hoo, they don't like me.
Rule Two: You grab
that scared little loser inside you...
and beat the living crap out of him!
Rule three: When is enough, enough?
Enough is never enough.
Enough is enough right now,
Mr. Adamian!
I'm trying to talk to you!
I'm trying to tell you what's...
Why am I even wasting my time
trying to talk to you?
You know what? I quit.
- You what?
- I quit.
- You can't.
- Why can't I?
Fourth quarter sales are in the toilet
in this store...
and all the other stores, too,
for that matter.
Your department has
the highest profit record in the place.
I just... I can't afford to lose you.
How come
you never told me this before?
I didn't want you to do
what you're doing right now.
Holding me up for more money.
Which I'm happy to pay.
As God is my witness.
As God is your witness, huh?
As God is your witness?
All right. I'm prepared to offer you
50 cents more an hour!
75 cents more an hour. 75.
Ms. Byrd, $1 more an hour. $1.50.
Hey, Georgia. Your shift done already?
Yeah, I'm done.
Listen, I feel terrible
about what happened the other day.
- I wanted to make it up to you.
- It wasn't your fault.
Well, anyway...
Hey, I have a pair of tickets
to the Hornets game.
Now, the game
is a couple of weeks away...
but I know you're a busy woman,
so I wanted to put my bid in early.
Sean, there is nothing I would rather do
than to go to that game with you.
Yeah? That's great.
Well, look, I figured we'll go
to dinner early, then after the game...
I can't go, Sean.
I mean, it's not like I don't want to. I...
I can't.
You have to be somewhere else.
Yeah.
Hey, well, Georgia. Georgia!
Look.
I already paid for the ticket, so...
maybe your plans might change, huh?
Brothers and Sisters...
I'm sad to announce that...
Senator Dillings will not be gracing
our flock this morning as planned.
Pressing business
in our nation's capital has kept him.
But I'd like to take a moment of prayer
for the Senator.
He toils so hard
toting the burden of our welfare.
And I ask the good Lord
to guide his hand...
in his important good works. Amen.
- Amen.
Oh, why me?
- Oh, dear Lord, why me?
- Georgia?
Why me, Lord? Why me, Lord?
- Oh, dear Lord! Lord, why me?
- Bless the Lord.
Oh, Lord, no!
Oh, no, no.
Lord! Lord, come on!
Come on, Lord, why?
I don't understand!
I followed your Commandments, Lord
Why in heavens me?
I never slept around
even though my sister did!
Why in heavens me, Lord?
Why in heavens me?
I never cussed my boss
or nothing like that!
Why in heavens me, Lord?
Why in heavens me?
- Why?
Come on, now, somebody tell me why!
Why, Lord?
- Why, please?
- Why?
I got to know
I got to know, God!
Why me?
Why? Oh, why?
Why, Lord? Why? Oh, come on
Why? Why? Why?
You're sure you want to liquidate
the entire IRA? All of it?
Yeah, and the bonds my mama left me.
Well, I'm sure a disciplined woman
such as yourself...
has a very useful purpose
for this money.
Yes, I do.
I'm just gonna blow it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we want to thank you...
for flying with us on Christmas Day.
We're going to make your trip
as comforyable as possible.
Stewardess...
this person behind me
is giving me a hard time.
Okay, sure, sir.
Ma'am, would you mind
lowering your knees...
so the gentleman in front of you
can put his seat back down?
Actually, I very much would mind.
Am I going to have to
call the Air Marshal, ma'am?
People been calling me ma'am
a lot lately...
and, you know,
I'm hardly older than you.
Do people call you ma'am?
No... No, they don't.
Is there a problem here?
Yes. Yes, there is.
I'm gonna tell you what the problem is.
This greedy airline put all these seats
so close together...
just so they can make more money.
- Makes sense.
- Yeah.
All right?
Now, I'm not flying
all the way to Prague...
with some stranger in my lap.
I know that's right.
That's a big boy.
That's a big old man right there.
I can't... Look at him.
Had you chosen to fly first class...
Ma'am? Hi.
Had you chosen to fly first class
instead of economy...
you would have had plenty of room
in one of our cocoons.
- How much is it?
- Beg your pardon?
How much for the damn cocoon?
- Work it!
- I like that.
- All right.
- Hear, hear.
For our first class clients
flying with us during the holidays...
we thought we would do
something special.
Thank you. Wait, don't go.
Just leave that right here.
Look at that taxi line.
Oh, this is gonna take forever.
That's it. That's the Pupp.
That's the hotel I'm going to.
Who is that?
- What's going on?
- I'm not sure, Congressman.
Who is that?
All I know, Senator, is that the last time
someone arrived by helicopter...
it was Elton John. Sir Elton John.
Wow.
Hello. Welcome!
- Thank you.
- Welcoming.
- You are here for retreat of the health?
- I guess you could say that.
How are you?
Well I'm hung-over, I'm jet-lagged.
I'm dying.
- Other than that, I'm fine, thank you.
- Great, great.
Oh, you are from Louisiana?
Your Senator Dillings, he here now.
Skiing.
- Senator Dillings is here skiing?
- Yes.
Well, that explains why he didn't make it
to our meeting on Sunday.
- Please, I'll meet you at reception desk.
- Okay.
And here I was thinking I might not fit in.
- Excuse me. Georgia Byrd.
- Madame Byrd?
Welcome to Grandhotel Pupp.
Come on. Y'all really say it like that?
- Pupp.
I'm sorry, Miss Byrd,
but your room is not ready yet.
We weren't expecting you
for two more hours.
Well, I wasn't expecting
to take a helicopter.
But my time is kind of precious
lately now.
Don't y'all have anything available now?
I'll check it.
Don't that ceiling ever just
make you want to cry?
I've never noticed, madam.
Only the presidential suite.
It's C3,000 a night.
About $4,000 a night.
Did you see me blink?
Madam Byrd, welcome.
I know that you will find our
presidential suite most comfortable.
- Mr. Kragen, would you sign my book?
- Yes.
- Matthew Kragen.
- You know Mr. Kragen?
We are so honored that he comes
to our hotel every year at this time.
- You playing with me, right?
- Pardon me?
- Oh, not you, Him.
- Excuse me.
Is the spelling okay?
You get yourself
young, hip and rich, okay?
- Thank you.
- Mr. Kragen, sir.
- I hope everything's okay.
- Wonderful, Arturo, wonderful.
- And will Mrs. Kragen be joining us?
- Well, not this trip, Arturo.
This is strictly business.
As always, if there's anything,
even the slightest thing, you will tell me.
- Well, I won't, but she will.
- Lf I need you, I'll call you.
Excellent.
Can you believe that?
Don't worry about it. Now, listen,
just double-check everything...
and I want to keep tabs
on the Congressman and the Senator.
Schmooze, impress, whatever it takes.
This deal's got to happen.
Madam Byrd.
Felipe will show you to your suite.
Okay.
Matthew, Miss Burns.
The Senator's gone skiing
for the 83rd time. Let's go have a drink.
Get upstairs and put some silk on.
Congressman!
If it's any consolation,
he's gonna have a shitty fourth quarter.
Who is that?
Oh, Mademoiselle Byrd. Very rich.
From Louisiana.
She and Senator Dillings
were supposed to have...
a very important meeting together.
Hang on, let me give you a little
something for your troubles.
I haven't quite figured out
this money yet.
Did I just give you
a ridiculously large tip?
No, madam.
Now, more reasonable.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye!
What world was I living in?
Make me international.
We could try.
Give me my money.
I can't wear this.
Oh, yeah, there we go. Like that.
You think anybody'd call me ma'am
in this outfit?
- No.
- Definitely not.
- Table for one, please.
- Yes, mademoiselle.
Please.
May I take your pashmina?
Oh, is that what this thing is?
Sure.
Hello, sister.
Who the hell is she?
- Mademoiselle.
- Thank you.
Her name is Georgia Byrd.
She's loaded and she's an old crony
of Dillings from Louisiana.
I...
I'm sorry.
No. It's okay, it's okay.
Water. Flat. No ice.
- Please, serve everyone.
- Of course.
Matthew, what are the chances
of our meeting Chef Didier?
Margaret here's got a couple
of his books. She's a big fan.
Is that right? Arturo!
Yes, sir.
Make sure Didier comes and says hello
to the table.
And fire that guy.
For the specialties de maison,
we have the cassoulet.
We have risotto Barolo with truffles.
The rouget citrus beurre blanc
with capers.
Roast quail with brioche stuffing.
And a braised lamb shank
with blood orange relish.
Blood orange relish.
Now, that all sounds so good.
Will he have the same specials
tomorrow night?
No. Chef Didier never creates
the same menu twice.
Well, I guess I better try them all
tonight then.
Tout? All?
Tout, baby! Tout de suite.
Do you think he would do a risotto
without the dairy?
I think I'm going to have
the rouget citrus without the potatoes...
and the blanc without the beurre.
No butter, no cream, no wheat,
no dairy, no fat!
Merde! Why do they bother to eat?
Next time, stick this in my neck!
And no substitutions?
I will do it myself.
She has got them eating
right out of her hand.
Well, she's sure not watching
her cholesterol.
I wish I could command
attention like that.
Is that the lamb?
- Mademoiselle.
- Oh, look at that!
Looks so good!
Everything looks so good.
Bon appétit.
Amen.
I was thinking maybe we could get Bob
up to speed tomorrow at lunchtime.
Yes, Matthew. I'd like to know more
about this merger.
Here he is!
How do you find everything,
mademoiselle?
- Arturo.
- Yes, sir.
I think he'll be by.
I'm sure he'll be right over, sir.
- I'll be up there, on top of the mountain.
- Okay. Will Margaret join us?
Because we do need to talk
some business.
Okay, what time?
Depends on Kragen's schedule.
You know, where I come from...
we do a barbecue quail
with an andouille pudding.
I think you would just love it.
And, you know, call me crazy...
but am I tasting rendered lards
of pork belly here?
Oui?
Pork belly?
Oink, oink.
Very sensitive palate.
Half clarified butter and half pork fat.
- I knew it.
- No? But you keep it to yourself.
You know how some people are
about pork's fat.
Yeah.
They don't like the pork...
Chef Didier, you're crazy!
Matthew, you seem to know everybody.
Who is she?
I was gonna ask the Senator
the same question.
- I don't know her.
- Really? You sure about that?
Well, for your information,
I don't know everyone who's black.
Well, apparently she knows you
from New Orleans?
Really? Maybe it was last year's
Entrepreneurs of Diversity.
Well, whoever she is, I'd sure like
to have her ordering 10 plates...
at a $10,000-a-plate fundraiser.
Why, Bob?
Haven't I've been contributing enough?
No, Matthew, I didn't mean it that way.
You've been very generous
and it's much appreciated.
Dr. Gupta.
Sir, if this is a medical question,
I'm still on my break...
for two and a half more minutes.
Well, actually, excuse me,
it's not about me.
It's about Georgia Byrd.
Remember the lady who hit her head?
Sir, why do you think
I'm so desperately trying to relax?
Well, she's been acting
really strange lately.
She up and quit her job.
Nobody's seen her.
And I was wondering if you had said
anything that might have upset her?
- Or if you know something...
- I'm sorry.
Patient privacy prevents me
from commenting, I'm very sorry...
- You're gonna tell me!
- Okay, okay.
- Sir?
- Tell me!
Georgia Byrd is going to die.
- What?
- I'm very sorry.
- I'm very sorry, sir.
No, this can't be.
My break is over. We can talk about it.
Come, put me down.
That's nice.
I do it with love.
Okay.
And the gonging, flushing
negative energy.
Wait. I gotta use the bathroom.
They say these waters
have curative powers...
let you live to be 100.
Yeah, well, I hope they work fast.
Clarence Dillings.
Senator Clarence Dillings.
- I know who you are.
- Oh, so, we have met.
Entrepreneurs of Diversity?
- No, afraid not.
- Washington?
They do know each other.
Well.
Church?
- But I didn't go to church last Sunday.
- That's right.
You know, you left a whole lot
of church folk disappointed, Senator.
People who voted for you.
I hope you'll communicate
my sincerest regrets.
I don't wanna have nothing
to do with your regrets.
I got my hands full of my own.
I got a gut feeling about that woman.
She's trouble.
You know, Matthew,
who was it who said:
"Adversity is the stone
on which I sharpen my blade"?
Me.
Excuse me.
Ms. Byrd, is it?
We've not been introduced.
- My name...
- There's no need.
Everybody knows Matthew Kragen.
The man for whom
"enough is never enough."
I mean, who is she?
How do I know she's not part of some...
consumer watchdog group
or something?
Well, it's not like there's some law...
against being at the same hotel
with a congressman and a senator.
Actually, there is,
if they're on my plane and my dime.
Well, watchdogs don't stay
in $4,000-a-night hotel suites, okay?
So, how about you and I
just forget all about...
retail empire building...
and let's just take a little bath? Yeah?
I'll take a bath, all right.
A $500-million bath
if these mergers don't go through.
You just keep your eyes open
and remember why we're here.
Are you all right, Madam Byrd?
Yeah. I just... I just love these sheets.
I love them. I was just taking them
for a little ride around the block.
I am Gunther. Floor valet.
Oh, that was you
that put my clothes away.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Well, Miss Gunther,
what do you do for fun around here?
What do I do for fun, madam?
I shine the guests' shoes
when they leave them out in the hall.
If that will be all.
No, actually, that won't, Miss Gunther.
I'm gonna be wanting to have
one of these snowboarding lessons.
- Very good. Will that be all?
- No, no.
No, it won't.
I want some more
of these spa services. Like maybe...
Maybe this algae flotation wrap
and the reflexology massage.
No anti-aging treatment?
- No, I ain't worried about aging.
- So, that will be all?
Yes! The colon irrigation treatment.
That's my gift to you.
Sort of like a "let's be friends" gesture.
Now, you think of me
when you're having it!
Oh.
I've been waiting my whole life
to do something like this.
- All right then, let's go.
- Okay.
- Just lean forward. Lean forward.
- Lean forward.
Left leg, that's it. And go!
Go, that's it. Just go! Yeah!
You got it, lean forward! Balance!
Yeah! That's it. Lean...
Are you all right?
Let's go.
- Let's turn.
- Oh, man.
- You feel the rhythm?
- I feel the rhythm.
- Yeah. Feel the rhythm.
- That's good.
- That's it. Right. You got it?
- I think I got it.
So, go! Just lean forward.
Lean forward and go!
Lean forward. Lean forward.
Lean forward.
- Lean forward.
- Yeah, that's it, that's great.
- Oh, Lord.
- That's great. No, no, no.
Slow down. Slow down a bit.
No. Slow down!
Turn the board sideways!
Slow, slow down!
Stop!
Scusi! Watch out!
Get out of my way! Watch it!
What?
It's steep here, Matthew.
Hey, Matthew, this is
a Black Diamond run.
Yeah, you're looking good.
- Look at her go!
- Matthew?
Matthew!
- Enjoying yourself?
- Not really.
Please, don't do that.
I guess you don't believe in turning?
I believe in it,
I just don't know how to do...
Oh, hold me, hold me! Please!
- Please get off of my skis!
- Okay, I think I've got it.
Let me go.
Sorry. I'm okay! I'm okay!
Damn you!
Nobody makes me do a face-plant!
Damn it!
Watch your mouth!
What the hell are you doing?
You trying to kill me?
Watch out!
Get over here, you!
They should get you off this mountain!
You figure...
You... You ski like that...
you're gonna be in court
for the next two years!
That's fine with me, baby.
Oh, my God.
And we are going to leave you now...
- to relax and meditate.
- Thank you.
Why, Lord?
I don't want to die.
I want to live.
What are you trying to do to me, huh?
You have big knot in neck.
You do something at work where
you hold head in strange position.
Excuse me? Are you suggesting that I...
Too much holding phone
on neck, maybe.
You know what?
Why don't you just shut up...
and do what you're supposed to do,
okay?
You're a masseuse, not a life coach!
Excuse me.
Hey. Hey!
I don't like the way
you're talking to that woman.
I'm sorry if I disturbed you, Ms. Byrd.
She was hurting me, though.
I don't care. You don't talk
to working people that way.
Now, it's plain to see
what the problem is here.
You got tension in your neck 'cause
you keep going down on Mr. Kragen.
And he's a married man.
At least this poor lady
is trying to work it out of you.
Don't take it out on Brigitta.
Thank you.
Anyway, enjoy your massage.
- Thank you very much.
- Bye.
Is it that obvious
that I'm sleeping with him?
I knew it.
None of the other women
at the company will even talk to me.
I'm marked by this.
And there's no one in my life
who I can talk to about it.
Well, I wouldn't lose too much sleep
over what other people think.
Now, come on, girl,
we're supposed to be meditating.
I've been at the company six years.
I've worked really hard, you know?
Oh, you don't understand.
I hate the retail business.
Oh, believe me, baby, I understand.
I worked in the retail business
for 10 years myself.
Look, I know this whole story.
My sister was seeing a married man.
Matthew's gonna leave his wife.
It's a bad time for her right now,
but he is gonna leave his wife.
Baby, come on, now.
I know you're holding out some hope...
but come on, they're never bad people,
they're greedy people.
They want a little bit of this,
little bit of that, little bit of that...
They ain't leaving their wives.
Yeah, you just need to leave him.
It's not that easy.
If I leave him, I'll have to quit my job.
What am I going to do?
I didn't finish school.
Well, then you go back to school.
There now, we solved it.
Let's tackle something heavy,
like world hunger.
Well, did you at least find out
what she's doing here?
She's just here enjoying herself.
Unlike us.
How can I enjoy myself?
Dillings is suddenly telling me
that his committee...
has problems with my acquisitions.
Matthew, what does that
have to do with Georgia?
Oh, Georgia, is it now?
Oh, well, why don't you tell me?
I don't know, Matthew.
She said she worked in retail.
Did I mention to you how she told me...
you were gonna have
a shitty fourth quarter?
How can she possibly know
about our fourth quarter?
I barely know about our fourth quarter.
Well, maybe she's an executive
for Wal-Mart.
I mean, the competition
wouldn't want to see you...
triple the size of your retail empire,
would they?
You know what? That's it. That's it!
She's here to drive a wedge
between me and those guys.
If I don't have their support,
my bill is dead on the floor.
That's what's gonna happen, see?
I need to relax, that's what I need to do.
Oh, God, my blood pressure is...
You know what?
I need to just do something to relax.
- Come here...
- Take a cold plunge, Matthew.
What?
Georgia?
- You guys seen Georgia?
- I ain't seen her in a while.
No.
Hey, what are you doing,
casing the place?
- Where's Georgia?
- Hey, you're that guy.
You're the Possibilities man.
The guy in the book.
What? What book?
What are you talking about?
- Where's Georgia?
- Hold on.
- What?
Here, I found this in her garbage can.
That's my employee of the month photo.
- Did she say anything about me?
- No.
Why? You like her, right?
Easy, killer.
Did she say where she was going?
A place with healing waters
or something.
Look, it's really important that you
remember, all right, little man?
Maybe it's in here somewhere.
I know she told me before she left.
I think this is it.
Calamari Vary, I think the name is.
- Karlovy Vary?
- Yeah, Karlovy Vary, that's it!
- Oh, good evening, Georgia.
- Hi.
- How are you this evening?
- Good, thanks.
Why don't you join us?
We got plenty of room at our table,
don't we, Matthew?
- Sure, yeah, why not?
- No, please. Please, come join us.
- Yes, come, it's decided.
- Good evening, Ms. Byrd.
Chef Didier has reserved a special table
for you. If you'd like to come with me.
Well, thank you,
but why don't you join me?
It seems I have a special table.
- Thanks so much for having us.
- Oh, thank you. Thank you.
You really look beautiful.
- Yes, you do.
- Thank you.
- You really do.
Pull up a chair, Matthew.
Glad you decided to join us, Matthew.
Could you maybe just... A little room.
It...
Hi. Thank you so much, Chef Didier.
No, you are my preferred guest...
and I have prepared a special menu
just for you tonight.
But I will make no substitutions.
Don't worry.
We will have your special menu
exactly the way you make it.
No substitutions?
No substitutions.
That was delicious.
- Oh, my goodness, I hurt myself.
- Thank you.
So, Georgia,
Ms. Burns tells me you're in retail.
I was.
Well, you've obviously done very well
for yourself.
Actually, I just clipped a lot of coupons.
And when you say coupons,
you obviously mean bonds?
No. No, I sold all my bonds.
You sold all of your bonds?
Ms. Byrd, as Chairman
of the Commerce Committee...
I'm always interested in how
savvy people such as yourself...
operate the market.
Did you think that rates
were going up, or were you...
pessimistic about the future?
- Well, Congressman...
- Bob, please. Bob.
Well, Bob, I find that the future
is too depressing to think about.
Oh, come on, Georgia.
Miss Byrd,
what are you doing tomorrow?
I would very much like to continue this...
Well, hold on, hold on, hold on.
You see, tomorrow I've arranged
for our group to go to Moser.
Moser? What's that?
Moser! Glass. Factory.
All of us. Special tour.
That's what we're doing tomorrow.
To answer your question,
I'm going BASE-jumping, Bob.
Really, BASE-jumping?
You're kidding! Well, why?
Well, I hear it's a completely
liberating experience.
Well, at least that's what
the brochure says.
Oh, that is amazing.
Oh, come on, Matthew,
why don't we all go along and watch?
It sounds like fun! Let's do that.
That is a great idea.
Better than some glass factory.
Fine, fine, fine.
But I'm not going there to watch.
So, because it's a dam
and not a straight jump...
Yes.
...when you don't do it right,
you will catch the current...
and it will slam you
in the side of the dam.
So, we don't want that, okay?
- So, are you ready?
- Yes, I am.
- Go get them, Matthew!
- Come on!
Damn.
Okay, now we're gonna do this.
I don't know what the hell makes people
want to do something like this.
I try to avoid any plummeting sports.
Matthew's only doing it
because Georgia's doing it.
He's the most competitive person
in the world.
He may have met his match in Georgia.
Camcorder!
Oh. Bob, Bob, the camera.
You got the camera going?
- We're rolling! Go ahead!
- Okay!
Oh, oh. He's gonna... There we go.
He's going over the rail.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, wow.
Oh, my God.
Oh, come on.
All right, here we go.
Okay. Look.
I have told you before...
we have lost a couple of people
doing this.
- What, like people died?
- Yeah.
- Sugar.
- Which one first?
Ladies first.
Ladies first. Okay.
Ready?
- Three...
- Wait, wait, wait, wait!
- Okay. All right.
- Three, two, one, go!
Perfect.
Whoa, baby!
Okay.
Three, two, one, go!
Is there a problem?
Yeah, I'd say there's a problem, Klaus.
I know a thing or two
about BASE-jumping.
I know that the canopy is supposed to
be connected to the rigging and it's not.
And that's how people get killed.
No wonder you've lost a few people.
Here I come. Watch it now!
Oh, hold it now!
I can't jump!
Canopy not connected to rigging!
- Mechanical difficulties!
- It's all right.
- I don't know why this happens!
- What are you doing?
- Klaus, just shut up!
Oh, man.
- It's so...
- Disappointing.
Really?
She's the most amazing person
who ever came to this hotel.
Oh, yeah.
She lives on the edge.
She say what she wants.
She does what she wants.
True existentialist.
Hero worship, bought with a kiss
and an extravagant tip.
She's a fraud, I tell you.
Look what eating sauerkraut has done
to your heart, Fräulein Gunther.
- Mr. Kragen.
- How are you?
Good.
Do me a favor. Georgia Byrd...
just find out where she's from,
what she does.
- Quietly.
- Of course, Mr. Kragen.
Prince Dominic comes tonight.
He's insisted on my venison roast.
A prince? A real prince?
They have a charity dinner in town...
where everybody gets to feel generous.
I tell you, these people are all alike.
Yes, you know, I tell you,
they are all alike.
Oh, people are not as bad as you think.
No, you're wrong, Georgia,
you're wrong. They are.
Like Kragen at the hotel
who looks for life everlasting...
in a tablespoon of extra-virgin olive oil,
you know.
You know...
you and I, we know the secret of life.
Well, what is that?
The secret of life is butter.
Butter? Don't tell nobody.
- Butter, huh?
- Butter, yes!
Three cases of écrevisses.
Hotel.
- Georgia, there you are.
- We were worried you checked out.
- No, not quite yet.
- Are you gonna join us for Smokey?
- Kragen's got it all arranged.
- No, I don't think so.
I'm a little lightheaded
from all that rich food.
Come on, Georgia, you have to join us
for some gambling.
Look, I just think I want to...
Yeah, well, you look exhausted
from all the heroics.
You probably just wanna take it easy.
Oh, no, come on, Georgia.
It won't be half as much fun without you.
I don't know how much fun
it's gonna be. It's a charity event.
Oh, it'll be a great time and Georgia
can help us liven up the evening.
- It's gonna be great.
- Great time. Great time.
Great time had by all.
- Fine, fine.
- Good, it's settled then.
Smokey Robinson.
You can't miss Smokey.
Just take a little nap.
If you're reading this letter,
my disease has run its course.
Enclosed is some money for my burial.
I would like to be cremated.
Spent my whole life in a box.
I don't want to be buried in one.
Ladies and gentlemen,
because of turbulence...
the captain has turned on
the "fasten seat belt" sign.
Excuse me.
Please return to your seats
and remain seated...
with your seat belt fastened
while the sign is illuminated.
Scared of flying?
- Do I look scared to you?
- I used to be scared, too.
It helps if you color.
Georgia, whatever you got,
give me some.
Believe me, you don't want it.
Place your bets.
Don't know where to go.
I'm following you wherever you go.
That's a lunatic bet.
That's just a lunatic bet right there.
Georgia, that's a lot of money.
I know, huh?
- You always bet on black, baby.
- Yeah?
- Yes.
- All right. I'll give that a try.
- No more bets.
- Matthew, Matthew...
doing it your own way.
Georgia's our Lady Luck tonight.
Come on, 17.
- Here we go.
- There it goes.
- 17 black.
- Yeah!
- That's the ball over there.
- Where to next, lucky?
- What was that number I just played?
- 17.
Seventeen. Sounds good to me.
Isn't it a bit reckless
to bet on the same number twice?
I guess that's why they call it gambling
and not crocheting.
Gambling it is.
- Well, the house is loving you guys.
- I'm in.
- Place your bets.
- Me, too.
Here we go, here we go,
here we go. Red.
No more bets.
- Come on, show me something.
- Come on, 17.
- Come on.
- Big money, big money!
- Come on, come on, come on.
- Red, come on.
17 black!
- What?
- Yes!
Oh, my Lord!
Give me a little kickback over here.
- Thank you.
- Wow.
Mesdames et messieurs,
place your bets.
Place it, place it.
What are we doin' here?
I'm going with 17.
Georgia, you can't go there a third time.
A third time? Come on!
Come over here
and get some of this luck.
Maybe I am pushing it a little bit.
I was born on the 13th.
Thirteen, thirteen.
Put this on the thirteen.
You sure about that?
But then again,
I lost my mama when I was 11.
Good idea.
Double me up. Double me up.
Eleven. Yeah. Thank you. Eleven.
- I love my mama.
- Could you please just place the bet?
But my mama was born on the 17th.
What am I doing?
- Oh, come on, bet!
- Wherever you're going, I'm following.
No more bets.
Thank you.
- Here we go!
- Come on, come on.
Come on, please, 17. 17. 17.
17 black.
What?
Georgia!
Great. Now you change my luck
for the better?
You know what?
I'm not playing with you no more.
- Can I cash in my chips, please?
- Yes, I'd like to cash in mine, as well.
And me, too. Thank you.
Gosh, how much?
That's 3,546,305 crowns.
Wow.
- How much would you guess that is?
- That's about $100,000.
Wow!
Not very well-traveled.
Sales associate?
I wonder if your new friends would be
so impressed if they knew the truth.
Oh, mademoiselle...
You were incredible tonight.
You amazed us all.
And myself, too.
So, how is it the two of us never
bumped into each other back home?
Probably because you're not home
that much anymore.
Well, Washington
is a hard place to resist.
Come visit me sometime. You'll see.
I'm sorry,
but I just can't seem to get past...
that big flashing "for sale" sign
on your forehead.
- What are you talking about?
- You know what I'm talking about.
What are you doing here with Kragen?
I mean, what exactly is it
that you two do for each other?
I'm helping him over some regulatory
hurdles in committee, that's all.
Well, it seems like you should be
helping some of your own people...
over some hurdles.
I mean, precious little's happened...
with that Community Redevelopment
Program of yours.
And nothing ever will happen with
that youth center unless I get re-elected.
Having generous supporters
like Matthew Kragen is a political reality.
Yeah, well...
I'm sorry, but...
I only have time for reality realities.
Good night.
Good night, Georgia.
Mademoiselle Byrd, I hear you were
the highlight at the casino tonight.
- I don't know about that.
- But there's no need to be humble.
Did you have a marvelous time?
Why're you being so nice to me?
Yeah, I know. I'm a bitch.
At least that's what people tell me.
Oh, Miss Gunther...
no, you're not. You're just like
a lot of women who work too hard.
And yet you are always so kind.
You are a woman of distinction
and courage.
Yeah, apparently I am, all of a sudden.
Wish it had happened a little sooner.
Miss Gunther.
I hope you're not trying
to make a pass at me...
'cause I really can't handle that
right now.
Please don't die, Miss Byrd.
I read the note.
- You went through my stuff?
- Oh, yeah, I go through everyone's stuff.
I apologize.
Well, to tell you the truth,
I'm kind of relieved...
to have somebody to share it with.
Don't worry, I'll be with you here
to the very end.
I don't know if I want to be here
Why are you here
with these terrible people?
You should be with people you love.
Yeah, I've been thinking
about that myself.
One in particular.
It's time I go home and find him.
Thank you, God.
That's a lot of snow.
- What's going on here?
- It's an avalanche.
I'm sorry, but we'll have to go back.
I can't believe this happened
on New Year's Eve.
You're just not gonna cut me
any slack at all, are you?
You're telling me there's nothing else?
- I wanted you to find out everything...
- As I told you before, nothing.
- Nothing?
- Nothing out of the ordinary.
Except that she is a saint.
- And from New Orleans.
- Yes.
- And her occupation?
- You should know. She works for you.
- Now, please.
- Wait, wait, wait.
- She works for me?
- That's all I know and all I'm telling.
Here's your tip back.
At this rate,
we're going to be here all night.
Oh, no, we are not.
We are going back down the mountain.
I prefer to spend the night with my wife.
Hey, what are you doing?
- Are you crazy? It's dangerous.
- Yeah, I know.
But I don't have much time.
Keep the change.
Wish me luck.
I hate snow.
Snow sucks.
Cookware? Are you sure?
I heard you were a little shorthanded
because of this avalanche.
I just thought I'd check
to see if you needed any help.
But I don't want to get in your way
or nothing.
No, no, no, it would be an honor,
a privilege.
What is this?
It's a turnip.
No, it's not. That can't be no turnip.
The poor baby turnips.
Nobody likes them, you know?
Of course.
Life is easy if you are a truffle
or a shiitake mushroom.
But the turnip is to be loved...
because she's a self-made woman
of vegetables.
All the others you can only destroy
with cooking.
But the turnip, she gets better.
So, you see, it's not how you start...
but how you finish.
That's gonna be good!
The first time I saw you...
I was so happy
to see your appetite for food...
for life.
I'm so sorry.
Gunther.
Does anybody else know?
No.
Okay.
Well, good.
Let's not say anything, all right?
Let's just... Let's just cook.
The onions, they make me cry.
You have been very lucky.
Well, you didn't get everything
you wanted...
but you have...
Next time, we do things different.
We will laugh more, we'll love more.
We'll see the world.
We just won't be so afraid.
Happy New Year.
Look at you.
Now, see, look at these tumors.
Georgia Byrd, Mr. Smith, and mine.
Now there's no way,
even if we all had it...
that they would be
exactly in the same place.
So, I said to myself, "Rabindranath,
it has to be the machine."
Oh, my God.
Thanks. I'll see you.
Excuse me, young man,
do you live here?
Yeah, I live right here.
- Please tell me you know Georgia Byrd.
- Yeah, I know Georgia.
Thank you.
Tonight I'd like to make a toast...
to a woman whose presence
has captivated us.
To Georgia Byrd.
Well, hear, hear.
To Georgia.
Now, who is this fascinating woman?
It's the question
we've been asking ourselves all week.
Is she a representative
from a competing boardroom?
Is she a power broker from the corridors
of our nation's capital?
Is she a brash
and successful entrepreneur?
The truth, which I discovered tonight,
will amuse you.
You see, Georgia Byrd is a sales clerk...
in my New Orleans store.
In the cookware department, no less.
Salary? $29,000 a year.
Cheers, Georgia.
- What?
- No.
Or as we might say back home:
"Attention Kragen shoppers,
impostor, aisle three."
Oh, come on. Georgia, is this true?
Mr. Kragen is right about me.
I'm just a sales associate
in one of his stores.
One of the best.
Or I was up until a couple of weeks ago.
- That's when...
- You owe these people no explanation.
No, excuse me. I think she does.
She's had plenty to say
about our behavior all week...
and the only reason we took it was...
because we thought
she was somebody.
Well, I'm sorry.
I didn't come here to give anybody
the wrong impression about me.
I just came here to blow
every last cent of my money.
You see...
I'm gonna die.
- Georgia, please.
- Oh, it's okay, it's okay.
It's all right.
Yeah, see, I had that same reaction
when I found out...
I only had three weeks to live.
I mean, I tried to keep it to myself
for exactly this reason.
It's a party-killer, ain't it?
But I did land on that mountaintop.
And I ended up on the cover
of a ski magazine.
Don't feel sorry for me, baby.
Never in my life did I think...
I would end up
in such a beautiful place...
doing so many incredible things.
So...
I'm sorry if I was...
maybe a little too honest with you.
But I wasted too much of my life
being quiet.
I was afraid, I guess.
You know how it is.
You keep your head down
and you hustle and hustle.
Then you look up one day and wonder:
"How did I even get here?"
Huh, bro?
See, some of the things
we care about a lot are pretty worthless.
So...
I hope I haven't spoiled your evening.
And...
it's truly been my pleasure.
Happy New Year.
- Happy New Year, Georgia.
- Thank you.
Asshole.
That's a very appropriate sentiment,
darling.
I second that.
Happy New Year, Matthew.
Where are you going?
Well, first I'm gonna find Georgia.
And then I'm gonna go back to school...
and I'm going to get
my business degree.
And then one day, when your wife
finally decides to divorce you...
and takes half of everything you have...
I'll only be too happy to help her figure
out exactly how much that should be.
Marie, what are you doing?
Has that ceiling
ever made you want to cry?
What ceiling? Get back to work.
- Hey.
Georgia, I just wanted to say
how sorry I am that...
Girl, it's okay. I know you are.
I left Matthew.
I'm going to the airport now.
Oh, well, I don't know if they've cleared
the road yet to the airport.
- What do you mean?
- The avalanche and stuff.
Ms. Byrd,
something terrible has happened.
Matthew Kragen's
jumped out a window?
Pity, but not yet. He's still on the ledge.
- What?
- Come on.
I'll get my jacket.
What's going... Wait a minute.
Who? Hey, that's Kragen!
- What the hell is he doing?
- He does not take rejection well.
Matthew!
Matthew, what are you doing?
- What you doing?
- Thinking.
- About what?
- Not falling.
- Oh, no. What's she doing out there?
- Oh, my goodness.
This is crazy.
You don't have to be nice to me.
I know I'm a jerk.
You don't think I know I'm a jerk?
Oh, so, this is where jerks come
to hang out?
You're starting to get
a little crowd down there.
Happy New Year!
- Wave to the people.
- Happy New Year!
I can't believe this guy.
- They'd like me to jump.
- Well, don't start people-pleasing now.
Matthew. Come back in here.
You know you're not gonna jump.
You couldn't even jump off the dam.
Equipment failure.
- See? You know...
- Miss Burns, let me handle this, please.
Mr. Kragen, you know what?
You're really starting to piss me off.
- Give me that.
- No, no, no.
Oh, heads up!
Damn, that is a long drop.
Look, a guy like you has all the money
and time in the world...
to turn things around for himself,
you know?
So, just stop whining and get with it.
Get with what, exactly?
I don't know. I mean, I don't have...
Georgia Byrd's five rules
to how to be a better human being.
All I know is, if you want somebody
to care about you...
stop trying to buy and sell them
all the time.
Do I do that?
And you know what?
Get your pasty face off the cover
of your own magazine every month.
Yep, that's the face right there.
Every month!
I can't believe I had somebody like you
working for me all this time.
Well, I wasn't gonna work
for you forever.
I had plans, you know.
Yeah? What were you gonna do?
Well, nothing big by your standards.
But I was gonna open me up
a little restaurant.
Bistro style.
And, of course, a husband and a family.
Do you have a boyfriend?
Well, I wouldn't call him that.
He works for your company, too.
His name is Sean.
Georgia!
- It's starting to happen.
- What?
I mean, I can hear him
calling my name right now.
Well, someone actually
did call your name.
Georgia!
- Is that...
- Sean, what are you doing here?
Wait, I'm coming!
- You are here to see Miss Byrd?
- Yeah, how did you know?
Lucky guess.
Do you have the arrivals list
for tomorrow?
And where is everyone?
I don't have any help upstairs.
Yeah, I'll take care of this.
Georgia!
What the hell? I mean...
Come on.
How many people
can get on that ledge?
Who the hell is that?
Sean, what you doing here?
Well, I found out, you know,
about the Lampington's disease...
and, well, I up and quit my job.
Well, what would make you do
something like that?
I didn't feel like I had a future there.
Besides, after you quit...
I didn't feel like I had a reason
to be there.
It seemed like there should be
more possibilities in life.
Oh, no! You done up
and read my Possibilities book.
Well, what exactly
is a Possibilities book?
Georgia, I gotta talk to you.
Okay. Talk to me.
I can't do it now, here on a ledge!
Come on now, you're gonna have to.
I'm kind of in the middle
of something here.
Well, look, I...
Georgia, I had all kind of thoughts
running through my mind.
I should've told you this a long time ago.
I don't know what I thought or...
It doesn't even matter what I thought.
I have feelings for you.
Georgia Byrd, I want to be with you.
Whether if it's for five minutes
here on this ledge, or 50 years.
- I like this guy. Good guy.
- Me, too.
Oh, come on, knock it off.
Now, why you gonna send him
all the way around here...
when you know I gotta die?
- Who you talking to, baby?
- God.
Hello!
Oh, God.
- We're the only ones not up there.
- We should join them.
Urgent fax to Miss Georgia Byrd
from Dr. R. Gupta!
You were misdiagnosed
due to a faulty dog scan.
You don't have Lampington's disease.
You're going to live!
- I'm not gonna die?
- No!
- I'm gonna live?
- Yes!
I'm gonna live! I'm gonna live!
I'm going to live, everybody!
I hope that doesn't mean you want
to rethink that last statement.
About the five minutes or the 50 years,
and all that.
Oh, no.
Five minutes, 50 years, 100 years,
a million years...
my whole life!
All right!
- Can we get off this ledge now?
- Yeah.
It's colder than a snowman's ass
out here.
What do you say, Mr. Kragen?
You ready?
- You had enough of this?
- Yeah, go in inside.
- Yeah, it's time to get warm.
- Give me your hand. Careful, careful.
I want to tell you, thank you...
and I'm gonna make
a lot of changes in my life.
I'm gonna put somebody else
on the cover of the magazine, too.
You are funny.
You had me going for a minute.
You so wrong.
How you gonna do me like that?
Come on, baby. Come on.
Yeah, now we go.
Put them crawfish in there, baby.
How about a little taste? Smell.
Don't ask me. I'm only here on holiday.
Yeah, don't be careful now, huh?
Hey, it's getting crazy out there!
Everybody's arriving.
- Come on, baby, let's go.
- Go out and see to your friends.
And I'll take care of the rest.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Remember, it's not how you start,
it's how you finish.
Okay, all right.
Merci!
- Welcome. Welcome. Welcome.
- Thank you for coming.
- Thank you so much for coming.
- Welcome to Georgia's.
- My baby!
- Tough guy!
- Who's my little guy?
- Congratulations.
- Rochelle.
- Thank you. Thank you.
You did it!
- I quit my job.
- Thank you.
You did? Oh, congratulations.
- I quit my job!
- You should never have had that job.
- I'm so glad.
- Hi, I quit my job!
Hi, Mr. Mayor. Hi, Mrs. Dean.
How're you doing?
- Welcome.
- Come on in to Georgia's.
Good to see you.
Mrs. Dean, it's a pleasure.
Congratulations!
Thank you so much for inviting me.
- Thank you for coming!
- Thank you. Congratulations.
- She loves you.
- Congratulations.
Thanks for coming.
Pleasure.