I believe in America.
America has made my fortune
and I raised my daughter
in the American fashion.
I gave her freedom,
but I taught her
never to dishonor her family.
She found a boyfriend.
Not an Italian.
She went to the movies with him.
She stayed out late.
I didn't protest.
Two months ago,
he took her for a drive
with another boyfriend.
They made her drink whiskey,
and then they tried
to take advantage of her.
She resisted.
She kept her honor.
So they beat her like an animal.
When I went to the hospital,
her nose was broken...
her jaw was shattered...
held together by wire.
She couldn't even weep
because of the pain.
But I wept.
Why did I weep?
She was the light of my life.
Beautiful girl.
Now she will never
be beautiful again.
Sorry.
I, I went to the police,
like a good American.
These two boys
were brought to trial.
A judge sentence them
to three years in prison...
and suspend their sentence.
Suspended the sentence.
They went free that very day.
I stood in the courtroom
like a fool.
And those two bastard,
they smiled at me.
Then I said to my wife,
"For justice...
we must go to Don Corleone."
Why did you go to the police?
Why didn't you come to me first?
What do you want of me?
Tell me anything,
but do what I beg you to do.
What is that?
That I cannot do.
I'll give you anything you ask.
We've known each other many years,
but this is the first time...
you ever came to me
for counsel or for help.
I can't remember the last time
that you invited me...
to your house
for a cup of coffee...
even though my wife
is godmother to your only child.
But let's be frank.
You never wanted my friendship...
and you were afraid
to be in my debt.
I didn't want
to get into trouble.
I understand.
You found paradise in America.
You had a good trade,
you made a good living.
Police protected you,
and there were courts of law.
So you didn't need
a friend like me.
But, now you come to me
and you say,
"Don Corleone, give me justice."
But you don't ask with respect.
You don't offer friendship.
You don't even think
to call me 'Godfather.'
Instead, you come
into my house
on the day my daughter
is to be married
and you ask me to do murder
for money.
I ask you for justice.
That is not justice.
Your daughter is still alive.
They must suffer then
as she suffers.
How much shall I pay you?
Bonasera. Bonasera.
What have I ever done to make you
treat me so disrespectfully?
If you'd come to me
in friendship,
then the scum
that ruined your daughter
would be suffering
this very day.
And if, by chance,
an honest man like yourself
should make enemies,
then they would become
my enemies.
And then they would fear you.
Be my friend?
Godfather.
Good.
Someday, and that day
may never come...
I'll call upon you
to do a service for me.
But until that day...
accept this justice as a gift
on my daughter's wedding day.
- Grazie, Godfather.
- Prego
Give this to Clemenza.
I want reliable people,
people that aren't
going to be carried away.
I mean, we're not murderers,
in spite of what
this undertaker says.
- Where's Michael?
- What? Don't worry.
It's early. He'll be here.
We're not taking it.
We're not taking the picture
without Michael.
No picture now.
- What's the matter, Sonny?
- It's Michael.
Don Barzini.
Welcome to our house.
Hey, Paulie!
Let me have some wine.
Paulie! More wine.
Scusi, please.
You look terrif on the floor.
What are you,
a dance judge or something?
Go take a walk around
the neighborhood. Do your job.
Hey, Sandra, come on. Do me a favor.
Watch the kids.
- Don't let 'em run wild, all right?
- Well, you watch yourself, all right?
Twenty or thirty grand.
In small bills, cash.
In that little silk purse.
If this was
somebody else's wedding.
Hey, Paulie!
I got two gobbagool...
gabagol and a prosciutto.
Stupid jerk!
Hey, what's the matter?
- I have to go back to work.
- Oh, Tom.
It's part of the wedding.
No Sicilian can refuse any request
on his daughter's wedding day.
Don Corleone,
I am honored and grateful...
that you have invited me
to your home...
Get outta here.
This is a private party.
Go on.
What is it?
Hey, my sister's wedding.
Goddamn FBI
don't respect nothin'.
Hey, come here, come here.
Come here!
There.
But towards the end
he was paroled...
to help with
the American war effort.
For the last six months, he's been
working at my pastry shop.
Nazorine, my friend,
what can I do for you?
Now that the war is over...
this boy, Enzo, they want
to repatriate him back to Italy.
Godfather, I have a daughter.
See, she and Enzo...
You want Enzo to stay
in this country...
and you want your daughter
to be married.
You understand everything.
Mr. Hagen. Thank you.
And wait till you see
the beautiful wedding cake...
I made for your daughter.
Like this, with the bride
and the groom and...
- Who should I give this job to?
- Not to our paisan.
Give it to a Jew congressman
in another district.
Who else is on the list?
Hey, Michael.
How are you?
Hello.
He's not on the list,
but Luca Brasi wants to see you.
Is this...Is this necessary?
He didn't expect to be invited
to the wedding...
so he wanted to thank you.
All right.
Don Corleone,
I am honored and grateful...
that you have invited me
to your home...
on the wedding day
of your daughter.
And may their first child
be a masculine child.
- Don...
- Michael?
Don Corleone...
That man over there
is talking to himself.
See that scary guy over there?
He's a very scary guy.
Who is he?
What's his name?
His name is Luca Brasi...
and he helps my father out
sometimes.
Oh, Michael, wait a minute.
He's coming over here.
Mike!
Ho! Tom.
Heyyy!
You look terrific!
My brother Tom Hagen.
This is Kay Adams.
- How do you do?
- Nice to meet you.
Your father's
been asking for you.
- Very nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
I'll be there.
If he's your brother,
why does he have a different name?
Oh, uh, when my brother Sonny was a kid...
he found Tom Hagen in the street,
and he had no home.
And so my father took him in...
and he's been with us ever since.
He's a good lawyer.
Not a Sicilian, but...
I think he's gonna be consigliere.
- What's that?
- That's...
like a counselor, an advisor.
Very important to the family.
You like your lasagna?
Don Corleone,
I am honored and grateful...
that you have invited me
to your daughter's wedding...
on the day
of your daughter's wedding.
And I hope
that their first child...
be a masculine child.
I pledge my ever-ending loyalty.
For your daughter's
bridal purse.
Thank you, Luca,
my most valued friend.
Don Corleone,
I'm gonna leave you now...
because I know you are busy.
Thank you.
Senator Cauly apologized
for not coming personally...
but said you'd understand.
Also some of the judges.
They've all sent gifts.
What is that outside?
Johnny!
I love you.
Hey, Johnny, look over here!
He came all the way from California
to come to the wedding.
- I told you he was going to come.
- It's been two years.
- He's probably in trouble again.
- He's a good godson.
Sing a song.
Michael, you never told me
you knew Johnny Fontane.
- Sure. You wanna meet him?
- Huh? Oh, well, sure.
My father helped him
with his career.
- For my Connie.
- He did? How?
I have but one
- Let's listen to the song.
- No, Michael
Heart
This heart I bring you
I have but one heart
To share with you
I have but one dream
That I can cling to
You are the one dream
I pray comes true
Please, Michael. Tell me.
My darling, until I saw you
Well, when Johnny was first starting out...
he was signed to this
personal service contract...
with a big bandleader.
And as his career
got better and better...
he wanted to get out of it.
Now, Johnny is
my father's godson...
and my father went
to see this bandleader...
and he offered him
$10,000 to let Johnny go.
But the bandleader said no.
So the next day
my father went to see him...
only this time
with Luca Brasi.
And within an hour,
he signed a release...
for a certified check of $1,000.
How'd he do that?
My father made him an offer
he couldn't refuse.
What was that?
Luca Brasi
held a gun to his head...
and my father assured him
that either his brains...
or his signature
would be on the contract.
That's a true story.
That's my family, Kay.
It's not me.
Beautiful!
My godson comes all the way
from California.
Give him a glass of wine.
I'll take care of it.
I want you to find Santino.
Tell him to come to the office.
How are you, Fredo?
My brother Fredo.
This is Kay Adams.
- Hi.
- How ya doin'?
- This is my brother Mike.
- Are you having a good time?
Yeah.
This is your friend, huh?
I don't know what to do.
My voice is, is weak.
It's weak.
Anyway, if I had this part
in the picture, you know...
it puts me right back
up on top again.
But this, uh...
this man out there,
he won't give it to me.
- The head of the studio.
- What's his name?
Woltz. Woltz.
He won't give it to me...
and he says
there's no chance, no chance.
Sonny?
Sonny, you in there?
- What?
- The old man wants to see you.
All right, one minute.
A month ago, he bought
the movie rights to this book.
A best-seller.
And the main character
is a guy just like me.
Why, I wouldn't even
have to act.
Just be myself.
Oh, Godfather, I don't know what to do.
I don't know what to do.
You can act like a man!
What's the matter with you?
Is this how you turned out?
A Hollywood finocchio
that cries like a woman?
"What can I do?"
What is that nonsense?
Ridiculous!
- You spend time with your family?
- Sure I do.
Good.
Because the man who doesn't
spend time with his family...
can never be a real man.
Come here.
You look terrible.
I want you to eat.
I want you to rest well,
and a month from now...
this Hollywood big shot's
gonna give you what you want.
Too late.
They start shooting in a week.
I'm gonna make him an offer
he can't refuse.
Now just go outside,
enjoy yourself and...
forget about all this nonsense.
Listen. I want you
to leave it all to me.
All right.
What time does my daughter
leave with the bridegroom?
In a few minutes,
right after they cut the cake.
Now, your new son-in-law,
we give him something important.
Never.
Give him a living...
but never discuss
the family business with him.
What else?
Virgil Sollozzo called.
We have to give him a day
sometime next week.
We'll discuss him when you
come back from California.
When am I going to California?
I want you to go tonight.
I want you to talk
to this movie big shot...
and settle this business
for Johnny.
Now if there's nothing else, I'd like
to go to my daughter's wedding.
Carlo, we're gonna take
the picture.
Wait a minute.
No, Michael, not me.
Just a little closer.
Okay, that's it.
Just like that now. Hold it.
Isn't that nice?
All right, start talking.
I was sent by a friend
of Johnny Fontane.
This friend is my client and would
give his undying friendship...
to Mr. Woltz, if Mr. Woltz
would grant us a small favor.
Woltz is listening.
Give Johnny the part in that new
war film you're starting next week.
And what favor
would your friend...
grant Mr. Woltz?
You're gonna have
some union problems.
My client could make them disappear.
Also, one of your top stars
has just moved...
from marijuana to heroin.
- Are you trying to muscle me?
- Absolutely not.
Now listen to me,
you smooth-talking son of a bitch!
Let me lay it on the line for you
and your boss, whoever he is!
Johnny Fontane
will never get that movie.
I don't care
how many dago, guinea, wop...
greaseball goombahs
come outta the woodwork.
I'm German-Irish.
Well, let me tell you something,
my kraut mick friend.
I'm going to make so much trouble for you,
you won't know what hit you.
Mr. Woltz, I'm a lawyer.
I have not threatened...
I know almost every big lawyer
in New York. Who the hell are you?
I have a special practice.
I handle one client.
Now, you have my number.
I'll wait for your call.
By the way, I admire
your pictures very much.
Check him out.
- This is really beautiful.
- Look at this.
It used to decorate
the palace of a king.
Oh, yeah. Very nice.
Why didn't you say
you worked for Corleone, Tom?
I thought you were just
some cheap, two-bit hustler...
Johnny was running in,
trying to bluff me.
I don't like to use his name
unless it's really necessary.
- How's your drink, Tom?
- Fine.
Hey, come on over here with me. I want to
show you something really beautiful.
You do appreciate beauty,
don't you, Tom?
There you are.
$600,000 on four hooves.
I'll bet Russian czars...
never paid that kind of dough
for a single horse.
Khartoum.
I'm not gonna race him, though.
I'm gonna put him out to stud.
Beautiful.
- Thanks, Tony.
- You're welcome.
- Come on.
- Let's get something to eat.
Mr. Corleone
is Johnny's godfather.
To the Italian people,
that's a very religious...
sacred, close relationship.
I respect that.
Just tell him he should ask me
anything else.
But this is one favor
I can't give him.
He never asks a second favor
when he's been refused the first.
- Understood?
- You don't understand.
Johnny Fontane
never gets that movie.
That part is perfect for him.
It'll make him a big star.
I'm gonna run him
out of the business.
And let me tell you why.
Johnny Fontane ruined
one of Woltz International's...
most valuable protégés.
For five years,
we had her under training.
Singing lessons,
acting lessons, dancing lessons.
I spent hundreds of thousands
of dollars on her.
I was gonna make her a big star.
And let me be even more frank.
Just to show you that I'm not
a hard-hearted man...
that it's not all dollars and cents.
She was beautiful!
She was young, she was innocent!
She was the greatest piece of ass
I've ever had...
and I've had 'em all over the world!
And then Johnny Fontane comes along...
with his olive oil voice and guinea charm.
And she runs off.
She threw it all away
just to make me look ridiculous...
and a man in my position can't afford...
to be made to look ridiculous!
Now you get the hell outta here!
And if that goombah
tries any rough stuff...
you tell him I ain't no bandleader.
Yeah. I heard that story.
Thank you for the dinner
and a very pleasant evening.
If your car could take me
to the airport...
Mr. Corleone is a man who insists
on hearing bad news immediately.
- You're not too tired are you, Tom?
- No, I slept on the plane.
I have the Sollozzo notes here.
Now...
Sollozzo is known as "The Turk."
He's supposed to be
very good with a knife...
but only
in matters of business...
with some sort
of reasonable complaint.
His business is narcotics.
He has fields in Turkey
where they grow the poppy...
and in Sicily he has the plants
to process them into heroin.
Now, he needs cash and he needs
protection from the police...
for which he gives
a piece of the action.
I couldn't find out how much.
The Tattaglia family
is behind him here in New York.
Now, they have to be
in it for something.
Santino Corleone.
What about his prison record?
Two terms,
one in Italy, one here.
He's known as
a top narcotics man.
Santino, what do you think?
There's a lot of money
in that white powder.
Tom?
Well, I say, yes, there's more
money potential in narcotics...
than anything else
we're looking at.
Now, if we don't get into it,
somebody else will.
Maybe one of the five families,
maybe all of them.
Now, with the money they earn...
they can buy more police
and political power.
Then they come after us.
Now we have the unions,
we have the gambling...
and they're the best things
to have, but narcotics...
is a thing of the future.
Now, if we don't get
a piece of that action...
we risk everything we have.
I mean, not now,
but ten years from now.
So? What's your answer
gonna be, Pop?
I need a man
who has powerful friends.
I need a million dollars in cash.
I need, Don Corleone,
those politicians...
that you carry in your pocket
like so many nickels and dimes.
What is the interest
for my family?
Thirty percent.
In the first year, your end
should be three, four million dollars.
And then it would go up.
And what is the interest
for the Tattaglia family?
My compliments.
I'll take care of the Tattaglias.
Outta my share.
So, I receive 30%
for finance...
political influence
and legal protection.
- That's what you're telling me.
- That's right.
Why do you come to me?
Why do I deserve this generosity?
If you consider
a million dollars in cash...
just "finance"...
I salute you, Don Corleone.
I said that I would see you because...
I heard that you were
a serious man...
to be treated with respect.
But I must say no to you.
And I'll give you my reason.
It's true, I have
a lot of friends in politics.
But they wouldn't be friendly
very long...
if they knew my business was drugs
instead of gambling...
which they regard
as a harmless vice.
- But drugs is a dirty business.
- No, Don Corleone...
It doesn't make
any difference to me...
what a man does for a living,
you understand...
but your business is...
a little dangerous.
If you're worried about security
for your million...
the Tattaglias will guarantee it.
You're tellin' me the Tattaglias
guarantee our investment...
Wait a minute.
I have a sentimental weakness
for my children...
and I spoil them,
as you can see.
They talk when they should listen.
But anyway...
Signor Sollozzo,
my no is final...
and I wish to congratulate you
on your new business.
I know you'll do very well,
and good luck to you...
especially since your interests
don't conflict with mine.
Thank you.
Come here.
What's the matter with you?
I think your brain
is going soft...
from all that comedy you're
playing with that young girl.
Never tell anybody outside the
family what you're thinking again.
Go on.
Tom, what?
What is this nonsense?
It's from Johnny.
He's starring in that new film.
Well, take it away.
Take it over there.
And...
tell Luca Brasi to come in.
I'm a little worried
about this Sollozzo fellow.
I want you to find out what he's got
under his fingernails, you know?
Go to the Tattaglias...
and make them think...
that you're not too happy
with our family...
and find out what you can.
And I got something
for your mother and for Sonny...
and a tie for Freddy...
and Tom Hagen
got the Reynolds pen.
- What do you want for Christmas?
- Me?
Oh, just you.
Tell Paulie to get the car.
We're going.
Okay, Pa.
I'll have to get it myself, Pa.
Paulie called in sick this morning.
Paulie's a good kid.
I don't mind gettin' the car.
Luca, I'm Bruno Tattaglia.
I know.
Scotch? Prewar.
You know who I am?
Oh. Tom Hagen.
- Merry Christmas.
- Yeah.
I'm glad I run into you.
I wanna talk to you.
I haven't got time.
Oh, make time, consigliere.
Get in the car.
What are you worried about?
If I wanted to kill you,
you'd be dead already.
Get in.
Wait a moment, Fredo.
- I'm gonna buy some fruit.
- Okay, Pa.
Hi. Merry Christmas.
I want some fruit over there.
Gimme three of them.
No, that one.
Fredo!
Papa.
Papa!
Mike, would you like me better
if I were a nun...
like in the story, you know?
No.
Well, then would you like me better
if I were Ingrid Bergman?
Now that's a thought.
Michael.
No, I would not like you better
if you were Ingrid Bergman.
- Michael.
- What's the matter?
They don't say
if he's dead or alive.
Sonny, Michael.
Michael, where you been?
Is he all right?
We don't know yet.
There's all kinds of stories.
He was hit bad, Mikey.
- Are you there?
- Yeah, I'm here.
Where you been? I was worried.
Didn't Tom tell you?
I called.
No. Look, come home, kid.
You should be with Mama, you hear?
All right.
Oh, my God.
Who is it?
Open up. It's Clemenza.
What?
There's more news about your old man.
The word is out on the street
he's already dead.
Shut your mouth.
What's the matter with you?
Jesus Christ!
Take it easy. Take it easy.
- Where was Paulie?
- Paulie was out sick.
- He's been home sick all winter.
- How many times he been sick?
Only maybe three, four times.
I mean, I asked Freddy if he wants
a different bodyguard.
- He said no.
- Pick him up right now.
I don't care how sick he is.
If he's breathin', I want you to bring him to
my father's house now. You understand? Now
- You want me to send people here?
- No, just you and him. Go ahead.
All right.
I'm havin' a couple of our people come
over to the house. A couple of our people.
- Hello?
- Santino Corleone?
- Yeah.
- We have Tom Hagen.
In about three hours, he'll be
released with our proposition.
Listen to everything he has
to say before you do anything.
What's done is done.
And don't lose that famous temper
of yours, huh, Sonny?
No, I'll wait.
Your boss is dead.
I know you're not in the muscle
end of the family, Tom...
so I don't want you to be scared.
I want you
to help the Corleones...
and I want you to help me.
Yeah. We got him outside his office...
just about an hour after we picked you up.
Drink it.
So now it's up to you to make
the peace between me and Sonny.
Sonny was hot
for my deal, wasn't he?
And you knew it was
the right thing to do.
Sonny will come after you
with everything he's got.
That'll be his first reaction, sure.
That's why you gotta
talk some sense into him.
The Tattaglia family is behind me
with all their people.
The other New York families
will go along with anything...
that will prevent a full-scale war.
Let's face it, Tom,
in all due respect...
the Don, rest in peace, was slippin'.
Ten years ago,
could I have gotten to him?
Well, now he's dead.
He's dead, Tom,
and nothing can bring him back.
So you gotta talk to Sonny.
You gotta talk
to the caporegimes...
that Tessio, and that fat Clemenza.
It's good business, Tom.
I'll try.
But even Sonny won't be able
to call off Luca Brasi.
Yeah. Well...
Let me worry about Luca.
You just talk to Sonny.
And the other two kids.
I'll do my best.
Good.
Now, you can go.
I don't like violence, Tom.
I'm a businessman.
Blood is a big expense.
He's still alive.
They hit him with five shots,
and he's still alive!
Well, that's bad luck for me...
and bad luck for you
if you don't make that deal.
Your mother's over
in the hospital with your father.
Looks like he's gonna
pull through, thank God.
- That's a lot of bad blood.
- What do you think?
It's too far.
I think it's too personal.
- The Don will consider this over.
- You gonna kill all those guys?
- Hey, stay out of it, Mickey, do me a favor.
- Sollozzo's the key.
You get rid of him,
everything falls into line.
What about Luca? Sollozzo
didn't seem worried about Luca.
I don't know. If Luca sold out,
we're in a lot of trouble.
Has anyone been able
to get in touch with Luca?
We've been tryin' all night.
He might be shacked up.
Hey, Mick, try him again.
Luca never sleeps over
with a broad.
He always goes home
when he's through.
Well, Tom, you're consigliere.
What do we do
if the old man dies, God forbid?
If we lose the old man...
we lose our political contacts
and half our strength.
The other New York families might
wind up supporting Sollozzo...
just to avoid a long destructive war.
This is almost 1946.
Nobody wants bloodshed anymore.
If your father dies...
you'll make the deal, Sonny.
You know, that's easy for you to say,
Tom. He's not your father.
I was as much a son to him
as you or Mike.
What is it?
Hey, Paulie, I thought
I told you to stay put.
Well, the guy at the gates,
they say they got a package.
Yeah?
Tessio, go see what it is.
- You want me to hang around?
- Yeah, hang around.
- You all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Yeah? There's some food
in the icebox. You hungry or anything?
- No, it's all right. Thanks.
- How 'bout a drink? How 'bout a little brandy?
- That's good to sweat it out.
- All right, sure.
- Go ahead.
- That might be a good idea.
I want you to take care
of that son of a bitch right away.
Paulie sold out the old man, that strutz.
I don't wanna see him again. Make that
first thing on your list, understand?
Understood.
Hey, Mickey, tomorrow.
You get a couple of guys.
You go over to Luca's apartment. Hang
around. Wait for him to show up.
Maybe we shouldn't get Mike
mixed up in this too directly.
Yeah.
Listen, hang around the house
on the phone. It'll be a big help.
Try Luca again. Go ahead.
- What the hell is this?
- It's a Sicilian message.
It means Luca Brasi sleeps with the fishes.
- I'm goin' now.
- What time you gonna be home tonight?
I don't know. Probably late.
- Don't forget the cannoli.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Rocco, sit on the other side.
You block the rearview mirror.
That Sonny's runnin' wild.
He's thinkin' of goin'
to the mattresses already.
We gotta find a spot
over on the West Side.
We'll try 309 West 43rd Street.
You know any good spots
on the West Side?
- Yeah, I'll think about it.
- Well, think about it while you're drivin'.
I wanna hit New York sometime this month.
And watch out for the kids
when you're backin' out.
Hey, Paulie, I want you to go
down 39th Street. Colosanto's.
You pick up 18 mattresses for the guys
to sleep, will you? Bring me the bill.
- Yeah, all right.
- Make sure they're clean because...
Those guys are gonna be stuck up
in there for a long time, you know?
They're clean. They told me
they exterminate them.
"Exterminate"?
That's a bad word to use.
Exterminate. Get this guy.
See how we don't exterminate you.
- Youse funny, or what?
- Hey, Paulie. Did you fart?
- Yeah, Rocco, what'd you do?
- No, me. Nothin'. It wasn't me.
- It's gotta be him.
- Hey, pull over, will you.
I gotta take a leak.
Leave the gun.
Take the cannoli.
Hey, Mike?
Hey, Mikey?
Yeah?
You're wanted on the telephone.
- Who is it?
- It's some girl.
Hello, Kay?
How's your father?
He's good.
He's gonna make it.
I love you.
Huh?
I love you!
Michael?
Yeah, I know.
Tell me you love me.
Yeah, I can't talk.
Can't you say it?
Yeah, I'll see you tonight.
Hey, Mikey. Why don't you tell
that nice girl you love her?
I love you
with all o' my heart!
If I don't see you again a-soon,
I'm-a gonna die!
Come over here, kid.
Learn somethin'.
You never know. You might have to cook
for 20 guys someday.
You see? You start out
with a little bit of oil.
Then you fry some garlic.
Then you throw in some tomatoes,
some tomato paste.
You fry it.
You make sure it doesn't stick.
When you got it to a boil, you shove in
all your sausage and your meatballs.
Add a little bit of wine.
And a little bit of sugar.
- And that's my trick.
- Why don't you cut the crap?
I got more important things
for you to do.
- How's Paulie?
- Oh, Paulie. Won't see him no more.
- Where you going?
- To the city.
Send some bodyguards with him.
- No. I'm just going to the hospital to see Pop.
- Nevermind. Send somebody with him.
Oh, he'll be all right.
Sollozzo knows he's a civilian.
- All right. Be careful, huh?
- Yes, sir.
Send somebody with him anyway.
I have to go.
Can I go with you?
No, Kay. There's gonna be
detectives there.
People from the press.
Well, I'll ride in a cab.
I don't want you to get involved.
When will I see you again?
Go back to New Hampshire...
and I'll call you
at your parents' house.
When will I see you again,
Michael?
I don't know.
What are you doing here?
You're not supposed
to be here now.
I'm Michael Corleone.
This is my father.
There's nobody here.
What happened to the guards?
Your father just had
too many visitors.
They interfered
with hospital service.
The police made them leave
about ten minutes ago.
Get me Long Beach 4-5-6-2-0, please.
Nurse, wait a minute.
Stay here.
Sonny, Michael.
I'm at the hospital.
Listen. I got here late.
There's nobody here.
Nobody. No Tessio's men,
no detectives, nobody.
- Pop is all alone.
- Don't panic. We'll send somebody.
I won't panic.
I'm sorry, but you will
have to leave.
You and I are gonna move my father
to another room.
Now, can you disconnect those tubes
so we can move the bed out?
- That's out of the question.
- Do you know my father?
Men are coming here to kill him.
You understand?
Now, help me, please.
- Who are you?
- I am Enzo... the baker.
- You remember me?
- Enzo?
- Yes, Enzo.
- You better get out of here, Enzo.
There's gonna be trouble.
If there is trouble,
I stay here to help you...
For your father. For your father.
All right, listen.
Wait for me outside,
in front of the hospital.
All right? I'll be out
in a minute. Go ahead.
Okay, okay.
Just lie here, Pop.
I'll take care of you now.
I'm with you now.
I'm with you.
Get rid of these.
Come here.
Put your hand in your pocket
like you have a gun.
You'll be all right.
You'll be okay.
You did good.
Here he is.
All right, hold still.
I thought I got
all you guinea hoods locked up.
What the hell are you doing here?
What happened to the men who
were guarding my father, Captain?
Why, you little punk.
What the hell are you doing,
telling me my business?
I pulled them guys off of here.
Now, you get out of here
and stay away from this hospital.
I'm not moving until you put
some guards around my father's room.
Phil, take him in.
The kid's clean, Captain.
He's a war hero.
- He's never been busted...
- Goddamn it, I said take him in.
What's the Turk paying you
to set up my father, Captain?
Take a hold of him.
Stand him up.
Stand him up straight.
I'm the attorney
for the Corleone family.
These men are private detectives
hired to protect Vito Corleone.
They're licensed to carry firearms.
If you interfere, you'll have to
appear before a judge...
in the morning and show cause.
All right, let him go.
Come on.
What's with all the new faces?
Gonna need 'em now.
After the hospital thing,
Sonny got mad.
We hit Bruno Tattaglia
at 4:00 this morning.
Jesus Christ.
Looks like a fortress around here.
A hundred button men on the street,
24 hours a day.
That Turk shows one hair
on his ass, he's dead. Believe me.
Hey, Mike, come here.
Let me look at you.
You look beautiful.
Just beautiful.
You're gorgeous.
Hey, listen to this.
The Turk, he wants to talk.
Imagine the nerve
on this son of a bitch.
Craps out last night,
he wants a meeting today.
- What'd he say?
- What did he say?
He wants us to send Michael
to hear the proposition.
And the promise is that the deal
is so good that we can't refuse.
What about Bruno Tattaglia?
That's part of the deal.
Bruno cancels out what they did
to my father.
Sonny, we ought to hear
what they have to say.
No. No. No. No more.
Not this time, Consigliere.
No more meetings, no more discussions,
no more Sollozzo tricks.
You give them one message...
I want Sollozzo.
If not, it's all-out war.
We go to the mattresses.
Some of the other families
won't sit still for a war.
- Then they hand me Sollozzo.
- Your father wouldn't hear this.
- This is business, not personal.
- They shot my father.
Even shooting your father
was business, not personal, Sonny.
Well, then business will have to suffer.
All right?
And do me a favor, Tom...
No more advice on how
to patch things up.
Just help me win, please.
All right?
I found out about this Captain McCluskey
who broke Mike's jaw.
What about him?
Now he's definitely on Sollozzo's
payroll, and for big money.
McCluskey has agreed
to be the Turk's bodyguard.
What you have to understand,
Sonny...
is that while Sollozzo's
being guarded like this...
he is invulnerable.
Nobody has ever gunned down
a New York police captain. Never.
It would be disastrous. All the
five families would come after you, Sonny.
The Corleone family
would be outcast.
Even the old man's political
protection would run for cover.
So do me a favor.
Take this into consideration.
All right, we'll wait.
We can't wait.
Can't wait.
I don't care what Sollozzo says
about a deal.
He's gonna kill Pop.
That's it.
That's the key for him.
Got to get Sollozzo.
CLEMENZA: Mike is right.
Let me ask you something first.
What about this McCluskey?
What do we do with this cop here?
They want to have a meeting
with me, right?
It will be me...
McCluskey and Sollozzo.
Let's set the meeting.
Get our informers to find out
where it's going to be held.
Now we insist it's a public place...
a bar, a restaurant.
Someplace where there's people,
so I feel safe.
They're gonna search me
when I first meet them, right?
So I can't have a weapon on me then.
But if Clemenza can figure a way...
to have a weapon
planted there for me...
then I'll kill them both.
What are you gonna do?
Nice college boy, huh?
Didn't want to get mixed up
in the family business.
Now you want to gun down
a police captain?
Why? 'Cause he slapped you
in the face a little bit?
What do you think this is, the army,
where you shoot them a mile away?
You gotta get up close,
like this and...
You blow their brains all over your
nice Ivy League suit. Come here.
You're taking this very personal.
Tom, this is business, and this man
is taking it very, very personal.
Where does it say that
you can't kill a cop?
- Come on, Mikey.
- Tom, wait a minute.
I'm talking about a cop
that's mixed up in drugs.
I'm talking about a dishonest cop,
a crooked cop...
who got mixed up in the rackets
and got what was coming to him.
That's a terrific story.
Now we have newspaper people
on the payroll, don't we, Tom?
They might like a story like that.
They might.
They just might.
It's not personal, Sonny.
It's strictly business.
It's as cold as they come.
Impossible to trace, so you don't
worry about prints, Mike.
I put a special tape
on the trigger and the butt.
Here. Try it.
What's the matter,
the trigger too tight?
- My ears.
- I left it noisy.
That way it scares pain-in-the-ass
innocent bystanders away.
All right, you shot them both.
Now what do you do?
Sit down, finish my dinner.
Come on, kid.
Don't fool around.
Just let your hand drop to your side
and let the gun slip out.
Everybody will still think
you got it.
They're gonna be staring
at your face, Mike...
so walk out of the place real fast,
but you don't run.
Don't look nobody directly in the
eye, but you don't look away, either.
Hey, they're gonna be scared stiff
of you, believe me...
so don't worry about nothing.
You know, you're gonna turn out all right.
You take a long vacation,
nobody knows where...
and we're gonna catch the hell.
How bad do you think
it's gonna be?
Pretty goddamn bad.
Probably all the other families
will line up against us.
That's all right. These things
gotta happen every five years or so.
Ten years.
Helps to get rid of the bad blood.
Been ten years since
the last one.
You know, you gotta stop them
at the beginning...
like they should have
stopped Hitler at Munich.
They should have never let him
get away with that.
They was just asking
for big trouble.
You know, Mike,
we was all proud of you...
being a hero and all.
Your father too.
Nothing.
Not a hint.
Absolutely nothing.
Even Sollozzo's people don't know
where the meeting's going to be held.
How much time do we have?
Gonna pick you up in front
of Jack Dempsey's joint...
in an hour and a half...
exactly an hour and a half.
We could put a tail on them,
see how it turns out.
Sollozzo'll lose our ass
going around the block.
What about the negotiator?
He's over at my place playing
pinochle with a couple of my men.
He's happy.
They're letting him win.
It's too much of a risk for Mike.
Maybe we ought to call it off, Sonny.
The negotiator keeps on playing cards
until Mike comes back safe and sound.
So why don't they just blast who's ever
in the goddamn car?
Too dangerous.
They'll be looking for that.
Sollozzo might not
even be in the car, Sonny.
I get it.
Yeah.
- Louis Restaurant in the Bronx.
- Well is it reliable?
That's my man in McCluskey's precinct.
A police captain's got to be
on call 24 hours a day.
He signed out at that number
between 8:00 and 10:00.
Anybody know this joint?
Yeah, sure. I do.
It's perfect for us.
A small family place, good food.
Everyone minds his business.
It's perfect.
Pete, they got
an old-fashioned toilet...
You know, the box
and the chain thing.
We might be able
to tape the gun behind it.
All right.
Mike, you go to the restaurant.
You eat, you talk for a while,
you relax.
You make them relax.
Then you get up
and go take a leak.
No, better still,
you ask for permission to go.
And when you come back,
you come out blasting.
And don't take any chances.
Two shots in the head apiece.
Now, listen.
I want somebody good...
and I mean very good...
to plant that gun.
I don't want my brother coming out of that
toilet with just his dick in his hands, all right?
The gun will be there.
All right, listen. You drive him
and you pick him up after the job.
Come on. Let's move.
Thank you, Tom.
Did he tell you
to drop the gun right away?
Yeah, a million times.
Now, you don't forget...
two shots apiece in the head...
as soon as you
come out the door.
Let's go.
How long do you think it'll be
before I can come back?
At least a year, Mike.
Listen, I'll square it with Mom, you know,
you not seeing her before you leave...
and I'll get a message
to that girlfriend...
when I think the time is right.
Take care.
- See you, Mike.
- Okay, Tom.
I'm glad you came, Mike.
I hope we can
straighten everything out.
I mean, this is terrible. It's not the way
I wanted things to go at all.
It should have never happened.
I want to straighten
everything out tonight.
I don't want my father
bothered anymore.
He won't be, Mike.
I swear on my children he won't be.
But you got to keep an open mind
when we talk.
I mean, I hope you're not a hot-head
like your brother Sonny.
You can't talk business
with him.
He's a good kid.
I'm sorry about
the other night, Mike.
I gotta frisk you,
so turn around, huh?
On your knees, facing me.
I guess I'm getting
too old for my job.
Too grouchy.
Can't stand the aggravation.
You know how it is.
He's clean.
We're going to Jersey?
Maybe.
Nice work, Lou.
How's the Italian food
in this restaurant?
Good.
Try the veal.
- It's the best in the city.
- I'll have it.
Understand?
I'm gonna speak Italian to Mike.
Go ahead.
- I'm sorry.
- Forget about it.
What happened to
your father was business.
I have much respect for your father...
but your father's thinking
is old fashioned.
You must understand why
I did what I did.
I understand these things.
I do.
You do.
Now we have to think about what happens
between you and the Tattaglias.
We have to work through
where we go from here.
How do I say...?
What I want...
what's most important to me...
is that I have a guarantee:
no more attempts
on my father's life.
What guarantees could I give you, Mike?
I am the hunted one.
I missed my chance.
You think too much of me, kid.
I'm not that clever.
All I want is a truce.
I have to go to the bathroom.
Is that all right?
You gotta go, you gotta go.
I frisked him.
He's clean.
Don't take too long.
I've frisked a thousand young punks.
Everything all right?
I respect myself - understand?
and so I cannot allow your
father to hold me back.
What happened was unavoidable.
I had the unspoken support of
the other Dons.
If your father were in better health...
without his eldest son running things...
Hey, come on.
Come on. Let's go.
Joe, you take over.
Hi, Grandpa.
I love you, Grandpa.
I'm sorry, Pa.
He doesn't know you yet.
- Here you are, big guy. Give it to Grandpa.
- Okay.
"I hope you get red, Grandpa...
and I wish
I would see you soon.
Love, your grandson, Frank."
Go with your mother.
Go ahead.
Take 'em downstairs.
Go on, Carlo. You too.
Go on.
I got chicken cacciatore
for you, sweetheart.
- That's enough bread.
- I like bread.
I know, but how much can you eat?
What's the matter with you, Carlo?
Shut up and set the table.
Since McCluskey's killing...
the police have been cracking down
most of our operations.
And also the other families'.
Been a lot of bad blood.
They hit us, so we hit them back.
Through our contacts
in the newspapers...
we've been able to put out
a lot of material...
about McCluskey being linked
with Sollozzo in the drug rackets.
See, things are
starting to loosen up.
Dad, I'm sending Fredo
to Las Vegas...
under the protection
of Don Francesco of L.A.
I want him to rest.
I'm going to learn
the casino business.
Yeah.
Where is Michael?
It was Michael who killed Sollozzo.
But he's safe. We're starting
to work to bring him back now.
I want you to find out where that
little pimp Tattaglia is hiding.
I want his ass now...
right now.
- Hey, Sonny.
- What?
Things are starting to loosen up
a little bit.
If you go after Tattaglia,
all hell's going to break loose.
Let the smoke clear.
Pop can negotiate.
No, Pop can't do nothing till
he's better. I'm gonna decide what...
All right, but your war's
costing us a lot of money.
Nothing's coming in.
We can't do business.
Well neither can they.
Don't worry about it.
- We can't afford a stalemate.
- Well, then there ain't no more stalemate.
I'm gonna end it
by killing that old bastard.
You're getting a great reputation.
I hope you're enjoying it.
Well you just do what I tell you to do!
Goddamn it, if I had a wartime
consigliere, a Sicilian,
I wouldn't be in this shape!
Pop had Genco. Look what I got.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean that.
Mom made a little dinner.
It's Sunday.
Them niggers are having
a good time...
with our policy banks
up there in Harlem.
Driving them new Cadillacs,
paying 50% on a bet.
I knew that was gonna happen as soon
as they started making big money.
Look, Papa never talked business
at the table in front of the kids.
- Hey, shut up, Connie.
- Don't you ever tell her to shut up.
- You got that?
- Santino, don't interfere.
You know, Sonny, Tom, I'd like to talk
to you, maybe after dinner.
I could be doing a lot more
for the family.
We don't discuss business
at the table.
Michael
Corleone.
Look there. Corleone.
Hey, American!
Take me to the America! G.I.!
Hey, hey, hey!
Take me to America, G.I.
Clark Gable.
America! America!
Take me to the America, G.I.
Clark Gable.
Rita Hayworth.
Hey, host.
A bottle of wine.
I apologize if I offended you.
I'm a stranger in this country...
and I meant no disrespect
to you or your daughter.
I'm an American hiding in Sicily.
My name is Michael Corleone.
There are people who would pay
a lot of money for that information.
But then your daughter
would lose a father...
instead of gaining a husband.
I want to meet your daughter...
with your permission...
and under the supervision
of your family...
with all respect.
Apollonia.
...this is my daughter, Apollonia...
and this is Michael Corleone.
Thank you.
Your welcome.
What's the problem with your eye.
No, no. It's nothing. It's fine.
Hey! I'm gonna knock you dizzy.
Save it for the library.
Come on. We gotta go
pick up my sister. Let's go.
What's the matter?
- It was my fault!
- Where is he?
Sonny, please. It was my fault.
Sonny, it was my fault. I hit him.
I started a fight with him.
Please, Sonny.
I'm sorry.
Okay, I'm just...I'm just gonna get a doctor
to come and take a look at you.
Sonny, please don't do anything.
Please, don't do it.
What's the matter with you?
What am I gonna do?
Am I gonna make that baby an orphan
before he's born?
All right?
Still betting the Yankees
pretty heavy?
Tell him to stop
taking action, all right?
You lost enough money
last weekend to me.
Carlo, come here.
You touch my sister again,
I'll kill you.
Weren't expecting you, Kay.
You should call.
Yes, well, I have.
I mean I've tried writing and calling.
Now, I wanna reach Michael.
Nobody knows where he is. We know
that he's all right, but that's all.
- What was that?
- That's an accident.
But nobody was hurt.
Tom...
Would you give this letter
to Michael, please? Please?
Well, if I accepted that...
in a court of law they could prove that
I have knowledge of his whereabouts.
Now you just be patient, Kay.
He'll get in touch with you, all right?
I let my cab go, so can I come in
to call another one, please?
Come on. I'm sorry.
Come on.
Hello?
Is Carlo there?
- Who's this?
- This is a friend of Carlo's.
Would you tell him that
I can't make it tonight until later?
Bitch.
- Dinner's on the table.
- I'm not hungry yet.
Your food is on the table.
It's getting cold.
- I'll eat out later.
- You just told me to make you dinner.
Hey, fuck you, eh?
Go fuck yourself!
This little guinea brat.
That's it. Break it all,
you spoiled guinea brat.
Break it all!
That's it. Break it all.
Why don't you bring
your whore home for dinner?
Maybe I will.
Why not?
- Now clean it up!
- Like hell I will!
Clean it up,
you guinea spoiled brat!
Clean it up!
You son of a bitch!
Come on, now! Kill me!
Be a murderer like your father!
- Come on! All you Corleones are murderers!
- I hate you!
- Come on!
- I'll kill you!
Kill me!
Get up!
Get out of here!
- I hate you!
- Now go ahead. Now I'll kill you.
You guinea brat, you.
Get out here!
Connie, what's the matter?
I can't hear you. What is it?
Honey, talk louder.
The baby's crying.
Santino, I can't understand.
I don't know.
I don't understand.
Yeah, Connie.
Listen, you wait there.
No, you just wait there.
- That son of a bitch.
- Sonny, what's the matter?
- Son of a bitch!
- What's the matter?
Damn it!
Open the goddamn gate.
Get off your ass.
- Sonny, come on!
- Get out of here!
Go after him.
Go on.
Son of a bitch.
Come on! Come on!
Give me a drop.
My wife is crying upstairs.
I hear cars coming to the house.
Consigliere of mine...
I think you should tell your Don
what everyone seems to know.
Well, I didn't tell Mama anything.
I was about to come up and wake you
just now and tell you.
But you needed a drink first.
Now you've had your drink.
They shot Sonny on the causeway.
He's dead.
I want all inquiries made.
I want no acts of vengeance.
I want you to arrange a meeting...
with the heads
of the five families.
This war stops now.
Call Bonasera.
We need him now.
This is Tom Hagen
calling for Vito Corleone...
at his request.
Now, you owe your Don a service.
He has no doubt that
you will repay it.
Now, he will be at your
funeral parlor in one hour.
Be there to greet him.
Well, my friend...
are you ready
to do me this service?
Yes.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to use
all your powers...
and all your skills.
I don't want his mother
to see him this way.
Look how they massacred my boy.
Monday, Tuesday, Thursday...
Wednesday, Friday,
Sunday, Saturday.
- Fabrizio.
- Yes, sir?
Are you driving yourself, boss?
- Yes.
- Is your wife coming with you?
No. I want you to take her to her father's
house till I know things are safe.
Okay. Anything you say, boss.
Don Barzini,
I want to thank you...
for helping me organize
this meeting here today.
And also the other heads
of the five families...
from New York and New Jersey.
Carmine Cuneo from the Bronx.
From Brooklyn...
Philip Tattaglia.
And from Staten Island...
we have with us Victor Strachi.
And all the other associates
that came as far...
as from California
and Kansas City...
and all the other territories
of the country.
Thank you.
How did things ever get so far?
I don't know.
It was so unfortunate
and so unnecessary.
Tattaglia lost a son...
and I lost a son.
We're quits,
and if Tattaglia agrees...
then I'm willing to let things
go on the way they were before.
We are all grateful to Don Corleone
for calling this meeting.
We all know him
as a man of his word.
A modest man.
He'll always listen to reason.
Yes, Don Barzini.
He's too modest.
He had all the judges
and politicians in his pocket.
He refused to share them.
When did I ever refuse
an accommodation?
All of you know me here.
When did I ever refuse,
except one time?
And why?
Because I believe
this drug business...
is going to destroy us
in the years to come.
I mean, it's not like gambling
or liquor or even women...
which is something that
most people want nowadays...
and is forbidden to them by
the pezzonovante of the church.
Even the police departments
that have helped us in the past...
with gambling and other things...
are gonna refuse to help us
when it comes to narcotics.
And I believed that then...
and I believe that now.
Times have changed.
It's not like the old days...
when we could do
anything we want.
A refusal is not the act of a friend.
If Don Corleone had all the judges
and the politicians in New York...
then he must share them
or let others use them.
He must let us draw
the water from the well.
Certainly, he can present a bill
for such services.
After all, we are not Communists.
I also don't believe in drugs.
For years,
I paid my people extra...
so they wouldn't do
that kind of business.
Somebody comes to them and says,
"I have powders.
If you put up a three, four
thousand dollar investment,
we can make 50,000 distributing."
So they can't resist. I want
to control it as a business...
to keep it respectable.
I don't want it near schools.
I don't want it sold to children.
That's an infamia.
In my city, we would keep the traffic
in the dark people, the colored.
They're animals anyway,
so let them lose their souls.
I hoped that we could come here
and reason together.
And as a reasonable man, I'm willing
to do whatever's necessary...
to find a peaceful solution
to these problems.
Then we are agreed.
The traffic in drugs
will be permitted, but controlled.
And Don Corleone will give our
protection in the east...
and there will be the peace.
But I must have strict assurance
from Corleone.
As time goes by and
his position becomes stronger...
will he attempt
any individual vendetta?
Look, we are all
reasonable men here.
We don't have to give assurances
as if we were lawyers.
You talk about vengeance.
Is vengeance gonna bring
your son back to you?
Or my boy to me?
I forego the vengeance of my son.
But I have selfish reasons.
My youngest son...
was forced to leave this country...
because of this Sollozzo business.
All right.
And I have to make arrangements...
to bring him back here safely,
cleared of all these false charges.
But I'm a superstitious man.
And if some unlucky accident
should befall him...
if he should get shot
in the head by a police officer...
or if he should hang himself
in his jail cell...
of if he's struck
by a bolt of lightening...
then I'm going to blame
some of the people in this room.
And that I do not forgive.
But that aside...
let me say that I swear...
on the souls of my grandchildren...
that I will not be the one to break
the peace we've made here today.
When I meet with the Tattaglia
people, should I insist...
that all these drug middlemen
have clean records?
Mention it.
Don't insist.
Barzini is a man who'll know that
without being told.
You mean Tattaglia.
Tattaglia's a pimp.
He never could've outfought Santino.
But I didn't know until this day
that it was...
Barzini all along.
Come on, Nancy.
Keep together, everyone.
Brian?
Okay. All right.
How long have you been back?
I've been back a year.
Longer than that, I think.
It's good to see you, Kay.
Hi, Miss Adams!
I'm working for my father now, Kay.
He's been sick.
Very sick.
But you're not like him, Michael.
I thought you weren't going
to become a man like your father.
That's what you told me.
My father's no different
than any other powerful man.
Any man who's responsible
for other people.
Like a senator or a president.
- Do you know how naive you sound?
- Why?
Senators and presidents
don't have men killed.
Oh.
Who's being naive, Kay?
Kay, my father's way
of doing things is over.
It's finished.
Even he knows that.
I mean, in five years
the Corleone family...
is going to be completely legitimate.
Trust me. That's all I can tell you
about my business.
Kay.
Michael, why did you come here?
Why?
What do you want with me
after all this time...
without even calling or writing?
I came here because I need you.
- Because I care for you.
- Please stop it, Michael.
Because I want you to marry me.
- It's too late. It's too late.
- Please. Kay.
I'll do anything you ask, anything to
make up for what's happened to us.
Because that's important, Kay.
Because what's important is that...
we have each other.
That we have a life together.
That we have children.
Our children.
Kay...
I need you...
and I love you.
Barzini's people
chisel my territory...
and we do nothing about it.
Pretty soon, there won't be one place
in Brooklyn I can hang my hat.
- Just be patient.
- I'm not askin' you for help, Mike.
- Just take off the handcuffs.
- Be patient.
We gotta protect ourselves.
Give me a chance to recruit
some new men.
No.
I don't wanna give Barzini
an excuse to start fighting.
Mike, you're wrong.
Don Corleone, you once said
that the day would come...
when Tessio and me
could form our own family.
Till today,
I would never think of it.
I must ask your permission.
Well, Michael is now
head of the family...
and if he gives his permission,
then you have my blessing.
After we make the move to Nevada...
you can break off from the Corleone
family and go on your own.
- After we make the move to Nevada.
- How long will that be?
Six months.
Forgive me, Godfather,
but with you gone...
me and Pete'll come under
Barzini's thumb sooner or later.
And I hate that goddamn Barzini.
In six months' time, there won't be
nothing left to build on.
- You have faith in my judgment?
- Yes.
- Do I have your loyalty?
- Yes, always, Godfather.
Then be a friend to Michael...
and do as he says.
There are things being negotiated
now that are going to solve...
all your problems
and answer all your questions.
That's all I can tell you now.
Carlo, you grew up in Nevada.
When we make our move there,
you're gonna be my right-hand man.
Tom Hagen's no longer consigliere.
He's gonna be our lawyer in Vegas.
That's no reflection on Tom,
but that's the way I want it.
Besides, if I ever need help...
who's a better consigliere
than my father?
Now that's it.
- Thank you, Papa.
- I'm happy for you, Carlo.
Mike, ehh...
Why am I out?
You're not a wartime consigliere, Tom.
Things may get rough
with the move we're trying.
Tom...
I advised Michael.
I never thought
you were a bad consigliere.
I thought Santino was a bad Don...
rest in peace.
Michael has all my confidence,
as, as you do.
But there are reasons why
you must have no part...
in what is going to happen.
Maybe I could help.
You're out, Tom.
I can't get over the way
your face looks.
It really looks good.
This doctor did some job.
Who talked you into it, Kay?
Hey, hey, wait.
Leave them out here.
We'll deal with them later.
He's tired.
He wants to clean up.
For right now, let me open the door.
All right?
Hello, Mike.
Welcome to Las Vegas.
All for you, kid.
It was all his idea, right?
- Well, your brother, Freddy...
- It was... Girls?
I'll be right back.
You keep them occupied.
That a boy.
Anything you want, kid, anything. Huh?
Who are the girls?
That's for you to find out.
Get rid of them, Fredo.
- Hey, Mike...
- Fredo, I'm here on business.
I leave tomorrow.
Now, get rid of them. I'm tired.
Get rid of the band too.
Hey, just take off.
Come on. Let's go.
Hey, that's it.
Hey, Angelo, that's it.
Let's go.
Hey, come on!
Scram!
Come on, honey. Let's go.
I don't know, Johnny.
I don't know what the hell's
the matter with him. I'm sorry.
It's all right, Freddy.
I don't know.
He's tired, he's hot.
What happened to Moe Greene?
He said he had some business.
He said give him a call...
when the party started.
Well, give him a call.
- Johnny, how are you?
- Hello, Mike. Nice to see you again.
- We're all proud of you.
- Thanks, Mike.
Sit down, Johnny.
I want to talk to you.
- The Don's proud of you, too, Johnny.
- Well, I, owe it all to him.
Well, he knows
how grateful you are.
That's why he'd like to ask
a favor of you.
Mike, what can I do?
The Corleone family is thinking
of giving up all its interests...
in the olive oil business,
settling out here.
Now, Moe Greene will sell us his
share of the casino and the hotel...
so it can be completely owned
by the family. Tom?
Hey, Mike, are you sure about that?
Moe loves the business. He never
said nothin' to me about sellin'.
Well, I'll make him an offer
he can't refuse.
See, Johnny...
see, we figure that entertainment
will be a big factor...
in drawing gamblers to the casino.
Now we hope you'll sign a contract
to appear five times a year.
Perhaps convince some of
your friends in the movies...
to do the same.
We're counting on you.
Sure, Mike.
I'll do anything for my godfather.
You know that.
Good.
Hey, Mike.
Hello, fellas.
Everybody's here. Freddy, Tom.
Good to see you, Mike.
- How are you, Moe?
- You got everything you want?
The chef cooked for you special, the
dancers will kick your tongue out...
and your credit is good.
Draw chips for everybody in the room
so they can play on the house.
My credit good enough
to buy you out?
Buy me out?
The casino. The hotel.
The Corleone family
wants to buy you out.
wants to buy me out?
No, I buy you out.
You don't buy me out.
Your casino loses money.
Maybe we can do better.
You think I'm skimming
off the top, Mike?
You're unlucky.
You goddamn guineas
really make me laugh.
I do you a favor and take Freddy in
when you're having a bad time.
- And then you try to push me out!
- Wait a minute.
You took Freddy in because
the Corleone family...
bankrolled your casino,
because the Molinari family...
on the coast guaranteed his safety.
Now, we're talkin' business.
Let's talk business.
Yeah, let's talk business, Mike.
First of all, you're all done.
The Corleone family don't even have
that kind of muscle anymore.
The Godfather's sick, right? You're
getting chased out of New York...
by Barzini and the other families.
What do you think is going on here? You think
you can come to my hotel and take over?
I talked to Barzini.
I can make a deal with him
and still keep my hotel.
Is that why you slapped
my brother around in public?
Oh, no, that was nothin', Mike.
Now, now, Moe didn't mean nothin' by that.
Sure he flies off the handle
once in a while...
but Moe and me,
we're good friends, right, Moe, huh?
I got a business to run.
I gotta kick asses sometimes
to make it run right.
We had a little argument, Freddy and I,
so I had to straighten him out.
You straightened my brother out?
He was banging cocktail waitresses
two at a time!
Players couldn't get a drink at the table.
What's wrong with you?
I leave for New York tomorrow.
Think about a price.
Son of a bitch.
Do you know who I am?
I'm Moe Greene.
I made my bones when you were
going out with cheerleaders.
Wait a minute, Moe.
Moe, I got an idea.
Tom, you're the consigliere.
Now, you can talk to the Don.
- You can explain...
- Just a minute.
The Don is semiretired and Mike is
in charge of the family business now.
If you have anything to say,
say it to Michael.
Mike! You don't come to Las Vegas
and talk to a man like Moe Greene like that!
Fredo. You're my older brother,
and I love you.
But don't ever take sides
with anyone...
against the family again...
ever.
I have to see my father
and his people.
- So have dinner without me.
- Oh, Michael.
This weekend we'll go out.
We'll go to the city.
We'll see a show and we'll have dinner.
I promise.
Oh, Michael. Michael, your sister wants
to ask you something.
- Well, let her ask.
- No, she's afraid to.
Connie and Carlo want you to be
godfather to their little boy.
- Oh, we'll see.
- Will you?
Let me think about it. We'll see.
Come on.
So...
Barzini will move against you first.
He'll set up a meeting with
someone that you absolutely trust...
guaranteeing your safety.
And at that meeting,
you'll be assassinated.
I like to drink wine
more than I used to.
Anyway, I'm drinking more.
It's good for you, Pop.
I don't know.
Your wife and children,
are you happy with them?
Very happy.
That's good.
I hope you don't mind
the way I...
I keep going over
this Barzini business.
No, not at all.
It's an old habit.
I spent my life
tryin' not to be careless.
Women and children can be careless,
but not men.
- How's your boy?
- He's good.
You know, he looks
more like you every day.
He's smarter than I am.
Three years old,
he can read the funny papers.
Reads the funny papers.
I want you to arrange
to have a telephone man...
check all the calls that go
in and out of here.
- I did it already, Pop.
- Could be anyone.
- Pop, I took care of that.
- Oh, that's right. I forgot.
What's the matter?
What's bothering you?
I'll handle it.
I told you I can handle it,
I knew that Santino was gonna
have to go through all this...
and Fredo...
Well...
Fredo was...
But I never, I never wanted this for you.
I worked my whole life...
I don't apologize...
to take care of my family...
and I refused to be a fool...
dancing on a string
held by all those big shots.
I don't apologize. That's my life.
But I thought that...
that when it was your time...
that you would be the one
to hold the strings.
Senator Corleone.
Governor Corleone.
Something.
Another pezzonovante.
Just wasn't enough time, Michael.
Wasn't enough time.
We'll get there, Pop.
We'll get there.
Now listen. Whoever comes to you
with this Barzini meeting...
he's the traitor.
Don't forget that.
Put it over the tree.
- Can I water these?
- Yeah.
That's fine.
Over here.
Be careful.
You're spilling it.
Anthony, come here.
Go ahead. That's right.
We'll put it right there.
I'll show you something.
Come here.
Now, you stand there.
Give me an orange!
That's a new trick.
You run in there.
Run in there.
- Where are you?
- Who?
Ouch!
Mike, can I have a minute?
Barzini wants to arrange a meeting.
He says we can straighten
any of our problems out.
- You talked to him?
- Yeah.
I can arrange security...
on my territory.
All right?
- All right.
Do you know how
they're gonna come at you?
They're arranging a meeting
in Brooklyn.
Tessio's ground...
where I'll be safe.
I always thought it would've been
Clemenza, not Tessio.
It's the smart move.
Tessio was always smarter.
But I'm gonna wait.
After the baptism.
I've decided to be godfather
to Connie's baby.
And then I'll meet
with Don Barzini...
and Tattaglia...
all the heads
of the five families.
Go forth from him, unclean spirit,
and give place to the Holy Spirit,
the Spirit of God.
Let us pray.
Our prayers through through
Christ our Lord. So be it.
Michael.
Signed with the sign of the Lord's cross,
so that, preserving this first experience
of the greatness of thy glory,
he may deserve, by keeping
thy commandments,
to attain to the glory of regeneration.
Through Christ our Lord. So be it.
Let us pray.
Almighty, everlasting God,
Father of our Lord Jesus Christ,
look graciously down upon this,
thy servant, Michael.
Who shall come to judge the living
and the dead,
and the world by fire. So be it.
Michael. Receive the salt of wisdom.
Let it be to thee a token of mercy
unto everlasting life.
May it make your way easy to eternal life.
So be it.
May the almighty God, the Father
of our Lord Jesus Christ,
Who hath regenerated thee by water
and the Holy Spirit,
and who hath given thee the
remission of all thy sins,
may he, himself anoint thee with
the Chrism of Salvation,
in the same Christ Jesus our Lord,
unto life eternal. So be it.
I annoint you with the oil of salvation
in Christ Jesus our Lord,
that you may have everlasting life.
So be it.
Do you believe in the Holy Ghost,
the Holy Catholic Church,
the communion of Saints,
the forgiveness of sins,
the resurrection of the body
and life everlasting? I do believe.
I exorcise thee, unclean spirit,
in the name of the Father,
and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit,
that thou goest out and depart from
this servant of God, Michael.
For he commands thee, accursed one,
Be opened, for an odor of sweetness.
Be thou, devil, begone,
for the judgement of God shall draw near.
Michael, do you believe in God,
the Father almighty...
- creator of Heaven and Earth?
- I do.
Do you believe in Jesus Christ,
his only Son, our Lord?
I do.
Do you believe in the Holy Ghost,
the Holy Catholic Church?
I do.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread.
And forgive us our trespasses,
as we forgive them that
trespass against us.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
So be it.
Michael.
Enter thou into the temple of God,
that thou mayest have part with Christ
unto life everlasting. So be it.
I believe in God the Father almighty,
Creator of heaven and earth,
and in Jesus Christ his only
son our Lord,
who was conceived by the Holy Ghost,
born of the Virgin Mary,
suffered under Pontius Pilate,
was crucified, dead, and buried.
He descended into Hell.
On the third day,
He rose again from the dead.
He ascended into heaven,
and sitteth at the right hand of
God the Father almighty,
from thence shall he come to judge
the living and the dead.
I believe in the Holy Ghost,
the Holy Catholic Church,
the communion of saints,
the forgiveness of sins,
the resurrection of the body,
and life everlasting. So be it.
Michael Francis Rizzi,
do you renounce Satan?
I do renounce him.
And all his works?
I do renounce them.
- And all his pomps?
- I do renounce them.
Michael Rizzi,
will you be baptized?
I will.
in the name of the Father,
and of the Son,
and of the Holy Spirit.
Michael Rizzi, go in peace.
And may the Lord be with you.
So be it.
- Carlo.
- What?
Can't go to Vegas.
Something's come up.
Everybody's gonna have to leave
without us.
- It's our first vacation together.
- Connie, please.
- What do you wanna do?
- Go back to the house.
Wait for my call.
It's important.
I'll only be a couple of days.
Have a nice trip, Mama.
We're on our way to Brooklyn.
I hope Mike can get us
a good deal tonight.
I'm sure he will.
Sal, Tom, the boss says
he'll come in a separate car.
He says for you two
to go on ahead.
Hell, he can't do that.
It screws up all my arrangements.
- Well that's what he said.
- I can't go either, Sal.
Tell Mike it was only business.
I always liked him.
- He understands that.
- Excuse me, Sal.
Tom, can you get me off the hook?
- For old times' sake.
- Can't do it, Sally.
You have to answer
for Santino, Carlo.
Mike, you got it all wrong.
You fingered Sonny
for the Barzini people.
That little farce you played
with my sister.
Did you think that could fool
a Corleone?
Mike, I'm innocent.
I swear on the kids.
- Please, don't do this to me.
- Sit down.
Don't do this to me, please.
Barzini's dead.
So is Phillip Tattaglia...
Moe Greene...
Stracci...
Cuneo.
Today I settle all family business,
so don't tell me you're innocent, Carlo.
Admit what you did.
Get him a drink.
Come on.
Don't be afraid, Carlo.
Come on. You think I'd make my sister
a widow?
I'm godfather to your son, Carlo.
Go ahead, drink.
Drink.
Now, Carlo, you're out
of the family business.
That's your punishment.
You're finished.
I'm putting you on a plane to Vegas.
I want you to stay there.
Understand?
Only don't tell me
you're innocent...
because it insults my intelligence.
It makes me very angry.
Now, who approached you?
Tattaglia or Barzini?
It was Barzini.
Good.
There's a car waiting for you
outside to take you to the airport.
I'll call your wife,
tell her what flight you're on.
- Please, can I...
- Get out of my sight.
Hello, Carlo.
Will you stop crying?
What are you trying to tell me?
- I'm trying to tell you you're wrong.
- Mama, please!
Michael! Michael!
Where is he?
Michael, you lousy bastard!
You killed my husband!
You waited until Papa died
so nobody could stop you...
and then you killed him!
You blamed him for Sonny.
You always did. Everybody did.
But you never thought about me!
You never gave a damn about me!
Now what am I gonna do?
Why do you think
he kept Carlo at the mall?
All the time he knew
he was gonna kill him.
And you stood godfather
to our baby.
You lousy, coldhearted bastard.
Want to know how many men
he had killed with Carlo?
Read the papers!
That's your husband!
Take her upstairs.
- Get her a doctor.
- Oh, God!
She's hysterical.
Hysterical.
Michael, is it true?
Don't ask me about my business, Kay.
- Is it true?
- Don't ask me about my business.
- No.
- Enough!
All right.
This one time.
This one time, I'll let you
ask me about my affairs.
Is it true?
Is it?
No.
I guess we both need a drink, huh?
Come on.
Don Corleone.