Sir, I have a missile fire order
from the Antarctic Network.
Why the Antarctic Network?
I'm not going to annihilate
4.3 million Pakistanis
without hearing from someone
whose authority I recognize.
I got a fix on
the boat who shot us, sir.
It's the "Illinois."
Our own people
tried to sink us?
The "Colorado"
has its own magnetic signature,
which turns a $4-billion sub
into a sitting duck.
Except now with the prototype
I've put on board--
no signature.
We have commandeered
the NATO early warning station
on the island of Sainte Marina.
I am declaring
a 200-mile no-man's-land
around this island.
Sam? Sam, is that you?
It's me. I'm okay.
Listen to me, I don't know
what you've heard,
but I can explain it all.
Just please believe in me.
On your knees!
I'm not gonna let you do this.
What the hell did you just do?
If the current
United States executive
violates this perimeter,
we will all burn together.
You've been warned.
Hey, dad. So this will be
the last of these for a while.
We're headed out tomorrow.
I'm excited.
We're ready.
Captain's on the conn.
Status?
Heading 0-7-0 to a depth
of 200 feet, sir.
Very well. Sonar?
The "Princeton"
and the "Monterey"
have reached the perimeter.
I'm tracking 16 other
signatures, all closing on us.
Well, people, we are now
the popular girl at the dance.
Lieutenant Shepard,
what do you see?
We're reading
some 20 other warships
closing in
on the 200-mile line,
most should arrive
within the next 48 hours.
We're preparing to test
the prototype.
Keep those eyes on us.
Sophie, should we
be helping these people?
You have to decide that
for yourself.
I won't be a part of it.
Engineering, conn.
Stand ready to engage
the Perseus prototype.
Aye-aye, sir.
The prototype is tied in to
every major system on the sub.
It goes down, we're done.
And with respect, sir,
we should be on the phone with
DC sorting through this mess
before it can't be sorted out.
Attention, all hands.
This is your Captain.
There are some 20-plus warships
descending on us.
These are our brothers in arms,
sent now to kill us.
There will be a time to talk,
but right now we show strength.
Captain, out.
Engineering, conn.
Engage the Perseus.
Aye, sir.
SSTD is still online, sir.
You just vanished
off our screen, sir.
Looks like the prototype works.
They're hunting for us.
Sir, something patrolling low
right outside the perimeter.
ID off those screws,
it's the "Illinois."
She's dipping back and forth
across the line.
She's testing the fence.
We don't make that line
real to them,
sooner or later,
she'll cross over to kill us.
Man battle stations.
134 on board the "Illinois,"
sir.
Helm, put us on intercept
with the "Illinois."
Captain,
they've just disappeared.
Looks like Marcus
has a new toy.
Listen carefully.
Launch transients dead astern!
Evasive maneuver--
right full rudder.
Launch countermeasures now!
Too late. Torpedo is homing.
Impact in five, four...
Three, two...
Disabled warhead's a hit, sir.
"Illinois" turning away.
She's rolling over,
showing us her belly.
But she'll still bite
if she gets the chance.
Weapons, conn.
The next torpedo's armed.
Keep your lock.
Nav...
Take us back.
Yes, sir.
Do you see?
The devastation could have been
so much--
"Could have"?
That's gotta be maybe 200 miles
off the coast.
That's further than Vegas was
to the Nevada test range.
And they set off
a couple hundred nukes there.
Your husband
and all the men and women
following Marcus Chaplin
will die
if we can't end this now.
Now Sam is out there alone.
He's confused.
He probably wants,
more than anything,
just to do the right thing.
Then help him.
Sitrep, Lieutenant.
We've
manned stations and patrols,
but about a quarter of the crew
aren't reporting for shifts.
Cortez and Brannan
are still missing
and assumed AWOL.
Cortez is third tour.
She's not AWOL.
We gotta start looking for 'em.
And, sir, the COB--
he's under guard in what
the town uses as a jail,
and he is not making things
any easier.
Sailor, open the gate.
Tell her we ain't home, Red.
Sailor, I just gave you
a direct order.
Sorry, ma'am.
I don't have the key.
You know, Grace,
when they find you guilty
of mutiny, of murder,
it's not gonna be the jail cell
that gets to you.
It's gonna be the sound
of the people outside
chanting for your death.
That's what's gonna
drive you insane...
Break it down.
And knowing
that your admiral daddy
is not gonna be able
to visit your grave.
I said, break it down. Now.
Lieutenant.
Open it up.
She should've never been wearing
those stripes to begin with.
But you put her there,
and she killed one of my men.
You have everything
you need, COB?
I never would've believed that
my friend and commanding officer
would go soft when it
came time to do his duty.
Oh, I know my duty.
Do you?
Your duty, sir, is to fire
when you're told to fire.
Your duty, sir, is to be
the strong
and unwavering fist
of our nation.
Why'd they send the orders
through the Antarctic channel?
Why would they fire on us?
I'm a sailor.
I don't have the luxury to ask.
No, you don't,
which is why you're the COB,
and I'm the Captain.
You're my friend, Marcus.
But you're no longer
the captain of my boat.
That uniform
you're still wearing?
That's borrowed glory.
I've always appreciated
your candor, COB.
Lock it up, sailor.
You all right, Lieutenant?
Not really.
XO, you're gonna
have to relieve me.
I'm sorry, but I'm not setting
an example for the enlisted.
And it's not their fault.
It's me.
I don't know who I am here.
Well, then figure it out.
Look, we lose control here,
we're all dead.
You get that?
I can't fix this for you,
but I do need you.
They don't believe in you?
You make them, today.
That's closer
than 200 miles.
Aircraft crossed the perimeter
15 seconds ago.
Whatever it is, it's big.
Working the ident.
Open hatches. Make sure
the world can see it.
"Eisenhower" is scrambling F-18s
to intercept, sir.
They're asking if they can cross
our line to turn her around.
ID the bird, now.
Wait.
Pilot of Taiwan air 29-76,
turn around. Do you hear me?
It's a passenger 747.
How close do you think it got?
I don't know.
Maybe 40 miles.
A Delta Force Team could
HALO down from that plane,
hit the water on the far side,
paddle in.
They could be here
six hours after that.
They didn't waste any time.
I'll go.
I'll take a team,
try and cut 'em off.
- Sam, if those are Deltas--
- I know.
If they don't think we made 'em,
maybe we get the upper hand.
You stay here.
You do what you can.
I'll go.
Show strength.
Then talk.
If you're right,
you'll need a second out there
you can trust.
Volunteering
for the mission, sir.
Hangover cure.
Drink it.
There's another at the bar.
I thought
you special forces hot shots
could handle your liquor.
Do you have a boat,
some way off the island?
There are boats, but--
Get yourself off this rock.
This whole place just became
the biggest bull's-eye
on the planet.
I'm sorry.
It's just...
This whole island is a volcano.
The stories we heard as kids,
they were about lands plucked
from the bottom of the ocean
by a giant fish hook
or tossed down from the sky
by angry gods.
Telling an islander
they're going to die violently
is just reminding us
we're home.
Shower's $10.
Didn't ask.
You will.
Gentlemen.
You saw that plane?
Yeah.
I'd say you got yourself
a bad case
of between seven and ten
special forces.
Almost certainly Delta.
So you think they'll move
for us
or for the sub first?
My captain seems to think
you might be of some help
coming up with a plan here.
A plan?
Yeah, a plan.
You're not coming up
with a plan.
What you're working on is just
a really complicated suicide.
Okay, let me get
one thing straight.
I'm only here because
my captain asked me to be.
'Cause me? I'd rather
beat my own brains out
than have you help me
with anything.
So do me a favor.
Why don't you stay here
and drink yourself more stupid,
if that's humanly possible?
Thanks for your help.
Oh, Whoo! That is good.
13 of our sailors are about
to face off with something
they don't understand--
Do you want to know what's
the really great thing
about a perfect HALO jump?
It's that, before the jump,
you're still stateside
in your head--
rent, ex-girlfriends,
car payment, whatever.
That free fall--
it cleans you right out.
By the time you rip your chute,
everything's gone.
And what's left
is a single-minded focus
to accomplish the mission,
which in this case would be
killing you and your pals.
Look, the least you could
do is tell--
If I had to choose sides,
I'd be out there with them.
So this?
This is the very least
I can do.
Hi.
So we think there
might be some soldiers
coming over the island.
Since you know this place
better than anyone,
I was hoping to get your help.
You know,
I don't really think you get
what's going on here, do you?
Oh, I do.
I understand that millions
of people died yesterday.
But do you understand?
No, you can't.
Because you're a soldier.
You're made to believe
such things are normal.
Have you even looked at the TV?
Have you seen the faces--
Hey, we're the ones that
didn't fire. Do you get that?
Do you get it?
Me and my captain, we didn't
fire nukes at Pakistan.
You know what the prize is
for being such stand-up guys?
Men come to kill us and kill
anyone that gets in their way.
And right now
our only advantage is surprise.
And I'm here
asking for your help.
XO, a call's come in for you.
I thought the phones were dead.
So did we.
You should take this.
Hello.
Hey, babe.
I've been trying to
reach you again. Are you okay?
I know. I know.
Things have been
pretty crazy here.
And I bet for you, too,
right?
Christine, talk to me.
Are you okay?
Sam, they'll give you
full amnesty...
You and the crew.
All you have to do
is give them the sub.
And you have to
give them Marcus.
They're ready to let you
come back to me.
Sam...
Don't trust them.
Whatever they say to you,
whatever I say to you,
don't trust it!
Just know that I love you, Sam!
I love you!
We knew this wouldn't
just be bullets.
They'll come at you
where it hurts the most.
You okay?
We'll get inland and we'll
set up a kill zone.
Maybe they walk right into it.
Worst-case scenario,
they get wise, they kill us all.
Best-case scenario,
we send a complement
of American body bags home.
Either way, this sucks.
The siege of Grozny in '94.
2,000 Russians died
fighting their own.
In the aftermath,
generals resigned,
others were tried.
But for days, they fought,
brother killing brother
by the thousands
in the freezing cold.
And you have to
ask yourself why.
Sometimes the enemy
is just the man
keeping you from getting home.
A symbol of the Cold War,
the Ohio class submarine
is one of 18 in its class
designed to run silent and deep
and then deliver deathly...
20 bucks says we take this guy
out within 24 hours.
Cruise missile. Who's in?
Hey, brain surgeon.
The "Colorado" can launch
its remaining 17 nukes
in under five minutes.
Your cruise missile
is a slow weapon.
Takes maybe 20 minutes.
ICBM's faster, but you gotta
launch it up and down.
That takes time.
And you better be 100% sure
you kill her,
'cause Chaplin's got eyes now.
And once the "Colorado's"
tridents are airborne,
there is not a thing
in this world that stops them
'cause somebody kept my daddy
from building star wars
20 years ago.
So tell me exactly how you would
take out that submarine?
Linus.
What is my favorite
deep cover mole
in the Defense Department
drinking this evening?
- For God sake, Kylie.
- Oh, relax.
I could give you a lap dance
right here
and no one would notice today.
I would.
So what's your news?
Your Perseus prototype?
Chaplin went ahead and tested it
this morning, on his own.
The "Colorado" dropped
right off everyone's screens.
Kylie, it works.
Waiter, champagne. Right away.
We're celebrating.
No, no, no, no.
You don't understand.
They will
take it away from you.
They will go patriot act,
they will go National Security,
and they will
take it away from you.
And there's nothing
you can do about it.
Chaplin said it was
actually the "Illinois"
that tried to sink
the "Colorado."
Chaplin's insane.
Really? 24 hours ago,
you would've said
he was the paragon of virtue
and patriotism.
Now someone ordered
the "Illinois" to fire.
Somewhere that was recorded,
and if you're right
and they're trying
to take my tech,
than that order is
my get-out-of-jail-free card.
I need you to get that for me.
Are you not hearing me?
I can't help you anymore.
What was the name of that
brunette at your bachelor party?
God, she was hot.
Like,
make-me-want-to-switch-hit hot,
wasn't she?
Was it Carole?
Oh, no. No, no.
That's your wife's name.
I thought we were friends.
We are friends.
But you're a friend I pay
a lot of money to.
Linus, go find me that order.
Good-bye, dad.
I bet this isn't how you saw
your weekend going.
My weekends are not as boring
as you imagine.
Yeah. Well, it isn't
how I saw mine.
I was there.
If you hadn't killed that man,
we'd all be dead.
You didn't have a choice.
It doesn't matter now, does it?
Shepard killed one of us.
Sometimes in battle,
these things have a way
of working themselves out.
Sorry, Cam,
you're too important up there.
With all due respect, sir.
If this doesn't work,
there will be no "up there."
Full complement
ready to go, sir.
Good.
Careful out there.
Don't get a sunburn.
You don't need this
or this or this.
Hey.
This will get you shot
while you're busy
trying to unstrap it.
You got
your rig strapped right.
Doesn't mean you're ready
for what's out there.
There is a place they will
have to go through to get here.
I'll show you where.
That's all.
Aiding and abetting
a terrorist enterprise,
aiding and abetting
known terrorists,
sedition, treason,
aiding and abetting
an attack on the homeland--
and this isn't
just your husband.
After that stunt,
this is now you as well.
Read between the lines.
You think you know him?
You don't.
You just know the easy parts,
the parts he wanted you to see.
I know Sam better than anyone.
You sure?
I'm not gonna talk about that.
I told you I'm not gonna
talk about it
so we're not talking about it.
What is this?
There were 18 of you
taken prisoner.
When was this taken?
What is this?
Seven men under your command
didn't survive.
What the hell is going on?
That has to weigh on you.
I was surprised you showed.
So am I.
These men
you're ready to fight,
they might as well
be your brothers.
Hey, you know, I get it.
You don't like killing,
you don't like war,
you want us
to all just get along.
That's what anybody thinks
that's never had their back
up against a wall.
Who do you think I am?
I've seen what your wars do.
And there's always
some other way.
Yeah,
I used to think that, too.
I was wrong.
What happened
to change your mind?
Thank you for showing us
this spot.
You should go now.
Ma'am.
Can you check my weapon for me?
I want to make sure it's ready.
Thank you, ma'am.
I feel much safer now.
You just let them go off alone.
Ahh.
It's not my business.
Here on Sainte Marina,
sometimes a family
breaks apart--
a marriage goes bad,
a debt goes unpaid,
a small war starts.
Don't worry. I'm not gonna
break out the patchouli.
But here when this happens,
a man is selected and marked
to make the peace.
The marks are an honor.
Do you deserve them?
It would be 3:00 or 4:00
in the morning
when they would come.
They'd drag us
out of our cells.
They would march us out
into the yard.
Together?
Mnh-mnh. Alone.
There would be a table
and gun. One bullet.
They'd make you load the gun.
They'd spin the chamber
and put the gun to your head.
Click.
That sound...
Your husband was a captive
of the Democratic People's
Republic of North Korea
for over 17 days.
No, that's not possible.
Marcus Chaplin
went off the reservation
to force his release.
Put his career on the line.
Sam just tell you that was
a regular deployment?
Why does a man lie to his wife?
I don't know.
Well, Marcus had him
lying to you,
to everyone.
And if he's capable of that,
what else could Marcus
get him to do?
You think that's the only lie
your husband ever told you?
I don't know, okay?
Why don't you tell me? Because I
don't know what this is.
I lost seven of my men.
You want their names?
Look, it happened. I'm over it.
Could we move on, please?
That's your husband...
learning to lie.
Deputy Secretary
of Defense Curry,
it's good to talk to you again.
It's Secretary now, Captain.
Well, I'm glad the last 24 hours
has been good to someone.
You know, we have a lot
of frightened people here.
You have a team of Delta
on my island.
I want them gone. Now.
We got about 1.6 billion muslims
deeply pissed at us.
We're trying to de-escalate
this situation,
not make it worse.
There are no Delta
on your island. Over.
So who can shoot?
I mean actually hit something.
I suppose I can.
Okay.
Ah, hell.
Guess I can, too.
Good.
When this starts,
they're either gonna fall back
or try to make it to cover.
You do not let them.
You got it?
Good.
XO,
we're all set up here.
How long do you think we have?
Probably an hour
or more, but be ready.
Must feel weird,
killing one of your own,
especially like this, without
them knowing it's coming.
Hey, Hawkes,
we're gonna need
every gun we have.
So if you're gonna shoot me
in the back,
maybe you could wait
until we're done here.
We've got
the whole thing ranged.
If they come, we'll take 'em.
Good.
XO...
You gonna get married
someday, Lieutenant?
'Cause these men are coming,
and only one of you
gets to have a future.
I plan on being
at that wedding.
I'll make sure
and invite you, sir.
Go, quick. Go.
Captain, they're here.
If we're gonna find another way
out of this, it's gotta be now.
You're on your own
for now, Sam.
I can't help you yet.
Secretary Curry,
tell me again how you have
nothing on my island.
Tell me how I'm imaging
my XO is going up against
an armed contingent.
And if I think you're lying
to me, then I'm gonna have to
- leave this in the hands of a
higher power. - Excuse me, sir.
Wh-what do you want me
to say, Marcus?
Yes, we sent Delta?
No, we didn't send Delta?
Does it really matter
what I say?
Hold your fire.
Sir?
I have the shot.
I'm coming out to talk!
I am unarmed!
I repeat, I am unarmed!
I'm coming out to talk!
Do not fire!
Sir...
What are you doing?
We got you ranged
from both sides.
You are in a kill zone.
I just want to talk.
We are all Americans.
At least some of you
gotta be wondering
what you're doing here.
Hell. I don't even know
what I'm doing here.
There it is again.
They're essentially
beaming it through the water
from their base to the team
and then using
an ultra-low frequency.
Who is beaming it
through the water?
They are.
All I know is,
none of us has to die today.
Sam, they're not Deltas.
They're Russian Spetsnaz.
Sam, do you read?
Ah, hell.
Three went back!
Two forward!
We got two but--
Grace, they flanked us to
the top of the hill you're on.
You gotta get up there.
We're already on our way.
But we're pinned down, Sam.
There is no way up.
We're not gonna survive
like this, Lieutenant.
I need you to take
that position out.
Do you hear me?
Hawkes.
Hawkes, we need cover.
No!
Turn that down, sailor.
Sir?
You heard me.
Turn it down.
Marcus Chaplin.
This is an unexpected honor.
Viktor, you have a team
of Spetsnaz on my island,
dropped off the back
of a Taiwanese 747.
You're running support off
a Ukrainian container ship
50 miles beyond my perimeter.
And it might not be
your mission, Viktor.
But someone in the Kremlin is
making a play for my submarine.
No one would want to attack.
I'll sink the ship, Viktor.
And then I'll target
the Sevastopol base
where your two sons
are stationed
and I'll turn it to glass.
Grace,
I need to know right now,
can you take care
of that position or not?!
I'm sorry, Sam.
I'm sorry.
Russians are signaling,
they want to talk.
Get Curry back on the line.
Let him hear everything,
but mute that son of a bitch.
Marcus,
many people are asleep here.
It's not easy.
That's okay, Viktor.
I've got all the time
in the world.
Radio's dead.
Everybody listen up.
On my go, you're gonna
get to the truck
and get the hell out of here.
One of you guys go down,
you just keep moving.
On my go.
Red. Red.
We're gonna do this.
Do you hear me?
It's not more than 25 yards.
Do you understand me?
I can't. I can't.
I'm sorry. I can't.
Viktor,
what is that kid's name...
on your boat back in the day?
The one who got so freaked out
under the ice.
You and I called off
the Cold War for an hour
so you could get him topside.
That's called trust.
Ah, Nikolai.
Admiral's son.
Marcus,
just between two old warriors,
let's say for argument's sake
we had our people there.
Maybe you could surrender
your submarine.
Maybe then nobody
would have to be hurt.
Viktor! This is
Secretary of Defense Curry.
You put a play in motion?
This is our conflict.
Unless you want to start
World War III,
you pull those men back now.
And I thought you were
a man of your word.
I didn't give you
my word, Viktor.
But I'll let you work out
the ramifications
of trying to steal a U.S. sub
with SecDef Curry.
I did the math.
We dated two years.
Married one.
Mm-hmm.
Yet, we have actually
only spent 124 days together.
You did the math?
Who are you, Sam Kendal?
We're gonna be okay.
What do you want?
I just want you.
XO.
XO!
You don't have to do this.
Go, go, go, go!
Don't die. Not today.
Don't die.
Yeah!
XO, are you there?
XO.
Remaining Russians
have bugged out.
We lost five.
Grace is wounded.
But she's gonna be okay.
We have two prisoners.
We're coming home.
Probably a waste of time.
You really think you can break
that kind of devotion?
Well, she's got faith.
She's in love.
But both those things
are curable.
Then cure her.
Okay, I'm here with her now.
All right.
Christine...
My name is Paul Wells.
We've been trying to find you.
Do you remember me?
You're Sam's friend.
Yes. Yes, from college.
Look, I'm a lawyer, okay?
The government has...
radically exceeded
its authority here.
But that all stops now.
Come on.
Let me take you home.
All right, lock 'em up.
Oh, hell, no.
They killed five of us, man.
Yeah, five.
Five of our friends,
five of our people.
These guys get wasted.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Put your weapon down right now!
Red, that is an order!
Put it down!
An order? We're on
a damn island, not a sub.
So excuse me
if I'm not even sure
what an order means anymore!
I know you didn't ask for this.
I know you're all scared
and you're wondering
what we're doing here
and how you're gonna
get back home.
And now you've lost friends
and you have bloodlust
in your hearts.
Vengeance might give you
some satisfaction,
but let me remind you
who you are.
You are the American crew
of the Ohio class ballistic
missile submarine "Colorado."
Your rank is what
it says on your collar.
You salute the sailor
above you...
and you expect the same
of the one below.
And your final duty
is to say "how high?"
When I say "jump."
Are we clear?
- Yes, sir.
Are we clear?!
Yes, sir.
Now as Americans,
there's no debate about
the fate of our POWs.
Lieutenant Shepard,
secure the prisoners.
I know what you did.
Try it again.
I'll still be here.
Marcus!
Tell them what you told me
when we were still pals.
Tell them that your son
got killed by friendly fire
two weeks ago in Afghanistan.
Go on.
These young people
have followed you into a hell
they'll never be able
to climb back out of.
For what?
Because you wanted payback
on the country
that took your son
away from you?!
Tell 'em the truth, Marcus!
Tell them what they're really
fighting for!
You know me, Joe.
All of you...
you know me.
One more for me.
One more for the lady
with the, uh, face.
You think I came to thank you?
We lost people.
I thought you might want
to know their names.
I got my own list
a lot longer than that.
One of these days,
you're gonna have to decide
what you believe in.
Ahh.
What did it feel like?
It's a hell of a buzz,
isn't it?
You may not know it,
but you did something today.
Peace...
maker.
You think I made
the peace, Tani?
I just ran out of people
to kill.
The so-called
"Pledge of Allegiance"
swept through congress today
as legislators lined up
in support of the President,
even as international
condemnation mounts
for the attack
the White House has called
"necessary and unavoidable."
Oh, finally.
I did my part. How about...
They said it was an allergic
reaction to something he ate.
But by the time
they got to him,
his brain had been without
oxygen for ten minutes.
So how could that
be an accident?
It's your fault, isn't it?
You smiled and promised him
so much money.
You know, he used to say,
"You should see her.
It's like nothing
can touch her."
It's true, isn't it?
Nothing touches you.
I hope you die alone.
We've got two teams looking
for Brannan and Cortez.
If they're out there
to be found, we'll find them.
I think it was July deployment.
You're due any minute
for general inspection,
and, man...
It's not good.
Cam's got some new sonar display
that's not even working.
The cook, he's got,
like, 200 cans of stew
that exploded in the mess
and the smell...
The smell is everywhere.
And here comes the captain.
Here you come.
Everybody's freaking out
because the place
is a complete disaster.
Except instead, for two hours,
you're all smiles
and back slaps.
You told some story
about fishing off the back
of an LA class attack sub.
Finally,
it's time to put to sea.
I find Christine
and I say good-bye.
Yeah, you'd been married...
three weeks?
I join you on the bridge,
and you got this big dumb smile
plastered all over your face--
totally undignified.
And Jeffrey's there
on the pier.
He's home from his first tour.
He's there to watch his old man
pull out to sea.
Give me your dumb hand, sir.
I can't imagine
what you're going through.
But I am your friend.
And I know who you are.
And I trust you.
They find
what hurts you the most
and they try to break you
with it.
But that's where they miss.
What hurts us the most,
that's our strength.
That's what gets us through.
I'm excited.
And I know you of all people,
you get that.
I'll tell you stories
on the other side.
I love you, dad.
Hi, dad.
I hope you never
have to watch this.
I wish that I had
let you know me better.
If I had, then you would know
how scared I am.
But you would also know that
I'm not gonna run from this.
That's not who I am.
I love you, dad.
You've indicated that
you're not going to tell
your wife about this.
Why is that?
The whole time I was there,
Christine's what kept me alive.
You want to know why
I'm not gonna tell my wife?
'Cause she's the one good thing
I got left in this world.
Maybe this way,
I get to keep that.