Woman: Come on! Come on!
[laughter]
[indistinct shouting]
[cheers and applause]
Team Heather by a hair!
- What?
- No, we totally... we totally had that!
Hey, first rule of emergency medicine...
don't piss off the nurses.
- That breaks all ties.
- Oh, my God.
- I knew I should have been pushing.
- Oh, my God!
Hey, come on. Let me...
let me try that thing.
- You know what I'm talking about?
- Yeah.
Let me try. Let me try.
All right, try to get
out of this choke hold.
Tell me when you think you got me.
Oh, uh, let me... oh, I got you.
[grunts]
Well, that was easy.
Yeah, I guess that's why
you fight MMA and I don't.
[grunts]
I have to say, as an administrator,
these shenanigans would
have driven me nuts.
I am having such a great time.
Who knew this ER could have
such a quiet night, huh?
- [conversations stop]
- Wh-What's wrong with you?
Don't... don't ever say the "Q" word.
- What, I just...
- [stammers]
You don't talk about fight club,
you don't talk about a no-hitter,
and you never, ever mention
the "Q" word in an ER.
You will jinx it.
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
I didn't know!
Jordan: I haven't told my mom about us yet
because she doesn't understand
why I broke up with Scott
and she knows how hard it was for us
when you got back from the war.
She didn't like me before I went to war.
Hold on, did she really
like Scott that much?
W-well... [sighs] What can I say?
You know, he called her on mother's day.
Look, all I'm saying is that... [sighs]
If I tell her now before she leaves,
I'm not gonna get a moment's rest.
And to be honest with you,
I don't feel like dealing with her nagging.
So I just figured that
I would tell her after.
[pagers beeping]
- Someone said the "Q" word.
- [siren wails in distance]
Okay, team, so much for
coasting through the morning.
We have a multi-victim traffic collision,
stragglers filling the waiting room.
- What do you got?
- The first two were in a rollover MVA
when it slammed into
another vehicle in the rain.
- That vic's still on the scene.
- Okay, I got this.
First victim is 18 years old.
He has a deep gash to his left
thigh from the broken glass.
Me and Jordan in Trauma Two.
Victim two was a front-seat passenger.
She's a minor with
blunt-face and chest trauma.
- [groans]
- She has mild respiratory distress,
but her sats are holding.
Take the girl into Trauma
One. Krista, you're with me.
Paul and Drew, start working
through the waiting-room patients...
and, Drew, take Ragosa with you.
- Show him the ropes.
- Me? What? Why not Paul?
He's almost as green. You're not.
- Put the girl right here.
- Son of a bitch.
You know I can hear you, right?
Have fun with that.
[panting]
How's Taylor? Is she okay?
Ah, we're working on her in the other room.
But let's focus on you right now, okay?
I didn't even see the other car.
- Is that driver okay?
- Not here yet.
I'll get you an update when we have one.
Oh, okay, looks like he got
the femoral. I need more gauze.
Jordan, the third MVA
vic is two minutes out.
We got this. Go ahead.
All right, I'll send off a
type and cross for six units.
Get me a large BP cuff
to tourniquet the leg.
There's one in the next room.
[monitor beeping]
How's the boy?
Aah, femoral artery injury.
But TC's on the case.
- Here?
- The jaw's dislocated.
It's obstructing her breathing.
Intubation tray is ready.
- I don't think we'll need it.
- [wheezing]
If we can reduce the jaw,
breathing should be fine.
Just in the next room.
- Call me if you need me.
- Okay, thanks.
Gwen: 1, 2, 3.
Thank you. I've got it from here.
Is this the woman the kid's car ran into?
Yep, approximately 30-year-old female.
Tachy, but otherwise stable.
Paramedic on the scene
found her unconscious
with bleeding scalp lacerations.
- Doctor Chavez has been paged.
- Okay, thank you.
Okay, I need to tie this one off now.
- 4-0 Prolene.
- Okay.
- Oh, hey, Gwen.
- Jordan.
- Hey, Scott.
- 4-0 Prolene.
See you around, Jordan?
Joey's off on some family thing,
and I'm on call, so what do we got here?
Hemodynamically stable, but
came in with a scalp pumper.
I'm placing a purse-string suture,
which should do the trick.
It says here abdominal trauma.
Could be internal bleeding.
I'll check a fast scan.
Ultrasound, please.
Woman: Yes, Doctor.
Uh, Jordan?
She's pregnant?
Well, this just got a lot more complicated.
I'd say so.
- Krista, let's go!
- Done.
The tongue depressors
will protect your thumbs
from being bitten off,
but be careful, okay?
Taylor, you're gonna feel some pressure,
but it'll help you breathing, okay?
Just look at me, Taylor.
Everything's gonna be okay.
All right?
Place your thumbs along her bottom teeth,
then push inferior and posterior.
- [groaning]
- Slow and steady pressure.
- [screams]
- [rapid beeping]
Pulse ox is dropping.
Krista, you got to do this.
- Don't make me step in.
- Her jaw isn't moving.
Sats are down to 80.
You have to push harder.
- Now's not now the time to be polite.
- Okay.
- [crack]
- It moved! It moved!
[groans]
- [rapid beeping stops]
- Feels back in place.
- Sats are up to 95.
- Nice job, Krista.
- Let's get her to X-ray.
- How's my...
Don't talk, sweetie, okay?
Until we know your jaw's back in place.
- How's my husband?
- Your what?
My husband, Ryan. We
just got married tonight.
What are you, like 14, 15?
I just turned 16.
Do me a favor. Please don't
tell my dad about the marriage.
I don't think he's gonna be happy.
Yeah, that would be my guess.
Things are crazy in there. We got
to keep things running out here.
We just had two new patients come in.
We have one lady
complaining of a kidney stone
and an elderly woman with
an altered mental status.
Paul, you got the Queen
Mother. We got the kidney stone.
Wait, hold on... uh,
this isn't one of those
"old people with STD" pranks, right?
I promise you she's not here for STDs.
In fact, if she has one,
I'll pay you 500 bucks.
Paul, listen, I-I wouldn't go
looking for STDs if I were you.
That's Marilyn Capshaw, the matriarch
of this hospital's biggest donor family.
You mean... oh,
crap... the  Capshaws,
like, the ones that fund
the residency program.
Exactly.
The family's a total bunch of
pain-in-the-ass hypochondriacs.
They have made my life a living hell.
You knew.
Of course. I had her sister my first year.
She came in at 3:00 a.m.
nothing wrong with her.
She had me written up as incompetent.
Enjoy.
- Nice move. I did not want...
- Okay, just take this lady's
chart and come get me when you
have a differential diagnosis.
Taylor: I knew we should
have stopped to rest,
but we wanted to get back before
our parents knew we were gone.
- And you really got married?
- We had to.
Our parents wouldn't let us see each other.
We thought, if we got married,
they couldn't keep us apart.
Uh, I don't think that's how it works.
- I mean, don't you need their permission?
- No.
We found a 24-hour wedding
chapel in Arkansas online,
and you only have to be 16,
- which I turned tonight.
- [sighs] Note to self.
Don't let daughter anywhere near Arkansas.
Taylor, is that you?!
Oh. Remember, don't tell him I'm married.
I don't want to get in trouble.
I'm her father, Denny Sawyer.
- Taylor, are you okay?
- I'm fine, Daddy, I think.
She's been in an accident.
I'm Doctor Zia. This is Doctor Bell-Hart.
- Hey.
- Your daughter took a pretty good
shot to the head
so, we're gonna get it scanned,
and then we'll know more.
Okay, good. I was scared to
death when I got the phone call.
Well, I'm sorry I scared
you, but it's all okay now.
Well, not everything.
I mean, you're gonna be grounded
for being out at 3:00 a.m.
- Dad, I...
- and that's the last time you stay at
Candace's house. I'm gonna
have a word with her parents
- Excuse me.
- and make sure they understand...
Taylor's friend Ryan
keeps asking to see her.
- Can I get...
- M-Mollie.
- Ryan? Ryan's here?
- Okay, sir, l-let's just...
I told you I didn't want
you seeing that punk Ryan.
And now you're out in the middle of
the night with him, in a car no less?
- Let's settle this after the CAT scan.
- I'm sorry Daddy!
We got married! We had to!
- You gave us no choice.
- Married?!
- How... how do you...
- Okay, Krista, get her in the scanner.
How could you be married?!
You're only 16 years old!
Sir, please, please calm down.
There's plenty of time to be angry.
Let's just make sure
she's okay for now, okay?
Kenny: All right, first unit is in.
Pressure's up to 84.
Run two more units on the rapid infuser.
I need another 6-0 of silk.
Ryan's parents are here.
They want to see him.
- Just for a minute.
- Okay.
Oh, my God, Ryan.
- Is he gonna be okay?
- Yeah, he's injured his femoral artery,
- but I got the bleeding under control.
- Oh, thank God.
We got the call, and I almost had
a heart attack on the way over here.
Yeah, I understand.
Those late-night calls must
scare the crap out of you.
Listen, he's gonna be okay,
so if you just let me finish...
Harrison, I told you to keep
your son away from my daughter.
What are you doing here?
They went off and got married.
What do you mean, "married"?
Did she get pregnant?
- I'm not talking to you.
- Hey, I'm trying to work here.
- Take it outside.
- I'm talking to him.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, that's my wife.
- Kenny, take it outside.
I'll talk to her anyway
I want to talk to her.
[indistinct shouting]
♪♪♪
Sync & corrections by PetaG
- www.addic7ed.com -
I'll talk to her any way I want.
I think that's part of the problem.
This is what your daughter learned from!
This is why she cats around Ryan!
No wonder she dresses like a slut!
- You son of a bitch!
- Everybody...
Hey, hey, hey, no! No!
- Hey!
- What are you gonna do about it,
Huh? Huh?
Stop! Look, this is a hospital!
People are working!
Okay? Show some respect!
Now, Ryan's mom and dad, you
can go to the waiting room.
Go on.
Now you go to the cafeteria.
Well done, Kenny.
Didn't have to call security or anything.
These are the only guns I need. [Grunts]
E-even I would look
ripped in your scrub top.
I mean, w-what is this,
like, a boy's small?
Anyway, let me know when Krista
brings Taylor back from CT.
Nobody makes fun of Superman.
He got a tight shirt.
Woman: She's waking up.
- Okay. Mm-hmm.
- All set?
[pulsing]
My... my baby! How's my baby?!
Your baby's doing great, okay?
Look, see?
I'm Doctor Alexander, and
this is Doctor Clemens.
And we'd like to do a scan of your brain.
No. My brain is fine,
okay? I don't want to expose
- my baby to any radiation.
- I agree.
And that's why I'm going to
use the ultrasound machine
to check the pressure in your brain...
make sure it's okay, there's no bleeding.
And it is 100% safe for your baby.
Yeah.
Okay. Okay.
- Okay.
- That's fine.
I'm sorry to be such a pain.
I just want to protect my baby.
Okay, go ahead and close your eyes for me.
This might feel a little funny.
[warbling]
Hmm. This is a great idea, Scott.
Yeah, I've been known to have a few.
[monitor beeps]
So, your fiancé's in the army?
Yeah, yeah, he's a corporal stationed
at the Ramstein Air Base in Germany.
We're getting married once he gets back,
- you know, before she's born.
- That's great.
Okay, it looks like the
diameter of your optic nerve
is well within normal limits,
so I would say you are good to go.
- Okay. Thanks for understanding.
- Well, what can I say?
I'm an understanding kind of guy.
Ow! Ow, ow!
Is everything okay?
Yeah, yeah. She's just kicking, you know...
[laughs] Do you mind calling
my fiancé and just explaining
- to him what's going on?
- I'd be glad to.
Next time, don't make us wait as long.
I need you to do every
test here immediately,
and I do not want to have
to wait for the results.
- You understand?
- Uh, yes, s-sir.
She's been off lately,
but it got so bad tonight
I couldn't deal with it anymore.
I'm expecting a precise
diagnosis by morning.
- Uh, yeah.
- You're a beautiful dancer.
Do you know how to rumba?
See what I mean? Here are her things.
I'll be checking in.
Mother, I'll be back in a few hours.
Uh, this way, please. After you.
Mm, soft as a baby.
Gwen: What are you doing, cruising Tinder?
Yeah, I'm trying to get in
touch with Chloe's fiancé,
but I keep getting his voicemail.
I'm gonna have to get one of the nurses
to track him down for her.
Hey, let me do it.
They're still working.
I just got off my shift.
You don't want to go home?
To an empty apartment?
I'd rather stay and help the pregnant girl.
Nice to know someone
who's getting laid, huh?
- All right, thank
you. - Mm-hmm.
All right, now I would like
you to follow my finger, okay?
All right, and now...
a-and repeat after me.
"No ifs, ands, or buts."
No ifs, and you have a nice butt.
[both laugh] Okay, all right.
Let's, uh... let's try
and focus, all right? Okay.
Um, name as many animals as you can
in 30 seconds, all right?
And... Go.
- Zebra.
- Mm-hmm.
Coyote. Coyote.
I suppose you're too young
to remember Wile E. Coyote.
No, I'm actually... I-I...
always trying to catch
that damn roadrunner,
but he never could.
Beep, beep! That's the
sound Road Runner made.
- Beep, beep!
- [laughs]
- All right. No, I... no, I get it.
- I... that's sweet. Yeah.
- Oh, but I like it.
How's it going teaching Ragosa?
Ohh, if it was any other
physician's assistant,
I wouldn't mind babysitting.
But that guy, he's always
been such a pain in our asses.
Oh, come on. He's not that bad.
You just have to get to know him.
Yeah, that's right on
the top of my to-do list.
Hey, Jordan?
So, that cell number that Chloe gave us
is still going to voicemail.
I left a message to call,
but there's also no record
of Chloe's fiancé ever being at Ramstein.
Never heard of him.
Well, maybe the guy wanted
out, so he just lied.
Wouldn't be the first
time someone got scared off
by a baby or lied about
ending a relationship.
My gut tells me that's not the case.
Uh, why don't you try calling
Fort Hood and see if...
If he was deployed in the Middle East.
I know right where you're headed.
- Thank you.
- [clicks tongue]
Hey, Scott.
- Hmm?
- Uh, do we need to talk?
'Cause I feel like you're taking
these not-so-subtle jabs at me.
No. No, no, no. Not at all.
No, no, I was...
I was talking about Chloe
and her situation, not ours.
Look, was I pissed at first? Yes, I was.
Was I hurt? Yeah.
But trust me, I am more than fine
with how everything's worked out, okay?
- Okay.
I'll go page OB for you.
Thank you.
- [monitor beeping]
- [sighing]
Hey. Look who's awake.
How are you feeling?
Terrible. How's my wife, Taylor?
You wife is getting some tests.
And just so you know,
your parents are here.
And her dad.
Nobody seemed particularly happy.
- Her dad?
- Yeah.
He just hates me because we're rich.
Well, I don't think your marriage
is gonna do your case any favors.
[door opens]
- Is this Ryan Harrison?
- Yeah.
Yeah, he's stable. You can talk to him.
[police radio chatter] Just
for a few minutes, though.
Uh, Officer, this is my son.
It was my car that he wrecked in the crash.
Uh, here's our insurance
card. Anything else you need?
I'm not here about the car.
Ryan Harrison, you are under arrest
for the sexual assault of a minor.
Get those off my boy.
- You have the right to remain silent.
- Get those off me. You can't arrest me.
- We're married. It's not illegal.
- Anything you do say can and will be used
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey. Hang on.
- against you in the court of law.
- What's going on?
- Dad, help me! Get these off me!
You have a right to an attorney. If you
cannot afford an attorney, one will be
provided to you. Do you understand
these rights as I have read them to you?
Please! Dad, she's my wife! Help me.
- Ow! Ow! My baby!
- What happened?
I'm not sure. I found her like this.
It's my stomach! [Crying]
Hey, Kenny, start her on morphine.
Chloe? Chloe, these are contractions.
- You're in labor.
- No, no, no!
It's not... it's not time.
It's too early for the baby.
We can try to slow the contractions down.
But, honey, worst case,
your baby's far enough along to be viable.
- No.
- All right, morphine's in.
- Thank you.
- Oh, God, oh, God, oh, God.
- Why is this happening?
- Okay.
Look, I promised my dad
I'd be married before I had the baby.
I'm sure he'll understand.
No! He died last month!
Look, I can't break my promise to him!
Please, it would crush my mom!
Chloe, I am so sorry.
Honey, the best thing you can do right now
is try to focus on staying calm,
'cause that's what's best
for you and your baby.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Okay?
- Kenny, start a mag sulfate infusion.
- On it.
[crying] I don't want to do this alone.
You're gonna be great. It's okay.
Now, Deputy, you don't need
to escalate this, all right?
He just wants to know what's
happening with his son.
He's an 18-year-old having
sex with a 15-year-old.
She's 16.
Oh, and that makes it okay for you?
You son of a bitch. You
did this, didn't you?
You're damn right I did.
I told you to keep your
son away from my daughter.
And you wouldn't, so I will.
- This will ruin Ryan's life.
- His life?
His life is set! He's got
a BMW and a trust fund.
My Taylor was at the top of
her class until she started
- running around with your son.
- Whoa, whoa, she's chasing him!
And he quit the baseball team
'cause of your little gold digger.
- Hey! Hey! Hey, hey, hey, hey!
- [indistinct shouting]
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Hey, hey!
- Cool it.
Okay, okay, fighting is not
gonna make your kids any better.
Topher: This is the second
ruckus you guys have started.
If it happens again, I'm
booting you both. You understand?
I'm gonna call my lawyer,
and this is gonna end.
You've gone too far, Sawyer. You're done!
Your money's not gonna
help you this time, dick.
Okay, Mr Sawyer, I
understand why you're upset.
Do you have a daughter?
No.
- But...
- Then you have no idea.
She's all I have left.
Mr Sawyer.
Why don't you wait in the waiting room?
- That sounded intense.
- Yeah.
- Young love, Texas style.
- All right.
Hey, do you have a minute to do me a favor?
Yeah, sure. What's up?
Well, my pregnant
patient is so stressed-out
about having her baby before she's married
that her BP is off the charts,
which just complicated premature labor.
- Yeah, that's not good.
- No.
And Gwen found out that her fiancé lied
about being stationed in Germany
and he's really in Afghanistan.
He told her that so she wouldn't worry.
- Sound familiar?
- No.
I mean, I was gonna tell you eventually...
When I got back.
And I figured out where you
were in less than a week.
- Anyway... oh, thank you.
- Here's the list.
Uh, we've managed to track down his unit,
but we've been unable to reach him.
So I was wondering if maybe you could ask
one of your army buddies to help out.
- Yeah.
- Hey, Tee?
- Can I have a word?
- Yeah.
Yeah, yeah. Coming.
Uh, yeah, I can do that.
Thank you. I owe you one.
Yeah. What you got, Toph?
Oh, having seconds thoughts?
- Mm-hmm.
- No.
I just didn't know that he
was seeing someone so soon.
Really? Oh, by the way, your mom called me.
She wanted to know the real
reason why you guys broke up.
Well, what did you tell her?
The truth.
Herpes.
I didn't say who had it.
- [chuckles]
- You're a horrible friend.
You know that, right?
Topher: Mr Sawyer, the
sheriff called me himself,
telling me to remove the cuffs immediately
and... and to apologize.
That deputy who did this
is being reprimanded.
He was enforcing the law.
He was enforcing your revenge.
Apparently, in Texas,
there's something called
The Romeo and Juliet Law,
which allows for consensual intercourse
with a minor within three years of age.
It's... it's not illegal.
TC: We heard the deputy was your buddy,
and that's why you did it.
He did it because we served together.
We'd do anything for each other.
Look, I get that.
With all due respect, boys...
Hey, I did three tours in the sandbox.
Rangers. Doctor Zia here did two.
I thought you were just doctors.
You sound like
my mother-in-law.
Where were you?
[sighs] Paktika, Helmand, Gawardesh.
[scoffs]
I spent some time in
Helmand I'd like to forget.
Two... two long deployments, you know.
I come back the second time...
my daughter is living with friends.
My wife, gone.
Didn't want to be a wife anymore,
or a mom, or... just gone.
I'm sorry. That's... that's rough.
You know, sometimes, it's, uh...
it's harder coming back
than it is being there.
Yeah, yeah. [Sniffles]
That's true. Yeah.
And... and now I work
these two crap jobs to...
just to keep her in that
school so she's got a future.
I'm not gonna let that punk ruin it.
Why don't we get some coffee?
And I'll... I'll get an update
on your daughter's scans.
- We can talk it out.
- Great, right. Thanks, doc.
Right.
Drew: So, what's your assessment?
32-year-old female
with colicky flank pain
and large blood in her urinalysis,
which indeed points to a kidney stone.
I ordered her a CT, some IV fluids,
and I was gonna give her
pain meds for the discomfort.
How about a band-aid?
- Band-aid? - Your
finger, please.
The other finger.
She pricks her finger,
puts a few drops of blood
in the urine sample to make it look like
a kidney stone so she can get narcotics.
I cut this on a magazine. I saw you
in here last month trying to same gag,
and I remember you 'cause you
were wearing a Lakers T-shirt
and I hate the Lakers.
Stop wasting our time. You understand me?
We got real patients. Get some help.
If you had checked the chart,
you would have found she's been
in here a ton of times
trying to get narcotics.
Things often aren't what they seem.
So, my brother... and
he's a platoon leader.
So he... he yells up, "hey, hey, I got him!
I smoked... I smoked his ass!"
So we run down there, right,
just making sure it's all clear.
And he smoked him, all right,
except it wasn't Taliban.
No? It was a cow.
A cow? Yeah.
It was the first steak we
had in about six months.
And after that, Thad was
forever known as "Smoke."
"Lord Smoke."
[both laugh]
Yeah.
How's your brother doing?
- Is he... is he still in?
- No, no.
No. No, no. No, no. H-he was KIA.
- [sighs]
- I'm sorry.
Nah. [Scoffs] It's cool.
Were you over there when that happened?
Yeah, yeah.
I... I was about 15 feet
from him when it happened.
[chuckles]
- What are you gonna do?
- Oh, my God.
[sighs]
Let me ask you something.
How are you so together?
Nah, I'm not together,
man. It's still a struggle.
- [chuckles]
- Ah. You got a good job, right?
You got a good woman?
Yeah, the best.
You marry her?
Almost. Almost.
I-I planned on asking her
when I got back from the war,
and then everything went to hell.
I'd say you got it pretty well together.
Me? I-I'm back two years.
I... I can't seem to get ahead.
Like quicksand, you know.
I get myself out and, uh, you
know, I'm right back in it.
Over there, I was a leader of men.
- Yeah.
- I was kicking down doors, taking names.
I wore the uniform proud, you know?
I mean, look at the uniform I wear now.
I'm a joke.
No.
It took me a few years to get where I'm at.
I was a mess.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
And the only thing that turned it around
was... was me asking for help.
Well... Who am I gonna ask, you know?
I mean, Taylor, I can't talk
to her. She's just a kid.
There's a lot of programs that can help.
You got to turn it around, man.
Otherwise, you're gonna
drown in anger and self-pity.
I've been there.
You got to drop the pride BS.
There's a lot of people
who are willing to help you.
But  you  got to ask for it.
And then, I-if they offer
it, you got to take it.
I'm offering.
So just... just take it.
Okay.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
- Do it for the cow.
- [laughs]
- [monitor beeping]
- [whimpering]
This is not gonna hurt.
We're just checking your heart, okay?
- Okay. Have you heard anything?
- About Ryan?
Yeah, he's resting comfortably.
He's no longer under arrest.
And, yes, he's been asking about you.
- How is she?
- Head CT looked good.
Her others scans are coming up shortly.
- Oh, that's great.
- Yeah.
I don't want to talk to you.
Taylor, I love you. I'm
trying to protect you.
So you got Ryan arrested?
- We're nothing to them, sweetie.
- [rapid beeping]
You never even tried to get to know him,
- or how he makes me feel.
- I'm just doing what's best for you.
I... you know, I hate you.
I hate you.
- Don't say that.
- I hate you!
Don't say that!
- Heart rate's going up.
- [groans]
She needs to rest.
- My chest!
- Taylor, what's wrong?
[gasping]
What's going on? I heard an alarm.
It looks like a heart attack.
- Heart attack?! She's 16 years old! Do...
- All right, all right.
Okay, it's not an
infarction. It's a dissection.
Her aorta's tearing in half.
Call Scott. Tell him to
meet us in the OR now.
What's happening? Where are you taking her?
Sir, we're going to the
OR I need you to stay here.
- Taylor! Taylor!
- I will check back in with you!
Woman over PA: Doctor
Clegg to Trauma One.
Doctor Clegg to Trauma One.
She coded in the elevator.
16-year-old with aortic
dissection from an MVA.
16? Her parent's here? Her
father and husband. Long story.
All right, tell the OR we're
going on bypass immediately.
♪  Come on and make a move  ♪
♪  there's another world
outside your door  ♪
You got stuck with Marilyn Capshaw, huh?
- Yeah, yeah.
- [chuckles]
Here with altered mental status,
disorganized thinking and attention.
I'm thinking acute delirium,
- maybe encephalopathy.
- CT?
Normal, as was her EEG, CMP,
CBC, and all her other labs.
Her, uh... her son has
called over five times
and left messages about her diagnosis.
I just... I wanted to
run the case by you first.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Mrs Capshaw? Hello. I'm Doctor Zia.
We've met a couple of times before.
Do you have change for a $20?
I need more chips.
I-I don't have any cash on me.
Do you mind if I take a
look at your pretty eyes?
Well, sure, you sweet thing.
All right.
- [chuckles]
- Yes. Uh-huh.
Pretty as ever.
Thank you, love.
Did you do a tox screen?
[scoffs] Um, no.
She's, uh... she's 82.
She's 82 and high as a kite.
Wait, what?
Baked, blazed, stoned out of her gourd,
whatever euphemism you want.
Trust me. Send the test.
♪  So, you can fall down
or you can bounce up  ♪
- Want some chips?
- Mm.
So, how's checking vitals going?
Uh, it was going fine, but I
can't feel this guy's pulse.
What do you mean?
You're checking for it in the wrong spot.
No, I-I-I know how to
check a radial pulse, okay.
Th-there isn't one. I
can't feel a femoral.
Son of a bitch. What did you do?
What did you do?! I
stepped out for one minute!
Not... n-nothing! I-I-I was
practicing vitals like you said.
Get the crash cart.
- Yes, Doctor.
- Wait, wait wait! Wait, wait!
- You're gonna shock him?!
- Yes.
- Damn it, he's got dogjaw.
- What?
- Dogjaw! Check his carotid and see
- Oh, my God.
if you can find a pulse.
[barks]
[clatter]
[laughter]
Mr Howard has a ventricular assist device.
Comes in a couple times
a year to get it checked.
His blood flows continuously
rather than by pump,
so no pulse.
Freaky, huh?
[laughter]
Ah, pranking that
someone's in cardiac arrest.
- Yeah, that's... that's hilarious.
- Welcome to the night shift.
And what did I tell you last time?
Check the chart. It's all right there.
You're a great teacher, Drew.
Thanks for all your help.
- [laughter]
- [barks]
The good news is we
stopped your contractions.
But you have an early placental abruption.
- So when the OB is done with his other
- Oh, God.
delivery, you're going
to need a c-section.
Can... I need to call my
fiancé. Have you found him?
- I need to talk to him.
- Yes... technically, yes.
[groans]
We just need to get our
hands on him physically.
Look, stress is not good for
the baby or the abruption.
Okay?
Remember, deep breathes.
Just please find him.
- How's Ragosa doing?
- Pouting.
Still thinks he's a VP and not the PA.
Well, Rome wasn't built in a day.
I still don't understand how
you can give him this job.
He was such a dick to
you and the rest of us.
Yeah, he was. You remember
when you first came out?
Wait, I'm gay?
- Doctor Alister.
- One of the board members
wanted to fire you, which, as
you know, they can in Texas.
Guess who called him a bigot
and said he'd fight him
tooth and nail on that?
Ragosa?
Mm.
"Check out the big brain on Brad."
- Hey.
How's the girl?
Scott's got his hands full.
I-I came out to talk to her
dad, but I couldn't find him.
- Hmm.
- I wanted to tell you my buddy tracked
down the fiancé. He's
in Afghanistan in Bagram.
- Oh, good. And he's still...
- Totally into her.
Just freaked out about her and the baby.
Yeah, well, it doesn't look like
this baby's gonna wait for a wedding.
What are you... what are you doing in here?
Getting some privacy.
Well, your lab results came back.
They show very high levels of marijuana.
Could have told you that.
S-so why didn't you?
You made me look like an
idiot in front of my boss.
You did that to yourself.
You saw an old lady
and never thought of the possibility,
though I was exhibiting
all of the behavior.
Look, I-I-I need
to tell your son.
He's been all over me
about what's wrong with you.
There's nothing wrong with me.
A little advice, Paul.
Don't try to so hard to please everybody.
You know, you'll only end up with regrets.
W... hey, hey, you... you can't do that.
Not here.
Why do you think I wanted privacy?
Besides, you gonna stop me?
You want a hit?
N-no, thank you.
Go ahead.
Your father would be very disappointed.
- Wait, what? How do... how do you...
- Know your father?
What do you think?
Called me last year about your internship.
He... he got me in here?
Actually, he wanted us to keep you out.
You know, h-he still
calls me once a month,
trying to get me to quit ER.
He says one day I can join
him and my brother's practice in Chicago.
And why don't you?
'Cause I don't want to follow anybody.
The real reason.
[sniffs]
Uh, what if... what if
I'm... I'm not good enough?
Maybe... maybe I'm Peyton Manning, right?
But maybe I'm Jeffrey Jordan.
Th-those are the sons of...
I know who they are.
Okay.
Now, look, I know I'm buzzed,
but I'm gonna give you
one last piece of advice.
Now, even though I was the
black sheep of the family,
I still never followed my heart.
I did what they wanted me to.
So you figure out what you want to do.
Not from fear, but for the right reasons.
And they can go to hell
if they get in your way.
[chuckles]
[inhales deeply] Thank you.
I will.
Now... Here's what we're gonna tell my son.
[flatline] Ragosa: Hey, you paged me?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
I'm not falling for this
crap again, okay, Drew?
This is real. You want to learn something?
Grab that crash cart. This is Mr Simpson.
He came in with a heart
attack, went into v-fib arrest.
Now, hit "power." Set the voltage to 360.
- [beep]
- Press "charge."
Okay.
- [paddles whine]
- This is all you.
B-but I've never done this before.
Then it's gonna be a hell of
a good time to learn, isn't it?
Set the paddles at 10:00 and 5:00.
Okay. Okay, like this?
Yeah, everybody clear.
- Go.
- [thump]
- Still v-fib.
- [flatline]
What are you gonna do?
Okay, uh, charging again.
[paddles whine]
- [beeping]
- Clear.
[thump]
- [monitor beeping]
- Oh, man, that's sinus.
- I can feel a pulse.
- Yes, it is.
Hang an amiodarone drip.
Get him to the cath lab.
Woman: Okay, right away.
Oh, holy cow.
- That man was...
- ... dead.
And now he isn't.
Congratulations. You just saved his life.
Thanks.
It turns out she just had low blood sugar.
I-I gave her IV dextrose.
And here's a list of dietary adjustments.
That's all? I mean, she was...
Get the car.
- Doctor Zia?
- Topher: Yes, Ma'am?
Are you aware of what a remarkable
young doctor you have here?
I expect him to be made
an attending physician
at this institution one day very soon
in whatever specialty he pursues.
How did you pull that off?
Uh, it must be my wonderful
bedside manner, I-I guess.
[monitor beeping]
I love you, baby. [Chuckles]
You look so beautiful.
Hey. You paged me?
Uh, yeah. We're all set here.
We just need an in-person
proxy groom to read the vows.
- [chuckles]
- You game?
Sure. Why not? I got a few minutes.
- Good man.
- Thank you.
Of course. Tom, I'm Doctor Callahan.
It is an honor to stand
in for you, Sergeant.
The honor's mine. I
can't thank you enough
for making this wedding
happen, Doctors.
Can't get married without a bouquet.
[laughing] Why, thank you.
Are you ready?
Yes, I'm ready.
Dearly beloved,
we are gathered together
here in the sight of God
- to join together in holy matrimony...
- [gasping]
- ... Chloe and Tom.
- [rapid beeping]
Jordan: Baby's having accelerations.
- I'm feeling short of breath.
- All right, that's it.
We're getting her to the OR.
- What's happening? Chloe?
- Sorry, Daddy. Baby, I'm sorry.
This ain't over yet,
sweetie. Okay, somebody
- tell the OB we're on our way.
- Okay, what is...
- w-where are you taking her?
- Reverend, skip to the good stuff
- and try to keep up.
- Somebody talk to me.
I've never done anything like this.
Move it along, Padre.
You got about 15 seconds.
- Chloe, are you okay?
- Do you take this woman to be your
- wedded wife?
- I do.
Do you take this man to
be your wedded husband?
- I do.
- Chloe?
- She does.
- Then I pronounce you man and wife.
BP's down to 40 systolic.
Chloe, I love you.
- Gwen: Jordan!
- She's hemorrhaging!
We can't get her to the OR
we got to do it down here.
Trauma One. Let's go.
The baby's heart rate is still down.
Opening the peritoneum.
Two units of blood are in.
Well, this is a hell of a honeymoon.
Any word from OB? Scalpel.
She has her hands full with
a uterine rupture upstairs.
Glad we got started.
Incising the uterus.
Hey, setting up the Skype
with the father in 15 minutes.
Anything I can tell him?
Yeah, I'll have the story
for him in about five seconds.
- You want to watch?
- Yeah.
There we go.
Here she comes.
[baby crying]
All right.
You tell them, sweetie.
Topher: Cutting the cord.
My... my... how's my baby girl?
She's beautiful, just like
her mother and her doctor.
I think he was talking about himself.
Yeah, I'm sure he was.
[laughter]
[voice breaking] Sorry, I just love babies.
- And weddings.
- [chuckles]
Chloe: Thank you for everything.
You have no idea what this means to me.
Who's my baby girl?
Hey, Tee. Hey, Scott needs to talk to you.
It's okay. We'll close up.
[monitor beeping]
♪ I've gone on too long ♪
- ♪ carrying the ♪
- Is she dead?
- ♪ weight of this heart of stone ♪
- No. But she's comatose.
Her brain was deprived
of oxygen for too long.
We've done everything we could possibly do.
[voice breaking] Oh,
my baby! My little girl!
It's her birthday.
♪ Just let me go ♪
I'm sorry.
There's still a possibility
she could come out of this.
We have to run a few tests
on her brain function.
No, no, just leave her.
Leave her. Leave us alone.
[sobbing] Okay.
♪ After all the things
that I've done wrong ♪
♪ I don't belong ♪
[sighs]
What's wrong with her?
"What's wrong with her"?
You did this to her!
You did this to her.
- Hey, hey. Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- No, no, no, no, no.
Hey. Hey, whoa, Denny.
- What are you doing?
- He killed her.
No, no. She's not dead.
- She's brain-dead. It's the same thing.
- [gun cocks]
It's not. Hey! It's not, and she isn't.
She still has brain activity.
There's still hope.
I got no hope. Get out of the way.
That's not true, okay?
We're gonna help you.
Doc, you've been good to me.
I don't want to shoot you, but I will.
I don't want you to shoot me, either.
But I'm not gonna let you hurt that boy.
- Get out of the way.
- No.
Get out of the way!
You give me that gun.
We can figure this out.
Just you and me.
Come on. Give me the gun.
We can figure this out.
There's nothing to figure out.
Come on. It's you and me.
[gunshot]
♪ Save my soul ♪
[flatline]
- ♪ Who will save my soul? ♪
- This is the 10th unit of blood.
He's gone five rounds of epi.
Cross clamped for 20 minutes already.
- ♪ After all the things ♪
- But I'll keep going if you want.
♪ that I've done wrong ♪
♪ who will save my soul? ♪
No.
Let's call it.
Time of death is 6:13.
Just too much damage to his heart.
Yeah, and everything else.
[siren wails in distance]
[crying]
Such a damn waste.
What the hell are we supposed to do now?
You hug your son...
- ♪ on the other side, I hope all is calm ♪
- Every chance you get.
♪ on the other side,
I hope all is bright ♪
♪ oh-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ on the other side, I hope I am able ♪
♪ on the other side,
I hope I am strong ♪
_
♪ oh-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
- ♪ oh-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
- Hey, man, come over and
check out my baby.
- [baby crying]
- Shh, shh-shh-shh-shh.
God, look at you.
Chloe, you're beautiful.
The baby's beautiful.
I got a baby girl!
I love you, baby.
I miss you so much.
Wish I could be there with you.
[monitor beeping]
Poor guy.
Just couldn't find his way back.
Yeah, it happens.
He didn't have what I had here...
you and Jordan.
[sighs]
I would have never made it without you.
Yeah, well... Had to.
Too much of a pain to
train a new best friend.
[chuckles]
Yeah.
♪ On the other side,
I hope I am strong ♪
♪ oh-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ 'cause I know, 'cause I know ♪
We're trying to contact Taylor's mom,
see if she wants to step in again.
- That's a hell of a bridge to repair.
- Yeah.
No other family to speak of?
No.
Just all of us and Ryan's family.
We, uh, got her lined up
in a good care facility.
She actually may recover.
[scoffs] It's unbelievable.
I mean, just when you think
you've seen everything,
her waking up has got
to go down as a miracle.
Yeah.
If only we could have had another one.
- Hmm.
Anyway, why don't we go back to my place?
I'll make you a nice breakfast,
and we can think about how lucky we are.
Actually, let's go to my place.
I think it's time that I
told my mother about us.
[sighs]
Are you sure now is the right time?
I've never been so sure in my life.
♪ oh-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
Let's go home.
Sync & corrections by PetaG
- www.addic7ed.com -