Come have a seat here.
You, are my butler from today on.
How can I serve the chairwoman
of Gold Group? No thanks.
Do you have somewhere to go to?
♪ I'm completely fine ♪
Jeong Ran.
I have a good eye for products, but
I also have a good eye for people.
No matter how you've lived up until now,
whether you've had a good education
or not, it doesn't matter.
Your attitude of even risking your own
life to help a complete stranger...
Just with that one aspect of you,
you're a very worthy person.
♪ I think I feel a little bit sorry ♪
- Jeong Ran.
- Yes?
I'm very thankful to you
for having taken care of me with all your
heart and soul. I could always rely on you.
Why are you saying such embarrassing
things so early in the morning?
You have to say what's in your heart freely while
you have the chance, instead of holding back.
If you don't do it then,
you may never be able to.
Why are you speaking like someone
who's about to leave on a trip?
I'll get your breakfast ready.
Okay.
♪ And I’m So Fine ♪
♪ Fading memories So Fine ♪
♪ An unfamiliar expression also So Fine ♪
Grandmother had a way of life that was all
her own. ♪ Without any regrets So Fine ♪
And I am Grandma's Precious who loves
Grandma and her way of life.
Episode15: My Way - My Splendid Life
Bok Sil!
Bok Sil...
The power is off, so you'll be
redirected to the voicemail...
Bok Sil!
Wait, where did that guy go?
Did he go inside and is he
sleeping indoors all by himself?
This little rascal! Aish...
Hey! Where did you go?
- Have you seen Bok Sil?
- No.
This is strange.
I was supposed to meet up with her, but she did
not come and I can't get in touch with her.
Just the ring was lying on the ground.
First of all, calm down.
Let's go to her room first.
She might have gone back to her room.
Okay.
So noisy.
No manners.
What are you doing so late at night?
- What about Bok Sil?
- Huh?
Wait.
Did she tell you anything?
She left to go meet Louis.
You weren't together?
Team Leader Baek, wake everyone up
and let them know what's going on.
We'll go look outside for her first.
What's going on?
Go Bok Sil has gone missing.
Omo! What to do?
Ji Sung! Bok Sil!
Bok Sil. Bok Sil!
Bok Sil! Bok Sil!
- She's not there?
- No.
Her cellphone is off and the
ring was on the ground.
I don't think it's just a
simple case of disappearance.
Then?
I have to check first.
I'll go to the surveillance room first.
Please keep searching.
Let's go together.
Keep looking for her. If you find anything,
get in touch with us right away.
You give us a call if
you find anything too.
Alright, I understand.
- Let me go with you!
- Let's hurry up and go.
- Ma Ri, let me go too, then.
- In Seong.
- Yes?
- You come search this way with me.
Okay. But I... I...
I have your daughter.
What?
Tomorrow at noon, bring the money
to the Clock Tower at Gold Plaza.
I'll let you know where your
daughter is once I get the money.
If you let the police know,
I can't guarantee what'll
happen to your daughter either.
Hello? Hello?!
Oh, Dad!
M-M-Ma Ri! Are you okay?
Where are you right now?
Where would I be? I told you I
was going on a company outing.
Oh, you did. You're really okay, right?
Oh, hang up if you've got
nothing else to say.
Go Bok Sil suddenly disappeared,
so I'm quite distracted!
Is this it?
What's this now about Go Bok
Sil suddenly going missing...
Did this bastard possibly take
Go Bok Sil instead of Ma Ri?
How can this bastard not
do even one thing right?
I mean... What is he trying to
do by messing with Bok Sil?
I'm going to go crazy, seriously!
No.
He said that he'd let me know where
she is if I just give him the money,
so all I have to do is give him
the money and save Go Bok Sil.
That's right.
Stop! Zoom in there.
- Here?
- Yes.
It's not definite yet. You can't
see her face that well either.
- You can't make it any clearer?
- No, this is the clearest.
Wait, that is Go Bok Sil!
I let her borrow that coat. I'm sure!
Bok Sil!
I feel like I've seen him a lot somewhere before.
Does anyone know who that man is, by any chance?
I can't really tell because of the mask.
I don't know either.
Why is he kidnapping Bok Sil? There's no one who
hates her, and she doesn't have any money either.
You have a lot of money, though.
Goldline heir, Kang Ji Sung.
You're saying Bok Sil got
kidnapped because of me?
Because of me?!
Because of me...
Get a hold of yourself, Kang Ji Sung! You
have to keep grounded at times like this!
You're the only guardian the kidnapped
Go Bok Sil's got! You understand?
Yes. I'll find her, no matter what.
So what do I need to do, then?
If he's really after your money, then
he'll get in touch with you soon.
Keep checking your phone. Let's stop the
search and go to Seoul for right now.
I should go to the station and
pull up the car records first.
Bok Sil...
This woman is...
This woman is involved with Louis,
so find out about her
and keep an eye on her.
This is Go Bok Sil!
I bought it from a boutique that I go to
often. Do you think it'll look good on Ma Ri?
What in the world happened?
I definitely double-checked her clothes.
Are you insane? What are
you doing right now?
There was a slight misunderstanding.
I told you that I would give you money in the first
place. Why do you keep making bigger problems?!
You first acted in such a way
that I couldn't trust you.
What in the world are you talking about?
Anyway, I just have to give you the money.
I'll give you the money right
now, so let Go Bok Sil go.
Come to the place we met
before with the money.
Sorry, for keeping you waiting.
I checked on the car 1511
and it's a stolen vehicle.
So, as of now, I won't be
able to point out a suspect.
What about security camera footage?
Nothing from there yet, either.
We're looking through all the footage around the retreat
center and toll gates, so we'll get a call in no time.
We put the stolen vehicle in the wanted
list, so let's just wait a little longer.
Have you got a call from the kidnapper yet?
No.
If he asks for money, I'll give it to him,
but he's not contacting me,
it's driving me crazy.
Cheer up. You'll get a call soon.
What's taking him so long?
The police people can trust and rely on.
I can't wait anymore. I'm
going to go look for her.
Where the heck are you trying to go to?
I don't know. I have to
look for her anywhere.
I'm worried sick for Bok Sil.
If you act like this, you'll be
worn out first. Brace yourself.
I wish I just get the call.
Go Bok Sil
Bok Sil!
Bok Sil?
Do you know the owner of this cell phone?
Are you not Bok Sil? Who are you?
This is a hospital.
The owner of this cell phone was in a
traffic accident and brought in here.
What?
Where is this? What hospital is it?
That bastard. Why isn't he coming?
He gets the money I gave him stolen,
he kidnaps someone else and
screws up the matter even more.
Why isn't he coming when I
brought the money again?
Seriously!
Bok Sil!
It's not Bok Sil.
What's going on here?
T-this guy..
Why is this guy...?
It's Secretary Goo!
You know him?
Yes. He's a brother of Ahjussi
Seon Gu's hometown friend.
I saw him at Ahjumma Audrey's
book store the other day.
What?
He's the guy who got hit by a hammer
and collapsed at your rooftop place.
What?
Has the patient injured his head before?
Yes. He lay unconscious for a long while,
and he left the hospital
without getting treated.
There is a chance that he
might never wake up again.
Then what about Bok Sil?
He knows where Bok Sil is.
What about Bok Sil!
Calm down. There must be a way.
Bok Sil... Are you talking about
the lady who came together?
Where is she right now?
Hey! Detective Nam seems to have found that Eunseong-dong
case victim who had run away from the hospital.
From where?
He was brought to a different hospital
after an accident. Go join him.
Yes, sir.
Detective Lee? What do I owe this call to?
That victim is at a hospital.
W-What did you just say?
He got into a traffic
accident and hurt his head,
so he's unconscious again.
We, the police, will take care of him from now on,
so don't concern yourself with him any longer.
W-Why? Did he do something?
He tried to kidnap someone tonight,
so a full-scale investigation is on.
Bok Sil!
Louis!
Bok Sil, are you hurt?
Where? How much?
I'm okay. I just pulled a ligament.
Louis...
Bok Sil... You must have been shocked.
I said I'd protect you. I'm sorry
for not keeping my promise.
I'm okay though.
I'm so sorry, Bok Sil.
Aren't you hungry? You had a tough night.
A little.
Then wait a little. I'll go get some stuff.
That male human detective is
really the best civil servant.
But why did he kidnap me?
We thought it was for the money at the
beginning, but now we don't think so.
That culprit is the one who got hit
with the hammer at our rooftop.
What?
Are you sure that guy is an
acquaintance of President Baek?
Yes. He surely said he was a younger
brother of his hometown friend.
It's really strange, right? Why did Ahjussi
Seon Gu's acquaintance come into our house?
Honey.
Where were you all night long?
You look terrible.
Jae Sook...
Are... you not feeling well?
Could you take the box on my
desk to Mother's house in Busan?
There is a secret space under the
floorboards in Louis' attic,
you can just put it in there.
Why do I have to put it there?
Please, don't ask any
questions and do me a favor.
Get going now.
O-Okay.
Attorney Hwang, it's me.
Can we meet right now?
Is it good?
Yeah.
Here, eat some more.
Just a sec.
What are you trying to do?
I'm making a ponytail.
Make it pretty.
Of course.
Wow!
Whoever did it, it's really pretty.
Really?
Then... let's eat.
Okay.
I spilled.
I just have to wipe it for you.
Wipe my mouth, too, please.
♪ Lost The Way, I lost the way Far Away ♪
Get me water.
♪ I'm searching for myself again All Day ♪
Drink it.
♪ In the smoky sunlight ♪
♪ I ask again ♪
I thought I lost it, but it's
made its way to the owner well.
Just one look and I knew.
Is this your present?
Yes.
And there's one more.
There's another present?
Come closer to me.
Huh?
♪ Fly Away, The space where
memories fell asleep, Your Space ♪
♪ Will I be able to wake up someday ♪
I really like you a lot.
A confession is your gift?
What do I do?
Hey, no! What are we going
to do if people walk in?
♪ Find The Way, I want to know.
Let Me Know ♪
All set.
♪ These tears like paint spreading ♪
♪ Is there an end Perhaps ♪
Miss Go Bok Sil.
Hey! Don't! No, go away! Don't touch!
- It's not that.
- Don't! No!
No! Go away! Don't touch!
What are you d...?
Miss Go Bok Sil, you can go home today.
Okay.
I will clean everything up before we leave.
Yes, please do.
We're sorry.
Here.
I'll get it.
You got one here.
It's not all clean here yet.
No, no. Let me.
- Why?
- I'll get it.
- Why? Your wrist hurts.
- No, I'll get it.
- It'll hurt.
- It's okay.
Sister-in-law!
- They're here!
- In Seong, put down the blankets.
Yes, yes.
Move, move.
Oh, Bok Sil! Are you alright?
Yes.
- What do I do?
- Here, lie down.
Our Bok Sil, you must've been really
shocked. Maid 1, Maid 2, Maid 3, Maid 4
You got hurt a lot.
I'm okay.
It was tough, right?
I'm okay. You're treating
me like a patient.
You need to take a rest. Sleep.
Why did he take our innocent Bok Sil
and make her go through all that?
That damn bastard. Wait until I catch him,
I'll break his legs into three pieces!
So, did they catch the culprit?
He's hurt and still unconscious.
That guy at the hospital has high chances of
being an illegal immigrant and a hit man.
We've been keeping an eye
on him for that reason.
What?
How can a person like that be a brother of
President Baek's hometown friend? Isn't it weird?
It's just my speculation, but I think he
could be a person President Baek hired.
If President Baek hired a hit man...?
Aish...
That guy is such a weirdo.
Wait, wait!
Hello.
Yes... Where did the guy who
was in front of you go?
He just left.
Do you know him well?
No. What's the matter?
Yeah... It's nothing.
President Baek might
have known much earlier
that dead Louis was actually alive.
But why was he hiding it?
Louis
I just wanted a minor fender
bender, not such a huge accident!
What are you going to do? How will you
take the responsibility?! A person died!
You think we did it on purpose?
We just followed our plan,
but he suddenly started speeding
making the accident big.
Only if the matter hadn't
gotten out of hand back then,
I wouldn't have attempted a
plan to cover up that crime.
What does it matter now?
Detective Nam, Secretary
Goo's still unconscious?
You have to ask him right away when he
wakes up, why he kidnapped Bok Sil, okay?
I will take care of things here,
you should try to get some sleep.
You've exhausted so much
energy since yesterday.
You did too, Detective. Alright.
Thank you for your trouble. Bye.
It's warm milk.
Drink it and take a nap.
Butler Kim.
Yes, Young Master.
May I drive?
Why all of a sudden?
I want to drive Bok Sil myself.
You always whined to drive,
even back in France.
You're right.
But you screwed up by taking President Baek's car without
permission and driving away on the day of your return to Korea.
I'm not sure if Chairwoman would let you.
What? What do you mean
driving without permission?
I heard that you took off in the car while
President Baek went to the restroom.
You go ahead. Something urgent came up,
so I have to stop by the company first.
- You can drive, right?
- Okay.
I didn't do that.
Excuse me?
To be honest, I was very suspicious
about President Baek in many respects.
Like that time he had your baby tooth
and watch taken from the Busan house,
and the time I ran into him, while
I was asking around about you.
But he ended up bringing you back,
so I had to believe him.
Hello. He did seem pretty
shocked to see me that time.
I got all my memories back.
It was the same when he
heard I got my memory back.
What?
The reason I shouldn't return alive...
The reason I shouldn't
get my memory back...
What could it be?
Who is here at this hour?
I'm sorry for stopping by so late.
No problem. I was planning on
going to see you tomorrow anyway.
Does that mean you know why I'm here?
Ji Sung... I'm sorry.
I did a terrible thing to you
for which I deserve to die.
Ahjussi...
I didn't plan,
such a huge accident from the beginning.
I mean to leave Gold Group to Louis.
Without consulting me
at all, the Chairwoman
all of a sudden said that
she'd give Gold Group to you.
At that moment, I got so mad. Gold Group
was a company that I spent
my youth to build up.
After your father died, I served
the Chairwoman like my own mother.
It was so easy for her to
push me aside and decide
to give you everything, when you
were in a faraway foreign land.
That decision really aggrieved me.
If I get you hurt a little
bit with a traffic accident,
I thought the Chairwoman would get
scared and send you back to France.
But things got bigger.
The accident spun out of control.
It's the truth, Ji Sung.
Since the day you, who were
thought to be dead, came back,
I didn't have a single
day of peace of mind.
I was always worried that
my crime would be revealed,
and I lived like a fugitive.
Ahjussi...
I'm thankful to you for staying
by Grandma's side up to now
in place of my late parents and me.
Louis...
I think that I'll be able to
forgive you just because of that,
but still... someone died
because of the accident.
I'm going to accept the
punishment for my sins.
I was already getting things
ready to turn myself in.
I already told Lawyer Hwang to
transfer all the company shares
that I got from the Chairwoman to you, too.
Ahjusshi...
When it comes to people,
when they start getting greedy,
their conscience also begins
to dwindle without an end.
There's one thing that's
still weighing on my mind.
The Chairwoman might collapse
if she finds out about this.
That worries me.
Don't worry about that.
I'll make sure Grandmother never knows.
I don't want to make her sad.
Thank you, Louis.
Detective 1-3 Team
Please take good care of Ma Ri and
her mother while I'm not there.
Okay. Don't worry.
I came to turn myself in.
I'm thankful to you for putting down
everything and admitting your crimes,
but there's a part of your statement that doesn't coincide with
Mr. Goo Jeong Hoon's, so I'll have to interrogate you together.
What?
President Baek ordered me to do everything,
from the car accident to kidnapping Go Bok Sil.
What are you talking about? This
man threatened me for money.
Me?
I've never asked him for money.
That's not true. He's framing me.
This man was trying to kidnap my daughter, and
ended up kidnapping Go Bok Sil accidentally.
I'm just an employee at a
private investigator's office.
I just did what he ordered me to do.
That's not true.
I didn't do that!
I know it won't be easy to believe
what I say in this kind of situation,
but I really didn't do it, Louis.
I heard a rundown of
everything from Detective Nam.
Do you have anything you can use as proof?
I definitely brought the bag of
money and went to the bookstore,
but it was after Secretary
Goo had disappeared.
They said there are no CCTV's
around the bookstore area.
There's no way to prove it.
The bookstore, you said?
Director Cha. I've got
something for you to do.
Are you sure that's the car?
Ah, you surprised me.
Don't whisper in my ear.
Yes. He's been there for a few days now.
In that spot, just like that.
Then shall we head over first?
He's excited, so excited. Jeez!
This is the police. I have
a few things to ask you.
I caught him!
Stay still. Stop moving!
Wow, where did all these
pictures come from?
There was a stalker following Mrs. Audrey.
- A stalker?
- Yes.
He set up camp in front of the store and
took pictures. We confiscated all of it.
Detective, you have to take
care of this one. Okay?
Of course.
If you look at this picture, you
can see the both of them talking.
And look here. You can see that Ahjussi Seon
Gu brought the bag of money the very next day.
Now, his story is proven, right?
Wow. You could become a detective.
Your eye for things is awesome.
But! Why did you go to the
bookstore, Detective Nam?
The atmosphere looks so warm and cozy.
It's hard for a woman to run
a bookstore by herself.
Also, she was a big help in finding Louis.
Since I was so thankful to her, I'd carry heavy
books for her and help her out from time to time.
Anyway, you're so nosy. You're in the final
stages of your Servant's Disease. Terminal!
Why did you go so far as kidnapping
Go Bok Sil, no, I mean, Baek Ma Ri?
What did you do with the bag
of money you got before?
My bag of money got snatched,
so I had no other option.
That grandmother seriously had
unreal skills like a ghost!
A professional pickpocketing grandmother?
Detective Nam, what are you doing?
Oh. Did you get the CCTV footage?
I got her identity as well.
Her name is Jo Ha Ni. She has
9 prior larceny convictions.
She's someone I've caught before.
Do you know her residence as well?
This is my field of specialty.
I've already sent the guys.
Good work.
Stop trying to get out of this now.
The CCTV captured everything.
That isn't me.
It's someone who looks like me.
Seriously.
I'm glad that it's all better.
Still, you can't overwork it, okay?
Okay.
Let's stop by the police
station on our way out.
I told Ahjussi Seon Gu to
apologize to you in person.
He's not even the one who did it.
But still, he must be having a hard time.
Let's at least greet him and then go home.
Okay.
Ms. Jo Ha Ni, let's hurry and finish up.
Where did you hide that bag of money?
You really don't believe
what other people say.
Omo, what time is it already?
Is it okay to detain a person like
this without any proof, Mr. Detective?
Ah, this grandma, seriously.
Detective!
Oh, Bok Sil.
Grandmother!
Grandma!
My grandma also had cold hands, you know.
Grandmother, I won't ask or argue with
you about you lying about your grandson.
I just want you to give that money back.
It belongs to someone that I know.
I-I told you that I don't
know anything about that.
Mr. Detective must be waiting for me.
I see your hurt leg is all better now.
That's a relief.
Aigoo, what kind of clothes are
these for a young girl to wear?
It's so old-fashioned.
I don't wear this kind of stuff.
Then give me those clothes
back and go in your undies.
This is the first time I've seen a
girl so obsessed with her clothes!
This was my late mom's.
I'm sorry.
Don't take to heart what a silly
old woman like me says to you.
Go and live well.
Living in Seoul is pretty tough.
Yes, ma'am. You find your
grandson too, Grandmother!
Grandmother!
With this, at least buy yourself a meal.
Return home safely.
I'm remembering such useless things.
It's so annoying.
Call the Detective for me.
I'll tell you where the bag is.
Really? Then I'll go get the detective.
I never knew I, the Black Sable, would
exchange 1 million USD with $10.
Kang Ji Sung wanted to clear
you of your false accusations
and even found evidence. You
shouldn't be like this.
Someone died in that accident. Who would
believe that you had no intent to kill anyone?
Detective, this is so unfair.
Frankly, wasn't it your guilty conscience
which led you to even bribe me?
Please make sure to give me a call when the
unconscious patient in the hospital wakes up.
You don't have to give
me something like this.
That was... because I was worried about
when Secretary Goo would wake up.
There was no other hidden motive behind it.
I retrieved the money bag.
And we discovered this.
There's an audio recording in here.
- Secretary Goo, you just have to cause a simple fender-bender.
- Isn't it better to get rid of him while you've got the chance?
No, even if Ji Sung gets hurt a little bit,
the Chairwoman will send him back to France.
Don't complicate the matter needlessly.
There aren't any more copies
of this recording, right?
Of course not.
Secretary Goo lied to me!
This is a relief.
Thank you.
Detective, thank you so much.
I found it thanks to Bok
Sil, so thank her later.
Thanks to this, your sentence
will decrease drastically.
Thank you. Seriously.
I owe you guys so much.
Thank you, Louis.
So the President of Joong Won's workplace
got arrested for something shameful?
It must be unsettling for
the company and employees.
I'm more worried about my
Audrey than the company.
She must be having a hard time after
sending her husband off to prison.
Jae Sook, sorry for always being irritable.
I haven't been in the
right mind for a while.
I committed a sin and I've
been so focused on that.
But just know that I've been
having a hard time too.
I will gladly pay back for what I did,
so stay healthy and well with Ma Ri.
I want to thank you for being
always kind to Louis in my place.
Will I ever be able to repay
you all the debts I owe you?
Why did he? Why?
Why did you do this?
I looked for it everywhere. Are
you sure you left it here?
Absolutely. I'm sure.
I told you I was right.
When I came here last time,
it definitely wasn't there.
Since you are getting older,
get some reading glasses.
I still have 20/20 vision.
Stop attacking me about my age.
I'm going to get upset.
Ahjussi Seon Gu said that when you
get older, you sweat when you eat.
Becoming more tearful, is
that also because of the age?
Young Master...
Okay.
Here is the 30th anniversary music box.
"Go Bo Ssi"
Hello Go Bo Ssi.
You treasured him so much that you
even wrote his name down here.
I been wanting to ask you this,
but what is "Go Bo Ssi"?
Is it a name of a seed? (Ssi
means a seed in Korean.)
It's the name of a very cute
kid with a beautiful smile.
That kid must be living a good life, right?
Probably, I guess.
Anyway, it's a relief that
you got your memory back.
After your supposed death, the Chairwoman
was looking for this box everywhere.
Grandma did? Why?
Because this contains
Chairwoman's treasured memories.
Chairwoman, I finally found it.
Really?
You wanted to look at it so badly,
so look at it as much as you want.
March 15, 1996. Mom, Dad, Ji Sung.
I will be outside.
Okay.
Their voices... their voices...
I missed them so much.
Should we jump? One.. Two... Three! Whee!
Was that fun?
My son Geum Seok, daughter-in-law...
I miss you.
What should I do?
Chairwoman...
Did Sister-in-law go somewhere?
It's brother-in-law.
Oh yeah, brother-in-law.
The name I learned first
got stuck in my head.
He went out to play.
It must be so hard for him to keep
his butt in contact with the floor.
It's okay if he goes out a bit. I really
wanted to wander around at that age,
I'm sad that I couldn't.
Okay.
Oh yeah, Louis!
This, this.
Are you giving this to me?
It's what you earned and
saved, so this is yours.
If there was something you
wanted to buy, go buy it.
Should I get a present for grandmother?
Yeah, do that.
Usually with your first paycheck, you're supposed
to buy red thermal undergarments for your parents.
Buy your grandmother some undergarments.
No. I want to buy something else.
What?
There's something like that.
Grandmother, I bought this with the
money I earned while working hard.
It wasn't a paycheck from Gold
Group but my real first paycheck.
Louis.
Bok Sil told me to buy red
undergarments, but I bought these.
You are a silver angel wearing high heels.
Oh my goodness, how did you choose
the ones that I really like?
Try them on!
Yes, okay.
Aigoo, yes!
Aigoo, they fit perfectly!
How is it? Does it suit me?
Perfect.
These are high heels that were
created in this world just for you.
What really came into
this world just for me
is you, Louis.
Thank you so much
for coming to me.
Grandma...
- Why isn't Grandma coming?
- I'll go get her.
No, I'll go.
Grandma! My Grandma!
Grandma, get up. We set the table.
Grandma!
Grandma.
Grandma...
Grandma!
I'm sorry for coming so late, Grandma.
Chairwoman, if you leave me like
this, what am I going to do?
Grandma!
Goodbye, Grandma.
♪ Now the end is near♪
♪ And so I face, the final curtain♪
♪ My friend, I'll say it clear♪
♪ I'll state my case,
of which I'm certain.♪
♪ I've lived a life that's full♪
♪ I've travelled each and every highway♪
♪ And more...♪
People buy things with
different values in mind.
If you look at someone's purchase pattern,
you can understand who that person is.
♪ Regrets I've had a few♪
♪ But then again, too few to mention♪
♪ I did what I had to do♪
But Grandma, why do you wear stilettos
even though your back hurts?
♪ Without exception♪
Because to your grandmother, who
always wants to live young,
stilettos are like an attitude toward life.
When I wear heels, this
stooped-over back becomes straight,
and my gait becomes energetic.
♪ I did it♪
I always wanted to walk like that.
Young and confidently.
♪ I'm sure you knew♪
♪ When I bit off more then I could chew♪
♪ But through it all♪
The one who came into
this world truly for me
is you, Louis.
Thank you so much for coming to me.
♪ And I stood tall♪
♪ and did it my way♪
♪ At some point, you ♪
A good amount of time passed, but it still felt like something
was missing in the empty space Grandma left behind.
♪ I'm fine with it. ♪
And then one day...
♪ The time we are spending together today ♪
Jeong Ran. Jeong Ran!
A new life came into our house.
As if it were Grandma's gift to us.
Jeong Ran.
I love you.
♪ I think I feel a little bit sorry ♪
I'm dizzy!
My beloved Butler Kim
hasn't been able to properly propose
because he's still analyzing things.
And the Queen of Stubbornness Go Bok Sil is ignoring
me when I tell her to live with me at my house,
and is still insistently
living in our rooftop room.
- Bok Sil, I'm here!
- You're here?
- Hyung!
- Oh, Brother-in-law was home, too.
- I'm taking a break at home today.
- There are too many people outside on the weekends.
- Yes, I see.
I made some ramyun, so let's eat it
together. Bok Nam said he wanted some.
I did well, didn't I?
Yeah. Aish, I wanted to
eat out with Bok Sil...
- Louis and Bok Nam, set the table up!
- Okay.
Is it working now?
Yes. I'm finished with the repairs,
and I also got the tape out of it.
Thank you.
What is it?
Where did this come from?
It's good!
- Yes, Ahjumma Audrey. How is it going?
- Louis!
I have a present to give you!
What present?
♪ On the road which is as difficult as
being in a maze for the first time. ♪
♪ I can't speed up unlike
my pressing heart. ♪
♪ On Love Way which is moving like a snail
whether due to traffic or an accident ♪