Time of the wolf
Ben! Leave the birdcage in the car until the house has warmed up.
But it's hungry!
It will last for 10 minutes.
Take that box instead.
Will help me, Eva?
It's wet at the bottom. Don't soil your clothes, Ben.
Where shall I put that one?
Doesn't matter! Put it anywhere.
Let's see...
- Freeze!
Close the door and come back.
What are you doing here?
I mean... How did you get in here?
What do you want?
Please. Put the gun down.
Stay put, or I will shoot!
What did you think? This is private property.
You can't simply ...
Tell them to leave.
- Shut up!
And take the baby away.
Let's talk this through.
Surely, we can work this out.
He shall leave!
We are not your enemies...
How long do you plan to stay?
Do you have food? For how long?
For long.
We share some with you, if you want.
Where do you come from? Are you from the city?
How much gas do you have?
It's almost gone.
Water?
Just some bottles.
Will you let the children go?
I implore you!
Get into the car.
Eva, take Ben and get outside.
What do they want?
Check that box.
Listen: We will get our things inside.
You killed him!
Be quiet!
Enough! Shut up! Scram!
Scram!
Leave!
Come on! Leave! Take him an leave.
My husband was shot.
But you do know me!
So...?
There are people in our cottage. They shot Schorsch!
They took our car and the provisions.
I am very sorry.
It's your duty to help us.
You do know the situation.
Do you just act stupid?
Why did you come here from the city in the first place?
Take the children an leave.
Go away.
Madame Ordnaire!
I know that you can here me.
I will be back shortly.
Eva will stay with you.
I'll find some food. Probably even a place to sleep.
Take care.
Come here Benny.
Try to get some sleep.
I'll make as fast as I can.
Come on! You must sleep now.
Don't come here again. My husband must not know!
You have always been kind to me, too.
I can't give you any more.
Good luck.
Wait! I'll give it a try.
You must get it!
It won't escape us.
Please! It must not escape!
Now!
Look out! It's getting away!
I know! Quiet!
Stay there!
Come on! Get it down!
Be quiet!
Your shouting is scaring it.
Quiet... Shit!
What?
Lie down! Don't move.
Take a clean tissue.
Put your head back. Come on!
Calm down.
When you stay calm, I'll get the bird for you.
Promise.
Come on.
You do want to go to Benny, don't you?
Quiet... There we go!
There it is.
Sleep now!
Mom! Mom wake up!
Mom! Benny is gone!
What?
- Benny! He is gone!
He way lying next to me, now he is gone.
Get more hay.
- Can you give me the lighter?
Take care not to burn down the barn.
- I know.
Benny! Where are you?
You must light it outside.
There is so much falling down.
There is too much lying on the floor.
We need more. Go, get more.
It's no use like this. We must go looking for him.
Can you keep the fire burning?
- Sure.
Give me the lighter. You must keep it burning brightly.
When it dies down, I won't find my way back to you.
Did you understand?
Don't worry. We will find  him!
Don't go! I'm scared!
Me too. But don't worry.
We will find him.
Keep it burning and be careful.
I will go now.
Eva, I love you! Don't you forget that!
Benny! Can you hear me?
Get over here! To the light!
Benny! If you can hear me, answer me!
Is there somebody there? Hello? Anybody?
Our jackets burned!
What have done? Are you too stupid to be careful?
Why did you leave!
If you had stayed, none this would have happened.
Eva! Eva! Don't run away!
I'm sorry. I didn't mean it.
It's all to much for me to bear.
You did your best.
Benny!
Stay where you are!
Stay there!
Please, let my boy go.
I think it's him.
- Who?
The one I saw last night.
Where do you come from? Please let him go.
Why should we want to you any harm?
Thank you! Come here!
You are freezing. Where have you been?
You can't simply run away.
Promise me you won't run away again.
Don't you want to stay?
Come on.
Where did you find Benny?
Won't you tell me?
Is there something wrong with you? Are you hurt?
May I see it? I may be able to help you?
Are those sheep yours?
Tonight some sheep were close by. I could hear them scream.
Are you freezing? Give me the jacket?
- Mom, he is not freezing.
Did you catch a cold? What is wrong with you, Benny?
What?
Leave him be. He is just tired.
Do you have something to drink?
Can you spare some?
- What will I get in return?
What's your name?
It's no use being nice to me.
Why not?
I'm not a nice person is why
Did you always think of yourself as that?
What you are telling me...
is hard for me to believe.
Where do you come from?
Why do you want to know?
Be fair. I helped you out, so you can should me.
Do you have jewellery? Or maybe a radio with batteries?
Why?
And that bike?
- What's with the bike?
Did you cross the railway?
- Yes.
Was that far away from here?
- Three, maybe four hours.
There is a train station to the south. Trains are stopping there.
The personal is said to be corrupt.
Who did that?
- Who did what?
Died of thirst. Or it drank too much polluted water.
Or the Sheppard slaughtered them to drink their blood.
It was dogs.
- What dogs?
What dogs? What dogs? The dogs from the villages.
They don't have anything to eat.
That's a normal thing. They will anything they can find.
Shit.
Two day old. Full of maggots.
Let's go.
What are you doing?
- Eva. Come on.
Do you honestly believe you will last long with only one jacket?
I didn't even have a lighter.
And your lighter won't last forever, too.
Come on!
He doesn't need it any more.
Stop! Stop!
Stop! Please!
STOP!
Stop! Wait for us!
Wait for us!
Hello.
You can go inside, there are other people too.
I am Anna Loren. These are my children Eva and Ben.
We are from the city.
Other people? I don't understand you...
Where are those other people? We didn't see anyone.
How many people stay here?
- He doesn't understand you.
I know. Be quiet!
It's so cold in here.
May I start a fire?
Did the train stop here?
The train... Outside?
Hello.
Where do you come from?
We are from the City.
I am Anna Loren. These are my children Eva and Ben.
Hello. My wife, my daughter.
What do you want here?
The boy tried to steal something...
I see. Thank you.
I can't understand hoe you can stay so calm?
Did you steal something from me?
It's not so easy. The woman is right.
If we give up the most basic rules, we can give up anything.
What is it you could give up?
Are you the one in here to look after the order of things, Mr. Koslowski?
Why you? Because you carry a gun?
Do  you want to impress us?
Shut up.
Empty your bags.
Shall I take them away from you?
Let go of the boy!
- I told you to shut up!
Before you and your wife showed up here, we stuck to the rules.
Rules that are necessary for living together in a civilised manner.
You call this "civilised"?
The rules stay the way they are. They apply to you too! Understood?
If you don't like it, pack you wife and child an leave.
I told you to let go of the boy.
Do you want to get beat up?
Who do you think you are? Why is it you, that makes the rules?
If you would...
Eva.
Please mom, let me go.
Don't you dare coming back!
- Fuck off!
Please, let me talk to him.
Mom? Please? I'll be back.
Honestly, you didn't steal anything?
- No!
Then I'll tell them that.
- I don't care!
You don't want to go back, do you?
- I'll leave.
Don't come nay closer!
- But your hand...
Does it still hurt?
How did that happen?
It doesn't matter, who cares?
Did you get in a fight? With whom?
Won't you tell me?
- No.
Please, don't go.
I prefer to be alone.
- I don't believe that.
Forget it. See you later.
Do you know what that is?
Those guys spectacles.
- But you...
I can use those to make a fire.
Your mother has a lighter.
Will you give them to me? I'll return them.
They will et you inside again.
You just don't get it.
Possibly the train will really stop here.
I'll stick around.
Would be stupid if I missed it.
Why don't you obey me?
I did come back, didn't I?
You have to do as you are told.
- Hah!
You won't hit me again.
Did you talk to him?
Can you spare a cigarette?
Sure. There.
I don't have may left
Don't worry. Apart from us, no one is smoking here.
Are you from the city?
- Isn't that obvious?
Which district?
- The 11th.
Are you here long?
- So, Just six days.
And the others?
- Some longer, some shorter.
Koslowski said, the last train pass ten days ago.
Did it stop?
Looks like it. Otherwise they would all still be here.
My name is Bea, but please call me "Be".
- I am Anna.
Do you want?
- Yes. Thank you.
Do you have anything you can swap?
- What?
It depends. I don't know what counts.
I have some jewellery.
The bike is quite good.
Keep it as long as possible,... and the lighter too.
- My watch?
Useless.
And you?
- Me?
I don't have a thing. That? Don't mention it.
Koslowski can be paid in other ways.
Do you think he is one of the "just"?
Pardon?
It's hard to realise, even if you are fucking.
But he has complete control over all of us.
probably he is one of the "just".
At least it would be nice that way, wouldn't it?
What do you mean by "just"?
Once, I knew one...
My friend Manfred was one of them.
You can't simply tell from looking, that's the funny part.
There are 36 altogether.
Since the beginning there were 36. Always.
They guarantee our existence...
and that God protects us.
If only one of them is missing... everything will go.
Really?
- Yes.
I'm not sure with Koslowski.
But now I am almost positive...
Where do you want to get it?
What does a winch cost?
- It's up to you.
Please, excuse me.
Eva, what happened?
They can't stop the train because they can't move the wagons.
Listen. It's all quite simple.
If you want to leave here, we must force the train to stop.
If we used a roadblock it could derail.
Quiet! Listen to me!
We must move to wagons over to the right rail track.
So? What do you want to do? Everyone must contribute to this.
We cant use the winch outside, because it needs electricity to work.
I could try to get hold of a hand operated winch.
But you must understand that it will cost you.
Does everybody understand that?
Make up your minds. And don't blame me for wanting to help you.
Quite the contrary, Mr. Koslowski. We love you for your selflessness.
Why do you have to stir things up all the time, Madame Brandt?
Nobody did invite you. Nobody forces you to stay.
When does the next train come? What, when there are no trains any more?
What, when others stop the train before us?
Don't you touch me!
What if they don't take us, because we don't have anything to swap?
All the time you want something for water, food and winches.
Do you have a better idea? Why don't you drive to the village...
I mean you no harm...
- Quiet!
Excuse me... Listen... Information of supplies.
In the north everything is under control.
Only few supplies from the south...
...increasing losses...
...only little diesel, little personal...
...little meat because of polluted water...
...cutting down rations...
...and the usual instructions for power saving.
Is that all?
Are you joking?
Always the same! Probably someone else should be taking over radio duty.
You sounding like an oracle is frustrating!
I only tried to repeat the facts. I am sorry...
I am sorry.
Stop apologising!
How dare you say something like that?
My husband tries to report as accurately as possible.
And you insult him as a response!
Have you all gone mad?
I don't want to sit there like her, because my husband was run over by a train.
I want to know, when we move on.
I don't want to waste more time.
Don't you have any sympathy?
- Sympathy?
You are talking about sympathy? I can't afford any sympathy.
I'm content with that puddle of blood outside.
You and you sympathy. Show this woman some of your sympathy!
Shut up. Your praying makes me sick.
I think we had enough!
Thank you.
I'm sorry. I was in a rage.
Sure. I can understand that.
My dear husband was able to show us, how to behave.
Mr. Azoulay is the great news reporter again...
... and Mrs. Azoulay's honour has been restored.
- Stop.
And with a great gesture he put his shitty wife in her place.
You have enlightened me. Thank you!
Finished you performance?
Why doesn't he puke from being that self-content?
What do you say, Mr. Koslowski?
Instead of hitting you, he rather beats me.
It doesn't matter. He always has moral on his side.
Some day I'm gone kill you.
I hope that day comes soon.
Stop it. I can't stand it any more.
Please, stop it.
If only because of the children. Stop it.
You should be ashamed of yourselves.
Rest assured that we are ashamed of ourselves.
But you should be ashamed of yourself too.
Come... Let's be ashamed.
Did you realise they didn't bark?
Yes. You're right.
When they burned the cattle in the village, there was a whole pack.
None of them barked.
They are in all those towns.
Since they don't have food or water any more
they roam around.
They have become more careful.
Mean.
and why did you...
- Because I was stupid!
I lured one in using some meat.
He stayed with me.
Followed me, as if we were friends.
Two days before I met you, it bit me.
Why?
- Why? Because it was mad.
Because it wanted some meat. What do I know?
Probably it was mad at me, because I couldn't feed it enough.
Doesn't matter. It's my on fault.
Wanting to have a mad dog a friend.
Where is it now?
- I beat it to death.
And in doing so spilled all the burning ash.
What are you doing?
- Nothing.
What are your plans now?
- Nothing. What is there to do?
Take it. I hope it's of some use.
- Hm.
Well...
See you soon. I have to get back.
Aren't you freezing?
- I'm used to it.
I don't know if I can be back tomorrow, but...
...if I come I will bring you some food.
Mom did swap her jewellery...
... Koslowski has some good contacts in the village. He got me the ointment too.
Eva!
There.
50 litres. Maximum.
Give me some water, please. Please.
Koslowski isn't giving us enough. We are six persons.
My husband, my sister and me can work.
We work harder than others and my child is sick.
I implore you.
Please. We don't have anything to swap.
We only have what we are wearing.
You have to argue with him.
- No.
He doesn't give us any. Me has no mercy.
I implore you! I do anything you want. Do with me what you want.
Please stop. Don't cause trouble.
We can help you out, can't we?
Can't we discuss that later?
- No. Not later!
No!
Later, there will only be two glasses per person.
Please, give me some water!
I implore you! Otherwise you can beat me to death right here.
How much are ten litres?
A rich man? What do you have?
We don't have much. We are waiting for the train.
Don't you say!
I beg you! Don't go.
What would you give in exchange for a bike?
I don't really need a bike.
A watch?
Nice. You should have given that one up sooner.
Thanks. No more for you.
We have other customers to serve. Bye.
Dear Dad,
Now, that I have found a pen and paper...
I must write you.
So much is happening, and there is no one whom it could talk with.
I don't know, if you can see or hear or read this...
or if you are able to sense anything at all.
But I so much want to believe you can.
My dearest dad,
It's so hard, to put all this into words...
when there is no one to talk to...
it feels like I am suffocation on all this.
You might ask, why I don't talk to Benny or mom?
But I can't. You would know about it, if you were here.
I have to think about every word I say to mom,
because otherwise she will suffer breakdown.
Her hands are constantly shaking and I can't help her.
I don't think, that Benny could understand, what you can, dad.
An then there is this boy...
...I could talk to him.
But he acts so proud, and
as if he cares for nothing at all.
Even if I know that's not the case.
It must seem very confusing to you.
But that's the main reason I write all this down.
I hope it makes more sense in writing.
I want to tell you one thing after another,
so you can understand the life we are leading.
We get up early every morning.
Simply, because someone gets up early,
and wakes all the others.
We work every day...
Arina! The boy is dying!
Where do you come from?
- Aren't you one of us?
Look out, dammit!
Put the canisters below the roof? Look out.
Behind the building there is a pool with rainwater...
...you can wash up with it, if you feel like it.
Hey! Excuse me. Those are our things.
What?
- This is our spot.
So what?
- Let's go outside.
Move somewhere else!
- What does this make your spot?
Because the horses drink too much, we will slaughter three of them.
There will be fresh meat for all of us.
Excuse me.
- Yes?
I wanted to ask, what you are doing here?
- Are you not one of our group?
We are waiting for the train.
- What train?
What are you doing here? Where do you want to go?
- Away, of course.
Excuse me.
The water was expensive. You can't simply take it.
I did understand that. So?
- What's going on?
Nothing. He is all fired up, because we take some of his water.
Are you the one who is responsible?
- Everyone here is responsible.
Suddenly it gets a little crowded.
Is he all mad again?
- Yes.
But is right.
How is your young friend?
Did you see him again?
- Yes.
We should light another fire, if a train should come.
Otherwise the train will simply run by.
That would be really  bad.
If we started another fire,
maybe the train brakes and stops.
Give it to me. Now look.
What's going on? What's going on?
Mh, tastes good.
Let's see how that razor-blade tastes.
Here. Give it a try.
Yes. You! Come on!
Come on! Eat it! Don't be a sissy.
Hey. You don't even swallow!
Don't be a sissy!
You have to careful.
Otherwise you cut yourself.
Hey, come on...
I told you to get rid of the bike.
Otherwise people will hurt themselves.
It has to go.
It's nothing.
Please. Some Milk.
Please?
What? Am I daydreaming?
What do we have here?
It's the Pollack from the village. Boy are we glad to see you.
The bastard that worked at Francois'.
And suddenly Francois was dead.
Just like that. And the Pollacks were gone.
Didn't think we would meet again so soon, eh?
You will look at me, when I'm talking to you, Pollack.
Wait. Leave them.
Pig!
Bastard!
Take this.
- Thank you.
Mom.
What are you doing here?
- Leave me alone.
With all these people, there will be something left over for me.
That's why I'm here.
What's with the goats? What do they get to drink?
Water, I guess.
No. You can't do that.
There are little children with the group!
The milk is for them. That's why they feed the goats.
If you...
Hey, wake up.
Mom!
I swear! I never saw that woman before.
No! Liar! That's a lie!
Ask the children. They don't lie
I say it again! It's untrue!
Ask my wife! We have never been in this area before.
Leave him be!
- You bastard!
Murderer! Pig!
Let go of him!
- You bastard!
Please be reasonable.
Listen. Everyone can see that the woman is not lying.
What can I say? It's absurd!
Everybody could accuse everyone.
What's going on?
- The woman says that the he shot her husband.
Where did that take place?
- It's not true!
What's going on?
She says it has happened in their cottage.
When?
Some days ago.
On Sunday.
The 17th.
Impossible! We still were in the city then.
My wife and the boy will state that too.
Do you have proof?
- My husband is dead! He is dead.
You know that is no proof.
- But...
Ask my children. He is dead.
I'm sorry. I can't decide that now.
Please calm down. We will settle that all later.
Put up the tarps. Hurry!
Please come inside. You're getting all wet.
Hurry. Come on.
Benny! Where is Benny?
Ben! Benny!
How would you decide?
You accuse each other. Correct?
Neither of you have proof.
Whom shall I believe?
I am n judge.
My friends and I just try to keep chaos at bay. That's all.
I'm sorry.
Probably one of your "just"?
Anyway, in Pont Monterre,
I have seen one of them with my own eyes.
In the middle of the town square he undressed and leapt into the fire.
Burning like a torch.
I thought I couldn't believe my eyes?
- Don't tell such stories.
I'm serious. They will redeem us.
They are everywhere. Well "everywhere" is probably a bit exaggerated.
Everywhere where there are mad people.
In Pont Monterre. In Vogne.
They say in Arrieux there were several.
They jump in the flames all naked an burn to their deaths.
They sacrifice themselves for us.
So the damned world will be alright again.
I guess they are belong to your "just".
On the other hand... When they are of the "just"...
Everybody that burns in the flames,
is one "just" less.
You said they were 36, didn't you?
So the world can keep on turning.
So what does logic tell us?
Your 36 are a different team.
Excuse me.
- Yes?
Do you want some?
- No. No, thank you.
What is it then?
- What was that music you played yesterday?
Did you like it? Sit down.
Hold that.
Glad you liked that music.
Gimme.
I forgot to pack some salt.
Now I have to swap two pair of socks for it.
You would like to hear it again, wouldn't you?
- Yes. Please.
I rewound it with my finger.
You have to do that too, understand?
Georges! Over here!
Get up! Get up you bastard.
What do you want?
- Shut up!
Get outside, before I put a bullet in your head right here.
What's going on? What did my husband do?
Shut up!
- Did he commit a crime?
Let him go! Let him go
- What did he do?
Are you insane? I asked you what he did to you.
Listen, smart-ass!
It's none of your business, but anyway:
Your nice foreign buddy and his brood...
they steal everything they can get their hands on.
And not only since we are here.
Ain't it so?
I know you, my dear fellow.
Back in my village he killed a farmer and stole his stuff.
That's not true. I swear that's no true.
Certainly! You want to accuse me of killing that farmer? Filthy pig!
None of that is true.
What's going on?
Have you all gone mad?
I have been robbed. Meat, water and a goat are missing.
We just found out. I'm sure he took it.
Since we are on our journey, no one ever stole anything from us.
That's not true. My husband was here all night.
Where should he out your goat. That's ridiculous!
You should have kept your eyes open.
Who was on night watch?
Maybe Koslowski knows where the things have gone.
That's too low. Do you want to accuse me?
Maybe it was the boy.
- What boy?
She knows him. He stole some spectacles before.
Why did you do that?
I thought you would stick with us, when we travel on.
I never said that.
- Really?
Great! So now everything is fine!
Because of you they almost killed the foreign man.
They need the milk for their children.
I don't find goats every day.
You don't care what people say, do you?
Don't you care about anyone?
Generally no.
What is it?
I'm sorry!
The girl killed herself.
Why?
I thought you could help me?
- With what?
With everything.
But you destroy everything.
Your dog...
Now it works.
- You think that will fit?
Those are my daughters clothes. Maybe they fit your children.
Thank you.
Would you help me to bury my daughter?
I´m sorry. I can't do it on my own. It's too much.
Ok. I'll make my round.
What's going on? What are you doing there?
Are you mad? Are you completely insane?
What are you doing?
Get over here, please. Please?
I won't harm you. Come here.
Please believe me. I won't harm you.
The horses! The run into the flames.
No!
- Calm down. Everything is alright.
Let go of me!
- Stop it. Calm down.
Let go of me! Let go of me!
Calm down! It's alright!
What in God's name did they tell you?
You can't believe all those things they talk about.
He's getting on our nerves too with his nonsense.
That razor-blade-idiot.
Probably he believes in it himself.
You got guts.
Tell me, where are your parents?
Where are they?
Why do they let you run around at this time?
You would have walked into the flames. That's for sure.
But believe me, the fact that you wanted to...
that's enough. You are brave.
Everything will be alright.
Probably tomorrow a car arrives...
a fast racing-car, you know?
You like those, don't you?
And a man jumps out and tells that everything is alright again.
And water runs into your mouth,
and the doves fly. And maybe the dead come back to live.
It's enough that you really wanted it.
I'll tell everyone, how brave you are.
subs by
gesabbel