LET THE RIGHT ONE IN
Squeal like a pig.
Squeal!
Squeal like a pig!
The police have ways
to determine foul play.
You remember
that fire in Ängby, hm?
A house burned down.
A body was found inside.
We knew the fire had been set,
to conceal the fact...
the victim had been murdered
before hand.
So, how could they know that?
Well?
Go ahead.
There was no smoke in the lungs
of the person who died.
That's correct.
Did you figure that out, right now?
No... I read a lot.
What kind of books
would that be?
Just books.
Okay! I'm gonna talk to you
about drugs.
What do you figure the most
common types of drugs...
to be found in this town?
Hey, Oskar!
What are you staring at?
Huh?
Are you looking at me?
Well, fuck off.
Pig!...
What a good piggy you are.
- Come on, it's time for gym!
- Wait for me.
...the weather report...
(inaudible)
...be a little bid...
...clearing up by tonight...
(inaudible)
...again be extreamly cautious...
I can not emphasize enough...
(inaudible)
...will be extreamly dangerous...
...search and rescue effort...
(inaudible)
- Excuse me... huh?
- Yes.
You have the time?
I don't have a watch.
What's that?
Oh, this?
Huh... it's called halothane.
Hm...
- Huh, you are the first to find out.
- Get it off...
No!... Don't...
Ricky!
Beat it!
Ricky?
Ricky?!
Damn dog!
Ricky!
What're you staring at?
Well?
Are you looking at me?
Well, fuck off.
What's your problem?
Are you scared?
Squeal!
So, squeal!
What are you doing?
Huh... nothing.
- What're you doing?
- Nothing.
- Do you live here?
- Yeah...
I live back here in the jungle gym.
Seriously.
Where do you live?
Next door to you.
How do you know
where I live?
I can't be your friend.
Just so you know.
What do you mean?
Does there have to be a reason?
That's just the way it is.
What makes you think
I wanna be your friend?
You're supposed to help me!
Do I really have to
take care of myself?
Say something!
I'm sorry.
They don't know why
the young man was killed.
We realise some of you
may be scared scared.
The counselor
will be here all day.
So, go talk to her
if you feel you have the need.
Any questions?
Is it alright if we kill the killer,
if we meet him?
Conny, that's not nice.
You may go now.
O~S~k~A~R!
Oskar!
Where are you, piggy?!
Where are you, piggy?
Piggy!
Now go home
straight after school!
And don't leave the court-yard
until I come home.
It was way over there
in Vällingby.
A person who kills children.
Is certainly capable of taking
the subway to Stäsha
And walking a mile?
No, that won't be possible.
Oskar will be staying
with his dad next week.
No... no...
I already told you.
No...
I really couldn't do that.
Murder in Vällingby:
Murderer Drained Victim's Blood.
Senseless massacre in Beirut.
No survivors in Arab murders
manhunt for killer continues...
Eyewitness identifies murderer
prior to confession...
Murderer Drained Blood
From His Victim
Hey.
Hope, you didn't mind
that one, honey.
The death penalty
has no justification...
in a society
based on the rule of law.
Based on the rule of law.
The goverment wants us...
to believe...
in that crap
just like the Russians...
Are you saying
there aren't any Russians?
- Of course there are.
- Who's that guy?
- Huh?
- Never seen that guy before.
But take vipers...
does anyone actually...
get bitten?
That guy just moved into
my neighbourhood... with a kid.
He now lives up
in Janne's old place.
- He could join us? May I ask him?
- Sure!
- I don't think so.
- Yeah.
He might pay for a round and...
in that case he's welcome...
even if he's got cancer.
Bad news?
Yeah, life stinks.
Did you just move
into number 15?
You don't have to sit here all alone,
join us and have a laugh.
No thanks, I'm in a hurry.
Mom?
I'm going out.
Aren't you gonna watch
the show?
No, it's no good.
Stay in the court yard, okay?
I'll just watch it by my own.
So, you're back?
I don't need your help.
Me neither.
Then go home!
You go home.
I lived here way longer than you.
What's that?
This?
It's a... Rubik's cube.
Is that some kind of puzzle?
Yeah.
Oh...
You want to try it?
You can give it back tomorrow.
I might not be here
tomorrow.
You can return it...
the day after tomorrow, try it?
How do you play that?
You want each side
to be a solid color.
Like this.
Hey, you smell funny.
Aren't you cold?
- No.
- Why not?
I guess...
I've forgotten how.
See you tomorrow.
Mh-hm.
Ohh...
The legal issue
is really interesting, you know?
- I enjoy talking about it.
- Yeah...
Joche...
Thanks for another night
of friendship and happiness.
Good night, old buddy.
- See you tomorrow.
- Yeah.
You're the best, Jocke.
No, you are.
Help.
Help me.
Hello?
Please, help me.
Is something wrong?
Are you hurt?
- Can you get up?
- No...
I...
can't...
Ahh... come here...
I'll carry you.
Take you to a phone.
Careful... careful.
You don't weigh
a thing...
...never again...
- Gösta?
- Gösta!
- It's been ages.
- I haven't seen you all year.
- It's Jocke...
- What?
- Poor Jocke...
- Hey, what's happening?
I was out... out on the balcony...
- and I saw... I saw Jocke... and this kid.
- Calm down! Where was the kid?
It was around here somewhere.
- Somewhere?
- Where? Somewhere?
I don't see anything here.
- There's nothing here!
- Hey, move it!
Damn!
What the hell is this?
- Oh, my god.
- It's blood!
Who the hell did this?
Whew...
How did you do it?
I was turning it.
Do I smell better now?
Um... what is your name?
Eli.
What's yours?
- Eli?
- Yeah.
I'm... I'm Oskar.
How old are you?
Twelve... more or less.
And you?
12 years, eight months,
and nine days.
What'd you mean,
more or less?
When is your birthday?
I don't remember.
Don't... you...
ever celebrate your birthday?
Your parents...
they've got to know.
Don't you get any
birthday presents?
No.
You can have this if you want.
- Hm...
- It's yours.
- I don't get how you did this.
- Hm...
You want me to show you?
Here... go ahead.
You start at the corners...
and then this side...
has to go...
like this.
"...Dodging in and out of the shadows,
running rapidly and silently...
...and hiding from the sun...
...They returned quickly, between
...moans and curses, to care for the portal..."
"Bilbo, had escaped".
Well...
that's all for today!
Has everyone handed in their slip,
for the field trip on Thursday?
It's not to late.
- Oskar, aren't you done?
- No, not quite, I got more things to do.
Hurry up, Conny.
Samuel Morse
What were you writing down?
What'd you mean?
Let me see it!
No.
What'd you mean, no?
I want it!
Who's gonna tell
your mommy now?
Wait for me!
Oskar!
Piggy!
I fell down during recess.
I tripped on a rock.
Oh, honey.
You've got to watch
your step, okay?
Hm'hm?
Short... long...
long... short, long.
long... short... long.
Short... long...
Exactly.
Here.
What happened?
There.
Oh... some class mates.
Where do you go to school?
Oskar... listen.
- Hm?
- Hit back.
- Hmm...
- You've never hit back...
have you?
- Uh'uh.
- So, do it... hit back!
Hard.
There are three of them.
Hit back even harder!
Hit 'em with more force,
than you dare.
Then they'll stop.
- But if...
- Then I'll help you.
I can do that.
Come.
Come on.
Move over.
- Move, I have to be here.
- Why?
Go on.
Let's see...
Short, long...
S~s...
O~o...
A~a...
V...
G...
Keep your distance!
Not too close, not too far.
Keep the right distance!
Nice and steady.
Yes?
Excuse me, Mr. Avila
the school fitness program...
could I sign up for it?
You don't have to sign up,
just be there at seven.
Are you thinking of doing it?
- Yeah.
- Good!
if you practice you can get
at least 50 times stronger.
See you.
Wait a second...
Mixed.
Eli.
No.
Alright.
I can... try one.
Are you alright?
Oskar...
do you like me?
Yeah, a lot.
If I wasn't a girl...
would you like me?
I suppose so.
Why you asking?
Oskar!
Hello, poor son!
- You're early.
- Hi, Dad!
There are people
who know my face...
who know
that I live here with you.
- Maybe you shouldn't.
- Whatever else am I good for?
Could you do
one thing for me?
Would you not see that...
boy tonight, alright?
- Please!
- Hmm...
What the...?
- Let's check if Matte is still around?
- Alright.
Hey! Matte?
You can jack off at home!
Matte, hurry up.
- What're you up too?
- Matte!
- Hey!
- Where am I?
What'd he's doing
in there, man?
Let me down!
Matte?
Help!
Hey, open the door, man.
Matte?
- Open the door!
- Help!
Open the stupid door.
Help!
- Open the goddam door!
- Help!
Help!
- Open the door Matte.
Help me!
Help?
Help!
- What the...?
- God...
- What happened?
- Cut me down.
What're doing up there?
Come on, let's get him down.
Eli.
...police, is coming as party
chairman and plead diversion.
Now on the local news, an unidentified
man was arrested yesterday...
charged with murder
and attempted murder, in...
Vällingby, near Stockholm.
The mans self-inflicted facial wounds...
made it impossible
to identify him.
And now in sports:
Severy Vagstead to report.
The Canadians
unfortunately lost in a heart-breaker...
Come on in.
Remote door.
Hello.
I'm looking for my pappa.
Is he here?
What's his name?
He is sick.
The police took him.
Do you know where he is?
He's on 7th floor, sweety.
But that's a restricted ward.
- I could call him...
- No.
That's alright.
Oh, you poor thing.
Invite me in?
What Kid?
Why would a kid kill, Jocke?
Jocke was the sweetest guy
there ever was.
Why? I don't know.
I'd like to tear
that damn kid apart.
A kid alone
couldn't have done it.
Oskar!
May I come in?
Mm...
- Don't look at me.
- Mm...
You have to say I can come in
You can come in.
Close your eyes.
How did you get in?
I flew.
Yeah, sure.
You're as cold
as ice.
Are you wearing anything?
Sorry.
Is that coarse?
No.
"Hickory, Dickory, Shock...
How many fingers
am I tapping you with?"
Eli...
What do you think of going steady?
What'd you mean?
Well...
Do you wanna be my girlfriend?
Oskar...
I'm not a girl.
Oh...
Well, do you wanna
go steady or not?
Can't we just keep on
the way we are?
I guess.
Do we do anything special
when we go steady?
No.
So, everything is the same?
Yeah.
- Then... we'll go steady.
- Yeah?
We'll never be alone.
- Really?
- Mh'hm.
Good.
I must be gone and live,
or stay and die.
Your Eli.
Listen up!
The lower grades
will skate with me.
Middle school... they get
to skate totaly free!
Ahh...
Watch out for her holes!
Over there!
Understood?
Avila...
- I think you meant THE holes.
- The holes.
I meant to say the holes!
You wanna go play?
Beware of the hole in the ice!
Hey, Conny...
Over here.
So, you wanna go swimming?
No.
- Mr. Avila?
- Yeah.
Mr. Avila...
I have to go pee.
- Go behind a tree.
- On the ice?
What does it matter?
You make a new ice.
Yellow ice.
What's that stick for?
To hit you with...
If you try anything.
Are you a brave pig
all of a sudden?
Look little pig,
I'm gonna push you.
And you aren't gonna do a thing.
Isn't that so?
Little piggy...
...watch out...
we're gonna get you...
...we're gonna get you now...
Look.
- Come on.
- Huh...
Mr. Avila... freak out,
I don't...
Are we suppose to...
just let 'em stand there?
Avila!
What's going on?
Oskar!
What did you do?
Come on.
POLICE
What do think I do all day?
Just sit around and...
Not likely...
What?... No!
Oh, yes... he's a dreamer...
Am I suppose to tell them
my son doesn't have a father?
Yes, it is.
Here he comes.
They called from school.
You better talk to your father...
Hello?
I'm fine.
- Oh...
- I don't know.
Are you're back working?
We'll see.
Hello, Oskar.
So, you did go swimming
after all.
I'm only kidding.
We're not really allowed
to be here.
But some of the bigger kids
come here anyway.
Eli, you know what? Today...
They tried to push me
on the ice...
But I... I had this stick...
- and I hit Conny so hard...
- Oskar...
that he had to go
to the E.R.
His head was bleeding so much,
everyone saw it... huh...
Oskar?
Yeah?
Well done!
What did you want us to do?
We're going to mix.
It doesn't hurt.
All you need to do
is prick your finger.
Eli?
Get out!
Leave!
They had to use a chain-saw,
to get him out.
- Go tell the cops your story!
- What's your problem, Gösta?
They'll ask me questions.
What do you mean?
They might shove me
into one of those rooms...
and shine bright lights
into my eyes...
- Jocke and I, we were this close...
- I'm sorry, but I can't...
like this!
Gösta, it's your duty,
you witnessed a crime.
God...
We go on...
about what a good he was...
And now that he's gone
I have nothing.
- Nothing left...
- Poor, Lacke...
Stop it! Fuck you!
Don't "Poor Lacke" me...
You don't get it!
You're so damn cold.
No one get's it.
Ginia,
you don't understand a thing!
I'm feelin' so bad about this.
- Ah...
- Ow!...
- Very subtle, Lacke.
- Ah...
Ginia!
Please... wait up!
Can't we at least
talk about it?
Come on...
No...
Get off of her!
Now!
Hey!
Get off of her!
Oh... Oh, come on, sweetheart...
Okay then, Ginia.
- Hey, wait up!
- I love you.
- You took my lighter, huh?
- Ginia?
What?...
It's so hot...
Nah...
- I didn't see that coming.
- You never do.
Hm'hm.
Well, this time I'll get you.
- Dream on.
- Hm'hm.
- You go first.
- Sure.
All right.
- Well, look who's here.
- Good evening to you all.
Hmm...
Looks like...
you're having a good time.
That's right.
Well, Oskar is here.
Hm'hm.
Be back.
Dad?
It's your turn.
Yes, yes..
we have a guest.
Nice and cozy in here.
We have all something.
I must be gone and live,
or stay and die.
Your Eli.
It ended up all wrong.
It was suppose to be great,
but their calculations were all wrong.
It was all wrong from the start.
It just got worse...
when he cleared these buildings,
I... I was so confused...
And I couldn't tell
what was going on...
It just got so much worse,
I don't know what to do now...
Busy night.
Come on in!
Ginia?
Where the hell have you been?
- What's going on?
- No!
I've been so damn worried!
What's wrong?
- What's wrong with you?
- No!
- What's going on?
- Leave me alone!
- Hey...
- Stop!
- Ginia!
- Stop right now!
Come on!
Tell me what happened?
- What is it?
- Let go of me!
What the hell is wrong
with these cat's?
Gösta,
what the hell is going on?
Get away!
Help!
Come on!
Oskar... is that you?
Yeah.
Are you a vampire?
I live off blood.
Yes.
Are you...
dead?
No.
Can't you tell?
Um...
but...
how old are you?
I'm twelve.
But I've been twelve
for a long time.
Are you like... poor?
- You see that egg over there?
- Yeah.
If you sold it you could buy
a whole nuclear power plant.
For real.
Yeah... sure.
Put your finger on it.
Huh...
where did those rings
come from?
I'm going home.
I have fresh papers
to distribute tomorrow.
- To earn money?
- Hm'hm.
I can give you money.
Here.
Take it.
You stole this!
From the people
you killed, right?
- It was given to me.
- By who?
By different people.
I want to go home now.
If you let me.
The time has come to sell this.
Dad's stamp collection.
What a guy.
One stamp...
80,000.
80 grand!
When I find the right buyer
I won't except any less.
80 thousand...
That's it.
Then we'll buy this pretty cabin.
The country-side
is so beautiful.
The two of us can live there.
Listen to the birds sing.
Grow our own vegetables.
And taking long walks...
in the afternoon sun.
Lacke, you gotta help me, please!
Yeah, sure.
- That kid.
- Yeah?
She must have infected me.
I don't wanna live.
- Good morning!
Things are looking up...
you can probably go home today.
Won't that be nice?
I'll just unlock this...
take a little blood sample.
There.
- Listen?
- Ah'ha?
Could you open
the blinds for me?
Sure.
No problem.
Hand over your cap.
- Do it!
- What's your problem?
Give it to me!
What're you?
Some kinda clod?
- Hey?
- Go for it, Conny.
- Let me go!
- You can do it!
- Get off me!
- Come on!
You're a big guy.
- Hey.
- Hi. What's up?
Hey, can I borrow your keys?
- What for?
- I wanna get home.
Alright...
- Here.
- Thanks.
- Hm'hm.
- See you later.
Who sent you home?
Well, well...
- That's your stuff, Conny.
- What're you laughing at?
- Hey.
- Hi.
You have to invite me in.
What happens if I don't?
What happens if you walk in anyway?
Is there something
in the way?
Tsk-tsk-tsk...
Tsk-tsk-tsk.
No!
You can come in!
Who are you?
I'm like you.
- What'd you mean?
- Well...
What're you staring at?
Are you staring at me?
So, squeal!
Squeal!
That was one of the first words
I heard you say.
I don't kill people.
No...
But you'd like it...
if you could.
To get revenge.
Right?
Yes.
Oskar, I do it
because I have to.
Be me for a while.
Oskar...
please, be me.
You can borrow one
of my mom's dresses.
Oskar!
Let me in.
What are you up to?
Let me in!
I'm in the bathroom.
I'm coming!
Let me in, Oskar!
Hi! I'm in the bathroom.
Please don't come in.
Would you like
to meet me tonight?
I like you very much.
Your Eli.
Can't see a thing...
No!
Huh?
Let go!
Let go of me!
Thank you.
Oskar...
I have to go away.
Who Killed That Man
In The Ice?
Hello.
- Is that you, Oskar?
- Yes.
It's me, Martin.
Mr. Avila wanted to know
if you're coming tonight.
Why?
I guess...
He just wanted to know.
Maybe he wants you
to be there.
I'm... really not sure.
It was good by the way...
what you did to Conny.
He had it coming.
That's really good, man!
- Do you think so?
- So...
are you coming tonight
to practice?
POOL
Well, Oskar.
Hi.
Alright...
-This is how some of you get hurt,
You can't leave this here, okay?
-Hey Oskar.
when are they going to learn,
these kids just don't get it.
Hey.
Come, we start with
upper aerobics.
Hurry up!
Come on, Oskar!
Let's go!
One, two, one, two...
Move your body!
What? What?
You do that.
Call the fire department!
Fire! Fire!
Fire!
Beat it!
Clear out!
You know who I am?
- Yeah.
- Good.
Then you get it.
We're going to have
a little contest.
You stay under water...
for three minutes.
If you do it...
I'll just nick you.
But if you can't...
I'll poke one of your eyes out.
An eye for an ear, right?
But... but... but,
that's impossible.
That's your problem.
Three minutes.
Better take a deep breath!
Five...
four...
three...
two...
one.
- Jimmy...
- Shut up!
- Conny, let's go.
- I told you to shut up!
- Subtitles posted by Radar1
- Edited by Forkedman