CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
WARNER BROS.
♪ OOH ♪
♪ OOH, OOH ♪
♪ OO-OOOHHH ♪
♪ DO IT ♪
♪ DO IT AGAIN ♪
♪ OOH ♪
♪ LET'S DO IT AGAIN ♪
♪ GONNA DO IT AGAIN ♪
♪ DOING IT, DO IT ♪
♪ LET'S DO IT AGAIN ♪
♪ SOMETIMES THE RAIN ♪
♪ GROOVIN' WHEN I HEAR
THE SOUND ♪
♪ LIKE YOU AND ME, BABY ♪
♪ GETTIN' DOWN
WITH THE SOUNDS AROUND ♪
♪ OHH, THE SMELL
OF THE MORNING FLOWER ♪
♪ AS WE PASS AWAY
THE HOURS ♪
♪ I WANT TO DO IT AGAIN,
DO IT AGAIN ♪
♪ DO IT, DO IT ♪
♪ LET'S DO IT
IN THE MORNING ♪
♪ SWEET BREEZE
IN THE SUMMERTIME ♪
♪ FEELIN' YOUR SWEET FACE♪
♪ ALL LAID UP
NEXT TO MINE ♪
♪ SWEET LOVE
IN THE MIDNIGHT ♪
♪ GOOD SLEEP
COME MORNING LIGHT ♪
♪ NO WORRIES
ABOUT NOTHING ♪
♪ JUST GETTING GOOD,
JUST GETTING GOOD ♪
♪ JUST GETTING
GOOD LOVIN' ♪
♪ DO IT AGAIN ♪
♪ NOW I LIKE YOU, LADY ♪
♪ SO FINE
WITH YOUR PRETTY HAIR ♪
♪ IF YOU DON'T MIND
THE COMPLIMENTS ♪
♪ JUST DIGGIN' ON
THE CLOTHES YOU WEAR ♪
♪ I'M JUST A MAN,
NOW, DON'T YOU FEAR ♪
♪ I CAN LOVE YOU
NOW I BROUGHT YOU HERE ♪
♪ DO IT NOW, DO IT AGAIN ♪
♪ OOH ♪
♪ DO IT ♪
♪ OH, YEAH ♪
♪ DO IT AGAIN ♪
HEY, WHAT HAPPENED
OUT THERE, BILLY?
MY CLUTCH STUCK.
YEAH, I SAW WHAT
STUCK YOUR CLUTCH.
SEE YOU TOMORROW NIGHT
AT LOU'S, BILLY?
NO, SIR.
NO POKER FOR ME.
TAKING MY WIFE
TO NEW ORLEANS THIS WEEKEND.
YOU GOING
TO SEE THE FIGHT?
NO. JUST TAKE IN
SOME SHOWS.
DO A LITTLE DANCING.
WHAT KIND OF DANCING
YOU GONNA DO
WITH THEM 2 LEFT FEET
YOU GOT THERE?
2 FLAT LEFT FEET.
YEAH, IF YOU
DON'T WATCH IT,
YOU MAY FIND
A FLAT LEFT FOOT
IN YOUR NAVEL.
YEAH,
YOU AND WHO ELSE?
JUST ME, CHUMP.
OOH!
AND A FLAT LEFT FOOT
IN YOUR NAVEL.
LOOK OUT NOW.
YOU'RE GONNA GET YOUR CLUTCH
STUCK AGAIN UP YOUR--
WATCH YOUR LIPS,
BECAUSE THEY MAY
GET YOU INTO SOMETHING
THAT YOUR BEHIND
CAN'T GET YOU OUT OF.
AND YOU
MAY HAVE 2 LEFT FEET
DEAD IN YOUR STERNUM.
I THINK WE CAN
GET IT ON RIGHT NOW.
WHAT? WHAT?!
RIGHT NOW.
BECAUSE I AM
TIRED OF YOU, MAN.
EVERY TIME
YOU COME AROUND HERE
IT'S BEEN WORDS
BACK AND FORTH.
I'M SICK OF IT.
I DON'T CARE
HOW MUCH
YOU SWELL UP.
HEY, KEEP AN EYE
ON HIM NOW.
NOW...
NO, WAIT. DON'T--
DON'T THROW NO PUNCHES.
I WANT TO TALK TO YOU
FOR ONE SECOND.
NOW LOOK, LET ME
TELL YOU SOMETHING.
NO, BEFORE WE GET IT
ON, I JUST WANT
TO TELL YOU
SOMETHING, MAN.
THIS IS ALL--
I LOVE YOU.
♪ OOH ♪
♪ WHOO-HOO-HOO ♪
COME HERE.
GO ON.
GO ON, SAY HELLO.
COME HERE.
WWWHHHOOOAAA!
SEE?
THERE YOU GO.
MM-HMM. YOU WRITE...
1...
2...
DO 3. 3--
UHH....HEH.
SHE GOT ME.
HEH HEH!
THANK YOU. SHE'S--
SHE'S ALL FINISHED NOW.
MR. WILLIAMS,
MR. FOSTER?
I'M SORRY.
YOU GOTTA DO IT.
I SAID NO.
WE'RE AT THE END
OF THE LINE.
THERE'S GOT
TO BE ANOTHER WAY.
I'LL TELL YOU
WHAT IT IS.
YOU'VE GOT TO DO IT!
YOU'VE GOT TO BE CRAZY.
I HAVEN'T DONE THAT
SINCE I WAS IN THE ARMY.
YOU DID IT AT SISTER JOAN'S
BIRTHDAY PARTY LAST YEAR.
NOW, THAT
DON'T COUNT.
IT WAS. I SAW IT.
LOOK, I GOT IT
ALL FIGURED OUT.
I'M TAKING BETH
TO NEW ORLEANS
FOR THE WEEKEND TO
CELEBRATE OUR ANNIVERSARY.
NOW, YOU AND DEE DEE
COME ALONG
AND HELP US CELEBRATE
OUR ANNIVERSARY,
AND WHILE WE'RE THERE--
NO!
LISTEN TO ME!
SOME OF THESE LODGE
MEMBERS HAVE BEEN THERE
FOR 60 YEARS OR MORE,
AND THEY'RE
OUR RESPONSIBILITY!
YOU BETTER
CHANGE YOUR PANTS
BEFORE PEOPLE THINK
YOU CAN'T HOLD YOUR WATER.
YOU'VE GOTTA DO IT!
WE'RE RUNNING
AN HOUR LATE ALREADY.
MAYBE THEY'RE TAKING
SO LONG IS A GOOD SIGN.
I THINK I BETTER GO IN
AND TELL THEM
TO START THE MEETING.
YEAH, GO AHEAD.
CLYDE, HONEY, THE WORLD
IS NOT RUN ON C.B. TIME.
YOU TWO GONNA BE LATE
FOR YOUR OWN FUNERAL.
I HOPE SO.
BILLY AIN'T HERE?
NO.
WHAT THEY SAY?
BILLY FOSTER,
WILL YOU HURRY UP?
EVERYBODY'S IN THERE
WAITING ON YOU.
BILLY,
WHERE IS OUR CAR?
I SOLD THE CAR.
WHAT YOU SELL
OUR CAR FOR?
I SOLD THE CAR.
IS IT OUR WEDDING
ANNIVERSARY TOMORROW
OR IS IT NOT OUR WEDDING
ANNIVERSARY TOMORROW?
SO WHAT?
SO, FOR 14 YEARS,
YOU'VE BEEN WORKING
YOUR FINGERS TO THE BONE
FROM SUNRISE TO SUNDOWN,
AND I'VE
NEVER HAD A DOLLAR
TO SPEND NOTHING
ON YOU,
SO I SOLD THE CAR.
I'M TAKING MY WIFE
TO NEW ORLEANS
FOR THE WEEKEND.
A MAN CAN ALWAYS
GET A CHEAP CAR,
BUT HE
CAN'T GET A WIFE.
AIN'T THAT SWEET?
YEAH.
THEY'RE UP
TO SOMETHING.
I KNOW IT.
I AM.
Congregation:
YES, YOU ARE.
AND I'M GONNA BE.
YES, YOU WILL.
TRIUMPH HAVE I?
YES!
STEADY OF HEART?
NO VALLEY OF SORROW
IS DEEP ENOUGH.
NO!
NO MOUNTAIN OF PLEASURE
IS HIGH ENOUGH.
NO!
TO CAUSE MY FEET
TO STUMBLE ONE STEP
IN OUR EVERLASTING
JOURNEY
TO THE RIGHTEOUS
SIDE OF LIFE.
PRAISE TO HIM!
AND MARCHING OUT AT THE HEAD
OF OUR GREAT MULTITUDE
TO SHOW US THE WAY
IS OUR FOUNDER.
THE GREAT, GREAT, GREAT
GRAND WARRIOR
OF THE KINGDOM OF SHAKA.
PRAISE TO THE KINGDOM!
HE STAMPED HIS FEET
ON THE GROUND THAT IS AFRICA
AND THE EARTH TREMBLED.
TO THE EVIL,
HE SHOWS NO MERCY.
NO!
TO THE DECEITFUL,
HIS BLOWS ARE SWIFT.
YES!
BUT TO
THE PURE IN HEART,
HE IS LOVE.
LOVE, BROTHERS
AND SISTERS.
HE IS OUR LEADER.
THE GREAT, GREAT,
GREAT GRAND WARRIOR
OF THE KINGDOM OF SHAKA!
ALL PRAISES DUE
TO OUR FOUNDER!
TO THE KINGDOM OF SHAKA!
BROTHERS AND SISTERS...
ANOTHER DAY HAS DAWNED,
AND THOUGH WE ARE HERE
IN OUR GOOD HEALTH
AND STRENGTH,
TODAY IS NOT A GOOD DAY
FOR US.
THE CITY HAS REFUSED
TO GRANT US THE EXTENSION
THAT WE WANTED.
AND SO I GUESS THE BEST WAY
TO START THIS MEETING
IS WITH A FINANCIAL REPORT
ON OUR SITUATION
FROM OUR TREASURER,
BROTHER BILLY FOSTER.
WELL, WE ALL
KNOW THE SITUATION.
WE HAVE KNOWN
FOR THE PAST 3 YEARS
THAT THIS CITY WAS GONNA
TURN DOWN THIS SECTION
COMMENCING NEXT YEAR.
IN 6 WEEKS, WE'VE GOT
TO BE OUT OF THIS BUILDING.
2 YEARS AGO,
Y'ALL MADE PLEDGES
TO THE NEW BUILDING FUND,
AND YOU'VE FULFILLED
THOSE PLEDGES,
BUT THAT'S NOT ENOUGH.
BROTHERS AND SISTERS,
FOR THE PAST 2 YEARS,
WE'VE BEEN
RAKING AND SCRAPING,
BUT IT IS NOT ENOUGH.
THE INITIAL COST
OF THE CONSTRUCTION
IS $55,000.
THAT MEANS WE GOT
TO HAVE AT LEAST THAT
BEFORE WE CAN START.
AND SO FAR IN THE KITTY,
WE'VE GOT $18,000.
NOW WHAT ARE WE
GOING TO DO ABOUT IT?
WHAT ARE WE GOING
TO DO ABOUT IT?
FIGHT IT.
TIGHTEN UP AND DIG DEEPER.
NOW, I KNOW
IT'S GONNA BE ROUGH.
IT IS NOW OR NEVER.
NOW THE SONS AND
DAUGHTERS OF SHAKA
HAVE ALWAYS THRIVED
ON ADVERSITY.
THAT'S RIGHT!
WE LIVE TO OVERCOME
SUFFERING.
YES!
WE LIVE TO CREATE LIGHT
WHERE THERE WAS DARKNESS.
YES!
WE HAVE GOT TO PUT
OUR HEART IN IT.
YES!
WE'VE GOT TO PUT
OUR SOUL IN IT.
YES!
WE'VE GOTTA PUT
OUR SPIRITS IN IT.
YES!
AND WE'VE GOT TO PUT
SOME MORE MONEY IN IT!
THAT MONEY
SHOULD BE IN A BANK!
IT WAS.
WE CAN GO TO JAIL
IF THIS DON'T WORK.
IT'S GONNA WORK.
IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME.
YEAH, BUT YOU'VE
STILL GOT THE TOUCH
BECAUSE I REMEMBER
AT SISTER JOAN'S PARTY
WITH VICTOR BROWN,
YOU HAD HIM
GOING AROUND THERE
CROWING LIKE A ROOSTER
IN A HENHOUSE.
ROOOOO!
KOO-KOO-ROO!
THAT'S RIGHT.
HEH HEH HEH!
$2,000.
MORTGAGED
MY FURNITURE,
SOLD MY CAR, CLOSED
OUT MY BANK ACCOUNT.
$2,000 FROM ME.
$18,000
FROM THE LODGE.
$20,000.
20,000.
NO. UN-UH.
NO, MAN. I'M A MILKMAN.
YOU'RE A FACTORY WORKER!
WE DON'T LOOK LIKE NOBODY
WHO'D COME UP
WITH NO $20,000.
WE GONNA LOOK LIKE
WE GOT A MILLION.
HOW?
YOU JUST LEAVE THAT
UP TO ME.
I'LL TAKE CARE
OF THAT.
OUR WOMEN MUST NEVER
KNOW NOTHING ABOUT THIS.
NEVER. THEY'RE JUST
GOING TO NEW ORLEANS
TO HAVE A GOOD TIME.
ROOO!
♪ HEY ♪
♪ WHOO, YEAH ♪
♪ MMM-MMMMM ♪
♪ OH, DOWN IN NEW ORLEANS ♪
♪ BABY ♪
♪ MMM ♪
♪ NEW ORLEANS ♪
♪ WHAT CAN I TELL YOU? ♪
♪ HARD FOR ME TO SAY ♪
♪ I GOT MY MIND
ON LOUISIANA ♪
♪ OH, YEAH ♪
♪ EVERYBODY UP ♪
♪ DOO-DOO-DOOT,
DOO-DOO-DOOT ♪
DOOT-DOOT-DOO ♪
♪ DOO-DOO-DOOT ♪
♪ DOO-DOO-DOOT-DOO ♪
♪SWEET LOUISIANA ♪
♪ WHOO-WHOO-WHOO-WHOO ♪
♪ WHOO-WHOO-WHOO ♪
♪ SURE ENOUGH
LIKE TO TALK ABOUT ♪
♪ BABY,
HOW YOU TURN ME OUT ♪
♪ RIGHT TO THE REAL
NITTY-GRITTY ♪
♪ IN THIS FINE FUNKY CITY ♪
THAT'S FOR SHOWING ME
ONE OF THE NICEST TIMES
I'VE EVER HAD
IN MY LIFE.
IS, UM, THAT
ALL I'M GONNA GET?
WELL, THAT'S ALL YOU
GONNA GET IN PUBLIC.
HO HO HO!
OHH! STOP!
WHOO!
YOU FRESH THING!
YOU KNOW YOU LOVE IT.
YES, I DO.
WHOO!
AND TONIGHT, I'M GONNA
LAY A BLOCKBUSTER ON YOU
TONIGHT.
YEAH?
WELL, I'M GONNA
HAVE A BLOCK
FOR YOU
TO BUST, TOO, BABY,
SO YOU BETTER BRING
A WHOLE LOT OF HAMMER.
HAVE HAMMER, WILL TRAVEL
AND GO DEEP
INTO YOUR CREVICE.
Beth!
WELL,
IT'S THE TRUTH.
WELL, I KNOW,
BUT I CERTAINLY WISH
YOU TWO WOULD STOP
PUTTING YOUR BUSINESS
IN THE STREET LIKE THAT,
AND THAT'S ALL.
ARE YOU GONNA SIT
THERE AND ACT ALL PROPER
LIKE CLYDE
AIN'T BEEN HITTING
YOUR SWITCH
REGULARLY?
UH-UH! I AIN'T IN IT.
I COULD SAY
SOMETHING,
BUT I WON'T.
HEH HEH!
OF COURSE CLYDE
AND ME HAVE RELATIONS.
WE CERTAINLY DON'T LET
THE WHOLE WORLD KNOW
ABOUT IT. DO WE, HONEY?
UH-UH. ME AND DEE DEE,
WE DON'T MAKE NO NOISE.
WE WHISPER A LOT.
HEH HEH HEH!
OH, BABY, OH, BABY!
SHH!
WE ALL GROWN.
AND WE KNOW
WHAT'S HAPPENING.
BESIDES, IT'S
OUR ANNIVERSARY.
YES, WELL, I KNOW THAT.
BUT SUPPOSE SOMEBODY
WHO DIDN'T KNOW YOU
HEARD YOU
TALKING LIKE THAT?
I MEAN,
WHAT WOULD THEY SAY?
THEY WOULD SAY
I WAS HAVING
A HORNY CONVERSATION
WITH A MAN
IN A FANCY
RESTAURANT,
AND HE WAS PICKING
UP ON MY VIBE.
PICKING UP ON THEM.
DEE DEE,
I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU WERE A PRUDE.
WELL, I AM NOT A PRU--
I AM NOT A PRUDE.
BUT THERE ARE SOME
THINGS THAT I WON'T DO,
AND THAT'S ALL.
WELL, LA-DEE-DA.
HEH HEH HEH!
BABY, THAT
WAS A GOOD LUNCH.
NOW I'M READY
FOR A NAP,
BUT FIRST I'M GONNA
GO TAKE A WEE-WEE.
DEE DEE,
COME ON AND GO
TO THE POWDER ROOM
WITH ME.
COME ON, GIRL.
YOU TELL ME WHY?
WHY?
THE FELLA
WITH THE PINK FLOWER,
THE BIGGEST OF THE BIG-TIME
GAMBLERS IN LOUISIANA.
KANSAS CITY MACK. OWNS
THIS RESTAURANT RIGHT HERE.
YOUR BOOKS DON'T LOOK GOOD
AND I DON'T LIKE IT.
22% OFF CAN ONLY MEAN
ONE THING--
BAD MANAGEMENT.
YOU, YOU GOT TO START
INCREASING YOUR VOLUME NOW
IN ALL YOUR OPERATIONS,
ESPECIALLY IN THE GAMBLING
AND JOY HOUSES
AND THE LIQUOR BUSINESS.
BOSS, INFLATION--
INFLATION AIN'T BOTHERING
BIGGIE SMALLS
AND HIS BOYS IN KENTUCKY
AND ALABAMA.
THEY'RE ROLLING RIGHT ALONG,
HEADING IN THIS DIRECTION.
AND IT'S YOUR TERRITORY
THEY'RE GONNA GRAB FIRST.
WE'RE PUSHING
AS HARD AS WE CAN.
WE'RE ON TOP OF IT
7 DAYS A WEEK.
THAT'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH.
YOU'VE GOT TO COME UP
WITH SOME NEW IDEAS.
THAT'S WHY BIGGIE SMALLS
AND HIS BOYS
KEEP BEATING US
TO THE PUNCH.
HE GOT THEM YOUNG,
COLLEGE-EDUCATED FAGGOTS
DOING HIS THINKING
FOR HIM.
MAYBE Y'ALL TOO OLD.
MAYBE Y'ALL NEED
TO TAKE A WALK.
MAYBE I OUGHT
TO GET SOME OF THEM
YOUNG COLLEGE-EDUCATED
FAGGOTS
TO DO MY THINKING
FOR ME, HUH? HUH?
NOW, HOW THINGS LOOKING
ON THIS FIGHT?
NOT SO GOOD. WE'RE
GETTING PLENTY OF ACTION
ON 40th STREET BLACK,
BUT NOTHING ON FARNSWORTH.
WELL, THAT FIGURES.
EVEN FARNSWORTH'S MAMA
AIN'T DUMB ENOUGH
TO BET ON HIM.
WELL, LOOK,
USE YOUR HEADS.
IF THERE AIN'T NO
FARNSWORTH MONEY AROUND,
CLOSE YOUR BOOKS
AND SIT THIS ONE OUT.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
WELCOME TO THE TRAINING CAMP
OF THE MIDDLEWEIGHT CHAMPION
OF THE WORLD
WHO WILL DEFEND
HIS CHAMPIONSHIP
THE NIGHT AFTER TOMORROW
RIGHT HERE IN THE FABULOUS
CITY OF NEW ORLEANS
AT THE SPORTS CENTER.
HE IS NOW
COMING TO THE RING
TO SPAR IN 3 ROUNDS
OF BOXING
FOR YOUR ENTERTAINMENT.
THE MIDDLEWEIGHT CHAMPION
OF THE WORLD
40th STREET BLACK!
LET'S HEAR IT,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN!
ANYBODY
RUNNING INTO HIM
BETTER BE DRIVING
A MACK TRUCK.
OK, LET'S GO SEE
THE CHALLENGER.
WHAT'S HIS NAME?
BOOTNEY FARNSWORTH.
BOOTNEY FARNSWORTH?
COME ON, BOOTNEY,
KEEP YOUR RIGHT UP,
PROTECT YOURSELF, BABY!
PROTECT YOURSELF!
MOVE, MOVE, MOVE, JAB!
JAB, JAB, JAB, JAB!
THERE YOU GO,
THERE YOU GO!
THROW THEM PUNCHES IN,
THROW THEM PUNCHES IN.
MOVE, MOVE,
BOOTNEY, MOVE!
OOH!
HEY, HONEY, BOOTNEY FARNSWORTH
IS KNOCKING OUT
HIS FELLAS, TOO.
NO, DEAR, THAT'S
BOOTNEY FARNSWORTH THERE.
LOOK, LOOK HERE.
MOVE. USE YOUR JAB.
UNDERSTAND?
DON'T TRY
TO SLUG IT OUT.
IF YOU GET TAGGED,
CLENCH.
KEEP YOUR GLOVES UP HIGH
AND PROTECT YOURSELF.
OK, LET'S GO.
GO GET HIM.
TAKE HIM.
PUNCH, PUNCH!
COVER UP!
MOVE IT, MOVE!
40th STREET BLACK IS
GONNA KILL THAT POOR BABY.
HERE'S
YOUR PRESS CARD.
WHERE'D
YOU GET THESE?
I PRINTED THEM UP
MYSELF.
ALL RIGHT, YOU GUYS GOT
ONE MINUTE AND THAT'S IT.
MY FIGHTER'S GOTTA EAT
AND GET SOME SLEEP.
ON THE BASIS
OF YOUR LAST FIGHT,
A SPLIT DECISION
OVER MARTIN,
DO YOU FEEL THAT YOU DESERVE
A SHOT AT THE TITLE?
MARTIN WAS A PUSHOVER.
BOOTNEY WAS CARRYING HIM.
I HEAR YOUR SPARRING
PARTNER DECKED YOU TODAY.
HE SLIPPED.
Second reporter:
BOOTNEY, WORD'S GOING AROUND
THAT YOU'RE
NOT REALLY IN SHAPE.
WHAT DO YOU SAY
ABOUT THAT?
LIES, PROPAGANDA!
THEN WHY ARE YOU
A 5-TO-1 UNDERDOG?
BECAUSE WE DO OUR
FIGHTING IN THE RING,
NOT IN THE NEWSPAPER
LIKE THAT BIG-MOUTH,
EMPTY-HEADED SISSY.
CAN WE QUOTE
YOU, BOOTNEY?
YEAH, YOU CAN QUOTE HIM!
YOU TELL THE WORLD
WHEN WE GET THROUGH
WITH 40th STREET BLACK
HE'S GONNA LOOK LIKE
30th STREET YELLOW.
BOOTNEY,
ANY TRUTH TO THE RUMOR
THAT YOU'RE DEVELOPING
A SECRET PUNCH?
DON'T ANSWER THAT,
BOOTNEY!
EVERYTHING
IN ITS PROPER PLACE.
IF YOU LOSE, BOOTNEY,
WHAT ARE YOUR PLANS?
WE CAN'T ANSWER THAT,
BECAUSE LOSING'S THE LAST
THING WE THINK ABOUT.
Reporter:
HOW LONG'S
THE FIGHT GONNA
LAST, BOOTNEY?
IT WON'T GO THE DISTANCE.
BOOTNEY, IF YOU WIN,
WILL YOU BE AN ACTIVE CHAMPION?
WE'LL FIGHT ANYBODY,
ANYWHERE.
ONE LITTLE PERSONAL
QUESTION, BOOTNEY.
HOW'S YOUR LOVE LIFE?
HOW'S HIS LOVE LIFE?
HOW'S HIS LOVE LIFE?!
HE'S GOT HIS HANDS FULL!
OK, IT'S TIME TO GIVE
MY FIGHTER SOME REST.
SO UP AND OUT, LET'S GO.
YOU KNOW WHAT TO WRITE,
YOU KNOW
WHAT PICTURES TO PRINT.
I APPRECIATE
YOU COMING DOWN.
WE'LL SEE YOU WHEN WE
WIN THE CHAMPIONSHIP, OK?
OUT YOU GO, FELLAS.
THANKS A LOT FOR COMING BY.
APPRECIATE IT A LOT.
MR. ELLISON.
YOU REALLY THINK
I GOT A CHANCE?
HE'S GONNA BEAT
YOUR BRAINS IN, BOOTNEY.
BOOTNEY...
YOU'VE GOT SOMETHING,
BUT WE JUST CAN'T SEEM TO--
YES, YOU DO
HAVE A CHANCE, SON.
BUT NOT
A GOOD ONE, HUH?
NO, NOT A GOOD CHANCE.
BUT YOU NEVER KNOW.
COME ON, KID.
GET SOME REST.
WE'VE GOT ANOTHER DAY'S
WORK AHEAD OF US.
Bootney Farnsworth,
can you hear me?
Listen to the rhythm
of the chimes.
of my voice.
You are going
into the deepest part
of your sleep.
Deeper and deeper
and deeper and deeper.
Deeper, deeper.
Now your subconscious
belongs to me.
Open your eyes.
IN THE INNERMOST
REACHES OF YOUR HEART,
YOU ARE A TIGER.
TIGER!
YOU ARE CAPABLE
OF GREAT FEATS
OF STRENGTH
AND COURAGE.
STRENGTH AND COURAGE!
YOU CAN BEAT ANY
FIGHTER IN THE WORLD.
YOU WILL WIN
THE CHAMPIONSHIP.
OHH--
I WILL?
YES.
OUT OF SIGHT!
TOMORROW AT YOUR
SPARRING SESSION,
YOU WILL DEMONSTRATE
ALL THE POWER
YOU ARE CAPABLE OF,
AND ON THE NIGHT
OF THE FIGHT,
YOU WILL WIN OVER
40th STREET BLACK.
WIN!
INVINCIBLE!
MEAN!
WIN!
DOWNRIGHT NASTY
WITH STRENGTH!
NOW...
GO TO SLEEP.
Go to sleep.
Sleep, sleep.
Win, win.
What are we gonna do?
The fire escape.
What are we
gonna do?
You can't
go down there.
What you gonna do?
We're gonna put knots
in these sheets,
throw 'em out
the window,
and climb down.
You're crazy!
We can't go down there
on these!
Are you crazy?
Do you know
what they'll
do to us
if they catch us?
KEEP MOVING, FOOL!
WOULD YOU GET YOUR FOOT
OUT THE WAY?
AAH!
OH!
AHH.
OHH.
OH, YEAH.
HEH.
OH, BOY.
COME HERE.
MMM. OHH.
OOH.
AHA!
WHO ARE YOU?
JUST AS I THOUGHT!
WHO AM I?
DO YOU REALIZE HOW MANY
RULES YOU'VE BROKEN
REGARDING A SINGLE
OCCUPANCY ROOM
IN THE STATE
OF LOUISIANA?
DO YOU REALIZE
HOW MANY LAWS
YOU'VE BROKEN, SIR,
SINCE YOU'VE
ENTERED THIS ROOM?
WHO ARE YOU?
WHO AM I?
WHO AM I? HA!
I WORK FOR THIS HOTEL.
I AM
THE HOUSE DETECTIVE.
AND THIS
IS MY ASSISTANT FRANK,
AND FRANK WILL READ YOU--
READ HIM HIS RIGHTS.
HIS RIGHTS?
YES, THE RIGHTS!
RIGHTS. UH--AHEM.
ANYTHING YOU SAY MAY
BE HELD AGAINST YOU.
Billy:
AND IT DOESN'T MATTER
BECAUSE WE'VE
GOT ENOUGH AGAINST YOU.
NOW, YOU, YOUNG LADY,
I'LL GET TO YOU
IN A SECOND.
BUT YOU FIRST.
NOW, WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
RUFUS ISAACS.
ARE YOU MARRIED, RUFUS?
NO.
AHA. OK.
WHERE DO YOU WORK?
RIGHT HERE
IN THE HOTEL.
RIGHT HERE IN THE HOTEL,
AND, RUFUS,
IT'S GONNA REALLY
BE HEAVY ON YOU.
NOW, WHAT DO YOU DO
HERE IN THE HOTEL?
I'M THE HOUSE
DETECTIVE.
HOUSE DETECTIVE. I SEE.
WELL, THAT ABOUT
CLOSES THIS WHOLE THING UP,
UH, DOESN'T IT? YES.
WELL, Y-YOU GOT US.
UH, YOU GOT US.
WELL, I GUESS YOU WANT
TO PUT THE HANDCUFFS ON US,
TAKE US ON DOWN
TO THE MANAGER'S OFFICE AND...
EXPLAIN TO HIM
HOW YOU, UH,
CAUGHT US BEHIND THE SOFA
WHILE YOU WERE IN HERE
MAKING LOVE TO A MARRIED WOMAN.
WAIT A MINUTE NOW.
WHAT?
NOW, JUST WAIT A MINUTE.
OH, NO. I DON'T
UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU MEAN.
WE HAVE TO GO DOWN
AND TALK TO THE MANAGER.
NO, NO, NO.
WHAT?
YOU KNOW,
IT'S--IT'S COOL.
Clyde:
HEH HEH HEH.
IT'S COOL. IT'S COOL.
IT'S COOL.
RUFUS SAID COOL.
RUFUS SAID
IT'S COOL.
I KNEW HE WAS HIP.
WITH THE NAME RUFUS.
RUFUS. HA HA HA.
YOU WANNA TAKE US DOWN?
FORGET ABOUT IT,
YOU KNOW.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
WE WILL NOW HAVE 3 ROUNDS
OF SPARRING
BETWEEN THE CHALLENGER,
BOOTNEY FARNSWORTH,
AND--AND, UH--
OH, HELL.
WHAT'S THE USE?
NOTHING BUT HORSE
THE REST OF THE WAY, FELLAS.
THAT'S ALL.
WE BELIEVE IN CHANGE,
AND WE'RE PREPARED FOR IT
WITH NEW TECHNIQUES
AND NEW APPROACHES,
AND AS FOR OUR PART,
WE FEEL THAT YOU'RE
THE BEST PIECES
OF MANPOWER
AVAILABLE
IN THIS WHOLE REGION.
THANK YOU,
MR. SMALLS.
CALL ME BIGGIE.
WE HOPE TO BE ABLE TO MOVE
INTO THIS AREA PEACEFULLY.
NO VIOLENCE.
BUT IF MACK AND HIS BOYS
PROVE, UH, STUBBORN,
THEN WHAT HAS TO BE
WILL BE.
THAT'S WHERE YOU COME IN.
AND IF YOU'RE AS GOOD
AS YOUR REPUTATIONS,
THEN WE CAN LOOK FORWARD
TO A SMOOTH TRANSITION.
COME IN.
EXCUSE ME.
GET THE BROTHERS A DRINK.
MONGO SLADE
FROM NEW YORK, HUH?
THAT'S RIGHT,
BIGGIE SMALLS.
WELL, WHAT
CAN I DO FOR YOU?
I HEAR YOU'RE TAKING
BETS ON THE FIGHT.
BIG BETS.
I LIKE FARNSWORTH.
10 GRAND.
MR. SLADE, SIT DOWN.
LET'S HAVE A TALK.
SIR, THERE'S A MAN OUTSIDE
WANTS TO SEE YOU
ABOUT PLACING A BET.
TELL HIM THIS IS A RESTAURANT,
NOT A BOOKIE JOINT.
I DID.
HE SAID BIG MONEY.
OK, LET'S SEE
WHAT HE LOOKS LIKE.
YOU WANNA SEE ME?
YEAH,
I WANNA SEE YOU.
ABOUT WHAT?
MY NAME
IS MONGO SLADE,
AND I'M FROM OUT
OF NEW YORK CITY,
AND ME AND MY BOYS
WANT TO MAKE A BET
WITH YOU.
WHY DON'T YOU TAKE IT
TO ONE OF THE LOCAL BOOKIES?
UH, MAINLY BECAUSE
WHEN WE GO
TO THE LOCAL BOOKIES
AIN'T NONE OF THEM
GONNA TAKE YOUR BET
UNLESS
YOU SAY IT'S OK,
SO WE'RE JUST
COMING TO SEE YOU.
HOW MUCH
YOU WANNA BET?
WELL, UM, WHO ARE
THESE PEOPLE HERE?
THESE ARE MY PARTNERS.
YEAH.
BUBBLETOP WOODSON,
FISH AN' CHIPS FREDDIE,
JODY TIPPS.
HOW MUCH YOU WANNA BET?
I WANNA BET $10,000.
5-TO-1 ODDS,
FARNSWORTH TO WIN.
WE WOULD
HAVE BET $20,000
BUT WE DON'T WANNA
OVERLOAD YOUR CIRCUIT.
COUNT IT.
NO NEED.
MONGO SLADE.
NEW YORK CITY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I THINK WE CAN DO BUSINESS.
UM, YOU SEE,
KANSAS CITY,
WHEN WE, UH,
WHEN WE LOSE,
WE PAY OFF. DIG?
NOW, WHEN--
WHEN WE WIN,
WE DON'T WANNA HAVE
TO GO CHASIN' Y'ALL
ALL OVER LOUISIANA.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
YOU WIN, WE'LL BE HERE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
NOW, EVERYTHING'LL
BE COOL.
FOR NOW.
AND NOW,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THIS IS THE MAIN EVENT
OF THE EVENING.
15 ROUNDS OF BOXING
FOR THE MIDDLEWEIGHT
CHAMPIONSHIP OF THE WORLD.
JUDGING AT RINGSIDE
WILL BE CECIL BETHEL
AND BILLY ADAMS.
THIRD MAN IN THE RING,
YOUR REFEREE,
THE MAN IN CHARGE,
LARRY ROSADILLA.
INTRODUCING
IN THIS CORNER
THE CHALLENGER,
WEIGHING IN AT 155 POUNDS,
WEARING WHITE TRUNKS
WITH A BLACK STRIPE,
FROM POSSUM'S PAW, ALABAMA,
BOOTNEY FARNSWORTH!
AND HIS OPPONENT,
DEFENDING HIS TITLE
AND HIS CROWN
AND WEIGHING IN
AT AN EVEN 160 POUNDS,
WEARING BLACK
TRUNKS WITH A WHITE STRIPE,
FROM BIGFOOT, MISSISSIPPI,
THE MIDDLEWEIGHT
CHAMPION OF THE WORLD,
40th STREET BLACK!
OK, FELLAS,
YOU BOTH KNOW THE RULES.
I WANT YOU TO OBEY
MY COMMANDS.
WHEN I SAY BREAK,
I WANT YOU BOTH
TO STEP BACK CLEAN.
KEEP YOUR PUNCHES UP,
PROTECT YOURSELF
AT ALL TIMES.
THIS IS IT, BROTHER.
SHAKE HANDS NOW
AND COME OUT FIGHTING.
I JUST HOPE
HE'S STILL UNDER.
WHAT?!
I AIN'T SURE.
THAT'S NOT RIGHT.
WHAT IS HAPPENING?!
6...7...
8...9...
IF YOU AIN'T
CLEAN AS A MOP,
YOU GONNA HAVE
A SHORT LIFE.
WHAT?
YOU MAY BE LIVING
A LITTLE TOO
DANGEROUSLY, MR. SLADE.
YOU CAN'T SELL NO WOLF TICKETS
HERE, KANSAS CITY.
NOW, WE GONNA BE BY TO SEE YOU.
HAVE THE BREAD READY.
YOU GOT MY MEANING?
MEET ME AT MY WAREHOUSE
ON MACON STREET
IN HALF AN HOUR.
WE GOTCHA.
YOU BETTER GO
UN-HYPNOTIZE FARNSWORTH
BEFORE WE DO ANYTHING ELSE.
I'M GONNA MAKE A PHONE CALL.
BETH, LISTEN.
YOU AND DEE DEE GET PACKED
AS SOON AS YOU CAN,
AND WHEN YOU'RE FINISHED,
HERE'S WHAT I WANT YOU TO DO.
NOW, DON'T ASK QUESTIONS!
MY MAIN MAN! OH!
WE DID IT! WE DID IT!
WE DID IT! AAH!
WHAT'S GOING ON?
HOW DO YOU FEEL,
BOOTNEY?
I DIDN'T FEEL A THING.
HOW COULD YOU
WHEN HE NEVER LAID
A GLOVE ON YOU, CHAMP?
NEVER LAID
A GLOVE ON ME?
UH-HUH.
CHAMP? YOU MEAN...
I WON?
OF COURSE!
OH, KID,
YOU WERE TERRIFIC.
BETTER THAN THE LAST
SPARRING SESSION.
THE LAST
SPARRING SESSION? I WON--
YOU MEAN I'M THE CHAMP?
THAT'S RIGHT! HA HA HA.
I'M THE CHAMP?
THAT'S RIGHT!
THAT'S RIGHT,
'CAUSE I AM BAD!
I'M SO BAD THAT SOMETIMES
I EVEN SCARE MYSELF!
HA HA HA!
AND DON'T NOBODY
MESS WITH ME,
OTHERWISE, I'M GONNA
DRIVE ON THEIR FACE!
I HEARD THAT!
I AM THE CHAMP!
NOW, WHO AM I?
THE CHAMP!
WHO?
THAT'S RIGHT,
AND DON'T Y'ALL FORGET IT!
AH HA!
WE GONNA HAVE A PARTY
IN THIS HOTEL SO BIG,
WE GONNA BE BOOGYIN' DOWN
ALL NIGHT!
I AM THE CHAMP!
HA HA HA HA!
HOLD IT!
WE'RE GONNA
WAIT FOR A CALL.
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE
THAT NEITHER FIGHTER
WAS DRUGGED OR HYPED UP.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
YEAH, SURE.
TAKE YOUR TIME.
HELLO.
MM-HMM.
RIGHT.
SEE YOU AROUND.
WHO THE HELL
IS HE?
THIS IS MY--
I'M HIS PARTNER.
WHAT'D YOU DO
TO 40th STREET BLACK?
WHAT YOU MEAN?
HOW'D YOU
PUT THE FIX IN?
YOU ACCUSING US
OF A CHEAT?
THOUGHT YOU MIGHT WANT
TO SHARE A PROFESSIONAL SECRET.
YOU LOST, MACK.
LIVE WITH IT.
YEAH.
THERE'S YOUR MONEY.
COUNT IT.
NO NEED
TO COUNT IT.
SURE HOPE YOU BOYS
DON'T HAVE AN ACCIDENT
ON THE WAY HOME
WITH ALL THAT MONEY.
KEEP AN EYE ON 'EM
FOR A WHILE.
WE OUGHT TO KNOW
WHERE THEY ARE
IN CASE WE NEED
TO PUT OUR HANDS ON THEM.
♪ BABY, WHATCHA
TRYIN' TO DO TO ME? ♪
♪ I'M BLIND
OUT OF MY MIND WITH LOVE ♪
♪ MMM ♪
♪ BUT, SWEET THING,
CAN YOU SHOW IT? ♪
♪ I KNOW THIS GOOD LOVIN'
CAN KNOCK YOU OUT ♪
♪ AND I'LL DO IT
TILL THE MORNIN' COMES ♪
♪ BABY, ROCK MY SOUL ♪
♪ I'M YOURS TO HOLD ♪
♪ YOU'VE LOVED ME
SO LONG ♪
♪AND YOU'VE
BEEN SO STRONG ♪
♪ KEEP ME HANGIN' ON ♪
♪ LOVE YOU TO THE BONE ♪
♪ OOH, OOH, OOH, OOH ♪
♪ OUT OF ALL THE THINGS
A WOMAN DREAMS... ♪
CONGRATULATIONS,
MR. ELLISON.
OH, HELLO,
MR. MACK.
THE BOY WAS FANTASTIC.
THANK YOU.
HE CAME INTO
HIS OWN TONIGHT.
SCOTCH AND SODA.
IT ALL STARTED
THE LAST DAY WE SPARRED.
HE KNOCKED OUT ALL
OF HIS SPARRING PARTNERS,
SMASHED UP THE RING,
AND HE HIT
THE HEAVY BAG SO HARD
THAT THE CEILING CAVED IN!
HA HA HA HA HA!
NO KIDDING?
I'M TELLING YOU!
MAN, HE MUST
HAVE REALLY
HAD HIS SELF
PSYCHED UP FOR IT.
PSYCHED UP IS WHAT IT WAS,
BECAUSE THERE WERE TIMES
WHEN I DIDN'T EVEN
KNOW HIM MYSELF! HA HA HA!
MY, MY,
CAN YOU BEAT THAT?
YEAH, IT WAS LIKE HE
WAS IN A TRANCE. YOU KNOW?
MY, MY.
♪ DO DO DO ♪
♪ DO DO DO DO ♪
HERE COMES THE CHAMP!
IT WAS LIKE
HE WAS IN A TRANCE!
LET'S GET TO A PHONE.
♪ DO DO DO DO DO ♪
♪ SWEET LOUISIANA ♪
OHH.
HA HA HA HA HA HA!
WHOO WHOO WHEE!
♪IT'S TRUE ♪
♪ LOVE WITH YOU ♪
♪ SPIRITUAL AFFECTION ♪
♪ LIFELONG PROTECTION ♪
♪ SEE THE PAINTED CITY ♪
♪ OOH, AIN'T IT PRETTY? ♪
♪ FUNKY AND RICH ♪
♪ WORKIN' FOR THE BOSS ♪
♪ CARRYIN' THE CROSS ♪
♪ WHAT DO YOU DO? ♪
♪ JESUS IS TRUE ♪
♪ SPIRITUAL AFFECTION ♪
♪ LIFELONG PROTECTION ♪
♪ GIVE US THE STAGE ♪
♪ OOH, YEA-HEAH, LORD ♪
BROTHERS AND SISTERS,
WELCOME TO THE NEW HOME
OF THE SONS AND DAUGHTERS
OF SHAKA.
THE STORM HAS PASSED!
AND ONCE AGAIN
OUR MIGHTY SHIP
IS BACK ON COURSE!
I WANT TO THANK ESPECIALLY
OUR TREASURER
AND VICE MARSHAL
FOR THOSE SUCCESSFUL
INVESTMENTS THEY MADE
ON THE STOCK MARKET.
THANKS TO THEIR EFFORTS,
WE ARE NOW IN A BRAND-NEW HOME.
WE HAVE A BRAND-NEW
DAY-CARE CENTER
RIGHT DOWNSTAIRS,
AND $10,000 TOWARD
THE NEW NURSERY SCHOOL
BUILDING FUND.
BUT...NOW, I PROMISED
THAT THERE WASN'T GONNA
BE ANY SPEECHES TODAY,
AND I'M GONNA
KEEP MY PROMISE.
UH, BUT BEFORE
I DO SIT DOWN,
THERE IS ONE MORE THING
I JUST GOT TO SAY.
NOW, NO LONGER
ARE WE GONNA HAVE TO CRAWL
ON THE BACK ROADS
OF NO CAN DO!
FROM NOW ON WE ARE RIDING
ON THE FREEWAY
OF YES, WE CAN, TOO!
NOW...
SO, LET'S EAT, DRINK,
AND ENJOY OURSELVES
ON THIS MOST MOMENTOUS
OCCASION.
I THANK YOU.
PARDON ME, SISTERS.
YES? MAY WE
HELP YOU?
YOU CERTAINLY CAN.
I'M MacARTHUR CLUTCH.
ME AND MY ASSOCIATES
WOULD LIKE TO SPEAK
TO YOUR HUSBANDS
REGARDING INVESTMENTS.
INVESTMENTS?
YES. YOU SEE, WE KNOW
THAT YOUR HUSBANDS
HAVE BEEN DOING SOME
SMALL-TIME INVESTING
TO HELP OUT THE LODGE.
LIKE SOME BETS THEY MADE
IN THE STOCK MARKET.
WE'RE HERE TO SHOW THEM
HOW THEY CAN INCREASE
THEIR DIVIDENDS.
IN OTHER WORDS, HOW THEY
CAN GET PAID BACK...
MORE.
OH. HEH.
YES. YOU SEE, WE REPRESENT
A NEW ORLEANS BREAKAGE FIRM.
HE MEANS
BROKERAGE FIRM.
WE WANT TO SHOW
YOUR HUSBANDS SOME BREAKS.
YEAH, WE'D LIKE
TO SHOW THEM
HOW THEY CAN
MAKE MORE BREAKS
FOR THEMSELVES
AND THE LODGE.
WELL, LOOK, WE REALLY
DON'T KNOW TOO MUCH
ABOUT WHAT YOU'RE SAYING,
BUT WHY DON'T I TAKE YOU
OVER TO MY HUSBAND,
AND THEN YOU AND HIM
CAN TALK IT OUT. ALL RIGHT?
OH, THAT WOULD
BE JUST DANDY.
OH, GOOD.
I TELL YOU...
I KNEW THIS BIRD
FROM ANOTHER LIFE.
BILLY.
HMM?
THERE'S SOME MEN HERE
WHO WANNA TALK TO YOU
ABOUT INTEREST
AND DIVIDENDS.
FELLAS, THESE MEN
ARE FROM NEW ORLEANS.
THEY REPRESENT
A BROKERAGE FIRM.
THE STRONG-ARM
BROKERAGE FIRM
OF NEW ORLEANS.
OUR MOTTO IS,
"WE GET EVEN,
AND YOU CAN
COUNT ON IT."
THEY'RE HERE
TO HELP THE LODGE
MAKE SOME MONEY.
MONEY?
SOMEBODY SAY MONEY?
YES, GRAND SUPREME,
UM--
THESE, UM, THIS IS
MR. MacARTHUR CLUTCH
AND HIS ASSOCIATES--
A BROKERAGE.
WELL, NOW.
HOW DO YOU DO, GENTLEMEN?
HOW DO YOU DO?
JUST FINE, SIR.
ACTUALLY, THERE'S
NOT TOO MUCH TO DISCUSS
AT THIS TIME,
GRAND SUPREME,
JUST A FEW
MINOR DETAILS
FOR PRELIMINARY
PURPOSES.
BUT I WAS WONDERING
IF I MIGHT BORROW
YOUR TREASURER
TO DISCUSS THIS MATTER
IN PRIVATE.
YOU KNOW,
ALL THE BORING DETAILS.
WELL, I THINK THAT
WOULD BE JUST FINE.
NOW, UH, I'D LIKE
TO GO WITH YOU MYSELF,
BUT MY PLACE
IS DOWN HERE RIGHT NOW.
BUT WHY DON'T YOU TAKE
BROTHER WILLIAMS ALONG
AS MY PROXY?
OOH, I WAS JUST GONNA ASK YOU
IF THAT MIGHT BE POSSIBLE.
OF COURSE IT'S POSSIBLE.
NOW, BETH AND DEE DEE,
SHOW THESE KIND GENTLEMEN
RIGHT UP TO MY OFFICE.
WE'LL JUST
BE A MINUTE.
US BREAKERS DON'T TAKE
TOO LONG TO DO NOTHING.
WON'T YOU
FOLLOW ME, PLEASE?
WELL, WE'LL SEE Y'ALL
WHEN YOU GET
DOWNSTAIRS, HEAR?
BYE, BABY.
I'M GONNA KILL 'EM!
OH, WAIT!
WAIT A MINUTE!
WAIT! WAIT!
WAIT!
WAIT A MINUTE!
WAIT! WAIT!
NOT NOW,
BUBBLETOP.
NOT HERE.
I'LL MURDERIZE 'EM!
I'M GONNA LET YOU
HAVE 'EM, BUBBLETOP.
YOU CAN PICK 'EM
CLEAN,
BUT FIRST WE TALK.
DISHONEST CROOKS.
HYPOCRITSITS.
YOU MADE FOOLS OF US,
MR. MONGO SLADE.
YOU WON A SMALL VICTORY,
BUT YOU GONNA LOSE THE WAR.
YOUR WIVES
GONNA BE WIDOWS
AND YOUR LODGE GONNA BE
MARCHING BACK AND FORTH
TO THE CEMETERY.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
I'M TALKING ABOUT
FARNSWORTH'S HYPNOSIS
AND 10 GRAND
AT 5-TO-1.
HYPNOSIS? WE DON'T KNOW
NOTHING ABOUT NO HYPNOSIS.
DO YOU KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT HYPNOSIS?
NO, WE DON'T KNOW NOTHING
ABOUT NO HYPNOSIS.
BUBBLETOP KNOWS
ABOUT HYPNOSIS.
WANT HIM TO SHOW YOU
WHAT HE KNOWS ABOUT IT?
NO!
NO, NO, NO, NO.
WE--WE--
WE KNOW A LITTLE
ABOUT HYPNOSIS.
JUST A LITTLE.
YOU PUT THE WHAMMY
ON FARNSWORTH,
MADE HIM THINK
HE WAS SUPERMAN.
THEN YOU PUT THE BITE
ON US AND DISAPPEARED.
TOOK A WHILE
TO FIGURE IT OUT
AND A WHILE LONGER
TO FIND YOU,
BUT WE GOT
YOUR ASSES NOW.
WHAT YOU LOOKING
AT ME LIKE THAT FOR?
YOU'RE THE ONE THAT PUT
THE WHAMMY ON FARNSWORTH--
DON'T YOU LOOK AT ME
LIKE THAT.
AND DON'T LOOK AT NONE
OF MY BOYS, NEITHER.
LOOK AT HIM.
ANY OF YOU GUYS
FEEL SLEEPY?
NOW CUT THAT OUT!
WHERE'D YOU LEARN
TO PUT THE WHAMMY
ON PEOPLE LIKE THAT?
IN THE ARMY.
MEDICAL CORP.
WELL, BUBBLETOP
GONNA PUT BOTH Y'ALL
TO SLEEP SOON ENOUGH
IF YOU DON'T JUMP
AT THIS PROPOSITION
I'M GONNA LAY ON YOU.
PROPOSITION?
WHAT--
WHAT PROPOSITION?
ONE THAT
WILL GET OUR MONEY BACK
AND AT THE SAME TIME
WE WIPE OUT BIGGIE SMALLS,
PUT HIM OUT
OF BUSINESS FOR GOOD.
THE REMATCH
BETWEEN FARNSWORTH
AND 40th STREET BLACK
IS COMING UP
ONE WEEK FROM TONIGHT.
THE 6 OF US IN THIS ROOM
ARE THE ONLY PEOPLE
IN THE WORLD THAT KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED LAST TIME.
NOT FARNSWORTH
NOR ANY OF HIS PEOPLE
HAVE THE SLIGHTEST IDEA
WHAT WENT DOWN.
QUIET AS IT'S KEPT,
FARNSWORTH
IS HIS OLD SELF AGAIN.
HIS SPARRING PARTNERS
ARE KNOCKIN' HIM
AROUND THE RING.
HE LOST THAT CONFIDENCE
YOU GAVE HIM,
AND NOW HIS PUNCHES
CAN'T BREAK AN EGG.
SO?
SO YOU COME
BACK TO ORLEANS
AND HYPNOTIZE
FARNSWORTH AGAIN
3 DAYS BEFORE THE FIGHT
SO THE WHOLE WORLD CAN SEE
THAT HE IS BACK
IN WINNING CONDITION
AND EVERYBODY
WILL WANT TO BET ON HIM.
ME AND MY BOYS
WILL COVER THOSE BETS.
THEN ON THE MORNING
OF THE FIGHT,
YOU WILL DEHYPNOTIZE
FARNSWORTH
SO WHEN HE CLIMBS
IN THAT RING,
HE'LL BE HIS OLD,
SCARED SELF AGAIN.
AFTER THE FIGHT,
WE'LL BE EVEN
AND YOU'LL
BE FREE TO GO.
WELL, HOW DO WE KNOW
WE CAN TRUST YOU?
I TRUST YOU.
ME, TOO.
SO WHAT'S IT GONNA BE?
YOU COMING
BACK TO ORLEANS
OR YOU GONNA ASK
THE GRAND SUPREME
TO MAKE OUT YOUR
FUNERAL ARRANGEMENTS?
WELL, I'VE ALWAYS ENJOYED
GOING TO NEW ORLEANS.
I'D--I'D RATHER GO--
I'D RATHER GO
TO NEW ORLEANS...
THAN THE CEMETERY.
MMM.
WELL, WELL, WELL.
MONGO SLADE.
WHAT CAN
I DO FOR YOU?
I WANT TO PLACE
A BET ON THE FIGHT.
NO KIDDING.
HOW MUCH OF A BET?
50,000.
ON WHO?
BOOTNEY
FARNSWORTH.
YOU KNOW LIGHTNING DOESN'T
STRIKE THE SAME PLACE TWICE?
SAYS WHO?
UH, LOOK.
EXCUSE ME A MINUTE.
I GOTTA DISCUSS
WITH MY COLLEAGUES HERE
BEFORE I CAN OK
A BET OF SUCH MAGNITUDE.
YOU UNDERSTAND,
DON'T YOU?
BROTHER.
TAKE
YOUR TIME...
BROTHER.
THE LAST TIME THAT
CHUMP WAS IN HERE,
HE BURNED US GOOD.
HE KNOWS SOMETHING.
I CAN FEEL IT!
YEAH,
ME, TOO, BOSS.
WE'RE GONNA
HAVE TO STALL HIM
FOR A COUPLE
OF DAYS.
AND LET'S TAKE A LOOK
AT FARNSWORTH,
SEE IF
WE CAN GET SOME KIND
OF LINE ON HIM.
BECAUSE IF THAT GUY
KNOWS SOMETHING,
THERE'S NO REASON
WHY WE SHOULDN'T
TAKE ADVANTAGE
OF IT, RIGHT?
RIGHT.
RIGHT. OPEN IT.
MONGO, I SUSPECT
WE CAN COVER YOUR BET,
BUT YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO GIVE US A COUPLE OF DAYS
WHILE I GET SOME EXTRA CASH
IN FROM OUT OF TOWN.
JUST SO LONG
AS YOU'LL COVER ME
BEFORE FIGHT TIME,
BIGGIE.
OH, NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT.
IN THAT CASE,
I'LL EASE ON.
WELL, IF IT AIN'T
SHUFF-ALONG MACK
AND HIS
OLD-TIME DARKIES.
BIGGIE SMALLS.
YOUR MAMA STILL WORKING
IN THEM $10 HOUSES?
SOME OTHER TIME.
ONE OF THESE DAYS,
I'M GONNA CLIMB
ALL OVER YOU.
IT'LL TAKE MORE GUTS
THAN YOU'VE GOT, BIGGIE.
YOU GOT TO BRING ASS
TO GET ASS.
YOU'RE COLORFUL,
MACK.
DUMB, OLD-FASHIONED,
AND OUT OF STYLE,
BUT COLORFUL.
BIGGIE, YOU
OUT OF YOUR TERRITORY,
AND I DON'T LIKE IT
WHEN PEOPLE COME INTO MY TOWN
WITHOUT
PAYING THEIR RESPECT.
WELL, WE NO LONGER
CONSIDER THIS TOWN
AS OUT
OF OUR TERRITORY.
WATCH YOUR MOUTH, SON.
IN FACT, I'VE BROUGHT YOU
A MESSAGE FROM THE BOYS
IN KENTUCKY AND ALABAMA.
THEY SAY YOU RUN THIS TOWN
LIKE A SISSY
AND THEY THINK YOU OUGHT
TO CONSIDER RETIRING.
WE'RE READY TO TALK A DEAL.
DEAL? LISTEN,
MISSISSIPPI AND LOUISIANA
BELONG TO ME
AND MY BOYS,
AND YOU'LL BE
ONE DEAD SUCKER,
ALONG WITH ALL THE REST
OF THESE YOUNG COLLEGE CLOWNS,
IF YOU TRY THAT
EXPANSION STUFF ON US.
YOU KNOW HOW THINGS
ARE NOWADAYS
WITH THE GAMBLING
AND SPORTING LIFE
IN THE BACK BELT.
THERE'S NO NEED
FOR TWO OF US.
YOU GOT THAT RIGHT,
BIGGIE.
NOW, MACK.
I WOULDN'T LIKE
TO SEE NO VIOLENCE.
YOU AIN'T GONNA HAVE TO.
I'M GONNA HIT YOU SO HARD
YOU WON'T SEE NOTHING, EVER!
MEANTIME, WHILE
YOU A GUEST IN MY TOWN,
IF YOU AND YOUR BOYS
LOOKING FOR SOME ACTION,
WE BETTING ON FARNSWORTH.
IF Y'ALL LIKE
40th STREET BLACK,
I'LL COVER EVERYTHING
YOU GOT, SUCKER.
HEY, BOSS.
YOU SEE WHAT I SEE?
I'M LOOKING.
THOSE GUYS
ARE WORKING FOR MACK.
Biggie:
WELL, I'LL BE DAMNED.
IT WAS MACK ALL ALONG
WHO BEAT US OUT
OF THAT BREAD
IN THE FIRST FIGHT.
YEAH, LOOKS
LIKE WE WERE SET UP.
IT SEEMS THAT LIGHTNING
IS TRYING TO STRIKE
IN THE SAME PLACE TWICE.
THIS WHOLE THING HAS
FINALLY COME TOGETHER.
OH, YEAH, BOSS?
YEAH!
SLADE COMES OVER TO US
TO DROP SOME HEAVY CASH
ON FARNSWORTH,
THINKING WE'D BE ONLY
TOO GLAD TO PICK IT UP
BECAUSE THE WORD IS OUT
THAT FARNSWORTH
AIN'T GOT NOTHING
GOING FOR HIM.
MACK IS BETTING
ON FARNSWORTH
WHILE TELLING US
THAT WE CAN BET
ON 40th STREET BLACK.
SO WHERE'S ALL
THE HEAVY MONEY GOING?
ON 40th STREET
BLACK.
RIGHT!
SUCKER MONEY,
EVERY LAST CENT OF IT,
'CAUSE HERE IT IS
THE LAST DAY OF SPARRING,
AND FARNSWORTH CHANGES UP
AFTER PLAYING POSSUM
FOR ALL THESE WEEKS.
AND FOR THE SUCKERS
IT'S TOO LATE,
AND MACK KNOWS IT.
AND IF WE HADN'T SEEN
THIS SESSION,
WE'D HAVE BET
ON BLACK, TOO,
AND WE'D HAVE
BEEN CLEANED OUT.
MACK IS A FOX,
A DIRTY OL' FOX.
YOU CALL KENTUCKY
AND ALABAMA
AND GET EVERY CENT
YOU CAN MUSTER UP
IN HERE TO ME
AS FAST AS YOU CAN GET IT.
RIGHT, BOSS.
WE ARE GONNA HIT
EVERY BOOK
IN THIS TOWN
WITH BIG BUCKS,
UNDERSTAND?
NOTHING BUT
HEAVY, HEAVY BETS!
YOU GET THE WORD
AROUND TOWN
THAT WE'RE BETTING
ON FARNSWORTH,
AND YOU TELL
ALL TAKERS
THAT THE ODDS
ARE NEGOTIABLE.
IT'S AS GOOD
AS DONE, BOSS.
OK, YOU CONTACT
EVERY BOOK IN TOWN.
TELL 'EM THAT BIGGIE SMALLS
AND HIS BOYS ARE BETTING
VERY HEAVY ON FARNSWORTH,
AND WE COVERING EVERY CENT.
LET'S GO.
YEAH, THIS IS MACK.
GOOD.
FELLAS...
WE'RE ON OUR WAY.
YEAH?
Mack:
EVERYTHING'S SET.
IT'S TIME
TO DEHYPNOTIZE OUR FRIEND.
AND DO IT RIGHT,
UNDERSTAND?
YEAH.
WE'RE LEAVING NOW.
WHERE DO YOU
HAVE TO GO SO EARLY?
IT'S 8:00
IN THE MORNING.
THAT WAS MR. CLUTCH, DEAR.
YOU CAN PLAN A LONG DAY.
WELL, MAKE A LOT OF MONEY
FOR THE LODGE, HONEY.
SURE.
MACK JUST CALLED.
IT'S ALL SET.
IT'S UP TO YOU NOW.
UHH! WELL?
I COULDN'T
CATCH HIM.
WELL, WHERE IS HE?
AT THE RATE
HE'S GOING,
HE'S IN MEXICO
BY NOW.
WELL, COME ON.
WE HAVE TO CATCH HIM
AT HIS HOTEL.
COME ON, STICK, STICK.
THERE YOU GO.
STICK IT, STICK IT.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
CROSS WITH THE RIGHT.
CROSS THE RIGHT.
THERE YOU GO.
SHOOT SOME JABS.
JAB, JAB!
FELLAS, GO AHEAD
AND PUT HIM TO BED.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
I DID WITH THE KEY.
I MUST'VE LEFT IT
DOWN IN THE BAR
OR SOMEWHERE--
OH, MISS!
PARDON ME.
DO YOU HAVE A KEY?
COULD YOU
OPEN THE DOOR
'CAUSE I LEFT THE KEY
DOWN IN THE BAR
OR SOMEWHERE,
I DON'T KNOW.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
CERTAINLY APPRECIATE IT.
THANK YOU.
WHAT THE HELL'S
GOING ON?!
OH!
OH, UH...DO YOU
HAVE YOUR CARD?
GET--GET--
GET YOUR CARD OUT.
SEE IF YOU CAN
FIND YOUR CARD.
OH, MY CARD.
HERE IT IS!
HERE'S THE CARD!
NO, THIS IS
FROM THE SUIT.
UH...
WE REPRESENT
THE CHAMP'S HOMETOWN--
WE'RE THE LOCAL BOARD
CHAMBER OF COMMERCE
FROM THE CHAMP'S
HOMETOWN--
AND, UH, THIS
IS MY FRIEND HERE
AS YOU CAN SEE.
NOW, UH...
YES! YOU DID,
OF COURSE,
AND YOU'RE RIGHT
ABOUT ALL OF IT.
BUT WE WROTE A SONG
FOR THE CHAMP
COMING FROM
POSSUM'S PAW, ALABAMA.
THIS IS, UH...
MR. SEBASTIAN SEBASTIAN.
HE'S THE COMPOSER
OF THE SONG.
MR. SEBASTIAN.
NOW, YOU'RE
PROBABLY, UH...
WONDERING
ABOUT THE WINDOW.
YEAH.
NO.
YES. WELL.
UH, YOU SEE,
WHEN WE FIRST
ARRIVED HERE,
WE CAME UP TO SEE
THE CHAMP LEGITIMATELY.
CAME UP AND WE SAID
WE'D LIKE
TO SEE THE CHAMP.
NOW, PEOPLE SAID
YOU CANNOT SEE THE CHAMP
THE DAY
BEFORE THE FIGHT.
SO, MY FRIEND AND I
TOOK IT UPON OURSELVES
TO COME OUT ON LEDGES
AND DO ALL SORTS OF THINGS,
MAINLY BECAUSE
IN OUR HOMETOWN
OF POSSUM'S PAW,
ALABAMA,
WHICH IS THE CHAMP'S
HOMETOWN ALSO,
THERE IS AN ORPHANAGE.
NOW, THIS ORPHANAGE
HAS REAL ORPHANS.
I MEAN, THESE KIDS,
THEY DON'T
EVEN HAVE...THINGS.
SOME OF 'EM WE DON'T KNOW
WHERE THEY CAME FROM.
WE GOT, UH,
ONE GREEN ONE.
POOR CHILD.
AND HE LOVES THE CHAMP
MORE THAN ANYBODY
BECAUSE HE DOESN'T HAVE
ANYONE TO IDENTIFY WITH.
BUT IF YOU SAY
THE CHAMP'S NAME,
WHY, THEY START ACTING
JUST LIKE
THEY HAD REAL PARENTS
AND THEY'RE
RUNNING AROUND
WRITING THEIR NAMES
ON THE WALLS.
WE DECIDED TO TAKE IT
UPON OURSELVES
TO COME IN
THROUGH THE WINDOW...
TO TRY
TO GET TO THE CHAMP
TO SEE IF THERE'S SOME WAY
THAT WE COULD SING THE SONG.
SO WE'D LIKE
TO SING IT FOR YOU
IF IT'S ALL RIGHT.
♪ MM MM ♪
♪ OH, CHAMP,
WE LOVES YOU ♪
♪ YES, WE DO ♪
♪ WE LOVES YOU
EVEN IF YOU WIN ♪
♪ OR LOSE ♪
♪ OH, CHAMP ♪
♪ OH, CHAMP,
WE WITH YOU ♪
♪ THROUGH THICK ♪
♪ AND THIN ♪
GET DOWN. GET DOWN.
CALL THE POLICE.
NOW, WHAT THE HELL'S
THE SENSE OF TALKING
ABOUT BUILDING
A RECREATION CENTER
FOR THIS AREA
WHEN OUR COMMUNITY
RELATIONS TEAM
SITS ON THEIR FAT ASSES
AND BLOWS STEAM?
$2,500 IN 6 MONTHS.
IS THAT THE BEST
THEY CAN DO?
NOW YOU TELL 'EM
TO GET OFF THEIR TAILS
AND GET OUT IN THE COMMUNITY
AND RELATE.
TELL 'EM I WANT
TO SEE SOME IMPROVEMENTS
OR I'M GONNA
HAVE THEIR HEADS!
NOW, GO AHEAD.
OPEN IT UP.
MY NAME IS
LIEUTENANT BOTTOMLEY,
27th PRECINCT.
WE GOT YOU HERE
ON A VARIETY OF CHARGES.
YOU HAVE?
BREAKING AND ENTERING.
CRIMINAL TRESPASS.
CRIMINAL MISCHIEF.
BURGLARY.
ATTEMPTED LARCENY.
ATTEMPTED MURDER.
IT ALL DEPENDS ON WHAT
YOUR INTENTIONS WERE
TO FARNSWORTH.
BUT WE DIDN'T TRY
TO MURDER ANYBODY.
WE WOULDN'T
HURT A FLY.
THEN JUST WHAT WERE
YOU DOING THERE?
WELL, SEE, WE'RE
FROM THE CHAMP'S HOMETOWN,
BILLY AND ME,
AND WE CAME UP
TO SING HIM A SONG
THAT WE SPECIALLY
COMPOSED FOR HIM.
AND, UH, I HAD TO HAVE
THE RIGHT VOCAL PITCH
IN ORDER TO GET
THE RIGHT VOCAL LEVEL.
I'M SURE YOU UNDERSTAND.
JUST LISTEN
TO THE SOUND
OF THE CHARM.
JUST LISTEN.
LISTEN, LISTEN, LISTEN.
LISTEN...LISTEN...
WELL, WE
GOT OUT OF THAT.
WHAT DO YOU
MEAN "WE"?
I GOT US
OUT OF THAT FIX.
AND FROM NOW ON,
I'M GONNA DO
THE THINKING.
ALL ALONG YOU'VE BEEN
TELLING ME WHAT TO DO,
AND MACK'S BEEN
TELLING ME WHAT--
WELL, NOW I'M GONNA
TELL ME WHAT TO DO.
AND I'M GONNA TELL YOU
WHAT TO DO, HUH?
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
WELL, SINCE THERE'S NO WAY
TO GET TO FARNSWORTH
TO DEHYPNOTIZE HIM...
YEAH?
EVERYTHING'S
PERFECT AT MY END.
YOUR MOVE.
WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA DO WITH IT?
I'M GONNA INVEST IT.
Dee Dee:
WITH MR. CLUTCH?
IN A MANNER
OF SPEAKING, YES.
NOW, UH, WE NEED YOU,
AND THE LODGE NEEDS YOU,
MORE THAN EVER BEFORE.
NOW, I DON'T WANT YOU
ASKING ANY QUESTIONS.
I DON'T WANT YOU
TO GET UPSET.
I WANT YOU
TO LISTEN CAREFULLY.
WE CANNOT AFFORD
ANY MISTAKES.
BIGGIE SMALLS?
WHO WANTS HIM?
I WANT TO MAKE A BET
ON THE FIGHT.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
HE TAKES BETS ON FIGHTS?
WELL, IF HE DON'T,
I GUESS I'LL JUST
HAVE TO TAKE MY $5,000
AND GO SOMEPLACE ELSE,
NOW, WON'T I?
WELL, WHO IS
BIGGIE SMALLS?
YOU DO YOUR BUSINESS
WITH ME FOR THE TIME BEING.
WHERE'S YOUR $5,000?
ON WHO?
IT'S RIGHT THERE
ON THE PAPER.
YOU SERIOUS?
IS THERE SALT
IN THE SEA?
DOES HONEY COME
FROM A BEE?
YOU BET YOUR ASS
I'M SERIOUS.
YOU SURE YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE DOING, LADY?
IF I DIDN'T,
I WOULDN'T BE HERE, SUGAR.
$5,000
AT 20-TO-1 ODDS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND YOU'RE
BETTING ON, UH--
BETTIN' EXACTLY
WHAT'S ON THAT PAPER.
IF YOU WIN,
I'LL MOVE ON,
YOU KEEP MY 5 GRAND,
AND BLESS YOU, SUGAR.
IF YOU LOSE,
I'LL BE BACK
FOR 100 THOU.
DEAL?
LADY, YOU MUST
HAVE MONEY TO BURN.
DEAL.
EXCUSE ME.
YEAH?
HELLO, THIS IS ZACK.
I GOT A CRAZY LADY
DOWN HERE
WHO'S PUTTING DOWN
5,000 BILLS
ON THE WEIRDEST BET
I EVER HEARD.
SHE WANTS...
5,000 AT 20-TO-1, HUH?
PROBABLY SOME NUT.
SHE'S GOT THE MONEY THERE?
UH-HUH.
YEAH, WELL, TAKE IT.
WHAT THE HELL,
AS LONG AS THE MONEY'S REAL.
YEAH.
LET'S EAT.
15 ROUNDS OF BOXING
FOR THE MIDDLEWEIGHT
CHAMPIONSHIP OF THE WORLD!
JUDGING AT RINGSIDE,
MARVIN LEWIS,
ON MY LEFT AT RINGSIDE,
LLOYD GOWDY.
YOUR REFEREE, THE MAN
IN CHARGE IN THE RING,
GIVING INSTRUCTIONS
AFTER INTRODUCTIONS,
LARRY ROSADILLA!
HERE WE GO!
IN THIS CORNER,
THE CHALLENGER,
WEIGHING 160 POUNDS,
WEARING BLACK TRUNKS
WITH A WHITE STRIPE,
THE FORMER MIDDLEWEIGHT
CHAMPION OF THE WORLD,
FROM BIGFOOT, MISSISSIPPI,
40th STREET BLACK!
AND HIS OPPONENT,
DEFENDING HIS CROWN,
WEARING WHITE TRUNKS
WITH A BLACK STRIPE,
THE MIDDLEWEIGHT CHAMPION
OF THE WORLD,
BOOTNEY FARNSWORTH!
OK, FELLAS,
YOU BOTH KNOW THE RULES.
THIS IS FOR THE MIDDLEWEIGHT
CHAMPIONSHIP OF THE WORLD.
I WANT YOU
TO OBEY MY COMMANDS.
WHEN I TELL YOU TO BREAK,
I WANT YOU BOTH
TO BREAK CLEAN,
BUT PROTECT YOURSELF
AT ALL TIMES.
SHAKE HANDS NOW AND
GOOD LUCK TO BOTH OF YOU.
STAY AWAY!
HIT HIM WITH IT!
GET UP!
NO!
DIRTY ROTTEN, NO-GOOD
CROOKED TURKEYS!
THEY CROSSED US!
THEY BEAT US AGAIN!
MACK!
THAT DIRTY ROTTEN
DOUBLE-CROSSER!
THIS IS WHAT HE WAS
RIGGING FROM THE START,
AND WE COULDN'T SEE IT!
WE COULDN'T SEE IT!
THAT BROAD!
THEY SENT THAT BROAD
INTO ZACH'S
WITH 5 GRAND
AT 20-TO-1.
THEN THEY FIXED
THE FIGHT,
KNOWING IT WAS GONNA END
IN A FIRST-ROUND DRAW.
HE SENT THAT FROWSY BROAD
UP THERE TO MAKE THAT STUPID
$5,000 BET!
AT 20-TO-1, HE STANDS
TO SCORE 100 GRAND!
LET'S GO. WE GOT
TO GET TO ZACK'S.
WE FIND 'EM,
AND WE KILL 'EM.
♪ BIG MACK ♪
STEP ON IT, MAN.
THAT BROAD
WITH THE CRAZY BET!
SHE JUST LEFT.
YOU PAID HER?
WELL, YOU
OK'd THE BET.
AW, DAMN IT, ZACK!
WHERE'D SHE GO?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU DON'T KNOW?
HEY, WAIT A MINUTE, BOSS.
WE KNOW WHO SENT HER.
YEAH!
THEM 2 KNUCKLEHEADS
FROM ATLANTA,
AND THEY'RE GONNA
BE DEAD BEFORE SUNRISE!
IT'S GOT TO BE SOMEBODY
THEY TRUST A HELL OF A LOT
TO HELP WITH THIS CON.
A WIFE!
BUT WHICH ONE?
I'LL BE DAMNED.
BOTH OF THEM.
THEM DUMB FIELD HANDS
SMARTER THAN I THOUGHT.
I'LL BET YOU
BIGGIE SMALLS GOT HIT
FOR 100 GRAND, TOO.
THE LINES ARE ALL DEAD.
THE PAY PHONE
ACROSS THE STREET.
♪ BIG MACK ♪
I WANNA SPEAK
TO BIGGIE SMALLS.
IT'S URGENT.
I'M SORRY, SIR,
BUT MR. SMALLS
IS OUT FOR THE EVENING.
I'M NOT SURE
WHEN HE'LL BE BACK.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
OUT FOR THE EVENING?
LET'S GET TO HIS HOTEL.
DON'T TOUCH IT!
THE ONLY THING YOU'RE
GONNA LEAVE HERE WITH
IS YOUR LIFE
AND A MESSAGE.
OH?
WE KNOW WHO YOU ARE,
AND WE KNOW WHO SENT YOU.
WHO SENT ME?
TELL KANSAS CITY MACK
IF HE WANTS THIS MONEY
TO COME HERE
AND GET IT HIMSELF.
JUST TELL HIM
TO COME ON UP HERE.
JUST TELL HIM TO COME UP HERE
AND HE'LL GET THE BIG PAYOFF!
KANSAS CITY MACK.
KANSAS CITY MACK?!
YOU THINK I WORK
FOR THAT SMALL-TIME
COUNTRY CHUMP?
YOU SURPRISE ME,
MR. SMALLS.
YOU AIN'T GOT THE SMARTS
I THOUGHT YOU HAD.
WHAT?
I WORK FOR THE NEW
SYNDICATE, SUGAR.
I'M ON THE ROAD 10 DAYS
OUT OF EVERY MONTH.
ALL I DO IS MOVE MONEY
FROM ONE CITY TO ANOTHER.
WHEN THEY WIN, I PICK UP.
WHEN THEY LOSE, I DELIVER.
NOW, THAT MONEY IS THEIRS.
AND THEY WANT IT IN CHICAGO
WITH ME BY MORNING.
YOU'RE LYING.
YOU TRY ME.
WILL YOU TELL
THIS CHILD
TO GET THAT THING
OUTTA MY FACE
BEFORE I MAKE HER
EAT IT?
YOU BETTER LET ME
CALL CHICAGO.
YEAH, GET ME
CHICAGO, SUGAR.
225-3599.
HELLO, CHIEF?
I'M HAVIN' TROUBLE
WITH THE PICK-UP.
HE'S RIGHT HERE.
UH-HUH.
SAY, ARE YOU CRAZY?
NOW, LISTEN,
I UNDERSTAND
THAT YOU'RE 6'2"
AND GOOD-LOOKING.
NOW HOW WOULD YOU LIKE
TO BE 4'2" AND UGLY?
AIR-CONDITION YOUR BRAINS
AND ARRANGE FOR YOU
TO SPEND SOME TIME
IN THE BOTTOM OF THE OCEAN
IN A BOX OF CEMENT!
YOU GET UP OFF OF THE MONEY
AND KEEP YOUR GOOD LOOKS
AND YOUR LIFE!
NOW, WE WANT THE WOMAN
AND THE MONEY IN CHICAGO
IN THE MORNING.
NICE TALKING
TO YOU, BIGGIE.
TAKE IT.
JIVE TURKEY.
SEE YOU, SUGAR.
THERE THEY ARE!
THERE THEY GO!
WELL--HA HA.
LIEUTENANT, UH...
YOU HAVE TO EXCUSE US FOR
BARGIN' IN ON YOU LIKE THIS.
HEH HEH.
YEAH!
LOOKS LIKE WE
TURNED DOWN THE WRONG ALLEY.
YOU SEE, WE WERE LOOKIN'
FOR THE BAIL ENTRANCE,
NOT THE JAIL ENTRANCE.
RELAX, FELLAS.
IT'S ALL OVER.
WE KNOW WHAT
YOU FELLAS HAVE DONE,
AND IT'S GONNA
FOLLOW YOU FOR LIFE.
LIFE?!
WE PLEADIN'
THE FIFTH.
WE WANT OUR LAWYER.
SEE, I TOLD YOU
THEY WERE UNDULY MODEST.
YOU BETTER LET ME
GO OVER AND TALK TO THEM,
CONVINCE THEM THAT
THEY SHOULD TAKE THE RAP.
NOW, IF
Y'ALL DON'T GO ALONG
WITH WHAT ME AND CLYDE
IS ABOUT TO PUT DOWN...
WE'RE GONNA START
SINGIN' LIKE
THE TEMPTATIONS
AND EVERYBODY
GONNA DO SOME TIME
AROUND HERE.
BUT Y'ALL GONNA DO
ABOUT 30, 40 YEARS
BEFORE THE MAN EVEN START
THINKIN' ABOUT PAROLE.
SO ALL I WANT YOU TO DO
IS SMILE, SEE,
AND SHOW THAT
YOU'RE GONNA COOPERATE
WITH WHATEVER WE DO.
OH, THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
THEY'RE
READY TO CONFESS.
THEY ARE READY
TO CONFESS...
THAT IN THE PAST YEARS,
THEY HAVE WREAKED HAVOC
AMONG THE BRETHREN
OF THE COMMUNITY,
SAUSAGE NOSE,
CHITLIN EYES.
AND I SAY TO YOU,
THAT MacARTHUR CLUTCH...
AND HIAWATHA SMALLS--
HIAWATHA. HMM.
WHEN THEY HEARD
ABOUT THE POLICE
COMMUNITY
RELATIONS TEAM
TRYING TO GET MONEY
TO AID
THE RECREATION FUND
FOR THE LITTLE
SLUM KIDS,
IT BROUGHT TEARS
TO THEIR EYES.
THEY SHED TEARS.
TEARS!
HA HA! AND SO
WHEN THEY HEARD ABOUT IT,
THEY CAME RUNNING FORTH,
THROUGH A DOOR THAT THEY
DIDN'T KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT.
JUST CAME RUNNING!
AND YOU SAW THEM.
THEY WERE EXCITED,
LIKE LITTLE CHILDREN.
OH, HO, HO, WE DON'T
KNOW WHERE WE ARE.
WE DON'T KNOW WHO WE ARE
OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
AND THEY PLEAD THE FIFTH
'CAUSE THEY'RE GANGSTERS!
AND THAT'S WHY
THEY LOOKED FUNNY
WHEN THEY RAN IN HERE.
DIDN'T DO IT ON PURPOSE.
THEY WANTED TO HELP.
AND SO THAT'S
WHY THEY'RE HERE--
TO AID
THE POLICE DEPARTMENT.
SO, ON BEHALF
OF MR. MacARTHUR CLUTCH,
$10,000 FOR
THE COMMUNITY TEENS
RECREATION CENTER!
AND ON BEHALF
OF MR. HIAWATHA SMALLS,
ANOTHER $10,000
FOR THE 27th PRECINCT
COMMUNITY YOUTH CENTER!
BECAUSE MR. SMALLS
AND MR. CLUTCH
ARE SUCH
CONCERNED CITIZENS,
THEY HAVE ONE MORE
DONATION TO MAKE.
THESE 2 RECONSTRUCTED
GENTLEMEN ASKED
THAT $5,000 EACH
BE DONATED TO A LARGE
NURSERY SCHOOL FUND
IN ATLANTA, GEORGIA.
HA HA HA! HA HA HA!
OH, MY--
THIS IS FOR ATLANTA.
THE NURSERY
BACK THERE.
NOW, UH...
HA HA HA.
YES, SIR.
EXCUSE US A SECOND.
IF IT'S
THE LAST THING I DO,
I'M GONNA GET YOU
FOR THIS.
OH, THAT'S
REALLY TOO BAD.
IT SURE WOULD BE.
I MEAN, THAT WOULD MEAN
LIEUTENANT BOTTOMLEY
WOULD HAVE
TO OPEN THAT ENVELOPE
WITH ALL THAT EVIDENCE.
THAT'S REALLY
TOO BAD
BECAUSE I LIKE
SOME OF THESE GUYS.
YOU LYIN'.
OH? LIEUTENANT
BOTTOMLEY?
♪ OOH HOO ♪
WOULD YOU TELL THEM
ABOUT THE ENVELOPE?
YES. I HAVE AN ENVELOPE
IN MY SAFE.
IT'S TO BE OPENED
IN CASE MY FRIENDS HERE
MEET WITH
ANY UNTIMELY ACCIDENT.
OR COME DOWN WITH
A SEVERE CASE OF DEATH.
HA HA HA!
YOU CAN TRUST US,
LIEUTENANT.
WE WOULDN'T DREAM
OF HURTIN'
THESE 2 FINE GENTLEMEN.
NO.
GOOD. JUST IN CASE,
I'M GONNA MAKE
MY OWN STIPULATIONS.
NOW, THAT ENVELOPE
STAYS LOCKED IN MY SAFE
JUST AS LONG
AS I DON'T SEE
A TRACE OF YOU TWO
IN MY FAIR CITY AGAIN.
AGREED?
OH, YOU CAN COUNT ON US,
YOUR HONOR.
I NEVER DID LIKE NEW ORLEANS
THAT MUCH NO HOW.
JUST SO'S WE
UNDERSTAND EACH OTHER.
SAY, CLYDE, LET ME
ASK YOU A QUESTION.
IF YOU HAD
A BOXING MATCH
BETWEEN MUHAMMAD ALI
AND SAMMY DAVIS JR.,
HOW MUCH YOU THINK
THEY'D DRAW?
ARE YOU CRAZY?
NO, I'M SERIOUS.
HOW MUCH?
AND I SUPPOSE YOU'D
WANT ME TO HYPNOTIZE SAMMY?
HA HA HA.
NO.
YOU HEAR ME?
N-O. NO!
MILLIONS OF PEOPLE
BETTING AGAINST
SAMMY DAVIS JR.
AIN'T NOBODY GONNA
BET ON SAMMY DAVIS JR.
MAN DON'T WEIGH
BUT ABOUT 118 POUNDS.
FIGHTIN' A MAN
WEIGH 230 POUNDS.
ALI'D BE SO COMFORTABLE,
HE'D COME IN
WEIGHING 340 POUNDS.
COME IN, HIT SAMMY DEAD
ON TOP OF THE HEAD,
BREAK BOTH HIS LEGS.
THAT'D BE THE END
OF THE FIGHT.
BUT IF YOU
HYPNOTIZE HIM,
WE GO IN THERE
800-TO-1.
Staple Singers:
♪ ALL LAID UP NEXT TO MINE ♪
♪ SWEET LOVE
IN THE MIDNIGHT ♪
♪ GOOD SLEEP
COME MORNING LIGHT ♪
♪ NO WORRIES 'BOUT NOTHIN' ♪
♪ JUST GETTIN' GOOD ♪
♪ JUST GETTIN' GOOD LOVE ♪
♪ DO IT AGAIN ♪
♪ DO IT, DO IT ♪
♪ NOW, I LIKE YOU, LADY ♪
♪ SO FINE WITH
YOUR PRETTY HAIR ♪
♪ IF YOU DON'T MIND
MY COMPLIMENTS ♪
♪ JUST DIGGIN' ON
THE CLOTHES YOU WEAR ♪
♪ I'M JUST A MAN,
NOW, DON'T YOU FEAR... ♪
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
WARNER BROS.
CAPTIONED BY THE NATIONAL
CAPTIONING INSTITUTE --www.ncicap.org--