[
[E
[En
[Enc
[Enco
[Encod
[Encode
[Encode,
[Encode, S
[Encode, Sy
[Encode, Syn
[Encode, Sync
[Encode, Sync o
[Encode, Sync or
[Encode, Sync or S
[Encode, Sync or Su
[Encode, Sync or Sub
[Encode, Sync or Sub b
[Encode, Sync or Sub by
[Encode, Sync or Sub by A
[Encode, Sync or Sub by Ar
[Encode, Sync or Sub by Are
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreL
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLi
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLif
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
w
ww
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www
www.
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.s
www.sh
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sha
www.shar
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.share
www.shared
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedm
www.sharedmo
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmov
www.sharedmovi
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovie
www.sharedmoviel
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovieli
www.sharedmovielin
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovielink
www.sharedmovielink.
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovielink.b
www.sharedmovielink.bl
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovielink.blo
www.sharedmovielink.blog
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovielink.blogs
www.sharedmovielink.blogsp
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovielink.blogspo
www.sharedmovielink.blogspot
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovielink.blogspot.
www.sharedmovielink.blogspot.c
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovielink.blogspot.co
www.sharedmovielink.blogspot.com
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
Nacho! Nacho!
For you.
One for you.
How come we can't ever have
just, like, a salad?
Be grateful, Juan Pablo.
Today is especially delicious.
Orphans, smile and be happy,
for God has blessed us
with a new teacher.
She hails from
the Oaxaca Parish Convent
of the Immaculate Heart
Sisters Lady Mountains
of Guadalupe.
Sister Encarnacion.
Thank you, Brother.
Children, today I want to tell you
a story about Isabel.
Okay, new game.
- Go get it!
- Hey, that's my ball!
Sister.
I'm Ignacio.
God be with you, Ignacio.
Anyways,
I was wondering
if you would like to join me
in my quarters this night
for some toast.
Look alive!
There is a man sick with influenza.
I need for you to pay him a visit, huh?
- But the sister and I...
- You are always complaining
of never having priestly duties.
Here is your big duty, huh?
Go now,
so that Sister and I may talk
of holy things.
I like your cow.
Where is he?
Holy Father, please receive this man
to your kingdom.
Thank you for coming here today.
This man lived a good life.
He had a wonderful woman,
a lush garden,
and a collection
of Russian nesting dolls.
May he rest in peace.
Okay.
Hey!
Ramses...
NEW WRESTLERS TOURNAMENT
GRAND PRIZE $200
ENTER TODAY
Nacho! Nacho! Nacho!
Nacho! Nacho!
Okay.
How's it going?
It's very late, Ignacio.
Give me a second.
Good toast.
So,
everyone calls you guero.
My mother was a Lutheran missionary
from Scandinavia
and my father,
a deacon from Mexico.
They tried to convert each other,
but they got married instead.
And then they died.
So anyways, let's get down
to the nitty-gritty.
Tell me,
who is this Encarnacion?
Well,
my favorite color is light tan.
My favorite animal is puppies.
I like serving the Lord.
Hiking.
Play volleyball.
You gotta be kidding me.
Everything you just said
is my favorite thing to do
every day.
So, you enjoy yourself here
at the Brotherhood?
The children, I love the children.
They are my heart.
But to tell you the truth,
the brothers make me cook stew
and stuff all day,
but they don't give me money
for fresh ingredients.
And they don't think I know a buttload
of crap about the Gospel, but I do.
Okay?
Today, I saw a man in town.
People were throwing daisies at him
and giving him goodies.
Sometimes I would like
that kind of respect.
Who was this man?
Well, to tell you the truth,
he was a luchador.
Wrestling is ungodly, Ignacio.
People cheer for him,
but he is a false idol.
Whatever.
Be patient, Brother.
This, too, shall pass.
What is this?
Leftovers.
Enjoy.
There is no flavor.
There are no spices.
Where are the chips?
Somebody stole them.
Did you not tell them
that they were the Lord's chips?
I was trying to...
- You are useless, Ignacio.
- Silence, Brothers.
This is the worst lunch
I ever had.
Your only job is to cook.
Do you not realize
I have had diarrhea since Easters?
Okay.
Maybe I am not meant
for these duties.
Cooking duty. Dead guy duty.
Maybe it's time for me
to get a better duty.
I think your food is good.
I am the gatekeeper
of my own destiny,
and I will have my glory day
in the hot sun.
Okay?
See you.
Hey! Listen to me! Hey!
Mucho take it easy.
I need your help.
Take out the legs!
Listen to me!
Today, I have the chance of a lifetime,
but first I need a man.
Get off me!
Don't you see?
Your skills plus my skills
in the ring, tag team.
You're crazy!
Aren't you tired
of getting dirt kicked in your face?
I am!
Don't you want a little taste
of the glory?
See what it tastes like?
No!
If we win, we get 200 pesos!
Chancho!
Chancho, I need to borrow
some sweats.
Are you leaving us?
No, Chancho,
I would never leave you.
I just need to borrow
some sweats.
NEW WRESTLERS TOURNAMENT
His hair. We bet his hair.
What?
You can take the Stallion.
I'll take the Pony.
I can't wrestle him.
But you are tall and fast like
a gazelle. You can do it.
Pray to the Lord for strength.
I don't believe in God,
I believe in science.
You have not been baptized?
Hey. How you doing?
He's good.
Hello!
I'm talking to you.
I will come.
Save me a piece of that corn.
Save me a piece of that corn
for later.
Hey. Take it easy.
Come on, Esqueleto!
Okay.
No problem.
We are dancing.
That didn't hurt!
And then I disappear!
Taste it. Yes!
I'm going to pull you.
The shoe!
Anaconda squeeze.
Okay.
Nacho! Nacho! Nacho!
Nacho! Nacho!
Semental! Semental!
Those guys were
a couple of wussies, huh?
They scalped my hairs, okay?
- I look hideous.
- Come on, baby.
And you gave them permission
to hurt me like this.
But I couldn't have anybody see
my face, Steven, come on.
Tonight,
I felt something deep inside me,
I've never felt before.
Do you remember that one time
when everyone was shouting
my name
and I used my strength
to rip my blouse?
Yeah.
And I saw them
knock you unconscious, all right?
What's this?
It's money.
What did you think?
But we lost.
We all get a piece.
Listen,
the people, they like you guys.
Come back next week,
and I will get another fight for you.
Chancho.
When you are a man
sometimes you wear stretchy pants
in your room.
It's for fun.
Don't worry.
I won't tell nobody.
I'm a little concerned right now.
About your salvation and stuff.
How come
you have not been baptized?
Because I never got around
to it, okay?
I don't know why you always
have to be judging me
because I only believe
in science.
But tonight,
we are going up
against Satan's Cavemen.
And I just thought
it would be a good idea if you...
Praise the Lord!
Hey, we're not allowed
to watch that.
Hey! Hey!
Tag me!
What? What are you doing?
No, no, no, no! No, no!
Ignacio.
No! No, no, no!
No, no, no!
What the...
Move!
Fight! Fight!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Chancho! Put him down!
- Fight! Fight!
- Put him down, Chancho! Stop it!
- Fight! Fight! Fight! Fight!
- Please, stop it!
Break it up! Break it up!
Break it up!
What's wrong with you?
But, Sister,
they are just ninos trying
to release their wiggles.
Ignacio, they are wrestling
in a sacred place.
Okay, orphans, listen to me.
Listen to Ignacio.
I know it is fun to wrestle.
A nice pile-drive to the face,
or a punch to the face,
but you cannot do it.
Because it is in the Bible
not to wrestle your neighbor.
So you've never wrestled?
Me? No, come on. Don't be crazy.
Listen, I know the wrestlers
get all the fancy ladies,
and the clothes,
and the free creams and lotions,
but my life is good.
Really good.
I get to wake up every morning
at 5:00 a. m. and make some soup.
It's the best.
I love it.
I get to lay in a bed by myself
all of my life.
It's fantastic.
Go.
Go away!
Read some books!
Have you ever had feelings
for a nun?
No way.
There is this nun.
I just wish I could take off this robe
so she could see how strong I am.
Well, bring her
to our next wrestling match.
Yeah, right.
Then I'll get kicked
out of the monastery.
I have an idea.
Tell me.
Take her on a date tonight
and I will bring some of my friends
to beat you up,
but we will let you win.
So where are you taking me?
Well, Sister,
I saw a bum here today.
There were two bums,
and I said to myself,
"Let's talk to these guys
about the Gospel. "
Well, where are they?
I don't see them.
They should be coming by.
Where is your robe, Ignacio?
It was stinky.
But these are
my recreation clothes.
- They look expensive.
- Thank you.
I mean, yes,
they may have
the appearance of riches,
but beneath the clothes,
we find a man.
And beneath a man,
we find his nucleus.
- Nucleus?
- Yes.
Listen, I don't like the way
those guys just looked at you.
Hey! Can't you see
this woman's a nun?
And if you guys
have a problem with that,
well, you can just fight me.
Okay.
You ready?
You messed with
the wrong guy this time.
You ever seen these moves? Huh?
You see these moves? Huh?
You think you gonna... Huh?
- Come on!
- This way. I think he's over here.
Surprise.
Get that corn out of my face!
Release! Release!
I looked like a fool last night!
What took you so long?
It's no use.
I wanna be a great fighter,
but I can't even beat
a couple of guys in the street.
Nacho.
I think I know someone
who can help you.
- The Lord?
- No.
He's a water gypsy.
He know wheres to find eagle eggs.
Eagle eggs?
I'm not listening to you.
You're crazy.
Nacho, I'm telling you.
This is for reals.
His eagle eggs possess
magical powers.
You could become the greatest fighter
who ever lived.
In order for you
to become empowered
by the eagle,
you must climb that cliff,
find the egg,
crack open one of them,
and then swallow the yolk.
So, what you're saying to me
is if I can eat this yolk,
my moves will become
the best in the whole world.
Definitely.
High five.
- Summon your eagle powers.
- What do you think I am doing?
Eagle powers, come to me!
Please!
Tag. Tag! Tag!
Those eggs were a lie, Steven.
A lie!
They gave me no eagle powers!
They gave me no nutrients!
Sorry.
I don't want to get paid to lose.
I want to win!
I need professional help.
I need Ramses.
He's the best.
We need to get in
with him and his buddies.
We must learn their ways.
But they are pros.
They only hang out with each other.
Then we must go pro!
But going pro is not that easy.
It's political, obviously.
My area, amigo.
You see that guy over there?
His name is Senor Ramon.
He's Ramses' manager
and he owns all of the big arenas.
He's having a party tomorrow night.
We need to go and show him
we mean business,
that we are ready for the big leagues.
Over there in the tree
is a chipmunk nest.
Here we have the corn.
The best in the city. It's delicious.
That is where I get the day-old chips,
over in a secret place.
And that is a crazy lady.
So now you got a little taste
of what I do.
It's pretty dang exciting, huh?
Ramses!
- How do you know him?
- He's the best.
No, he's not.
May I have his autograph?
Please?
Okay. Let me see what I can do.
Ramses.
How are you?
Hi.
I was wondering
if the children could get a
signature from you
and maybe a picture.
Listen, the kids are orphans.
They like you. You are the best.
This party's gonna be crazy.
I mean, we're gonna be pros.
Feel it.
Go on. I made them.
Go lay down.
Ignacio,
I've been looking for you.
- Where have you been?
- I've been here.
I've been sleeping.
In a frilly shirt and slacks?
They are my PJs.
Can I come in?
No, people might get
the wrong idea about you.
Like maybe you are a floozy.
Ignacio, I was in the kitchen
and there's no food
for tomorrow's breakfast.
Don't worry,
I'll take care of it.
- But when?
- Good night.
Hey, let go my blouse.
We are wrestlers, too.
We are invited.
- Give me a boost.
- Okay.
Hey. What about me?
I don't think I can lift you.
You are too fat.
Good luck.
Senor Ramon.
- Who are you?
- I am Esqueleto, the luchador.
Everybody is a luchador,
mi amigo.
I think that me and my friend
are ready to go pro.
Ramses, would you like to fight
this man in the ring?
So you want to make a name
for yourself, horseface?
Win the Battle Jam next week.
The winner will fight Ramses
in exhibition
in front of 5,000 people.
Then you will be a pro.
I forgive you.
Come here, soldier.
How did you get up here so fast?
Secret tunnels.
Some say wrestlers make
bad lovers.
That they save themselves
for the ring.
Huh?
I love you.
Sing!
Sing something for Ramses!
Okay, my friend,
this one's yours.
What?
This one yours.
I am singing at the party
I am singing
It's my turn to sing
at the party
Everyone is dancing
Happy party
But Ramses is not dancing
He does not dance at the parties
Ramses is number one
He knows the secrets of desire
Ramses is the one
He puts the people all on fire
Ramses
Steven!
Come here.
That party was lame.
I hate that place.
Hey!
Take it easy.
It sucks to be me right now!
- How come?
- How come you think?
I used to really like Ramses.
I wanted to become him.
But it turns out
he's a real douche.
Well, win the Battle Jam this week
and you can fight him yourself.
Forget it.
What?
Because I can't go on
living a lie.
Earth to Steven.
I'm a friar.
I'm not for that world.
The orphans, they need me,
and I have forsaken them.
I got no groceries for breakfast
because of you!
I'm sick of hearing
about your stupid orphans.
- What did you just say?
- I hate orphans.
- Say it again to my face.
- I hate them!
Come again?
I hate all the orphans
in the whole world.
I'm not listening to you.
You only believe in science.
That's probably why we never win.
We never win because you are fat.
Buenos dias, Sister.
So, what you cooking?
Breakfast.
Ignacio, you have a responsibility
to these children.
I know.
Well, where have you been?
I've been gone because I had
a lot of church-y opportunities lately,
outside of the orphanage.
Like what?
Where were you last night?
To tell you the truth,
I went to a wrestling match.
You went to watch a wrestling match?
Kind of.
You are a man of the cloth.
Lucha libre, it's a sin.
But why?
Because those men
fight for vanity,
for money,
for false pride.
Yes, it's terrible. Terrible.
But is it always a sin to fight?
No.
If you fight
for something noble,
or for someone
who needs your help,
only then will God bless you
in battle.
You must pray for forgiveness.
Excuse me, Ignacio.
Precious Father,
why have you given me
this desire to wrestle
and then made me
such a stinky warrior?
Have I focused too much on my boots
and all my fame and my stretchy pants?
Wait a second.
Maybe you want me to fight
and give everything I win
to the little ones
who have nothing
so they can have better foods
and a better life.
Yeah, maybe that.
Okay, if I win tonight
at the Battle Jam,
I will know that you bless
my mission
and that you want me to be
a wrestling servant of you.
I smell cookies.
Flame! Flame!
No, no, no! No, no, no, no, no!
Roll, you fool!
Flame, flame, flame!
Yes, it's true!
I am Nacho, the luchador.
Who?
Maybe you have seen me on TV.
Nacho!
No. This is forbidden.
I knew it.
He is not a man of God.
Tonight,
I will fight
the seven strongest men in town,
maybe the world,
and I will win
because our Heavenly Father
will be in the ring with me.
And he and I will win
10,000 pesos.
And with it,
I will buy the orphans
a big bus
to go on field trips to parks
and places like that.
I'm serious!
Nipple twist!
You can't win them all.
Nacho!
Where are you going?
There is no place for me
in this world, Chanchito.
I don't belong out there
and I don't belong in here,
so I'm going into the wilderness,
probably to die.
Well, you might need this.
My mother gave it to me
before she died.
It was her lucky machete.
You can have it.
I hope to see you again,
little Chancho.
Maybe in the next life.
How did you find me here?
I saw you from the village.
I have some news.
Silencio isn't going to be able
to fight Ramses.
He got injured.
Silencio bruised his bunions.
They are swollen really hard.
He's not gonna be able
to fight tonight.
You were second place.
You get to fight Ramses.
But I have given up wrestling.
Nacho, you are a great fighter.
And you got something
none of these guys have.
The childrens need a real hero.
But I thought you hated
all the orphans in the whole world.
Not anymore.
I like them.
And they need you, Nacho.
Okay.
Dear Sister, I know
you probably hate my guts by now
and already believe that I must have
died long ago in the wilderness.
But you are wrong,
I'm still alive.
Tonight I'll be fighting
the greatest wrestler who ever lived,
the great Ramses.
I know you don't like wrestling,
but know that I am leaving
all my monies to the orphans.
And if I die in the ring, know that
I always loved you as a brother in God.
Ignacio.
P.S. If we didn't end up taking
our vows of celibacy,
we could maybe get married
and have a family with some ninos.
But, you know, whatever.
Hug, hug, kiss, kiss,
hug, hug, big kiss,
little hug, kiss, kiss,
little kiss.
Ramses is the number one.
His legs are number one.
His eyes are number one.
His muscles are number one.
Ramses is the number one.
While I was in the wilderness
I wrote a song for Encarnacion
in my mind.
- Shall I sing it for you?
- Sure.
When the fantasy has ended
And all the children are gone
Something good inside me
Helps me to carry on
I ate some bugs
I ate some grass
I used my hand
To wipe my tears
To kiss your mouth
I'd break my vow
No, no, no
No, no, no way, Jose
Unless you want to
Then we'd break
our vows together
Encarnacion
They are ready for you now.
Nacho! Nacho! Nacho!
Maybe we should pray.
Dear Lord, please bless Nacho
with nutrients and strength.
- Amen.
Ramses! Ramses! Ramses! Ramses!
Ramses! Ramses!
High five.
Take it easy.
Go, go, go, go, go.
Nacho! Nacho! Nacho! Nacho!
Nacho! Nacho!
Okay. Vertebrae kick!
Timber!
I did it!
Hey! We did it!
Yes!
- Yes!
[
[E
[En
[Enc
[Enco
[Encod
[Encode
[Encode,
[Encode, S
[Encode, Sy
[Encode, Syn
[Encode, Sync
[Encode, Sync o
[Encode, Sync or
[Encode, Sync or S
[Encode, Sync or Su
[Encode, Sync or Sub
[Encode, Sync or Sub b
[Encode, Sync or Sub by
[Encode, Sync or Sub by A
[Encode, Sync or Sub by Ar
[Encode, Sync or Sub by Are
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreL
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLi
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLif
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
w
ww
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www
www.
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.s
www.sh
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sha
www.shar
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.share
www.shared
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedm
www.sharedmo
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmov
www.sharedmovi
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovie
www.sharedmoviel
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovieli
www.sharedmovielin
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovielink
www.sharedmovielink.
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovielink.b
www.sharedmovielink.bl
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovielink.blo
www.sharedmovielink.blog
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovielink.blogs
www.sharedmovielink.blogsp
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovielink.blogspo
www.sharedmovielink.blogspot
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovielink.blogspot.
www.sharedmovielink.blogspot.c
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]
www.sharedmovielink.blogspot.co
www.sharedmovielink.blogspot.com
[Encode, Sync or Sub by AreLift]