Previously on The Fosters:
Don't feel to bad. He
knows everyone's name.
I mean, except mine.
Kelsey told Principal
Sanchez about everything.
You are suspended.
If you keep making decisions
the way you've been making decisions,
you're gonna ruin every good
thing that comes your way.
You've got a family that wants you.
I know where I need to be now.
Jesus kicked me out of my room.
He called it his room.
Um, hi. This is Brandon Foster.
I can't take piano
lessons from you anymore.
My family just can't afford it.
- I love you, Brandon.
- I never realized until today
that for us to be together
you have to give up everything.
Dad?
What was your mom's funeral like?
Everyone just kept telling us
she's in a better place now.
Some article in the newspaper today?
Make me some overzealous
cop with a vendetta.
I thought this was supposed to go away.
Isn't there something that
you need to say to your wife?
Something about a baby?
You wanna have a baby?
So, Callie, you're
going home. How you feel?
Good. Excited.
- Yeah.
- Scared?
No.
A little.
Be sure to tell Jesus I say hi.
Oh, really, Gabi, why don't we talk about
what scares us all about going home.
Anybody?
- Temptations.
- Yeah.
Like Brandon. How's that gonna work?
Yeah, how is that gonna work, Callie?
Have you had any time
to think that through?
I mean, he's gonna be my brother.
Once Jude and I are adopted. So...
You're gonna be sleeping
under the same roof,
he's right next door.
You're not gonna be like laying awake
thinking you could just
sneak into his bedroom?
- Ok, Gabi, enough.
- Come on.
Are you like, really over him?
I know what I want.
I mean, it's great that you're leaving here
knowing what you want,
it really is a good start.
But it's easy to get confused.
You're not going to have group twice a day.
You're not going to be confronted
by any of these lovely young ladies,
trying to get you to
talk about how you feel.
You gotta hold yourself accountable.
Mm, that's right.
Least you got people.
- You're lucky.
- Yeah.
The mistake most girls
make when they go home
is they underestimate just how tough
it's gonna be out there in the real world.
So don't be cocky.
And that goes for you too, Daph. Right?
Why don't we go around now
and everybody can tell Callie
what it is they learned from her.
Ok, well,
Callie, I learned from
you to shut up and listen.
- Gab?
- And to not to interrupt.
- Ok, well, you know, it's still a work in progress.
- Yeah.
I learned we've all got addictions.
And, I could trust you.
Carmen?
I, um, learned to not judge
just on, you know, looks.
She looked like she didn't belong here...
but she did.
I didn't really learn anything from you.
Except I learned how to look
like all blank and superior.
- That's harsh.
- Come on.
No, that's like a really good skill
to have in certain situations.
Mm. Yeah, that was a nice save.
Really, good. Cole.
You're up.
I learned...
that you're my friend.
And I learned about forgiveness.
Callie, why don't you share with
the girls what you learned from them.
Um, yeah.
Well, you all, um...
taught me what courage is.
Every one of you,
you're so brave and awesome.
Even you Becka.
And Rita. Um...
you taught me that compassion
is given for free...
but...
respect has to be earned.
I really respect you.
Thank you, Callie.
I really respect you, too.
- And we're gonna miss you, right?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, you better come back and visit.
Come on, group hug, let's go.
Everybody, Becka, Cole.
The last one for Callie, make it good.
Ohh!
Remember you've got people who love you!
Welcome home! I missed you.
I missed you too, big time.
Welcome back.
I have to, uh, finish my book report.
- It's due tomorrow.
- Sweetheart, can't you finish that after dinner?
Oh, it's ok. We'll catch up later, right?
Jesus wanted to be here,
but he had practice.
It's cool.
So let's go set the table.
Ok, I'll take this for you.
Thank you. Thank you.
I'm really glad you're back.
Thanks, me too.
What's up?
Look, um...
this is just something
I needed to do, for me.
Ok, it's not your fault or anything.
What's not my fault?
I asked my moms...
uh...
our... moms,
uh... not to tell you, because I
didn't want to affect your decision.
Brandon, what?
I just need some time to figure things out.
So I moved in with my Dad.
Thanks you for cleaning up, sweetheart.
Why don't you come sit
down with us, Callie.
Um...
I just want to say I'm really...
really sorry about Brandon moving out.
I feel terrible.
It's ok. It's only temporary.
But he's gonna be around here a lot
so you guys are gonna have to...
Stick to the ground rules, I know.
So listen, things are going to
be a little different around here.
We're going to need to know where
you are at all times, all right?
You have wireless and you
can text but no Internet.
And we're going to need you to leave
the Find My Phone app on so we can...
Track me down if you need to find me.
- We know that this is a little bit...
- No, I get it.
I have to earn back your trust.
Everyone's trust.
- ... and you need a comma right here.
- Ok.
I think you could cut this sentence shorter
and just get to the theme quicker.
- Right.
- Hey.
Hey.
Mariana's been helping me with my paper.
That's great.
- See you in the morning.
- Yes, you will.
He's just...
I know. It's ok.
Where's Jesus?
He's still getting ready.
Don't forget you need to take
him to acupuncture after school.
Yeah, he swears that it's not working.
Well, that is part of the deal.
He's not been meditating either.
Jude, your book report's perfect.
Thanks.
My stomach's in knots,
I've been suspended for a
week but it feels like forever.
Are you afraid that
they're talking about you?
No, I mean... maybe.
- Do you think they were?
- What are people saying about Callie?
It doesn't matter, honey?
I think all they heard was
that you ran away with Wyatt
and, you know, not anything else.
I don't really care
what other people think.
Good for you.
Yeah, me either. Let the
whole school talk about us.
We can be like notorious together.
See, I've been notorious.
Ain't all it's cracked up to be.
Ok, where is, uh...
Jesus, come on, dude!
Where are you? Let's go, shake a leg!
- Hi. Can I help you?
- Stefanie Foster?
Yeah.
You've been served.
What's that?
Uh, it's a summons.
I've been called by the D.A.
to testify in Mike's case.
Why? You were unconscious.
I wasn't unconscious.
Ana's boyfriend shot me
and then dropped the gun.
Mike came into the room firing,
and did not see that
the shooter was unarmed.
I was afraid he might've said something
and then I would contradict him.
I just... I don't...
It was a judgment call and...
It was a terrible judgment call.
Thank you. Thank you.
You were heavily sedated when
they talked to you, right?
You weren't thinking clearly.
I wish that were the case.
Mike did the right thing.
I should have trusted
the system, that's all.
You were just trying to protect Mike.
Well, it doesn't matter, I lied.
And now, they're gonna
question me under oath.
So what happens if you come clean?
I get fired.
Whoa! Uh, jeez.
Hey. Hi.
Sorry. I'm Dani. I'm a,
friend, of your dad's.
Oh, uh, it's cool. I just didn't...
Yeah, I meant to get up and out.
So it wouldn't be awkward.
Too late.
- Yeah, exactly.
- Yeah.
Nice jacket.
Except for your collar is crooked.
Oh.
Men just aren't good
at dressing themselves.
- Hey.
- I overslept!
It's ok. Hey, uh, I see
you met Hurricane Dani.
Shut up! All right, I'm
gonna go get dressed.
I'm gonna be late and
Pilates is my religion.
Gotta keep everything high and tight.
Don't be late for school!
You have a girlfriend?
She's my sober buddy.
Well, do you sleep with
all your sober buddies?
Excuse me?
I'm sorry, I thought that you
weren't supposed to be getting into
any kind of relationships
when you're getting sober?
It's not a relationship.
I'm not drinking. That's
the most important thing. Ok?
Now get moving. You're not
gonna be late on my watch.
Oh, uh, for lessons this week.
Um... I was actually thinking
maybe I could, you know,
take a break from piano.
What do you mean? You love piano.
You worked your ass off to
get this teacher to take you.
Yeah, I know, I'm just a little burned out.
Should I be worried?
No.
Is this about Callie?
No, Dad, I'm ok. I...
Thank you for paying for the lessons but...
it's not forever. Ok?
Ok.
- All right. Yep. See you.
- All right, I'll see you later.
Ignore them.
I have no intentions of
acknowledging her miserable existence,
or her questionnable taste in leggings.
Look, I just, what if she's telling
Chase terrible things about me?
You know that feeling in
the pit of your stomach?
That is what it feels like to be notorious.
Hey, welcome back.
Aw, you noticed I was gone?
So, cast party tonight. We still on?
Oh, uh, I don't know.
I'm mean, Kelsey's gonna be there
and I think I'll just feel weird or...
I couldn't care less about the cast party.
Maybe we could, go see
a movie or something?
Yeah. Sure. That sounds good.
Sweet! I'll see you at lunch?
Hey.
How are you?
I'm, great.
Oh. Good.
What about you? How's your dad's?
Oh, um...
You know, it's...
I gotta...
Yeah.
See ya.
Ok.
Hey, uh, Professor Marshall, this
is Mike Foster, Brandon's dad.
Uh, today, he told me that he wanted
to take a break from his lessons.
And I'm not sure I should let him.
Um, I'd like to discuss that with you,
if you can call me back
that would be great.
Uh, thanks.
- Sorry man.
- What the hell, man?
Faulty boomerang. Maybe
I'm not throwing it right.
Mind throwing it somewhere else?
Want a hit?
No, thanks.
How does that work?
Ditching class when your
mom's the vice principal?
- Don't know.
- You're not gonna narc on me, are ya?
No.
That Callie girl, she's
your foster sister, right?
Did she really run away with
the mop head? You know, Wyatt.
Yeah, I know. She didn't run away with him.
Hey, I don't know why
everyone keeps saying that.
Look, I'm buying the
booze for a party tonight.
You should come check it out.
Sounds like you need
to blow off some steam.
You're buying the booze?
Twenty-three?
I look young for my age. Good genes.
Where'd you get this?
A buddy of mine uses his school ID maker.
And it really works? You
don't get busted or anything?
I use it at liquor stores,
bars, never had a problem.
If you want one, I could hook you up?
I had to say it. It was so cool.
- Is one of you, Jude?
- Uh, he is.
Then these are for you.
- Thank you.
- Enjoy!
What was that?
I don't know.
Well, actually, tomorrow
is kinda my birthday.
How does the cupcake
delivery girl know before me?
I don't think that's her actual job.
My mom gave birth to me at home and
when she went to file the paperwork,
they messed up the date by a couple weeks.
So when Callie and I went
into the foster system,
we never told anyone my real birth date.
We kept it a secret, you know, just for us.
- So can we eat them?
- Hold on.
She must be trying to send me
some type of message or something.
What does it mean?
I have no idea.
Here.
Now, can we eat 'em?
- Hey.
So, how's it going at your dad's?
Ok. Um, he has a girlfriend.
Wait, really?
It's kinda weird.
Well, I mean, he's not working
and he's under investigation,
I guess he kind of deserves a girlfriend.
What's going on with the
D.A. and all that, anyway?
I mean, is everything ok?
Yeah, seems like it.
Um, you know, he says they have nothing,
except for Ana's testimony.
So it should blow over.
You know, if it wasn't for me,
Mom would've never gotten shot
and your dad wouldn't be
going through all this.
I just...
I wish there was something I could do.
Maybe if I talked to her...
No, don't even think about
it. No way. Stay away from her.
Yeah, you're right.
She'd probably just ask me for more money.
Whoa. Hey.
Hey. What are you doing home?
Um, I'm... I needed something from my room.
- Ok.
- What about you?
I, um...
I'm being questioned by
the D.A. this afternoon.
And the lawyer told me to come as a person,
not a cop, no uniform.
This is going away right?
I mean, Dad said they have no case.
Yeah. Yeah, it's just politics, you know?
Nothing to worry about.
- Ok.
Good to see you.
Did you find any more clues at school?
I don't think so. I looked all over.
Here's one.
It says 'anxiety'. That's what I'm
getting looking for these clues.
I don't see any more ducks.
- Look for candy!
- Ok.
Oh, I got one.
Up here!
I don't see any more.
Oh, here's one.
Hmm. "And... all... anxiety... "
they... was... perfect"?
How about...
"Perfect... anxiety... "
they all...
and was.
I don't think that's it.
Hey, Chase.
Um, I just wanted to apologize
for the whole stolen fedora thing.
I don't want you to think
I'm that kind of person.
Kelsey actually took it, but I should
have made her take it back to the store.
But you loved it so much
and now I'm babbling so...
It's fine. No harm done.
I just miss you working on the play.
I missed that smile, too.
You gonna come to the cast party tonight?
Yeah, totally. I wouldn't miss it.
Sweet, see you there.
Do you solemnly state that
the testimony you will give
in this deposition proceeding
is the truth, the whole truth,
- and nothing but the truth?
- I do.
Please state your name, rank and
position in the police department.
My name is Stefanie Foster.
I am a corporal with...
At which point, you were
in the second bedroom
by yourself, is that correct?
Where was your partner at the time?
He was clearing the kitchen.
And it was at this moment you were shot,
fell to the ground, unconscious, correct?
No.
- I'm sorry?
- No, I was not unconscious.
I have here your statement to Internal
Affairs, and you clearly state...
I lied. I was awake. I saw the whole thing.
After firing on me, the shooter
dropped his gun and it misfired.
He did not have his hands up in
surrender when Officer Foster entered
and fired on him, as we were trained to do.
I see. And how do I know
you're not lying now?
Because I'm under oath.
And because by telling you this,
I could very well lose my job.
I was surprised to hear from you.
Thanks for meeting me on such sort notice.
Is this about Jesus and
Mariana? Are they ok?
They are.
I mean, they're pretty upset
about our mom getting shot.
Of course, I'm sure.
Can you just tell them that I'm sorry?
If you're sorry then why are you lying?
Lying? About...
Being at the house when
my dad shot your boyfriend.
- I was.
- With Jesus. At the Women's Shelter.
You wouldn't have gone to meet him,
knowing that our mom could be dying.
Just to get money from him.
You wouldn't do that.
Right? Because I mean...
they would hate you.
I mean, right?
Right. I wouldn't do that.
Because, you care about them.
I do. I love them.
And you want to maybe
someday be a part of their lives.
So you gotta tell the D.A. the truth.
That you weren't there.
Because if you were there...
they would never forgive you.
I want to tell the truth.
It's just...
they really want me to testify
and I don't... I'm scared that
they're gonna cut off my food stamps...
Maybe I can help you.
That's a lot of money.
I just want you to feel safe,
you know, to do what's right.
The last time you went to a
party, Mariana, you got drunk.
And I also got grounded
and learned my lesson.
Besides, it's the cast party, there's
not gonna be any alcohol there.
Ok, what if Callie goes with me?
She didn't drink last time. She can
be like my chaperone or something.
Yeah, um, I don't think I
want that responsibility.
You know, I'm on probation, remember?
Yeah, I agree. It's not Callie's
job to babysit you, honey.
Ok, well, you can like
drive us off and pick us up.
We can even take a
Breathalyzer test if you want.
- Mariana...
- How are you gonna know if you can ever trust us
if you don't give us the
chance to prove ourselves?
I mean, you want Callie to
make friends and get involved.
How is she going to do that
if she's locked up at home?
All right, I will discuss it
with mom when she gets home.
I found 11 clues. Are there more?
I don't know what you're talking about.
At least tell me if there are 13.
Maybe. Have you figured
out what it says yet?
No. What does it say?
- What does what say?
- The puzzle.
- What puzzle?
- You just admitted...
I admit nothing.
Well, if you... if you lose
your job, we'll figure it out.
- It's just...
- I won't have a baby.
I don't want to be the reason
that you don't have a baby.
It's... life is the reason, ok?
Sometimes things are just not meant to be.
Hey. Did you talk about
the cast party? Can I go?
What's wrong? Am I in trouble?
No, love.
Hey.
Hey. What're you grinning about?
Ana recanted.
Said she's wasn't even there
at the time of the shooting.
D.A.'s dropping the investigation.
Oh, my God.
You're kidding me?
Wow. Congratulations, Mike. I'm so happy.
Me too.
There's something you don't see every day.
- Right?
- Hey, bud.
I got your text, what's up?
Ana changed her story. It's all over.
That's great news.
So, how does this affect your deposition?
Well, it's dead, right?
Yeah, it's dead.
I'm gonna open a bottle of champagne.
- Apple juice for me.
- You got it.
Wow, so...
- Roberts called.
- You're kidding.
Yeah, said the D.A.'s
office called her and...
Hello?
Yes.
My dad called you?
No, I understand.
If you could just let me tell him first...
Please.
No, I will. I promise.
Thank you.
And I'm sorry to put you in this position.
Put who in what position?
No one.
You just had a conversation with no one?
That was my piano teacher.
I stopped going a few weeks
ago but I didn't tell my dad.
And I kept the money.
Why would you do that?
I was gonna give it to Callie when
she was getting her own apartment.
Oh, Brandon.
I know. It was dumb.
I'm going to tell my dad
and I'll give the money back.
Ok, good. At least you didn't spend it.
Just let me know how it goes, ok?
I thought it was supposed
to be a small party.
There were only four people in the
cast, that's not much of a party.
Dude, help me get the rest.
Ok, I'm not gonna do anything stupid.
Oh, there's Chase. I'm gonna
go say hi. Be right back.
So you think there's anything
to drink other than beer?
There was a refreshments budget but
clearly I wasn't on that committee.
Hey, um, I'm sorry if I crashed
your... thing with Mariana.
It's the only way our
moms would let her come.
Yeah, yeah, no, I mean,
the more the merrier.
You were so brilliant in the play.
Did you always know you wanted to act?
I always knew I wanted to change lives.
You do. Every night.
Hey, I got you a beer and one for myself.
I would have gotten you one, but I
remember the last time you drank at a party.
- Two words: Projectile vomit.
- Not true.
It's ok, there's nothing to be ashamed
of, some girls are just lightweights.
Um...
you know, I'm gonna go
say hi to my leading lady.
Back off.
Or what? I can't believe I ever
thought that you were friend.
You know, you're just embarrassing
yourself in front of Chase.
He sees you as a sophomore
fan girl and that's it.
Oh yeah?
Then why did you feel so threatened
you had to get me kicked off the play?
Do I need to hose you two down with water?
Hashtag cat fight.
Cat fight? That was incredibly sexist.
Is one of those for me?
Well, one of them was, but
I don't want to be accused
of being sexist for not
letting you get your own.
Hey bro. You made it.
What're you doing here?
- I'm with Mariana.
- What's she doing here?
- This is the cast party.
- This is the cast party?
Nothing gets past you,
man. Here, have a beer.
Um, I should probably go check on her.
You got a thing for her.
So listen. When can I get that fake IDs?
How soon do you need it?
I'm looking to make some quick cash so,
I don't know, I thought maybe I could
buy some beer for parties like you do.
Don't bogart my business, man.
Look, if you want to make some fast bank,
why don't we sell some I.D.s?
Isn't that, like, a felony?
Only if we get caught.
Dude, your mom's the school veep.
You have access to her keys,
we have access to the
ID maker at Anchor Beach.
There's no end to the demand.
We can make a major business out of this.
I only need like a thousand bucks.
Well, if you want to think small...
Hey.
I'm so glad you came!
You need to make a bold move.
Like what?
Well, this one time, I went to
a party and there was this guy
I liked and I wasn't
sure if he was into me.
So, I went in the bathroom and took off my
panties and slid them in his front pocket.
That's a thing?
It worked for me.
Who was the guy? Wait, don't
tell me it was my brother.
I'm gonna get another beer. You want one?
No, thanks.
- Hi.
- Hey.
I was just talking about
you. Your sister's in here.
I know. She's with Callie.
Oh. So that's why you're here.
- I didn't know she was gonna be here.
- What a coincidence.
Callie shows up and you follow her
around like a sad, little puppy.
I think you've had enough to drink.
I should probably just walk
away right now but I told you.
I told you she wasn't into you and
you were just going to get hurt.
You know what? I'm so sick
of you and everyone else
telling me about my business.
Ok, Callie is into me.
We kissed at the wedding and
that's why she ran away with Wyatt.
Because she didn't want
to mess up Jude's adoption.
And the only reason we're
not together right now
is because she needs a
family more than a boyfriend.
So don't talk about things
you don't understand, ok?
If you're interested,
I'll be waiting upstairs.
- Hello, captain, come on in.
- Thanks.
- Thank you for letting me swing by.
- Absolutely.
I didn't want to have this
discussion at the station.
- The D.A. e-mailed me your deposition.
- I see.
Strangest thing, I...
I can't get the damn thing
to open on my computer.
But with Ana recanting and
the charges being dropped,
I can't think of a reason to read it.
Thank you.
One thing, though, Foster, I.A.
took a lot of heat during all this.
They're gonna keep their
eyes on both you and Mike.
So I wouldn't give out so much as a
parking ticket without following procedure.
- You got it.
- I'm serious,
Not a whiff of impropriety,
or heads are going to roll.
- Am I clear?
- Yes, ma'am.
All right, I'll see you on Monday.
Yes you will.
Have a good night.
You too.
Thank you.
What are you doing up here?
Oh, um, nothing.
I was just looking for
someplace quiet to hang.
Oh, cool. Oh, do you mind if I join you?
So I...
I just want you to know, that,
like in case you were wondering...
Well, the thing is, I...
Oh. Sorry, am I interrupting something?
Kind of.
No. Not really. We can
finish this later. Right, Zac?
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
It wasn't important. It's
just, Callie's looking for you.
I believe...
these belong to you?
You're pathetic and disgusting.
I knew it the first time I saw you,
and I let everyone convince me I was wrong.
But I wasn't wrong. I was right.
Hey girls, watch your backs with this one.
She's a two-faced whore,
who will kiss your boyfriend,
then lie to your face about it.
You know, I hope the next
time you go back to juvie,
that they let you rot in there, bitch.
Wait. What are you doing?
Taking my pants off.
Why?
'Cause it's kinda hard
to have sex with them on.
Ok, whoa, sex?
I though we could just make-out a little.
You put your underwear in my pocket.
I was, you know, flirting.
That's not flirting.
That's like... it's on.
Ok, well, it's not.
So what, you're just
like a tease, is that it?
No. I'm...
What, a virgin?
I'm not surprised.
That's funny?
Who put you up to this?
Is this a joke or... ?
So this is not gonna happen?
I thought you liked me.
All right, look. Can you
at least, like, help me out?
Um, no.
Whatever. Thanks for wasting my time.
Hey, you ok?
Did Talya say something?
It's fine.
- Where is she?!
- She left.
Don't!
Don't make a thing out of this, ok?
I understand why she's mad.
It's my fault. I'm so stupid.
- I told her about us.
- Why?
Because I can't stand how everyone
thinks you ran away to be with Wyatt.
And I can't stand you avoiding me.
And...
How this easy for you?
It's not easy.
You're not the only one who
needs some space to get over this.
I'm sorry it hurts you.
Ok, it hurts me, too.
How long do we have to feel this way?
Until we don't.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Did Moms send you to check up on me?
No. I go to parties too, you know.
Oh, ok.
Good, I'm glad you're here.
Can you give us a ride home?
Sure.
Wake up! Get up! Get up! Get up!
It's your birthday!
Here.
More clues? Or is it, like,
a bomb I have to defuse?
Open it.
Mom used to read it to us all the time.
So you left me birthday breadcrumbs?
Something like that, yeah.
And the puzzle?
"Then all anxiety was at an end,
and they lived together
in perfect happiness."
Wait, you forgot one of the words.
I never got, "Happiness."
Yeah, it's downstairs.
Surprise!
Happy birthday!
Aww.
Jesus has an early practice
but he'll be back to celebrate.
You told everyone?
About my secret birthday?
Oh, yeah.
We don't have to keep secrets anymore,
- we have a family.
- Here we go.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday dear Jude... ♪