Oh, it's you. Eh?
No!
Lovely cheese.
I could just wash it...
I was just coming, lad.
Pop away, Gromit
With you in a jiffy!
Hi de ho.
Oh, no.
Excellent.
Fill her up, lad.
Lovely cuppa, Gromit,
but a slightly dieselly aftertaste perhaps.
How's that breakfast coming up?
Well done, lad. Very well done.
Thanks, dog.
Oh. Oh, dear. Another baker.
Battered with his own rolling pin.
Would you credit it?
Still looking on the bright side,
I suppose it means more business for us,
eh Gromit?
We're on a roll, lad.
Good days work, lad.
We're bang on...
...target.
# I'm light as a feather.
I'm the Bake-O-Lite girl. #
Gromit, did you see
who that was?
She's in trouble.
Here, Gromit. Take the wheel.
Don't fret, madam.
Tea cakes, lad.
The whole meal fruit on me knees.
I should have tried
the granary rolls.
Oh, egg.
Oh, dear. Are you all right, miss?
Madam?
Oh, I do apologise.
It's an honor to be of help.
I must get those brake seen to.
We're so grateful,
aren't we, Fluffles?
- Fluffles.
- Oh, it was nothing.
What a lovely little doggie.
My name's Piella. Piella Bakewell.
I know who you are, miss.
# Light as a feather,
you're the Bake-O-Lite girl. #
Oh, that's me.
I'm Wallace. I'm in bread myself.
Oh, really?
- Are you still ballooning, Ms. B--
- I do beg your pardon?
Oh, no, no. I mean
the Bake-O-Lite balloon.
- Do you still fly it?
- Oh, I see. No. Not any more.
Well, back to the grind.
As it were.
Good bye, Ms. Bakewell.
Oh, I'd rather say
au revoir.
Oui, oui, madame,
and bon apetit.
Bye-ee.
The Bake-O-Lite girl.
Oh, fancy that, Gromit.
It's not every day you meet
the girl of your dreams, is it?
Oh well, this isn't gonna put
bread on the table, is it?
Oh, hallo.
We were just passing by
going for a walk...
...and Fluffles insisted on dropping in
hoping you would join us.
Please say yes. She'd be
so disappointed, wouldn't you, Fluffy?
Yes, Fluffy.
Oh, well, if you insist.
But I'm in me work things.
I like a man in uniform.
Come on. Walkies.
Manage without me, won't you, lad?
Oh, cripes.
Mr. Wallace, you are cheeky.
Oh, makes some change,
doesn't it, my fudgecake?
Gromit's gonna love this.
Well I thought you could do
with a woman's touch around the house.
You naughty slovenly boys.
What do you think, Gromit?
You wouldn't know it was
our place, would you, lad?
Fluffles, where are you?
Same time tomorrow,
my apple strudel.
Love is a many splendored thing, Gromit.
But it doesn't half tire you out.
I'm cream crackered.
Oh, my egg. Piella's purse.
I must return it forthwith.
Oh, uh, Gromit?
Funny. I'm sure I heard something.
Oh, there it 'tis.
It must have been there all along.
Early night, Fluffles?
Big day tomorrow.
Our final baker is nicely
potted off.
Good night, Fluffles.
Sweet dreams.
Hello, stranger.
Where have you been?
Hey, wait. Hold your horses.
I've got something
to tell you first, old pal.
Haven't we, dearest?
Of course,
my little cheesecake.
Wallace and I are engaged
to be married.
Til' death do us part.
I think congratulations
might be in order, lad.
Oh, I can see he dying to
give me a great big kiss.
I know we're going to get on
like a house on fire.
One big happy family.
- Hello, my vanilla slice.
- Come in, my sponge cake.
- What's going on?
-  You have to forgive him.
He's been a bit
security conscious of late.
Well you can't be too careful
these days, can you?
- Not with a cereal killer on the loose.
- Oh, yes.
How about a nice spot
of cock-a-leekie soup?
Oh, smashing. I've got just
the bread to go with it.
What the...? That dog!
- Smells delicious.
- I do hope you like it, my shortcrust.
It's my own special recipe.
What the...? Hey!
What do you playing at, lad?
This is getting ridiculous.
Oh, Wallace. He just wants
a bit of attention. That's all.
Now, my little poochy woochy,
let Auntie Piella sort you out.
He bit me!
I was just trying to help and
he bit me, Wallace.
Gromit, how dare you bite
my betrothed? That's very impolite.
Oh, don't be too hard on him, Wallace, please.
Just a little punishment, that's all.
I'm surprised at you, Gromit.
I really am.
Wallace, my sugar dumpling,
have you got a mo'?
On my way, my cupcake.
You'll not leave this kitchen
til you've done every last one.
I don't know. Taking a bite
out of my lovely fiancée.
It really is the limit.
I'm such a silly sausage.
It just sort of fell off my foot.
Stay well back, my precious.
Leave it to me.
Oh, you're so brave, Wallace,
my minced pie.
Got it.
Are you all right, my flower?
Oh, flour.
Get it? Flour?
Get your hands off me.
I hate flour, I hate bread
and I hate bakers,
utter and complete fruitcake.
That's a bit steep,
isn't it, my sweet?
Fluffles, I want a word with you.
Back home.
Oh, thanks, old pal.
I just don't get it.
One minute they love bakers
and the next minute they hate them.
I know I'm not a fruitcake,
am I, lad?
I suppose you can't be
everybody's cup of tea, can you?
I am so sorry, Wallace.
So so sorry.
I don't know what came over me.
Apart from the flour, of course.
Let's forget about it.
Here's a cake to celebrate.
Whoops. Must be my keys.
Celebrate?
Us. Getting back together again,
you gooseberry fool.
Oh, yes. Yes, of course.
We could have that
with our four o'clock tea.
- Won't you join us?
- I would, but Fluffles isn't feeling too well.
Why don't you two celebrate?
Must fly!
Roll on four o'clock, eh.
This'll go down a treat.
Got you, you meddling mutt.
So nice of you to come.
Pity you'll miss
your master's tea party.
It'll go off with a bang.
Oh, I say.
Get the kettle on, Gromit.
I'll deal with you two later.
Come on, lad.
What's keeping you?
At last. My thirteenth.
My baker's dozen.
What?
Curse that balloon. And curse
that prevailing southwesterly.
They will be there in no time.
Oh! Strike a light...
There you are.
I think these matches are a bit...
...damp.
It's one of those joke candles, lad.
Where're you going with that
c-a-a-a-ke?
Gromit, it's a bomb.
The cake's a bomb.
Wait a minute. You don't think
Piella could be--
...the cereal killer? Well done, Wallace.
Sharp as a brick.
Now do exactly as I say
or Fluffles get snuffled.
You've crossed me once too often
you treacherous little --
Get that thing away, lad.
That's it, lad. Use your loaf.
That has put a spanner in the works.
But, Piella, you're the Bake-O-Lite girl.
Was the Bake-O-Lite girl.
I ate too much you see.
- Oh, really?
- I couldn't ride the ballon any more.
- So they droped me.
- What a blow.
Me! A curse on bakers
and their loathsome confections.
Gromit!
Well done, lad.
Lass?
Come to mummy, Fluffy Wuffy.
Atta girl, go for the knockout.
Don't worry about me, lad.
I'm fully in control.
Yes.
No.
Oh, dear.
Anyone seen the bomb?
What? What?
Bomb voyage, Wallace.
Your bum is as good as toasted.
Gromit, I've got a bomb
in me pants.
Help me, Gromit. Do something.
It tickles!
What a relief. Oh, evening, sisters.
I will be back to get you, Wallace.
I will have my baker's dozen.
But, Piella, the balloon won't hold you.
They cant just drop me.
I'm as light as a feather.
- I'm the Bake-O-Lite girl. Noooo!
- No!
Farewell, my angel cake. You'll
always be my Bake-O-Lite girl.
I think I need a cup of tea
after all that.
Care to join me you two?
Oh, never mind, lad. We've both been
through the mill this week, haven't we?
But at least yours wasn't the bread-hating
baker-murdering cereal killer...
...like mine.
Tell you what, lad.
Let's go and deliver some bread. Eh?
That'll cheer us up.
Hey. Always room for a small one.
# And they called it puppy love #
Both paws on the wheel, lad.
Concentrate.