-Each fall, it's the same thing.
We are both scared and eager
to see us again.
The brunette, it's Stephane,
my best friend.
The blonde, it's Charlotte,
my other best friend.
and me, I'm Lola
But everybody calls me Lol.
So here, we are on slow motion
because in american series
...when the most gorgeous girls of the school arrive,
they always are on slow motion.
Well okay we're in France so it's not that cool,
but still, it's stylish.
Oh! Here's my baby...
The handsome guy there, it's Arthur.
I'm not gonna draw a picture, you get it.
-What's up, tuft ?
-Medhi, he's Stephane's ex
when I say ex... it's not that simple
Over there with his chauffeur
it's Paul-Henri.
He's the son of a minister
but he's very nice.
And him, with his hands in his pockets
it's Maël, my best friend.
Well, he's also Arthur's best friend.
They missed me so much
-How you doing ?
-You're so handsome!
The 'over-oxidized' blonde there,
it's De Peyrefitte.
Yeah I know, you think she's gorgeous, well that's normal
She does everything she can to be noticed.
When I say "everything" I know what I mean
What a bitch!
All the others there, they're walk-ons
Here we go again!
FRENCH SONG-Je veux seulement l'oublier
I just wanna forget him
Et puis je fume
And I smoke
So, I'm Mr. Gerbère.
your 'natural sciences' teacher
Now, as you all know we say biology.
I'm also your...
..'head teacher'
(French concept)
So.. Barouin, Luc?
Here!
-Clavel, Stéphane (French name usually for boys) ?
-Here.
-I'm sorry. Stéphanie ((girl name))
No, Stéphane ((usually for boys)). It's used for both.
for both what ?
For both genders
And do you know the french word for that,
Mrs...
..Clavel?
-I don't know.
Mixted
Your first name is mixted
So we say about school nowdays.
But it's another subject.
Or for ham and cheese sandwiches
Guys, I swear
I'm disgusted
Have you seen David Lévy?
He's so tanned, so handsome!
It's Provence. It's Weird
Don't you think it's weird
that she's keeps staring at me ?
dunno, it's weird
I'm so gonna hit on him.
Did you hear me?
I'm disgusted!
what, because of Medhi?
well yeah
We're in the same class.
I was motivated to forget him.
It's really fucked up to be
in the same class again.
She breaks my balls.
You don't care anymore it's over huh?
Yeah, more or less
-Since when you're jewish ?
-It's for David.
-You're crazy!
-"I'm crazy..."
Hey look at this, there's De Peyrefitte
she chose her new prey!
I downloaded you're new song from Myspace,
it's awesome!
well, thanks a lot.
-yeah, it rocks so much
-it's appreciated
-Didn't she put some weight on a lil' bit ?
-Yeah, on the ass
She put so much weight on the ass
You see that ? I'm so happy!
So you didn't do so many bad things this summer ?
Well no! You ?
Well I prefer to tell you, I didn't cheat on you, but I...
well I...
I had sex with some girl
but it was to give it a try, you know
oh right, okay that's cool.
Nothing important.
Well it's a good thing that you're telling me this because...
me too, I slept with some guy...
Oh, well it's cool
All right
To give it a try , too.
Well at least I hope it went well ?
Yeah.
-They don't seem to be fighting over there
-It's gonna be year with fights I'm telling you
I swear, guys... unbelievable
I'm disgusted!
Oh yeah ?
I hope you kept his number.
It would be silly if you became alone, no ?
Look who's talking...
Go ahead, get outta here!
Lola!
What's wrong with her ?
Looks like he pissed her off
-Let's roll.
-Hey man, what's wrong ?
I don't know nothin' about girls no more.
What's so wrong ?
Wait a second.
-What are you doing ?
-I have a little impulse of romantism.
"A   L" .
Mum?
What's your favorite matter?
-cashmere, sweetie.
At school! ((same word in French))
Oh! Well...
Lola?
-Who do you wanna be?
-I'm getting home right now..
Oh no I don't wanna play to figurines, it's boring
You're not at your hip-hop lesson?
I have a bit of a bellyache.
So you, you're the fawn
..and me I'm the walrus and the horse.
What's your name ?
-My name is... Bernard.
Mum no! Not Bernard!
hey can you make me some place please?
Hou!
Lola, but.. how did you shave?
Mum!
-What "mum"?
-Show me, show me!
It's okay... it's my body!
I do whatever I want with it.
Well, no! I mean...
You don't do whatever you want
You're not gonna
..become a porn actress!
not at all! But mum...
Mum, what's a porn actress ?
Forget it.
Well...
Tell me sweetie, you're not gonna do some awful things
with some awful boys, will you ?
You'd tell mum, huh ?
-Come on...
-It's just that I don't like hair, that's all!
But these, nobody saw them, right ?
You know what, I come in the bath
to have a good time
..with my family, but if it's a trial...
-Mum, what is that a trial ?
Huh? what ? And get your stuff all over there please!
Hello?
Shit!
He gotta be shittin' me
Léon!
Shut the fuck up, Léon!
Come on this asshole does it on purpose!
Léon, shut the fuck up!
-You'll see where I put it...
-Mum!
Stop it, Charlotte!
Help!
What's going on?
Dinner's ready!
-Dinner's ready!
-Comin'...
Comin'...!
Yeah, I'm comin'!
-Comin'!
-How many times
..do I have to repeat it?
THE DINNER IS READY!
Stop it, Théo.
You know what, touch your ass now.
Mum, you see how she talks to me ?
Lola avoid that language would you.
And stop that music!
Right now, Voulzy is all I can take.
Are you shitting me ?
Let's go we're dining now!
Now look who's talking about language!
-TEXT MESSAGE: "Hug ?"
My Love...
My little love...
Mum
Have to go, I got class.
Come on, get up! You're gonna be late!
Sleep, sweetheard.
I'll write you an excuse.
Mum, I'm begging you, I'm late!
Well, you should have woken up earlier.
I didn't even had the time to take a shover.
It's my clothes!
Stop taking my stuff!
-It's cold!
-Sure it is!
Tomorow, you take the subway, sweetheart!
No way!
Every day it's the same thing!
The same comedy!
It's cool, you see, I figure
I give her a ride at least we'll
tell each other our life,
the things of the world, of the life,..
..philosphy or...
the beauty of nature...
And in fact not at all...
hello? Earth is calling.
You hear me ?
Peekaboo!
There you go.
I figure you have a good reason to be late ?
Well in fact 'mam you're gonna laugh 'cause...
As you see me there, I'm at my best
Well, you see this morning I had a breakfast accident.
I got a Choco Pops
..stuck in the nose.
My mother had to take me to the emergency to...
-And you, I figure it was a Frosties or something ?
-What a face she had!
-Unbeleivable
Well, ciao!
bye
By the way with Arthur did it get better?
So-so
I just wanna tell you that if I was him,
I would never have left you.
Yeah, but you're not him
Yeah, I know...
You know, it's not because
he's my best friend that
I agree on everything he does.
I know...
And...
You, I adore you. Really.
I don't want this to destroy our friendship, Lola.
I adore you too, Maël.
Really.
All right then.
We will go on with some factorization
..by resolving the following equation :..
..(x   1)   (x   3) = 0.
There you go.
You want me to help you to finish it, Charlotte ?
Yes
It' not very complicated, you'll see.
Make love to me, like we do at 16
Make love to me...
..without experience
Make love to me shyly
Like a beautiful evening of adolescence
minus 2!
Voilà!
Does everybody understand?
Make love to me, like we do at 16
May I ?
Huh? yeah, sure. Come on in, it's all right.
We continue with another exercise...
What's wrong with the girl, they're turned on or something ?
It's good for you, no ?
-I'm sorry ?
-It's good for you, no ?
...(x-2)   (x  3)...
"Absolutely fabulous!"
Nespresso
Silence, be quiet!
Please!
I wanna be able to ear a fly...
Well.
The first one who opens his mouth...
I send him straight "directly" to the principal.
I've seen Maël.
Oh yeah ?
I'm warning you
this year...
..I refuse to be the victim of one of your childish jokes.
What's happening ?
You hear me ?
bye
Bye
hu, sir...
-Yes Charlotte?
-My mother is wondering if you give
..private lessons at home?
Lessons of?
Of mathematics, sir.
For your mother?
Well no, for me.
Oh Yes! Oh NO...
I don't do..
..this kinda things.
at home, I mean.
-oh... No big deal.
It's unfortunate. Bye sir.
bye.
So good-looking!
He was so ambarassed, poor guy!
I'm sure he likes ya.
-Who ?
-the maths teacher!
oo yeah, sure!
No doubt about it.
and you Lola
what do you thing about it ? LOLA!
Does the math teach likes her?
Don't know
Damn it, Arthur's there!
-I don't give a shit about it!
-Really ?
Yeah, totally
-There she is, De Peyrefitte this bitch.
-She's a real sticky note this one.
Damn you're right!
I love your t-shirt, where d'you get it?
And where d'ya get what you got under that shirt of yours ?
What a sense of humor. You went shopping.
Well I gotta say you needed it...
-She's funny this one, huh ?
It's rare to find a girl with so much spirit.
-That's right
-I look up to you
Can I talk to you for a sec ?
yeah, go ahead.
Cool.
-yeah you're right I'll have your spot.
-Anyone got smokes ?
What do you want ?
I want you to tell me
To tell you what ?
Well your sexual miracles,
your stories...
Leave me alone...
Medhi, you got a light?
Why? The one you got on your ass isn't enough ?
You're a jerk!
Yeah and so classy by the way!
Come on drop it now!
I hope you came at least, 'cause it'd be stupid otherwise.
You're disgusting, go fuck yourself!
The specialist is talking now, that's great
You know what you're talking about, huh ?
-What's your problem ?
-classy!
Shitty ambiance
Arthur is so much of an asshole
How did I manage to put up with him all year long ?
In fact now, I don't even give a fuck about him.
I think he's jalous
Of Maël, nonetheless.
Thank God he's there him.
I adore him so much
Can I come to your house tonight?
Well no, not yet
Why is that?
Well not every night. Otherwise I don't see the point
of being divorced
Damn!
Crazy thing!
My father is screwing my mother again
or vice versa.
It's crazy!
You have to repeat again, sweetie
"France is exposed to..."
"the 3 frontages" .
"to the 3 mari..."
"Mari..."
" ...nated frontages"!
So silly! "marinated"!
Don't mock your sister, téo
It's not cool
"3 maritine frontages... which are"
The North Sea, the Medeteranean sea..
..and the Pacif... Atlantic ocean!
What's wrong ?
Why are you looking at me like that ?
Just looking at you, that's all.
TEXT MESSAGE: "Where R U ?"
Here I am!
How you doin' ?
Fine.
Lola do you mind if we meet in front of the school?
I don't want Arthur to see us arriving together.
-Yeah you're right, it's not...
-See ya.
We started at the "Planches" club,
and we finish the night the "Mix" club.
-Seriously?
-I'm exhausted!
I understand.
Well I'm exhausted, too!
Damn, look at her lingerie
She gots it all, this bitch!
Yeah, you're right
But I'd like to her ass, you see!
You'd have to stop eating a kilo of Nutella every night.
-no way!
-Come on...!
-"No way"!
-You're a douchebag!
Check this out Stéphane, hey Charlotte
is it "Petit Bateau"..
..or "Titanic", your underwear?
Stop it, it's my mother! She only buys that.
-Right!
Stop it
I'm thinking my mother she robbed the whole H&M store,
many thongs don't fit her
I can give you some if you want
Yeah, that'd be cool
And you Provence, you're instrested?
Na I don't like thongs, honestly I think it's vulgar.
Got it!
Damn it, chief...
Move your ass, Goddamn it!
Normaly you know all about it...
There, you see it that one ?
Clavel, you need help ?
Paul-Henri, don't fall in love with the ball
Watch it, Arthur!
What's wrong with you ?
He's crazy this guy!
-It's Lola, man, she's a girl!
-she's "a" girl or "your" girl ?
It ain't a box ring here, all right!
It ain't "your" problem anymore!
Yeah, Maël the BIG justice lover!
He's insane!
So pathetic!
YOU are pathetic
Shut up you!
I love him, I love him...
I love him...
I love him, I love him, I love him...
"Think about you"
"THINK ABOUT YOU TOO"
"If Arthur wasn't my friend..."
Yeah ????
LOL :) Good night.
Good night.
"Thinking about you"
"I'm thinking about you too"
"If Arthur wasn't my friend..."
"Yes ????"
"lol. Good night"
"Good night too"
Listen Lola, I'm at the police headquaters
they just confiscated my car registration document, so please..
..Because it's like that
I'm not Dolto, I don't have to justify
everything to everyone all the time.
Now that's enough!
Oh shit! Come on now...
Shit! Shit!
Fuckin'...
May I help you?
-Are you a cobbler?
-Nop.
That's too bad.
Yep' that's too bad.
Where you going like this ?
Well I don't know I'm gonna take a cab.
'cause the fucking cops impounded my car!
The station, it's.. it's quite far,
you're not gonna cross it like that...
Yeah you're right but...
I'll give you a ride.
That would be great, It's nice of you
Take this.
And you ?
I don't need it.
Be carefull, 'cause they're real..
..real assholes!
Yeah, I know, I know.
See you later.
Oups!
I'm sorry.
Voilà
Thanks a lot
You're welcome. Wait a sec... it often gets stuck
There you go, carefull
And I'm sorry I insulted your collegues.
Oh you know I'm used to it.
Was he goodlooking ?
Yeah, but whatever, I'm not gonna screw a cop
that'd be all I need.
For one night!
Short and sweet...
Na, not my type...
Who, the guy ?
No, the one night stand...
Well, I'm telling you...
If I was divorced,
I'd screw everything that moves...
What'd you do if you were divorced?
Nothing, nothing..
Yes, yes, yes!
I'd get laid by one guy,
every night just like "you" do!
-Who's that, "you"?
-"you"..
-..men.
-Oh us!
The big assholes congregation!
But you can't do what we do, sweetheart!
And why is that ?
-Everything's fine kiddos ?
-It's all right.
By the way ma, I don't know if you knew, but
Julien has a moto.
-So ?
-So I was thinking it could
..help me not being late
-No, no, never!
-Seriously, you got a moto ?
-Dad says it's not dangerous.
I'll take you to Garches Hospital to show you people
in their wheelchair.
Lola, if I ever see you on a moto...
And what are you doing exactly ?
I'm getting some food up in the room
'cause I'm gonna show Julien
some things on the computer.
That's not cool
I laid the table
-OK!
-We'll get down for the desert.
You too should go to Garshes Hospital, she's right you know
Oh! Come on that's not cool...
We just go upstair to watch some stuff
Dad we can, right ?
Yeah
-It's okay, we'll be in peace
-Plus, old people's conversations... you get it
-Well educated, my daughter!
-Well.
-She's very nice, it's the kinda things I appreciate
-It's lovely
-This tall kid huging you...
-The tall kid has ears you know?
-Dady he can't resist
-Mummy, come on, it's all right
You're tiresome
You say yes to everything!
The moto?
-Yes, for the moto, for going upstairs
-All right, let's eat, dinner's ready!
So what do you think ?
Not bat, what is it?
-It's a friend.
-Do you mind if I roll a joint ?
Sure! But I'm gonna close the door...
She smokes Lola ?
Are you nuts ?
Wait... No I don't want it...
That's what you think!
Did she ever see you smoking ?
I try to avoid it...
Julien,..
..he's at war, he hates drugs.
I don't worry about it.
I'm gonna do my surfing training course with the UCPA.
That's nice.
And you, what do plan on doing?
I don't know 'cause dad is screwing mum again.
No!
Yep! Maybe it'll change everything.
And you're happy about it ?
I don't believe in their story anymore.
Not very optimistic!
Tell me sth, Julien...
I wanted to ask you a favor...
hmm ?
Can we have sex ?
No, no
You women, you don't get laid
just like that
You need feelings...
-fee.. what ?
You don't go to prostitutes
Why, do you ?
No but in general, you can't say that
..sexuality is the same for men and women
And what's so different ?
I mean, explain it to me!
I'm guessing I'll be interested
-Yeah me too
-You, I don't talk to you anymore anyway.
Ah come on it's not like I asked you euthanasia
Even if I wanted to, and that's not the case, I couldn't do it
Why ?
I have too much respect for you
Fuck you guys with your respect
Girls!
When we don't respect you, we're assholes
and when we do,
..it fuckin bothers you!
-We've known each other for 8 years
-That's the point Lola
Do I walk around and ask
"hey do you wanna have sex with me" ?
What would you say ?
I'd say 'yes'
-Well I    say   no
-Gotcha
Do it with your boyfriend
-With my boyfriend ?
-It seems more logic!
No I told him I already did it.
He can't know that I lied.
Man! Women really are insane!
Na, we ain't insane!
Look at Lucie, she's living the life
-Damn right she does!
-Yeah!
Since she got seperated,
she met tons of men.
and not even on Meetic.
She fucks whoever she wants
She doesn't get bored with the same
guy with a stincky mouth
Welcome in the 21e century, sweetheart!
-Well Lucie she's a whore, sorry to tell you!
-Come on!
Having lovers doesn't make a woman a whore.
Whatever, I'm the only man here so...
-Poor you!
-And Alain, do you see him sometimes ?
Na, just for the kids.
Just that.
Oh! We saw him with a bitch.
-huh, what ?
-Alain, we saw him with a bitch.
-A blonde.
-We don't know if he was with her...
"we don't know"!
He had his tongue in her mouth
..and his hand on her ass!
What more do you want, Colombo?
What?
Did I do something wrong ?
-Is it a problem for you ?
-No no why ?
It's just that... I don't know...
Do you want some pie ?
Sssssh, take off your shoes
They're sleeping
The stairs are making noise
Like a robber in my own house.
Former home
You don't see other women, do you ?
Who ?
You heard me.
You mean, if I sleep with women
other than you ?
You got it!
Are you nuts or something ?
So you see no other women except me ?
But...
I don't know. To me we're..
..we're together
I don't understand, it's crazy!
Crazy!
Crazy, huh ?
Wait a sec! Shhh!
Yeah mum. I'm at Arthur's right now
I'm finishing a math lesson
Kiss
Gotta go
Man forget it
I have no choice.
Plus Medhi isn't here
That's the point! Medhi doesn't come
And you gotta go after 5 min... Come on
-Don't worry we'll kill it
-We ain't gonna kill nothin man, it's a competition
with guys from Dunkerque or Rennes or something
Music is the only thing they got in life
Me too man, you think I wanna end up
like my father ?
I call you if I can come back.
I'm sorry!
Drives me fuckin crazy...
-There!
-What's your band ?
No Shampoo.
What's that ?
Pop folk music
And what's that...
..folk music ?
What is it ?
It's not for you
-Since when do you hand flyers ?
-Since it's better when a gorgeous girl does it
Oh yeah, you're a pro at that kinda thing
Don't be jalous!
Don't worry about it
Oh no!
'No Shampoo' live!
No Shampoo!
Nobody gets out without a flyer
Principal's order
there!
It's for the festival Emergenza, in the 11th district
Where's that ?
Give it to your friend, or your grand ma'
-You killed it, guys
-We're preselected!
It's crazy!
I was so excited when all the hands were up
You were so handsome tonight
You're the most beautiful
Maël!
Shall we go ?
-It's all right
-we're going
-Hi
-Ah!
Good evening. Please forgive me. I'm sorry.
Can we know where you were ?
I was with Arthur, I was finishing revising a math test.
It took longer than I thought.
-Did it go well ?
-Very well.
And you believe him ?
-You want some soup ?
-Yes, thank you.
Dad, I talked to you about a music festival called Emergenza.
And if you're selected you can record an album with real producers.
Thank you very much.
I'd like to do it.
Can you give me the salt, please?
Did you hear what I just said ?
You didn't hear what I just asked ?
Give him the salt
There!
Thank you.
You're welcome
-Come on that's it I know you love me
but stop following me!
-In your dreams yeah
Get the fuck out you filthy bitch
-Why do you fuckin treat me like that ?
-So exciting when you're pissed off
Stop it I'm so scared
-I'm done with your shit, damn it!
-Lola, stop it
Stop it! Stop it! Goddman you Arthur!
What you doin' like that ?
-Come on!
-How could I have dated this asshole ?
-Stop it, damn it!
-Stop acting the justice lover man!
What you're talkin' about ?
The Beatles split up because of a woman!
The Beatles ? Bullshit!
Arthur stop it!
I wanna kill him
I've had enough of him!
Where do you think you are ?
I swear to God, it ain't my fault!
He doesn't stop insulting me!
No but...
Don't call my mum please
Call your friend to tell them
your birthay party is cancelled
Please ma' you can't do that to me
Oh yes I can
The bad marks, all right, I can understand
But behavior problems, no!
But Arthur is calling me a whore!
So what ? I let him insult me ?
I say nothing ?
What ? Your Arthur ?
Yes.
And he's not my Arthur anymore.
Why did he insult you ?
I won't give you details it's my life.
-All right, all right, we cancel
-Ok but there..
..it's blackmailing
-Yes
-You have no rights
-I know
-You're rude!
We'll go to the theater instead
Great
All right, you win
Arthur slept with a girl last summer.
I acted like I didn't give a shit
So I told him I did the same.
You did ?
Of course not! That's the only thing you wanna know
No, not only that!
But I wouldn't want you
to do some stupid shit
just out of pique
Out of what ?
Uneducated generation
I'm kiddin
So, is it yes or no ?
For my birthday party
Hmmm...
Please...
Thank you so much mum
Will you lend me your collar ?
Don't you wanna tell me your name ?
No. Anonym. More Exciting...
Am I "in it" now ?
yeahhh
A chicken doesn't disappear just like that!
Léon!
-Did you take the chicken, Léon ?
-Damn it!
Léon!
Léon, will you answer me ?
Léon, where is the chicken ?
Do you hear me or what ?
What ?
Did you take the chicken ?
-I didn't do anything I swear!
-Nothing huh ?
Stop it, it's not me!
Why do you always accuse me ?
And that, ain't it a chicken ?
I hate lies!
I swear to God!
I hate it!
I swear, it's not me
Fuck! I'm tired of this
Who are you leaving with ?
-With a friend
-Do I know her ?
No, you'll call the children
You got grand ma's number ?
-Yeah yeah
-Mum, you let her go shopping
And order some pizzas
Understood ? I know you
Be carefull, she'll do whatever shes wants
They're heartless, mum.
-Not at all!
-Come on, hurry up!
-Let's go mum!
-You're kicking me out!
-Yes
-Not at all!
-All right... bye
-bye!
-Admit it grand ma', you knew for mum and dad!
-Look at them!
-They look like teenagers
-Yeah
Unfortunatly teenagers aren't like that anymore.
Now let's have some vodka!
You want a funnel ?
a what ?
Forget it
There's too much of it!
Don't worry,
my mother takes 3 every day.
Yeah but still..
I'm not sure about this
She'll have the best time of her life, and us too!
Excuse me, mam.
-Yes
-You want a drink ?
-hmmm. Yes a coke please.
-With a lil bit of whisky.
-Damn!
What are you drinking ?
Just water
Very good
She'll be high as a kite, grand ma'
Don't say that
It's all right
-Isn't it dangerous with the meds ?
-no..
You sure ?
Of course I am! There!
No, you do it!
You're not funny.
There you go, mam.
Thank you
It is cold enough ?
It's perfect, thank you!
Charlotte!
-How you doin ?
-Fine, you ?
I'm all right.
This t-shirt, is it yours ?
It's my grand ma's but she lend it to me.
Don't fuck with me. Are there many of them out there ?
I can't really ask her she's dead.
Damn!
Don't worry, she didn't suffer
Plus, it's a joke.
Thank you
You sure you all right ?
yeah yeah
man, there you go, smoke this
Be carefull it's strong
You sure she won't wake up ?
Don't worry, not with the dose I gave her.
You have condoms ?
Well no
Oh come on... I didn't expect we'd date again.
Fuckin genius!
Fuck it
You see ?
There you have it your threesome
Fuck you're right
Fuck I'm so drunk
Yeah me too I drunk too much
I really wanna kiss you
-Yeah me too
-Lola, come here!
Let's dance
I'm sorry
I must have drunk too much
I don't know what's happening
Don't worry. We have all the time we want
Come on looks like we're in TV movie or something
Damn right
The Young and the Restless
I don't know, we've know each other for too long
We're too close
-Damn right, especialy these times
-Yeah, especialy these times
A good and a bad news
The good one: mum dumped my dad again
He lied to her about who he was seeing
The bad one is that because of that
she got home ealier.
And honnestly we aren't done
with the cleaning yet.
Lola!
Lola!!
How you doin mum ?
Do we start with the joints or the condoms ?
-It's not my fault
-Mum, that's not funny
-I'll explain it to you
-Yeah
Explain it to me
Stéphane and Medhi they did it again
They used the whole box of condoms ?
I can take out the trash...
Oh you
thank you
-I'm listenning
-Well I don't know really I wasn't with them
-I was there..
-Are you shitting me, Lola ?
Hell no, I promise!
-You shittin' me Lola?
-No....
Yes you are
Don't get pissed off for a few joints.
when you smoke some every night in your room
I'm sorry ? But I,
I'm 40, young lady!
I have my high school degree, my degree in architecture!
When you'll have all that then you'll talk!
If I see you again with that, you move the fuck out!
You go live with your father!
Well that's what you're waiting huh ?
That I move the fuck out, that I go live with dad ?
So you can live the life, like a teenager
Because you're jaelous of me!
Jalous of me!
Fuck!
You're so fucking bored with your life
..that you can't even find another man than dad.
You can't even...
..do that, in 40 years!
So you too, you get high with joints ?
Huh ?
Why is it that you all have
to fuck around with me today ?
That's it!
It's over, no more favors like that.
-What do you want ?
-What do I want ?
I want us to stop fighting for nothing
Nothing ? You have sex with prostitutes!
I'm tired of all this
I won't make more effort, Alain.
You're both the best and the worst thing
that happened to me.
-Anne I promise you
-Stop promising...
And stop lying, all of you!
Shit!
"Hug ?"
"CONFERENCE ON DRUGS. STUDENTS NEEDED"
Be quiet, please.
There are some empty chairs on the first rows
Come on! Hurry up!
So, I introduce you to Mr. François
... with the police, specialized in narcotics. Shh!
We won't start the conference
..until we get a complete silence. Thank you.
You're also conerned, Mr Collet.
Is it true that you banged Lola at her party ?
Bullshit man, you're so full of shit!
I knew my best friend coudn't do that to me.
I'm sure now.
So, let's get started.
*-The health minister informs you that...
"DRUG. A DANGER TO THE YOUNG PEOPLE"
Yeah, I know I know
So! here's the brain of a 15 year old boy
..who doesn't do drugs.
The blue area still has to grow until adult age.
Here, it's in contact with some THC
No way it'll happen to you, you ain't got a brain
You shut the fuck up!
still more dangerous
Damaged areas will stay damaged for life
which you give that in picture
You see that ?
What ?
"What ?" that! the soccer match just right there!
I don't smoke!
No
Sometimes, more rarely
..apparition of a mental disease called schyzophrenia.
Shit! you see that, drugs...
You can talk, with your meds
-You have a light ?
-We can't smoke here
-What ?
-We're in school
Goddamn it! Fuck!
I want a cigarette
Why you running ?
I don't wanna bump into someone
-Who ?
-Anne!
Hi
-I didn't see you. How you doin ?
-You ?
-It was interesting
-It was good no ?
Yes
I don't know if it'll change anything
It's a good thing to talk about it.
Hello.
Ah hello!
Hello
It was great
Thanks
Your heel, is it better ?
Oh the heel ? Yes it's fine
Well, I leave you two
See you later.
Ciao
Two times randomly, that's a lot!
They know each other ?
I don't know
How about we have a drink ?
uhh...
It's not a question.
We'll have a drink.
All right. But...
This cop will cuff your mother to the bed
Yeah, whatever
I'll cuff you..
Check this out
THe sticky note is sticking to Maël
What a bitch!
She doesn't leave him alone
Let's go to a café
Ask your mother
OK
-So it's like that huh ?
-Mum ?
I'm gonna hang out with friends...
Lola, I introduce you to...
Lucas.
Lola, my daughter. No way, you go home.
But everybody's going
No it's like that and
it's like that
Grand ma can't stay
So you go babysit the kids
and do your homework.
Okay. Fuck...
I'm sorry ?
No, nothing. See you later then.
So is it okay ?
-I thought it wasn't a question!
-Oh yeah, right!
"Oh yeah right"!
Maël?
So was it good ?
Well listen yes it was very good
You're disgusting!
Was it good ?
What are you talking about ?
Oh come one!
At least take responsability when you do that....
What's wrong ?
What did you say to her ?
Nothing, we're chating.
Your girlfriend doesn't have any sense of humor.
You ain't got nothing better to do ?
Lola!
What happened in those toilets stays in these toilets, got it ?
I get out. You wait 5 minutes
before getting out, is it clear ?
Yeah, well... I guess it's clear.
Lola!
Leave me alone
What is this ?
Everybody knows that this slut sucks in the toillets.
What ?
At least there's one girl who knows that
you can't get it hard.
Impressive!
I think that settles it.
I think so yeah!
Fuck!
Lola?
Lola!
Lola...
Sweetheart?
Are you okay?
I'm fine
Come and eat.
One has to eat when one's sad.
I'm not hungry.
You're not gonna get anorexic, are you ?
You don't get anorexic just like that
I've seen it on a TV show, it comes quickly.
Don't worry
It's not that
You'll see.
It's not such a big deal.
And I bend over you
A drop of dew on your lips
A beam on your fingers
I can read in your dreams
And you think like I do
An exile, an exile
Far, far away from here
Oh my muse
In the toillets with De Peyrefitte
But when ?
At the anti-drugs conference
Charlotte?
-And you're sure it was them ?
-Yes
There he is!
I so wanna kill Maël
or De Peyrefitte.
I so wanna get out
this shitty highschool!
And as a bad news never comes alone
"French : A real tourist would have at least
taken picture."
I took some
You wanna see them ?
And this one, you see it ?
You didn't get the congratulations
Yeah but I had encouragements
That's my point, it's not as good as before
yes mum
Can you explain me this 112 in French ?
Woooo... Really, they're so messed up these teachers
Yeah, sure
5 in maths, 6 in French
6 in history and geography
2 in physics!
Are you kidding me ?
No mum I don't. I just can't get interested
in the global population of China
.. and in the activity of cells
The only thing I'm thinking about,
the only thing that hurts
..is Maël
and this bitch called De Peyrefitte.
How am I gonna hurt them
as bad as they hurt me, mum?
How am I gonna do that?
Second trimester
So who's the asshole we wanna get jaelous ?
the guy with his retard
the blondie just dehind
He sure looks like a retard
And her ?!
They're looking at us!
Who's that guy over there ?
It's Julien.
Is it a problem for you ?
No, absoluty not
You comin' ? We're gonna buy some cigars
Motos, it's so out of fashion
Not only the moto is out of fashion
I can't believe it
She blocked me.
Fuck...
Come see your girlfriend instead of playin' poker.
I just wanna know if you come to sleep over at my home tonight
All right. I leave you the keys under the doormat.
"Your house 19pm ?"
Mehdi pisses me off, I swear to God.
We should have seen each other yesterday.
I'm still waiting!
He's an assholes, forget it.
Potatoes ou fries ?
Yeah, act like you don't see me!
Potatoes.
Two potatoes
If he comes to talk to me, I blow him off.
What, mum ?
No I don't know where your grey cashmere is!
No I'm not wearing it!
No!
My mother she drives me nuts
Will it be all ?
A toffee sundae, please.
Isn't Paul-Henri so ugly?
Damn right!
Oh yeah he is!
With his fry!
Isn't he disgusting ?
Revolting!
You're overstatin it
Could you date him ?
Oh no, no way!
Stop looking at them they'll think we're interested in them
We're interested in them.
A lil bit you gotta admit.
Don't you think they obsessed with us ?
Last time I played poker I had a three ases!
And this guy he had a fifth!
I got fucked up!
Calm down with the poker
I only got a pair of converse to bet
Why don't you bet your hair ?
It's bad to play poker
And it's bad to eat like a pig
You're disgusting
Maël, show what you got
What ?
The founder of "ni pates ni sushis" (neither pastas nor sushis)
Oh damn!
Not her...
Lola, check this out!
All we needed right now!
Hi boys, how you doin'
Fine, you ?
He's comin'
Who ?
My ass!
How you doin ?
Can we hang out tonight ?
-Sure
-At yours ?
Well yeah
See you then
Later
No comment.
The sticky note won't let him go!
What a bitch!
And my mother again
What mum ?
Lola, have you seen your cupboard ?
What a shithole!
If I don't find my clothes, no more messenger!
Shit!
-"One night, we were so fucking bored so
Charlotte called some friend from an old trip
"I thought only a whore
would call boys at night,..
"..but Charlotte said that they were the whores,..
"..and that life was too short to be fuckin bored
a saturday night."
Leave me alone
Why are you doing this ?
"Don't tell me that men
and women have the same sexuality."
"A woman with lovers
isn't necesarely a whore."
What a fool I am.
What a goddamn fool I am!
Unbelievable
Shit!
Yeah, hello ?
Yeah, I'm fine
I was just leaving. Okay!
In two minutes. All right, see you then.
-Djamel and Vincent, is that right ?
-And maybe Gilles
Go straight to the Orfèvres
and give that to Manusco
He's been waiting for this all morning.
Ciao
Sorry I'm late
Doesn't matter. How you doin' ?
Fine
Well ?
What is it ?
Nothing
-What would you like ?
-2 minutes, please.
He'll think it's me who makes you cry
What's the matter ?
No no, nothing.
It's only human to have looked in this diary!
-You're not gonna feel guilty ?
-Yes, I feel guilty with kids.
When I let them do what they want
I feel guilty
When I yell, it's worse
I got the feeling of being a cop.
It sucks, doesn't it ?
yeah...
No but I don't how to say...
you see ?
We've been fighting all our life
..to have the same rights as you do,..
..and have the same sexuality.
-You, you said that ?
-You defended that ?
Absolutly
I defended that!
Whatever..
When you see your little girl like who
..goes live her life as a freed women,
you don't agree anymore.
I swear
I don't even what to think
You don't have to think anything.
She sleeps with some boys, she does drugs...
She tried to have sex with a boy
and she smokes a little bit.
No big deal.
Look who's talking
I know how to make the difference between
a teenager who's got issues..
..and on who checks where the limits are.
As long as it keeps hapening with people
the same age...
You're telling me this to cheer me up ?
I think that you think too much.
TEXT MESSAGE: "I'm leaving now, be there soon, Maël"
Come on, let's revise some poetry.
Dad, check out my cartwheel
Beautiful, sweetheart
You wanna go out, have diner, both of us
Like old times?
wherever you want, Mcdonald's?
Oh yes!
No no no forget it no
Tomorow you got school
and your mother will drive me nuts
-Go back to your homework
-please!
-Go. No.
-Saturday, I'll take you on saturday.
Tonight I can't
Oh !
Can you sign this ?
I need both your signatures
What's that ?
A parental approval for a trip to England.
Thanks
-Where you going ?
-At Arthur's
-Are you shitting me ?
-I really don't have time
That rings a bell ?
You think I don't know what that is ?
Listen to me! All we needed is a drug addict in our home
Next year, it's boarding school!
Waiting for that moment, no more music,
no more guitar
What are you doing ?
What the hell ?
Stop it, goddamn it!
I could have broken it on your head!
Freak!
And that, it's confiscated
You happy ? congrats!
Fuck!
Thanks for listening to me
It's part of my job mam!
No, it's very nice of you!
It's not nice
It's interested
-Oh yeah ?
-Yeah
What are you doing here ?
Alain. Lucas.
the father of my kids
Lola forgot some books
Ok then...
I leave you two...
Yeah
-You okay ?
-Yeah, yeah I'm fine.
I'll let you feel guilty alone.
yeah
I'm sorry
Maël's voicemail.
You can leave a message.
Hey it's me Lola, you remember ?
THe girl you had a date with ?
I've been standing here for an hour
Don't try to fool me.
Good evening sir.
Good evening Etienne. Thank you.
It's my son!
We can follow them if you want.
Yeah if it's okay with you.
I don't mind.
Do I go pick him up ?
No, I don't wanna cause a scene.
But it's unreal! 2 am. in the middle of the week.
What are the parents doing ?
Like you, sir.
And what is that ?
Thinking their children are sleeping.
You think my daughter is a lesbian ?
Hum.
"Hum" yes or "hum" no?
Can you stop with your 'hum' and give
some real awnsers ?
Is it more chocking if she sleeps with
a girl instead of a boy ?
You know what, I prefer you 'hum'
-You see ?
-Hum
Hey, how you doing ?
You wanted...
..to talk to me?
We have to talk about Lola.
Hum
You're not gonna do that too?
Do what ?
My shrink always does some 'hum'
it drives me nuts
Yeah, and you told her that you're
screwing another guy ?
First, I'm not screwing anybody
Oh yeah that's right
I'm sorry
Us, men, we fuck bitches but you women
you make love with some extraordinary men.
Stop it!
It's not the time.
For you.
Because everything's fine with me
I'm chating with 'Madam I give lessons'
who causes a scene because she thinks
I'm "banging a bitch"
You sure you wanna take this path ?
Yeah, because you own me some explanation
I own you explanation
I remind you that we're divorced
Yeah when you feel like it
Well!
Lola does drugs
What ?
Joints, not yet some...
If you didn't leave your shit all over the house...
I remind you that you are her model on Earth.
If she follows you on the sex...
You're an asshole, you know that ?
It's amazing how big of an asshole you are.
Wait a sec, wait
I'm not an asshole, I'm just jealous
I came to talk to you about Lola.
We should get her to a private school.
When you feel like talking, call me.
Hello ? Lola, I have to tell you
I got nothing to say
I really had some troubles
I'm sick of all your lies
Are you kidding me ?
We're dining now!
Come on give me a break
No I don't give you a break
What's with all the yelling ?
I'm tired of all this mess!
Clean your room
Okay so I don't dine ?
After diner!
Don't act stupid!
And you stop it!
I'm sick of your bad behavior!
Me too I have a bad behavior ?
Mrs Delgado, please.
No, first I'll see the girl alone.
He! I don't wanna go to another school!
It's all I have, my friends!
You still has a familly!
That's nice!
Oh yeah I forgot, a familly who
have sex without telling me
I don't give a fuck about having a familly
No doubt, she's her father's daughter.
Yeah let's say that
-Sweetheart ?
-Hmm?
No, nothing
Look at this bitch
She acts like she won the match.
Pisses me off
It's not who Maël would chose
It's who every man would chose
She's ridiculous. You seen her shoes ?
-So lame!
-and she's coming with us in England
We should stop lookin at them 'cause otherwise...
He's gonna imagine I'm interested in him
Right
Stop it!
Stop it
Be quiet!
Who wrote that ?
Mehdi
I'm sure
So disgusting
Keep quiet
You understood ? Not a noise.
And concentrate.
"Tamaget au baconnet" ?
(doesn't mean anything in French,)
yeah yeah
I'm warning you
The next one who talks...
One more noise and I cancel..
..the trip to England, you understand me ?
No London!
Hello
Charlotte, how you doing ?
Very well
Doing some shoping ?
Well yeah
Very well
You live around here ?
Yes, as you can see
You too I figure
Funny huh ?
What's that ?
Come on!
The probability for us to bump into each other
..is what... ?
You could reckon it
There you are!
Did you think about the milk ?
No, I forgot about it.
Mr Messier...
.. my maths teacher
Hello
I'm sorry
..for the lessons at home
Lessons for Charlotte ?
No no
I got confused with another studend
Quite ambarassing having memory issues
when teachin maths!
Come on, let's go!
Mam.
I hope they're not all like him
He was alone so he's single
Why do you care ?
You're not gonna fuck him ?
How can you be so sure ?
Gotta go
My unknown person is doin some weird things
Who is he ?
Don't know
Don't know him
You're insane
Fucking insane
I have a double call, ciao.
He's fuckin insane
Big breaking news
What's that ?
Guess who doesn't go to England
Maël?
Better
Who ?
*-De Peyrefitte. Appendicitis
-you're kidding
-Awesome!
-And God exists
-Gotta go
Ciao.
Easy with the meds mum
I'm just going to England
That's for bellyaches.
Will you remember ?
I will
I write it down, "bellyache"
It's okay mum I have a brain
Good for you baby. Good for you.
I'll finish packing
Okay
Thank you
What's that ?
It belongs to Lola
Have to give it back to her
You exchange your underwear ?
No but she slept over once, and huh...
And that ? and that ?
She forgot it
oh yeah ? and that's Lola's too ?
Are you kidding me ?
You haven't left yet, you know that ?
I never want to see you
wearing that shit!
Plus, you're a liar.
Straight to the trash bin.
you're not taking many books
Well no, I'm going there essentialy
for learning English
You'll be carefull right ?
Sure!
Why are you telling me this like that ?
No because...
No, not that one!
Mum, please!
No way!
I don't have any hot clothes
You got so many
it's itchy! Yours' soft
High-end cashmere, you bet!
please! England is cold
And English people...
..they're real cheap on heating
Lola will get a pneumonia
she'll die and you'll never see me again
I can't believe you! All right take it
Thanks
Get out
Come on...
Stop it!
Come on now
Need a special device to see the colors or sth ?
What a shitty weather!
Check this out, a garden gnome!
They sure look like winners
We're not gonna learn English
..but suicide attempts
I'm gonna ask to see their
criminal record
The old one, with the odd chick
lucky like we are, it's for us
Doesn't change too much
from your family
Damn!
Man, I can't believe it!
She freaks me out
Gotta get outta here
A little tolerance
Dont' say that
You don't have monopoly of discrimination
'More like the MPV of anxiety'
(French joke)
She's dribbling on me!
Ouch! Damn man can't believe it
Sorry
No thank you
You think they're Al Quaida members ?
Stop it!
I'd love to be taken hostage
by the mum or the daughter
And is there a plug for the cellphone ?
I had a nice trip
Okay. Welcome to the feaks' home!
I call you again when we have an adaptator
They don't have one
My family is very weird mum, very weird
Yeah, I'll explain it to you
And how you doing ? Is everything all right ?
Okay, call whenever you want
-Kiss, my love
-Kiss mum
I love you Lola.
-kiss
Shit! I forgot to give her an adaptator.
-I'm late.
-where you going ?
You go brush you teeth and then go to bed.
Come on let's go, it's late already
So you like him ?
Who ?
Navarro.
I asked you not to call him that
I never thought about it
You should have my love.
It's high time for you to start over
I hate that expression.
As if we're lost without men.
That's the truth
-Kiss
-So tell me, where is he taking you ?
It's a suprise
You should wear a scarf
I'm not 14!
They look like Mum and Lola
See you later
What about your teeth ?
-Done!
-Let me see.
Yeah
For Lady Di they would
have turned the heating on
Damn right! I'm so cold
I have to tell you sth
What's that ?
It wasn't Maël and De Perrefyte who
were fucking in the toillets
I know, Maël to me in the bus
Oh yeah ?
And you, how do you know?
Well, it was me
It was you ?
Hmm
But with who ?
With Paul-Henri.
You fucked things up
you realize that ?
With Paul-Henri, nonetheless
Shit!
With Paul-Henri
I'm sorry
I fucked things up
I am sorry for you
What do you do again ?
I'm a cop
oh ?
narcotics
You're a narc ? really ?
I'm used to it, don't worry.
No no..
It's all right
Breathe
You seem more anxious suddently
No no, but it's..
And is it a good job ?
What a coward
No big deal you know
-hum ?
-I didn't know
-What ?
That he was a...
What did you think I was...
I don't know really...
No seriously you don't look like..
..a cop
-Come on, he's not wearing the hat
I fell like I'm in a movie
Shhh!
Don't make any noise
Come on let's go
You're a genius
Move
Thanks man, you're the best
Go fuck yourself!
All right
It's weird here
The decoration is so weird
yeah
They're nice
Sure they are
-You think she believed us ?
-Don't think so
"She's deaf and mute"
Can I ask you a favor ?
Could you keep my guitar, back in Paris ?
You the only one I trust
No problem
Why does it always go bad in Paris
I don't know, Everything's complicated in Paris
-Maël ?
-What is it ?
I have to tell you sth
What is it ?
Well...
It's the first time
It's the first time...
.. that I make love to another man than my husband
shhh...
I hope it won't be that cold in Paris
I'll have to tell Charlotte
..that love with man we love
must be different
maybe not better,especially when
we don't know it's only for one night
but it feels so great
that it ends up hurting
I don't how one survives to that
no, honestly I don't know
THIRD TRIMESTER
-They're here
-Anxious ?
yeah
If he kisses you on the lips, he takes repsonsability
If he doesn't, it's over
-Hi
-How you doing ?
-Fine, you ?
-Fine
-Everything went fine ?
Why didn't you kiss me ?
you're ambarassed?
-No no
-I thought...
It's not that I don't love you
but it's hard to show it
in front of Arthur.
You understand ?
Yes.
For real ?
No.
-Hey
-How you doing sweetheart?
Fine
So! You didn't tell me
tell you what ?
Well, England!
Oh! It went very well
What did you do ?
We visited... Nothing special really
And you ?
me ?
What did you do ?
Nothing... nothing
Nothing special either
all right
I do what's worse to do, betraye secrets!
It's hard to live with it
Tell her!
What ?
Everything
That you found her diary, that you read everything
No way, she'll never forgive me!
hmmm
take it, take it!
Hey!
-Hello, mam
-'lo
-see ya
-see ya, Lola.
You saw how you said hello to her ?
What do you mean ?
Cold as ice like "hello".
I'm not thrilled that you hang out with this girl
She's my best friend.
I hand out with whoever I want to!
It's my life!
I'm sorry ?
It's my life
You're my daughter, and you're not
18 yet, and there's a few things..
..that I don't accept, you feel me ?
And what might that be ?
That you're screwing up your life!
Not at all!
You smoke joints, you get drunk,
you sleep with whoever is there...
and you're not screwing up your life ???
Bullshit! Where'd you get that from ?
I know everything, Lola!
What ?
And stop acting like I'm a fool!
Like your father does
-You're so lame to say that
-I... I've read your diary!
You what ?
I didn't do it on purpose
Stop it! I's hidden!
At least, we know what we're talking about
You don't need to know about my life.
That's my private life
Don't try to be part of it
Fuck I'm tired of this
You have no rights
You're really a bitch!
You could write this one down on your diary!
Idiot!
-Lola!
-Mum!
Lola!
Not enough men around here
What about me ?
Oh sweetheart...
Open up right now
It's my room
Even that you can't respect
We need to talk
Never again
Go fuck yourself!
You have no idea what you'll get when...
I don't even tell you
Where you going ?
-To my father's
You dreamnt about this. Is it a problem ?
Not a problem at all!
I can even take you there
No need for that!
See you everybody!
Where R U ?
At my father's...
I add garlic to the sauce
hmmm No
Huh... yes I add garlic to the sauce
I got into a fight with my mother!
And still your mother ain't like mine!
Charlotte!
Dinner's ready!
yes, I'm comin'
Ready for a "tongue lesson" ??
So the image of the triangle J.F.K
..by the translation of vector I.D
..is the triangle E.F.J..
..or E.A.F.?
I'm sorry ?
You know what a vector is ?
Yeah! a dvd 'vector'
(French joke: 'vecteur' (vector) is close to 'lecteur' (player))
-OK
and where are you going ?
hum... Well...
to the bathroom...
With your shoes ?
Well some people read magazines
I like to have my shoes...
Stop it!
You see this door ?
Brand new technology!
-The same museums use
-Museums ?
You get close to it, the laser detects
what you're
trying to get out and the alarm turns on
And.. you're punished
I didn't want to get out,
just go to the bathroom
Be careful!
You don't want it to turn on again!
Calm down, François!
-Understood ?
-Yes
-Yes, who ?
-Yes dad
You goin to sleep my love ?
See you tomorow
Good night
Come to bed
Why don't you say "my love" to me too ?
You'll see that by many aspects
that pig, or pork
..shares many similarities with human.
For once we agree on sth..
-Mrs Clavel,
We don't need your comments, thank you.
The valve
It's the most important part of the heart
that we're gonna study
What's a valve ?
Mr. Reynal?
Isn't it like a vulva ?
Epic
..Mr. Reynal. Epic.
Take your scalpel
and cut in a smooth
..and frank way.
No way I'm touching that
Let's get started
Hmmm...
Damn I like doing this
Freak!
It's disgusting.
How many pigs
..did we kill for this class ?
What's Greenpeace doing ?
The same thing they do for all
the wales they killed for you to wear
..this make-up only a whore would wear.
Stop saying women
..are whores
Honestly
Thanks
Straigh from the heart
How we doing over there ?
A rabbit foot!
That's harsh sir!
no it's not!
You're not happy ? you can leave
We were right to get the fuck out
-"I don't touch pork" . You killed me
Fuck you guys, with your religions
I was enjoying
Serial killer!
Give me a break!
oh no
Oh no, fuck!
Before I even get here, you can all
take out your "teachers-to-parents note"
(French concept)
I don't have it
We'll save some time
-What do we do ?
-Well... we'll see.
-It's because of her
-it'll be detention
No more subway and the fresh air of Paris.
I don't wanna go to boarding school
and leave the band
I'm fuckin with you but
I'll miss all this. What d'ya think ?
Don't worry, I won't go
Crying time!
the 2 best friends
..on the balcony
But for you and Lola, really
I don't give a fuck
You knew?
well...
You don't give a shit ?
I'm pleased.
I'm pleased more than anything else.
thanks dude
Still don't abuse it,
Vanilla, I love it, but caramel not so much
hmm. It's the contrary for me
I prefer caramel
It's complicated huh ?
Yeah, complicated
It's mum, I miss you sweetheart!
And I'm so sorry I read your diary...
baby...
For the Emerganza festival
11th district, as usual
I didn't find it
Buy a map of the subway and fuckin eat it
My father won't let me go out
-I thought you dealt with that
-I'm sorry
That's too bad
The same for me
Same shit for me
We won't have to cancel ?!
I have a plan
For real ?
I think I can pull it off
Lola!!
My Lou!
-I missed you!
-Lola!
I'm so happy to see you!
-My baby my baby
-Mum
-I missed you
-Me too!
Lola's here
-Let me see you
-Have I changed ?
-I don't like it when you're not there
-me neither
-My little love
-We'll never leave each other
It feels so good
Mum ?
Can I ask you sth ?
Already ?
You're the best mum we ask that.
Who's that "we" ?
-Well...
Hello
-Hello
He's not alone I can see..
Maël?
What an idiot!
10 bucks
-Maël!
Thanks a lot.
To someone who I really love...
Mum ?
Inspired by a true story...