Look at y'all niggas
Look at y'all smokin' ass niggas
After every pull, niggas start chokin' ass niggas
Nigga-nigga
Look at y'all bitch ass niggas
Stop lyin' on your dick ass niggas
Nigga-nigga
Look at y'all lookin' ass niggas
Stop lookin' at my ass ass niggas
Look at y'all lyin' ass niggas
Talkin' 'bout "It's paid off" but it's financed, lyin' ass nigga
Bunch of non-mogul ass niggas
Frontin' like they got a plan, Boost Mobile ass nigga
Nigga, nigga, look at y'all
Can't get a job so you plottin' how to rob ass niggas
I ain't gotta check for y'all
But if I'ma check for y'all, I'ma need a check from y'all niggas
I 'on't want sex, give a fuck about your ex
I 'on't even want a text from y'all niggas
I'm rapin' you niggas
Look at this pic, look what the fuck I gave to you niggas
Ain't feelin' these niggas
Niggas want my time, call me Clinton, I'm billin' these niggas
All I know is there should be no reason
All I, all I know is there should be
All I know
All I, all I know is there should be no reason
All I know, you know it, and you know it
Look at what, reason
Look at y'all sharin' one bottle in the club
One bottle full of bub' ass niggas
Look at y'all not havin' game ass niggas
Y'all niggas share a chain ass niggas
Same cup in the hand ass nigga
In the club with a credit card scam ass nigga
No dick in the pants ass nigga
I be damned if I fuck a non-man ass nigga
I will, I will, I will never fuck a non-man ass nigga
I would never lie even if that nigga flew me and my bitches all the way out to Dubai
Pussy, you tried, pussy ass nigga you lie
Pussy ass nigga, you high
Bitch I'm me, hundred on the wrist, I ski
Art on the wall, Basqui, fuck who see
Look at you fake dope dealers
Know real niggas that be movin' weight in them villas
Talkin' 'bout ki's, say it's ki's in the van
But he really move grams and he split it with his mans
All I know is there should be no reason
All I, all I know is there should be
All I know
All I, all I know is there should be no reason
All I know, you know it, and you know it
Look at what, reason