Based on Real Events
Only the dead have seen the War Ended
--- Penerjemah: CilokMovie3 ---
CilokMovie3.blogspot.com
Somalia, East Africa
Many Years War among Tribe Cause the Great Famine.
300,000 people die of hunger.
Mohamed Farah Aidid, leader of The Strongest, Mastering the capital Mogadishu.
He intercepted Foreign Food Aid At the Port. The weapon is hunger.
Answering the world. Along with 20,000 US Marines, Food Delivered and Order Restored.
Then Withdrawn Pending Marines Aidid State War With ...
... The United Nations Peacekeeping Survive.
In June, Aidid militia Ambushing and massacred 24 Pakistani troops ...
... And Start Eyeing American personnel.
In late August, US Elite Forces, Delta Force, Army Rangers and SOAR-160 Ke ...
... Sent to Mogadishu to capture Aidid and Restore Order.
The mission was supposed Lasts For 3 Weeks ...
... But the 6 Week Pass, Washington Start Impatient.
Saturday, October 2, 1993
Red Cross Food Distribution Center
Healthy.
Armored vehicles, 9 o'clock direction.
Shit! You see that?
The commander, fired on unarmed residents here at 9 o'clock.
I see Matt. I guess we can not interfere.
Food is owned by Mohamed Farrah Aidid!
Return to your homes!
Command, here Super 64 ...
... Militiamen opened fire on civilians at the food distribution center.
Ask permission to shoot.
Super 64, are you fired? Change.
No, Command.
UN jurisdiction, 64. We can not intervene.
- Return to base. Change. - Good.
64 back.
Bakara market, Mogadisgu REGIONAL POWERS AIDID
It's ready, Tn. Atto.
He departed.
Then.
Keep moving!
I would arrive late.
Telepon nanti.
General Garrison?
No, thank you. I already have.
But this is from Cuba.
Bolivar Belicoso.
This too.
Miami, not Cuba, Comrade.
I saw failed to capture Aidid has become a routine you.
We're not trying to catch Aidid. We are trying to catch you.
I?
But as important is that what I am?
I do not think so.
- You're just a businessman. - Trying to make a living.
Yes. Selling guns to Aidid's militia.
How long have you been here?
Six weeks?
Six weeks you are trying to catch the general.
You plug the reward poster.
25,000 dollars. As if this is? Duel weapons in KO Corral?
The true OK Corral.
You think the arrest will make him suddenly come to you?
Makes it more by?
You know where he sleeps.
You financed his life, much less his militia.
We will not leave Somalia before we find it.
And we'll find him.
Do not think because I'm a big no running water ...
... I'm dumb, General.
I know something about history.
See all of this? Just shape the future.
Future without much idea of ​​white boys Arkansas.
I do not know about that. I'm from Texas.
Tn. Garrison, you should not have come here.
This civil war.
This is our war.
Not your war.
300,000 dead and counting.
This is not a war, Tn. Atto. This annihilation.
I enjoy it now.
How does he think?
Polite, intelligent, ruthless.
Yes, he's a good catch.
It takes time, but Aidid will feel the loss.
I guess we do not have much time.
This is not Iraq. Which is much more complicated.
Boss, most of Washington disagree.
They asked daily situation report.
Tell them that the situation is vulnerable.
Mogadishu Airport Headquarters US Forces
Passenger and gentlemen, I'm Cliff "Elvis" Wolcott.
I'll be your pilot today.
Appropriate federal rules, this Black Hawk helicopter smoke.
Mogadishu routinely fly program participants will get 100 free credits.
As usual, sickness bag in the back of the seat in front of you.
A good indication of the number one, Cliff. Take it to number two.
The sky was still bright.
61, is 64. Move to UHF secure.
I have some bad news.
"Limo" is a word, Durant. I do not want to hear it.
That's not a word, but condensation.
"Limo" is a commonly used word.
The keywords in Scrabble, my friend. Commonly used.
When not in the dictionary, it does not count!
Nothing should be in the dictionary!
There should be in the dictionary!
If we go back to the base, said it should be reduced.
You touch my limo, will kutampar ass, Nightstalker.
Yes, the promise remained a promise.
A nice beach down there.
How's the water?
Warm reassuring. And filled with sharks.
- Name. - Todd.
- Last name. - Blackburn.
First name, Todd.
- So, what is it? - How is it like?
Mogadishu. Battles.
- Registration number. - 72,163,427.
The first, called "Mog" only. Here nobody calls it Mogadishu.
Secondly, I do not know about the battles, so do not ask.
Why can not?
I told you, "Do not ask".
You seem almost 12 years, so I'll explain something.
I have a rare and mysterious skill that took me out of the mission.
Type.
- You can type? - No.
- Date of birth. - February 27, 1975.
I'm here to fight.
Let us enter.
Good, Comrade! Very smooth!
One shot penetrated the engine block.
Too bad. Though it was a nice jeep.
Stop shooting!
Check your weapons!
Sergeant Eversmann.
Pratu Blackburn.
Ya?
Reporting for duty.
Not me. Report it to Lt. Beales. He was around here.
Can I leave him with you?
Yes, please.
- Did you bring your gun. - Yes, Sir.
Do you want me to shoot? I am ready.
- When did you arrive? - Just now, Sergeant.
Hey, who's hungry?
What is this, Sergeant? Safari Delta financed by taxpayers again?
- Not if Jend. Garrison asked. - I asked.
Bon appetite, Captain.
- Lineup, Friend. - I know.
- This is not a rear end. - Yes I know.
Sergeant.
What is this?
Only a shooting exercise, sir. I do not want to leave.
I mean weapon.
Delta or not, the weapon was not yet secure.
You know that safety should always be installed at the base.
This is my safety, sir.
Leave it alone, sir. He had two days without food.
You guys are a bunch of cowboys Delta troops were undisciplined.
Let me tell you something, Sergeant.
When we've approached the target, you will need a Ranger-ku.
You must learn to be a team player.
Discussion over.
Speak up. You say this is your seat?
This shoe, son.
And this would fit in with enough force anusmu.
- It was a Jersey accent? - While I do this, given the opportunity.
Open sunglasses.
Delta wants to wear Oakley, that's their business.
I do not want to see you wear it again.
The weapon was not safe?
Is that your ways?
Hand on the chess pieces?
I can beat you in three steps.
I'll keep an eye on that queen before defeating the other.
He just lay waiting.
Gosh.
Nice drawing. You're growing.
If I can give any advice or observations.
Please.
- It's a children's book, right? - Yes.
Supposedly it does not make children become afraid.
This part of the story where the knight would slay the dragon.
It's scary. Moreover, my daughter like this.
I thought you had it done last week.
Already completed?
We are in the line of 10 yards here.
You understand?
Can you count? One, two, ten.
Understand? Where players bertahanku?
Where players bertahanku?
I do not see you in church on Sunday.
There are other more important activities?
Not on Sunday. No longer.
I'll make you believe, understand?
Funny, huh?
A great impersonation. I got to know if it was me.
All right, go ahead.
- I want to talk, Specialist. - Sir.
You understand why we have a chain of command, right?
Yes, Sir.
Because if you memperolokku again, you'll clean the toilet with your tongue ...
... Until you can not distinguish where human feces and fries.
- Understand? - Yes, Sir.
OK.
Listen to this.
When a murder of a Somalian Somalia More ...
... Tribe tribe owes 100 camels on the dead man.
100 sleep.
Camel. I do not want to pay the camels.
There is definitely a lot of debt camels.
Is that true, Lieutenant?
Ask Sergeant Eversmann. She loves people of Somalia.
Sergeant Eversmann, you really like the Somalis?
Not that I like or do not like. I respect them.
You do not know if the sergeant is an idealist.
He really believes this mission. Do not you, Sergeant?
Look, they have no jobs ...
... Had no food, education, let alone the future.
I think there are two things we can do.
We can help ...
... Or silent watch this nation destroyed itself on CNN.
True, is not it?
Somehow you guys, but I was trained to fight.
You're trained to fight, Sergeant?
I guess I was trained to make a difference, Kurth.
As said Kurth, the sergeant is an idealist.
Wait. This is my favorite part.
Stay away from the cans!
You're dead handyman content of gasoline!
Possible.
He's having a seizure. Put something in his mouth.
It's okay, John.
At 5:45 the morning Sunday, October 3
He'll be fine. But not in this army.
He came out of the game. He suffers from epilepsy, had to go home.
Kau Kutugaskan memimpin regunya.
- Do you mind? - No sir.
It's a big responsibility.
Regumu will count on you to make the right decision.
Risk their lives.
OK.
- Ranger led the way, sir. - Along the way.
Good luck.
Hawlwadid road, Bakara Market BASIS Aidid MILITIA
Aidid's senior cabinet meetings may take place at 15:00 today.
I say "may" because we all know ...
... If the information we get on the road nothing definite.
This information was confirmed by three sources.
Two classes of officials may be present.
Omar Salad, Aidid's main political adviser ...
... And I Hassan Awale, the interior minister.
They are what we seek.
Today we depart.
The pattern of the same mission as sebeleumnya.
15:45, Striker Force Delta will infiltrate the target building ...
... And catch all the suspects in it.
Striker team Ranger: Ranger 4 under the command of Captain Steele ...
... Will be joined at 15:46 ...
... And keep the 4 corners around the target building.
Nobody in or out.
Troops of the pickup.
Lt. Col. jeep entourage. McKnight will get in at 15:47 ...
... Road Hawlwadig and waiting at Hotel Olympic.
Wait for the green light.
Once Delta gives the word ...
... McKnight team will toward the target and load the prisoners onto trucks.
Immediately after the prisoners are loaded ...
... The four Ranger teams will be drawn from the target building ...
... Climbed into the jeep ...
... And all the team will return to base 4.8 km away.
The mission will take place no more than 30 minutes.
I had requested armored vehicles and aircraft AC-130 Spectre ...
... But Washington wisely opposed this.
Too invite attention.
So Black Hawk and Little Bird will provide air support ...
... With small arms and rocket 2.75.
Colonel Harrell.
In the C-2 helicopter, Colonel Matthews will coordinate the air mission ...
... And I will coordinate ground forces.
Colonel Matthews.
Irene's mission is to launch code.
Any question?
Building that, Sir?
Being ascertained now. Somewhere near the Bakara market.
I did not choose the time or place of their meetings.
I have no comment, sir.
Make no mistake, once arrived at the Bakara market ...
... You are in a very dangerous area.
Do not underestimate their capabilities.
We will skip friendly territory before it gets to the market ...
... So remember the rules crossfire: Do not shoot if not shot.
Now, let's get this implemented.
Good luck, gentlemen.
What is it, Danny? There's something you like?
No Spectre gunships, daylight instead of night ...
... As they chew khat leaves ...
... This part of town where Aidid could do counterattack.
- Why did not you like? - Life is not perfect.
You two, spinning 500 feet on it, it is not perfect.
Street below, there is no forgiveness.
Geez, Smith?
- How? - How what?
We leave?
- Why did you have to tell? - Because it's me.
Yes. 3:00. In the middle of the city.
- Bakara Market. - OK.
Listen, Smith, I want you to help out there.
Stay alert.
Good, Sergeant Eversmann.
Ev, this is not nothing.
It's nothing.
Milling decisive. Do not be too smooth or rough.
This is an exact science, Friend.
I have people who believe in advertising.
"Try your best."
I make coffee during Desert Storm.
I make coffee for Panama, while everyone fought ...
... To be a Ranger.
Now "Grimesy, strong coffee made of sugar" or "Grimesy, you have coffee?"
- What is wrong with you? - Accidents ping-pong.
What?
Guess what.
Your request is granted. You're going out today.
Are you kidding.
You take my place as an assistant gunner M60.
Sergeant Eversmann told you to pack up and prepare yourself.
That's what you want, is not it?
Ya.
Of course.
Grimesy, remained with Waddell and give him ammo when needed.
I would not worry about that. Somalis errant shot.
Keep an eye on them just a stone's throw, and you'll be fine.
This might even be fun.
Delta duty. We only protect them.
Helicopters will protect us, and we'll be fine.
Listen, this is the first time I became a squad leader ...
... But this is not our first duty. This is serious.
We Ranger, not JROTC.
Our elite team.
We act like it out there.
Any question?
We'll be fine.
Grab your gear. We're off.
You will not need it, pal. We will not be there long.
You will not need it too.
We will be back before dark.
Better bring opium and beer.
What?
Ammunition, my friend. Bring ammunition.
Let me tell you something, Grimes. You've brought 22 kg of equipment.
Needless to plus 5 kg more.
Somehow you, but I do not plan on shot during a run.
Should I still use mine.
Grimes.
The most important.
Remember, when everyone is shooting, menembaklah same direction.
Look at that. He paste blood type in shoes.
- It brought bad luck. - No, it's clever.
All Delta do that.
It also brought bad luck, pal.
Let's go.
Fortunately, you're not left-handed, Adonis.
- If not, what do you do either. - You're funny, man.
- I do not accept the death certificate. - We had a deal.
I will return in an hour.
- Blackburn, you okay? - I can hardly wait.
Positively. I've been training for this lifetime.
Never shoot people before?
No sir.
I also.
14:29 pm Lunch
Do you think he can be relied upon?
We will see later. It's the first time he came out.
- Tell him to turn off his radio. - Good, Sir.
Tell him to turn off his radio.
Abdi, you must turn off your radio.
Hi. Here residence Stephanie and Randy, leave a message. Thank you.
Hey, darling, it's you. You are there?
Pick up if you're there.
I'm just calling to make sure everything is fine.
I'll call in a few hours.
We recommend that you do not sleep.
Your turn, Randy.
I miss you.
I love you, sweetheart.
Halo? Halo?
Thank you buddy.
It's ironic.
The beautiful beaches, the sun is beautiful.
Nearly so beautiful tourist spot.
Almost.
You think we should not be here.
Know what I think? It does not matter what I think.
Once that first bullet passing close to your head, politics and the like ...
... Had no meaning anymore.
I just wanted to do it right today.
Beware. Takeout entire regumu alive.
Is this the place or the car broke down again?
For me, answer.
Abdi, can you hear me? Is this the place?
Can you hear me? Abdi.
Abdi, answer. Is this the place?
On the way to my right, above the cafe.
He says it's the building.
He sure?
Abdi, you need to be sure.
Are you sure?
In this way, two blocks from the direction of my left.
Too many militias.
When I got closer, they might shoot me.
Now he says the building was still two blocks ...
... But when she looked outside, she would be shot.
I'll personally shoot him.
Tell him to park in front of the building.
He will not be paid before he did it.
4.8 km from the target area. We never got out of the main road.
At the roundabout K-4, we are to the north and then east on National ...
... And we wait until the collection is completed prisoners here.
And with full power to Hawlwadig ...
... Load the prisoners, avoid attacks and bring them home.
Return in an hour. Understand?
There will be a shoot-out. Bakara market is the Regional Cowboy.
Be careful when shooting. There were citizens.
Reportedly they shoot his own head while playing Russian roulette.
Pak, the car stopped.
So this is the truth. This time he was sure.
- He sounded scared. - Good. It is always a good sign.
Thats it. It marks us.
OK.
All QRF move.
All units, Irene. I say again, Irene.
Checking preparation. Barber 51 ready. Star 41 is ready.
Irene!
Received, Irene.
To hell with Irene!
Come on.
Good luck, my friend.
Be careful.
There are no friends left.
What is wrong?
Nothing. He never did that.
Shit!
Let's go.
Sergeant Struecker. Let's go.
Two minutes.
Why are they burning tires?
Signs of the militias if we come!
56, there seems to be some friends on the ground.
One minute.
What for?
In the previous jump, I almost bite my tongue off.
Almost there.
Two legs, one leg ...
...to.
Little Bird reached the target.
These!
Quick! Quick!
Team One has landed. Two teams have been revealed.
Here McKnight. 64 troops approached the area specified.
Get down!
Keep your heads down!
Get down! They all hit the deck!
You, get down!
Get down!
Get down on the floor.
Come on, get down!
Grimesy! Have no fear!
Of course!
Ranger secured the area around. Four corners.
Colonel, they're shooting at us!
Reply shoot!
64. The team here has been lowered, we're going to wait formations.
Here 62, the team has been delivered. Protection formations.
Super 62, give protection from sniper fire. Change.
Here the Super 65. The team has been lowered, we're going to wait formations.
Down, Blackburn! Download!
Down, Blackburn!
RPG!
Hold on!
No!
C-2, there is a fall.
Super-61, you're an easy target.
Protection against snipers. Change.
Accepted. 61 out.
13, continue. You have to move towards the northern part of the road.
Right to the north. Change.
While! While Schmid!
Come on!
Schmid, who was shot there.
- He was shot where? - Not a shot, but fell.
- What? - He fell.
Why do not you shoot?
We have not fired!
Do you know where?
Sibilation means close.
Now they're shooting at us!
Galentine!
Connect me with Captain Steele!
Juliet 64, here Juliet 25. Answer. Change.
Blackburn, can you hear me?
I could not reach him!
Juliet 64, here Regu Four! No members hurt!
We have to take him out of here! Change.
64. I repeat here again, 25. Change.
No members hurt! Change.
Breathe quiet, 25, and repeat. Change.
- People get hurt! - I can not hear, 25.
- Shit. - Repeat again.
Matt, jeep distance away!
Bring a stretcher here. We take him to the target building.
What did he say?
Super 61, no one was hurt on the ground.
- Stretcher! - Get me a stretcher!
Fast. Stretcher.
Come on!
Hold the tip!
- All right. - Lift.
Take him to the jeep. We will maintain this angle.
Bring to a jeep! Now!
Come on!
So, Grimes! Run!
- Safe! - Let's go!
Everything stands! Come on!
Street!
Come on! Quick way!
- Grimes, run! - Good.
C-2, here Super 61, began circling the target areas.
Team Four, is secure. Answer.
Kilo 11, this is 61, providing protection for the evacuation of prisoners. Change.
Kilo 64, the green light.
- Ready for evacuation. Change. - Received, Kilo 11.
Thats it. We get them.
Troop 64, ready for evacuation. Change.
Be accepted. It was his calling. Let's go!
- Let's go! - Hold on.
- How much longer? - Five minutes, sir.
- What? - Five minutes.
Nothing for it!
What happened to him?
- Falling from the rope! - How can?
Put him into a jeep! Grimes, help him!
Come on! We're off!
Quickly, the road! Come on!
Put him!
Prepare to go!
Come on! All the way! Quick!
Stand up!
Grimes! Ayo!
Grimes!
Shit!
Let's go.
Come on!
Come on! Quick!
Street!
Romeo 64, I sent three jeeps with a seriously wounded.
He seems severe. Should be evacuated now.
Accepted, 64 teams.
We will send you the best shooters. Change.
Be accepted.
I need more security in the jeep!
I will go. I'll take my team, make sure they come back safely.
Do it.
Struecker, you take the jeep forward.
Three ground vehicles moving, we'll get back to base.
Depart!
How is the condition? All right in there, Struecker?
I do not want to talk about it now, Colonel!
I am busy.
Sergeant Pilla shot!
He hit a landslide!
There is a shot?
Struecker, speak to me!
Sergeant Pilla!
What is its status?
He was killed.
Pilla was killed, sir.
C-2, here McKnight. There were no fatalities, Dominick Pilla. Change.
Be accepted.
50 rifle was fired!
Someone fired a gun 50 it!
Just me.
Three people with RPG will emerge from the side. Now!
Hold on!
Here 61. I'm shot.
Super 61 shot. Wolcott helicopter was shot.
Do you want to turn off the PCL or not?
OK.
Come on.
61 will fall.
Super 61 will fall.
61 will fall. I repeat, will fall.
61 will fall.
Hold on!
Black Hawk crashed.
Super 61 falls. There is a helicopter crashed in the town.
Super 61 is now falling.
Send MH-6 to the location falls. Search for survivors.
Send a SAR helicopter.
Muster ground forces and secure it around the location of the helicopter crashed.
Can you scout convoy there?
Can.
Hurry up and move.
The whole city will come to them.
Star 41, try approaching and landing on the location of the helicopter crashed.
Good. Star 41 approached.
We just lost the initiative.
25, here 64. Change.
25. Change.
25, Team Four nearest location falls. Change.
64, I could not see the crash site. Change.
25, in the direction of timurmu. You will find it.
Leave the security elements in place. Bring the rest of the team to the site crashed.
Search for survivors. Secure the area. The other group will follow.
You hear me, 25? Change.
Galentine! Schmid!
Call Yurek.
Call Twombly.
There is a Black Hawk crashed.
Twombly, Nelson, stay here.
Maintain this angle then go by jeep.
Galentine, Schmid, you come with me. Come on.
Why am I still here?
Because you can rely on.
OK...
...Let's go!
I hate dependable, my friend.
Juliet 25, the group approached the hostile position parallel to the west of you.
Women and children among them. Change.
Against the wall.
Look out!
Grenade!
Come on.
There are still our people inside.
I will go to the location falls.
You take the rest of the team. Will finish loading the prisoners.
No! We aka locations to fall together.
Secure the area, waiting jeep.
- Good. - Follow my directions.
Sergeant, you hear me?
Yeah, I heard. We must leave immediately.
Well, we have to leave now!
Will finish loading the prisoners and pick you up at the location of the fall!
Let's go!
Move! Come on!
Get in!
Quick!
Clockwise 8!
Grimes, stay away from the wall.
Grimes. You okay?
Ya!
Ayo, Maddox.
- C-2, the convoy departed. - Be accepted.
Maddox, look at these fools!
Come on! Right, Maddox, right!
Twombly, the convoy go!
Hei, Twombly!
What?
- I think they forgot us. - What?
Never mind.
63 reported. Somali people come from all sides. They need help.
The local militias moved toward the location falls Wolcott.
Repeat.
Many people approaching.
How far Team Four of locations fall?
- Six blocks, sir. - They have to be quick.
Get down!
Scotty, are you okay?
Do not come back!
Get down!
Armed car!
Shoot them!
Directions at six! Quick!
Come on!
Quick!
Yurek, go!
Come on!
Team 64, turn left.
Romeo 64, I need to know before I arrived on the street!
You should reduce speed. There was a delay.
From the time relayed from surveillance to JOC, then to me.
Can not reduce speed! We were attacked with great force!
Can not reduce speed!
Danny, I'll get the information from Orion surveillance above.
So give me directions to the location of fall!
Danny, be patient. I no longer have the best views rutemu.
Work with incompetent, jerk!
What troupe status Struecker jeep?
Colonel Harrell, when arriving at the base, the group Struecker.
The arrival time soon.
Open the gate!
- Take him out! Come on! - Fast.
Caution head.
Slowly.
- Blackburn, can you hear me? - Take him to the medical.
Star 41 is already on location fell evacuate the wounded. Change.
Be accepted.
I got you.
Slowly.
Galentine, you okay?
Galentine, Kurth, follow me! Fire protection, now.
Full protection!
How many are there?
Two pilots were killed, two crew members were injured!
- The wound was severe. Should be taken away. - Go.
26, here 25. Did you sprayed the car with the gun?
26. Right here.
DiTomasso, take the southeast corner. We will create a cover. Change.
26. D iterima here. We are moving there now.
Move!
Captain Steele, answer.
Come in, 25. Here 64.
There are two wounded and two pilots died in a helicopter!
We need to evacuate now!
Too dangerous to land the helicopter. Ensure safe first.
Where a group of the jeep?
I gave them know, 25, the convoy will be there.
They face a lot of resistance. 64 out.
- Prepare the gun 50! - The location can be seen at the front.
All I see is the roadblocks!
I had to find another way.
Give us a secure area in order to raise the injured.
Fired weapon, Othic!
Tell my daughters that I'm fine.
The tree!
Joyce! Come on, help me lift it!
Take us away from this street! Where's the crash site? Repeat.
Continue 200 meters ahead.
Be accepted.
Come on!
Come on, Dammit!
Hey, Twombles. Come here.
Jeep excursions will not be back, buddy.
What?
What we have to catch up with them?
I thought they would pick us.
- I think we should follow them. - Shit.
Come to the location of the helicopter crashed.
OK.
Do not fired it into my head. Now I have trouble hearing.
Let's go.
Shit! Get down!
- Did I say anything? Oath if ... - Shut up!
You are okay? Nelson.
You okay?
SAR helicopter medical escort.
Come on!
Fuck. C-2, here 68. We shot.
Super 68, there is smoke coming from the top rotormu.
- Kusarankan kau pergi sekarang -. Diterima.
Lowering the last.
Art, no militia with RPGs in the direction at 12. Can you see them?
I see. Turn 90 degrees to the left.
68 leave the premises.
Super 68 leaves the premises. Change.
--- Penerjemah: Rizal Adam ---
http://rizaladam.wordpress.com
Wilkie, what is the situation there?
Both pilots were killed.
25, we can not take them, Matty.
Brought only they could die.
- Stabilized here? - Good.
Stabilized in the helicopter. I repeat: stabilized in a helicopter. Change.
Understandably, Wilkie. We protect you. Change.
Super 64, come closer and take Wolcott's position.
Be accepted. 64 approached.
Super 64, you do nothing?
This is Super 64. We're not anything.
Are you sure? It seems that you hit pretty badly.
The instrument panel is fine.
We did nothing. Slight wobble in the steering rod, but we did nothing.
Go back to the runway, 64. Check to be safe.
Be accepted.
Steering a lot of vibration. Checking the system again.
We lost the tail rotor! The rotor was not there!
64 will fall!
64 will fall hard.
64 will fall.
We will fall.
Struecker told the team to go there for protection.
They need to fall Durant location quickly.
- A helicopter crashed again. - I want them taken away.
All.
Captain Steele, we have to go or we'll be stuck!
We are moving as quickly as possible.
We do each task. Change.
- Fuck - Ruiz, do not wake up.
A tree.
Captain Steele, I'll tackle the threat in the window.
We met in the building of gray. Soon, Captain.
Sergeant!
All right, let's roads!
Protect me!
- Let's go! - Moving.
Friend!
Friend will be late!
Let's go! Quick!
Come on!
Quick way! Come on!
What are you doing outside of that?
Doing my job! We have to go to the location of fall!
We must go back to the streets and moving!
And you have to follow, sir!
Do not ever give me orders, Sergeant.
We can not fight well, understand?
Too many wounded to be taken!
Then give me some shooters and I'll detour to the helicopter.
Grimes! You members of Team Four?
Yes, Sir!
Come with Delta! Rejoin Sergeant Eversmann.
The rest of you, secure this position!
Treat the wounded, we'll wait for the convoy!
Then we go to the location of the fall. Accepted!
Friends, come on!
C-2, I have two Delta snipers, Shughart and Gordon ...
... Ask yourself secure the location of the second fall. Change.
Super 62, the request is denied. I can not jeopardize other helicopters.
We did not see anything that moves in there, who knows what anyone is alive.
Land team was prepared to go there.
When the arrival? Change.
Not yet known, shortly.
Do as much as possible from the air.
Gathered!
64 Durant fell. We will be back to pick him up!
It was crazy. Do you have a life?
It does not matter, there's nothing left. You know that.
We're wasting time.
Take the ammo and grenades extent, when you were five minutes!
Sizemore, where are you going?
- Come with you. - Not with that cast.
OK. Bring helmet yours.
Speak up.
I can not go back there.
Thomas, everyone feels the same to you.
What are you doing right now, it makes a difference.
Decide.
It would help if the blood in the jeep was cleaned.
Sergeant Struecker!
Sergeant Struecker! Can I come, Sergeant?
- You got ammo? - Yes, Sergeant!
Follow!
Wait!
Come on, Thomas. Come up!
Which direction?
- To get there, I guess! - Do not be loud.
Smart ass.
Ranger?
Who?
I Yurek! You idiot!
Shit!
Friends, we almost killed you!
- Here! - You guys are here.
Sorry, Sergeant!
Friend, where have you been?
Forget it. You brought NOD, right?
No, I did not take it and you know why?
Because you said: "You do not need it, we'll be back in half an hour."
I did not say that to you.
Nelson, take direction here.
We'll need night vision.
What happened to you?
He's deaf. My fault.
- We should get out of here! - Go that way.
We're certainly not far from where the helicopter crashed. Which direction?
I thought you knew.
Let's go.
Nelson, Twombly? Please answer. Change.
Nelson, Twombly, this Galentine. We need the convoy. Change.
I can not contact them, Sgt.
Sir, we go out of here and do evacuate!
- Let's go. - Back to the defense!
Come on!
Ground forces have occupied several buildings in Rehan Road ...
... But they are scattered.
Team 4 Eversmann form of defense around the site fell Wolcott.
DiTomasso was in the building opposite.
40 Ranger Captain Steele and here are a few blocks away.
They hurt pretty badly.
He forms a collecting point victim, I guess they can not move.
Sergeant Sanderson and a small Delta team ...
... Moving from Steele's position to the location of the current fall.
Shot switcher!
When they stopped to refill cartridges, cover me!
- Go! - Yes, Sir.
Again!
Reloading!
Shoot straight!
Rifle jammed!
Just me!
Seriously!
RPG!
You okay? You are okay?
Yes. I could hear the bells tolling.
Come on!
There was a crowd approaching 6 or 7 blocks to the site crashed.
Shughart and Gordon again request permission ...
... To secure until convoy arrives. Change.
General, the crowd now numbering in the hundreds.
From his position, they can see more clearly than us.
They know what they are asking.
Let me talk to them.
Here Garrison.
I want to make sure you understand what you are asking, say it clearly.
We asked down and form of defense until ground support arrives.
You know I can not say how long, maybe longer.
- Be accepted. - You still want to go there?
Yes, Sir.
- Colonel Harrell? - Yes, General?
Decide.
Be accepted.
Goffena, turunkan mereka.
What an asshole.
RPG!
Form of defense!
No rocket in him, sir!
Othic, calm down! There explosives, blew!
Fuck.
All right, hold him! Slowly!
All right, put him there! Nice! Slowly!
Get in the truck and driving.
- But I'm shot, Colonel. - All people are shot.
We need his prisoner! Come on!
Reconnaissance sent via Hawlwadig, and then continue from there.
McKnight, we need you to turn around and go back to Hawlwadig.
Are you kidding! We just came from there!
There is definitely the most secure!
That's the information I received from JOC, you should turn around and go back.
Be accepted.
I can not believe this! Turn around, Maddox.
They tried to kill us!
We did it! Street!
Fuck!
Take us out of here, go!
Continued to stomp the gas pedal!
Fuck!
Shit.
C-2, Shughart and Gordon have gone down. Change.
Be accepted.
Friend!
Glad to see you!
Glad to see you too. How severe?
My legs were broken and my back feels weird.
We have to get you out of here.
Would I pull him out! Give protection!
Wait for me...
I'm going to drop.
C-2, we are in a location 64 falls, securing the area.
- Are you okay? -Yes.
Loaded weapon.
Anyone militia over here, you protect us from behind.
- Where are the rescuers? - We have.
All right, stop, Maddox. Stop.
What an asshole.
Romeo 64, we are back to where we started.
The bullet is low, many wounded including me ...
... Vehicle was barely able to walk.
All right, I need your estimation, Danny.
Can you reach the site down?
Colonel, I can not see anything.
Can not.
With so many injuries, we only increase the level of danger.
We had to return to base, did weaponry and then back out again.
Good.
C-2, bring them back. Take them away from there.
All right. Back to base.
We will return!
Let's go. To the left.
16:54 pm Afternoon
Understandably. The convoy returned to base.
- What is wrong? - They were sent home.
Convoy returning to base.
Now it makes sense, does not it?
We must take away the wounded and get out of here before it's too late!
If Colonel McKnight returned to base, he had a good reason.
It does not change anything.
All right, listen.
We will keep this region and also our defense.
Save hours of bullets. Shoot what you can shoot.
The convoy will come.
We will return.
Reloading!
Randy, I need a pistol bullet!
Randy, the last bullet!
Gordy!
Shit!
Gordy had been killed, my friend. I'm going outside.
Good luck.
We need the 10th Mountain in there. All they got.
Pakistan, Malaysia, I want their tanks and APCs.
They do not know we attack.
We have to disturb a beehive. We're fighting the entire city.
I want all four-wheeled vehicles and armored. Take it all.
Once they are ready, we bring troops out of dangerous territory ...
... And back to the Pakistani Stadium, the safe zone.
- Go on. - Execute, Bos.
Mohamed Farrah Aidid ...
... Give this man his prisoner alive!
Kneel!
Stay with me. There was a bullet in your leg.
Check tires are burning? All that black smoke?
Yes. I can see it, but I can not get there. Change.
100 meters from there. That location jatunya.
Can not. You do not understand.
All the roads were blocked. You must swatch another route. Change.
No. Only routes that circled the city.
Understandably.
Kilo 64, here Kilo 11.
Ask permission to move to the location of the second fall walk. Change.
The green light, Kilo 11.
Stop the car. Let me down.
17:50 pm Afternoon
Once I'm done with this, I'll make a margarita for you.
Which as usual. With the blender, without salt.
Here Kilo 12. We have to change positions. Change.
Eversmann, answer.
Eversmann.
- Yes. Who is this? - Sanderson.
Do not shoot toward the east. We will be closer to you.
Understandably.
DiTomasso and his men were in the southeast corner.
We need you on the northeast building.
Good. We will do.
Caution militia. They're on the roof.
They were praying, but no longer.
Do not shoot to the east.
Eversmann? It's Yurek.
No Nelson and Twombly with me.
We saw the helicopter. Where are you?
We at sudur southwest. You from anywhere? You do not what?
Ya.
Do not shoot. We will be approaching.
We have to go.
Shawn, listen! Sergeant Yurek will run first.
As he crossed the street, he would turn around and protect you when you run.
Listen carefully. When I got there, you'll turn around and protect me.
Do not run straight toward Eversmann.
You're going to stop and protect me.
It is important for you to understand.
All right, you ready?
Yes, I guess.
- Do not forget. - What?
Do not forget.
I saw them, Sgt. They came from the west gate.
I see them.
Let's move.
Can you protect us, Sergeant?
We protect you.
Nelson!
Shit!
Twombly!
Smith! Do not!
You okay?
Remove from me!
Let go!
Come on, friend. Come on.
Dock! Smith here need help!
My legs!
Come on, Jamie, I got you!
Lift, one, two, three.
- You do not have anything. - I need some pressure on this wound.
My right thigh!
Pressure, yes.
- Zakarku still exist? - Zakarmu still there.
I need more people here.
Twombly! Nelson!
I need the chair.
- It really hurts! - Direct pressure on the wound.
It's okay.
- Let me see it! - Good.
Okay, so I checked.
Shit!
- What's that? - It's okay.
Hold the wound. I need medical evacuation now.
Galentine!
It's okay
Galentine! I connect with Captain Steele!
- Sergeant Ruiz, how are you? - Juliet 64, answer. Change.
They will not come to help us.
You must survive, Sgt. You need to focus.
- Can you do it? - Juliet 64, answer. Change.
You can hold your gun?
Yes, Sir.
Whoever passed that door, shot twice in the chest and once in the head.
- You understand? - I'm still ready to fight, sir.
Captain Steele, I need a medical evacuation here, now!
- Corporal Smith was shot! - Hold on, 25.
I'm still ready to fight.
He was injured very badly.
25, we are also a lot of casualties. You have to endure. Change.
If I can help in a half hour, he is in danger!
C-2, here 64.
Requesting medical evacuation for the wounded very badly at the location Regu 4. Change.
Command, Team Four Star requested medical evacuation.
Can not. It's too risky.
Captain, we can not send a medical evacuation at this time. Hold on. Change.
25, here 64. The medical evacuation is not possible.
JOC not want to lose the helicopter again. You must endure.
All right. I held.
I want direct pressure on the wound.
Not any.
I think this is mine!
Here Kilo 11. I was on location Durant fell.
Be accepted.
Location fall both already secured.
Lieutenant Colonel Cribbs contact you, sir.
Cribbs?
SAFE ZONE - PAKISTAN STADIUM 10th Mountain and UN Base
- They're still debating the route. - How long?
At least two hours.
We have no time for it, Joe.
Said Gen. Pakistan, because we did not tell about the attack ...
... Will take time to mobilize the 10th Mountain and 100 vehicles.
Tell this to the general ...
I understand, but it was my duty to remind him ...
... Troops besieged thousands of armed Somali militia.
It's important to take them out of enemy territory to the safe zone.
I need help now.
Good, Sir.
Durant.
Michael Durant.
Ya.
You Ranger who kills my people?
I'm not a Ranger. I am a pilot.
Correct.
You Americans do not smoke anymore.
You live long, boring, uninteresting.
What do you want with me?
You bring the hostages.
We menyanderamu.
My government would never negotiate for me.
Then maybe we can both negotiate, is not it?
Inter soldiers.
I'm not authorized.
Certainly not. You have the power to kill, not to negotiate.
In Somalia, killing is negotiation.
You really think if General Aidid captured ...
... We'll drop the weapon ...
... And apply the American democracy?
That the killing will end?
We know this: Without victory can not be peace.
There will always be murder.
That's the rule in our world.
Mike Durant, we will not leave.
You must take my place. Both hands.
His femoral vein, but I could not see.
This means that the vein was drawn to the hip bone.
Must I found and pinned. The only way to stop the bleeding.
I do not have drip again.
So, I'll need you to stand beside me.
Ya.
Listen, Jamie. I had to do something that will be painful.
Your pain will increase, but I must do to help you.
You understand?
- Morphine. - Can not.
That would weaken the heartbeat. Sorry.
Twombly, why do not you catch hold of his hand?
Open wounds, keep the pressure on the foot.
Yurek, pegangkan kaki dan senternya.
In my count.
It's okay, Jamie.
One. Two.
Three.
Wait. I feel it.
I feel the pulse.
I found.
Yes, I've found.
- I found it. - You found him?
Clamp?
Should kujepit.
- Hold. - Good.
This, catch sinews.
- Sinews would tear. - It's getting.
- Doc, sinews would be interested! - Hold!
Want to tear!
- Good. Hold the wound. - While I held.
Minggirkan hands.
What is wrong?
Already repaired?
Yes. Already we're fixing.
What are you doing?
Milling determine, Sgt. There should not be too coarse or too fine.
Grimesy, you look calm.
Sergeant, like coffee warm?
Kopi Gold Coast.
Sit down. I wanted to check it away.
- It is okay. - Come on.
- Where did they find you? - Behind the counter.
Very. You think I'm kidding?
- There is taxable? - We're okay!
You guys okay?
Ya!
Everything is alright?
Look out!
Keep shooting. Faster!
DiTomasso shot! Evacuate him!
Ranger is here. Here Kilo 11.
Team Four. We are in the southeast corner of the site crashed. Who is this?
The Hoot. I came with 3 friends.
I need fire protection. Change.
Well, Kilo 11. Hold your fire! Team Delta will come.
Hold your fire!
Ground personnel have to mark target positions with infrared.
Tell helicopters patrolled all night.
If we do not hold this town ...
... There will be 100 coffins to be filled tomorrow morning.
Yes, Sir.
Colonel Harrell, ground personnel at the site of the first fall ...
... Will mark the target with infrared preparation for air strikes.
STADIUM PAKISTAN
McKnight.
Between the 10th Mountain and UN, we got enough personnel, right?
Danny, you guys do not have to go back there again.
At 23:23 hours
I can not die here.
You're not going to die.
Forgive me.
There is nothing to forgive.
You saved Twombly. You're doing a great job.
You do not have any, Twombs?
I'm all right, Jamie.
You act accordingly trained.
You should be proud of it.
Be proud of it.
- Home? - Or.
Help me.
Tell my parents that I fought bravely today.
That I fought very persistent.
You would like to own them.
Did you hear?
Understand?
- Jeep had arrived? - They're on the way, Jamie.
They will come.
You hang on a minute.
- Hold on a minute. - I can.
I can.
This is not nothing.
- It's not nothing. - It's nothing.
It's nothing.
Shit.
Hold the wound.
Doc.
It's fine.
What are you doing?
We need ammunition.
You've tried everything you can.
They should have sent a medical evacuation.
It should be at this time we were out there maintaining the helicopter crashed.
More people will get hurt.
Maybe.
You're thinking. Do not.
Because you can not control who is shot or not, Sergeant.
Who falls from a helicopter or why.
It's not up to you. It's war.
Yes, but Smith still dead.
- It's all because Blackburn fell. - It should be possible not important.
You will have time think about it later. Trust me.
Sergeant, you're led anggotamu so far.
You did the right thing today.
You have to think about how to bring them out of here.
Should we help?
Place the four shooters in this corner!
RPG!
Here Barber 52 in position for shooting.
Oh, my God. Look at that.
Here 25! I can see you. You're right on top of me.
Eversmann, I can not distinguish people down there. Too much activity.
Target will I give the signal! Change.
Be accepted.
Do you see it?
I can not see anything.
- Will threw it to the roof. - You'll need help!
Protect me.
We will provide cover fire for him on the count of three!
Ready?
One.
Two.
Three. Come on!
I have seen the position and your target. We will be closer and shoot.
C-2, the bullets run out. Asked permission to return to base. Refill. Change.
Be accepted. The second team on the way replace you.
Four minutes to get to your location again.
They're here. Prepare the injured to be moved.
Give covering fire!
I think I heard a noise outside!
- Raise. We go from here. - Yes, Sir.
25, here 64. Rescuers arrived and we'll be there in five minutes.
Prepare anggotamu for withdrawal.
Good, Sir! Be accepted!
Five minutes! The convoy will arrive in five minutes!
I need ammo! Eversmann, bullets run out!
The bullet last!
2:05 pm Early Days
Convoy has arrived!
Sergeant Eversmann. I heard you guys need a ride!
Yes, Sir!
Bring out the wound and begin to raise them!
Let me memapahmu.
It is okay. I'm going my own way.
Yes, I would. Let's go!
Quick!
We remove the bodies of the pilot and then we go to the stadium.
We started to run out of space here.
Force any room available.
Okay, 10th Mountain will protect us to get out of the danger zone.
10th Mountain? No.
Sir, with respect, my Ranger troops can give protection from the rear.
We will escort you out of the danger zone and more recent vehicle.
All right, let's go from here.
Let's go.
- You're holding it? - Yes, let's.
Come on!
These cars magnet for bullets. Let's go!
We go if there had been an order, soldier.
Be careful.
Slowly.
Colonel, there's nothing there?
They were cutting across the cockpit around the body.
Will take how long? I need a real estimate.
They do not know!
Danny...
... Nothing is left out.
You understand, son?
Yes, General.
Do what you must do.
Good.
- Come on. Take him. - Already.
Bring all your equipment. Remove injured.
At 5:45 the morning Monday, October 4th
Quick!
Move! Quick!
Fuck!
Beware explosives!
- Come on! Quick! - Fast!
- Open the door, there are personnel here! - Not fit! Come on!
What is wrong?
- On top of the car? - I do not want to ride to the top!
Already full.
We ran. Straight ahead. Use the vehicle for protection.
Street! Come on!
Stop.
- Fast! - Come on! Quick!
Come on!
Get down!
Get down, Mom!
Ammunition runs out!
Sanderson, ammunition runs out!
Do you do.
- What are you doing? - Do you do.
Kurth, ayo!
Slowly.
Shit.
Three millimeters longer uric throat hit by bullets. Do not move.
Hurry.
Coffee stay a little, but I'll bring tea.
How are you, soldier?
I can not feel anything.
Check your heart rate.
Hey, Sergeant.
Captain.
Lorenzo. How are you?
Bullet translucent. Medical interpreter said, I will recover in a few days.
That's good news.
We will strike again?
Certainly. We must reorder strength.
Jangan pergi tanpaku.
Jangan pergi ke sana tanpaku.
I can still do my job.
You must rest.
You're going back?
There is still our colleagues there.
Fuck.
When I got home ...
... People ask me ...
"Hey, Hoot, why did you do it?"
"You're sort of addicted to war?"
I will not say a word.
Why?
They will never understand.
They will not understand why we do this.
They will not understand this about the fellow next to us.
Only that.
That is all.
Never thought about it. I should go alone.
We start the new week. It's Monday.
I was talking to Blackburn a few days ago ...
... And he asked, "What's changed? Why are we going home?"
And I answered, "Nothing."
But it's not true. I think everything changed.
I know I have changed.
A friend of mine asked me before I came here.
It was when we were assigned.
She asked me.
"Why did you join the war of others?"
"You think you're a hero?"
At that time I did not know what to say ...
... But when he was asked again, I will answer no.
I'll answer at all.
Nobody wants to be a hero.
Sometimes just happens.
I'll talk to your mother's father when I returned home.
During the raid was 1,000 Somali militiamen and 19 US soldiers Autumn.
My dear, you'll feel strong and good in life.
I love you very much as well as children.
Today and tomorrow, let each day grow and grow.
Keep smiling and do not give up even when things are very difficult.
So, in conclusion, my dear ...
... Tonight snooze children in the warmth.
Say I love them. Then they hug me ...
... And give them a kiss goodnight from their father.
Sergeant Gary Gordon and Randy Shugart is the First Warrior Which Accept ...
... Medal of Honor posthumously Since the Vietnam War.
Michael Durant captured Freed After 11 Days.
Two Weeks Later, President Clinton ...
... Interesting Delta Force and Ranger From Somalia.
Major General William F. Garrison Accepting full responsibility ...
.... Top Results raid.
2 August 1996, Mohamed Farrah Aidid in Mogadishu killed.
The day morning, Gen. Garrison pension.
--- Penerjemah: Rizal Adam ---
http://rizaladam.wordpress.com