Hit me with some syrup.
Jack, I'll be right with you.
Here you go.
You got the sausage,
and pancakes for you.
He's over there.
- Decaf or regular?
- Regular, please.
You're young to be smoking.
It ruins your sex drive.
I'll get it!
I got it! Hello?
We're out of here tonight,
housewife.
I have to ask Darryl.
You mean you haven't
asked him yet?
Thelma, is he your husband
or your father?
It is just two days,
for God's sake.
Tell him you're going with me.
Say l'm having
a nervous breakdown.
Darryl already thinks
you're out of your mind.
- Are you at work?
- No, the Playboy mansion.
I'll call you right back.
Darryl?
Honey, you better hurry up.
Goddamn it, Thelma!
Don't holler like that.
I can't stand it
when you holler in the morning.
I'm sorry, doll.
I didn't want you to be late.
Thank you.
- Hon...
- What?
Have a good day at work today.
Jesus. Thank you, no.
Hon?
What?
You want anything special
for dinner tonight?
No, Thelma. I don't give a shit.
I may not make it home.
You know how Fridays are.
Yeah. Funny how so many people
buy carpets on a Friday night.
You'd think they'd forget
about it for the weekend.
Well, then, it's a good thing
you're not regional manager
and I am.
Ooh, yeah.
I've got to get
the hell out of here.
Jesus!
Goddamn it, Homer!
I've got to get to work!
I don't need this bullshit!
I'll get them. Thank you.
For Christ's sakes!
I want you out of here by 5:O0.
No, get out of here by 3:00.
Good morning.
- Good morning. Is Louise in?
- Yes, she is.
Thelma, run away with me.
She's running away with me.
What did he say?.
When are you picking me up?
All right! Around 2:3O.
OK. What kind
of stuff do I bring?
Warm stuff, I guess.
It's the mountains.
I'm bringing everything.
OK. I will, too, then.
- Steal Darryl's fishing stuff.
- I don't know how to fish.
Darryl does it.
How hard can it be?
See you in a bit.
OK. All right. Bye.
Hi. This is Jimmy.
I'm not here now.
Thelma, we don't
need the lantern.
The place has electricity.
- I'll take it in case.
- In case of what?
There's some psycho
killer on the loose
who cuts the electricity off
and tries to kill us.
Sure. Then that
lantern will come in handy.
Maybe we should tow
your car behind, too,
in case he steals spark plugs.
We'd have to. It barely
makes it down the driveway.
Careful.
All right. Everything in?
Yeah.
Careful.
Here you go. Be careful!
All right.
Smile.
See you later!
Sit down.
Oh, Louise.
Take care of this gun.
Why in hell did you bring that?
Psycho killers, bears, snakes.
I just don't know how to use it.
Put it away. Put it in my purse.
Thelma, good Lord.
So whose place is this again?
It's Bob's, the day manager's.
He's getting divorced.
His wife's getting this place.
He's letting friends use it
till he turns over the keys.
I've never been
out of town without Darryl.
How come Darryl let you go?
Because I didn't ask him.
Shit, Thelma.
Why...he's going to kill you!
Well, he'd never let me go.
He never lets me
do one goddamn thing.
He wants me around the house
while he's doing God knows what.
Well, you get
what you settle for.
I left him a note.
I left him stuff to microwave.
Thelma.
Thelma, what are you doing?
Smoking.
Hey...l'm Louise.
Can't we stop somewhere
for a minute?
We'll get there
after dark as it is.
Then what difference
would it make if we stop?
I never get to do
stuff like this.
OK, but it's a quick stop.
OK!
Haven't seen a place like this
since I left Texas.
Isn't this fun?
- Do y'all want a drink?
- No, thanks.
I'll have a wild turkey
and a Coke back.
Thelma.
Is this my vacation or isn't it?
God, you're as bad as Darryl.
Sorry. I'm not used
to seeing you this way.
You're usually so sedate.
I've had it up
to my ass with sedate.
You said we'd let our hair down.
Darlin', my hair is coming down.
All right.
I changed my mind.
I'll have a margarita
and a shot of Cuervo.
All right. Get me another one.
Hey! What are you
kewpie dolls doing here?
- Trying to have fun.
- Minding our business.
Louise is mad
at her boyfriend because...
We just wanted
to get something to eat.
You come to the right place.
They got good chilli.
Harlan, you bothering
these poor girls?
I was being friendly.
It's a good thing they're not
all as friendly as you.
Your name's Harlan?
- I got an uncle Harlan.
- Is he a funny uncle?
If he is, he and I
got something in common.
I don't mean to be rude.
I've got to talk
to my friend in private.
I understand.
I didn't mean to bother you.
It's hard not to notice
such pretty ladies.
You better dance
with me before you leave,
or I'll never forgive you.
Sure. That would be fun.
Jeez, Louise, that wasn't nice.
He was hitting on you.
So what if he was?
- Waiting has made you jaded.
- Maybe.
Well, relax.
You're making me nervous.
All right!
I woke up in a hotel,
I didn't know what to do
I turned the TV on...
That's a good band.
They was talkin'
about a dragnet
Said they were
lookin' for a Cadillac...
- I wonder if Darryl is home.
- Wonder if Jimmy's back.
Tell him to get lost.
Why don't you
ditch your husband?
This one's on Harlan.
Thanks.
Jimmy will come off the road.
You won't be there.
He'll call you 10O,00O times.
Sunday night you'll call him.
By Monday he'll kiss
the ground you walk on.
Exactly.
In the meantime,
you said we'd have fun.
- All right.
- OK!
All right.
Let's dance.
I woke up in a hotel,
I didn't know what to do
I turned the TV on
and wrote a letter to you
They was talking
about a dragnet
Up on the interstate
Said they were
lookn' for a Cadillac
With Tennessee plates
Ma'am, want to dance some?
Since I left California, baby,
things have gotten worse
Seems the land of opportunity,
for me is just a curse
Tell that judge in Bakersfield
my trial will have to wait
Down there they're
lookn' for a Cadillac
With Tennessee plates
She sawhm singin' once
when she was 17
And eversince that day
she's been livin' in-between...
You've got great moves, honey.
Anyway, he wouldn't care
Hell, he gave them
to his friends
All right!
Here we go!
Hey, now, baby,
you're looking so fine
Cruisng around
in your Mercury '49
Isn't that enough, baby
lsn't that enough, baby
Don't drive
where you're looking
Cooln'on down the line
Thelma!
I'm hitting
the little girls' room,
then we're out of here.
I'm ready when you are.
Wait. Louise,
I want to come with you.
- I don't feel so good.
- What's wrong? Come on.
Stop.
I'm spinning.
Oopsy-doopsy. You need
some fresh air, little lady.
Look, did you see my friend?
Your friend? Yeah,
she's out there dancing.
How are you feeling now,
darling?
Oh, thanks. I'm starting to feel
a little better.
You're starting
to feel good to me, too.
I think I need to keep walking.
Wait a minute. Where do
you think you're going?
- I'm going back inside.
- Oh, no.
- Harlan!
- What?
Hey, quit it!
Stop it.
Thelma, I won't hurt you, OK?
I just want to kiss you.
No...
Come on.
Goddamn, you are gorgeous!
Let me go.
- I'm married.
- I'm married, too.
I don't feel good.
I've been sick.
I said I won't
hurt you, all right?
Harlan, stop it!
Please! I mean it!
I mean it! Louise will
wonder where I am.
Fuck Louise!
Never fucking hit me,
you bitch!
You hear me?
- Don't hurt me!
- Shut up!
Shut the fuck up!
Please don't hurt me, Harlan!
Goddamn bitch!
Let her go!
Get out of here.
Let her go, fucking asshole,
or I'll splatter
your face over this car.
Goddamn.
All right, calm down.
We were just having fun.
You got a real fucked-up
idea of fun.
Come on.
Turn around.
In the future...
when a woman's crying like that,
she isn't having any fun!
It's OK.
Bitch!
I should have fucked her!
What did you say?.
I said, "Suck my cock."
Oh, my God!
- Get the car.
- Jesus, Louise, you shot him.
Get the car.
Watch your mouth, buddy.
Louise, come on.
Watch it, you fucking asshole!
Louise?
Louise, where are we going?
I don't know.
Just shut up so I can think.
Shouldn't we go to the cops?
We ought to tell the police.
What should we tell them?
- Just tell them what happened.
- Which part?
All of it.
That he was raping me.
10O people saw you
dancing with him.
Who'll believe that? We don't
live in that kind of a world!
Goddamn it! Pull over!
Oh, great.
Thelma, l'm going to...
I'll stop for coffee -
just for a second -
and then l'm going
to get it together and...
I'll figure out what to do,
and everything's
going to be fine.
Now's not the time to panic.
Nobody saw it.
Nobody knows it was us,
so we're still OK.
We just have to figure out
what to do next.
what we're gonna do.
I'll say one thing...
this is some vacation.
I'm sure having a good time.
This is fun.
If you weren't so concerned
with fun, we wouldn't be here!
What is that supposed to mean?
It just means, shut up, Thelma.
So this is all my fault, is it?
I have to go to the bathroom.
Sorry.
Thanks. I'll try again later.
Get back, people. Stand away
from the line, please.
Could you identify them
if you saw them again?
I could identify them,
but they're not
the type to pull this.
You're not exactly an expert.
What makes you so sure?
If waiting tables doesn't make
you an expert in human nature,
nothing will.
I knew Harlan would end up
buying it in a car park.
I'm surprised
it didn't happen sooner.
- Who do you think did it?
- I hope it was his wife.
Do you have any ideas
or don't you?
I'd say it was some gal,
some gal's husband.
It wasn't one of those two.
The smaller one
with the tidy hairdo,
she left me a huge tip.
- Well...
- What?
Did you notice
what car they were driving?
It's a nightclub, Hal,
not a drive-in.
I don't follow customers
to the parking lot.
Lena, go on home.
You kept me here all night
to ask me the same
question over and over?
Aren't you going to offer me
some itty-bitty little drink?
Behave yourself.
Neither of those two
was the murdering type, Hal.
This is Jimmy.
Thelma, you in there?
Thelma, come on.
The Dow Jones dropped over
12 points today, closing at...
We're going to need money.
How much do you have on you?
- What?
- We'll stop at the next town.
We'll get a motel room,
rest, then decide what to do.
OK. Wait. I'm looking.
$61.
Shit.
$41.
We're going to need more money.
Why are you unpacking?
You said we was
going to take a nap.
I'm trying to figure out
what to do.
Well, when you figure it out,
just wake me up.
What the hell's wrong with you?
What's that mean?
- Why are you acting like this?
- Acting like what?
How should I act
when you blow somebody away?
You could help me figure out
what to do. You could try...
I suggested we go to the police.
But you didn't like that!
What's the big rush, Thelma?
They'll come to us.
I'm sorry.
I'm just not ready
to go to jail.
Why don't you...
Why don't you go out
to the pool or something?
I'll figure out what to do.
Jimmy, this is Louise.
- I've been trying to call you.
- Louise. Hey, baby.
Where the hell are you at?
Are you all right?
Yeah. I'm fine. How are you?
Long time no see.
You sound kind of funny.
I am. Real funny.
Are you in town?
This sounds long distance.
No. I'm out of town. I'm in...
I'm in deep shit, Jimmy.
Deep Shit, Arkansas.
Louise, just tell me
what the hell is going on.
I come back,
nobody knows where you are.
Is Thelma with you?
Listen, Jimmy.
I have about $6,70O in the bank.
I know you can't get it out,
but I need that money.
Can you wire me the $6,70O,
and I'll pay you back?
What the fuck is going on,
Louise?
Listen...
Something real bad has happened.
And I can't tell you what...
Just that I did it,
and I can't undo it.
Will you help me, please?
Yeah, baby. Of course.
Where? Why can't I
bring it to you?
Jimmy...
Do you love me?
Yeah.
Never mind.
Look, just wire it
to Western Union
in Oklahoma City, OK?
- So that's where you are.
- Not yet.
Call back and I'll
tell you which office.
All right.
I'll call you in an hour.
Thelma, get in the car.
Even if they didn't do it,
they most likely witnessed it.
- Put out an APB.
- All right.
Any reason to believe
they've left the state?
That's certainly possible.
Why don't we let
the Bureau in on this?
Louise, don't get mad, OK,
but where are we going?
Oklahoma City. Jimmy's going
to wire me some money.
You talked to Jimmy?
Did you tell him? ls he mad?
No. I didn't tell him.
Darryl's been calling,
mad as a hornet.
When you call him, you've got
to not tell him anything.
Sound real normal.
I called the asshole
at 4:O0 in the morning.
He wasn't even home.
I don't know what
he's got to be mad about.
Thelma, l'm going to Mexico.
I can make it in two
and a half days if I haul ass.
Are you up to this?
It's no game.
I'm in deep shit. I've got
to know what you're gonna do.
I don't know, Louise.
I mean, I don't know
what you're asking.
Don't you start flaking out!
Every time we get in trouble,
you get blank or plead insanity
or some such shit.
Not this time.
This time things have changed.
Everything's changed.
But I'm going to Mexico.
I'm going.
Louise?
Is that the way
you answer the phone?
I was afraid I missed you.
I got it. I couldn't
cash a cheque on Saturday.
- Who did it?
- Friend of mine. Owns a club.
You didn't tell him?
I told him I was buying a car.
That's real good. Where do I go?
It's a place called
the Vagabond Motel.
It's at 1921 North, East 23rd.
It's under "Peaches."
What?
That's the codeword.
I miss you, Peaches.
Thanks, Jimmy. I appreciate it.
Ma'am, wouldn't you rather have
the large economy size?
No, that's all right.
What are you looking at?
I want you to call Darryl.
Call him?
Tell him you'll be
home tomorrow.
Will I be?
I don't know. I won't.
The newspaper.
This is Darryl.
A collect call from Thelma.
Will you accept?
Why, yes, I will, operator.
Thelma, where in
the Sam Hill are you?
I'm with Louise.
We're in the mountains.
We're fishing.
Have you lost your mind?
I leave for work, and you
take leave of your senses!
Darryl, calm down, please.
Don't get so mad.
I can explain.
See, Louise...
Hold on.
Come on. Pick it.
Shit.
God!
Christ.
We're just going
to stay there and fish.
We'll just be gone one more day.
No, you'll be back today.
Get your butt back here,
Thelma, now.
Goddamn it!
Darryl, you're my husband,
not my father.
That does it.
That Louise is a bad influence.
If you're not back here
by tonight...
Well, then, I just
don't want to say.
Go fuck yourself.
That's, good. That's just sweet.
- Shit.
- I'm sorry.
- Did I cause that?
- No, I'm sorry.
Are you OK? ls there
something I can do for you?
No. It's OK.
Crazy women.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Could I ask
where you're heading?
I'm trying to get
back to school,
and my ride fell through.
I was thinking
if you're going my way,
or I'm going your way...
We're going to Oklahoma City.
- Perfect.
- I'm not sure.
Well, I'd appreciate it much.
Well, see,
it's really not up to me.
It's not my car.
We'd have to ask my friend,
but she'd probably say no.
She's a little uptight.
Maybe it's not a good idea,
but thank you for your time.
I mean, I can ask.
It wouldn't hurt.
Well, no, it wouldn't hurt.
Louise, this young man
is on his way back to school.
Since we're going
the same direction,
we could give him a ride.
It's probably not a good idea.
Probably not,
but I appreciate your time.
You all have a good day.
Did you see how polite he is?
What?
Cheer up, now. Bye.
Fill her up.
I wish we could have
brought him with us.
What did Darryl have to say?.
He said, "I just wanted
to make sure you was all right.
"I hope you're having fun.
You deserve it.
"I love you."
So how long before
we're in goddamn Mexico?
I just didn't think it would
hurt to give somebody a ride.
Did you see his butt?
Darryl don't have a cute butt.
You could park a car
in the shadow of his ass.
I'm sorry. I'm not
in the mood for company.
Here. Find all
the secondary roads
to Mexico from Oklahoma City.
We should stay
off the interstate.
We could get on this road, 81,
and head down towards Dallas.
No. I don't want
to go through Texas.
Wait. You want to go
to Mexico from Oklahoma,
but not through Texas?
Thelma, you know how
I feel about Texas.
Louise, we're running
for our lives.
Can't you make an exception?
The only thing between
Oklahoma and Mexico is Texas!
Thelma, l'm not going
to talk about this!
Find another way, or I will!
- Understand?
- No, Louise, I don't.
How come you never told me
what happened to you there?
Look, if you shoot a guy
with his pants down,
Texas is not the place
to get caught.
Trust me!
Happy birthday, lady.
Is the manager in?
Marian, there's
a police officer here.
The other night, there was
a murder at the Silver Bullet.
A man was shot.
Some witnesses saw
a 1966 T-bird convertible
Ieaving the scene,
speeding out of the driveway.
That vehicle is
registered to Louise Sawyer,
and we have reason to believe
that your wife was the other
occupant of that car.
What?
You're standing in your pizza.
Shit!
Miss Thelma,
how come you ain't got kids?
God gives you something special,
you should pass it on.
Well, Darryl - my husband -
says he's not ready yet.
He says he's still
too much of a kid.
Prides himself
on being infantile.
He's got a lot to be proud of.
- Louise and him don't get on.
- That's putting it mildly.
He's a pig.
Did you get married
real young, Miss Thelma?
Well, I guess 18
is kind of young.
We'd been going out four years
when we got married.
- How long?
- Four years.
I never been with anybody else.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Well, if you don't mind
me saying so,
he sounds like an asshole.
That's OK. He is an asshole.
Mostly, I let it slide.
You better slow down.
That's a cop up ahead.
Maybe you've got
a few parking tickets?
We'll take you to Oklahoma City,
then you'd best be on your way.
Prints on the trunk match
those of Thelma Dickinson.
I'll be damned.
Isn't that strange?
And the husband says
a gun is missing.
She took a lot of stuff.
It looks like she maybe planned
on being gone a while.
Her husband said
she'd never touch that gun.
He got it for her
because he's out late a lot,
but he said
she'd never touch it,
just kept it in the drawer.
- What kind?
- .38.
Right. Where are they?.
They left for some guy's cabin.
Now, I'm going...
Listen up, you two.
It'll just take a minute.
Say your good-byes.
Hi. I'm here to pick up
a money order for Louise Sawyer.
There's nothing.
How about Peaches?
Could you try codeword Peaches?
Did I hear somebody
say "Peaches?"
My God. Jimmy.
That's the secret word.
Show the lady what she's won.
What are you doing here?
I just came to see you, baby.
Can I have another room, please?
Put it on my credit card.
Thelma, get your foot down.
- Look who's here.
- Oh, shit! Jimmy! Hi.
What are you doing here?
Ask me no questions
and I'll tell you no lies.
Same goes double for me.
Who's the cowboy?
This is JD. He's...
He's gone.
We're giving him a ride to here.
Louise said he'd have to go,
so that's what he's doing.
Yep. That's what I'm doing.
He's gone.
- Have a good trip.
- Thank you. Nice meeting you.
Yep. That's him going.
I love watching him go.
Thelma kind of tookto him.
I got you a room, Thelma.
Take a nice cold shower.
I'm just a wild woman.
It's our future.
What will you tell him?
Nothing. I'm not going
to tell him a thing.
The least I can do is not make
him more of an accessory.
You are so sweet to that guy.
Imagine not wanting
to drag him into this.
I didn't invite him.
He's like any guy.
He loves the chase.
He's got his work cut out
for him now, don't he?
Put a lid on it!
Now...l want you to just...
You guard that money.
OK.
And if there's any problem,
call me in room 211.
I won't wait up.
- You want a drink?
- No.
Why don't you tell me
what's going on?
I'm not going to tell you.
Some day soon
you'll understand why I can't.
Can I ask you one thing?
Maybe.
Do you love somebody else?
Does this have something
to do with another man?
No, it's not anything like that.
What is it? Are you
gonna leave for fucking ever?
Did you fucking kill somebody?
You start this shit,
I'm out of here.
I'm sorry.
Come back and sit down.
I want to give you something.
I'm fine right here.
Give it to me here.
Here.
Why don't you try it on?
You didn't see
that one coming, did you?
Why, Jimmy?
Why now?
Try not to get
too excited, Louise.
I just flew across two states
with that ring
in my fucking hand,
and you know I hate to fly.
You came all this way
because you thought
I was with somebody else.
No. That's not why I came.
Because, you know,
I don't want to lose you.
I feel like you'll split.
That's not a good reason
to get married.
I thought
that's what you wanted.
I did...but not like this.
No, Thelma. It's me.
Surprise.
I was just out there,
and I was thinking...
I know I'm supposed to be
gone and all but, you know...
And I'm not having
a turd's luck getting a ride.
I was just thinking about you.
This is crazy.
I'm going to get
out of your hair.
Well, wait.
Where are you going?
I don't know. You know, nowhere.
You think I'm happy playing
one-night gigs in Ramada lnns?
I have dreams.
We got what we settled for.
I think maybe you don't
love me any more.
No. I do love you.
But I think it's time to just...
Iet go of the old mistakes.
Just chalk it up to...
bad timing.
I think it's time to let go.
Come on. You're too...
- All right. Your turn.
- Your turn.
Come on.
Don't leave...
just leave them there.
This is an unfair advantage.
You got too much
metal going here.
Want to lighten
the load a little?
I think that's better.
What do you think? Yeah.
Take me, break me, make me mad.
- Watch your head.
- I'm all right.
Who are you, anyway?.
The great and powerful Oz.
Who do you want to be?
You're not just some schoolboy.
Nobody ever tells me shit.
I'm just some guy,
a guy whose parole officer
is probably having a shit-fit.
What do you mean,
parole officer?
Are you a criminal?
No, not no more, Thelma.
Besides busting parole,
I haven't done one wrong thing.
- What'd you do?
- I'm a robber.
- You're a bank robber?
- No. I don't rob no banks.
What did you rob?
Well, let's see.
Let's add it up here.
Robbed a gas station,
a couple convenience stores,
liquor stores.
Oh, my God.
How?.
Come on.
OK. First, you pick your place.
Then I sit back and watch it
for a little while,
wait for that right moment
to make my move.
That shit cannot be taught.
And... Shit, I don't want
to talk about this.
I do.
All right.
Then l'd waltz right in.
Yep. I just waltz
on in and I say,
"Let's see who wins the prize
for keeping their cool.
"Everybody on the floor."
"Nobody lose their head,
and nobody loses their head.
"You, sir, you do the honours.
"Put the cash in a bag and you
got a great story to tell.
"If not, you got
a tag on your toe. You decide."
Simple as that.
Then I just slip on out
and get the hell out of Dodge.
My goodness. You were
gentlemanly about it
I've always believed,
if done properly,
armed robbery doesn't have to be
a totally unpleasant experience.
- What?
- You're a real live outlaw.
I may be an outlaw, darling,
but you're the one
stealing my heart.
- Smooth.
- Oh, isn't he?
- You're smooth.
- Isn't he? That's right.
I like it that way.
Remember when we first met?
Yeah.
Tell me what you said.
I said you had
a nice pair of eyes.
And what did I say?
Do you remember?
Yeah. You shut them,
asked me if I knew
what colour they were.
And what did you say?.
I didn't know.
Jimmy, what colour
are my eyes?
They're brown.
You want some more coffee?
Look, I don't know
what's going on with you
or what happened
or what you all did,
but I'm not going
to tell anybody anything,
or say I even saw you.
Did you take some pill that
makes you say the right stuff?
Yeah. I'm choking on it.
Sure you don't
want me to go with you?
It's probably not
a real good idea right now,
but I'll catch up
with you later...
on down the road.
Well...my taxi's here.
So why don't you
just keep that?
- OK?
- Thanks.
I just want you to be happy.
I am happy, sweetie.
Happy as I can be.
All right.
Well, why don't you give
old Jimmy a kiss goodbye,
and I'll be getting
out of here.
Come here, old Jimmy.
I'll be seeing you, Louise.
You have a safe trip.
Good thing he left when he did.
We thought we'd have
to put out a fire.
What happened to your hair?
Nothing. Got messed up.
Thelma, what's wrong with you?
Nothing. Why?
Do I seem different?
Now that you mention it, yeah.
You seem like
you're crazy or on drugs.
Well, I'm not on drugs,
but I might be crazy!
Thelma, what happened?
- What happened?
- JD came back.
My God, Louise.
- Oh, no.
- I just can't believe it.
No!
Oh, my God, it's like...
I finally understand
what all the fuss is about.
It's like a whole
'nother ball game.
Darling, I'm so happy
for you, I really am.
You finally got laid properly.
That's so sweet.
- Where is he?
- He's taking a shower.
You left him alone in the room?
Where's the money?
- Oh, my God.
- It's on the bed table.
It's OK!
It's on the nightstand.
Oh, goddamn it!
I have never been lucky,
not one time!
Shit! That son-of-a-bitch
burgled me.
I don't believe it.
You OK?
I'm sorry. I mean it.
Louise, it's OK.
- It's OK.
- No, Thelma, it's not OK.
It's definitely not OK.
None of this is OK.
I mean, what are we going
to do for money?.
How are we going to get gas?
I mean,
trading on our good looks?
I mean... Oh, goddamn,
Thelma, it's not OK.
Now, you listen to me.
Don't you worry about it.
You hear me? Come on!
Stand up.
Louise, just don't you
worry about it. You hear?
Come on.
Come on, damn it!
Let's get out of here.
Move! Jesus Christ, come on.
Come on.
Take your damn time.
Afraid of a little rain, Matt?
Well, come on in.
Wipe your feet.
As you know, we've tapped
your phone in case she calls.
- Is that going to cost me?
- Excuse me. May l?
Live it up.
That's what it's there for.
We'll have someone here
on the phones till we find them.
Don't let on
you know anything.
We want to find out
where they are.
I don't want to get personal,
but do you two
have a good relationship?
I love Thelma.
I don't intend anything
by that, sir.
I have to ask.
Are you close with her?
Yeah. I guess.
As close as I can be
to a nutcase like that.
Yeah, well, if she calls,
just be gentle.
You know, like you're
really happy to hear from her.
Like you really miss her.
Women love that shit.
OK. If you say so.
Oh, cool. Can I wear these?
Want anything?
Drive, Louise!
Drive the car!
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
What happened?
You robbed the store?
You robbed the goddamn store?
Well, we needed the money!
It's not like I killed anybody.
We needed money. Now we have it.
Oh, shit! Oh, shit, Thelma!
Louise, come on, get a grip.
Drive us to Mexico.
OK. Oh, shit.
How did you...
I mean, what did you say?.
I just waltzed
on in there, and I said...
This is a robbery.
If nobody loses their head,
nobody will lose their head.
If you would all
lie down on the floor, please.
Who will win a prize
for keeping their cool?
Sir, would you do the honours?
Put the cash in that bag.
You're going to have a great
story to tell your friends.
Or you'll have a tag
on your toe. You decide.
Hurry up.
Ma'am, would you be quiet?
Sir, get down, please.
Just get real comfortable.
Throw in a couple bottles
of Wild Turkey.
Yes, ma'am.
Now you get down, too.
Thank you all
for your cooperation.
Stay on the floor,
and have a good day.
Jesus Christ.
- Good God!
- My Lord.
Hey, Louise,
you better slow down.
I'd die if we get caught
over a speeding ticket.
For the first time,
I wish this car wasn't green.
Should we be driving
in broad daylight?
I want to put some
distance between us
and the scene
of our last goddamn crime!
Oh, man, you wouldn't
have believed it.
It was like l'd been
doing it all my life.
- Think you found your calling?
- Maybe. Maybe.
The call of the wild!
- You are disturbed!
- I believe I am.
Thelma, don't you litter.
Shoot! This always happens
when you're in a hurry.
You going to stay drunk all day?
Try to.
Oh, isn't that nice?
Truck drivers
are always so nice.
Oh, look. How original.
- Man, that's disgusting!
- You pig. Just a fucking pig.
- What's he got to do that for?
- They think we like it.
They think it turns us on.
- James Lennox?
- Yeah. Who wants to know?
Arkansas State Police.
What?
- Call Darryl.
- What for?
Find out if he knows anything.
If you think he does, hang up,
because the phone's
probably tapped.
Tapped the phone?
What are you talking about?
Come on! Murder one
and armed robbery?
We can't even say
it was self-defence?
- It wasn't. We walked away.
- But they don't know that.
I'll say he raped me
and you had to shoot him.
- It won't work.
- Why not?
There's no physical evidence.
We can't even prove by now
that he touched you.
God! The law is some
tricky shit, isn't it?
How do you know
about all this stuff?
What would we say
about the robbery?.
There's no such thing
as justifiable robbery.
All right!
Where did you get this?
Stole it.
- Who's the nut?
- Mrs Dickinson's husband.
Well, shit twice
and fall back in it. God!
Where did you get the $6,60O?
A friend.
A gentleman told us
he delivered close to that
amount to Louise Sawyer.
- Do you know her?
- Uh, yes, sir.
I believe she's the woman
driving the car.
He said he took her
to an Oklahoma City motel.
He says he met a man.
He identified you
from mug shots.
He also said you
and Mrs Dickinson seemed close.
Is that true?
Well, sir, you might say
we had a meeting of the minds.
Are you aware they are wanted
in connection with a murder?
Murder? What, Thelma? Damn!
Did they indicate
they were running from the law?.
Now that you mention it,
they seemed jumpy.
You know what?
What?
- You're irritating me.
- Me, too.
That will happen. You two boys
have a lot in common.
Maybe I should leave the room.
I got a better idea.
Mind if I speak to him alone?
What did I do?
Nothing, that's what.
This is a crock of shit,
Mr Johnny-fucking-law.
Son, I got a feeling
about something.
- Yeah?
- I want your opinion.
Do you think Thelma would have
committed armed robbery
if you hadn't taken their money?
Get your foot off that table.
Cat got your tongue?
No. How do you know I took it?
How do you know...
Don't fucking lie to me!
There's two girls out there
that had a chance.
You've screwed it up for them.
They're in serious trouble.
I'll hold you responsible
if anything happens to them.
I got no feeling for you.
You'll either tell me
everything you know
so there's a chance
I can help them,
or I'll be all over you
like a fly on shit.
Your misery will be
my mission in life.
Yes, sir.
- OK?
- Yeah. That's right.
We understand each other? OK.
- Mr Dickinson?
- Yeah?
Would you hang on?
I want a word with you.
I like your wife.
Come back here, you little shit!
Come here! Come here!
I'll kill you!
- What will it be, ladies?
- Fill her up. There you go.
Excuse me. Do you have a phone?
Thank you.
Thelma, listen up.
If you think he knows,
I want you to hang up.
Hello.
Darryl, it's me.
Thelma, hello!
- He knows.
- Shit!
I need more time.
What? All I said was hello.
Darryl, this is Louise.
- Let me talk to the police.
- Hey, Louise.
- There's no police here.
Where are you girls, anyway?
Will you let me talk
to whoever's in charge.
Hello, Miss Sawyer?
I'm Hal Slocombe,
Arkansas State Police.
How are you?
Well, I've been better.
- Be careful with that gun.
- Yes, sir, I know.
You girls are in some hot water.
- You both OK?
- Yes, sir. We're both fine.
Good. You want to tell me
what happened?
Sure, over coffee
some time. I'll buy.
Neither one of you
are charged with murder yet.
You're still wanted
for questioning.
Although now Mrs Dickinson
is wanted for armed robbery.
No kidding. We gotta go.
I'll call you back.
You won't make it to Mexico.
We should talk. Please.
I want to help you.
Shit.
That JD kid is a little shit.
What?
Thelma, how do they know
we're going to Mexico?
You told that thieving
little shit where we're going?
I just told him,
if he ever got to Mexico,
he should look us up.
But I asked him not to tell.
I thought he would
not tell anybody.
Why? What's he got to lose,
except my life savings.
Thelma, God damn it!
Look, l'm sorry.
We had only two things
going for us.
Nobody knew where we were
or where we were going.
Now one thing is gone!
Thelma, you got to stop
talking to people.
Stop being so open.
We're fugitives now, right?
Let's start behaving like that.
Right.
Thank you.
I was wondering...
Of course I want you to go.
That's what's worrying you.
Please don't think...
No. I knew you'd want me
to take the job, but...
Sorry.
Let's do it.
Let's get married.
- My God, this is beautiful.
- It surely is.
I always wanted to travel.
I never got the opportunity.
You got it now.
What's going on?
Nothing.
Well, we don't need
the east coast any more.
Hey, look who it is.
It's that guy.
Just ignore him.
Hey, baby! I'm your
captain muff diver!
Your storm trooper of love!
I ignored him.
What?
- What?
- Harlan.
What about him?
Nothing. Just the...
Just the look
on his face when...
What?
He sure wasn't expecting that.
"Suck my dick!"
Thelma, it's not funny.
I know.
It happened to you, didn't it?
What are you talking about?
In Texas.
I mean, that's what happened,
isn't it?
You was raped.
Look, l'm warning you.
Just drop it. I'm not
gonna talk about that.
You understand?
- Yeah.
- I'm not talking about it.
- Understand?
- Yeah. OK, Louise.
It's OK.
Shit. Thelma,
we're getting pulled over.
Shit. Shit.
- What should we do?
- I don't know!
Maybe he's just going
to give me a ticket.
Oh, God, please
don't let us get caught, God.
I'll pull over.
Turn off your engine.
He's putting on his hat.
God, he's a Nazi.
He's walking this way.
Hello, officer.
Is there a problem?
Let me see your licence, please.
Right.
Here it is.
Take it out
of your wallet, please.
All right.
I told you to slow down.
Officer, I told her
to slow down.
- How fast was I going?
- About 110.
Get out of the car, please.
Sure.
- Come with me, please.
- Yes, sir.
This your vehicle?
Yes, sir, that is.
Get in the car, please.
- Yes, sir. Front or the back?
- Front.
Want to take off
your eyewear, please?
Yes, sir.
Am I in trouble, officer?
Yes, ma'am, you're in
a lot of trouble.
This is 9-8...
Step back and get
in your car, please.
Officer, I am
so sorry about this.
Would you let go of that?
Now, I really, really apologise,
but put your hands
on the steering wheel.
If you get on that radio,
you'll find out we're wanted
in two states
and probably considered
armed and dangerous.
Then our plan's going
to be shot to hell.
Louise, take his gun.
- Take his gun, Louise.
- Right.
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
Step out of the car, please.
Three days ago,
neither of us would pull
a stunt like this,
but if you met my husband,
you'd understand why.
Put your hands on your
head, please. Louise.
- What?
- Shoot the radio.
The police radio, Louise!
- Jesus!
- Sorry.
Got it.
All right. Step to the back
of the car, please.
Louise, get the keys.
God! What happened?
Air holes.
Open the trunk.
Shit, Thelma,
who'd have thought it?
Step into the trunk, please.
Please! I have a wife and kids.
You do? Well, you're lucky.
Be sweet to them,
especially your wife.
My husband wasn't sweet to me,
look how I turned out.
Oh, wait a second. Excuse me.
Officer, could I have
your belt, please?
- Extra ammo.
- Good idea.
Could I trade glasses with you?
Thanks. Is that it?
- I'm real sorry about this.
- I apologise also.
Go.
- You ready?
- Hit it.
I know it's crazy...
but I feel like I got
a knack for this shit.
I believe you do.
Drive like hell.
I can't figure out
if these girls are real smart
or just real lucky.
Brains will only get you so far,
and luck always runs out.
Louise, are we still
going to Mexico?
Yeah.
Then aren't we going
in the wrong direction?
If you take
a state policeman's gun
and lock him in the trunk,
it's best just
to leave the state.
Don't dent my car!
I think I fucked up.
I got us in a situation
where we could get killed.
I don't know why
I didn't go to the police.
You know why. You already said.
What did I say, again?
Nobody would believe us.
We'd still have
our lives ruined.
- Know what else?
- What?
If you hadn't come out, that guy
would have hurt me a lot worse.
Probably nothing
would have happened to him.
They would've said
I asked for it.
My life would have been
ruined worse than it is now.
At least now I'm having fun.
I'm not sorry that
son-of-a-bitch is dead.
I'm sorry you did it
and not me.
- Hello.
- Let me talk to Slocombe.
She wants to talk to you.
Hello, Louise.
How are things going out there?
Weird. We got some kind
of snowball effect happening.
You're still
on the face of the earth.
We're not in the middle
of nowhere but we can see it.
I swear! Louise,
I almost feel like I know you.
- Well, you don't.
- You're getting in deeper.
This thing was an accident.
I believe you. That's what
I want everybody to believe.
Trouble is, it doesn't
look like an accident,
and you're not here
to tell me about it.
Did Harlan Puckett...
I don't want to talk about it.
- You want to come in?
- I don't think so.
Then l'm sorry. We'll have
to charge you with murder.
Do you want
to come out of this alive?
Certain words and phrases
keep drifting through my mind.
Things like incarceration,
cavity search,
death by electrocution,
life imprisonment.
Do I want to come out alive?
I don't know. I...
I don't know. We're going
to have to think about that.
Louise...I'll do anything.
I know what's making you run.
I know what happened
to you in Texas.
Come on, Louise.
Don't blow it.
- We got it.
- Give it to me.
Max, you got to take me there.
No. Sorry.
- I'm the only one...
- You're no good to me now.
I don't want anybody
losing their heads.
These girls are going
to get shot.
What?
You're not going
to give up on me?
What do you mean?
You won't make a deal
with that guy?.
I mean, I just want to know.
Thelma, l'm not
making any deals.
I'd understand
if you was thinking about it.
You got something
to go back for - Jimmy.
Jimmy's not an option.
But...l don't know...
Something's, like,
crossed over in me,
and I can't go back.
I mean... I just couldn't live.
I know. I know what you mean.
Anyway, we don't want to end up
on the damn Geraldo Show.
They're charging us with murder.
We got to figure out if we want
to come in dead or alive.
Gosh. Didn't he say
anything positive at all?
You awake?
You could call it that.
My eyes are open.
Me, too. I feel awake.
- Good.
- Wide awake.
I don't remember
ever feeling this awake.
Know what I mean?
Everything looks different.
You feel like you got
something to look forward to?
We'll be drinking margaritas
by the sea, mamacita.
We could change our names.
- We could live in a hacienda.
- I'll work at Club Med.
What deal could that cop
come up with to beat that?
- Have to be good.
- Damn good.
My God, Louise, look!
See if that's him.
It's definitely him.
Pass him.
You ready for a big dick?
Hi, there. You all right?
We're fine. How are you?
Great!
Are you girls ready
to get serious?
I think so.
Follow us.
Where are you going?
Fresno.
We've seen you all over.
Take off those shades.
I want to see your eyes.
Yeah, I been seeing you, too.
Yeah. We think you have
really bad manners.
Behaving like that
with women you don't even know!
What if someone
did that to your mom?
Or your sister? Or your wife?
What are you talking about?
You know what I'm talking about.
That business with your tongue
is disgusting.
What does pointing
to your lap mean?
"I want to show you
what a fat slob I am"?
Or "Suck my dick"?
- You women are crazy!
- Right.
We think you should apologise.
I ain't apologising for shit!
Say sorry.
Fuck that!
Say you're sorry,
or I'll make you fucking sorry.
Oh, Jesus.
I bet you called us
beavers on your radio.
Sure did.
- I hate being called a beaver.
- You going to apologise?
Fuck you!
God damn, you bitch!
- I don't think he'll apologise.
- I don't think so.
You bitches!
You bitches from hell!
Goddamn it!
You're going to have
to pay for this!
Where did you learn
to shoot like that?
Off the TV.
- Where did you learn?
- Texas.
Hello? Hello?
I'm a police officer.
The keys are over there.
Red hair, brown eyes.
5' 7" tall, 120 pounds.
Suspect Thelma Lauren Dickinson.
I got this guy running
around a burning truck.
Red hair, green eyes.
5'10" tall.
Both subjects armed
and extremely dangerous.
Approach with caution.
..on felony warrants
for armed robbery,
kidnapping
a law-enforcement officer,
assault with a deadly weapon.
Suspect driving,
Louise Elizabeth Sawyer.
Think they saw us?
I don't think so.
Get off just in case.
Got your seat belt on?
This is 112 in pursuit
of a green Thunderbird.
Oh, shit.
I have the suspects in sight.
Stay in position.
This is all my fault.
You should know by now
it wasn't.
Louise, no matter what happens,
I'm glad I came with you.
Shit.
He was in the middle
of the road!
Hold on!
- Everything will be shitty now.
- Unbearable.
- Nothing left to lose.
- You're so positive!
You're a good friend.
You, too, sweetie.
How do you like
the vacation so far?
I guess I went a little crazy.
You've always been crazy.
This is just your first chance
to express yourself.
Good drivin'.
Thanks.
- Oh, my God!
- What the hell is this?
I don't know.
I think it's
the goddamn Grand Canyon.
Isn't it beautiful?
Yeah. It's something
else, all right.
My God. It looks like the army.
All this for us?
Don't let them
shoot those girls.
This is too much.
These women are armed, Hal.
These boys know
what they're doing.
Place your hands in plain view.
Failure to obey that command
will be considered an act
of aggression against us.
I repeat -
turn your engine off.
Place your hands in plain view.
- What are you doing?
- I'm not giving up.
You've got to do something.
How many times
must they be fucked over?
Pull yourself together.
Don't make me
sorry I brought you!
Damn it!
Cut your engine off and place
your hands in plain view.
OK, then, listen.
Let's not get caught.
What are you talking about?
Let's keep going.
What do you mean?
Go.
You sure?
Yeah. Hit it.