Varel industries always trying...
that it should take the video games
world beyond than 3-d technology.
Did you ever think when you send
some data from one phone to another,
then how did it reach to across
the corner of the world.
In the world of satellite, mobiles
and internet...
so many rays and frequencies lives
around us,
they have surrounded in our world like
a virtual world.
And this world always surrounding us.
Everywhere...
in shopping malls, houses...
on the streets in fact right now
in this conference room,
and as you know because of these
rays entire digital world travels...
because mr. Barel couldn't come
to meet you,
that's why he sent me his
welcome photo.
Now the matter is that...
can i bring this photo to this room
without any computer...
because our technology is about that.
It's not some magic, projection
or 3-d techonology.
It has been made from those rays what
are always surroundings by you,
but you can't see them,
but with our techonology you can see
that and touch as well.
What can remove the difference between
the real and virtual world.
That night was so beautiful.
And that girl too,
night was waiting for the dawn,
and the girl was waiting for me,
waiting for me.
I am lucifer.
Sometimes you have to take life to
save life.
And the most three bruce lee's friend
was ready to get killed.
Then the fight was...
from the big daddy.
He was the only one who could
fight with me,
not a hero but villain,
what should i do?
Every girl likes me,
i don't like unexpectable guests...
bad time always come unexpected,
do you know who am i?
I just killed spiderman,
from baygon spray.
What kind of insect you are?
You always make punch lines...
or punch too?
Both of them!
People applause on one,
and it only screw up on other one.
Be carefull!
Don't worry my desi girl.
Let me handle him then
how about dinner.
Sure! But where?
Wherever you say,
not only chinese,
i just had it,
if your story is ever,
then shall we start the fight,
he have such a big gun,
you guys have started again,
get up!
But i can't talk on phone,
don't talk to me on phone and drive
your car with concentration,
what's happening in office today?
I am not fond of to see your faces
in the morning,
i just want to tell you that our
company got a contract of game,
and this game will be release
in india,
but this department's previous
two games...
were totally flopped,
and if this game will be flop...
then i will have to shut this
department down,
i won't suspend anyone,
because i am about to open
a restaurant here,
you and you will become waiter.
And i will make you main cook.
Because you will serve
marathi dishes here.
Does anyone have any problem?
I have a problem,
and what's your problem?
I can't make idaly.
Dosa?
I can make dosa.
You are working really hard,
i know you are not taking
me seriously.
But when my book will be in
best seller's list.
Then you will see...
you don't know these thesis are
really important for me,
how necessary is for india,
how necessary is for every
indian girl.
You are sonia subhramaniam not
sonia gandhi,
why every abuse is like that in india.
When my thesis will be over,
then every indian woman...
you are crossing the limits.
Will proudly say...
why the song is so loud?
I am not singing,
i am just saying that...
not you.
Can't you lower the volume?
Ofcourse it could be lower,
tell us about your new
video game,
it's totally a new game and it
has a new hero.
Heroes are boring either they
are new or old.
You don't like heroes then who
do you like? Villain?
They have no rules,
all they have to win,
and if anyone comes to their
way then just bang.
Make a game where villain
never lose.
Hero always wins.
Truth always wins.
I will show you to become a dad.
Mom! What are you doing?
Come fast we have to go school.
Today your dad will drop
you to school.
If dad will drive then we will
reach to school after 2 days.
But i wanted to tell you one thing,
you like villains.
Then i will make a video game where
villain is powerful than hero.
Where villain will never lose.
Always remember one thing...
what is lucifer?
Whenever i uses this computer and
play any video game,
my name is always lucifer,
i mean miss. Boel's computer can
be connected with our computers.
Miss. Boel will ask the permission
to connect from our computer.
We all will say no,
but only one fatso will say yes.
I have such a great idea for
our new video game,
we will make the most dangerous...
hero.
Villain!
Why villain?
Because villains are kick ass.
All for prateek,
what will be our villain's name?
How long we will call him
random access version one,
it's front of your eyes.
Where?
And what's our hero's name?
What are you doing?
I need hero's face.
Very good and this smile
is amazing,
i didn't put this smile in programme,
you didn't put it.
Why ra one is smiling in game,
this programme is not learning
things by itself.
Everyone look carefully.
This is the main part of
our game.
This heart is not an heart.
It will have the strength of
every player.
After winning every level this
heart's strength will increase.
And it will become more blue.
Until this heart doesn't attached with
g one and ra one's system,
till then you can't kill
both of them,
and to break the heart these
both won't die.
Perhaps they won't die to
hit their bodies.
When their hearts will be attached
with their bodies so you can kill them,
but how they will die?
Here they will get an anti heart gun.
Which will have only one bullet.
Amongst both of them whoever will
shoot the aim first,
he will won the game,
whoever will miss his aim he
will be die.
So this heart is their strength
and their weakness as well.
See! In this film villain lost again.
That's why thos movie was a flop.
Did you see villain was so cool,
he wasn't cool but bloody fool.
He was smoking ciggarettes and
ciggarette kills...
this kid is smoking,
let's go.
No! I will talk to him,
does your mom knows you smoke?
What else you have?
I gave you everything.
You didn't see me okay?
I am heading to level 3.
Nobody can beat ra one.
Otherwise i will come to your world
and kill you.
Nobody can beat ra one.
This game will be over...
when i will finish you.
I will have to stay in lab.
There is some problem in the game.
Today you have done amazing job,
you really like the game,
yeah!
You really like that game that you
hug your dad,
i just wanted to say that game
was really amazing.
So why you didn't said it?
We live in a same house.
I can say it tomorrow.
Aakashi is saying that...
please pick up the phone.
Out from the game,
i want lucifer,
i will finish him,
are you lucifer?
Are you lucifer?
I am lucifer!
You are lying,
what happen?
Dad didn't met an accident,
ra one killed him,
game's villain!
What are you saying?
I said i am not going to india.
Listen to me,
i have to find out what happened
with dad,
your dad met an accident,
we are going to india tonight,
i am not going,
you were right,
my god! How did it happen?
Ra one said it...
that i will come out from the game
and find you,
this is the first control suit for you.
I have made a ra one like
you wanted.
But remember...
if ra one has made from a
devil thought...
then g one has been made
from my heart.
And if you will be stuck in
the game...
then my g one will show you
the right way.
It means ra one has become aakashi,
thanks for the help.
Where are you?
Ra one has killed my dad.
Ra one has become aakashi,
what are you saying?
Where are you? It's flight time.
I am in the dad's office.
You stay there i am coming.
I will try to connect again and
you try to log in,
now upload the ra one's
back up programme.
It doesn't have ra one's programme.
We have to intercept this programme
otherwise how we will stop ra one.
If ra one can come out then
g one as well...
we can try to follow up those steps
and take the g one out.
Load this programme.
Okay!
I just saw aakashi was going
upstairs...
what happen?
It was sonia's phone call,
ra one is coming upstairs...
you go from here,
no! I will must have to try it.
I will must have to take g one out.
Ra one is coming after you.
I will try because he doesn't
know me.
Why he is coming with us?
Mom! G one saved us.
Mom! G one saved us...
okay bye...
that's what i am saying.
He can't come anyway...
you will have to cover up.
I will have to cover up.
What are you doing?
I don't understand anything,
please try to understand...
i will understand it later.
First you tell me that...
how we will pass this thing from
that metal detector.
Try to understand he can't
come with us.
G one!
Can you do it...
what are you doing?
Act like ra one...
i can't do it like ra one.
Because i am not powerfull like ra one.
Shall i take off my pent?
Who made you taxi driver?
You and your taxi both will go,
do you know the rules?
Will you come with me?
What nonsense?
I will take you,
what are you doing?
He will die.
Then i will reset him again and
press the play button,
he is human not a tape recorder.
Shut up!
It's not a game if someone dies
here once
then he never come back,
he can come like human changes
his clothes...
soul can change the body and
came back,
which page?
47.
Tell him to leave him,
g one!
Leave him,
you can't touch me here,
so! Where i can touch you?
You can't touch me anywhere.
So! How would i save you?
You don't need to save me,
g one!
Help!
Why did you stop? Do something!
I will have to touch you,
then touch me,
hit the punch,
listen! You are my dad and he is
dad's friend, say hi.
You did it,
no!
What did you say?
I have shekhar's folder in
my programme,
which has many lines like that,
do you have more?
"Who says my size is bigger than
everyone"
have you ever spend a night
with a mosquito"
if you don't understand this folder,
then i can delete it,
never delete it,
g one is on stand by,
go somewhere else.
When everything will be settle down
then i will have to do something,
he can't stay with us,
not at all...
he is not a tv who be placed
in a corner,
he talks like humans,
and he looks like dad,
do you think g one was right
about geeta.
It's also possible that dad has become
g one and came to protect us,
do you remember whenever we were in
trouble what dad always said...
i have charged inverter you want
to charge something else.
Yes!
Mom's mood...
don't you ashame talking like that
in front of kid.
Go to sleep.
I don't sleep.
I do run...
do whatever you want,
now i know what i have to do
with him,
we will send him to assylum,
he is totally crazy,
why do we pray?
So god could protect us,
so god came out from there
and protect us,
no! He send his angels...
do you believe in angels?
Shut up and pray.
Who are you?
How did you enter inside?
I want lucifer.
Prateek subhramaniam,
shekhar's son.
He have my heart and i am incomplete
without my heart,
they are gone and...
their address is not in record,
what are you doing?
I am helping you to remind,
you don't need to do it,
i can read your mind,
i can change it and i can
even control it,
wife prays for her husband's life.
We have good memories from
this house,
that's why i wanted to come here,
but sonia...
we can't stay on single place longer,
we will have to leave this house,
ra one can come here anytime,
until we have ra one's heart,
he can find prateek,
if we will destroy ra one's heart he
still won't following us,
we will always keep escaping
from him,
and if don't destroy the heart so we
will have to face ra one,
this is an emotional decision,
you will have to take this decision,
finally i have this thing left,
this house, prateek and
shekhar's memories,
i won't leave this house,
i won't escape anymore,
shekhar trusted in humanity,
you won't let anything happen
to my prateek,
it's not in my programme.
But those have all these things
in their programme,
they don't do anything for others,
as much you have done for us,
what's all this?
Can't you see they are burning raavan,
why?
It's dasera!
It means raavan finish,
people burn it every year,
you burn raavan every year,
because you know he never dies,
who dies once,
you don't need to kill him over
and over again,
you are looking good in
dad's clothes.
Shekhar and mr. Lyer celebrates their
kid's birthday together
everyone knows shekhar here,
please! Don't make any trouble.
Shekhar built this game for prateek,
he said he will present him
on his birthday,
if you will present this game
to prateek,
from his dad's behalf,
then he will be very happy,
and what about you?
I will also like it,
prateek!
Nothing will happen to him.
You said this plan will work.
You can't die g one.
You also prepare to die.
We are ready.
You forgot...
until our hearts are not connected
from our system,
we both can't die.
I didn't forgot but lucifer forgot,
he needed a villain whom you
never killed,
and if you didn't choose the
real ra one...
whose the real one amongst them?
I didn't play this game yet,
no! It's not possible.
Dad will never let evil win,
there must be something in this game,
dad must have left something,
i have a folder,
check in the folder,
real ra one has a shadow,
now i will have to go,
it wasn't the plan,
it was always the plan,
it's the plan and this plan
will remain,
if we have to kill the ra one forever,
then i will have to take ra one
and go back to that world...
where we both came from,
please! Don't leave me,
i can't lose my dad again,
no! You will never lose your dad,
until you have humanity
in your heart,
you dad will always with you,
good people died,
but their humanity always remain alive,
and tell sonia...
we both killed ra one...
you know i am really happy that
you came back,
are you alright?
How is prateek?
He is busy on computer all day long,
he says he will revive
g one's heart,
don't snatch his hope from him,
by the way where is my lucifer?