Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Magic Stars Team @ Viki.com
♫ Waking up before midnight, I’m as confused as the ocean ♫
♫ The stars forget to shine ♫
♫ We were children ♫
♫ We’ve been children born on this boat ♫
♫ The ark that people talk about is like a small boat ♫
♫ You could hear whispering through deck ♫
♫ Its flag sways in rainstorms ♫
♫ But humans’ endless disputes ♫
♫ push you and me to two most distant sides with ♫
♫ heresies, extremes and abandoned regrets ♫
♫ When have that thousands of thousands layers of color ♫
♫ quietly blossomed through the end of dark night? ♫
♫ On the top of clouds, ♫
♫ that ray is like a crown. ♫
[Magic Star]
~ Episode 17 ~
Would this work?
Hey, Bai Ze, do I look like I'm of the same height as Little Hai Xing?
How about letting me do it instead?
Why do you like stealing my glory?
This time, there's no use no matter who does the convincing.
Just wait and watch me teach them a lesson.
We will all be hiding at the periphery.
Once there's danger, we'll all come over to help you.
I got it. I got it.
Little Hai Xing, you must remember these Older Brothers and Sisters.
- They are risking their lives to save you.
- Yes.
It's something that we should do.
There seems to be some movement.
Everyone just follow the plan.
A Ji Ya, hurry and hide.
Hurry and hide. Hurry and hide.
- Let's go.
- Come.
We've arrived quite early.
There is still 15 minutes left.
Gong Zi Xu Xu and the others have entered already.
When do we attack?
Just wait for a while more.
Mister, he's trembling.
It's your first time to come here.
When you've seen enough of them, you'll get used to it.
A child being chosen to go up the mountains for training,
it can't be helped for him to be a bit anxious and nervous.
Trembling is normal.
Mister, he's shaking more violently.
Wait for me for a while!
I will immediately...
What's going on?
Look.
Wasn't that the drunk lady from before?
Older Brother Bai Ze!
A person who can't even control one's weapon is just a useless paper tiger!
Attack!
All of you be careful!
I'm coming!
This...
Be careful!
Xiong Fei!
They won't be able to hold up much longer.
No matter what, since they are enemies of the Illuminati,
then they are our friends.
Let's help them.
Hurry and run!
We've fallen into a trap! This is an ambush!
Retreat!
Older Bro Fei, were you the one who threw the bombs?
It  wasn't me.
It wasn't me, either.
Where did these people come from?
Think of a way to know their identities.
Right now, we must unite to resist the Illuminati's strength.
Okay.
I'll immediately check on it.
But just letting Gong Zi Xu escape like this,
we've missed this great chance.
You must always remember our main goal.
Killing a Gong Zi Xu is easy but it is not time for that yet.
Good thing that this child has them to protect him.
We don't need to be worry too much about it.
Let's go.
Older Bro Fei, are you alright?
I'm fine.
But A Ji Ya,
how come you just watched at the sides while we were fighting so fiercely?
I...
Yuan Shuai,
aren't we already okay now?
Just let bygones be bygones.
Good thing that we are all alright.
And A Ji Ya is a little lady.
Fine. Fine.
Just forget that I said that.
Xiong Fei...
When I saw you fighting with the Dark Shadow Man before, you were quite adept in using that Gray Thunder Edge.
How come earlier...
I also don't know.
When I was fighting with the Dark Shadow Man last time, I felt so angry.
I just wanted to defeat Dark Shadow Man.
But today, I...
Maybe it is because I'm not strong enough to
bring out the real power of the Gray Thunder Edge.
It's fine.
Elder, I was useless. I wasn't able to do my mission well.
Do you still remember what I've taught you?
The more pressing the situation is,
the more you should say it slowly.
Yes.
This is the bomb fragment that was thrown earlier from outside the walls which I picked up in our backyard.
When I went out to chase them, they had gone.
Bomb fragments?
Flash Bomb?
- You know this?
- What flash bomb?
Isn't this the flash bomb that I usually use during my magic tricks?
What is a flash bomb?
This can produce a high intensity light and sound
and then... it is usually used to scare people.
It doesn't really have much damaging power.
This is something that Illuminati disciples use during fighting practices.
Could it be that those people outside are also from the Illuminati?
That can't be. How can they attack their own?
Does it mean that the one hiding under the red cloth wasn't
the child who was supposed to be taken back here but someone else?
Yes. I saw it personally.
That person was holding a treasure sword.
That sword absorbed all of the sun's energy.
Right. We all saw it.
They even have back ups.
Surely, it's not only them that's around here.
Back-up?
Looks like they have already made preparations beforehand.
They were just waiting for you walk into their trap.
It's me who was careless.
Zi Xu, go down the mountain again tomorrow.
Investigate the background of this group of people.
The situation is still unclear right now.
Remember, don't alarm the enemies.
Yes.
Elder.
If what Gong Zi Xu said is true,
then that sword that he saw
is most likely the Gray Thunder Edge.
Gray Thunder Edge?
Wasn't that the legendary weapon that was passed on in the family of the Heaven Strategy Envoy Zhan family?
Indeed.
The mission of a Heaven Strategy Envoy is to find the Magic Stars.
Now that the Gray Thunder Edge has reappeared in Jianghu,
and it's even in the territory of my Illuminati.
It's quite interesting.
Then... tonight?
Tonight, we all will live here.
Since we've already interfered with this matter, we will surely interfere until the end.
Isn't that so, Bai Ze?
What Xiong Fei said is correct.
The Illuminati people will not just let this pass.
We staying here can at least give you some support.
Yes.
That's great.
There are still two rooms here.
Wife! Wife! Hurry and come here!
Coming.
Go and clean the other room and let these two ladies stay there.
- I'll just go with you.
- Okay.
A Ji Ya, go with them.
Tonight, let me be the guard.
Better just let me.
No. This morning, I didn't help because I got scared.
Give me a chance to make up for it so I can feel better.
Okay. Then you go.
Remember to be careful.
- Okay.
- Once there is any situation, immediately tell us.
- Thank you.
- Be careful.
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Magic Stars Team @ Viki.com
Junior Apprentice,
I really envy you.
You can even snore so energetically.
No wonder Teacher and Senior Apprentice really liked you, an outsider.
In just a few days, they already allowed you to become an elder.
Unlike me, no matter what I did, they couldn't see it.
Just because I am old already, they wanted to let me leave.
You don't understand.
I don't want to grow old.
I can't grow old, either!
Do you understand?
I forgot.
Your brain now isn't even smarter than a five years old.
You can't understand these words that I'm saying, either.
Okay then.
Junior Apprentice, it's time to drink your medicine.
Once you've drunk it, you can be like an idiot;
continue living happily like this.
So happy.
Come. Come.
This time, I wronged everyone.
A Ji Ya... A Ji Ya?
Wake up!
Hurry! Wake up!
- Wake up!
- What's wrong?
The Magic Star and Star Chart are missing.
Star Chart? Isn't A Ji Ya outside guarding?
But I didn't hear anything at all.
A Ji Ya! A Ji Ya!
- A Ji Ya!
A Ji Ya!
Could she be outside?
- A Ji Ya!
- Weird.
- There isn't even any sign of a fight.
- That's right.
So the truth is... A Ji Ya is a member of the Illuminati.
She is an accomplice of the people who came here last night.
Zi Su, right now A Ji Ya, the Magic Star and the Star Chart are all missing.
Although I don't know what the connection is between them,
- we still can't make rash conclusions that she is from the Illuminati.
- That's right.
I have my reasons for saying it.
And look.
This symbol is totally the same as the one I saw on A Ji Ya when we were taking a bath.
I don't know if you all still remember this.
When our carriage passed by the town,
it was A Ji Ya who stopped the driver.
Mister, please stop!
Did you take the wrong path?
Look at me. When one gets old, one easily gets confused.
If not because miss reminded me, we really would have gone past it.
Guangming Town is just one mile in front.
I'll just accompany you guys up to here.
Thank you.
The most suspicious clue is that when we were fighting with the Illuminati yesterday at dusk,
the A Ji Ya who usually charges to the front line didn't even help out at all.
Don't you all find that suspicious?
ZI Su, could you be overthinking about this matter?
Maybe it was the Illuminati who sedated A Ji Ya and stole the Magic Star.
But what use is the Magic Star for them?
Older Bro Bai Ze, all facts and evidences are in front of us!
You'd rather believe A Ji Ya than believe every word I say, is that it?
Zi Su, it's not that I don't believe you. It's just that we still haven't found any evidence right now and already...
Zi Su! Zi Su!
- Zi Su, Bai Ze didn't mean it like that.
- Don't talk to me. I don't want to hear it.
- Is A Ji Ya that kind of person?
- Don't misunderstand him.
- Zi Su...
- She doesn't look like one.
Zi Su! Don't put it to heart.
Bai Ze was just rash.
Zi Su!
Bai Ze, try to pacify her.
When she throws tantrums, she is always like this.
Hurry.
This isn't a question of pacifying her or not.
A Ji Ya is our friend.
She is with us.
Now that she is missing, aren't we supposed to think about her safety?
The trust between people is hard to establish sometimes,
but destroying it only needs one word.
I understand all of these that you're saying,
but you are a man. Isn't it just right for you to give way?
This is not a question of who is the man and who isn't.
This is a question of principles.
If you can prove that A Ji Ya is a member of the Illuminati,
by that time, I'll apologize in any way you want me to.
- Bai Ze!
- Why are you so stubborn?
Zi Su, what are you doing?
I'll go look for the Magic Star
and also the evidence that you wanted.
Zhan Xiong Fei, are you coming with me or not?
- Zi Su!
- Let go!
- Yuan Shuai, you and Bai Ze stay here to protect Little Hai Xing and his family.
- Okay.
Zi Su!
What's really happening with A Ji Ya?
Zhan Xiong Fei, not only you can understand the Hanyu Code.
Mount Guangming.
I was indeed right.
Men!
Right now, I will be giving a morning lecture to those children in training.
Without my permission, no one is allowed to disturb me.
Yes.
What kind of people are interfering with me?
Zi Su, where are we going?
To the Illuminati.
A Ji Ya took the Magic Star and Star Chart so she surely will be going there.
By that time, you must be my witness.
I am going to let Older Brother Bai Ze know
that the A Ji Ya he kept siding with is that kind of person.
What? Are you afraid?
If you're scared, you still have time to go back.
No. I just want to say that Mount Guangming is so far away.
We shouldn't be just walking towards there, right?
We should think of a faster way.
What you said is reasonable.
Let's go. I have an idea.
How dare you! This is the sacred place of the Illuminati.
How dare you come here without permission?
I know that this is the Illuminati headquarters.
I want to see your Elder Zhao Ran.
Go and inform him.
Where did you, a radical, come from?
Is Elder Zhao Ran just someone you can see just because you ask to?
Get back!
I was giving you guys some respect
and just asked you to inform him.
If I want to enter,
how can measly guards like you even stop me?!
You!
I am giving you fifteen minutes to tell Elder Zhao Ran
that the item that he has been wanting to have is in my hands.
If he won't see me, then don't you regret it.
Aren't you still going to hurry and go?!
Owner, how are you renting this horse?
Renting a horse?
This money is enough to buy your horse.
We are just going to rent it for a few days.
Then we'll return it to you.
This money is yours.
Then where are you heading?
We are going to Mount Guangming.
What?! Mount Guangming?!
I dare not rent my horses to you.
Why?!
How come you are changing your mind just like that?
Hadn't we already agreed a while ago?
That's right.
Owner, could it be that your horses has problems with their legs
that's why they won't be able to reach Mount Guangming?
It's not a problem with the horses.
Even if I rent my horses to you, you won't be able to reach Mount Guangming.
The Illuminati now are very different from before.
I fear that not only will you two be facing numerous dangers,
what if they recognize my horses? I'll also be dragged into this trouble.
Then isn't there any other way?
There is one.
In the Illuminati, there is an elder called Jiong Ye.
- Elder Jiong Ye?
- He is very different with the other members of the Illuminati.
He is very friendly to others.
- Elder Jiong Ye?
- He often comes to our town leisurely strolling around alone.
When he meets someone that he likes, he would bring them to the mountain to play with for several days
and even brings them back.
If you're lucky, he would even give you gifts.
Then when does he usually come here?
This I can't be sure.
But recently, he hasn't come.
Maybe today, he'll come.
Oh, right. You can take a look at the bun shop in front.
He likes to eat the buns in there the most.
Maybe you can meet him there.
There really is always a way out.
Oh, right. More importantly, you two must let him like you.
Elder.
Didn't I already say not to bother me?
There is a weird man at the gates whose name we don't know.
He said that he must see you.
People like that who are deliberately mystifying themselves, just directly make them leave.
But he says that he has in his hands something that you have always wanted.
If you won't see him, he said that don't you regret it.
Bring him to me.
Yes.
Looks like I gambled right this time.
It's been three years already. This opening still hasn't been blocked.
I brought you out here but don't tell anyone else about this opening.
If Lord Gong Zi Xu learns about this, we're dead.
Of course, I won't tell anyone.
Training is too hard.
Once I go down the mountain this time, I don't even want to come back anymore.
But if we don't come back, where else can we go?
We all don't have parents.
Are you from the Orphaned Child Camp?
I beg you. We won't do it anymore.
We'll go back right away.
It's not his fault. It was me who brought him here.
Let him go.
Go. I'll treat it as if I didn't see anything.
Aren't you still going to hurry and leave?! I'm going to take it back soon.
Thank you, Older Sister! Let's go.
This main hall is a bit narrow.
All of you, leave.
Yes!
Did you say that you have the thing that I wanted?
As they say, you may know a person, his face, but not his true nature.
Right now, I can't even see elder's face.
Do you... really want to see?
Yes.
Elder Zhao Ran is indeed a straightforward person.
Stop your nonsense already.
About the events at Clouds Harbor,
I already heard about it.
A distinguished Black Dragon King
actually ended up in such a state just due to some unskilled kids.
Really so depressing.
You came here not just to offer me some treasures, right?
Elder indeed knows every minute detail.
I want to use this treasure in exchange for
an elder position here in Mount Guangming.
Then it depends on what treasure you brought.
I won't beat around the bush then.
Right now, I have a Magic Star in my hands.
Don't know if it's worth an elder position.
Black Dragon King hasn't been dead for that long and you are already selling yourself to serve another master.
Black Dragon King really trusted the wrong person.
A good bird chooses the best tree to nest in.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Let's not talk about this anymore.
Better talk about you instead.
That recovering one's youthful vigor method of yours, looking for children whose birth date matches yours,
there will come a time that you won't find one anymore.
And you'll get older and older and the amount that you'll require will be greater and greater.
What do you plan to do in the future?
If you are able to get this Magic Star, you can then be young forever.
I admit that what you are saying is very tempting.
But... is the Magic Star really in your hands?
Are you now agreeing with my conditions?
Deal.
A distinguished elder actually also swindles people.
Aren't you looking down on me too much?!
You clearly know in your heart that people who have seen my real face
can never leave here alive.
Then it would depend if you have the ability to do that.
I initially wanted to tell you that there is another Magic Star that's also in Guangming Town
and let's work together to get it.
From the looks of it now, you are not an ideal partner.
Stinky brat...
Go die!
Respectfully greeting, Elder.
I like people who shoot hidden arrows.
That's right.
The other Magic Star won't be able to escape my palms.
Those little rascals that you were talking about include descendants of Heaven Strategy Envoys.
A monster like you
won't have a good ending.
Looks like, we have a new enemy.
Could it be that we only have this method left?
Having one method is not bad already.
It's way better than when we were just randomly going about things earlier.
I am not optimistic as you.
Didn't you hear what the owner said earlier?
Only by making him like us can he be willing to bring us up the mountain.
That's so easy. As long as I get to see him, I will surely beguile him and make him like me.
You are not some money or treasure so why would he like you?
Based on my individual charm.
Zhan Xiong Fei, you are the most vane person I've seen.
How about this? I'll just go look for some props.
Later, it will be of great use.
- Let's go.
- Okay.
It's been three years already.
It's still looks the same. No change at all.
How come the star chart isn't reacting at all?
Who's there?!
I was too naughty and planned to go down the mountain without permission.
Senior Apprentice, please have mercy.
I... I won't do it anymore.
Are you a disciple of our Illuminati?
How come I've never seen you before?
I only do chores under Gong Zi Xu.
It's normal that you haven't seen me.
Oh, since you are a disciple under Lord Gong Zi Xu,
then you must be very familiar with the rules of Illuminati.
The crime of going down the mountain without permission...
Senior Apprentice, so sorry.
I just got a bit too playful.
Just let me go and I will surely repay you.
Come. Come.
Get up. Get up.
You really followed the right person.
Lord Gong Zi Xu is an well-known future star of our Illuminati.
No need for you to repay me.
From now on, let's just take care of each other more.
Maybe in the future, we will be able to help each other regarding some matter.
Then... can I go now?
Go.
That was really scoring a lucky hit.
Unexpectedly, after being away for three years, Gong Zi Xu Xu's name is still this useful.
Wait!
Senior Apprentice, do you still need anything?
I still don't know what your name is.
My name is Jiang Ran. I am the guard of the Three Sacred Palaces.
Look at my memory.
My name is A Ji Ya. I work under Lord Gong Zi Xu.
When you go to Lord Gong ZI Xu's area, you'll find me.
I'll go now.
Wait again!
Last night, Lord Gong Zi Xu went down the mountain
to do some tasks for Elder Zhao Ran.
You surely know about it, right?
Looks like you aren't as stupid as I thought you were.
Wanting to test me? Just say it directly.
Of course, I know.
And also, I know that Lord Gong Zi Xu encountered a little bit of problem.
I know more than that.
But these are all secrets.
Forgive me for not being able to tell you about them.
It's fine. With something like that happening yesterday,
I was only just increasing my vigilance. There's nothing wrong with that.
What Senior Apprentice said is right.
I'll go now.
Wait again.
I have one last question.
What are the eight words internal incantation of the Illuminati?
Spread the brightness and the justice all over the whole world.
Not one word is wrong.
Be at ease and go back.
What happened today is just our secret.
No one will know.
Thank you, Senior Apprentice.
Senior Apprentice, did I say something wrong?
Why are you suddenly attacking me?
Who is your Senior Apprentice?!
Don't think that because I have one blind eye,
but my heart is not blind at all.
Even if you are going to kill me, you should still tell me why, right?
Okay. I'll tell you then.
You made a mistake on the simplest question.
The eight words internal incantation of Illuminati is "As bright as the sun and moon, only the Illuminati should be revered."
What you said was already the old one.
When I came here two years ago, it had already been changed.
That is the eight words internal incantation passed on for thousands of years by our ancestral court.
How can it be changed just like that?
What ancestral court?
I only know that right now,
only the words of Elder Zhao Ran and Lord Gong Zi Xu matter here in the Illuminati.
You caused me to waste my time on you for such a long time. I should have just directly used force.
Wow? Such arrogant words.
With just that skill of yours,
if you leave now, I can let you live.
Stop your rubbish!
Look at my sword!
Let's see now whose life will be lost.
Guard, we came late.
Not late. Not late. Just right.
So you were just dragging all this time, weren't you?
That's right. I already told you before that even if my eye is blind, my heart isn't.
Come!
Arrest this person imposing as Lord Gong Zi Xu's disciple
and bring her to him!
Yes!
Go! Move!
Let go of me!
I checked on the Mountain Creek Inn earlier.
That is where they stayed upon arriving here at Guangming Town.
The owner said that when they arrived, there were five of them, three boys and two girls.
After leaving last night, they haven't returned anymore.
From their stories, he learned that they came from Clouds Harbor.
But one man and one woman among them speaks with intonations coming from the capital.
Five people?
But we only saw four people yesterday.
There was one woman missing.
Since they are not from here,
how could they have any grudges with the Illuminati?
Maybe the problem lies on that woman we haven't seen.
I suspect that she might be someone we know.
A person we know?
Stop beating around the bush already.
Just hurry and say what you think.
Let's analyze it together.
I suspect that the girl that we didn't see
is A Ji Ya.
A Ji Ya?
You're talking about that A Ji Ya who left Illuminati without permission three years ago?
Yes.
But that was only my suspicion. I am not sure of it yet.
If it was really the missing A Ji Ya appearing now in Guangming Town,
this matter can't be that simple anymore.
But I remember that Gong Zi Xu and A Ji Ya's relationship before was very good.
Yesterday, could she have deliberately hid herself?
Then what is the motive of this group of people for doing that?
As for now, just base on these bits and pieces of clues we know,
we still won't be able to determine what the real situation is.
You guys continue investigating.
Remember. There surely is a reason for everything.
But there is only one truth.
Yes.
Right now, the atmosphere is a bit tense.
Shouldn't we stop the underground gathering
that we do for a while?
Let's evade this dangerous time for now.
We can't.
It wasn't easy for us to get the trust of those people who are bearing grudges against the Illuminati.
If we retreat now, then the tree will fall and the monkeys will scatter.
Continue everything as usual.
- Yes.
What's wrong with you?
You were still okay earlier.
Don't know why.
But since last time we met that old man who did magic tricks,
I suddenly remembered my father.
Since I was little, my father already taught me to do magic tricks.
He said that once I've learned this skill, I won't starve wherever I go.
But that time, I was too playful and didn't learn from frin him well.
When I already wanted to learn,
my father was already gone.
For so many years,
my impression of Father is becoming more and more blurred.
I already can't remember what he looks like.
Zi Su, am I not filial?
Don't think that way.
What you are doing now is exactly rebuilding the glory of your father.
What you said is correct.
Right now, we still have to do our present task well.
Make this Elder Jiong Ye submit to us with one move.
I have a feeling that we will be able to win him over.
Let's go.
- Let's go.
- Come. Let's go.
Older Brother Yuan Shuai. Older Brother Yuan Shuai, let's play outside.
We can't, Little Hai Xing.
It's very dangerous right now outside.
Let's just play inside the house, okay?
No. What's good to play inside the house?
I can make you a very powerful frog.
He can jump like this.
Okay! Okay!
Go and get some paper and I'll teach you how to make one.
Okay.
Let me tell you.  This frog, it can...
Bai Ze! Bai Ze!
Look. What is written here?
The current Illuminati has changed.
The so-called training for the young child is also just a hoax.
If we still don't unite and resist them, there will come a day
that we will become the next sacrificial victim.
From the real Illuminati.
The real Illuminati?
Is the Illuminati now a fake?
Where did you get this?
It's from my father.
Your father's?
- Let go of me!
- Hurry up!
Hurry up! Hurry!
Behave!
Let go of me!
Oh, Elder Jiong Ye. I'm giving you my respect.
Jeez, no need, no need.
Elder?
Elder Jiong Ye?
There really is always a way out.
Where are you going now?
Down the mountain to eat some buns.
If you want to eat some buns, you could have just told us to get them for you.
No need for you to personally go down the mountain.
What do you know? When you eat buns, you have to eat them while they're hot. So delicious.
Elder! It's me! I am A Ji Ya!
A Ji Ya?
It's me.
♫ How long can my friends around me to accompany me? ♫
♫ I’m tired of hearing those comforting words ♫
♫ I’m pulled between courage and collapse repeatedly ♫
♫ I cry out to myself to hang in there ♫
♫ I’m still awake at 3 in the early morning ♫
♫ I can only expect for a good night sleep but not having it ♫
♫ If I’m not careful, I’ll be disturbed once I think about you ♫
♫ Memory has been overturned into a kind of sin ♫
♫ Having loved one very much is wrong but so what ♫
♫ Loneliness is also just a process ♫
♫ We still have next person waiting for us ♫
♫ I’ll remember those wonderful things ♫
♫ Shedding tears isn’t need ♫
♫ Thank you for your choosing ♫
♫ Don’t force myself to give blessing ♫
♫ Be a mature person ♫
♫ Having loved one very much is worth the pain and so happy ♫
♫ I need to learn to let go those I can’t part with ♫
♫ Having loved one very much is wrong but so what ♫
♫ Loneliness is also just a process ♫
♫ We still have next person waiting for us ♫
♫ With a little regret, I’m more complete ♫