I am Ghost Agent K.
A shadow without a name or reputation.
Wasn't it your orders?
Fellow Ghost agent.
We must find the missing tapes.
Something the late Chairman Byung-do Mo
left only to Seung-jae Mo.
Everything, excluding myself,
The lonely hunter left behind
a riddle in his will.
I've solved it.
Byung-do Mo's dragon design.
Dong-hyun. Thank you for everything.
The picture Dong-hyun sent...
The hunting rifle with a dragon on it...
The NIS director has the same one.
I have seen it.
Will and Testament.
Why can't I reach Dong-hyun?
Where is he?
I don't have any more assignments.
In-soo Baek.
EPISODE 15
Why are you here?
What has this jerk been doing?
I said over and over, no hospitals or NIS.
How is Dong-hyun?
It's very bad.
We found the hit-and-run vehicle.
The hit-and-run driver drove
into a guardrail 10km away and died.
He was drunk.
His blood alcohol level was 0.18.
The police will likely write it off
as a simple drunk driving accident.
The tire marks go from dark to light
just before the site of impact.
Did he accelerate before the accident?
He accelerated on purpose
to hit Dong-hyun.
This wasn't an accident.
But then,
it's too clumsy for it
to have been the NIS director.
There must be someone else on the inside.
It doesn't matter.
They are all going to die anyway.
What are you doing?
Get over here and play a game with me.
Goodness.
Why do you want to play
when you always lose?
Goodness.
I would win if you didn't play cheap.
Cheap? I'm just highly skilled.
I beat up plenty of kids in my hood
for playing like you.
- You can't fight.
- I have my face.
I looked older than most kids.
I hit them in the face.
- That's convincing.
- That's right.
- Block it. No.
- Yes.
- Goodness.
Cheap move.
Damn it.
One more time.
I'm tired. Go home.
- Your wife is waiting.
- I'm working tonight.
I have to go on a stakeout later.
Why is a prosecutor going on a stakeout?
Is it that flasher?
Are you going to catch him?
I'm going to catch that punk soon.
I promise.
How?
Because I'm the prosecutor on the case.
What the hell?
Let's play.
Come on.
Now we can get rid of
all the bad guys, right?
It's all on the prosecutor.
By the law. By the rules.
I'll finish them all.
CONGRESSMAN IN-SOO BAEK
Why are you working with me?
I heard that unlike Chairman Mo,
who was a kingmaker,
you plan to enter into politics yourself.
You'll have to become the president.
You're not old enough
to run for president next year,
so you will need someone
to replace Congressman Baek.
You did this and fought Congressman Baek
out of your personal ambition?
I'll set the foundation for you.
You can take over afterward
and complete the reformation.
The first generation Ghost agents
want to maintain the relationship
with Songsan as well.
Your file is in there as well, right?
The records of illegal acts
you committed in your young,
Ghost agent days.
The past wrongdoings should be buried,
so that history can't remember.
What will you do about K?
Anyone who threatens national security
must be eliminated.
Search the place.
It has been disclosed that the prosecutor,
Dong-hyun Lee, currently in a coma
after being hit in a hit-and-run accident,
was investigated by the NIS for espionage.
An NIS representative stated that Lee,
a former NIS agent, used his connections
to extract confidential information
and shared it.
- What? What's going on?
- With his spy ring.
Last night's accident
may not have been an accident,
and may have been an act by the spy ring.
If it is proved that he indeed is a spy,
it would have a massive effect.
Next, the weather forecast.
That annoying old man.
He hid a safe behind his portrait.
He did?
Grandpa threw a sucker punch
at me from his grave,
so I have to return the favor.
I'll take my first step into politics,
which he was adamantly against,
in front of him.
At his memorial ceremony?
You have to go with me, so get ready.
I will.
Right.
There will be a guest there today
that you'll be surprised to see.
Who?
Why isn't Seol-woo answering his phone?
Where are you?
I'm...
at his studio.
- Is he there?
- No.
Seol-woo isn't here, but it looks like
someone searched the place.
It's a mess.
Come to my house right now.
He left the third wood carving
and $5,000,000 here.
My goodness. Tae-ho!
What brings you here so early
in the morning?
I'll explain later.
It's urgent.
Can you get in touch with Mi-eun?
I haven't heard from K.
How is Dong-hyun doing?
He's still in surgery.
It doesn't look good.
The NIS director is working
with my husband now.
I think they made
some sort of a deal last night.
With both Robert Yoon's death
and Dong-hyun's accident,
if the NIS director is the traitor,
it all falls into place.
K knows already.
If K knows...
I don't know what he'll do.
We have to stop him.
Who are you?
We're with the NIS.
Tae-ho.
We need to investigate something
regarding Dong-hyun Lee's espionage case.
Please come with us.
He got a call last night
and rushed off somewhere.
I think it was news about Mr. Lee.
What the hell is going on?
Something obviously went wrong.
I don't like it.
I've never seen that look in his eyes.
It was Dong-hyun, of all people,
who was attacked.
Hello?
This is Mi-eun Song.
BYUNG-DO MO
MAY YOU REST IN PEACE
CHAIRMAN MO'S MEMORIAL CEREMONY
SONGSAN ELECTRONICS
SONGSAN PRODUCE
Everyone, bow.
Stand straight.
Please take your seats.
In order to clean out those involved
with the slush fund,
we worked with the NIS
and began
the "Make Songsan Upstanding" project.
Using that experience as a foundation,
I plan to give my life
to begin a "Make Korea Upstanding" project
in using justice
to create a powerful Korea.
I believe my grandfather,
the late Chairman Byung-do Mo,
would support my decision today.
My companion and psychological mentor,
Mr. Suk-hoon Lim, the director of NIS,
will give his remarks.
First, I would like to thank you
for inviting me
to the late Chairman Mo's
memorial ceremony.
When I heard Mr. Seung-jae Mo,
the CEO of Songsan Group,
say he'll give his life to create
a just and upright Korea,
I was deeply...
What an incredible statement.
Look at this.
All the patriots are gathered here.
Brother.
I know you're watching. Pick up.
Brother, let's talk.
Brother, pick up.
Step aside.
I want to kill
these dirty, conniving bastards
as much as you do.
But Dong-hyun is being investigated
for espionage.
If you finish it like this,
what happens to Dong-hyun's honor?
Seol-woo.
You see me, don't you?
You hear me, don't you?
I...
trust you.
I want to kill
these dirty, conniving bastards
as much as you do.
If you finish it like this,
what happens to Dong-hyun's honor?
I...
trust you.
What do you think about the NIS' claim
that he is a spy?
His fake ID was submitted as evidence.
Did you ever notice anything suspicious?
My husband is not a spy.
Then, do you deny the charges?
- Where did he say he was going last night?
- Those bastards.
What are they doing to the family?
Don't get worked up.
Excuse me.
You're apparently society journalists,
but you must know who I am.
Hollywood superstar, Dark Death.
I'm Un-gwang Yeo.
- Un-gwang Yeo?
- Why is Un-gwang Yeo here?
- Why is he here?
- What's his relationship?
I would like to say something
about the prosecutor, Dong-hyun Lee.
- He wants to say something.
- What will he say?
Dong-hyun Lee's charge of espionage
was completely fabricated and forged.
I'm sure of it.
What proof do you have?
You can tell after
being an actor for so long
whether someone's eyes are lying
or telling the truth.
The prosecutor Dong-hyun Lee that I know
is full of responsibility
and a sense of duty.
He's the most righteous prosecutor
in all of Korea.
Double the security.
Put the most experienced guards
on Jae-young.
Yes, sir.
What's going on?
Un-gwang's bodyguard is
after the NIS director.
Is he? Why?
He's been charged with espionage
for working with foreign terrorists.
If you resigned,
you should just hike in the mountains.
Why did you come down?
Did you have to go that far
with Dong-hyun?
He's a suspect of espionage
who betrayed the country.
We're investigating
who caused the accident.
You're the traitor!
Have you been using us from the start?
The cameras are off,
so let's speak comfortably.
K.
Where is he?
He won't get caught easily as I did.
Okay.
Sure.
The person you're seeing right now...
Sharon Kim, right?
Well, it's late,
but if you plan to get married
and preserve your honor,
think very carefully.
Whether your name will be included
among the ring of spies,
or whether you'll be on my side again.
Are you threatening me?
K is being openly searched for espionage.
Think carefully.
You're not a doctor, are you?
My husband occasionally talked about
a junior agent who was a pain in the neck.
The doctors say...
he won't last three days.
But that's because they don't know him.
He will get up.
There are still too many bad people
that he needs to catch,
so he won't be able to leave like this.
Because he's an idiot who thinks
he has to catch every bad person himself.
By the law. By the rules.
He...
did what was right.
I left him alone
because he was doing what was right.
Had I known it was a losing battle,
I would have stopped him.
I should have tried to stop him.
It is not a losing battle.
I will take over from here.
By the law.
By the rules.
Good work. Go home.
- Who is it?
- It's Dad.
Is it you, K?
You came in exactly
when I didn't expect you.
There's no way to stop you now.
However,
do not touch my family.
I will not kill you.
Instead,
I'll make your remaining days
a living hell.
I hope you live a long life.
This is the NIS director.
The spy Seol-woo Kim
must be shot on sight.
How could...
What is this espionage about?
The cops barged in this afternoon
and caused a huge scene.
Who the heck is this prosecutor,
Dong-hyun Lee?
Do you know you're number one trending
because of what you said in the hospital?
I didn't say anything wrong.
Un-gwang.
It's hard enough for me
to prevent scandals.
If you make the society page too,
when will we ever make our movie?
If that's the situation,
should I create a scandal?
Something so big that it would
totally bury the espionage thing.
Un-gwang.
How can you make jokes right now?
Ms. Cha.
- Yes?
- Did you know Guard Kim was a spy?
You two were dating. You knew, didn't you?
Do you think Seol-woo is a spy?
Does what I think matter?
I don't think so.
He risked his life to save you.
He looks like someone who saves others,
not kills them.
So what?
Why does that matter right now?
See? I'm getting another call!
It's another reporter. Look!
Thank you so much!
I was about to call him myself!
Hello, Mr. Park. No. The thing is...
Anyway,
where do you think Seol-woo is?
Seeing how he left the third wood carving
and $5,000,000,
maybe he left.
Is there really no way to contact him?
We don't know anyone other than Mr. Lee.
There is another person
connected to the NIS.
- Who?
- The one who planted him as my bodyguard.
- Mi-eun?
- I need to confirm something anyway.
I have to see her.
Mr. Jang is being investigated
by the NIS for espionage as well.
How is Dong-hyun doing?
He's hanging in there.
Your husband is involved
with his accident.
The targets are the NIS director
and Seung-jae Mo.
Will you continue with the mission?
Yes.
Let's finish this.
No more sacrifices.
We must find the missing material
on the NIS director.
He already destroyed them.
I'm sure your husband made a copy.
Look into it.
You know things are crazy right now
because of the APB.
Did you see him?
I know these situations very well.
You need to listen carefully to me.
Love doesn't feed you.
The more you're being chased unfairly,
the more you have to eat well.
If you see Seol-woo,
give him enough money...
to feed himself.
Those evil bastards.
Doing that to Mr. Lee...
They should all go to hell.
I'll look after Mr. Lee.
You look after Seol-woo.
Don't let people catch on.
Dad.
Okay.
Be strong, my daughter.
Justice will surely prevail.
Okay.
Thank you for stopping this afternoon.
You're alone again somewhere,
devising a tactic, aren't you?
But do you know something?
We still haven't ended our lovers tactic.
You said to hold onto it for one more day.
Please remember this one thing.
You are not alone.
Thank you.
VIP, it is time to wake up.
Okay, Guard Kim.
I have to meet Mi-eun today and find you.
I have to get up...
Guard Kim?
It's Jongro Coffee from Jongro.
How did you get in here?
The cops have been staking out.
I'm a very skilled agent.
It's good to see you safe.
Do-ha was very worried.
Did you contact her?
You did.
You contacted her before coming to me.
I was very worried too, you know.
Hot.
I read the articles
about what you said about Dong-hyun
at the hospital.
Are you okay?
Don't you worry.
Hollywood stars say what they need to.
Still, you cannot meet with Mi-eun.
If Seung-jae Mo finds out,
everyone will be in danger.
Sure.
That's true.
You're back, so it's okay.
Did you start a plan?
Let me know if you need anything.
We need to punish those bastards
who did that to Dong-hyun.
You want the foundation?
I don't like having old fogies interfere.
That money was theirs to begin with.
If you would appoint
a chairperson of their choice
as a formality,
you and I can run it in reality.
I'll give you half the seats on the board.
But my wife will continue on
as the chairperson.
I guess you trust your wife a lot.
I trust her more than anyone.
You're more naive than you appear.
You put your whole trust in the person
you should be most cautious of.
Did you know that your wife, Mi-eun Song,
was a secret agent
with the NIS in the past?
I put her on you.
She was tasked to extract
information from you.
Think carefully.
Who do you think introduced K to Chewing
that he became Un-gwang Yeo's bodyguard?
If you don't believe me,
why don't you test her?
Based on what I know,
she seems to be helping K
with his mission.
What do you think of the NIS director?
He has an honest and upright image.
He kicked out Congressman Baek's gang
and reformed the NIS,
so he seems to have skill and drive.
Then you think
he's a good political companion.
I don't know.
I think you should be cautious with him.
Seeing how he joined you,
who was his enemy,
he'll betray you at any time
if it benefits him.
Don't worry too much.
I have a copy of the materials
which I could use against him.
It's in my safe.
Do you?
That's a relief.
I have a broadcast tomorrow,
so I can't have lunch with you.
It's a live broadcast,
so I can't change the time.
It's okay.
Good luck with the broadcast.
Thank you.
Are you doing okay?
You got rid of me
and became friends
with that kid Seung-jae.
All that rough talk tells me
you're adjusting well to prison life.
I found the tapes on you
and handed them over to the prosecutor.
A few more charges were tacked on,
so you won't get out of here alive.
Be strong.
You think your file will never get out?
Don't you fret.
I destroyed them myself.
You don't think Seung-jae, that smart kid,
made a copy for himself?
Here is the copy.
I can get a copy of the documents
on the true identity of the foundation
formed from the slush fund.
Also, a copy of the files
on the NIS director
is in my husband's safe.
Can you get it?
He has a live broadcast tomorrow.
That is the best time.
Did you know that your wife, Mi-eun Song,
was a secret agent
with the NIS in the past?
If you don't believe me,
why don't you test her?
She seems to be helping K
with his mission.
I have a copy of material
which I could use against him.
It's in my safe.
That's a relief.
Is your investigation by the NIS over?
Not yet.
I'm being watched carefully.
I heard Dong-hyun still has a chance.
Yes.
If only I hadn't pulled
out of the mission,
it would have been me, not him.
As the one in charge of the mission,
it is all my fault
and my responsibility.
I'm sorry.
Of all the orders that I know,
saying "I'm sorry" is not one of them.
The mission
is not over yet.
Hello.
Hello. But who...
Well, to introduce myself,
I worked with Mr. Lee...
My goodness.
How did this happen...
Those bastards.
- Are you a fellow prosecutor?
- No.
I was working with Mr. Lee,
whom I respect.
Well,
I was sort of a secret agent.
You must have gone through a lot.
I know because I have a lot of experience.
But no matter how hard they hide it,
the truth always gets out.
Okay.
Yes, well...
I'll take that.
- No, it's okay.
- No.
You must be so upset.
You need to rest.
- But...
- Why don't you drink something?
Okay, then.
At least you aren't lonely.
Mi-eun is getting the documents
and handing them over to you.
With that, we can bury the NIS director
and Seung-jae, is that it?
But whom will you give those documents to?
True. Since Dong-hyun is the only one
we can trust, and he's unavailable.
Can't we post it online and distribute
them to all the media companies?
They do that often in the movies.
I don't like ending it that nicely.
Villains should be placed on a train
to hell and destroyed for good.
I have a plan.
Let's shoot a movie.
What happened?
Espionage?
I need your help.
A man being chased for espionage
is asking me for help.
That's a first.
Do you trust me?
If you are a spy,
something is wrong with the country.
If you say you aren't, I believe you.
What I'm about to tell you
is a matter of national security.
Hey.
What's this urgent matter?
I wanted to talk to you
about the next project.
Yes.
We didn't even finish the current movie.
Why do you want to discuss the next one?
Come on.
We can't lose out on this.
We read the scenario,
and it will be a blockbuster.
Look.
HEARTS ON FIRE.
SCREENPLAY AND PRODUCTION: DAE-SHIK MA
Director Ma?
Sure, it would be great
if we could get it.
But it's not like
he would even meet with me.
Come on.
Who am I?
I already found out where he'll be.
Today is our chance.
Go with Ms. Cha.
If Ms. Cha says we should do it,
we really should.
HIGH-QUALITY DRAMAS
Look.
Mr. Ji.
- Hello, Director Ma.
- Hi. How have you been?
- Good.
- Can we speak for a few minutes?
I have a broadcast to get to.
- It'll be a minute.
- Hello, Director Ma.
- Hi. How have you been?
- Hello.
Still, you have time for some coffee,
don't you?
Coffee? Shall we? Sure.
Let's go.
We're finishing it up now...
- I have your coffee.
- Thank you.
Here.
You like it sweet
with a lot of sugar, right?
How did you know I have diabetes?
Thanks.
It's not half bad. Thank you.
- Sir.
- Yes?
Where are you?
Why aren't you here yet?
My intestines feels like
they're drying up.
- I can't do it.
- Pardon?
Hey.
I need to go.
Why this old man...
How can he do this at a live broadcast?
Goodness.
Mr. Choi.
Did your guest flake on you?
That's terrible.
You're a wanted man.
Do you have it?
I do.
But where do you plan to use this?
I need to blow them up.
I'll finish everything tonight.
So it was you.
You're the traitor
who got Robert Yoon killed.
You have to accept sacrifices
in running a country.
I'm sure.
I plan to leave.
Let's make a final deal.
Do you even have anything?
My husband has a copy of files on you.
I'll give it to you.
What do you want?
A safe escape and new identities
for me and my child.
I guarantee it.
Don't think of doing anything to me
when I hand you the item as you did
to Robert and Dong-hyun.
I'll choose the time and place.
PERSON TO PERSON.
What are you doing?
I'm looking over
some foundation operation documents.
You are?
Good luck with the broadcast.
Okay.
See you later.
What is it?
We need to check your bag.
My bag?
- Did you find it?
- She didn't have anything on her.
What?
That can't be.
It's ten minutes before we go live.
Please stand by in the studio.
Okay.
Can you get it?
He has a live broadcast tomorrow.
That is the best time.
But my husband is lying to me.
I saw suspicion in his eyes.
I'm sure there's a trap.
Let's begin our deal.
My husband is in the studio
filming a live broadcast.
- Mr. Choi.
- Yes?
- He's here.
- Okay.
Mr. Mo.
Thank you very much
for agreeing to do this.
My pleasure.
But there was a problem
with the other guest,
so we had to get someone else.
I heard you know each other well.
There he is.
Hello, Mr. Mo.
It's been a while.
I have a feeling today's show
will be very interesting.
PERSON TO PERSON.
You totally saved me.
Come on.
We're in the same industry,
so we should have each other's backs.
Have some.
We're in the same industry,
so I will buy dinner sometime.
Okay, let's test the cameras. Stand by.
PERSON TO PERSON.
What are you trying to do?
It's a talk show, so we talk, obviously.
Ask and answer.
Answer truthfully to the questions asked.
It's an assassination-use explosive
developed in Mossad.
With a press of this button,
only your heart will go...
boom.
Don't try to run or do anything stupid.
Just answer truthfully.
PERSON TO PERSON.
Only the truth can save you.
The final mission.
Why did you try to kill me twice?
All the truth will be revealed.
The world cannot take your side.
Once in a while,
the world flips upside down.
Today is that day.
Blow it up now.
My dear citizens, you must know the truth.
The person behind all of this...
It's time for revenge.
He left.
Guard Kim may have disappeared,
but Brother will be back.