And I'm in trouble.
The rascal has a pistol!
God knows what other
trouble you'll drag me into!
Quiet...
Go away...
Go...
- Finding them is tough.
- Let's go back. - Yes.
''See, there was no need to scream.''
What...?
Where is it?
Scared of a cockroach!
Now...?
''I'll hold this cap up
and move it, they'll shoot''
- And I'll die.
- Why? Don't die.
''I'll pretend. Then you stand
and scream, he's dead! ''
''The moment they come close to
catch you, I'll grab their gun.''
Let me know when they
are about 20 feet away.
He's dead!
Is that right? Dead!
He's dead! Very good Stay dead.
40 feet.
30 feet. Get ready.
''20 feet. Raghu, are you listening? ''
10 feet! Get up.
Get up!!
''Raghu, get up! ''
''- Enough, get up.
- Catch her.''
Don't touch me!
- Get up!
- He's dead.
Coward! Scaredy cat!
Hot air balloon!
Excuse me...
you...? All alone over here?
I left her with the aunt.
She was to have a baby.
- What did you have?
- A girl - Great.
- Congratulations
- Have you seen her?
- Just now.
- Some thugs carried her away.
- Thugs?
I'll show you.
Advance!
Advance forward not back!
''I said, I won't
call Daddy! Never! ''
''Look, don't scream.''
We're not bad characters.
You're hurt because you're kidnapped
But we don't touch strange girls.
Don't touch girls! My foot!
You are scoundrels!
Rascals! Swindlers!
Quiet!
Why do you scream so loud?
If a rich father loses his child
he has to pay a lakh or two.
That is why tell us
your father's phone number!
So we're not in trouble.
- Tell us...
- You want the number?
Come close. I'll tell you.
Hit!
There...
Hit him some more!
Now where will you escape?
Lower! Down!!
No...
Duffer! No!
Now where will you escape?
- You thrashed us a lot.
- Bravo!
What's in my hand?
I'll blow you to smithereens.
Save me!
''Let go, you egg head! ''
- Let's go. - what?
- My cap!
- No! Are you nuts?
- Let go!
My heart is yours
Cupid struck me
''You are my heart, my life''
Only you
My heart belongs to you
Cupid struck us
''My heart, my breath,
my life, my love''
Only you
''My heart is desirous
since I set eyes on you''
''You have no idea of
how much I love you''
''I can relate the
story of love to you''
I can tell you what's in my heart
''You wouldn't know
what's in my heart''
''I'm not to be blamed
if I fall for you''
''You're a traveller and
I am your destination''
''You are a song and
I am the gathering''
Car... gone!
What fun! How we fooled them!
You're wonderful.
Risked your life for me.
- What if you'd died...?
- If I hadn't risked my life.
You'd have died.
- What's this?
- I don't know.
Have you no shame calling
another's father your Dad?
''Get this clear, you maybe
a big actor on big posters''
Or if stupid girls chase you...
I have always hated you.
And I always will hate you.
You've told me this a hundred times.
I'll say it all my life.
Sit down!
I don't give a damn
about what you say.
Pooja loves me and
wants to marry me.
You can't stop us.
''Mr. Actor, these dialogues
won't affect me one bit.''
Pooja has left you.
You've failed to get her back.
I haven't slept a wink
I'm missing my daughter.
Tell me where she is.
I want to see her!
I give up. That's
why I've called you here.
2 dozen reporters are
waiting in my office.
Tell them I accept
your marriage to Pooja.
Get Pooja from wherever she is!
There he comes.
Mr. Dharamchand wants
to say something to you.
I want to tell you that...
Deepak and I have decided to make up.
Photo.
Look here... the dynamo broke.
It will have to be welded.
- Where will I get the cash?
- You'll pay me later for repairs.
Pay for the welding too.
I'll go get it done.
- How long will it take?
- I'll be back soon.
Great number. Turn it loud.
''I'm a traveller on the
path of love, don't stop me''
''I belong to those
who meet me with love''
I accept pain and succor
''I weave every kind
of flower into a garland''
''Sunlight was in my fate
that's how I lived my life''
Madam! Your picture
is in the paper!
See what this says. Deepak
and Dharamchand have made up.
''Dear, come back home.
I accept your marriage.''
Look...
I knew you were not ordinary.
''Madam, are you getting married? ''
My wishes.
Hurry up.
- Come on.
- Found a room?
- Agreed with great difficulty.
- Spoke about the money?
I told him we'll stay a week.
We'll see what to say in the morning
- You're great.
- Okay but I don't understand...
Why are you insisting
on staying the night?
''Lf we leave now, we'll
be in Bangalore in 3 hours.''
Till yesterday you were
in a rush to reach Bangalore.
Whom will we meet at 3 AM?
Everyone will be sleeping.
All right. Come on.
Gave the room again
without taking advance!
''I told you a hundred
times, don't trust anyone! ''
''The boy is decent,
married owns a car.''
Such decent people
cheat and run away!
Last stage.
Tomorrow you'll reach home.
Into your husband's arms.
And you'll write for the paper.
Strange story.
Will you come to see me?
- No.
- Why?
I don't meet married women.
You can come to ask about me.
No way.
Does this mean we'll
never meet again?
What's the need to meet me?
Your job has been done!
You had to reach
Deepak and you did!
That's all you wanted
from me! Talks nonsense!
What is wrong with you?
I am afflicted by love
There's no hope for me
People have started telling me
There's no way I'll survive
''Love burnt everything
and made me forget all''
''Look at the state
love has reduced me to''
I have lost myself
A fire engulfs me
''The world seems different
since I fell in love''
My heart is not in control
It doesn't hark my advice
''Love made me;
love destroyed me''
''Love made me, you and
the world come to its' knees''
Die for love
Let's do something drastic
''Let's spread the
fragrance of love all around''
''For your love, my love... ''
I have given up the world
It's only now that
I fully realise it.
Don't ever leave me
I can't live without you.
I know what you're thinking.
Don't think.
Let's elope!
Everything will be fine.
Don't be mad! Go to sleep!
Go!
Everything you said outside...
do you really...?
Will you marry me?
I'm going to Bangalore.
I'll be back by morning.
Have to arrange
money to get married.
I too love you and want to marry you
Wait for me. I'll be back
real soon with the cash.
''Yours, Raghu.''
I don't have money.
You may keep my bag.
How will the bag help?
I too have a bag.
- Know the price of fuel?
- Keep the spare wheel too.
When I return I'll give
you an extra 50 bucks.
What?
I don't have a cap.
- Now fill her up.
- Right away.
- You!
- Sir.
You! Here!!
I don't want to see your face!
- Listen to me...
- Anybody there?
Get him out of here
and take me somewhere!
Calm down my dear Sharma.
I'm not dear!
Don't take away my
freedom of speech.
- Speak on.
- I respect you.
This city has many papers.
I come straight here
with any exclusive news.
To you. And now for
this year's greatest scoop...
...is in my hands
Shouldn't I come here to you?
- Look into my eyes.
- Pooja is marrying Deepak.
I know it.
That's where you err
in knowing Raghu's genius.
Meaning?
Meaning if I throw a bombshell
that Pooja isn't marrying Deepak...
Everything is settled
and she isn't marrying...
She's marrying another.
Are you drunk? Yes?
Tell me news that Pooja is
marrying another not Deepak
Is it exciting or not?
''Yes, it is. So...? ''
Give me 10000 and
the news is yours.
''You're a cheat, vagabond.''
I don't trust you.
If this news is false...
I'm dead meat.
Use your brains.
''Lf I give false news,
will I survive in this line? ''
Who will give me a job?
''They could sue me,
send me to prison.''
And I'll be the first
to send you to jail.
All right. I accept.
Whom is she marrying?
''- Firs the cash.
- First the news, then the cash! ''
Who is she marrying?
Me.
Get the car out.
I'm going home.
It's true...
Climb down from the
editor's seat for a minute.
Look into my eyes.
Am I lying to you?
I met Pooja in a bus.
We were together all the time
I fell in love with her.
I love her
And she loves me.
Right now I'm in a rush.
She must be waiting for me.
She doesn't know I've
come to give you this news.
Every minute is valuable.
And I have not a penny.
''Under these circumstances, how
can I tell her I want to marry her? ''
''Yes, there is a story.''
The story has essence.
''Pooja, the daughter of the city's
richest man Dharamchand leaves... ''
...home in a huff to meet her lover.
En route she meets a
roadside Romeo.
She falls in love with him.
Yes! The story spins!
Where is the story?
Get up! Finally
what I said came true!
The boy ran away in the
car without paying up!
- I didn't know...
- How will you?
- You're always sleeping!
- Funny...
Let's go and see
what's the condition.
Hope he hasn't
taken away the fans.
What...? What's the matter?
Where's the husband you came with?
The one in whose car you came.
''- Must be here...
- Taken the bag, luggage... ''
- There's nothing here.
- What?
Who will pay the rent for the room?
She'll pay! She gets clients
to do business! Why won't she pay?
What nonsense! What are you saying?
Pay the room rent.
- I don't have money.
- Then get out of here!
Get out!
- Out
- But where will I go?
None of our concern.
Go to hell!
Drown yourself in a river
but get out of here!
Get out! Did you have to come to
this hotel for soliciting clients?
Don't touch the telephone!
Nor show your face again!
This hotel is for
decent people. Get out!
What's the news?
What's wrong with your voice?
Where are you my dear?
Why are you crying?
Tell me where you are.
I'll come to take you!
Stay there. I'm coming.
- You've made my life.
- Don't mention it.
Your pen has the power.
What a picture you paint!
You are somewhat greedy
but no writer like you.
Where the heck are you?
No! That story won't be printed.
This one will be. I want
a pretty picture of Pooja.
Where's the cartoon?
Sent the cartoonist here.
I want a cartoon of Deepak
standing near the wedding hall.
And Pooja waves bye to him
and leaves with another.
''Good, isn't it? ''
Send somebody and compose this.
That story won't be printed.
Just a minute...
Don't disturb me. I'm busy.
- I don't want to hear it.
- Pooja spoke to Dharamchand.
Pooja spoke to Dharamchand.
She's come back home.
What...?
He fleeced me for 10000.
I won't spare you!
Call the cops! Arrest him!
''You'll be the bride
and I'll be the groom''
''Wait for me, I'll come
for you in a procession''
''Drums, music, horses and
elephants will accompany us''
I'll envelop you in my arms
When the night of union approaches...
''With talks of
romance on my lips... ''
I'll keep you awake all night
''I'll be the bride
and you'll be my groom''
I will die with love for you
''Since you stepped into
my heart, my life partner... ''
''You've brought the love
of a lifetime with you''
Since I first saw you...
I asked God for you
I can't live without you
''Did you hear, Pooja
went back to her father? ''
Deepak is swinging.
What a crazy girl!
Give this money to Sharma.
''And tell him, I was joking.''
There was no such news.
The flush doesn't work.
Everyone cheats me of
my money. Money...?
- Raghu returned it.
- Why?
He said that was a lie.
Where is he?
What is this?
Thought I'd pull your leg.
But the story was good?
It happens. This happens in life.
Man plans something but
something else happens.
Keep this. Get back when
you're in the mood. We'll talk.
I knocked but you...
I was thinking.
Everything is arranged.
Your marriage is being talked.
I hear Deepak will come in
a chopper for the wedding.
I too heard that.
It's madness according
to me but it's all right.
He can do what he thinks is right.
''Dear, what's wrong? ''
- What is wrong?
- Nothing.
You seem upset since you came.
I'm worried abut you.
Are the marriage preparations fine?
Have Deepak and you...?
- No. - If there's
something... it's not too late.
Do you know my real
feelings about Deepak?
My child...
I want you to be happy.
I want to give you
the world's happiness.
What is the matter?
My baby...
Are you in love with another?
Love! You love somebody else!
Not Deepak? Fantastic!
- Where did you meet him?
- In the bus.
Bus...? Is he a bus conductor?
- No.
- Who is he?
I don't know much about him
but I like him.
You like the bus or him?
- Him.
- Then why are you serious?
No use.
He hates me!
- Hates...? - He thinks I'm the
spoilt child of a rich father.
Spoilt child of a rich man?
He thinks something
similar about you too.
He says you're
responsible for spoiling me.
You didn't raise me well.
Where is he?
I want to meet him.
- I want to meet him.
- Don't know.
I must meet him. It's urgent!
This wedding has to be stopped.
Stop it. Stop!!
- This marriage is wrong.
- Daddy...
Send the groom back!
I want the boy!
I don't want to trouble you more.
The boy was right. I kept
running around without thinking.
What did I want?
Now I must stop somewhere.
I must hold somebody's hand.
You've changed.
You were a kid when
you bolted from the ship.
But you've returned as a woman.
This boy must have a hand in this.
- The boy! I want the boy!
- You won't find Raghu now.
Who won't be found?
What's his full name?
What is this?
Nothing... no...
''Mr. Dharamchand, I want to
talk to you about money.''
Concerning your daughter.
- Will you see him?
- I'll have to.
He found you so I must reward him.
Do meet him and don't
forget to reward him.
He was good company
during the journey.
And do tip him.
Pooja...!
- Where's Pooja?
- Upstairs.
I've come to take you.
Get dressed. We're
going to a grand party.
''- You'll come, won't you?
- Yes.''
What's wrong with you?
Why are you standing morose?
Every year you're the life
of the party. What's it now?
I'm not in the mood.
''Forget it. At this age,
girls come and go.''
''Lf one girl leaves, will
you mope all your life? ''
Stand near the door and
receive all the guests.
You are the love of one man
But another man loves you
One man likes you
But somebody else wants you
''What is ours and
what belongs to others''
What is fact and what is fiction?
''What is ours and
what belongs to others''
What is fact and what is fiction?
Who in the world knows?
You are in one man's vision
But another steals glances
This often happens in love
''One laughs while
another sheds tears''
This often happens in love
''One laughs while
another sheds tears''
One wins while another loses
You are the life of one
''But somebody else
understands you''
I wonder how I can keep mum
''How can I bear the
pain in my heart? ''
I wonder how I can keep mum
''How can I bear the
pain in my heart? ''
''How can I say
I'm facing a dilemma? ''
You are my only companion
None other walks beside me
''Yes, this is Raghu Jaitly''
''No, I won't come home.''
I want to meet you in the office.
L; m going to Bombay in 2 days
Then I might go to America.
''Before I leave, I want
to clear your account.''
But I don't want to come
in the midst of the wedding.
That's none of your concern.
Come straight to my personal room.
All right.
I want to see your son-in-law
comes for marriage or a circus.
- I hear he'll come in a chopper
- Yes.
Let's see this spectacle
What's the victory of love?
Who is it?
Yes.
I got your letter.
Pooja told me about you.
She never told me how you
helped her in the journey.
Your daughter is good
at forgetting favours.
Don't mistake me. I meant
she didn't tell me till lately.
''According to her,
you should get your dues.''
Really? Full dues?
That's good news.
How should it be
according to you?
I don't know. Must see what
right you have over the cash.
I wouldn't come here
if I had no right.
''Here, it's the complete account.''
- Is it in English?
- You're holding it upside down.
Sorry once again.
''Hotel rent Rs. 45, iron Rs. 2,
toothpaste 9.30 I mean 9.50.''
''Tooth brush 3.25,
repairing car Rs. 75.''
''1 cap Rs. 35, 1 shirt 45,
2 pants Rs. 235''
''1 bag 135, 1 shirt 135.''
1 girl er... lungi 37.
Total Rs. 699.55.
699.55?
I even had to sell
my socks and shaving kit.
I haven't charged for that.
- That's fine but...
- What's it? This is less.
One generally spends
a couple of 1000 on such trips.
Just a minute. First
explain this to me...
You want Rs. 699.55
apart from Rs. 100000?
What lakh?
- The reward.
- I didn't speak of that.
I'm confused. Have you
come for the reward?
I've only come for 699.55
Pay up fast. I'm
getting suffocated here.
You're quite a man.
- We'll discuss it another day.
- Another man would come for a lakh.
It's about principles.
You won't understand it.
When somebody makes a fool of me
and I have to pay the price...
I don't accept that.
Fool...?
I was made a good fool.
- Will you pay or must I leave?
- Just a minute.
Rs. 700
- What's this?
- 45 paise.
One moment.
May I ask you one question?
Yes.
Do you love my daughter?
Any man who loves your daughter
should get his head examined.
That's not the answer.
Your daughter has found
herself a good match.
A strange specimen of today's times.
Your daughter needs a man
who'll thrash her day and night.
''Lf you had any sense, you'd
have done this a lot earlier.''
Do you love my daughter?
No simple man can live
with her and not turn mad.
I want nothing to do with her.
Do you love her?
Yes but I can't be blamed.
I too am crazy.
- Hope you've got the money.
- Right.
- Congratulations.
- To you too.
Won't you stay for the wedding?
It will be fun. You probably
would never have seen it.
I don't like watching dramas.
- I spoke to Raghu.
- I don't want to hear a word.
- Listen...
But...
''Come, my dear.''
You're making a big
mistake marrying this man.
Raghu is a good boy.
He didn't come for the reward.
He wanted the money he spent on you.
Leave this marriage and run away.
I'm probably the first father
to advise his child to elope.
Before Raghu runs
away from your life...
Sit in the car I've
parked behind and go away.
Your father's honour is at stake.
How can you marry such an ass?
My heart won't pay heed
Why am I feeling anxious?
The heart is unaware
- What's wrong?
- How can I marry an ass like you?
What are you doing?
''Run away, dear! ''
''Stop, where are you going?
What is wrong with you? ''
Run away!
What's going on?
Where has Pooja gone?
She's always running away
so she ran away again!
I want to go to Bombay.
Will you please help me?
God always gives generously.
I love you
That's all I know
I couldn't have lived alone
Had I not found you...
''Distressed eyes,
anxious breath... ''
repeatedly say...
My heart does not understand
My heart knows no reason