King's Family
It's been a long time.
You and your husband are con artists.
I almost called the police, did you know?
Con artists?
You're alive and well, so I'm sure now.
You wanted to get money from me,
but how sad!
I'm not an idiot, you know?
I can't believe he tried to steal from me.
What are you talking about?
Steal what?
Tell that husband of yours.
I almost fell for his acting, crying and screaming how he must save your life.
If he hadn't stolen my things,
I wouldn't have kicked him out in his boxers.
He took his acting too far.
Hobak, it's me.
I wanted to hear your voice,
but I guess you're not picking up.
Hobak,
I'll come back when I'm successful.
I'll come back with lots of money.
This is the only way to be forgiven by you.
Take good care of Sintong and Bangtong.
Also, take good care of yourself.
Goodbye.
You have one new voice message.
Hobak, Are you alive?
You are, right?
Nothing happened to you, right?
Why won't you pick up the phone?
I lost my phone, so I'm using a pay phone.
Hobak, Hobak!
Stay alive. You must stay alive.
I'll get the money, no matter what.
I'll sell myself if I have to save you.
Hobak, stay alive until I get there.
Wang Hobak, you can do it!
You're tenacious.
Stay alive no matter what happens.
If he attacks you, you must fight back.
Kick him in the balls! Real hard!
And run away, got it?
You have to escape,
so you can get back at me.
Survive this and get back at me!
Hobak, hold on.
I'm coming to rescue you!
Hobak.
Hobak!
Is that for me?
Yes, for Christmas.
It's so pretty.
I couldn't keep my promise.
I said I'd buy you one with a diamond this big.
A pin that size would break my neck.
What do you think?
Yes, it's pretty.
Did you pick this out?
I never bought anything like that.
You never bought anything for your wife?
She thinks I don't have any style.
She likes money better.
Do you like it?
I love it.
So what's up?
Why are we meeting here?
Let me pay for the food.
No, I'm paying.
I didn't get you anything.
I couldn't get you any gift.
What if your wife finds out?
I'll get you some food, so there's no evidence.
Sunjeong.
Yes?
We...
Can't see each other again.
Thanks for everything.
Thanks to you, my father is well again.
I was pretty down,
but seeing you made me happy.
Even my family noticed it.
They asked if I'm having an affair,
saying I'm glowing.
Thanks, Sunjeong.
Someone else will deliver your packages to you.
I'm taking another area.
I gave your neighborhood to a new guy.
Don't be upset.
So this is it for us?
We can't see each other again?
I'm sorry.
Don't cry.
Eat well, and stay healthy.
Take good care of Miho.
And meet someone nice.
We'll see each other again someday.
We live in the same city,
so I'm sure we'll meet again.
Sunjeong.
Sunjeong?
But it took you so long to meet again.
Sunjeong, tell him.
I can't.
I'll tell him.
I'll meet him and tell him.
Give me his phone number.
You can't.
He has a family.
He has kids.
His kids are important, too, but what about Miho?
You have to think about Miho, too.
What good will telling him do?
He has a family and kids.
Miho has never had a dad.
She did fine without one.
I just need to keep my mouth shut.
I don't want to bring him any pain.
Come home.
Really? Are you serious?
Thanks.
Thanks for taking me back.
But there are conditions.
Anything.
First,
we're not husband and wife anymore.
What do you mean by that?
We'll stay married, only by law.
You understand, right?
I went to law school, but I don't like law.
How can we only be married by law?
- I'll work hard.
- Whatever.
We'll just be parents to our boys.
Just until Bangtong turns ten.
Ten?
That only gives me 3 years.
Stay their dad until then.
That's the first condition for coming home.
If you're not happy with it, say so.
No, I'm fine with it.
Second.
I'm home.
Why are you home so early?
I hired another worker,
so I can take care of the kids.
But that will cost you a lot of money.
But that's a good idea.
Three bears
Live in one house
Daddy bear,
Mommy bear, baby bear!
You had a long day. You should rest.
You being here is a lot of help for me.
I'm sorry.
I'll work harder and make more money.
Everyone wants to make a lot of money.
Things just don't work out like that.
But you will, I'm sure.
When you and Subak argue,
I don't know what to do.
It never happened before.
Mother,
please forgive Subak for making you upset.
It's my fault for spoiling her.
What's this?
I'm making dumplings.
I'm going to make dumpling stew for dinner.
Nice.
Just hearing that is making my mouth
water, water, water.
Oh, boy.
So how long do you actually need?
You have to give me a date!
Have I ever broken my promises?
How dare you embarrass me like this
over just a few hundred thousand dollars?
So? When are you wiring the money?
Fine.
Oh, this is crazy.
Why? Is it bad?
It's not bad.
The longer it's tied up, the more interest I'll get.
It's your money that's bothering me.
It's okay. I can wait.
Grandmother's good at making dumplings.
She's upset, so she won't come out.
I'll go get her.
Grandmother.
Hey!
Don't open my door without knocking!
Where did you learn your manners?
Did your father teach you that?
I'm sorry, grandmother. Keep eating.
I wasn't eating anything!
Uh, well...
Okay.
He's so dense. Ugh!
She's eating buns.
I knew it!
She's waiting for my husband to come home.
Even after a big bowl of rice,
around the time my husband comes home,
she lies down, acting all sick, and says,
"You're home?"
I lost my appetite.
Egh, hyo, hyo, hyo.
That's her favorite line.
You want us to fight?
Scream at me, as if you're angry.
She won't eat?
It was the red bean cake.
She didn't have a proper meal but has been snacking all day.
Hurry up and start screaming.
But I'm not angry.
You couldn't become a singer and you didn't marry the miller's daughter. Get mad!
What's wrong with you?
How dare you talk like that to me?
And you just do whatever you want!
I'm the head of this family!
So take good care of my mother!
My mother is more important to me! Got it?
Do that again and I'll kick you out!
Hobak's not getting away with this.
I'm going to destroy her.
He's never been on a ship before.
How am I supposed to go on?
How am I supposed to eat?
I'm more worried about us than Sedal.
We don't have any money to move out.
Mom!
Huh?
What was that?
It's Sedal.
- Sedal.
- Mom.
Oh, Sedal...
What happened? Huh?
You didn't leave?
Hobak.
I brought him because the boys miss him.
Good. Good for you. God will bless you.
You won't find a woman like Hobak anywhere.
You look so good together. Perfect height.
You said I was too tall for a woman.
You said a woman should be petite.
When?
If I were tall like you, I wouldn't be here.
I would've become Miss Korea.
Sedal, congratulations.
Mom was crying so hard for you.
- Where are the boys?
- In bed.
Did you eat?
You must be hungry.
Hey, make Sedal dinner.
I already ate.
Get me some water.
Okay.
Oh, my.
We're out of barley tea, so make some.
And don't run the laundry machine at night.
Okay, I got it.
Hey, what are you doing?
What do you mean?
Here, water.
What do you think you're doing?
Why, mom?
I could bring her water.
Tell mother what's going on.
Later.
Why later?
She'll find out eventually.
Have a seat. Sit.
What is it?
Mother,
Sedal's going to do all the housework.
In other words, he'll be the housewife.
What? Housewife?
So Sedal's going to cook from now on? Wow!
Shut up.
You have no respect for your husband!
How dare you turn him into a housewife?
Yeongdal and I make money,
so why are you making my son do this?
What's wrong with that?
Lots of men do it these days.
Let them do whatever they want.
But I'd rather die than to
see my young son cook and do laundry.
I didn't raise him to become a housewife.
After my husband died, I treasured my son.
So how dare you belittle him like this?
What do you think about that?
Uh, I think she's wrong.
Did you hear that, mother?
We made an agreement, so go along with it
or move out if you can't handle it.
But this is how we're going to live.
You agreed to do this?
Yes.
Mom, don't get mad.
Just accept it.
One of my friends is doing it, and he loves it.
It's stress free. I can do it.
But you don't know how to do anything!
You can't even grill a piece of meat!
You can discuss it, if you want.
I'm tired. I'm going to bed.
Don't forget to check the boys school bags
and make soup for them for breakfast.
And read the manuals for the rice cooker,
laundry machine and vacuum cleaner.
Ask the maintenance office about the trash,
or you can ask the woman across the hall.
Okay, I got it.
Oh, boy...
Thank you, my sons.
Sons are always on their dads side.
Thanks to you, dad came home.
You guys are amazing.
I will be good to you.
And make up for the past mistakes.
Okay?
I'm home.
Jungji, go to sleep.
I don't want to come home.
They won't even say hi back.
I want to move out as soon as possible.
Even my parents treat me like a stranger.
It's your fault.
Make up with your mother.
I said those out of anger.
Put yourself in my shoes.
How could I say anything nice?
She lost my kid!
Regardless.
Apologize to your father, too.
But he slapped me.
He's your father.
You can't scream at him for slapping you.
I would've done the same in his shoes.
You're saying I deserved it?
You did.
Make up with your mother first.
And your father will forgive you.
Oh, man.
Order me some pig's feet.
Mom, stop begin angry. I'm sorry.
Forget it.
Tada! Your favorite, pig's feet.
Let's have a drink and make up.
I said forget it.
Mom, I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
Mom.
Mom, you know I never hold grudges.
I hate those who say whatever they want and say, "I don't hold grudges."
How can you say that to your daughter?
I learned a big lesson.
Never live with your children after you marry them off.
Daughters or sons, they are strangers.
It's okay to live close, but not together.
You always have run ins.
We never used to fight before.
Everyone envied our relationship.
But now, we argue everyday.
It's because of my kids.
I'm sorry, mom.
Let's try to be friends while I'm here.
You're moving out?
Eventually.
When I have enough money, I'm moving out.
How will you get the money?
Wait and see.
I'll send you and father on a trip.
I'll send you to Jeju Island.
It's okay.
We're making up because you're my daughter.
If you weren't, I'd never see you again.
If you ever pick on me again,
I'm going to kick you out.
I got it.
Mom, let's eat.
No, not that.
Eat this. Eat this one.
Say ah!
Was this Minjung's idea?
Who cares who's idea this was?
I was going to make up with you anyway.
It's been a long time, right?
Make us separate beds.
I was going to.
I was keeping your spot warm.
I wasn't trying anything.
Okay.
I'm done. I'll sleep here.
Here.
Lie down.
You know, right?
I know. I won't cross the line.
Should I give you a massage?
I told you. We're only pretending.
Don't lay a hand on me.
I'm letting you sleep here because I don't
want the boys finding out that this is all fake.
I know.
Honey, what should I make for breakfast?
Don't talk to me unless I talk to you first.
Yes, ma'am.
Don't call me ma'am. It's gross.
Okay.
- Turn the lights off.
- Okay.
Don't make any noise.
Okay.
I won't even breathe noisily.
Go back to sleep. Sleep.
Where's the rice?
Come on out, Mr. Rice.
I can't throw this out.
This was my first pot.
We started out with just this pot.
I made soy bean paste and kimchi stew here.
We were so happy back then.
Yes.
Let's be happy again, like back then.
Okay.
Where's the rice?
Sintong! Bangtong!
It's dad.
Wake up, wake up. It's dad.
- Dad!
Why is dad making breakfast?
He's going to do it from now on.
He'll cook and do the chores.
When you come home from school,
he'll be here.
Wow! How exciting!
I love having dad home every day.
Where's mother?
She said she won't eat if he has to cook.
Okay.
Huh?
What's wrong with this?
It's not cooked.
You said you made rice.
Yes, I pressed the button here.
What's wrong with this?
You pressed the wrong button.
I told you to read the manuals!
You can't even cook rice?
I did read it.
Sedal, make some noodles.
Hello.
Sit.
How have you been?
Did you have lunch?
You didn't tell Sangnam about meeting me?
No.
Don't tell him. He'll be worried.
Okay.
Why aren't you calling me mother?
Excuse me?
Don't just say "okay," and "excuse me."
And "mother" at the end.
What? You don't respect me?
I'm your mother in law.
Yes, mother.
Sangnam didn't tell you about me, right?
He hasn't said much.
We're not living together,
but Sangnam is my son.
You don't need to know anything more.
Give me respect as Sangnam's mother.
Understand?
- Yes.
- Again?
Yes, mother.
What are you doing about the wedding gifts?
We're not giving any gifts.
And we're having a small wedding.
What wedding?
You're not giving any wedding gifts?
You're funny.
Did you actually think you could do that?
Because he only had a dad?
You should've discussed it with me first.
Even a small wedding is a big deal.
You have to cover the basics.
I'm not asking for a mink coat, brand name handbag, or a diamond ring.
Just give me cash.
You told me to keep it for you.
Was that a lie?
It's not that.
I need some money.
Why? You're not buying wedding gifts.
Take it, then.
Did you think I'd use your money?
No, mom.
I'm sorry.
Hello.
Oh, hello.
Is there anything new?
You already bought everything here.
Our products are not good enough for you.
Remember the toner I bought before?
Can I have another one?
I want to give it to someone I work with.
Excuse me...
I forgot to give you some samples.
Pick some.
You can take more.
It's okay. I'll only take one.
I'll be back tomorrow for another one.
Excuse me,
thank you for coming to my store.
So I was thinking,
I'd like to treat you to dinner.
I'll buy.
I don't care who buys.
I thought you were Sangnam.
You whistle, too?
Jangbi,
here.
What is it?
It's the toner i use, and it smells nice.
Thank you, but you've been acting
like a skin care product sales person.
You buy some every day.
A friend of mine open a new store.
Let's go out for a drink.
Not tonight. I have plans. Maybe next time.
Mom.
Mom, I'm sorry.
Don't be and I don't need a hug.
I know you're disappointed in me.
I wish I could give it all to you,
but I think I need a bit of emergency cash.
I don't even have a job.
I don't want to live off my husband's salary.
And I don't know when I'll get published.
I don't want to ask my husband for money.
I didn't say anything.
It's your money.
Mom,
I opened an account for you.
It's not a lot, but it's yours.
Use it to buy whatever you want to.
I have to go out. I'll see you later.
It's me!
Really?
Yes. I'm giving him 3 years.
And I'm going to make my decision.
You're such a fool.
Why would you take him back?
She's doing it because of the boys.
It's not just because of the boys.
A woman shouldn't be so cold hearted.
You should look the other way sometimes.
Better the devil you know.
He's the father of your kids, so giving him a chance is good.
If you made that decision on your own, good.
Sedal is going to be doing the housekeeping.
He'll do everything.
Really?
Did he say yes?
I'm sure he did. He wanted to come home.
Anyway, he cooked breakfast today.
He cooked rice and soup.
Tell him to get a job.
Don't let him stay home and do housework.
Anyone can do housework.
Anggeum, you shouldn't say that.
Remember how you complained about it?
A man should go out and make money.
He has no skills or experience.
How can he get a job at his age?
The boys are young,
and I need someone to look after them
and take care of the household for free.
Good for you!
Make him work hard.
Goof-off needs to learn a lesson.
Make him work like a dog.
He still has a long way to go.
He really does.
Make sure he changes completely.
I'm planning on it.
I thought you wanted to drink.
I'm going off alcohol for a while.
You? I can't believe that.
I don't feel like drinking.
How's your wedding planning going?
There isn't much to plan.
Just a wedding dress and food.
So everyone except your uncle is married.
We still have Haebak and Daebak.
I should get a poofy dress because I don't have curves, right?
You must feel sorry for your single uncle.
I kind of do.
Can you help me pick a dress?
You have an eye for that stuff.
Your uncle didn't say anything?
I don't know how he feels, but he hasn't...
I think he gave up.
He's turning thirty-six. Ugh!
He's not seeing anyone?
I think he's going out on blind dates.
He is?
He's meeting lots of women?
But nobody seems to like him.
Who'd want to marry my uncle?
You never know.
He's my uncle, so I don't know,
but I don't think he's very attractive.
What do you mean?
He's plenty attractive!
Those women just don't know anything.
Do you think my uncle is attractive?
Well, I've known him since I was little.
He's not that bad.
Wow.
You're the only one who thinks so. Thanks.
I'm not saying I'm in love with him.
I know, girl.
You hate men like my uncle.
Yeongdal, can you set him up with someone?
But I don't know anyone!
All my friends are your friends, too.
Oh, Sina! Park Sina!
She's single, right?
Not her.
She was never without a boyfriend since high school.
Don't try to match him up with just anyone.
Your uncle must have a type.
You...
Weren't so great that night.
You're home late.
Were you out on a date?
No, I met up with Yeongdal.
Yeongdal? Why?
She wanted to know how my wedding plans were going.
What do you talk about when you meet?
About different things.
Are you curious?
I was wondering what women talk about.
You should start dating.
We talked about you tonight.
About me?
What about?
Did she badmouth me?
Of course.
You expected compliments?
Why would she do that?
Badmouthing a perfectly fine man like me.
It's not like she's perfect.
She can't even take care of herself.
That's not true.
Her salary is pretty high.
And now that she's got money,
she's not even looking for rich men.
She used to always talk about rich men,
how a handsome face is useless.
But she changed.
She doesn't even drink.
There's something different about her.
Maybe she did something regrettable after drinking.
Maybe she got sick from drinking.
Why am I so thirsty?
She can't be making that much money.
Is she seeing anyone?
I think she's taking a break.
She's not the type who'd take a break.
And she didn't say anything else?
No.
Uncle, you're being weird.
Are you interested in Yeongdal?
I was joking.
I know you two aren't a good match.
Besides, you're not interested in her.
But we went all the way,
thanks to that darn alcohol.
I'm going to quit drinking, too.
Suction.
Stealth brush sterilization...
You don't see Don anymore?
I've been busy and he's been busy, too.
But you two are friends.
I'm sure Don's lonely, too.
He is because he doesn't have a girlfriend.
What's going on?
Why are you calling him Don?
You always called him Loser.
I should give him more respect.
He's 6 years older than me.
Clean this up.
Hobak will get mad.
What's...
Hi. Isn't it cold outside?
Thank you for all your hard work today!
What happened here?
Oh,
I took it apart to clean it, but it's hard.
I'll put it back together by tomorrow.
Why would you take it apart?
I'll put it back together, no matter what...
Don't bother.
Oh!
I haven't been to a place like this in a while.
You don't come to places like this often?
I haven't gone on a date in decades.
I see.
Do you have any children?
I have a son and daughter,
and I'm living with my son's family.
I want them to move out,
but they insisted on living with me.
I'm going to live with my son after he gets married, too.
You should teach your daughter in law well.
Young women these days are so shrewd
that they think they're above you.
I won't let that happen.
You should raise your voice.
They should be grateful.
You shouldn't let her mistreat you.
I think you're too sweet, that's why.
I'm so soft hearted that I pass out when someone screams.
Right.
I saw that in you before.
You need someone to protect you.
Here. Have a drink.
Oh, I can't drink very much.
I'll teach you how to drink properly.
Having a drink with a nice person.
That's the greatest joy in my life.
Then teach me.
I will.
Here.
Cheers.
Oh, I feel tingly inside.
It's hot.
Oh.
Look at your plate.
You didn't eat much.
I'm not a big eater.
I can't even take big bites.
I can see that.
We have a lot in common.
I know how hard it is to raise kids alone.
I'm glad.
I thought you had a wife who took care of you,
so I was surprised to hear you are single.
How lonely you must have been at night.
I writhed in agony every night.
Oh, I'm dizzy.
I feel drunk already.
Seeing you made me happy.
Eat well,
and stay healthy.
Take good care of Miho.
Uncle!
Girl!
Why would you say uncle?
You always call for a man when you're scared.
Why don't you just say "Daese!"
How did you get in?
I climbed over the wall.
You kept the door open just for me.
Get out.
This is my son's house.
I told you not to sit there!
Did you introduce Sangnam to that girl?
You met her?
Of course.
I'm her mother in law.
I thought you went out to dinner.
My glasses.
I'll read it to you.
Meeting you tonight was...
Meeting you tonight was the best thing
that has ever happened to me.
My heart is pounding at the thought of
this turning into something special.
Good night. With love.
Mom, what are you doing?
It's nothing.
Who is it?
Nobody.
Me too.
I don't think I'll be able to sleep tonight.
Honey.
How dare you come here?
Get out right now!
Why did you let this woman in?
I didn't. The door was open.
Get out! Right now!
I'm sorry.
Please forgive me.
Forgive you?
You don't even deserve to use those words!
Honey, please.
Honey.
Get up.
Don't you dare help her up.
Father!
Get out!
I will.
I can't even go to my son's wedding.
I should just die.
Sangnam, have a nice wedding.
I will pray for your happiness.
I'm sorry.
Father.
She came to see us.
Let her come to the wedding.
No.
I'm not going to live with her.
And I don't want to see her again.
But she gave birth to me.
I don't feel right not inviting her.
When did you meet her?
How many times did you meet her?
You've already fallen for her act?
Sangnam, go upstairs.
Sangnam, Sangnam!
How long have they been meeting like this?
Did you know about this?
I found out recently.
They met a few times.
He's lost his mind.
She might be up to her old tricks.
Don't worry.
I won't let her come to Sangnam's wedding.
I'd rather die.
I have a plan.
I'm so upset.
The girl is so shrewd.
I talked to her but who knows?
Anyway, wait until I come home with money.
I almost won Sangnam over.
if he's on my side, it'll work out.
Darling, I miss you, too.
He's here. Bye.
You didn't have to come all this way.
I told you not to.
I'm sorry.
Why should you be?
I'm the one who's sorry.
You're leaving?
I should.
You saw how your father acted.
I only want one thing.
All I want is to see you be happy.
Your father was always so cold to me.
And he still is.
Don't go.
Come to my wedding.
It's my wedding.
Are you crazy?
Why are you going through my phone?
You have no class.
Can we talk?
Yes, honey.
I just washed my face.
What are you doing on Christmas?
Nothing much.
You're not having a party with your kids?
Things are too crazy for that.
Then want to have a party, just you and me?
A party? Really?
Okay. Honey, I'll see you tomorrow.
Oh, you scared me.,
Why were you eavesdropping?
How rude.
We need to talk.
About what?
Come with me.
What is it?
It's cold.
Why do we have to talk out here?
Your parents will hear us if we talk at home.
What is it?
Be honest with me.
About what?
Who is he?
Who do you mean?
The man you were on the phone with.
It wasn't a he. It was a friend.
What's wrong with you?
Are you cheating on me?
Why would I cheat on you?
You stay out all night,
and you get secret text messages.
It's not normal.
Are you seeing someone?
You must be crazy.
How can I be seeing a man?
You know how busy I am with work.
Are you losing your mind?
You should see a doctor.
I will if I have to,
so be honest with me.
Your condition looks really serious.
I can come home late when I have lots of work,
and I can come home in the morning
after taking a trip outside the city.
Why would you eavesdrop?
And you call yourself a man?
You have no class.
Don't try to turn me into a psychopath.
Or a man with no class.
You don't call a friend honey and kiss her.
Woman do that with friends.
Don't pick a fight with me like this.
You should go see a doctor tomorrow.
You need to quit your job.
What?
Quit it right now!
I don't believe this.
Just who do you think you are?
You brought me here in the cold to tell me that?
Unbelievable.
I want a divorce, then.
What?
Are you scared?
Then stop doing stuff like this.
You think I'm an idiot?
I have pride and I can be stubborn.
So?
You know how hard I'm trying here?
To protect this family,
for Aeji and Jungji, I'm being so patient.
Whatever you were doing, stop it.
I can forgive you this once.
Who do you think you are?
I'm still your husband.
Whatever happens next,
it won't be my responsibility.
You're leaving already?
Yes.
Eat first. I'll whip something up for you.
It's okay. I'll see you later.
What is it?
It's Minjung.
He's been skipping breakfast.
Sometimes he looks okay,
other times unhappy.
It must be because of work.
Parcel service is hard work.
Hurry up!
Have a nice day.
Buy groceries with this.
Did you see the delivered vegetables?
I didn't.
We get this every week,
so don't buy vegetables.
Just get a bit of meat, fish and fruit.
Don't buy too much at once.
I'll take care of this so you go to work.
Don't drink too much.
Come home early.
Hobak, why are you getting so many texts?
Are they spam?
They are worse than spam.
I'm pregnant.
What did you just say?
Did I hear right?
I didn't imagine it, did I?
I thought you should know.
Rudolph the red nosed reindeer
Had a very shiny nose
And if you ever saw it...
Merry Christmas!
Hello.
Yes, hello.
Oh, my! This is crazy!
Do you like it?
Of course.
How do I look?
Perfect, right?
I was in the Miss Korea pageant.
Let's go.
We should have a party.
I'm so happy.
What was that?
There is some hormone.
Anyway, I'm filled with lots of it.
Why don't they give hormones easy names?
So I could remember it.
Aeji, this is from your future uncle.
Thank him later.
Okay, aunt.
Lucky you! You got a gift from your uncle.
I don't need any gifts.
I just want Haebak to get accepted into a good school.
Did you send your application?
Yes.
Aeji, call your dad.
Tell him to hurry home.
When is Seoul National University sending acceptance letters?
Not for a while.
He must be really busy tonight.
Don said he's really busy, too.
I heard.
Oh, how about Subak?
She said she's coming after her meeting.
Dad.
Yes, Aeji.
Dad will come home right after I'm done.
Dad, I'm putting aunt on the phone.
Minjung, are you coming home late?
I'm trying to hurry up, but I might be.
This is my last Christmas at home.
You should be here.
Of course I'll be there.
Did Subak come home?
Okay.
Thank you for the gift.
I kept my promise.
You're a true man.
And that's why I fell in love with you.
Who's been calling you?
My husband wants me home.
Answer it.
- What is it?
- Where are you?
At the office.
I'm in a meeting.
Aeji's been calling me about
having a party at home.
Can you go home now?
But I'm working!
I'm really busy.
- I'm hanging up.
- Subak!
Minjung.
Hello.
I better go.
are you crazy?
Why did you hit him?
I want a divorce!
Fine.
Let's get a divorce.
Subtitles by KBS World
It's not much but I tried my best.
You think I'm an idiot?
I have a confession to make.
I get scared when you say that.
Is everything okay at home?
Nobody's been calling or dropping by?
No, why?
Why are you sitting so close together?
You look great together, sitting side by side.
Don't associate with Loser.
How can this happen?
How can they send this?
Daese, calm down.
I can't calm down! I won't!
Father, I'm getting a divorce.