Okay.
God damn it! Just load!
What the...?
Son of a bitch.
♪ Won't fall for it ♪
♪ You can't see ♪
♪ And you can't tell ♪
♪ I just can't drink
from the poisoned well ♪
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com
You have reached T-West.
Press 1 for Spanish,
3 for English.
Press 1 for phone.
Press 2 for Internet.
Press ...
- Hey, man.
- Hey, Bernie.
Yeah, you got a tire.
Yeah, yeah.
Press 1 for billing.
Press 2 for customer service.
Press 3 for technical help.
Press...
Hey, man,
you're being watched.
Oh, God damn it.
When the hell
did he get here?
Uh, 4:15 A.M.,
7:15 Eastern.
We've actually been
watching each other.
We have an understanding.
All right, all right.
Well, that's... that's my dad.
Huh.
You have a dad.
That's nice.
Long story short,
I had one.
Yeah? Well, that's mine,
and that's his house.
Press 1 for hardware issues.
Press 2 for connection issues.
You need a tire?
No, I'm good on tires.
I'm using
the barter system.
All right. Okay. Well,
I'm still on the money system.
- Press 1 for ...
- Come... come on!
I-I just... I don't have time to
deal with this shit right now.
I don't want to deal with it.
He's just sitting out there.
He wants me to go out there
and see what's going on.
Classic
bullshit power play.
Yeah. Or maybe he just pulled up
and had a heart attack.
'Cause that's
how my dad died.
But that was on a boat.
Short story long.
Press 1 for...
C-Come on, come on, come on!
I need to talk to a person!
A person!
A person, God damn it!
Ah. You're ordering
a pizza.
What? No, I'm on the phone with
my bullshit Internet company.
Man, you got to steer clear
of that shit!
You know, like, they watch you.
They hunt you.
That's why
I carry an antenna.
They can't track your stuff
through an antenna.
Okay. All right.
Well, I need Wi-Fi.
Thanks for waiting.
How can I help you?
Yes. Hello? Hi.
Yes, my Internet's been
going on and off for two days.
I'd like
to get it fixed now.
I'm very sorry, sir. Please hold
while I check your signal.
A sconce.
I could really use
a sconce.
No, Bernie.
I-I-I don't want a tire,
and I like my sconce.
I-I-I-I'll sweeten
the deal.
I'll throw in
a bunch of bricks
and a piece of a bird bath...
beautiful.
Oh, here we go.
Mr. Maron, I'm going to need you
to restart your modem.
Yeah, okay.
I can do that.
Where...
where's my son?
Oh, he's inside,
giving the feds access
to all his information.
I just want
to say goodbye to my son.
Oh, what does that
even mean?
And I always wanted you
to have this.
That looks new.
Yeah, well, I got it
a couple weeks ago.
And it means a lot.
That's bullshit.
Excuse me?
No, no.
Not... not... not you.
I have a giant, sad,
annoying baby on my lawn.
We can send out
a repairman tomorrow
between noon and 4:00 P.M.
Okay, great.
What are you doing?
You're just gonna
drop that and leave?!
Sir, can you write down
the 10-digit repair code?
Yeah, yeah.
Just give me the number.
4-7-4-4-3-2-8-9-8-9.
Okay. Thanks.
God damn it!
I'll trade you
the knife for the tire.
No.
The data light is out.
Yeah,
it keeps doing that.
Oh. There it...
Back on.
E-E-E... Off again.
Right. That's why
you're here, man.
Man.
Your cable from your router
to your modem...
it's all chewed on.
What do you have...
rats?
No. I have cats.
Boom!
Nailed it.
Shit!
Hey! Cable dude!
Hey! Hey, stop!
Come on! Hey! Hey!
I can't upload my shit!
Well, he didn't fix it,
all right?
He just left
two minutes ago,
and now it's doing
the same thing it was before.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Do you have your repair number?
Yeah, I do.
I do have it.
Uh, 4-7-4-4-3-2-8-9-8-9.
Nope, it's not coming up.
I'll give you another one.
- Ready?
- Yes.
- "A" as in "apropos"...
- Okay.
..."S" as in "shame."
Wait... what?
..."4" as in "4"...
What?
...7, 8...
"L" as in "llama"...
"O" as in "orifice"...
1.
Now I'm gonna send you
up to Tier 2.
Great, because whatever's
happening at this level
is clearly not working.
Hello, Mr. Maron.
How may I provide you
with excellent service today?
- You can fix my Internet.
- Very good.
First,
let me to apologize
for the problems
what you've been experiencing.
Whatever.
Let's just fix it.
And I'm going to help you
with that.
My name is Jeff.
Really?
What's your real name?
Jeffrey.
All right, I think we both
know what's happening here.
If we could just
focus on your Internet,
would you most kindly
restart your modem for me?
No, I've done that already.
That's not the issue.
And how am I gonna
trust you, Jeffrey,
if you are lying
about who you are?
Mr. Maron, I'm going to
schedule a specialist
to come to your home tomorrow
between 8:00 A.M. and noon
if it is most convenient.
Is there
anything else, sir?
Yeah... just that
you're full of shit, Jeff.
What an asshole.
I want
my Internet fixed now.
No bullshit.
That's why I'm here.
Yeah, well,
I want it actually fixed.
None of this, like,
"some shit that makes it
seem fixed" business.
Look, that last guy
was a consultant.
I actually work
for T-West.
I'm gonna get your Internet
running today.
Yeah, I'll believe it
when I see it, pal.
Hey. Look at me.
I got this.
Yeah, great. The last guy
showed me the lights, too.
But when he left,
they all went out.
I'm just
getting started, Marc.
Can I... call you "Marc"?
Yeah, I guess.
Thank you, Marc.
Thank you.
So, the modem is good.
Now let's go check out
that utility box.
Okay, can we...
can we...
can we do it
with less winking?
Could...
Would that be possible?
It's just past
this RV here.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Hey!
What's going on?!
Dad!
Come on!
Talk to me!
Hey, hey!
Where are you...
What are you doing? What are...
Hey, hold this for a second,
will you?
Huh? Yeah.
You trust this guy?
Yeah, it's the cable guy.
It's his job to fix it.
There's too many wires,
man.
Wires are liars!
Wires are wires.
But I understand
the apprehensiveness.
I don't think you do
understand my apprehensiveness.
Well,
everything looks good
with your modem
and your utility box.
They are primo.
All right, so what the hell are
we gonna do about my Internet?
Well, I'm gonna have
one of our specialists come out,
a guy who knows
a lot more than me.
Shouldn't be too hard to find
a guy like that, should it?
Hey.
We're gonna
get this done.
'Cause I care about you.
T-West cares about you.
It's a sign, man.
Antennas.
All right, what's going on, Dad?
Talk to me.
"The memories flicker
across my mind
like brown leaves
in the wind."
"I wait for the twist.
It comes like a fist.
Another bris.
Everything is amiss.
The waves
crash against my soul.
The murky filled bowl
is a dirty koi pond."
Yeah.
Exactly.
He gets it.
All right, okay. Okay.
You know what?
It's garbage,
and it's manipulative.
What's the point
of living?
My life's been
a disaster.
Disaster's exciting!
You don't know
what you got
until it's ripped open
and the juice is loose!
All right, well,
you both seem to have
an equal level of bullshit
going on,
so I'm gonna go inside,
and you two guys
can talk tires and poetry.
And maybe when you stop crying,
you can come inside
and we'll try to have
a conversation of some kind.
Yeah, sounds reasonable.
Okay. Perfect.
So, we start out in life
with these people who we have
these intense feelings about
and they're bigger than life
to us, and they're just people.
And then we grow up,
and sometimes you change roles,
where you're ending up
taking care of these people
who are
so important to you.
- I know.
- It's hard, right?
And if you don't
have good boundaries...
And you're not alone.
Obviously, a lot of people
deal with complex family issues.
I know. And they just go on
and on and on.
They do go on. They go on...
That's across the life-span.
They're things
that just keep going
and we have to
keep contending with them.
I know, but, like...
Okay, so, at some point,
it's like
things don't work out,
and then you just
have to deal with it
and hope
you don't suffer too much.
Well, you have to accept.
And then acceptance can lead
to happiness sometimes.
Oh, I don't know
about happiness.
But, you know,
I have to accept
that this podcast
might not be posted
because
my Internet is broken.
There's nothing
I can do about it
because my Internet company
is a monopoly.
And that is
a lot like family, too.
Is it?
Who's your Internet company?
T-West. But that's... that's...
that's getting us way off topic.
You're telling me
that you're just accepting
that you have
garbage Internet?
No, I-I actually have
a pretty good situation.
Really?
What do you mean?
They gave me a special number,
and if I have a problem, I call,
and they take care
of everything.
What?!
You have a special number?
They gave you
a number to call?
Can I have the number,
please?
Well, they...
Marc, they gave it to me.
I-I don't think I can just
give it out to anyone.
What... what?
You're better than me?
You're higher than me
on the celebrity power rankings?
Dr. Drew is higher than me?
I think we're equals at least.
I... Marc, I think
this is about something
far more
than just the Internet.
Just 'cause I have family issues
doesn't mean I can't be upset
that Dr. Drew has
some magic bat-phone to T-West.
I don't think
that's exactly what I'm saying.
What are you saying?
I don't have the number.
Dad!
What?!
All right.
Just checking.
I'm dying, son.
I'm dying.
Okay.
How do you know
you're dying?
I know.
This is
exactly what you do.
Do you know
how many times in my life
you've told me
that you're dying?
This time,
I can feel it.
Oh, really?
What does dying feel like?
Dark.
I never thought
I would say this,
but I'm...
I'm actually grateful
to have to deal with
my shitty Internet right now.
Oh, look...
it's the specialist.
Modem's in here.
I don't need to see it.
What?
You've had two guys
look at it.
Forget it.
It's pointless.
I was reading over
your repair report.
And, uh...
It's... it's shit.
It's... it's just shit.
You know what I was thinking
about when I was reading this?
"Cool hand Luke."
The system's
not gonna change.
They need you to break.
They need you to give in.
And if they can't,
they'll kill you.
Okay, well, that's...
that's pretty intense.
But, uh, I just
want my Internet to work.
You think T-West cares
if you have a good connection?
No, I don't.
You're goddamn right,
they don't.
The whole setup
is a joke.
So, I'm... I'm taking it
you're not a company man.
I'm gonna tell you something
that nobody
on your side of the fence
is supposed to know.
Come here.
It's the node.
It's the goddamn node.
The node, huh?
The node.
That's it right there.
That's the node.
Ahhhh.
What's it do?
It's a redistribution
point.
The signal goes into the node,
and then it sends the Internet
out to everybody
in the neighborhood.
Oh.
And it's broken?
Nope... overloaded.
Oh, we got
an overloaded node.
Yep.
Needs to be split.
We need
a node splitter?
Yep.
But that could
take weeks.
Why?
Because T-West doesn't
split the node
unless it's at 87%.
Yours is at 83%.
So I just have to live with
an overloaded node?
That's it.
Yeah. Bullshit.
They don't care.
It's total bullshit.
- Well, hey, Bernie.
- Hey.
- Will you hold that for me for one second?
- Sure.
What's happening?
Even trade.
Sure. Whatever.
I just broke the chains.
I'm a free man.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Hoo-hoo-hoo!
Ahhhhh!
There.
There!
God damn it.
Good evening.
This is Tier 3.
I didn't even know
there was a Tier 3.
Do you need my, uh,
10-digit repair number?
Nope. I'm looking at your report
right now.
Oh, my God.
I can't believe
what you've been through.
Look,
I know about the node.
I need a node splitter.
Yeah, I don't know
what a node splitter is.
Sorry.
Nothing more we can do.
Wait! Wait!
I know Dr. Drew.
In that case, you can expect
a call from Tier 4.
Hello?
Dad?
Hey, man.
How's it going?
Who's this?
Oh, come on, Marc.
You know who this is.
This is Tier 4.
Hey.
Do you need
my 10-digit repair number?
No.
Why do you give it out
if you never need it?
Well, to give people something
to hold on to... hope.
Yeah,
I'm not feeling that.
Things aren't always
what they seem, Marc.
Sometimes what's going on
is deeper and more impactful.
The real truth
is underneath.
Okay.
All right, I get that.
But I still need Internet.
Everyone needs Internet.
But that doesn't mean
that what you're feeling
right now is about the Internet,
because it's not.
It's about a deep-rooted need
for justice
and fear
of not being in control.
Yeah.
I understand that.
It's about
something deeper.
You need to stop
yelling at your girlfriends.
You need to make up
with your father.
And you need
to stop watching porn.
You don't watch a lot,
but you watch enough.
I don't watch
anything that weird.
A couple of weeks ago,
it got a little weird.
Well, yeah, but, you know, when
you get into the Baltic stuff,
you really don't know
what's gonna happen.
And then... I-I don't know.
All right,
so, what's your point?
Y-You... you want me
to engage in my life
and...
and be a better person?
Yeah.
Be a stand-up guy.
Okay.
Done.
I just split the node.
You can just do it
from there?
Yeah.
I'm the node splitter.
Sometimes
I feel completely hopeless.
Yeah.
Me too.
But not right now.
Everything's all right.
It's good to see you,
Dad.
Shit, yes!
Internet's working.
Well, now.
How about that?
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com