Timing and Subtitles brought to you by the Forget Dating, Give Me The Ring! Team
I'm okay.
I was really okay.
I usually didn't waver for most things.
I wasn't really afraid of anything either.
There was no door that wouldn't open with my strength anywhere in the world,
until I met that girl.
Joo Jang Mi!
Episode 7
Even though it's not okay, it's okay
Will you really be okay?
- I'll be okay.
- You probably won't be okay.
It's okay so give it to me.
What is it that you're being like this?
I captured the angle really well, right?
Yes, really.
That's why I said not looking would be better.
What are you doing right now?
I'm a fool.
♬  When I see you, my heart pounds and my lips dry up ♬
♬  Your face flickers before me today ♬
♬  I can't take it anymore ♬
♬  Starting from tomorrow, we will live happily together ♬
Hey... we...
Be quiet. Your aunt is watching us.
I thought you were kicking me away.
Because you really
didn't look okay.
♬ Just imagine ♬
♬ I know you want it ♬
Oh, so hot.
♬ The way you talk always mysteriously stays near my ears ♬
♬ My face grows red (and my heart gets excited) ♬
♬ Inside the square bus ♬
♬ I faintly hear a well-known song ♬
♬ At some point (falling into you) ♬
♬ What’s there to think about? ♬
♬ Wanna walk together now? (boy) ♬
♬ You know but pretend you don’t, I fall in love ♬
♬ Wanna take the subway or walking in the rain ♬
♬ Between the clouds, ♬
♬ as if it’s slippery and slowly ♬
♬ We are already walking ♬
I must be crazy.
Oh, so hot.
♬ Walking in that lane ♬
What do you mean?
That is love.
Just because it's a different way doesn't mean it isn't love.
Right?
Is that person still putting her neck out for your son's marriage?
Marriage is just one out of many different ways.
Right?
You are a bit old now so why don't you use a person?
Do you need something?
Give me a glass of water.
You know Kang Se Ah...
is there really hope between her and Gi Tae?
You liked Joo Jang Mi.
No, well...
Our Director Lee is trying to date Kang Se Ah
so they're a bit close-
I understand what you're saying.
The villain's role is always my part.
Se Ah.
Hyung, are these mushrooms or truffles?
Don't touch it, you bastard.
- Do you know how much one kilogram of this is?
- I don't know.
Five million won, five million.
Okay.
She's really diligent. She's driving me crazy.
Oh, you're here?
I missed you so much!!
Did you eat breakfast?
Why is this girl like this?
Should we eat something?
Get away from me.
You... I helped you...
Let's sit near the window.
Hey.
I think we need to straighten out what happened yesterday.
I'll straighten it out for you.
The reason why I chose you...
it was because I thought that we would never have useless things like feelings
that formed for each other.
The reason why we are doing this together is just one thing.
Um, that...
so that I could be by myself.
So... that... that...
I was hoping you wouldn't approach me if I don't need you
and I wanted to tell you to refrain from touching me uncomfortably.
Did I do it for me? It was all because of you.
I did it to help you.
Linking my arms with you just a moment ago was because your aunt was outside too.
Oh.
I'm crazy.
Because of this type of guy, my precious lips...
and on top of that in front of Han Yeo Reum.
I know. You were a bit too much.
She kisses anyone anywhere.
- No...
- That's what I'm saying.
It seemed far past necessary. She was probably just carried away by her feelings and-
Hey!
I was just-
I know. I found out roughly enough what type of person Joo Jang Mi is.
Like a fool she likes anyone, gets carried away, and can't even throw them away.
She's someone that ends up kissing a man who doesn't mean anything to her and isn't fun,
like a fool.
What do I not have?
But I like fool-like Joo Jang Mi.
Starting from today, for a month, we are having a truffle festival at Bon Weekend.
There's a special menu prepared with truffles by the chef so try eating it.
- Just a moment ago, that was a confession, right?
- No.
I think it's a confession.
Is there a confession where a girl is called a fool?
Han Yeo Reum
Come at night~!
I should leave. Bye then.
Don't you think the cost of your ingredients are excessive?
It's not even a high dining restaurant but yet you use the best quality truffles? That's excessive.
Our chef is a bit greedy when it comes to his cooking.
Are you sure you aren't harboring rat-like bastards in your kitchen?
Control your employees well.
I feel like I'm doing something bad.
I'm not bad though. I'm just thrilling.
It feels like I'm really secretly meeting a woman who's about to get married. Its fun.
Anyways, for right now, it's going to be hard to meet up.
If they find out it was fake then Gong Gi Tae they said he has to get married to someone he doesn't even like.
I don't really care though.
Because you were thinking of Gong Gi Tae, isn't that why you said to meet at night?
No. Because I want to make something good for you, I told you to come at night.
What is this?
The world's one and only egg custard.
Wait. The most important thing.
The smell is weird!
But it's good!
These are those famous truffles.
Yea, punk! I'm being serious.
The best quality truffles.
Wait a second.
Could it be Gi Tae's aunt?
Let's go!
My boss? He doesn't have time to care.
He doesn't care that I bought such expensive stuff.
Truffles!
Truffles!!
I never once thought of you as my employee. I always considered you as my person.
A person that I trust 100%. My person.
But... your response is to step on my trust like dog poop?
- I'm sorry.
- He stepped on $5000.
I kept wondering who it was that entered the kitchen secretly, I guess the bastard was you.
Tell me the truth. The one who has been pilfering the food ingredients is you, right?
Pilfering the ingredients? That wasn't me.
Hey, what do you mean its not you!
In order to seduce a girl, you used the kitchen however you wanted!
But, yea, it's true that I do cook secretly.
I'll honestly admit to what I did.
But I only used left over ingredients and the ones that were past their expiration dates.
I used the truffles because I was curious...
but besides that I really didn't touch anything else!
It's sad. I really didn't want to look at this.
CCTV. If you did something wrong, say it now. I'll forgive you.
I'll take responsibility for my wrongs.
Those kids nowadays. Even if they do wrong, they're so brazen about it!
Why don't you just fire him?
But why were you there at that time?
I... um... I... left something here.
I forgot my cellphone here.
Ah, right! I forgot I put something on top of the stove. I'll be going now.
Ah, you scared me!
You said you came to get your cellphone?
Yea, why?
When you came in here, you were talking on the phone.
How could you talk on the phone without your cellphone?
What the hell, bastard? Are you investigating me right now?
Where are you going? Aren't you coming back here?
I'm going to get $5000.
Hyeon Hee!
I thought about it a lot but I think it's best if I leave.
Even if you guys did break up, you once thought of Hoon Dong oppa as a man you were going to marry.
How could I continue to face you?
Why can't you face me? You can just look straight at me! Don't worry about it! I'm fine.
When I see you, I think of Hoon Dong Oppa.
You were really sincere with Lee Hoon Dong?
I'm sorry unnie.
What should I do?
I'm really sorry.
Hyeon Hee is outside.
Hyeon Hee sincerely likes you.
I thought it was best for Hyeon Hee if she didn't get involved with a guy like you but..
Hyeon Hee says she is dying to see you.
So please go meet her.
Are you okay with that?
With me and Hyeon Hee seeing each other?
Instead, meet her with a sincere heart.
Don't hurt her like you did with me.
How could you do this to me?
Lee Hoon Dong, we are done! Just accept it!
Because we're over, you do this?
In my restaurant, behind my back, you and Yeo Reum were lovey-dovey.
That must have been really fun.
Sorry, I didn't mean to do it like that.
But where's Han Yeo Reum?... You fired him!?
Are you worrying about that bastard in front of me right now?!
Han Yeo Reum did nothing wrong! It was because I had a situation...
Wow, you sure are an amazing woman!
During the day, you talk about marrying a Plastic Surgeon who happens to be my closet friend.
At night, you enjoy time with a younger flower boy who happens to be
the part time employee who gets paid by me. On top of that it happens to be in my restaurant where you hide and secretly
- date?
- I'm sorry,
but what you see isn't everything.
-To be honest...
- Don't say anymore.
My heart will just get hurt.
Wait!
Where are you going?
Sorry, Ms. Nam Hyeon Hee. I had someone else in my heart and I messed with you.
I'm trash.
Oppa.
Hey, Lee Hoon Dong!
Having two girls in one heart is a terrible thing to do.
And, two-timing.
Even if I were to die and come back alive, I can't comfortably two time with someone who is friends with Jang Mi.
I'm sorry.
Hey, Lee Hoon Dong!
What did I tell you?
I didn't want to do it.
Hyeon Hee...
I hate you, unnie.
Ugh, I'm going crazy!
I don't care at all!
You don't care at all?
Marriage and dating aren't different things.
There's no point in caring about a guy like Han Yeo Reum. Even if they date, at the most, it'll only last for about two months.
So I just leave them alone.
You really like Joo Jang Mi, right?
- It's heartbreaking. Just heartbreaking.
- What do you mean heartbreaking? Me?
Hey, I've met you for a while.
You're acting that cool and unaffected because you want to keep Joo Jang Mi next to you.
What is Joo Jang Mi? Is she that great?
I'm not acting cool, I am cool.
You say at the most two months but I know just by looking at you how you fuss about Han Yeo Reum.
You seem to care a lot.
I really don't care!
Your mother is already snooping around and really cares.
- My mother did?
- We talked on the phone earlier.
She asked a lot about Han Yeo Reum so
- I was going to show her what those two were exactly doing that was caught on the CCTV.
- You can't!
That's what I was going to do but didn't.
Please I beg you. Keep your mouth shut around my mom.
Aigoo, you like Joo Jang Mi to that extent?
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Go ahead and go.
Joo Jang Mi.
What happened?
Don't worry, I didn't get fired.
That..
But I've been kicked to the streets instead.
The price of the truffles that we ate turns out to be all of my fortune.
Did you pay it back with deposit money?
Sorry..because of me..
If you are sorry, will you let me sleep at your place?
Ah..You like Joo Jang Mi that much?
No...no..
Never.
You...really like Joo Jang Mi, huh?
Oh, you are home. I kept ringing the bell. Didn't you hear it?
Do me a favor.
Come in.
Hello, hyungnim.
What is this!?
Let Han Yeo Reum sleep here.
What?
Wow..the house is nice.
Why...
Ah..hyung.
Hey! Gong Gi Tae, are really going to be like this? Think about what I've done for you.
What have you done for me? For bothering me? For annoying me?
- Or pissing me off?
- For helping you with your fake marriage.
And I wasted my precious lips too!
What was the purpose of the fake marriage? I definitely told you it was so that I can live alone!
What did I tell you? Even a needle's tip wouldn't go through him.
That jerk!
Kang Se Ah
-What?
-You're still mad, huh?
You're home, right? I'm going to drop by for a bit.
Don't come. I want to be alone.
You're alone? That's good,
He says he's alone, mother.
-My mom?
- She made cucumber kimchi to give to you
but she hesitated because she was worried that it might bother you if you were with Joo Jang Mi.
Even if your mom cares for you, she cares for you too much.
It's a waste so I brought her with me.
Joo Jang Mi..Han Yeo Reum..
Do you have anywhere you can go?
For the time being, I'll just go to the sauna.
I feel so sorry. What do I do?
- I'll try to get the $5000 as fast as I can.
- It's fine.
If I accept that money, I'm not cool.
It's all because of me.
It's because of me that Gi Tae hyung is making it difficult for you. Anyways,
Kang Se Ah finding out about the secret was because of me, so let's call it even.
Hey, why are you guys still here?
Hey, Han Yeo Reum did it for our sake!
We were just about to leave. Let's go.
What are you doing?
-Mother is coming, mother.
-Go in! Go in!
Ah, great.
You've arrived, mother?
Ah.
You weren't alone?
I meant that I didn't want to be disturbed.
Anyways, thanks for coming out together.
I came to see her off.
You're not supposed to do that to someone who came to see you.
What were you thinking of bringing Se Ah over. You think I don't know you're intentions?
If mother had intentions, it would be to make sure her son is living well and eating well.
What's that?
I'm sorry, but take it back. Since it'll just be thrown away without being eaten.
-Gong Gi Tae..
- It's so wasteful, why throw it away?
Don't worry. I will clean everything off and eat it all.
If you were going to bring side dishes you could have told me. Why did you come with Se Ah?
That's because I've been friends with Se Ah for some time.
Not because you hate me?
You're against me, right?
If you're going to be against me like this,
our Gi Tae may have to live alone forever.
You dare..to threaten me?
I'm just worried. The Gong family might end.
Don't worry. I'm not against you, it's a misconception.
Then that's a relief. I want to be closer to you.
Going shopping, eating good food,
leaving the manner-less Gong Gi Tae out, let us girls have a date sometime.
Ugh, don't.
Let's go.
Bye, Mother-in-law.
Go ahead and go.
I'll make sure you will live alone for the rest of your life but just live with him for a few days.
If mother sees Han Yeo Reum and I walking down the street together.
It seems she's been keeping an eye on us. How are you going to explain that to her?
Huh?
Whoa..this is nice.
- Ugh, that Gong Gi Tae, really?
- Touching anything in this house is forbidden!
Ah..Nemo. Nemo-ah, hi! Unnie is here again.
Woah, the bathroom is so cool!
Bathroom is forbidden!
I'm hungry, do you want to order something to eat? I'll buy.
Delivery food is not allowed.
Ah, my belly.
This..ramen. I'm really good at making ramen.
Searching is forbidden. Eating is forbidden!
Don't make the house smell.
- Then what can I do?
- The time that is given to you is from 11 PM to 7 AM, 8 hours total.
Where you are allowed is from here...
to here. You will only sleep here.
Why are you so strict? Why are you making someone be wary of what they do?
Oh this is nice. Can't I sleep here?
Please, I wish you would have some sense!
Hey!
You're okay, right?
You..you still haven't left?
Get along nicely.
I'm leaving.
I'm really going.
I'm going.
Sleep!
Guitar is also forbidden.
Sleep well, hyung.
- I'm sorry you had to see that Se Ah.
- No, it's fine.
I'm used to this type of situation.
When we were in our 20's, every time Gong Gi Tae dated other girls, I experienced similiar situations.
Even though we're just friends,
girls would be really jealous and wary of me.
I see.
But where did all those many girls disappear to?
Next to Gi Tae, only Se Ah is left.
Because we're friends.
How has your father been?
-My father?
-What happened three years ago,
maybe he has not gotten over the issue yet. I was just wondering.
Not at all. Although the marriage was broken, he still likes Gi Tae.
He wants to scout him to our hospital.
Oh, really? I'm thankful then.
Anyways, he wanted to meet Gi Tae again
But..
Joo Jang Mi is stuck in my mind.
I'm worried that she might misunderstand. Gi Tae will probably refuse too
because Joo Jang Mi doesn't let go, either.
That problem, I can help.
What the?!
It's me. Han Yeo Reum.
Why are you sleeping here?!
It's was too cold this morning.
Get out this instant!
Why are you getting mad?
What are you doing there?
You told me eating was prohibited.
At least I can feast with my eyes.
I told you to get out.
I thought you meant to get out of the bed.
You're doing this on purpose, aren't you? To make me angry.
Me?
You? Why would I?
Hey, is there really no other place for you to go?
You don't have relatives or friends?
All my friends are girls. I lost contact with my relatives. I never had a dad and my mom ran away.
Do you think you can act pitiful so you can rely on me?
You didn't fall for it. Joo Jang Mi did.
If you aren't going to eat the egg, I'll eat it.
Be sure to clean up.
Are you going to work already? Let's go together, hyung.
You won't even give me a ride?
He's cuter than he looks.
That jerk... because he took the blankets...
In other words, the cartilage called the nasal septum is bent in the shape of a 'C.'
If we correct this, we can...
I think I should go home for today. Cancel the afternoon appointments, please.
Yes, Doctor. Go home quickly and rest.
Oh, right. There'll be electric maintenance work done today, right?
Yes, from 8 PM today until tomorrow morning,
the entrance will be blocked and all the phone lines will be out.
It just so happens that the electric generator is also being fixed.
Please make sure to take out the fat, ketamine, and the botox and filler products
that have to be refrigerated.
-Yes.
Doctor, are you alright?
I'm fine.
Yes.
Yes. This is Gong Gi Tae's Plastic Surgery Clinic.
I'm sorry, but the doctor can't see any patients today.
He has a cold...
Yes. I understand.
Is he in bad health? He couldn't drink alcohol very well either.
Ah, this...
Jang Mi's dad. Jang Mi's dad.
Ah, why are you waking up a person who earned money until dawn.
Did you earn it by yourself?
We earned it together. With me.
Go and buy some chicken from the market.
The freshest and healthiest ones.
Why?
Because I'm planning on feeding a brood hen for our son-in-law.
It sure is difficult to get our daughter married.
Ah, go away.
This man.
Ah, chicken and ginseng stew!
You knew that I was getting off work early today, didn't you?
Hey. Go give this to son-in-law Gong.
Mom!
Do you really think I can get married to that person?
He's on another level than me.
I gave birth to you with beauty from another level.
It can't be that
his parents are against the marriage, right?
Not yet.
But soon they will. It's obvious.
It hasn't even happened yet, so why are you worried about that already. Be quiet!
Just go and deliver the chicken and ginseng stew. Don't leave someone who's sick on their own.
Is Gong Gi Tae sick?
You don't even know that?
Hurry and go!
Ugh, but I'm tired.
Do you want me to go?
Ah, fine. I'll go. I'll just go.
My chicken and ginseng stew... it's mine.
Gong Gi Tae's Mother
Yes, mother?
You said you wanted to get closer with me?
Yes?
Ah, yes, yes.
Do you have time right now?
Right now?
-Welcome.
-Yes.
What kind of fashion is that.
Ah, I heard Gong Gi Tae was sick so I was on my way to deliver some chicken and ginseng stew.
Whatever, go put that away.
Yeah.
-Go try this on.
-Excuse me?
-You told my sister that
you wanted to go shopping with the girls and have a date.
Ah...
Before the chicken and ginseng stew gets cold...
Gi Tae said he would join us in the evening.
Here.
Dinner?
I'm tired.
I want to be alone with Jang Mi.
Joo Jang Mi is going to be there too.
We're meeting for Joo Jang Mi.
-What?
-It seemed like she was upset with me.
So I was going to buy you two some dinner at a nice restaurant.
Let's meet at the French Restaurant.
What is she plotting now?
Yeah, it's me.
Save me! They're taking me somewhere nice so they're making me try on this and that.
Because I wouldn't look appropriate with my clothes.
Why are they like this so suddenly?
I think mother really likes me.
Don't be intimidated.
That's definitely not it.
I'm don't know what this is. But for now, accept everything that they buy for you.
No, no. Buy everything you want.
What is it... the wasteful, mindless chick concept.
You're sick but still wicked.
Are you done yet?
What's taking you so long?
Yes, I'm coming out now, Aunt.
-Hang up for now
-Fighting.
Okay.
I'm going to go crazy.
Try spinning for me.
It won't do. Let's pick something else.
Shall we try this on?
Ah, Aunt, this is the one.
Too mature.
Mature.
-This is nice.
-Wow, so pretty!
You look like a chameleon. This is too green.
Let's go.
Yes, Aunt.
I'm going to die.
Almost there.
This?
Are you kidding me?
Ah, so pretty
I don't like that one the most.
Spin around.
I like it.
-This one is okay.
-Okay?
Make her style luxurious.
Make her makeup fancy.
The nail art is very important.
The atmosphere is good.
Then, I hope you go to your own stations and work hard.
Be precise with the concealer.
Put some curls to make her hair look fuller.
Oh, the purple is nice.
It's cute, I guess.
-Ugh!
-But this is NG too. *No Good
Take it out, take it out immediately.
It doesn't suit her, it doesn't suit her.
Be precise, precise.
Make her curls thicker.
♬  we will live happily together ♬
Again! Back to the chic style!
Stop! Aunt, please stop!
Where's the good place? Even if you don't know, let's just go.
No, no! Again, again!
I'm not going to pay!
Oh god.
Come in.
I'm tired.
This is heaven, Aunt.
What are you talking about? We have to go to a better place.
If you wait here, Gi Tae and Madame Shin will come to pick you up.
Is there a traffic jam? Why... aren't they coming?
I'll call Gong Gi Tae.
A girl shouldn't call and ask when are they coming, or come faster.
Then they don't have charm.
Ah, ok.
Sleep.
Uh hoo.
Jang Mi.
Joo Jang Mi.
I'm sorry Jang Mi, I didn't want to go this far either.
Sorry Jang Mi!
She fell asleep?
I was wondering how to hold on to her longer, but thankfully.
But how could you leave her alone?
What if she wakes up? What would Gi Tae know...
Don't worry.
I stole Joo Jang Mi's phone.
Here, you keep it.
Why are you here?
My father will come soon too, he wants to see you.
- What?
- And it also seems,
that your mother needs my father.
What are you trying to do?
What are you trying to do by using our parents?
I also feel uncomfortable involving them.
How about allowing them to speak to each other, and we slowly leave?
If you come with me, I'll give you a present.
They'll arrive soon.
Decide quickly.
If you don't want your mother seeing what's in here.
Am I too late?
No, you arrived right on time.
Where's your father?
He said he's going to be a little late because an urgent surgery came up.
What about Jang Mi? You ordered aunt to hold on to Jang Mi, didn't you?
As she wanted, she went shopping with the girls and got her hair done.
She's having a good time, so don't worry too much.
There's a call coming mother.
Pick it up.
Ok, I'll go outside for a second...
Can I see this?
- What are are you trying to do?
- It's Jang Mi's phone, isn't it?
Why do you have Jang Mi's phone?
Let go, it's a misunderstanding.
Where is Joo Jang Mi? Where is she?
What is this?
What happened?
Aunt?
Aunt!
Where did she go?
My phone.
My phone!
What the?
Aunt, your prank is a bit too harsh.
Aunt where are you?
Gong Gi Tae, it's you isn't it? Come out!
I know you're there!
Hey!
What's going on?
Is there really nobody here?
Ugh!
Excuse me! There's a person trapped here!
Why am I alone here?
Phone!
Where is it?
Ah!
Ouch, my shoulder!
What do I do?
Oh, no...
Hospital?
You're saying Jang Mi is there alone?
Today from the evening at 8 o'clock to tomorrow morning,
the entrances closes, electricity, and phones are all out.
Now you kidnap and imprison her there?
Kidnap? Imprisonment? Don't overdo it.
And people are watching, lower your voice.
Do you even know embarrassment?!
Don't get angry at her, I asked her to.
I'm really sorry.
It's not your fault, Se Ah. It's okay.
I'm really sorry to Joo Jang Mi too.
It's ok.
I'm not ok!
You can't leave her alone.
You can never leave her alone!
♬ Even if you ♬
To be honest, I...
♬  Smile for me ♬
when I was 5 years old, I almost died alone at home.
♬ You can't hide your dejection ♬
So I can't be by myself.
When I think about what happened back then... my heart still
feels like it's ripping apart.
♬ All I do is, ♬
Is there no one there?!
♬ watch you turn away ♬
♬  I already know about our love ♬
There's a person here!
♬  I guess this will be the last time ♬
♬  Even if we want to be with each other, there will be no forever ♬
♬  The times that are passing us by ♬
Please understand...
♬ When the times go by ♬
How our Jang Mi's heart is.
♬ My heart feels as though it will burst ♬
♬  Even if I forget my feelings for you ♬
-Hey you crazy bastard!
♬  Because we shared a precious love ♬
The store is closed.
Didn't you hear that they were doing the electrical maintenance work tonight?
How long has it been since the lights went out?
Since 8pm..? I think it's been around 30 minutes.
Why? What is the matter?
-Jang Mi got locked up at the clinic.
-What?
Joo Jang Mi!
Gong GI Tae.
Are you stupid? Why are you here?
Aunt told me to wait here.
If you're dumb, have some common sense at least!
and what is with the chicken and ginseng stew?
Why are you yelling?
Do you know how much I suffered because of you?
Do you know how scared I was?
It is okay. It is okay.
What a pity that it's wasted.
Mom sent this thinking of you.
I will go wash up.
There's a lot left. It should be enough for three people to eat heartily.
Are you Jesus? Are you going to create a miracle?
Sure I can. As soon as you allow me to cook.
Do whatever you want.
What are you doing?
Here. I made Samgyepasta.
Did you make it with my Mom's Samgyetang (chicken soup)?
Pasta is what you make when you can't cook but still want to make yourself look good.
It's good.
- Is it good?
- Yeah.
You should try it as well.
I don't have an appetite.
I'm telling you to try it. Open.
It's good, right?
It's probably the samgyetang's broth that's good.
He's right. I didn't do anything.
It's all thanks to your mother's cooking.
I feel sorry toward Mother.
I don't deserve to receive things like this.
It's okay. If it weren't for you, when would my mom ever get to dream of a doctor son-in-law?
Let's just say that you let my mom and dad have a sweet dream.
Well, although it's a very short midsummer night's dream (sounds like Han Yeo Reum).
Did you call me?
That guy doesn't even know when or when not to butt in.
Let's drink. There was wine.
-Call. (good)
-Call.
These people...
Hey, hey! I'm sick! Where are you going to have a drinking party?
Where is it...
Hey! Hey! I told you not to touch it.
♬ The way you talk always mysteriously stays near my ears ♬
-Cheers!
-One shot! One shot! One shot!
One shot. Aigoo..
-Eat it. Eat it. I don't want to eat.
-Open.
-Why?
I'll feed you just for today. Ah~
It's good, right?
Bread.
Open.
♬ Your eyes nose and lips
Your hands that used to touch me ♬
♬ Little finger nails and all ♬
♬ I can still feel you. ♬
♬ Like a flame which went out ♬
This song.
You thought you just do like this, right? That isn't right.
Do it once for us.
You can't leave that girl alone.
You can't EVER leave her by herself!
Being alone suits you better.
3 years ago
I like being alone.
I am sorry.
I think I can breathe now.
While preparing for the wedding,
my breath felt shorter and shorter each day.
This isn't right.
This isn't how I usually do things.
The truth is that I was very hurt.
Thank you for telling me first.
We're okay, right?
Of course we are.
What should I do, Gong Gi Tae?
I'm not okay.
What is this, seriously?
I'm a sick person. I am sick.
-Are you okay?
- Are you okay, Doctor?
You are okay, right?
No.
I am not okay.
♬  When I see you, my heart pounds♬
♬  And my lips dry up ♬
♬  I couldn’t sleep last night because of the butterflies ♬
♬  Why am I like this?♬
Preview
♬  My face is getting hot ♬
Did you guys kiss?
Starting from today, we are in love.
Your family got it for her, right? Thanks, hyung.
Mom!
How can you have a formal meeting between our families without even telling us?
If you can do it, do it once.
-Jang Mi? Jang Mi?
-I think mother-in-law has some special power.
Gong Gi Tae, where are you now?
He just went inside to take a shower.
I will definitely wear this dress and get married.