(dog barking)
Mom, it's 6:45.
Mom! It's 6:45.
Again?
No. Dummy.
Oh... Oh! Oh.
(meows)
What are you eating?
A doughnut.
For breakfast?
I put peanut butter on it.
What are these dishes
doing in the sink? It was
your turn to do them.
I'll do 'em tonight.
Is that when you're gonna
put everything else away?
What's wrong
with the refrigerator?
It's warm. It must've broke down
during the night.
Didn't I just have it fixed?
Didn't I just
pay those guys $47?
Thieves, all of them.
Goddamn thieves.
God damn it!
Why won't that door lock?
It's warped
because of the rain.
With any luck,
they'll steal the refrigerator.
(sputters and jerks)
What's wrong with it?
It's a year older
than you are.
(car backfires and sputters)
Hey, why don't you get
a new muffler, lady?
Why don't you try living
on a teacher's salary?
I'm in a terrific mood
today, aren't I?
Why do you stay up all night
marking exams?
I have 18 kids
flunking English.
18 out of 39 does not
exactly give a teacher
a sense of accomplishment.
It had a big engine.
How you doin', man?
Hey, Barry, how's it going?
(Nora) What do you want
for dinner tonight?
(Michael) Oh, I don't care.
You had I don't care
last night.
Anything.
What's up, Mike?
Hi, Steve.
I thought
they expelled that one.
Oh, he's all right.
Well, I gotta go.
Where's my kiss?
Oh, I owe you one.
Ah, ah, I don't give credit.
Come here.
Sorry to put you through
torture, but it gets me
through the day.
(boy) Sixth period.
(girl) OK, I'll come.
Hey, how you doin', Mike?
What's goin' on with you, man?
(bell rings)
Two heels and sole.
Excuse me, I'm late for work.
Would you mind terribly
if I went ahead of you?
Go ahead. I got
nothin' to do all day.
Aw... there you go.
Thanks a lot. Bye.
Thank you.
Wait a minute.
Wait, uh, uh...
Sir, sir, did you see
a '64 Volvo parked right there?
Sorry, lady.
Oh, no, this isn't happening.
This is impossible.
Oh, my God.
I can't find my car.
Something wrong?
You can't find your car?
No.
Did you park it here?
Certainly. I parked it
right here.
Oh, I don't believe this.
They stole my car.
Who did?
What do I know? Car thieves.
Oh, I don't believe this.
The dirty bastards.
I was just standing
behind her in line.
All my school papers
were in there,
even the final English
exam papers. I didn't even
finish correcting them yet.
What happened?
Somebody
stole her car.
Can I see your registration,
please?
It's in the car.
You should always
carry it on you.
If I ever get another car,
I'll remember that.
Were there any
distinguishing markings
on the vehicle?
There's the dent
in the fender.
Which one?
All of them.
And the parking lights
didn't work.
You know
that's a violation?
When you catch the new owners,
you can give them a ticket.
Hello, lieutenant.
Thank you.
Mrs. McPhee,
I'm Lieutenant Costello.
I'd like to ask you
a few questions if I may.
I am so angry.
I'm so goddamn angry
at people.
I understand.
It's enough
they stole the radio
last month.
Did you leave
the vehicle unlocked?
I just told you
they broke into it
last month.
The locks didn't work.
On each side of the vehicle?
Why do you
keep calling it a vehicle?
It was hardly even a car.
Don't you watch TV?
We all talk like that.
You left the keys
in the ignition?
Yes, I must've.
They're not in my purse.
I had ten minutes' sleep
last night, OK?
And you were not
insured for theft?
I didn't think
it would come up.
Oh, this is terrific.
My first class just started.
What do you teach?
English literature.
Contemporary?
Not when I show up
with 39 exam papers missing.
I'm sorry. I think we have
all the information we need.
If you just sign there...
(siren wailing)
Who's your favorite writer?
I beg your pardon?
I took English lit
at Michigan.
I was curious
who your favorite writer was.
2,000 detectives in L.A.,
and I have an English lit major
looking for my car.
I may not find your car,
but my reports will be
impeccable.
If my kids find out their
final-exam papers are missing,
you may have a more serious case
than auto theft to deal with.
Somebody should lose
my kid's papers.
If I hear anything
about your car,
I'll let you know.
Thank you.
Austen.
What?
Jane Austen. I like a writer
you can depend on.
Thackeray. I like somebody
who makes you work a little.
(all talking/
music on radio)
I'm sorry I'm late.
Wendall,
turn off the radio.
Patrick, get your feet
off Luis.
Celia, take the gum
out of your mouth.
It's not gum.
I would rather not hear
what it is. Just get rid of it.
All right, I'm going
to ask the class
to bear with me.
I have some rather bad news.
My car was stolen this morning.
(students murmur)
Where'd you lose it?
Maybe I know who did it.
Third and Magnolia?
Nah, ain't none of my boys.
(class laughs)
If you're ready
for the really bad news,
your final test papers
were in the car.
They're gone.
I don't know where they are.
I don't remember
what your grades were.
What?
So now what happens?
What happens? We take
the test over tomorrow,
that's what happens.
(all protest)
I'm sorry. Look at it
this way...
for those that passed,
they're not gonna have
any trouble passing again,
and for those that failed,
you have an extra night
to study.
Shit.
This is English, Luis.
Save that discussion
for Biology.
I suggest we spend
the rest of the period
brushing up on Shakespeare.
Get out your Hamlet books.
Shakespeare.
We left off with, uh...
beginning of Act Two
last class.
Page 46. Luis.
Oh, man.
Do you wanna read Polonius?
Yeah. "Give him this money
and these notes, Reynaldo."
Uh, Reynaldo... Wendall?
"I will, my Lord."
"Man -"
No, no. No "man."
There's no "man" in the script.
"You should do
marvelous wisely.
Good, Reynaldo.
"Now, before - man...
There's no "before"
and no "man."
Yeah, there's "before"
right there.
"And before you visit him,
to make inquire
of his behavior."
"My Lord,
I did intendeth."
Very good.
"Marry. Well said."
Oh, yeah, "Marry, well said.
Very well said.
Look... Look you, sir."
Man, this don't make sense.
Sure. Look you, sir. Instead
of saying, "Hey, look, man,"
he's saying, "Look you, sir.
"Look you, sir."
Ha-ha. You're dumb.
(class laughs)
Man, shut up.
I'm on a roll now, bro.
(bell rings)
Miss McPhee.
Maybe it's about my car.
Any news?
They found it at the bottom
of Topanga Canyon.
It was totaled.
Well, that's
just wonderful.
I'm really sorry.
Come on,
I'll give you a lift home.
We'll try and figure
something out.
(whistling)
(car horn honks)
Mike, get in.
Where's the car?
Well, thanks for the rides.
A very nice day. I'm sorry,
that sounds insensitive.
No, not for a man
who reads Thackeray.
Listen,
if I was out of line,
you can file
a formal complaint
by dialing 555-3000.
Ask for Lieutenant Costello.
I'm in charge
of formal complaints.
Nice meeting ya, Mike.
Ohh.
I can't believe
that you left the keys
in the ignition.
Please. Be thankful
I saved your shoes.
Hey, here's one.
A '64 blue Chevy Corvair,
white walls and radials.
$250.
It comes in a box.
You assemble it yourself.
Yeah. Well, you can't find
anything decent for less
than $1,000.
How much money
you have in the bank?
Funny, I was just gonna
ask you that.
Isn't there anybody who
you can borrow from at school?
You mean teachers? Please.
What about relatives?
Didn't Pop have any?
Not with any money.
Hey, what about
your father?
You never talk about him.
What did he do for a living?
I don't know. Whoops.
You don't know
what your own father
did for a living?
Well, he worked in a bank
for a while,
he was an accountant,
he did a lot of things.
When did he die?
He didn't. Well, he might
be dead. I'm not sure.
You told me he was dead.
Yeah, well,
he probably is.
I haven't seen him
since before you were born.
How come?
I don't know. Look,
can we change the subject?
What we need right now
is a car, not a grandfather.
(doorbell rings)
Are you expecting someone?
No.
Hmm. Please, God,
let it be the United Way.
(doorbell rings)
Outside.
What?
I said outside.
Let's go.
What are you doing?
Know how to ride
one of those?
No.
Want to learn?
Afraid?
Yeah.
OK, forget it.
I'll see ya.
Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Can we stop having
these Dragnet conversations
and just talk like human beings?
Yes, ma'am.
Well, uh, whose is this?
Formerly smashed-up
stolen property
reconstructed by the police
and sold at auction
to benefit needy kids
who probably stole it
in the first place.
It's mine.
I bought it.
I use it on weekends,
when I have 'em.
You want to rent it
Mondays to Fridays?
For how much?
Dinners
Saturdays and Sundays.
I'll pay ya $20 a week
plus parts and maintenance.
Does that sound fair?
What do I know?
I'm not Avis. Sure.
Is it a deal?
Well, you better show me
how to work this thing.
OK. Put your helmet on.
Is this dangerous?
Only if you start it.
Hey, where you going?
I don't know.
Keep your fingers crossed.
Your mother get a new friend?
Yeah, I guess so.
Just take a firm grip
on the handle bars
right here.
Put your hands right here
where mine are.
Uh-huh.
OK, got it?
Yeah.
Now just relax.
Uh-huh.
Ready?
Yeah.
OK, she's all yours.
Got it?
Uh-huh.
Take it easy, relax.
You're all right.
Don't take your hands off.
Wait a minute.
You're doing fine.
Now don't worry about it, OK?
You got control?
No, not really.
Aah!
You're all right.
Don't worry about it.
Just relax.
I am trying to relax.
Ease your grip
on the handle bars.
You're choking the handle bars.
I'm beginning to get it.
Just keep your balance.
Wait a second.
You are now proceeding
the wrong way
down a one-way street.
Aah! How do I make a U-turn?
You're not ready.
You can't go straight.
Well, I just made one.
That
doesn't mean you were ready.
That's a stop sign. Yes, ya did.
I'm in the traffic.
I'm riding straight.
That's good.
Watch out for the Jeep.
(speaking Spanish)
(pleads in Spanish)
Aah!
(owner yelling)
What are you doing?
Hang on to me tight.
(sirens wailing)
Police officer.
Just take it easy.
Holy cow.
Would you like to come in
for a cup of coffee
or a medal?
I would, but I
gotta be back at work
in half an hour.
You mean that was
leisure-time activity?
Some of us make arrests,
and some of us
mark exam papers at night.
I'll see you Saturday night.
We'll eat in a low-crime area.
Would - oh, thanks.
Would I be asking
for trouble
if I told you
I'm very impressed?
Nope. You'd be asking
for this.
I think I bought
a little trouble.
See you Saturday night.
Lieutenant, I don't know
your first name.
I knew I'd pique
your interest.
Brian.
Hey, what happened?
Can you ride it?
Can I ride it?
I just made an arrest
on Venice Boulevard.
Watch it.
(phone ringing)
Hello?
(Brian) Did I wake ya?
No.
I thought I made
a good impression tonight.
I see. Is that observation
or overconfidence?
Just probing, hoping
I'd get a positive response.
You really do put in
a full day, don't you?
Only on the interesting cases.
Thank you. Listen, lieutenant,
I have to get up at 5:30
in the morning
to practice on my bike.
I'll see you on Saturday, OK?
Hey, first line, what book?
"Buck Mulligan appeared from
the stairhead bearing a bowl
of lather on which a mirror..."
James Joyce, Ulysses.
Terrific.
Straight A's.
Magna cum laude.
I've got my work cut out
with you.
I gotta go.
OK. I'll see ya Saturday.
Bye.
(phone rings)
You're not gonna quote
the whole book, are you?
(man) Nora?
Oh, you remembered my name.
Now look, may I speak to you
for a moment?
It won't take long for me
to tell you what I have to.
Who is this?
See, that would take long.
I'm just down the street.
I'd call in the morning,
but it's urgent.
What's this all about?
Look, I just need
five minutes of your time.
Nora, look, please don't
refuse me here.
For old times' sake.
(hangs up/dial tone)
(thunder rumbling)
Uh, yes. This is
Mrs. Nora McPhee.
Could I please speak to
a Lieutenant Brian Costello?
(man) I'm sorry, the lieutenant
is out on a call.
Oh, well, is there any way
to reach him?
No, I'm afraid not.
May I help you?
You see, I got this
rather strange phone call,
and it's probably a prank,
but it made me sort of nervous -
Ma'am, did they use
any obscene language?
No, it wasn't obscene.
Let me transfer you
to the officer in complaints.
Well, it's probably nothing,
but would you please have him
call me as soon as he could?
Does he have your number?
Yes, he has the number.
OK. I'll give him
your message.
Bye.
(dog barking)
(man coughs)
Who's there?
The one who just called.
May I speak to you, please?
I've just called the police.
They're gonna be here
in five minutes.
You better tell me who you are
and what you want.
Does 1125 Franklin Street,
North Chicago,
apartment 2B,
pink elephant wallpaper
in your room
mean anything to you?
Max Dugan?
Well, I was half-hoping
you'd still call me "Daddy,"
but Max'll be fine.
I've got a gun.
I can assure you,
I am your father.
After what you did to us,
that doesn't make you
any safer.
Can I come in, please?
OK.
Close that door, would ya?
Is the boy sleeping?
What boy?
Michael, my grandson.
Just about 15 now,
isn't he?
Who told ya that?
I get around.
Hey, listen, do you have
any brandy in the house?
My blood isn't as thick
as it used to be.
Try to picture me
with darker hair.
Mm-hmm.
Well, the teaching profession
doesn't afford many luxuries,
does it?
How did you find me?
Oh, I still have
a few friends
in Chicago.
Apparently my mother
wasn't one of them.
Did you know
she died last year?
I did and I'm deeply sorry.
I sent her flowers anonymously.
Say, do you mind
if I pull down these shades?
I wouldn't want
a young attractive widow
getting a bad reputation.
What is it you want?
Me? A brandy.
Wait a minute. Why are you
pulling down shades?
Why'd you call me
in the middle of the night,
afraid to say who you are?
This window
needs a new lock.
Are the police after you again?
I'm a popular man.
Many people seek my company.
Oh, shouldn't keep a gun
with a small boy in the house.
I'm not afraid of small boys,
just older men.
Look, if it's a handout
you're looking for, I'm sorry.
I have too little,
and you're too late.
I don't care where you've
been for the last 28 years
or what you've been doing.
There are no openings
in this family anymore.
Family reunions
aren't what they used to be.
Neither are fathers.
Quick, very quick. OK, Nora,
let's make a deal.
If you won't favor me
with your hospitality,
can I at least
buy a drink from you?
You mean you can
actually pay for it?
* Liquor by the mile
* Can take you to places... *
I think that should at least
buy me a good brand of scotch.
It's $10,000. In Las Vegas,
I can get 2 drinks for that.
I do have certain talents,
you know.
Yes. They bought you
six years in jail.
Ha-ha. Refined 'em
since then.
Well, I see I'm not gonna
get the drink, so, uh...
perhaps we could use
the precious time
to conduct
a little business.
What kind of business?
I think you might
wanna sit down.
I'll decide that for myself.
Hmm. There's little doubt
I've been a neglectful father,
to say the very least,
but we can go into that
some other time.
We could go into it now.
I am 63 years old, and according
to a very reputable doctor,
if I take
very good care of myself
and avoid all stress
and tension,
it'd be a miracle
if I lived another six months.
(thunder)
I say this not to alarm you
or to elicit your sympathies,
which are vigorously
undisplayed at the moment,
but merely to present you
with the facts.
My heart
and the surrounding valves
have turned in their notice.
Now, I have enough money
in that suitcase
to spend the next
ten years of my life
living like Hugh Hefner,
but I have neither
the workable equipment to do so
nor the ten years.
To complicate matters,
there are certain parties
who think that six months
is much too long for me to live
and would like to get
their hands on me.
I'd like to buy something
from you, and I'm willing
to pay handsomely for it.
And even you must admit
that your ramshackle roof
could use some shackling.
What do I have
that you would wanna buy?
The last few months of my life
with my grandson.
Are you serious?
Deadly.
You show up here
in the middle of the night
afraid to say who you are,
I haven't seen you
since I'm nine years old,
and you greet me
with the same affection
you left with,
throw $10,000 in front of me,
which is probably counterfeit,
and then expect me
to burst into tears
because you tell me
you only have six months
left to live.
How do I know you only have
six months left to live?
We could sit here and wait.
Excuse me.
(thunder)
Nothing for dear old dad?
Ah, thank you.
Did you steal that money?
One of the subjects
I mastered in prison
was real estate.
When I got out, I bought
a small piece of property
in Las Vegas,
parlayed it
into a larger piece,
until I finally owned
ten lots that a large hotel
wanted to expand on.
I wouldn't sell it to them.
So they used
their political power
to legally separate me
from my land.
Took me for every cent I had.
Well, I took my loss
stoically
and even accepted another job
in another hotel
owned by the same
nefarious faction...
as a blackjack dealer.
I worked there
seven long and hard years,
and day by day,
dollar by dollar,
I ingeniously
skimmed off the top
what was rightfully mine.
H-How much is in this satchel?
Exactly what they took
from me - $687,000.
Perhaps a pot of coffee
would be safer?
Could I see it?
Yeah. I look all the time.
(whimpers)
Ah...
Oh...
It's your money now.
Wha...? Wha...?
What do you mean, "my money"?
It's your legacy.
Yeah, yours and Michael's.
You're my only heirs.
That's my last will
and testament.
I need a decision
as soon as possible.
The sun is my enemy,
and it'll be up in a few hours.
Wait a minute. Do you think
I'd touch a cent of that money?
I don't care if there's
$5 million in there.
That money is stolen.
From me. I might've got it back
in litigation,
but it would've taken six years,
five and half of which
I'd be dead,
and the lawyers would've
got most of it, anyway.
This is family money, Nora.
Well, find another family.
Just take that money and go.
I don't want any part of this.
Nora, I can never make up
for the years we didn't
have together,
but I don't wanna lose
the few remaining days
I could share with my grandson.
If you don't want the money,
fine, I'll accept that,
but a trust fund set up
for Michael would more than
get him through college
and a start in life
I was never able to give you.
Think of him, not us.
(phone ringing)
Oh, that's probably Brian.
Who's Brian?
A lieutenant
on the police force.
Hello. Oh, Brian.
Sorry I'm late...
You wouldn't hold
a little thing like abandonment
against your father, would ya?
Do you mean
they're after you, too?
Nora, are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine.
What's going on?
I got a message said you got
a crank or mysterious call?
It was nothing, just a couple
kids in the neighborhood
playing a prank.
I just felt like calling you
and saying good night again.
Did you?
Once we get the hang
of "good night,"
maybe we could start...
working on "good morning."
Thanks for calling back.
I'll see you Saturday.
You take care
of yourself, OK?
Little Nora Dugan has grown
into a compassionate woman.
Well, you've seen
the last drop of it.
I want you to go.
I want you to take
your $687,000 and just go.
It doesn't go with my furniture,
and if you want to see Michael,
$1.50 at McDonald's
will buy a terrific afternoon.
I have to say I was sorry
to hear about your husband.
Understand he was
a first-rate man.
Thank you.
I suggest you don't mention this
to the policeman.
I've always found 'em
to be busybodies.
Where will you go?
Well, there are some motels
that still accept cash.
Good-bye, Nora.
I would've enjoyed
getting to know ya.
Wait a minute.
I don't trust you.
Caution is a valuable trait.
And I don't want anything
from you, either.
Independence is something
I've always admired.
I feel funny about
letting you go like this,
so you can spend the night,
but you leave in the morning,
OK?
I pick up things quickly.
I can tell by the satchel.
Do me a favor. If this
ever happens again,
send me a postcard.
Morning, Mom.
Morning.
Who are you?
Me? I'm Mr. Parker.
Mr. Parker?
Mm-hmm.
Is my mother up?
I don't believe so.
You a friend of hers?
We became acquainted
last night.
Oh. You stayed over?
In the guest room.
You have a guest room?
The one next to yours.
I rented it from your mother.
Oh. When was that?
Now, that was about
12:30 last night.
She didn't tell me.
No. You were sleeping.
I heard there was a vacancy,
and I called rather late.
I see. You gonna
be here long?
That depends
on your mother.
Would you excuse me
a minute, Mister...
Parker. Certainly.
Mom...
(knocks on door)
...it's Mike. Are you up?
(knocks)
Mom, Mom, it's ten to seven.
Wake up.
(alarm sounds)
Oh, I didn't sleep.
I was up all night.
Did you have
your breakfast?
Yeah. Well, I was going to
until I met Mr. Parker.
Who?
Mr. Parker, the man
you rented the room to.
I rented a room?
Yeah, that's what he told me.
Mr. Parker?
Don't you remember?
Oh, my God, wait a minute.
Let me think.
Why didn't you tell me?
Why didn't I tell you?
Well, actually, I didn't know
I was gonna do it.
You see, it all
happened suddenly.
Just so quickly.
In the middle of the night?
Yes, well, you see,
he didn't have anyplace to go,
and it was only for one night.
You rented a room
for one night? You can't
make any money that way.
Uh, I know that.
So why did you do it?
Look, don't question me.
I don't know.
Actually, I was gonna
rent the room for a month,
but then I thought it was
a little weird having
a stranger in the house.
So why did you let him
spend the night?
Well, I didn't think
he was that strange.
What does he do for a living?
What?
What does he do?
I don't know.
Does he have any references?
Uh, I didn't ask him.
You didn't ask him?
No. It was late at night,
I was tired.
I never rented a room before.
Is he in there?
Yeah.
Good. I'll take care of it.
I'm much clearer now.
You go and make your bed.
I made my bed.
All right, then, make mine.
I don't wanna be late
for school. Go on.
Just what do you
think you're doing?
Making pancakes.
The boy needs a hot meal
before he goes to school.
Would you come outside
with me, please?
Outside? My batter
is all ready.
Where did you
get the name Parker from?
I saw it inside
on a box of dinner rolls.
It sounded more plausible
than Birds Eye.
Why did you give him
a phony name?
I was trying to take
the pressure off you.
If I told the boy
he was my grandson
and you decided
to throw me out,
he might've resented you
enormously.
Wait a minute.
You intend to stay.
Yes, but I leave that
up to you.
Why don't you try my pancakes?
I won three Bake-Offs
in my cell block.
How long do you think we could
keep up this subterfuge,
Mr. Parker?
According to my doctors,
five months at the most.
Will you stop saying that.
I find it in very bad taste.
But I'm the one who's dying.
I think I should reserve
the right -
All right, I won't
say it ever again.
A week. I'll give you a week.
I think that's enough time
to get to know your grandson.
Certainly more than
you ever spent with me.
And we'll stick to Mr. Parker,
and you stick to the house,
because I don't want any
of your Las Vegas friends
around here with shotguns,
or the police,
for that -
What do I tell Brian?
I'd stick to lying.
So far, you're doing great.
(phone ringing)
I want $100 for the week,
and you clean up
your own room.
Make it 250.
I said a hundred.
No! I said a hundred...
Hello.
Good morning, Michael.
It's Brian Costello.
Is your mother there?
Yeah.
Could I talk to her, please?
Hold on a second.
(Max) And can we have
breakfast now?
After you, Mr. Parker.
After you, Mrs. McPhee.
Brian's on the phone.
What did you tell him?
I told him I'd get you.
Well, you must never, ever
mention Mr. Parker,
because I don't have a license
to take in boarders.
You like pancakes?
Hello, Brian?
We don't have 'em much.
From now on,
you're gonna have 'em.
No, no calls.
...the boarder, huh?
You OK?
Sit down.
I dreamt about you last night.
I owe you an apology...
Hand me that plate. Thanks.
Drink your orange juice...
Listen, I've got to
get ready for school.
I'll talk to you
sometime, OK?
You like baseball?
Yeah.
Can you hit?
Not too well.
If you learn to hit...
Tomorrow night? Shh!
Don't disappoint me. I don't
wanna have to repossess
your transportation.
No, no, tomorrow night
is fine.
I'll pick you up about 7:30?
Pick me up? You mean here?
I could pick you up here,
but you don't live here.
Stove's no good...
7:30. Drive the bike
carefully...
Bye.
Nothing in this kitchen works.
Try these, will you?
Where'd you
learn how to cook?
Me? Books. Learned everything
from books.
Now, is there anything special
you want for dinner?
I'll take care of his dinner.
Michael, come on, we're late.
Go get your pants on,
for school, and don't
forget the helmet.
I'm gonna get dressed.
Finish your pancakes.
Thanks for the breakfast,
Mr. Parker.
You're welcome.
You didn't lose any time
hitting it off, did you?
Just doing what comes naturally.
We have a fine boy there, Nora,
don't we?
Yes, I do, thank you.
Listen, why don't you just
leave that stuff in the sink?
I'll do it when I get home.
Man in your condition
should probably
be laying down.
Yeah, doctor said it could
just as easily happen
lying down.
Sorry, bad taste again.
Say, why don't you go
to school?
I have a few chores
to take care of.
(water runs)
Why didn't you ever
get in touch with me before?
I never had anything
worth giving you before.
I always thought affection
would've been enough.
(all talking at once)
Celia, I want you to stay.
You, too, Maria.
I saw the note, Celia. Were you
passing answers to Maria?
Were you?
Yes, ma'am.
You know the rules. I have to
give you both failing grades.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm surprised at you.
You're one of my best students.
Why did you do it?
She didn't know the answers.
Maria has to deal with that.
I don't understand
your behavior.
Maria's my cousin.
Does that make
any difference?
It does to me. In my family,
we help each other,
no matter what.
(bell rings)
That'll be all, girls.
Yes, ma'am.
Party up in the balcony
or something like that.
Yeah, I'm into it.
It'd be good. We can do it
whenever you want.
I gotta go. Take care.
Nice to see you.
Bye-bye.
Hi, Mom.
What'd they expel him for?
Who, Steve?
I don't know.
He was selling some stuff.
What stuff? You mean drugs?
I suppose so.
I never bought any.
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
(siren wailing)
What's wrong? I was only
doing 40 miles an hour.
It's a 35-mile zone.
That's the first speeding ticket
I ever got in my whole life.
Give the ticket to Brian,
he'll take care of it.
Don't you ever talk that way.
You break the law,
you pay the fine,
do you hear me?
I hear they stole your car.
Yes.
Did you hear about the woman
who got raped last week
around the corner?
No, I didn't.
I'm glad you've got somebody
staying with you now.
What is he, a relative?
Uh, he just rented the room
for a few days.
Get references.
I never trust anybody.
Mom, Mom, you better
come in here.
What is it?
Is it Mr. Parker?
Just come in here, please.
Where did this come from?
I don't know.
You didn't buy it?
I didn't pay for
the old stuff yet.
It's got a microwave oven.
You could cook pork chops
in three minutes.
It can cook dinner
while you're in school.
No, this isn't ours.
Don't touch it.
It's a mistake.
Holy Christmas.
Close it. Don't eat anything.
It's all going back.
It's not ours.
Look at that.
Turkey. Chicken.
Ham. Ice cream. We could
live for a year on this.
No, we can't. Put all these
things back. It's not ours.
Where's Mr. Baker?
Mr. Parker.
Mr. Parker! Mr. Parker.
Crushed-ice dispenser.
Don't crush ice.
Don't crush anything.
Leave it alone.
Mr. Parker. Mr. Parker,
are you in there?
I believe so.
That is stolen property
in there.
I will not cook
on a stolen stove,
and I will not eat
stolen turkeys
and stolen chickens.
I have receipts.
I paid cash.
Yes, which you stole
from a casino.
They took my money,
I took their money,
and Sears, Roebuck
has our money.
That is called
circulating cash flow.
That's how
our economy operates.
Well, you have been spotted
by Mrs. Litke next door,
so you and Sears, Roebuck
better go tonight, Max.
Nora, no one is looking
for Mr. Parker.
Max Dugan, on the other hand,
is a very sought-after person.
Just let me buy
a little more time.
Time I can afford.
A wonderama kitchen I can't.
A few small pleasures.
What harm can it do?
Would you refuse
a dying grandfather -
Don't say things like that.
Never again. I'm sorry.
Max...
it's not
that I'm not appreciative,
but when I think about
where that money came from
to buy those things...
It's not from the mouths
of innocent babes.
It comes from men
with names like
Boomie Bonozo
and Mario Bananas.
And you'll take
all those things with you
when you...
It's all right, you can say it.
I can't, you see. I'm the one
who's not allowed.
(sighs) What
am I gonna tell Michael
about all those things?
Don't worry about it.
Just leave it to Grandpa.
Mom, you're not gonna believe
what's in my room. You gotta
come see this.
Come on.
It's got everything.
It's got a TV,
it's got a stereo,
AM-FM radio,
shortwave, video recording.
It's like my own studio.
Is this the most
beautiful thing
you've ever seen?
Over there is a video camera.
You can tape your own shows.
Wow, I can film me
taking batting practice
like
the big-league teams do.
It's got a zoom lens, too.
No, Mike, not me.
Why not?
Well, certain primitive tribes
believe that pictures
steal your soul,
and I don't have
all that much soul.
Did you buy this?
Me, no.
Who did?
Mr. Parker was just going
to explain that.
You won it.
I what?
You won it on a TV show.
What TV show?
I don't know.
One of those TV shows
that people win prizes on.
I was never on a TV show.
It was one of those shows
that you don't have to be on.
I was in here cleaning up
the breakfast dishes
when the doorbell rings,
and in comes a lawyer
with a blue suit -
No, no.
No.
No, I don't think so.
I don't think I won this.
I never won anything in my life.
This is a mistake.
But it had your name
and address on the invoice.
I signed for you.
She'll probably have to go down
and do a few publicity pictures,
but that's it.
The stuff is yours.
Maybe it's on
the 6:00 news.
It's not on the 6:00 news.
Just turn that thing off
and put everything down.
A man with a blue suit, huh?
Mm-hmm. He said you
didn't have to worry
about the income tax
because it was
already paid for.
That was first prize,
tax-free.
Second prize, you had to pay
the income tax.
Now, an elderly couple
in Billings, Montana,
won that one.
Billings, Montana?
That's it. Just one
of those wonderful things
that happens now and then.
Shall we have dinner?
Ah, not crazy about
my chicken pizzaiola, huh?
There's just so much
a person can digest
in one day.
You won some cigars, too,
but I'm sure you'll probably
wanna pass on that one.
Can I be excused?
Yes, after we finish
the dishes.
No, no, you don't
have to do the dishes.
Just put 'em in the machine.
What machine?
You didn't see the machine?
It's right over there
under the cardboard boxes.
Cleans, scrapes, dries,
presses and packages
the leftovers.
Clever little thing,
isn't it?
I can't believe it.
No more dishes to do.
With the time you'll save,
you'll probably graduate
a year early.
All right, Mike,
go do your homework.
He doesn't have
something in his room that
does his homework, does he?
I'll check the catalog.
Good night, Mr. Parker.
Thanks for the dinner.
Mm, you're welcome.
That was terrific.
Oh, Mike, write down
what you want
for tomorrow night
and slip it under my door
in the morning.
Are you a basketball fan?
I sure am.
There's a Laker game on
at 10:00, if you'd like
to come in and watch.
I was hoping you'd ask me.
See you later.
I think the boy likes me.
He just hit the jackpot.
You expect him to be hostile?
Life hasn't been
all that wonderful to you,
has it, Nora?
You take what comes along.
Why not take the good
as well as the bad?
When it comes
from the same place,
I get a little suspicious.
Watch your ashes.
Oh, does my smoking
bother you?
No. Doesn't it bother you?
What does the doctor say
about those things?
Oh, he said, "Send me
what you don't finish."
He's not sentimental.
Michael has a terrific
sense of values.
I don't want
somebody coming along
and corrupting them.
Whoever told you
that abject poverty
was a character builder
was misinforming you.
I can see he's a fine boy.
You built a solid
foundation there.
I just wanna
spruce things up a bit,
that's all.
(Max) Good night, Mike.
I told ya
the Knicks would lose.
Yeah. Good night, Mr. Parker.
Good night, Nora.
Uh, Max...
Yeah?
I've got a problem.
OK.
Yeah, I'm in a jam.
Oh. Well, talk to me, honey.
That's what fathers are for.
I don't wanna be Cinderella.
Somewhere along the line,
you gotta pay for it.
I see. You've been
reading Freud,
the man who was responsible
for the invention of guilt.
Yeah, something apparently
you have none of.
I did six years
in the big house, kid.
I paid my debt.
I'll, uh, make a bargain
with you.
Stay here,
live with me and Mike.
I'm not a nurse
and not much of a daughter,
but I'll take care of you
the best way I know how.
In exchange?
Don't become a hero to Mike.
He's got a 15-year-old
drug dealer for a friend.
He doesn't need a 63-year-old
hardened criminal
for a role model.
When the time is right,
I want you to tell him
what you've done,
how you did it,
and most important,
that what you did
was wrong.
I can live with that.
An ill-chosen phrase,
if I ever heard one.
Max, one - Oh, Max,
one more thing...
Brian Costello,
the lieutenant, I like him.
Don't worry.
I give my approval.
He's smart,
and he's dedicated.
I think if he had to choose
giving me up to bring you in,
we'd both lose.
I understand.
I'll, uh, move
to another place
and visit you and Mike
on the weekends.
No, I didn't say that.
I think you should be careful.
I don't trust Mrs. Litke.
I think you should stay
in the house.
Back to prison, eh?
Nora...
I never had it so good.
(dog barking)
(Mrs. Litke) Shh! Shh!
Be quiet, I mean it.
You're gonna stay
in the house all day.
I'm not gonna take you
for a walk tomorrow.
Be quiet.
Now you be quiet.
(crowd cheering)
Come on, Mike, let's go,
babe. It's all yours.
All yours, kid.
Remember what I said.
Keep your eye on the ball.
Swing nice and level.
(umpire) Play ball.
(boy) Over the fence, Mikey.
Over the fence.
Oh, why him? Why do they all
leave it up to him?
(coach) Come on, Mike.
Come on, Mike.
It's all yours, kid.
Come on, Mike, hit it
out of the park!
(man) You can do it,
Mike, you can do it.
Strike!
No problem, Mike.
Just don't press.
Come on, Mike, you can
hit it out of the park!
Now come on. Take your time.
You can do it.
No problem, Mike. You're
just pressing too hard.
Just take it nice and easy.
(catcher) No problem.
Don't worry about it.
You got two more shots.
He can't hit,
Scotty.
Come on, he's a bum.
Scotty, get him.
Strike.
Oh, I hate this game.
I wish they never invented it.
Come on, Mike.
That guy can't pitch!
(coach) Just take it
nice and easy.
Shh.
(opposing team razzes him)
Here we go, Scotty,
here we go.
Strike three. You're out.
Feel like getting a pizza?
No.
You don't feel like a pizza?
I feel like quitting
the team.
Aw, Mike, don't say that.
You're a terrific first baseman.
You never make an error.
I never get a hit, either.
Maybe I need glasses.
I don't even see the bike.
It's right behind
this yellow truck.
Look, what if we came out
real early in the morning,
and I pitched to you?
I used to pitch softball
in high school.
It's not the same thing.
Where is it?
No. No, no.
Dear God, not again.
They took the bike?
Why, this isn't happening
to me.
This isn't happening!
Didn't you
put the chain on it?
Well, I couldn't find
the lock,
so I just tied the chains
in a knot.
You tied them in a knot?
Look, don't start with me.
I had a lousy day, too.
Oh, those bastards.
Those dirty bastards.
What am I gonna tell Brian?
A car and a bike
in one week.
He's gonna think
it's some kind of disease.
I can't believe
you tied the chains in a knot.
Will you stop saying that?
I don't tell you how
to hit, do I?
Mike, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it.
Wha...?
What's the matter?
What's wrong?
(gasps)
Oh!
Oh, my God.
Don't touch it!
It's a mistake.
Somebody parked it
in the wrong place.
It's a 380 SL.
They delivered it
this afternoon.
Who did?
Do I ask questions?
Mr. Parker.
Mr. Parker!
Schopenhauer.
Really?
Is that his car
parked in my yard?
No, it's yours.
Registered in your name.
The plates will probably
be here this week.
You promised me.
You gave me your word.
My word isn't worth diddly-poo.
It's my money, my five months,
and if you don't like it...
you can make it
into a flowerpot.
(Michael honking horn)
Hey, where's the motorbike?
It was stolen.
Stolen?
Didn't you chain it up?
I don't wanna talk about it.
(horn honking)
Michael, get out of that car!
It's not ours!
I can't drive that to school.
I don't make enough
to pay the insurance.
It's paid for.
It's yours, Nora.
Don't be stupid.
Take what's coming to ya.
Look, you've gotten enough
dirty deals in your life.
Don't turn your back
on a payoff.
He almost stole
a baseball glove last summer.
How do I explain to him
it's OK to keep that thing?
Let me explain it to him.
The whole story?
The works.
About jail,
where the money came from...
Just give me ten minutes
alone with him.
Michael,
come in here, please.
It was all for nothing.
I spent seven years
in a Vegas pit,
all for nothing.
I didn't think
getting to know
one another again
is exactly nothing.
Ma, look at this.
I can't believe it.
It even tells the time
in China.
Where did you get that?
Oh, it was
in the front seat
of the car.
It was in a little box
that said, "Happy Birthday,
Mike."
Do you know what time it is
in Shanghai?
(watch beeping tune)
Michael...
Michael?
Mr. Parker has something
he wants to tell you.
I've gotta take a bath.
Brian is picking me up
at 7:30.
Brian Costello,
the lieutenant on the LAPD.
Everything.
Come on in, Mike.
Sit down.
Make yourself comfortable.
(Nora whispers)
Everything.
What time is it
in Istanbul?
(watch beeps tune)
3:15 am.
3:15 am, huh?
You're probably the only boy
in Southern California
that knows that.
Mmm.
Well, first of all,
my name isn't Parker.
It isn't?
No.
It's Wittgenstein.
Wittgenstein?
Gus Wittgenstein.
I was a friend
of your grandfather's.
I shared the same cell with him
for six years in Joliet Prison.
You did?
Max Dugan was a fine man.
Made a few mistakes in his life
and always regretted it.
One of them was
not getting in touch with you.
Died, a year ago, in Nevada.
Does Mom know about this?
Yeah. Told her
the night I got here.
She never said a word.
Well, the Dugans
were all like that.
Now, when your grandfather died,
he left a will
and made me the trustee.
The money was to go
to you and your mother.
There was a catch to it,
though.
What's that?
When Max was on his deathbed...
You were there?
Sitting at his feet.
He said,
"Gus, take care of them,
"but don't tell them
the money came from me.
"Make up some cockeyed story,
but keep my secret.
"See that Mike gets
a good education
"and make sure he goes
to a good college back east
and majors in philosophy."
Philosophy?
I have to take philosophy?
Well, it's just a suggestion.
Then his heart
just stopped beating,
and his hand went cold
in mine.
So, that's the story.
It's up to you now.
What's up to me?
The reuniting -
your beloved grandfather
and your mother and yourself -
by accepting his gifts
of love and affection.
I accept.
That's good.
I know he'd appreciate it.
It's your mother
that's the problem.
You see, a promise made
on a deathbed is sacred.
Yeah. You've got to convince
your mother somehow
to grant your grandfather's
dying wish.
I don't think the man
will rest in peace
until she does.
Wow. Sounds like a story
that I once saw
on Movie of the Week.
How often art imitates life.
Yeah.
Will you help me, Mike?
I'll try.
Good boy.
Can I ask one question?
Anything.
What business
was my grandfather in?
Philosophy.
That's why he wants you
to go into it, too.
You can make money
from philosophy?
Oh, yes, sir,
if you got the right one.
You OK?
Oh, yeah, I'm fine.
He told you everything?
Yeah, he told me.
About jail?
Yeah.
Where the money came from?
Then you can understand
why I can't accept it.
Oh, yeah, I can understand.
Oh, thanks, Mike.
I knew you would.
Are you gonna
give everything back?
Well, don't you think
I should?
Dying wish is sacred.
He told you about that, too?
Ohh...
I'm sorry.
I know how you feel.
I feel the same way.
What are you gonna do?
(sighs) I don't know.
I just have to
think about it.
But not tonight.
I have to see Brian tonight.
Aah!
What's that?
Is it real?
That's the most beautiful thing
I've ever seen.
There's a card in the box.
"For past days lost
but not forgotten.
Your beloved father."
Try it on.
See how it looks.
You think I should?
It's yours, isn't it?
Oh, you look great.
The card.
He got me with the card.
Did you know that your father
wanted me to go to college
and major in philosophy?
No. He didn't mention it.
Who didn't mention it?
My father.
Your father?
You spoke to your father?
Well, I may be angry with him,
but I still talk to him,
don't I?
Joy.
He put Joy in there.
That's $200 an ounce.
How can you talk
to your father?
He's dead.
Who's dead?
Your father.
He died in prison in Nevada.
Who told you that?
Mr. Wittgenstein.
Who's Mr. Wittgenstein?
Mr. Parker.
Mr. Parker
is Mr. Wittgenstein?
(doorbell ringing)
Should I get the door?
No, no,
don't get the door.
I don't want Brian
to see my father.
How can he see your father?
Because Mr. Wittgenstein
is my father.
I mean, Mr. Parker is.
I thought Max Dugan was.
He is. Uh, he was.
Well, I mean...
What did he tell you?
Look... wait.
We'll talk about this
when I get home.
(ring)
And, listen, don't go
into what's-his-name's room.
I think there's something
severely wrong with him.
You want me to get that?
It's the policeman.
Never mind.
(ringing)
Michael, just go answer
the door, and...
but don't let Brian
in the house
and just tell him
I'll be right there.
Don't you like doctors
or dentists?
Wittgenstein?
Yeah, the German
philosopher.
It's the only name
I could think of.
Well, what's wrong
with Max Dugan?
How do you know
I am Max Dugan?
You told me you were.
I told you a lot of things,
but so far, you haven't liked
any of them,
so I'll keep on telling you
new ones until you pick out
one you like.
Hi.
Mom's getting dressed.
Is that as far
as the door opens?
Oh, she'll be right with you.
I have to do my homework.
Excuse me.
Are you telling me
that you're not my father?
Maybe I am and maybe I'm not.
Maybe I'm your father
but you're not my daughter.
Do you know
what Kierkegaard once said?
Yes, and I am not interested
in any more of your roommates.
I have to go.
I have to live my life.
I have to try and appear
calm and intelligent.
I am dating a person.
We will discuss this
when I get home.
Hi.
It's been jammed all day.
Oh.
They're for you.
Thank you.
That's very nice of you.
You don't want to go in
and put 'em in water?
The pipes are rusty.
We have brown water.
It would kill the flowers.
I'll, uh, I'll carry them.
You look nice.
That's a beautiful necklace.
What? Oh... thanks.
If only they were real.
Shall we go?
Sure.
Who does that car
belong to?
What car?
Oh, the Mercedes.
I don't know.
You don't know?
Well, I don't know
who actually owns it.
I only rented it
for a couple of days.
You rented a 1982
Mercedes Benz convertible?
It was the only one
that they had left,
but they're charging me
the same as they would a Chevy.
That's their policy.
You didn't like
the motorbike?
I loved it.
You loved it?
You don't love it anymore?
I don't have it anymore.
It was stolen in a parking lot.
But I told the police.
I'm surprised
they didn't tell you.
They tell me when
other vehicles are stolen.
They don't tell me
when it's mine.
You mean, the man tells you
he has no Chevys or Fords left,
so he gives you a Mercedes
at the same price?
I guess I'll have to pay
for the mileage.
I really don't know.
Is that all we're going
to talk about tonight - cars?
Sorry. They just
fascinate me.
Listen, is there
something wrong?
I mean,
other than their stealing
your bike - our bike?
I am gonna pay for that bike,
every cent.
I just need a little time.
I don't care about the bike.
What I care about
is what's happening to you.
I'm glad you do. It's just
that going out right now
comes at such a bad time.
Why is that?
I'm really going through
a very trying period
right now.
I've got a lot on my mind,
and, I don't know, maybe
for the time being,
it would be better if we didn't
see so much of each other.
This is our first date.
I realize that.
It's just that Michael
is very insecure
about me seeing people - men.
It's not that he doesn't
like you. He does.
I'm just not sure
that he is ready
to accept someone new
in the house just now.
I haven't been
in the house yet.
I know. I know.
He's 15.
It's a very difficult age.
I understand.
My kid's 14.
It's a tough time.
Oh, no, 15 is worse.
They're very weird at 15.
So maybe if you didn't
come around for a while...
This way, please.
Thank you.
I don't know.
I can't think straight.
I've lost 37 exam papers
and 2 vehicles,
all in one week.
It's the money, too,
isn't it?
I know what it's like
to be that broke.
It can make you half crazy.
Would you give me
the honor and the privilege
of loaning you some money?
I don't want any money.
I haven't asked you
for any money, have I?
No, you wouldn't.
That's why I thought -
Well, you're wrong.
I appreciate it,
but please don't offer me
any money anymore.
It makes me feel terrible.
I'll get it.
(gasps) Shit.
What's that?
Nothing.
Could we please
just order?
Was that $5,000 in cash?
I don't know.
I didn't count it.
Waiter?
What are you doing
with $5,000 in cash?
How's the halibut?
It's delicious, ma'am.
It's not mine.
It's the school's.
The school's?
Yes. I'm on
the finance committee.
It's parents' donations.
We're building
a brand-new swimming pool.
What are you doing
carrying it around in cash?
Well, why not?
I'm having dinner
with a cop, aren't I?
It's safer
than being at home.
Could we...
just order, please?
I'm going to be frank
with you.
I had a lousy time.
I know. I'm sorry.
It's all my fault.
Do you wanna see me
again?
Yes.
Can I come in
for a minute?
No.
Why not?
I told you,
it's Michael.
No, it isn't.
You're lying.
You're dealing
with a professional now.
I'll go to your place.
Now?
Well, if you want me to.
Is that what you want?
Yes.
You're lying again.
What is it with you?
Listen, I'm trying
to keep so many people happy
all at the same time,
and I'm not one of them,
but don't give up on me.
I'm worth it, I promise.
I'll, uh,
I'll call you tomorrow, OK?
Good night.
Take it easy with him.
Don't pitch too fast.
I want him to hit.
All right, Mikey, you're up.
Come on, let's go.
(boy) Come on!
Go, Mike!
Come on, kid.
Get ready, Craig.
You all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
All right, nice and easy.
Just keep your eye
on the ball.
Let's go.
(boy) Come on, dude...
Level bat, level bat.
Remember what I taught you.
All right, Craig.
Go!
Pitch to him, now.
(boys groaning)
No pressure.
No pre--
Hey, guys, come on.
Let's hear some chatter...
(boy) Aw, man.
Just concentrate.
You can do it.
Come on.
Look alive.
(clapping)
All right, Craig,
let's go, let's go!
(boy) Aw, man!
Michael, you're pressing
too hard. That's it.
Just take it nice and easy,
all right?
Yeah.
Hey, you're not pitching
the All-Stars.
Take it easy.
Pitch to him.
Just don't press.
Level bat.
Keep your eyes on the ball.
That's all you gotta do.
It'll be all yours.
It'll be over the fence.
OK.
(boys groan)
Oh, man, if you can't hit,
let somebody else practice.
(coach) Pipe down, Pop.
It's all right, Mikey.
Come on, you can do it.
Let's go. Wait, wait, wait.
Are you sure you're OK?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
All right, you can do it.
I believe in you.
That's all you need.
(boys laughing)
All right, Craig.
(Pop) Next.
Damn.
(coach)
Mikey, take it easy, now.
What's the matter with him?
Don't be so hard on yourself.
It's gonna be all right.
All right. OK.
Danny, why don't you
hit a few?
Are you Michael McPhee?
Yeah.
I'm Charley Lau.
You ever heard of me?
No.
I'm the batting coach
for the White Sox.
What White Sox?
Chicago White Sox.
I've been watching you
swing the bat,
and you stink,
you know that?
Oh, yeah, no kidding.
It's not your fault.
No one taught you
the basics.
If you wanna learn,
I'd like to teach 'em to ya.
Are you serious?
Yep.
Why would you waste your time
teaching me?
I'm not wasting my time.
I'm well paid.
I got a nice check in the mail
along with a letter that said,
"Teach this young man
a basic swing
and the philosophy
of hitting."
The philosophy of hitting?
You don't have
the right philosophy,
you're not gonna
hit your weight.
You understand?
Yeah... I understand.
Thanks a lot, Mr. Lau.
Well, pal,
we got some talkin' to do.
When they're done,
we're gonna work,
but we're gonna talk
right now,
and we're gonna talk about
what we're gonna do
out there.
We're gonna work
on stance, a balanced,
workable stance
that allows you
to swing the bat
and not turn your head.
Take your stance
and let's see what happens.
Let's just see if you
are balanced to start with.
That's not awful,
awful good.
Where's the weight
on your feet?
It's on this foot.
I don't know
of anything you can do
sittin' like that.
Now, if that guy's
not your friend -
and believe me,
he's not your friend -
you have got to get positive
and aggressive,
and you've got to go at him.
Keep that distance,
relaxed and nice and...
There can't be any tension.
If this is a tee
and you're gonna
hit that ball off the tee,
what would you do?
Go ahead and hit it.
OK.
Swing at it and hit it.
All of a sudden,
we're gonna do this, all right?
Nice little wiggle.
That works.
I want you to be aware
of the discipline
of your head
and a good transfer
of the weight.
I want you to get
to a firm front side
and explode your hips.
Keep the head.
Try and hit
that handkerchief.
Not bad.
Let's do it again.
Hey, dummy, you can't hit
what you can't see.
I like it.
You got a chance.
(bat cracking)
Gettin' better.
I like it.
Michael, I need
a little more wiggle now.
Relax.
Come on, dummy.
(bat cracks)
Oh! I did it!
(laughs)
Oh! Oh! Ha!
(grunting)
I did it.
Mike, what a shot.
What a shot.
(laughs)
Whoa!
You're a genius.
You genius!
Oh!
...three of them
over the fence.
Charley says
he has to leave in a week
to go back to spring training.
He's gonna try
and come back on Saturday
when we play the Bears.
That's terrific, Mike.
I couldn't believe
that it was really
Charley Lau
until he mentioned
the philosophy
of hitting.
Then I knew who it was
who sent that check.
Hi. Hello.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
I like what you did
to your house,
honey.
Oh, thank you,
Mrs. Litke.
(giggles)
I like what you did
to your car, too.
Yes, the car.
Of course.
Here, I'll get the gate
for you.
I think
it's just beautiful.
I like the front
even better.
Come on, Tiger.
Come on, Popeye.
Well, how did he...?
Oh, that's...
(dogs barking)
Pigeons and doves.
They raise
the teachers' salary
this year?
No, no, no. I've been doing
private tutoring in the evening.
Who you tutoring - Arabs?
Promise me
you won't get angry?
You got an airplane in there.
He brought you a tiny,
little jet plane in there.
Is that what it is?
If you let me keep
this one,
I'll give back
everything else,
I promise.
I'll pay for this one
myself.
Open the door.
(barking)
His name's Plato.
It was on his collar.
Plato?
Yeah, you know, like the dog
from Mickey Mouse.
Pluto.
Yeah, whatever.
Isn't he beautiful?
He's a purebred.
Yeah. He comes
from royal lineage.
You can still see
the little marks
on his head
where he used to wear
a crown.
Max.
Yeah?
We have to talk.
Oh, sure.
Mike, you wanna take Plato
out for a walk?
Sure.
Does he fetch?
He fetches, he builds,
he destroys.
Anything you want.
Come here, Plato.
(laughing)
Come on.
(Plato barks)
Well, you don't have to worry
about bathing him.
I can always take him
to a car wash.
(cat screeches)
I can't fight ya
anymore, Max.
Should have seen the look
on Mike's face
when he powered that ball
over the fence today.
Damn, it was terrific.
You were there
in broad daylight?
Yeah. I'd have cashed
my tickets in today
to see that.
(coughs)
What's wrong?
Are you in pain?
Well, we may have to
cut our visit
a little shorter
than planned.
(murmurs) Water.
Ahh.
Nora, my love,
I'm havin' one hell
of a grand time.
If I knew it was gonna be
this much fun,
I'd have had
a dozen grandchildren.
Now you listen to me, Max.
You're not gonna
give up on me now.
I don't care
how much strength it takes.
You're gonna fight,
and I'm gonna help you.
I'll do whatever you want.
You wanna buy Mike and me
a present?
Yeah.
Buy me six more months
with an option for another six,
and then we'll negotiate
from there.
Is it a deal?
And if you ever
run out on me again,
I'll never forgive you.
(* rock on radio)
Have a nice day!
(Nora) You, too!
I'll get the gate!
(door opens/
Plato barking)
Can I help you?
I'm sorry. I was lookin'
for Miss McPhee.
Oh, she's at school.
Oh.
How'd you get in?
Well, she must have
left the door unlocked.
I knocked, and...
My name's Brian Costello.
I'm a friend of hers.
She left these flowers
in my car the other night.
Oh, thank you.
I'll take care of them.
Thank you.
I do odd jobs for her
now and then.
Do ya?
She didn't tell me.
Sort of a caretaker,
are ya?
No, no. I pick up a meal
here and there.
Anything you want me
to tell her?
No, no, no. No, I'll, uh,
I'll drop by the school later.
Anything you want me
to tell her?
Can't think of anything.
Good.
Well, it was nice to meet you,
Mister, uh...
Parker.
Thank you.
See ya.
(Plato barking)
Parker?
Do you do plumbing?
I'm always having trouble
with my plumbing.
Little out of my line.
I'm moving out of state
in a few days, anyway.
Aw, Miss McPhee's
going to miss you.
You've done
just terrific work here,
especially when you consider
her income.
(camera shutter clicking)
I'll have the salad,
a small grapefruit juice,
coffee - black, no sugar.
(man) You got it?
Thanks. OK.
If they stole the Mercedes,
I don't wanna hear about it.
I thought
you were gonna call.
I'm sorry. I've been busy.
Collecting more money
for the swimming pool?
I saw one downstairs
in the basement.
What'd they do -
rent it for the weekend?
I've only got 15 minutes
for lunch.
Could we talk about this
some other time?
I went by your house.
I'm really crazy
about the paint job.
It's a rented house.
The landlord owed it to me
for two years.
Mrs. Litke
has the same landlord,
and she's been there ten years.
She doesn't know how
to talk to him.
He give you the dog
as a bonus?
What dog?
The big one.
The one in the backyard.
The one that looks
down into the house.
Michael wanted a dog,
and we certainly
can't afford one.
So we went down to the pound
and picked him out.
That dog
has championship class.
He probably cost
$2,000, $3,000.
You mean
nobody claimed him?
Maybe he was badly treated.
There are a lot of rotten
rich people in the world.
I think it's time you and I
had a little talk, Nora...
in private.
Your neighbor, Mrs. Litke,
makes a routine call
to the police
complaining
about a large dog barking
in the middle of the night,
but we're a little busy
for dog-barking complaints.
But the boys
put it in the computer,
just for future reference.
The computer punches out
that the dog owner just had
a car and a motorcycle stolen
and also recently called
to complain
about an obscene caller
and a possible prowl suspect.
When the name
of Mrs. Nora McPhee - widow,
mother, schoolteacher -
prints out,
the card, naturally,
is dropped on my desk
by a burly sergeant
with raised eyebrows.
Shall I go on?
Do I have a choice?
Mrs. keen-eyed Litke
volunteered that delivery vans
pull up to your house
twice a day,
including Saturdays,
unloading large boxes
bearing such distinguished names
as Westinghouse,
General Electric,
Honeywell, Mitsubishi.
This, compounded by the fact
that one of the lowest-paid
Mercedes-driving employees
of the county
carries around $5,000
in brand-new bills,
compels me to ask
a very serious question -
what the hell is going on here?
There is a kid
not 50 yards from here
who is selling drugs
to 14-year-olds.
Surely you have
more important things to do
than drag a schoolteacher
away from her lunch.
Who is the man
living in your house?
What man?
This man.
Mr. Parker.
Does odd jobs, he tells me.
Came ten days ago
wearing a black hat,
black coat,
carrying a black satchel.
Mrs. Litke is more dependable
than the CIA.
Who is he, Nora?
An uncle,
a relative from back east.
A close relative?
No. He's only staying
a couple of weeks.
He deposited $400,000
in California First Federal
this morning, in cash.
It's none of my business.
I'm late.
The account was opened
in your name.
Talk to me, Nora.
I can't.
Please, don't ask me
anything else, Brian.
What are you mixed up in?
I'm just trying to help you.
Asking me questions
is not going to help me.
Why is he so generous to you?
What does he owe ya?
Nothing! He's just very rich
and very eccentric.
He does things like that.
It's his Mercedes.
He's taking it with him.
And the 400,000?
Can't you stop being a cop
for five minutes
and be a friend?
No. That's why
I don't have too many friends.
Well, if it's one less
you want, you're doing
a terrific job.
Nora.
I don't buy any of it.
I been at this job too long.
I don't think he's your uncle.
I think you're
involved with something
you don't know how to handle.
I'm going to take this picture
and follow up on it.
If you've got anything
you want to tell me,
you better tell me now.
All right.
Good-bye, Brian.
(bell rings)
$3, please.
Thank you.
No prob.
* Na-na ja ba-da dunh *
Wow.
Fantastic.
Gee, this must have cost
a fortune.
You like it, Ma?
Where were you?
I went to pick you up
after school.
You weren't there.
I stayed late
to practice hitting
with Charley,
and I took a taxi home.
A taxi?
It's OK. I had money.
Give it to me.
You are not to accept
any more gifts,
you understand?
No watches, no TV,
no taxi money, no dogs.
Nothing.
Is that understood?
Yeah, sure, but Mr. Wittgenstein
said that you wouldn't mind.
He is not Mr. Wittgenstein
or Mr. Parker.
He is Mr. Dugan.
Max Dugan.
He is my father
and your grandfather.
My grandfather?
And he spent six years in jail
for embezzling and forging,
and all of this money
doesn't belong to him
and it doesn't belong to us,
and everything is going back,
including Pluto.
Plato.
Whoever he is.
Michael,
he is in trouble,
and I have got to
figure out something
really fast.
(sighs) I didn't realize
how happy we were
before all this came.
I mean, I think we managed
pretty well, didn't we?
I thought so.
(* violin)
Me too.
Max!
(Max) It's open.
(* violin continues)
If I had six more months,
I could learn to play
this damn thing.
(music stops)
Oh, you don't like
the living room.
I can tell.
Max.
Hmm?
You gotta leave - today.
Tonight. The police
know you're here.
I know. We met.
He's smart, that one.
I can always tell
by the eyes.
He doesn't know who you are,
but he's got a picture of you
taken outside of a bank.
Well, I'm slipping, Nora.
Not as sharp as I used to be.
Listen, I've got an idea,
a plan.
Yeah?
I think you should
give yourself up.
You interrupted Bach
to tell me that?
If you give back all the money,
maybe they won't press charges.
Considering your condition,
they wouldn't be anxious
to prosecute.
You could stay with Mike and me
for as long as you wanted.
All three of us living
on your salary?
Heart failure
doesn't frighten me,
but malnutrition does.
Aw, come on.
We could work something out.
At least we'd all be together.
I am not going to my grave
without leaving some security
for you and Mike.
It's all I been living for,
for chrissake.
I'm not giving myself up.
You told me in this very room
to put up a fight,
and I'll be damned
if I'll take the count
without doing it.
(sighs)
Damn it. I blew it.
I could be sitting
on a sandy white beach
in Brazil right now,
drinking piña coladas
and fornicating my way
straight to heaven.
What if we went away
together, all of us,
to New Mexico or Arizona?
I could teach, get a job,
just until -
And the detective?
He's more interested
in getting his man
than his woman.
You'd do that for me? Why?
I'd miss your pancakes
in the morning.
You've grown into
an extraordinary
young woman, Nora,
and I deserve
all the credit.
If I didn't abandon you,
God knows what would have
happened to you.
(both laugh)
Well, let's sleep on it,
and we'll discuss it
in the morning.
No, we go in the morning.
You mean, we just -
Yep, just go
with the clothes
on our backs.
There's a moral
to all this, you know.
What?
It doesn't always pay
to get in touch with
your children.
Oh, is that so?
Mike?
Hey, Mike.
What time is it?
Huh?
I don't know. Uh...
(watch beeps tune)
In Singapore,
it's around lunchtime.
Are you just coming in?
No, I'm going out.
I'm leaving, Mike.
Leaving for where?
Oh, south. You know me -
easy come, easy go.
You mean for good?
No. You see, in the East,
they have a philosophy.
Once you meet
a man you like,
you're destined
to meet him again.
Are you going
because of the police?
Your mother told ya, huh?
Well, sort of.
You see, if I hang around,
it makes your mother
kind of an accessory.
She could go to jail,
and I lied to you
before, Mike.
The only thing
I ever learned in jail
was that it was
a terrific place
to stay out of.
So keep your nose clean.
Keep your eye on the ball.
So long, kid.
So I'll probably
be heading for
those white sandy beaches
and piña coladas.
I didn't deposit
all the money.
I may be sentimental,
but I'm not stupid.
Thank you both
for the best two weeks
of my life.
Sorry I won't be there
for the game today, Mike,
but if you happen
to get ahold of a long one,
as you're rounding the bases,
I'd be very proud and pleased
if you said,
"That one was for you,
Wittgenstein."
Be sure you destroy this tape
after you've heard it.
(click)
Why did he leave?
I didn't tell you
everything, Mike.
that he was sick.
I think he was grateful
for whatever time he did have.
If you knew that,
why did you let him
leave here?
I offered to move,
the three of us,
but it was his decision.
I mean,
how could I stop him?
I don't know.
You're a teacher.
You could have thought
of something.
(siren wailing)
I'm a police officer,
that is a police car,
and that is a siren
on a police car.
Now, when you hear
a police officer
yell, "Stop,"
you goddamn well
better stop...
Was I speeding?
Did I go
through a red light?
Did I make a right-hand turn
in the left-hand lane?
If you stop me,
you better goddamn well
have a reason to stop me!
I have.
He's your father,
isn't he?
That's right.
There any more questions?
I have a ball game to go to.
You know he's wanted
in Las Vegas, not only
by the police
but by some
very irate gentlemen
who break your legs...
If it's money you want,
pull up a van and take away
the house, including the car.
Now get out of my way.
Where is he?
I believe he went
for a piña colada.
They're gonna ask questions,
Nora, like "Did you know
where the money came from?"
Of course I did.
He told me.
You're not under oath.
You don't have to
stick to that.
Move along.
Why shouldn't I?
He's my father.
He came to me in trouble.
What do you expect me to do?
I'm a goddamned detective.
The chief of police
is not your father.
Our problems have nothing
in common.
You don't understand.
It's your neck I'm worried
about, not your father's.
Now give me a break,
will ya? Where is he?
I don't know.
Yes, you do.
Of course you do.
I always know
when you're lying.
You wanna end up
in jail, Nora?
I'll wait for ya
'cause I'm nuts about ya,
but I won't see you
on weekends.
I see my kid on weekends.
I'm going to Michael's
baseball game.
If you wanna stop me, you're
going to have to shoot me.
Nora!
Here, take the Mercedes.
You'll never get a cab
in this neighborhood.
Thank you.
Tell me something.
Do you think I'm corrupt?
Aren't we all,
just a little bit?
Just a little bit?
(spectators cheering)
Come on, Craig.
He's getting tired!
Come on.
Now whack it out!
(man) Right there
on the letters!
(cheer)
Get a piece of it,
Craig!
Hit the wild ball, kid!
Please, God,
don't leave it up to Michael.
(team cheering)
(Venice coach)
No problem, Craig.
You can do it, Craig.
Hit it outta here!
Come on, Craig!
(cheerleaders chanting)
Santa Monica's number one!
Why didn't you tell me
how sick he was?
Would it have made
any difference to you?
Yeah. I don't know.
How did you find out?
It's my job.
I'm sorry, Nora.
Well, save your sympathy
for Michael.
We're losing 2 to nothing
in the ninth.
You're losing 2-nothing.
My boy plays for Santa Monica.
Let's go, Kevin, baby!
Your boy? Which one?
The one pitchin'.
(Venice coach)
All right, Craig!
Don't swing!
Let him pitch to ya!
Easy out, Kevin.
Easy out.
That's your son?
He should be
in the major leagues.
I thought he was a midget.
(Venice coach) Yeah!
All right, Craig! Great!
(spectators cheering)
(spectators chanting)
Go, Mike, go!
We're in a jam now, Mike.
You haven't hit your weight
all year.
We got a chance
to win this game,
but I'm gonna leave it
up to you.
Want me to pinch-hit for you,
or you wanna swing?
(spectators chanting)
Santa Monica's number one!
I wanna swing.
What plane
is he taking, Nora?
You'll never catch him now.
I don't care
about catching him.
I care about you telling me.
Then you're off the hook.
My kid's coming up to bat.
Piña colada, you said.
Tropical climate?
Come on, get ahold
of one, Michael!
You can do it now!
Riviera?
Hawaii? Tahiti?
South America?
You looked at me.
It's South America.
Copacabana Beach. Brazil.
It's Brazil, isn't it?
...Michael, hit it
out of the park!
I'm calling the airlines,
Nora, right now.
You're gonna leave
while your son is pitching
and my son
is gonna hit that ball
right out of the park.
Against Kevin?
For how much?
All the information
you want.
(Venice coach)
Over the fence, Mikey.
Over the fence.
Come on, Michael!
Knock the hell
out of that goddamn ball!
Just concentrate.
Put it all together, kid.
(Craig's mother)
Wild man pitcher up there.
He can't pitch
to anything!
Strike!
(Nora) Come on,
just concentrate!
You can do it, Kevin!
Nobody up there!
Swing, Michael!
Just one swing!
Hit the shit
out of it!
Hey, Nora,
watch your language.
You're supposed to be
an English teacher.
They stole my car, my bike,
my goddamned exam papers.
You gotta fight back
sometime.
Hit it, Michael!
Hit it
for Gus Wittgenstein!
You're the best, Kevin!
Come on! Remember
what Charley taught you,
Michael!
Now watch the ball!
Strike two!
It's OK, Mike.
Nothin' to worry about.
We're behind ya.
For Schopenhauer, Michael,
and Spinoza
and Sophocles and Aristotle!
Come on, Kevin!
Doesn't even know the names
of her own team.
(Nora) Come on, Michael!
Do it for Pluto!
I mean, Plato...
(Venice coach)
Look alive there, kid.
Look alive!
...Michael!
You can do it!
Please, God. Please?
(Brian) Come on, Kevin!
(Venice coach)
Come on, Mikey.
Let's go!
(Nora) Don't pay
any attention to Brian.
(bat cracks)
Hey, son...
can I see that ball
for a minute?
(cheering)
(screams)
Whoo!
He did it! He did it!
I hate that kid of yours.
I'll get over it,
but I hate him.
That was for you,
Wittgenstein!
(boy) Up yours, McPhee.
(cheering)
That was some hit,
wasn't it?
Yeah, I just saw it.
Now give it back.
I tell you what.
You take $5 for it?
$5?
Yeah, and 5
for your friend here?
(both) Sure.
Sold.
Thanks, boys.
That ball means a lot to me.
Oh, you were wonderful!
I can't even catch
my breath.
I was so proud of you.
You know, I just wish
that he were here.
I mean, I wish
that he were here to see it.
I know, sweetheart, I know.
No chance. You pitched
a terrific game.
Only somebody like Hank Aaron
could have hit that ball.
Yeah, well, he swung
like Hank Aaron.
You two guys oughta meet.
Michael!
Nora!
Michael McPhee,
this is my son
Kevin Costello.
Hi.
You're one
terrific pitcher.
Hi, Kevin.
Nora McPhee.
Yeah. My pop told me
where you teach.
Mom and I are moving
next year, and I'll be
going to your school.
Really? What grade?
Tenth.
Tenth? I teach
tenth-grade English.
You may be in my class.
You might be in trouble.
You may be teaching it
in a state institution.
Brazil.
He's going to Brazil.
Damn it.
What's wrong?
I no longer have any idea
whether you're lying
or telling the truth.
Anybody hungry
for a giant pizza?
(Michael) For sure!
(Kevin) Totally!
I gotta make a phone call.
No, you don't.
It's the weekend,
and nobody works
24 hours a day.
You haven't had
your lunch yet.
And besides,
nobody important
is going to get away
while you're having
a pizza.
The Pizza Hut
on 8th Street?
Come on, Mike!
Let's ride in the Mercedes!
(laughs)
Where is it?
It was here.
I locked that car...
How can you lock the car
and it's not here now?
(horn honking)
Was that...?
My God, he's gonna drive
to Brazil.
So long, Pop.