They've killed the boy!
They've killed young Paolo!
They've killed your son Paolo!
Murderers! Murderers!
My son...
All my respect, Don Ciccio.
You killed my husband because
he wouldn't give in to you.
And his oldest son Paolo...
... because he swore revenge.
But Vito is only nine.
And dumb-witted.
He never speaks.
It's not his words I'm afraid of.
He's weak. He couldn't hurt anyone.
But when he grows, he'll grow strong.
Don't worry. This little boy
can't do a thing to you.
When he's a man, he'll
come for revenge.
I beg you, Don Ciccio,
spare my only son.
He's all I have left.
I swear to God he'll never do
you any harm. Spare him!
Move and I'll kill him!
Run, Vito!
Kill him!
Any family who hides the boy
Vito Andolini will regret it!
You understand?
Anybody who hides the boy
Vito Andolini is in for trouble!
Vito, we're praying for you!
If anyone is hiding the boy
Vito Andolini...
... turn him over to us.
Don Ciccio will thank you for it!
It'll be better for the boy,
and better for you!
Any family who hides the boy
Vito Andolini will regret it!
With all respect, I didn't
come here to eat dinner!
I know, I know.
Your family's still called Corleone.
And you'll run it like a Corleone.
My family doesn't eat here,
doesn't eat in Las Vegas...
... and doesn't eat in Miami...
... with Hyman Roth!
You'll have to excuse me. I'm tired,
and I'm a little drunk!
Cicci, the door...
She's really beautiful.
You've got to see her.
Wait till you see her.
Words can't describe her.
I left Naples. I left Mama.
For a no-good tramp!
Now here I am in America,
in New York.
Alone! Thinking of my mother.
Without news from home.
Finally, a letter from Naples!
Vito, how do you like my little angel?
Isn't she beautiful?
She's very beautiful.
To you, she's beautiful. For me,
there's only my wife and son.
Our dear mother -
... is dead!
We'll go backstage later
and take her to eat.
Sit down, you bum!
Oh, excuse me, Don Fanucci.
We'll go see her backstage.
Who was that?
The Black Hand.
That's Fanucci... the Black Hand.
We'll talk about it tomorrow.
Tomorrow! Always tomorrow!
You'll pay me today!
Let's go.
Not my daughter! Let her go!
Here, take all my money!
I know what you're thinking. But
you don't know how things are.
Fanucci's with the Black Hand.
The whole neighborhood pays him.
Even my father, in the grocery store.
If he's Italian...
... why does he bother other Italians?
He knows they have nobody
to protect them.
Forget that. Did you like my angel?
If you're happy, I'm happy.
Don't you feel well?
Is your boss treating you all right?
Forget it.
Hide this for me!
Next week I'll come and get it!
Abbandando, meet my nephew!
How's business?
It's good, it's good.
Fanucci's mad. Says the
neighborhood's getting sloppy.
People don't pay on time,
don't pay the full amount.
Says he's been too nice to everyone.
So Fanucci's changing?
Sure. He wants double
from everybody.
Even from my father.
I'm a friend, right? So you'll
let him work here?
I've got some bad news.
I feel rotten about telling you this...
But Fanucci... he's got a nephew...
And you have to give him my job.
You've always been good to me,
ever since I came here.
You looked after me like a father.
I thank you.
And I won't forget it.
Take this to your family.
Thanks anyway. But please,
I can't accept.
What a nice pear!
I'm Clemenza, you still
have my goods?
Did you look inside?
I'm not interested in things
that don't concern me.
A friend of mine has a nice rug.
Maybe your wife would like it.
Sure she would. But who has
money for a rug?
It would be a present.
I know how to return a favor.
My wife would like it.
That son of a bitch! He isn't home!
Damn, he didn't even leave the key.
Well, he won't mind.
This is your friend's place?
This is a real palace.
One of the best.
Vito, give me a hand, will you?
Look how pretty it is, Santino!
Michael Corleone is here.
He's in your den. You better hurry.
He's been waiting a half hour.
Is something wrong?
It's nothing.
Just some lousy bandits.
The police are cleaning them up.
It's New Year's Eve. Come on,
just for a minute.
Due to serious setbacks to our
troops in Guantanamo and Santiago...
... my position in Cuba is untenable.
I am resigning from office
to avoid further bloodshed.
And I shall leave the city immediately.
I wish all of you good luck.
Poor little Fredo, he's got pneumonia.
Young man, I hear you and
your friends are stealing goods.
But you don't even send a
dress to my house. No respect!
You know I've got three daughters.
This is my neighborhood.
You and your friends should
show me some respect.
You should let me wet
my beak a little.
I hear you and your friends
cleared $600 each.
Give me $200 each, for your own
protection. And I'll forget the insult.
You young punks have to learn
to respect a man like me!
Otherwise the cops will
come to your house.
And your family will be ruined.
Of course if I'm wrong about how much
you stole - I'll take a little less.
And by less, I only mean -
a hundred bucks less.
Now don't refuse me.
Understand, paisan?
I understand.
My friends and I share all the money.
So first, I have to talk to them.
Tell your friends I don't want a lot.
Just enough to wet my beak.
Don't be afraid to tell them!
600 bucks...
Suppose we don't pay?
You know his gang, Tessio.
Real animals.
Maranzalla himself let Fanucci
work this neighborhood.
He's got connections with the cops, too.
We have to pay him.
$200 each... everybody agreed?
Why do we have to pay him?
Vito, leave this to us.
He's one person, we're three.
He's got guns, we've got guns.
Why should we give him the
money we sweated for?
This is his neighborhood!
I know two bookies who don't give
anything to Fanucci.
They don't pay Fanucci.
If they don't pay Fanucci, then
somebody else collects for Maranzalla!
We'll all be better off if we
pay him. Don't worry.
Now what I say stays in this room.
If you both like, why not give me
$50 each to pay Fanucci?
I guarantee he'll accept
what I give him.
If Fanucci says $200...
... he means it, Vito!
I'll reason with him.
Leave everything to me.
I never lie to my friends.
Tomorrow you both go talk to Fanucci.
He'll ask for the money.
Tell him you'll pay whatever
he wants. Don't argue with him.
Then I'll go and get him to agree.
Don't argue with him, since
he's so tough.
How can you get him to take less?
That's my business.
Just remember that I did you a favor.
Is it a deal?
His family's out of the house.
Fanucci's alone in the cafe.
Are you sure he's going to go for it?
It looks like there's -
$100 under my hat.
I was right.
Only $100...
I'm short of money right now.
I've been out of work... so just
give me a little time.
You understand, don't you?
You've got balls, young man!
How come I never heard
of you before?
You've got a lot of guts.
I'll find you some work
for good money.
No hard feelings, right? If I can
help you, let me know.
You've done well for yourself.
Enjoy the festa!
Oh, this is too violent for me!
What've you got there?
Michael, your father loves you
very much.
Tell me something, Ma.
What did Papa think...
deep in his heart?
He was being strong...
Strong for his family.
But by being strong for his family...
... could he...
... lose it?
You're thinking about your wife...
about the baby you lost.
But you and your wife can
always have another baby.
No, I meant... lose his family.
But you can never lose your family.
Times are changing.
It's my pleasure.
I don't want money.
Take it as a gift.
Signora Colombo, why did you
come to see me?
Your wife told me to ask
if you could help me.
She's in bad trouble.
Her neighbors complained to the
landlord about her dog.
He told her to get rid of the animal.
But her little boy loves that dog.
So she hid it.
When the landlord found out, he
got mad and told her to leave.
Now she can't stay even if she
gets rid of it.
I'm so ashamed!
He said he'd get the police to
throw us out on the street.
I'm sorry, but...
I could give you a couple dollars
to help you move.
I can't move!
I want you to talk to him!
Tell him I want to stay here!
What's your landlord's name?
His name is Signor Roberto.
He lives on Fourth Street, near here.
They break the windows,
they dirty the floors...
A real pig-sty, eh?
My name is Vito Corleone.
Signora Colombo is a friend of my wife.
She says she's been evicted
for no good reason.
She's a poor widow, she has nobody
to take care of her.
She has no relatives, no money.
All she has is this neighborhood.
I already rented the place
to another family.
I told her that I'd talk to you.
That you're a reasonable man.
She got rid of the animal that
caused all the trouble.
So let her stay.
Are you Sicilian?
No, I'm Calabrese.
We're practically paisan,
do me this favor.
I already rented it!
I'll look like an idiot.
Besides, the new tenants
pay more rent.
How much more a month?
Five bucks.
Here's six months increase in advance.
But don't tell her about it.
She's very proud.
Come see me in another six months.
Of course, the dog stays. Right?
The dog stays.
Who the hell are you
to come give me orders?
Watch out or I'll kick your Sicilian ass
right into the street!
Do me this favor.
I won't forget it.
Ask your friends in the
neighborhood about me.
They'll tell you I know how
to return a favor.
What a character!
That landlord is here... Roberto,
the one who owns those ratholes.
He's been asking all around
the neighborhood about you.
I hope I'm not disturbing you,
Don Vito.
What can I do for you, Don Roberto?
What a misunderstanding! Holy Mary!
Of course Signora Colombo can stay!
I'm giving back the money you gave me.
Because after all, Don Vito,
money isn't everything.
Can I sit down?
Your kindness to that widow
made me ashamed of myself.
I'll even lower it.
I'll lower it $5.
I'll lower it $10!
Can I offer you some coffee?
I'm late for an appointment! I can't
this time! Ask me another time!
You'll have to excuse me for now.
I wish I could stay longer!
Just call me and I'll be here!
He won't be back. He'll hide out
in the Bronx!
Don Ciccio, it's Tommasino.
Allow me the honor of
introducing someone.
My partner in America, in New York.
His name is Vito Corleone.
We'll send him olive oil from here.
To his company in America.
They're olive oil importers, Don Ciccio.
We'd like your blessing, and your
permission to start work.
Where is this young man
from New York?
Have him come closer.
I can't see him so good.
My respects, Don Ciccio.
Give me your blessing.
Bless you!
What's your name?
You took the name of this town!
And what's your father's name?
His name was... Antonio Andolini.
Louder, I don't hear so good.
My father's name was
Antonio Andolini...
... and this is for you!
So... you're staying?
Yes, I'm staying.