Uh!
(breathes hard and gasps)
(Still "Choking On A Marshmallow"
in the background)
("Choking On A Marshmallow" fades)
Did you enter your weight?
It is important
that you set the super-Stairmaster
individual. . . Set it, individually,
because of the injury risk.
My name is Gunther. And you?
Mine not.
("Choking On A Marshmallow"
plays again)
Yes, a lot of fun. I already have ...
Sorry. Could I perhaps
Also use the "Wide Chest Press"?
You sit here so dreamy.
And I still did not today. ..
(Wild cry)
P. . Otherwise, I just come. ..
Again later...
(More threatening, strained sounds)
(More sounds in the background)
That is completely idiotic here.
Imagine that from the
perspective of outer space.
What are we doing here?
Totally insane.
The fact that people spend money for it!
We are NOT paying any money,
because I'm doing the campaign for them
if I may remind you.
- Now another 3 sets of leg curls.
- Is there really anything in life,
that you do not plan?
Thanks again for earlier.
Ah, don't mention it.
- By the way - I am Guenther.
- Jerome.
Nice name.
- Yes?
- Hm.
Gunther is not bad either.
You can pull The headband off.
I think_ here..
Hm? Oh.
Suppose, Jerome,
you have your first date with a woman.
Where will you go to?
Well, to my place.
Yes, ok, but I mean,
date technical wise....
- date technical wise.
- Yes.
Ts. . Well, anything which
has a number in its name.
Bar 23, 1 000, 1 03.
Cool.
("Choking On A Marshmallow"
instrumental in the background)
Philip, I do not want to keep
you in the dark any longer.
You probably know what's next.
Well, Mrs. Mack, I had of course
already few thoughts
how we can convince as
many people as possible
to become a Penguin godfather.
I think we should be especially
focused on an online strategy.
Philip. ..
I'm sorry, but
I'll have to let you go.
What you mean : go?
But I do not want to go..
What will happen to the project management?
Mr. Yokitashi will take over.
I have known for weeks that we
can not afford two Interns.
Mr. Yokitashi won the race.
Yes, but Mr. Yokitashi
does not speak German properly even!
But Mr. Yokitashi shows much
more motivation than you, Philip.
You know, I see it positive.
This is a chance.
I will be working more on my
business plan in teh near future.
Business Plan.
"LIFE".
For this eco-Mc. DUMB there?
Shh, Nina, not so loud!
This is top secret!
And if it works,
then I'll become real cool.
Put on my Adiletten (shoes),
buy me a Boat
and sail across the sea.
Just me and the wind.
You can't even sail.
So what? Then I just learn it.
Yes!
Tommi!
- Uah!
- Guys!
Why do you always have to fight,
Tommi? Why?
Fight, Tommi fight!
Yes, well, come on!
(Coach) out of there!
Yes! And now switch!
Back, back, back!
Please calm down now, Roland.
He will soon get another
red card.
I still may cheer up my son,
may I?
This is their relegation battle.
Oh!
(Trainer) Good, good, good!
Just that you know it, Susie.
I will never accept divorce, never.
I will fight for us.
But I do not want that you are fighting.
How long will this go on?
It's over! Finished!
(Coach) shoot, shoot!
Final whistle, do you understand?
After the game is before the game.
Go on, go, go! Holy crap!
(Susanne) Tell me, my darling,
Why did you beat Marcus?
You know,
that we should not beat anybody.
Marcus dragged Jasmin
by the hair.
Aha. Who is Jasmine?
She is new here.
They look very lovely, Beatrice.
And yet more charming
than on their online profil picture.
You look also good, Günther.
(Laughs) Thank you.
Did you know that today 25% of
all partnerships start online?
For my mother, that's
still something strange, huh? '.
Something wicked, dangerous, and so on.
This is of course nonsense.
It's not just perverts
in the internet.
- Of course not.
- Although I did read something the other day.
As it happened in Canada
a medical assistant and an architect
met on "My Face"
and met also in person.
And they fell in love..and so..
And as she stayed with him for the first time,
he has tied her to his bed
and sawed off her feet.
(Laughs gasping and sniffling)
Yes, a foot fetishist.
Terrible, 'right?
You have to be on guard all the time.
So, not that you think now that
I. . . So. . . I'm not a fetishist.
I'm just a normal man,
I search a normal woman,
- a totally normal relationship.
- (Cough)
(Sipping drink)
Did I mention,
that I am the second youngest commercial
regulatory official in Berlin-Brandenburg?
Yes. It's in your flirting profile.
Exactly.
Now we have
talked so much about me. ..
I have so many questions, Beate.
Do you like animals?
Excuse me, Guenther,
But somehow it does not work.
What is it?
That here with us.
I'm really sorry.
Nope, is not a problem, I...
(Soulful piano music)
(Stops to play abruptly)
I've written for you, Tamara.
Tatjana.
Ah huh! Tatjana. Right.
Ups. (Starts to play again)
Oh! My song! (Sigh)
(Niklas) This man is free
of conventions, fears, doubts.
No woman can put him in chains,
no enemy to stop him.
This man
is an urban jungle warrior.
Always looking for adventure,
always in fight-
and sexual readiness.
He enjoys life to the fullest.
And. . . No matter what will happen
this man
is determined on his path.
The path to his masculine truth.
And along the way he uses
her eye cream, shaving cream, deodorant,
Shampoo, toilet water, peeling,
Anti-wrinkle cream. ..
The complete skin care line.
(Applause)
Do you know why you are
fascinating me, Nicholas?
They create all these daredevils
these wild adventurers.
And you're more like ...
..like the Glöckle-Man (a soft egg).
Solid through and through.
As in the 50s.
All according to plan.
Please do not get me wrong.
I think that's great.
The normality
is the true revolution.
Well, if you
found the right one, than...
Well, you just do me a favor
and you do not take too long
off for your honeymoon in September.
I need you here.
(Steps away)
(Organ music)
(Priest) And so I ask you,
Niklas Michalke,
do you want to be a loving and
faithful husband to Laura Sandner,
till death do you part?
Are you really prepared to restrict
your sexual energy...
To a single vagina, and
always on the same pair of breasts?
Where "always the same pair" is put
very optimistically, Niklas.
We all know what the force of gravity
can do.
- Answer the priest, Nik.
- Are you one of those whiners,
who get the total crisis with 40
and try to repeat their youth?
What kind of man are you?
(All in unison) What kind of man are you?
(Panting heavily)
(Sighs.
Everything ok, honey?
Yes.
I had a nightmare.
What kind of a nightmare?
Anything. . . With nasty monsters.
Hm ..
(Bruce Berger sings)
'Dudududuuu dudududuuu!
'Yeah! Ahohohooo!
'Dudududududuuu!
'Tell me why.
'The wind calls your name.
'Love knows no boundaries.
'Tell me why.
'Sun burn.
"one separates hearts."
- 'Tell me, why have I. . . '
- Stop! Tell me, Bruce,
could it be that you screwed
the text a little bit?
Please, Jerome, no discussions now!
"Tell me why the sun burns"
that's totally insane, Loco!
Total.
I can not sign this
with my name!
Hello! Can I now sing again?
I'm going to lose the feeling!
Make me louder! I do not hear myself!
Bruce, you're turned up 100%.
If I make you louder
I will get the feedback circuits
of your headphones on my mic.
Are we to here to
gossip or what?
Come on, people, I need music.
(Inaudible)
'Ohooohohooohohoooho!
- 'Uhuhuhuhuuu, nananana!
- (Martin laughs)
'Ahaaaha!'
(turns off the music) Great, Jerome.
Great work.
There is still one number on it, Martin.
(House Music)
(turns off the music)
If you want to waste time with
this house music shit.
Please do it,
But do not waste my time.
I am concerned here only about Bruce Berger.
What do you want?
I produced the fucking soap opera
and paid back the advance for the
Girlie-band. Now we're even.
(Laughs) Jerome.
With your life style you are bankrupt
latest end of summer.
Or have you been already dry?
Hm?
What will you do then?
Give piano lessons?
- What do you want from me?
- You are really not getting it, right?
This is about the new
Bruce Berger album, you understand?
- The whole fucking album.
- I thought.
- That makes Karlotti Carlo.
- M-m, they broke apart.
Each producer is fighting for the deal.
Schlager is the last gold mine,
we have on the market.
Bruce craps money.
House in Sardinia,
Penthouse in New York, speedboat. ..
Never work again, Jerome!
(Questioning) Ok. ..
Produce one more track. Do this
Anthem about which Bruce always talks.
Then we see what the board says.
I can not decide alone.
Batman wise, dude. (Laughs)
Interest in a test drive?
(Engine howling)
Unfinished business studies,
rupted Egyptology studies
and a 3-year internship.
(Chugs) Listen, I have a plan.
I just need a job,
to pay the rent.
(Marshmellow Club: "In The City")
Sorry. Do you happen to know
where is the Pizzeria Adira?
(Laughter)
("In The City" fades)
Very funny.
Yes, Ma.
No, Ma.
Yes, Dr. Rothenburg
We have invited. Yes.
Oh, you know, I am not sure
whether we can do that...
To go with you to the wedding fair.
(Laughs) You, Mom,
I'll call you tomorrow. Yeah, bye!
She totally goes bonkers...
- She is already gone completely.
- The newly weds! (Laughs)
- Mrs. Koschinsky!
- Come in!
Shall we?
So!
(hot salsa music)
And so generous! You want to have
your private space in the bathroom.
You do not need to always
see everything from the other, right?
(Next Salsa Music
incomprehensible communication)
(Music stops)
(Birds chirping, gentle squeak)
Hello!
(More squeaks and weird sounds)
(Baby cries)
Yes sure you want to have own children,
or?
Um, next year.
My husband does all carefully planned.
Where can you find this kind?
My friend feels already restricted,
if I bring my toothbrush
once in a while to his place.
We know us already from school.
Now, this is sweet! (Laughs)
I gotta go. I've got another date.
I will send you the sales contract
Next week, Mr. Michalke.
Yes, thank you.
Goodbye, Mrs. Koschinsky.
At my age, Roman Abramovic already
bought FC Chelsea (soccer club).
And what am I doing?
(Sighs I'm an arrow.
(Laughs)
Hey, you, I might have
a job for you.
- As a model.
- Wow!
Yes, a campaign for Berlin.
That sounds cool.
What campaig exactly?
- The. . . I. ..
- (Phone rings)
Nina, hey!
Talk? Why talk?
Shit!
This is really a catastrophe, Nina.
Yes, that was clear,
that you react like that.
What do you expect that I react?
We know each other for just a few
Weeks and I've lost my job.
Wow, Philip, spare me the whining!
I can really not use that.
Tell me. . . And you really are
sure that the child is mine?
Whoa, you're really the last, hey!
That's not happening!
But that was not the point. . . Ouch!
That was just a question! Ts ..
(happy music begins)
40% of all accidents at the work-out
arise because one
has not warmed up properly.
I used to practice judo.
Are you collecting dog-bowl
faithful hearts?
Yes, I would like a faithful heart.
You get even 5. And from 45 on
You get a small animal cage.
Or an anti-mite cover.
You can choose.
This is really so nice,
Miss Feldberg. The. ..
27.50.
(Soft music begins)
Yes, because I do not even know
what . . . To say. The. ..
Thank you.
(Baby Bird: "If You'll Be Mine")
Tommi is in love! Tommi is in lo...
(shrill whistle)
(Still, "If You'll Be Mine"
in the background)
I don't look at nothing!
You're out of your mind!
To book a travel!
Throughout the day there's seafood buffet
and Tommi can go snorkeling!
If we are a while together,
You will see, I am a new person.
Roli, you have to look forward.
Eventually you will
meet a new wife and...
- (Roars) I do not want a new woman!
- You're hurting me!
All right, Mrs. Feldberg?
- What are you doing, Batman?
- (Groans)
(Loud clang)
Susi, I'm sorry,
I did not want...
If you do not immediately disappear,
I call the police.
I swear, Roland, I'll do it.
Look, Tommy, you have to learn that
you must not always beat others.
Marcus is just jealous.
Being in love is the most beautiful
thing in the world.
One is proud of it.
Nina?
I did simply respond
like an idiot.
If you want the child,
then. . . I will support you.
Wow. You support me? From what?
My God, Philip,
you're still yourself a child.
I begin in the fall
with the graphic designer training. ..
If we are honest,
we both don't want a child.
Now.
I've got an important event
planned for next week.
In the clinic Schultheis.
It is simply the most sensible.
Niklas has explained everything to you, right?
Yes, that's a campaign for Berlin.
For. . . Berlin. Exactly.
Should I do anything in particular?
A pose, or something?
Nah, stay just the same.
This is perfectly ok.
Niklas, I must come in.
Ah, I am sitting on the toilet.
I just need quickly
my contact lens solution.
Laura, believe me,
you don't want to come in..
(irritated sound)
Look what I found.
Do you remember?
The crocodile you stole from
the fat Italian boy...
Because I said,
I would also like to have one.
How could I forget? I have
been almost killed by the Mafia.
- Listen. ..
- Hm?
Did you actually today
already take the pill?
What's that now suddenly
for a stupid question?
Just because your friend does not know
how to use condoms,
- You panic now, or what?
- Oh, nonsense!
Laura!
Oh, now make no drama out of it.
Here. Now you can do a
daily check.
I'll not mess up
your life plan.
Although I honestly do not know
why I still take those.
When was the last time we had sex?
In the Bronze Age?
You, perhaps we would have more sex
If you would not constantly
wear those stupid baggy pants,
as soon as you get home.
Why do you not tell me just
what is really going on, Nicholas?
(House Music)
This guy
lived here for a month
and it is the 5th Time, that ..
He thinks because he's got a roof terrace,
he can get away with anything.
Calm down, he is nice. Yesterday,
he carried up my shopping bags.
Because he wanted to hit on you...
One have to know one's limits.
(Ncont. Music, voices, bells)
(Knocks)
(Music and voices are getting louder)
Hi. Come in.
(Sugababes: "Get Sexy")
Pedro, old scoundrel! You look good!
- How was Hong Kong? Mmmm!
- I think that's a mix-up.
Today we both will rock and roll.
To old times, Pedro!
"Old school"!
I get us a bottle.
Do not run away, Pedro, huh?
(To "Get Sexy" in the background)
Hey, neighbor! Glad you're here!
- Mr. Ades, sorry that I...
- Hey, I'm Jerome. That's Dany.
- This is my neighbor.
- Chic robe.
Ok, Jerome would it be perhaps possible
- ..to make the music a bit quieter?
- Oh, chill, amigo.
Have a drink, celebrate with us.
It's a cool party.
Ok, watch out, amigo.
My girlfriend and I,
We need to work early
tomorrow morning, ok?
Do you think
that is the Playboy Mansion?
This is my housewarming party.
If you do not like to join,
don't play your frustration on us.
Frustration? What kind of frus..
This is really. ..
Pedro!
Hm?
(You can hear the music
now just as a dull roar)
I'll call tomorrow to the property manager.
Philistine.
(Rag squeaks)
( continuing squeaking)
(Romantic Waltz Music)
(Dramatic final chord
Music stops)
(Still squeaking)
Hello, Mrs. Feldberg. Well? How are you?
Thank you. Extremely exciting today.
Oh!
(again squeaking)
I wanted to ask you,
whether you. ..
Um. . . Yet. . . Still have the
Biotrockenfutter. For the little ones.
Nah. Has no one bought except you.
Ok...
I've got a guinea pig.
Hm hm.
I also had one once.
When I was 7.
Mm! "I've got a guinea pig!"
God! How stupid must one be!
Well?
(Sings totally off tune)
'What is love? Baby, do not hurt me!
'Do not hurt me no more!
Oh, ohohohoho!
'Oh-ohohoho!
"Oho! What is love? '."
Huh. . . I'm speechless.
You. . . Have an extraordinary voice.
(The doorbell rings)
Yes!
Old father,
what do you want here, guys?
Do you know a Jenny from Weding (disctrict name)?
Works at the airport.
Sells credit cards.
Excuse me.
- Jenny? Never heard of her.
- Jenny says,
You were slightly charmless recently
You have not called and so on.
I do not know what you try to say
but you've chosen the wrong person.
Jenny is family, comprende?
Hey! I know you. You're
This sweet cute guy
from the Bravo photo-love story, right?
Guy do not fuck with us.
You stand a meter away from the cliff.
Do not play the gangster here
MC.Asshole.
What you can pull that off with
your little sister, but not with me.
Wanker.
Jerome! Are you okay?
Ah, no. . . Do you need ice?
I'll get ice cream.
(Bruce sings Berger)
'Ahhhhhhhha!
'All the children of this earth,
'Sing with me this song.
'That peace will come.
'And there is food for all.
"We warm our climate."
'And the animals are dying out.
'It really is not that great,
'Get involved, just do not stay away.
Our weapon is love,
Our hearts the ammunition.
'Against Hunger, AIDS and wars.
'Against Hatred and corruption.
'All the children of this earth,
'Sing with me this song.
'That peace will come.
'And there is food for all.
'Aha! Ahaha! Ahaha! Ahaha!
'Haha! Ha!
'Food for all!'
(Deep breath) I only say: Bambi!
(= German movie oscar)
(Both reluctant) Hm, hm. ..
Bruce, in the right direction anyway,
But the text, we still have to work.
The text is perfect! This is a song
for the whole world. "Planet Earth".
Just as "We Are The World".
We get a children's choir!
I. . . I got goose bumps, you!
Me too, hey.
(clears throat) Bruce. ..
I think Jerome is right.
The rhyme "climate prima"
that's silly, isn't it?
What should be silly with
global warming?
No-nothing.
How about if you just
skip global warming?
Skip?
Conceal the truth?
Hello, Loco! All of humanity
is struggling to survive.
Bruce! Who do you think,
who you are?
Fucking Bob Dylan, or what?
We make entertainment here!
That 's an easy job, ok?
So Give me a break
with the survival of mankind!
I can not hear the shit anymore!
(Gasps in horror)
For you this may be business, Jerome,
For me it's a matter of the heart.
I'll take global warming very seriously.
I ride bike!
Yes, because they took your driver's
license, you drunk skunk!
I must not listen to that any longer.
You are not ultimately the only
Producer who wants to work with me.
- Fuck!
- (Bruce) Where is the door?
(Loud Music)
I do not believe it
another scratch!
This motherfucker!
Maybe you should re-register
your car in Berlin.
I'm from Munich, my friend.
Well, maybe it is
not only your license plate.
Maybe you should remove
this one, you know?
Remove?
Before I remove this one, I'd
rather cut off my dick!
(More lively music, moans)
- Hey, Jerome.
- And?
- And when is the deadline?
- The day after tomorrow.
I can handle it pretty bad, Nik.
But in the end it is
Nina's decision and...
It is simply the most sensible
way, you know?
Hey!
Hey?
(Laughs) Do you know me no more?
Um. ..
The beer advertising last year. ..
The 3rd Bikini girls left behind.
(Laughs)
Yeah, uh, right.
Niklas.
I know.
- Mary.
- Ah.
- How's the modeling?
- Super.
That is why I work here
in the gym.
(Laughter)
If we again have a campaign
we have you in our files.
You can find also
my cell phone number in it.
(Swinging Music)
What are you doing?
Hm I'm working.
Are you an arrow? (Chuckles)
- Looks like it, doesn't it?
- (Giggle)
Yes. . . Children. (Laughs)
(Jasmine still giggles)
I want a pizza.
- With salami and tomato sauce.
- Tuna!
Ok, then. . . Just follow the arrow.
- Bye!
- Bye.
- Tye, little arrow!
This arrow was funny!
(Tommi) I would like tuna pizza
without vegetables.
(Susanne) tuna pizza without vegetables?
There's never vegetables on it, Tommy.
Nina! When you hear that here, then, um,
just call me back, because...
I wanted to ask you. . . With
the clinic, that was today, right?
And because I wanted to again...
..talk to you about it, yes?
Nina, it's me again. I now
already called a few times and uh. ..
Nina, now answer, man!
Nina, I do. . . I am coming now, ok?
I come now.
Shit!
The address of the clinic Schultheiss,
fast!
(Exciting Music)
(Squeaky brake)
(More exciting music)
Stop! I'm the father!
Of the appendix?
Carry on.
What was the name again?
Nina Hellmich!
Yes. She had an appointment.
(Chewing noisily)
This morning at 8:00.
Has not come.
(Laughs and claps his hands)
Whoo!
Yes. . . Thank you.
It's not that - Jerome -
I do not have the courage
to talk to her. It's about that
I still do not know what to do. ..
Guenther. . . Just be yourself Hm?
Yes, but the problem is,
whenever I am myself,
then it doesn't work with the women.
OK...
Do you know "Magnum"? The series
from the 80s with Tom Selleck?
- Yes, this detective in Hawaii? Hm hm.
- Hm hm.
Be Magnum.
("Magnum P. I." theme song)
(Still "Magnum P. I." melody
in the background)
Hello, Miss Feldberg.
How are you?
Well, thank you.
Interesting shirt.
Ah. ..
I ordered the organic feed for you.
Especially for you.
It's over there at the canaries.
Very nice, thank you.
I. . . Have one question
Mrs. . . Feldberg. I, uh. ..
I wanted to suggest
that we might...
...do something together
purely amicable.
Something nice, go to the zoo. ..
I work in the zoo.
(Laughs) Ah, yes.
Yes, or to. . To the movies? Hm.
No, no, das.. . Actually, that's
a very nice idea.
So if you do not mind
I would like to
bring along my son
and take his little girlfriend.
No! I love kids!
My name is Gunther.
Does not matter.
(Laughs)
(happy waltz music)
(Insane screams)
You have to call "Mau" said Dad.
W-what?
"Mau". You have to call "Mau".
Excuse me, please. ..
It's me, Dad. Roland.
Your Roland.
(Melancholic music begins)
Would be nice if you would
bake your cookies.
For me and for Tommi.
They don't let me anymore.
Who?
I pay a shit on
the damn manager!
If anyone here again hinders
my father from baking.
- Then it pops! Is that clear?
- Now you listen to me!
Your father almost burned down
the whole home last X-mas!
My father has baked all his life.
What else has he left?
What the hell are you doing, Jerome?
Bruce is pretty pissed off!
What is wrong with you?
When will this fucking anthem be finished?
It is not so easy
to work with colleague Bruce.
Bruce is a complete idiot, so what?
You won't have to marry him!
We're talking about the
deal of your life.
Do you want to mess up? You have
to fight, fight, fight!
I spoke 3 times on his answering machine!
What should I do
if he does not call back?
Write him a letter.
A letter?
Yes. By hand, with a fountain pen.
- (Laughs)
- "Old school".
Silk paper. He likes that.
Powder his ass.
You must now turn off your pride.
You are on the finish line. Stay cool.
(Troubled voiced out thoughts of Jerome)
'Dear Bruce,
'I can not tell you
how sorry I am for what happened.
'I was not myself.
'Your text to "all children of this earth"
is so profound,
'that I had to think about it
for a few days,
'To fully
understand its beauty.
'A Song for Mother Earth.
'A hymn to humanity,
'for Peace and Love.
'And against hunger, war,
Global warming and AIDS. '.
You're a great artist, Bruce,
and I would like nothing more
than to be friends again.
Forgive me.
Love, thy Jerome.
Oh, man, Jerome. ..
Sabrina
this has never happened to me originally.
This is most likely because I do. ..
Have too much in my head or something.
That's not so bad.
This can happen to anyone.
(The doorbell rings)
Who is that?
Everyone deserves a 2nd Opportunity.
And so we make up
for lost time,
I've thought to myself,
I move in for a while with you.
Excuse me, what, please?
Now we just make music.
Day and night! Nonstop!
Well, what do you say?
Super.
Do you have something to drink there?
'All the children of this earth,
'Sing with me this song. . . '
(gasps)
Here you should go to minor.
How does that work? It's D-major.
- Built in a bridge.
- Built in a bridge!
Bruce, it's late.
If you do not like the play-back,
I like to sit down tomorrow morning
and make a new one.
I want to be part of the process
Do you understand?
Part of the creation! I. ..
I am not only the artist, Jeronimo.
I am a writer!
I hear sounds, ideas I have!
Then you might want to
learn to play piano!
Jimmi Hendrix
could not play the piano.
Ha!
We must free ourselves,
let the vibe grow.
Come on! Let's jam!
Just chip in a beat!
What kind of Beat?
Well, just some beat. Wait!
Ts-ts-ts-ts-ts-ts-ts-ts!
(Strong rhythmic beat)
My name is Bruce Berger and I enter
the game and I'm bad! I'm bad!
- 'Never take a trade! I'm bad! I'm bad!
- (Sabrina) 'Yeah! What is love?
- 'Baby, do not hurt me! Ah-ah! Yes!
- 'I'm bad!
- 'I'm bad!'
- 'Yeah, yeah!'
(Unintelligible)
(More terrible singing)
(Voice fades)
'I'm bad, bad, bad, bad, bad. . '..
Mrs. Koschinsky,
I got the contract.
I want only to talk to my lawyer. ..
Mrs. Koschinsky,
I have a meeting now.
I call you back. Yes. Thank you!
We need the Sportscom Layouts
until tomorrow morning at 8:00.
- My turn, Wolfgang.
- The minister has called
and confirmed the appointment
to visit the church.
Thank you.
(Sighs.
(Whisper) Niklas!
He can better burry yourself
right now.
Nik! Let yourself not be confused
by this superficial hedonists.
You do everything right.
Is there anything better in life
than building a nest?
What are you? A blackbird?
Niklas. You have done everything right
your damn life long.
Do not you think it is time,
time to do something wrong?
Really wrong?
(Loud music begins)
And so are you studying Media Studies
and work here
and in the gym,
and. . . Take acting lessons. ..
I think I do not know...
not exactly what I want.
Hm I know exactly what you mean.
I have an audition next week
for another soap about stewardesses.
It sounds really cool.
Do you want to help me?
Thus, when learning text, or something?
Max and Steffi have promised.
And Paul and Marion also.
Caro and Holger
are no longer together.
They divorce now.
- Oops!
- Hm hm.
- These were married just what?
- 2 years.
Ts!
The idiot did cheat on her all
the time with a 20-year-old intern.
How embarrassing!
The RX-21 0-Turbo
in the sports version.
Including iPod cradle, sun roof
with ventilation windows and leather seats.
Thanks to the swiveling wheels
adjustable with gas spring.
Also ideal for high speed
and in rough terrain.
I did not really want to
participate in a rally.
As well. . . You can not
afford it!
And then of course the F-youth.
They start from 4 years.
- What youth?
- Football, Nina.
The very young.
You find buddies for life there.
This is how Nik and myself met.
Philip. ..
For you it's all
just a game, huh?
No, why?
I've got to go now. I have a date
with Lars for coffee.
How, Lars? THE Lars?
I thought he is in Australia
to find himself?
Apparently he has found himself.
- I'll call you later.
- Hey, I do not find this ok from you!
Philip! You always wanted that we
leave some room for ourselves...
Hello? Earth to Nina!
You're pregnant, pregnant from me.
So what?
Do you want to burn a horseshoe
on me or what?
I'm your brood cow?
I really do not need an
Australia loser ex-boyfriend,
who wants to slime his way
back into your life!
Hey, Philip, relax!
Lars and I are friends, not more!
In addition, he is no loser.
After all in Australia
he established his diving school.
And who needs
A fucking dive school?
Nina, I'm almost done
with the business plan.
I built something for us. An empire!
I did not know that you model...
I find that very nasty! You said
that's a campaign for Berlin.
- And now I'm Mr. suicide!
- I'm sorry. ..
'The whole town
is full of posters! '
("Magnum P. I." theme song)
(Jasmine)You look
like my uncle Gerhard.
- (All laugh)
- He looks like Gunther.
The bald ibis is native to
Central Europe since the Stone Age
and lives in a strictly monogamous
Couple relationship, the ibis,
Thus, is a life long. . . Faithfull.
(Still "Magnum P. I." Theme song
in the background)
(Happy laughter)
("Magnum P. I." theme song fades)
(Susan) Well, then 2 years ago
was this accident with the girl.
Some madman pushed her
in front of his train.
Then he could no longer work
and has just been sitting at home
and cried and cried and. ..
Beat around him.
Yes, maybe. ..
Do we want to go to the penguins?
- Oh!
- Ah. . . Tommi! Come on!
- (Hot pop music)
- (Mary) 3, 2, 1!
An arm!
Very good!
And we're shooting!
(More pop)
Oops!
Yesterday, she was a half hour
on the phone with me.
- Hm! That's a good sign, ey.
- Hm.
And on the weekend
we go together into the Park
- watch People. ..
- (Jerome) Nice.
Good, which is after all.
What I told you.
And you? How is it?
Do you have a relationsh...Ah. ..
Did you also. ..
A relationship with. . . There with a. . . Woman?
With a woman? Mmm. ..
- Time here and there.
- Ts.
So, you're not mar. . Married,
or. ..
No.
(Jerome breathes heavily)
- In love?
- Guy, hey!
No! That is not true!
No! Mannhart!
Ricky?
- Hey!
- I call you back, Mannhart.
Um. . . Philip?
Henrion!
- Hello!
- That's a coincidence, huh?
- How are you?
- Grandiose grandiose!
(Ricky) How long we have not
seen? Since the B-youth, right?
I think that's true fate,
that we meet now, Ricky.
You invest in
Start-up companies, don't you?
Yes, among others. Why?
Ricky. . . The time is ripe
for a fast food chain,
the laws of the modern marketing
combined with the ideals of our time.
- You mean a kind of "eco-McDonalds"?
- Exactly!
A high-quality
Organic fast-food chain.
But not one that looks like Eco.
High gloss, uniforms.
A recognizable brand,
a catchy name,
soon known in the whole world.
"LIFE".
Kinky, Philip.
Still the same spinner.
I love it!
(Both laugh)
- Kruger!
- The fact is,
such plans
have all the big fast food companies
for years in a drawer. Such a
Chain would have to ask elite prices
what with the philosophy of a
Commercial chain for all social levels.
- Is not compatible.
- Say,
what is Niklas doing, by the way?
He marries in the fall, right?
Do you still have contact?
Yes, we do. ..
Tell me, can let me out
there in front?
- My Dear. ..
- Bye, Ricky.
(Marshmellow Club: "In The City")
(Still, "In The City"
in the background)
(Sings very slanted) 'Everybody is
shakin 'their booty, whoo, whoo see. . . '
Jerome, I think this is
really not ok from you.
You never call, I do not know
where you are, I'm worried, really.
I was still in the studio with Sabrina.
Jerome, we both know, the woman
sounds like a wounded hyena.
But at your age I also fucked everything
which was not up a tree at the count of 3..
Male or female, whatever.
It was the 70s.
But then one day you check,
that you can not only fuck around.
What you are missing is a sense.
You have to make the jump.
Leave the party...
Who knows what would have happened if I
had not started with Aikido.
I'd probably be a
pretty crazy guy today.
Hm! Probably.
I've washed your socks.
Super.
(Bruce hums to himself)
Well? What do you say?
- Well. ..
- Nik, do you see that?
The potential!
When this stuff is out
than it's a dream, man!
Here we place tables
and this wall goes away completely!
I shit on major investors!
I just do my own thing!
I think it's great how you
want to pull this through, but. ..
How will you finance it?
(Beer bottles pop)
Well, good that you mention it.
Philip, I would really want to
help you, but you know,
- What a wedding costs?
- Yes, yes, yes. Take it easy.
I do not want money from you.
I just need someone to
guarantees at the bank for me.
For the loan!
Whoa, buddy, ey. ..
Nik, do you even understand
what is on the line here?
If I do not manage to
built something soon
my child probably grows up in
in Australia and plays cricket!
I must now show to Nina,
That I've got it!
Radiat economic security!
This is not possible being an arrow!
(Marshmellow Club:
"Choking On A Marshmallow")
Nik!
(Philip gaggles)
("Choking On A Marshmallow"
slowly fades away)
If only could fly to Paris
with you, Pierre.
I'd love to be again
in the city of love.
You know the rules of
the airline, Tina.
Pilots and flight attendants
are not allowed.
Do you think you can dictate a heart-
what it should feel, Pierre?
(takes deep breath)
I see turbulences on the horizon. Tina.
And you know what I see, Pierre?
No. What?
A rainbow.
A rainbow of our love.
(Laughs)
Um. . . Do I still say something?
No. Then we kiss.
You two. You and Pierre.
(Soft music begins)
So?
Or. ..
(Music is haunting)
I think I should really go now.
(Maria chuckles)
I'll call you.
- Ok.
Mouse?
I should go to the office again.
(Music fades)
(Quietly) shit. ..
Mouse. ..
I totally forgot
we wanted to cook together.
I am so sorry.
Just leave me in peace, ok?
(TV announcer) 'A lion in heat.
'He smells a
ready to mate female.
'And while this lioness is
feeding on the spoils of last night,
'the ready to mate female.
'Long fouind an admirer
among the males. '
(Woman) 'massage and lubricant.
'Durex. Because love is fun. '
(2nd wife)
'Fancy a threesome?'
'The hottest number in Germany!'
'Ok, here we are just
in the absolute power round.
'It can ring at any moment.
'I'm looking for an animal.
And a little tip from me:
- 'It begins with "M".
- (Monkeys screaming in the background)
'Warning! In 5, 4, 3,
- '2, 1. . . '
- (Monkey screams getting louder)
(Turns the TV off)
(Sighs)
(Insane screams)
(With Berlin accent)
My goodness, Roland!
You can not shout around like that.
You're not alone here!
Got it. I'm sorry, Heiko.
(Soft music begins)
Mau!
(Roland) Where were you?
Go home, Roland.
Where were you, I've asked!
If you met someone else
I'll make him flat!
Knock it off, man!
(Sobs violently)
You have to talk to someone, Roli.
Someone who knows about such things.
Are you listening?
I tear him to pieces!
(Sobs violently)
(Sobbing) I tear him to pieces!
(Romantic sounds)
Do you like musicals, Susan?
I have here 2 cards
for the new edition of "Cats."
Guenther. ..
We can no longer see us.
You are such a nice person.
I want to involve you
in that. Really.
Just not fair.....
But that is then
Surely my decision. ..
No. This is my decision.
I'm really sorry, but. ..
Please purchase from somewhere else now.
Why ...
(Melancholic, moving music)
(Nina) Oops!
Oh no! (Nina laughs)
Wow, Philip, this is so great!
I just can not believe it!
Ouch!
(Still moving music)
(Door opens)
Hello, Day!
- Hello.
'Scuse me,
But we are not open until next week.
Mr. Henrion, my name is Stobanski.
From the Factory Inspectorate.
Ah, I think, uh. ..
We do know us
from the gym, Mr. Stupinski?
Ah, Stobanski is the name.
Would you tell me
what are you doing here?
Yes, I'll open a restaurant.
Oh, then you obviously
do not know that
this here runs under
the retail license regulations?
I.e., you have no authorization,
Hto operate a commercial catering
here. Unless...
you ask for a special permit.
But I see no chance to get that.
Since you would need separate
Guest toilets, male, female,
and a modern exhaust equipment
with activated carbon filters.
And separate dirty water,
dish and hand sink.
Also, here in the kitchen.
The floor is made of wood,
which must be replaced.
Because of the risk of slipping.
Slippery?
That really is ridiculous!
We are not in Djibouti.
Now you stop it, You puppet!
This is where someone is trying
to build something up,
- And you just come and...
- Shh!
What you just said?
(clears throat)
She doesn't mean it, Mr. Stupinski.
Stobanski is my name.
Stobanski puppet.
And shall I tell you,
what the puppet is doing now?
The puppet, is revoking your
commercial license
and closes your shop until you
have rebuilt it immaculately!
This is what the puppet does!
Goodbye.
I had everything under control until
started with the puppet!
Are you kidding!
Under control?
What did you ever have under control?
- You are just building something. ..
- What do you understand of that, huh?
You play job wise
"Journey to Jerusalem"!
Do me a favor and just keep your
nose out of it in the future, ok?
OK. I will.
Hey, Nina. Hey!
I did not mean it that we....
(Breathes out heavily) shit. ..
(Quiet oriental sounds)
(still oriental sounds)
Fff! Hah! Hah! Hah!
Jerome! Dinner is ready!
(Groans)
- Hm! Hm hm! Hm, is good.
- Hm.
- Cambodian rice pudding.
- Hm!
I've even learned to cook sometimes, you know?
When I've lived in Darmstadt.
Hotel cook.
Hm.
Can I... put to you...
...a serious question?
Are you all just about the money?
I mean, I know
what is going on.
All they want is to milk me.
There is no one,
which really is interested in me.
Not for Bruce Berger, but. ..
For Manfred.
Manfred Eppelheim.
Your name is Manfred?
Be honest, Jerome,
is it all about money, or are you
standing behind the sound we make?
Bruce, I like the sound,
which we make.
I told you so written
in the letter.
Do you believe that?
And. . . We are friends?
You and me?
Well. . . Of course we are friends.
To us.
(Gary Go, "Berlin")
("Berlin" ends)
(Roland) Yes, come, run, run, run!
Max, come on, come on!
Sven, you must then go back too!
You have to go back sometimes!
(Trainer) Run, run, run, run!
Tommi come on, come on! Fight!
What's the matter, big one? Hm?
The Jasmine moves to Ingo. . .,
uh, Ingo city.
And that is that bad?
Oh! Tommi, huh?
You will again
meet a new wife, huh?
But I don't want a new woman!
Hey, Tommy, I must ask you something.
Some serious ok?
Does mom have another man?
Not? OK. Got it.
Well, son, and now,
Now you go back and play, ok?
Fight, Tommy.
You have to fight forever, forever!
Ok, come on, big one, yes?
Come, go, go, go, go, go!
How far away is Igor city?
Can we go there with the subway?
No, my dear.
Ingolstadt is located in Bavaria, you know?
And Bavaria is very, very far away.
But Jasmine could
live with us, couldn't she.
With her sleeping bag.
But she must
stay with her mom and her dad.
Hm?
What do you think,
if on Sunday we all go together
to the zoo again? With jasmine.
Hm?
Hm hm.
(A knock)
Jerome, is it a bad time?
It may sound
a bit stupid, but...
Can I sleep
in your bed tonight?
I won't touch you or something.
I usually get those bad dreams
before a performance, you know?
Now you are not serious?
Yes, I am.
(Deep breathing)
Jerome, are you sleeping?
Nah.
Tell me, of all the girls
to show up here
- just that I know -,
which is the one,
I mean, the one you love?
None.
But this is sad, Jerome.
Were you ever in love?
Of course, I was already in love.
But this is 20 years ago.
- Melanie.
- And?
I guess, I've screwed up.
How? Screwed up?
I just wanted to get out to conquer the world.
And then this guy came by
and he snatched her away.
And?
Has made her 2 children,
then he left her,
divorced. ..
And now she sits there all alone
with their two children.
And?
- And what?
- Why do you never call her?
I've just said,
that was more than 20 years ago.
And?
And now we sleep.
(Deep breathing)
Jerome?
(irritated sound)
I love you.
What?
(Baby Bird: "If You'll Be Mine")
(irritated sound)
(Still, "If You'll Be Mine"
in the background)
("If You'll Be Mine" slowly fades away)
We still have to do the banns,
decide the seating arrangements.
Print the menu card,
taste the food...
I'm glad when all the stress
is over and we are finally gone.
4 weeks to do nothing,
nothing, zero.
I didn't tel you yet, right?
Hm?
I've booked 8 days only.
8 days?
Yes.
8 days on the Fiji Islands?
Is this a joke?
I have 5 campaigns in September,
I can not do more.
It's called honeymoon weeks
not honeymoon daYS.
Laura, we have now
financial obligations,
We have a house,
which we want to buy. ..
Why don't we drive for a
weekend to the Scharmützelsee than?
- Hm?
- Oh, come on, mouse.
Shit. ..
(Clicks his tongue,
whistles and snaps)
Hey, Philip! What are you doing?
My pizza is over there
and you show on the kebab!
How shall this work?
Are you too stupid to be an arrow?
- I'm sorry.
- "Sorry"! You're fired!
- E basta! Finita!
- Vincenzo, you can not do that!
And how!
Then you stand here yourself!
Rudi, please! I told you,
that it is difficult at the moment.
Yes, of course the rent will be due! I...
Rudi. . . If you insist,
than inform your lawyer!
(Squeaky brake)
(Lars) And how many children
are in such a group?
(Loud clang)
1 2-1 5, or so.
Yes, look at that!
This is the famous Lars!
The great man with a diving school!
Wow! Lars is paying a round of Prosecco!
There's something to celebrate here, or what?
Say, I know you from somewhere else.
Very funny. I am the suicide
of Berlin, I know.
Nah, I saw you recently
at the Alex (place in Berlin).
With such 'an arrow costume. Can it be?
Now look here, Captain Nemo.
I would like to clarify one thing.
Nina gets my child!
And my son does not learn to dive
or such a shit
and my daughter also not! Understand?
And with this joker...
- ...you want to start a family?
- We can also go out the door.
- And make it like men!
- (Nina) Enough!
(Shrill trill)
That can not be true!
Man! He has provoked me!
From the beginning he has provoked me!
Ok, I think, the two of us
should go out the door.
Guy, are you inasane?
Philip, I've already said,
that Lars and I are just friends.
Can you finally relax?
Relax? Yes, of course,
I can relax super, Nina.
My shop is already finished, before it
once had opened!
I am in debt with over 12,000 €
and do not know
how to pay off the installments.
Not to mention all of the rent.
And to top it I have to watch,
how the mother of my child
drinks prosecco with her damned
"Jacques Cousteau for the poor " diving nut!
Hey, Prosecco!
This is super-relaxed,
this situation, right?
Why are you so jealous?
You are not interested in
me at all.
What a nonsense!
What makes you think that?
When is my birthday?
So, this is mean now, hey.
You are Capricorn, so far it's December?
I'm Taurus.
I know that.
Something with horns.
Today, Philip. I have birthday today.
I am... I, uh. ..
I'm sorry.
And then also the 25th.
That is a very special one.
24, Philip, I'm 24
Lars will fly back tomorrow to
Australia. He wanted to congratulate me
and say goodbye.
So, if you'll excuse,
I now drink my champagne.
Alcohol-free by the way.
Did they not call you?
Called? No, why?
Your father died yesterday.
What?
(Quiet sad music)
Hey, Master, how long
do you want to just sit here?
Can you stand up again?
I would like to use the machine.
Hello!
Knock knock, anybody home?
(Cracking)
What's going on here?
Are you crazy or what, Roland?
That's it! Once and for all! Harry!
Suleiman, Svetko!
Throw him out of here!
(Melancholic Music)
(Man) Mr. Feldberg, you have driven
through 23 Stations without stopping.
You have endangered hundreds
of human lifes,
and you have nothing to say?
(breathes strained)
Tach, Mr. Sti. . ., Um. ..
That's a coincidence! (Laughs)
Um. ..
Maybe I can later
invite you to a protein shake
and we can again
talk quietly about everything?
I'm here privately.
And I can not stand it,
when I am disturbed in my work-out.
You know what, Mr. Stiponski?
Nina was absolutely right.
You are a fucking puppet.
Let's see who's
the puppet here.
Philip!
- Niklas! Hey!
- Oh, Mary.
- You won't believe it!
- What?
- I got the part!
- The parte. ..
- Yes! Is it cool, right?
- The part!
So, the two of us will celebrate tonight.
Without you I would not have made it.
- No, I ...
- Do not argue.
Nik! You will not
risk everything now!
2 weeks before the wedding.
You can not be serious!
Now you let this tailless
Pasta Heini not spoil the fun.
Oh such empty.
Put on your apron if
someone shall take you serious.
- (Beep)
- Laura, it's me.
I must quickly go to Hamburg.
We have an agency meeting.
I'm back tomorrow morning.
Ok, then. ..
Until tomorrow, mouse. Kiss.
(Tires squeal)
No idea what's wrong with the fool.
We are done if he is not singing.
Talk with him!
We have no more time.
(Loudspeaker announcement)
'. . . In 5 minutes. '
(Sings) Aaa!
Siii!
Bruce, what's the matter?
- Suddenly I look so old.
- Oh papperlapapp!
I have a lousy feeling, Jerome.
I'm afraid I forget the lyrics.
Bruce, you're singing playback.
But what if people laugh?
Bruce, why should people laugh?
People love you!
You go out there and amazes
Millions of people, ok?
Bruce with your feeling,
with your voice.
With your great lyrics! Ok?
- You are my only friend, Jerome.
- Yes.
(Bruce) Oh!
(Small quiet sigh of Bruce)
(End of the race footsteps approach)
(clears throat)
(Woman) We have to!
(Sings) Aaa!
- The show must go on!
- Yeah! The show must go on!
(Sounds of techno music)
Jerome, I was on the phone with Heisel.
You got the deal.
(Laughs)
- Nope.
- Yes!
They give you a
half-million advance.
Half a million.
You are now one of the greats.
Yes, big time.
Oh! If that was not cool!
If that was not cool!
If this was not
top-tetra-mega-after-cool!
Wow!
(again loud techno music)
(Techno music now more in the background )
(Piano tones)
(Mary squeals)
(Techno music now dominating again)
(Music fades away, chirping birds)
(Burps and then begins to snore)
(Quiet music begins)
I'm just not one of those guys
one of those fucking around.
I can not do that.
I can not cheat on Laura.
- Ah, you, uh, have you just done that?
- Yes!
Ah, no. Oh. ..
I mean, if baggy pants,
But then the baggy pants of the woman,
which one is really close,
the one you really want to wake up with.
The special baggy pants.
I would love to go home immediately.
Hmmm. . . But I must stay here still,
otherwise it will be suspicous.
Buy her no flowers, by any means.
Say, Philip, have you already
used my bubble bath?
Hm?
I think this is really not ok.
And if the rent
is not paid next week,
I'll get you evicted. Because...
- Is that your famous business plan?
- Hm hm.
- Wow! Who has made the graphics?
- Nina.
She really tried hard.
- Want to have another coffee?
- Yes.
("If You'll Be Mine" is on again)
(Phone rings)
Hello, Philip.
Nina, I would like to
make one thing clear.
It is not true that I
am not interested in you.
I am very interested in you.
I now come to the kindergarten
and interrogate you. About your
Favorite color and shoe size
and when you name-day is
and things like that.
Are you stoned, Philip?
And I would like to clarify something.
I want the child because I want you,
Do you understand?
Because it's your child, our child.
I love you, Nina.
And somehow I always forget
to mention that I'm sorry.
- 'I love you!'
- (Brakes screech, scream)
(Clang,
"If You'll Be Mine" abruptly fades)
Nina?
(Threatening sounds)
(Ominous sounds)
Nina? What was that?
(Philip), 'Hello? Nina, '.
Shit!
Laura?
I've got a train earlier.
Do we have breakfast together?
Mouse?
(Stirring Music)
Hello? Hello!
I need a doctor!
Tell me, where have you been?
I was worried!
I was little partying with Caro,
for that we're both single again.
My Lord, I have a drunk skull.
What does that mean, "single"?
I did yesterday
call you in the office.
Me stupid cow wanted to know
what hotel you are in Hamburg
because I wanted to surprise you.
I do not know what to say.
You have nothing more to say, Niklas.
Pack your bags, you move out.
Laura. Laura, we are getting married in 2 weeks!
No, we do not.
Yesterday evening I did
sent out a collect mail.
- The wedding is canceled.
- What?
My mother probably gets
a heart attack, but what shall I do?
I also called Mrs. Koschinsky
and canceled the house.
You have to do the honeymoon
cancel, then you're done.
But. . . You can not
throw it all away now!
You said always. ..
What did I ever say Nicholas? What?
You always had the plan.
From the very beginning.
You wanted to move in together, you
wanted to get engaged and buy a house
all this shit Civil way
Do you think I like,
sitting around in 'suburban home
at 40 with a toddler (small kid)
while you run after some hores
and cheat on me,
until we meet again in court?
Do you think I like that?
(Melancholic Music)
Boo!
- Whew!
- Hey, Gunther!
- What are you up to ..
Hello! Well, that's a...
Surprise.
Since I am not familiar with,
such a situation.
I should have known that,
I can meet you here.
Yes.
The bald ibis.
Ah. ..
We wanted to go to the crocodiles.
Would you like to join?
- To the crocodiles?
- Yes.
(With pieping voice) Yes! Yes!
(clears throat) Ah, yes, yes.
But you must tell
me something! Anything!
Please wait over there.
Dr. Bahar will later
talk to you.
Mrs. Hellmich is currently operated.
Are you her friend?
It was.
I've hit her with the car
I have not seen her.
I'm so sorry.
She is pregnant, man.
Oh, God. ..
Can we please go to the sharks again?
Yes, children, just go.
Did you know that crocodiles
evolutionary
belong to the species of birds?
What you all know, Guenther,
Really.
Hm! Wikipedia.
(Asphixia sound, screams of horror)
(Exciting Music)
(Gasps) Ha!
(Shrill cries)
Günther!
(Screams of horror)
Help!
(Unintelligible speaker announcement)
- Are you the man of Nina Hellmich?
- Yes.
She broke her arm,
we had to operate.
Otherwise, laceration to the head,
Contusions, abrasions,
a mild concussion. ..
And the pregnancy
is also all right.
Yikes!
A little fighting spirit you have.
Far well.
(Quiet Music)
Good.
(Sugababes: "Get Sexy")
The party is over.
Go home! Go!
Come down from there!
- Hey! Jerome!
- The party is over!
- No home, or what?
- Do you want a Toast Hawaii?
Sabrina!
Please forget all the things I
've said about your career.
I told you total shit.
You really have a nice voice
but not when you sing.
I'm sorry.
Do not listen to that shit, Sabrina.
You have a great voice. Hm?
Well, now you go powder your nose.
What are you doing, huh?
We celebrate your deal, buddy.
There is no deal, Martin,
I'm out.
- (Laughs) Are you kidding me?
- Now go home.
- Hey, go home.
- What is it, huh?
- Did you get beaten again?
- Go home, Martin.
Uh!
Now all out of here!
Loco, you can stay here.
Sabrina, you too.
It's sad whow the business
changes some people.
Come on, Bruce, we are going.
I live here, Martin.
(Quiet Music)
Need not be sad.
Pop star is overrated.
To be normal is much nicer. Sabrina.
Actually, my name is Steffi.
I'm sorry, Manfred, however. ..
The sound we make,
is just not my thing.
This is total crap.
I've lied to you all the time.
I do not want this no more.
I can not do that anymore.
It's all ok, Jerome.
At least you're honest.
And that is what friends should be.
(Volume hiccups, clink)
Oh, and your neighbor.
I've just now found in the stairwell.
Messed up, this guy.
Wife gone. Great drama.
Mistake of his life and so on...
Poor pig, really.
You're a poor pig.
(Hiccup)
(Quiet Music)
From Tommi and from me.
(Laughs quietly)
1 4 stitches. Is not bad, right?
I'm terribly sorry that you
have been drawn in to that, Guenther.
I see it positive.
Otherwise you would not
be here right now, Susanne.
Also, I just want to say.
Not everyone can rightfully claim that,
he at some time fought with
a crocodile and survived.
How did you do that actually?
I used to do Judo earlier.
Hm hm.
(Both laugh)
(Waltz music begins)
You know, Nicholas, I don't
know your exact situation
but. ..
Believe me, there's always a comeback.
Always.
I think I'll go hoem first...
If you want,
I watch over your house,
until you're back from Munich.
I come from Heuchelheim.
This is such a small town
in Hesse near Giessen.
It's totally nice there.
Then say hello to Melanie from me.
You know, I'll
produce myself from now.
I am now so far, I think.
(Marshmellow Club:
"North Bergin Avenue")
(With a Bavarian accent)
Sorry, but you are.
Mr. Michalke
from the agency Wagner and Henke!
Yes.
I just wanted to personally
meet you. I am Jochen.
Hello.
Oh, you know me
only from the set-Card.
I am the model of your advertising.
The Ultimo-man.
I am originally from Nuremberg,
I just moved to Berlin '.
"You only live once", right?
Well, maybe we will meet
once for a drink?
Bye. See you.
("Bergin Avenue North"
now louder in the background)
(The doorbell rings)
("Bergin Avenue North" fades)
I just wanted to get my passport.
I'm flying now
to our honeymoon.
And I remain not only 8 days.
I'll stay as long as I want.
And your job?
I quit.
You go completely bonkers now, or what?
Laura. . . I. ..
I know now,
that there is nothing that I
can say will make up for everything.
(Deep breath)
So I let it be.
But one thing I say anyway.
I miss you.
I miss your baggy pants,
your electric toothbrush,
the impression on the pillow from
your face when you wake up,
I miss even how you're snoring.
- I do not snore.
- Yes, you do.
- No.
- Yes. If you're drinking.
And I miss it.
And. . . I wish nothing more,
than you come with me.
And then?
I do not know.
I have no plan.
(Laughs) I have no plan anymore.
All I know is. ..
I love you.
(Breathes deeply)
(Aircraft noise, accordion music)
I'd love to fly to
Paris with you, Pierre.
For so long time I haven't been
in the city of love.
You know the rules
of the airline, Tina.
Pilots and flight attendants
are not allowed.
'Do you think you can tell
a heart what it should feel?
'I see turbulences
on the horizon, Tina.
- 'And you know what I see, Pierre?
- 'No. What?
"A rainbow.
A rainbow of our love. '
(Voice of the geriatric nurse)
"Dear Roland.
'I hope you're feeling
according to the circumstances well.
'I have baked cookies for you.
So you know.
'Who I am, I have
a photo of me attached.
'I would be
very pleased to be a pen pal.
'Yours, Beatrice.'
(Quiet Music)
(Music fades)
(Door opens)
Hello!
Well?
Can you tell me what are you doing?
I... Buckle.
You know that.
We both had probably not our
best day last time, right?
Well, let's not rush things.
I'm here, uh. ..
This is your special permit.
You have now a
proper gastro-commerce.
Yes. ..
Thank you, Mr. Stubi. . ., Um. ..
Just call me Guenther.
- Philip.
- (Happy music plays)
(Gunther) is very nice here.
Perhaps it becomes an empire by times.
My sweetie,
I think your mommy is here now.
Hm hm.
- (All children) Bye, Jasmine!
- Hi, Tommy.
Bye!
- Bye, Jasmine!
- Here are the gifts of all of us.
When I grow up, I come
to. . . Igelstadt and marry you.
Then I'll marry you, too.
(Quiet moving music)
(Sounds of music)
(Gary Go: "Wonderful")
(Coughs reluctantly)
("Wonderful" fades)
(Breathes out nervously)
(Remote Ringing)
(Door opens)
Hello.
Well?
Who are you?
I am an old friend
from your mum. Is she at home?
Yes.
Can you get her?
Ok.
Some friend.
Hans-Jürgen.
What are you doing here?
Can I come in?
("Wonderful" starts again)
- Well, what is your name?
- Emily.
Emily! But this is a beautiful name!
Text song: Flinx.
("Wonderful" fades)
(Bruce Berger sings)
'Ahaaahaaaha!
'All the children of this earth,
'Sing with me this song.
'That peace will come.
'And there is food for all.
"We warm our climate."
'And the animals are dying out.
'It really is not that great.
'Get involved, just do not get out!
Our weapon is love.
Our hearts the ammunition.
'Against Hunger, AIDS and wars.
'Against Hatred and corruption.
'All the children of this earth,
'Sing with me this song.
'That peace will come.
'And there is food for all! Hu hu!
'Ahaaaha!
'For all the food there!
'For all the food. ..
'Food for all!
'Food for all the children!
'So. . . There is ...food for all.
'Aha! Ahaha! Ahaha! Ahaha!
'Aha! Ha!
'Food for all!
(Marshmellow Club:
"North Bergin Avenue")
("Bergin Avenue North" fades)