(Final Episode)
I'll make sure to watch him get caught.
We have to go and see
Chairman Park get arrested.
Stop talking and step on it!
I'll step on it while I'm talking.
Step on it!
I believe he ran away.
When did he leave work?
An hour ago?
What about his house?
Where the heck did he go? All right.
He's so quick.
He isn't home or at work.
Where's he hiding?
He isn't trying to hide.
He's trying to run away.
I'm fine. I'm leaving alone.
There's no use in issuing
him a travel ban now.
You can't get him if he
leaves in 20 to 30 minutes.
Okay, come quickly.
I hope he didn't take off.
We're almost there.
Go that way.
Park Hyun Do, where are you?
How dare you run away after
using me as a cover?
I will rip out his face.
Testing, testing. I am looking for a man.
This is an emergency announcement.
There is a certain criminal
trying to run overseas.
He instigated murder and embezzled money.
Do you know who he is? He is...
Chairman Park Hyun Do
of TQ Group, everyone.
Chairman Park is a man in his 50s...
with a very courteous face.
He also has a very deep voice.
- He's so weird.
- Where do you think...
he will run off to?
To the US? To Germany? To Tanzania?
Or could he be going to Denmark?
Right, he must be going to Denmark.
Anyway, he's determined to run and hide.
So if anyone sees him, make a report...
to a nearest army base or a police station.
Hey, stop fooling around
and come to gate eight.
Darn it, where is he?
Where are you going, Chairman Park?
- Let go of me.
- Come with me.
Let go. Call the security.
He is trying to attack me.
- Excuse me, here.
- Don't get me.
- You have to take him.
- Move away.
He is a convicted criminal
who wants to run away.
- How dare you accuse me?
- Come here.
Come here. No, don't do that.
Let go of me.
Do you know what he has done?
- You have to get him.
- Calm down.
Stop them.
You'll make me sad if you leave like this.
(Arrest Warrant)
Why didn't you come any sooner?
Yes, okay.
Great job.
Did he get caught?
Hey, Ga Eun.
Hello.
You must all be tired.
Take one each before you begin. You too.
Recharge your energy!
Recharged.
When will his lawyers get here?
They'll be here in 10 minutes.
I think things are finally
coming to an end.
We got them at the hospital yesterday...
and we got Chairman Park today.
Chief Kim, how did you come
up with the plan to...
catch those who tried to kill Mr. Lee?
Oh, that?
Mr. Choo, I'll go visit Mr. Lee.
Sure. Go ahead.
Yes.
Ha Gyeong.
Yes?
Do you really think so?
I'm sure they planted people there.
They're probably being
cautious after the accusation.
Will they put Soo Jin in danger?
We have to do something
before anything happens.
First, check and see if anyone is around.
If you do see someone, do as I say.
Ha Gyeong.
What's going on? Are his pupils reacting?
Yes. I could feel a bit of communication.
What did the doctor say?
He said he's as good as awake.
This is so great.
Come and see.
Since when was he around?
It's been a few days.
Don't worry, Soo Jin.
Make sure you keep your eyes on them.
Yes, I will.
Oh, really? Give me a second.
They were completely trapped, then.
What was in Mr. Lee's...
dash cam?
Why are you curious? You already know.
But still. Ga Eun, tell me.
Well...
Don't you dare say anything
to the prosecutor.
We cannot guarantee your safety.
So turn yourself in right now saying...
you're there for embezzlement and gambling.
And tell us where the materials are...
and erase all of the texts
and call history from us.
No.
I can't do that.
Who... Who are you?
Why are you doing this to me?
Wait, these are...
Write, "Please cremate me right away."
(I'm sorry. I can't turn back.
I have to protect you.)
(Please cremate me right away.)
Those jerks.
You have to take all of
them in while we are at it.
Yes. We'll interrogate them
and get their confession.
The lawyers are here.
(Bill of Indictment)
The murder and kidnapping were...
all your orders, right?
I don't know anything about this.
There's evidence to prove
your murder instigation.
Is there an evidence that it was my order?
Okay. Ms. Cho.
Those were ordered by
Chairman Park, correct?
Ms. Cho!
Everything is...
Ms. Cho...
did this on her own.
She stepped over the line...
to show her loyalty to me.
Ms. Cho, I always told you...
to stay within the bounds...
and to never cross the line.
He's so shameless.
He's no human being.
Don't you think he's putting
it all on Director Cho?
Embezzlement, tax evasion,
fraudulent tax reports and the slush fund.
Do you think that makes sense?
The money you say I embezzled.
Where is it now?
You haven't found it.
We have account details from
Taiwan and Switzerland.
Letters and numbers?
Anyone can fake them.
Name exactly where the money is, okay?
How dare he. I want to
burst through the window.
Can't you use a lie detector or something?
That's of no use.
This game will only end
when we find the money.
No.
That's not the end.
Sending him to prison.
That's the real ending.
However hard I think,
there's just no way to locate
the chairman's account.
Can't we get the information
from the Swiss bank?
Their clients' information is confidential.
They use account numbers, not names.
They're untraceable.
It's the perfect tax haven.
Didn't Switzerland agree
to share information...
to help eradicate corruption?
This bank didn't. That's
why the chairman chose it.
Do you mean only he can withdraw the money?
We need him to access the account...
so we can catch him in the act.
He'd never do that in this situation.
Wasn't Gang Sik in charge?
Though, he put someone else in charge now.
Do you think Director Go
and Manager Lee are okay?
Are you done yet?
I got two-thirds of the way through.
I think we'll be free in two more hours.
Okay. I can't believe they
starved us for two days.
Are they trying to kill us?
I'm starving.
- Hey.
- Stop calling me, I'm busy.
- I'm free.
- You can't be.
I need two more hours.
- Look.
- Stop asking me to look at...
My hands are free.
How'd you do that?
I don't know.
Shoot. Why didn't you tell me sooner?
I've been chewing a rope for
hours with bloody lips...
and my legs are cramped.
Why didn't you use that skill sooner?
I don't believe this. This is unbelievable.
- I'm sorry.
- This is so unfair.
- You did well.
- Untie me right now.
- I will.
- Hurry up, then.
I'm so tired.
- Hang in there.
- Hurry up.
- Okay.
- You're slow at untying me.
Work faster.
It came loose on its own. I
didn't do it on purpose.
We're detectives.
You're here to save us. Thank you.
- We're safe now.
- We're safe.
- Can you untie me?
- Go Man Geun.
Lee Gang Sik, you're under arrest...
for breach of duty and document forgery.
- What?
- And for fleeing.
We didn't flee. We were abducted.
My gosh.
There he is. Any comments?
This place...
is not about democracy at all.
They're forcing me to confess.
Do you admit the charges?
I spent my whole life working for TQ.
I never stole money...
and did nothing to apologize for.
I believe that once the
investigation is over,
you will see the truth that I am blameless.
What a joke.
(Park denies charges)
It doesn't work like that.
We don't deal with the
buyers' promissory note.
We can't tell you what the
current situation is.
- Yes.
- We didn't get any notifications.
I can't tell you that just yet.
Each manufacturer has their
own accounting team.
No, their contract has
nothing to do with us.
We only deal with the headquarters' files.
Okay then.
We don't deal with the buyers' debts.
I'll transfer you.
- This looks really bad.
- That's not our job.
- Will we really go bankrupt?
- I'll put you through.
It's possible, considering
our financial situation.
- Could all the subsidiaries flop too?
- Call them.
The whole group could go belly-up.
Then we'll all lose our jobs.
I hope it doesn't come to that.
We don't know enough...
to tell you what's going on.
What's wrong with him now?
Myung Seok.
What?
Are you upset?
It's not about me. It's
about what's going on.
Like what?
Will we and the subsidiaries
really all go bankrupt?
There is a possibility.
I got you the papers and the files...
from Tanzania to stop this, so why...
There's no hope at all.
We're all ruined.
Not yet. It's not that bad yet.
We have to try.
Try what? It's beyond saving now.
Stop trying to give me hope.
That's even worse.
You begged us last time,
so we gave you an extension.
That was days ago and
now look what happened.
This isn't about our finances.
It's about the chairman's arrest.
Once the media frenzy dies down...
It won't die down.
News will keep coming.
We're done making sacrifices.
Come up with a solution.
- We won't leave.
- Sort this out.
- Have it solved.
- Why is this happening?
I heard things are getting worse.
We can't pay off all the loans...
and promissory notes.
Why did you just let all this happen?
We trust you and followed you this far.
We want you to...
come up with a realistic
and reasonable solution.
Even with all the directors,
there's nothing they can do.
Tell me what you want me to do.
Put the embezzlement charges on my wife...
and instigation...
on Director Cho.
Tell those two women...
what I say word for word.
What do you mean?
It's what he said.
If they will...
drop all the charges against me,
I will prevent bankruptcy...
with my own assets, of course.
In return,
they must guarantee my
position as chairman.
Tell them very clearly that...
if this goes on, within two weeks,
TQ Group will crumble to the ground.
He wants an answer within two days.
He told me to give you a message.
Tell Min Young that if she
confesses to instigation,
I will see to it that she
lives well after her release.
He wants an answer within two days.
What?
That is what Director Cho said.
Tell him this.
If he wants me to take the fall for him,
he must give me half of what is in...
the account in Switzerland.
If he won't,
I'll open the proof that
shows he ordered the murder.
She is...
too greedy.
Her inability to lie is
a poor as her greed.
Proof that I ordered murder?
This is giving me a headache.
What shall I do?
Deal with him when the time is right.
She wants an answer within two days.
Will he stop the bankruptcy
with his slush fund?
Yes, he's using that to
make a deal with me.
He's amazing. He really is.
We're in big trouble, aren't we?
According to my analysis, yes.
Banks have been calling...
in regard to promissory notes.
There are three big promissory
notes due this week.
If we can't pay, next week there will be...
a cascade of bankruptcies.
If it's that serious,
then I'll have to rethink
for the greater good.
Ma'am...
Just to have Chairman Park punished,
- I can't let the employees lose...
- No.
You see it in the movies.
If you give the criminal money...
and helicopter...
He kills the hostages and runs away.
That's right. You can't cut him a deal.
I'm with him on that.
If you make a deal with the
chairman to avoid trouble,
the situation will get worse.
You must stay strong.
You have us even though
we have little power.
You're doing something...
no board member could ever do.
I'm sorry.
And thank you.
Thanks for the extension.
Okay. Please send someone
to Accounting Department.
Thank you.
I got Hanjoo Bank to extend the deadline.
Why did you wash your hair at work?
I couldn't shower this morning
because I was too busy.
It was so itchy. Now I feel refreshed.
What about the promissory notes?
I think I can hold it off this once,
but not for another time.
That's final.
I can't get any more
extensions from banks either.
We're at the end of our rope.
Not the chairman, but us.
Call my lawyer, please.
Why are you here again?
The chairman wants a quick answer.
Why?
He's thinking about an alternative.
That means he has an option, other than me.
I can't give you any details.
I haven't changed my mind.
Can't you just give him what he wants?
If dad gets out, the company
will ride out the crisis.
We need to save the company first.
I can't let him to continue
managing it poorly.
It's not like you've done
anything right either.
What have you done?
You very well know that...
Dad is the only one who
can clean up this mess.
Please be rational and face the reality.
- Myung Seok.
- Mom.
(Establishing Law and Order)
You're here.
Why did you call me?
What do you mean why?
Can't a father call his son?
Didn't your mom say anything?
She needs to give an answer today.
I'm not sure.
I heard what happened yesterday.
You're thinking more rationally than her.
It's not like that.
You've come to think deeper
since you started working.
No matter what,
we have to protect what's ours.
That way, you can inherit what's mine.
The only one I can trust...
in my family is...
you.
Yes, Father.
I have a message for you.
He said 50 percent is too much.
Then?
40 percent. 20 percent
when you give consent...
and the other 20 percent when
the chairman is released.
How can I trust him?
Haven't you trusted him
and worked with him?
Is this what I get for trusting him?
Now is your only chance.
Will you accept his offer?
I will.
(Father)
Yes, Father.
Right now?
Okay. I'll be right there.
Where are you going?
I'll be right back. Please wrap this up.
Hands.
Pardon?
Give me your hands.
My hands? Okay.
That's my Swiss bank account.
Send money there.
You take care of the account.
Father, how can I...
Be careful.
You should never get caught. If you do,
I'll be finished and the money too.
Okay.
My goodness.
(Chief Kim)
Did my wife send you?
Why did you make such a huge offer?
I guess she...
spilled the beans.
Of course. Because we're the brain.
I'm sure it's the answer I expected.
It's as you expected. She
declined your offer.
By the way,
I don't remember...
the offer I made.
If you tell me where your slush fund is...
I'll take it into consideration.
Transfer... Transfer amount.
This is crazy.
8, 3, 6.
Transfer.
Did it work?
Yes, it's in.
Let's see.
It's 1,000 no 10,000...
No, it's 100,000,000 dollars.
100,000,000 dollars?
My gosh.
Myung Seok.
You just...
transferred Chairman Park
Hyun Do's slush fund...
to Business Operations' reserve fund.
What did you say? I
couldn't hear clearly...
I'm sorry, come again?
Let me ask you one thing.
Why...
are you working so hard? For what?
Because that's righteous...
and that's the principle?
Because of my wife and you,
a company will be ruined.
Many employees will...
lose their jobs.
Many subcontractors will...
go bankrupt.
People like you who follow principles...
wreck the world.
No.
People who mistake greed for principles...
wreck the world.
Thanks to those who follow principles,
the world goes around.
Do you even have...
a right to say that?
You've been greedier than anyone else.
We've changed.
Especially after seeing how you lived.
We decided not to be horrible like you.
Km Seong Ryong, there's a call for you.
Mr. Seo.
I thought you'd act wisely until the end.
I made a foolish decision,
but I believe the result
will be a wise one.
If your decision is foolish,
then the result will be foolish too.
I'm not sure.
What you just said doesn't
really intrigue me.
Chairman Park, you were
actually a man of integrity.
- What?
- We only found 290 dollars...
in your slush fund account in Switzerland.
What?
Is there any other news?
I can't tell you who it is,
but a certain person returned
a huge amount of money...
into Business Operations' reserve fund.
That is awesome. That's amazing.
We'll use it well.
What are you talking about?
We will use this to a good use too.
What should we do?
Do away with him. Find the
right time to do that.
I saw your face during the
first cross-examination.
It looked like you were
greatly betrayed by him.
If he really cared for you,
he wouldn't have used you as a cover.
You will receive about 20
to 25 years of sentence.
When you get out, you'll be well over 60.
Where will you use your money at that age?
You'll be spending your
prime days in the prison.
So do as I say.
Cooperate. Your sentence
will be down to seven years.
Do you mean it?
I don't joke around with these things.
Will you come with me, or no?
Myung Seok, don't get me wrong.
I'm not trying to take your father's money.
I'm trying to return it
to where it belongs.
I heard you complained
to Ha Gyeong saying...
nothing changed even after helping me.
I didn't complain.
This is the last thing
you will do to help me.
Like I said, you don't have
to do it if you don't want.
You can live a grand life...
with your father's money later on.
I won't say anything.
That's your life.
I don't want to live that life.
- Really? No?
- Yes.
Then help me. I will make sure...
you live a shameless life.
Hey!
Hey, stay calm. This is
a correctional center.
I will never...
I will never let you get away with this.
How dare you take my money?
- But 290 dollars are enough.
- That's quite a lot.
What did you say?
He's so scary. I'm leaving.
Let's run away.
Unbelievable.
- Cheers.
- Great job, everyone.
- Yes.
I still can't believe it.
We took the chairman's money.
I was going to bring Myung Seok,
but he said he was going home.
So I let him go.
Good job. He probably wants to be here,
but he probably isn't feeling well either.
Our company isn't in a
danger anymore, right?
We took care of about 70
percent of the problems.
You really put everything
into this to make it work.
Anyway, great work, Mr.
Seo and Seong Ryong.
It's all thanks to your support.
You're good at faking compliments.
I'm not faking it.
Stop winking at me.
Don't try to kiss me.
I hate that tongue.
I'm sorry to bring this up right now.
But can we order another dish?
Go ahead.
You always do this.
Honey.
Soo Jin.
Eun Seok.
Honey.
What will you do now?
Well, I'll get ready...
to leave.
You're finally leaving.
What will you do?
I haven't thought about it.
I'll give myself a break.
I got too tired from acting as Mr.
Righteous.
I guess it's a vacation for Mr. Righteous.
Yes, something like that.
What will you do?
I heard the district attorney
asked you to return.
I don't want to.
Why not? You look like
a real prosecutor now.
No.
I'm looking for something that's cooler.
Anyway.
I thought I needed to tell you this.
Kim Seong Ryong,
you are the best Chief Kim
in this entire country.
Then let me tell you this.
Seo Yul is...
the best prosecutor,
director and a glutton...
in this country.
- My goodness!
- That was so gross.
Even my limbs feel weird.
Just go.
Get out of here.
Let's never meet again.
Accused.
Do you have any last words?
What it means to run a company
in this country is...
like sailing through rough
seas 365 days a year.
To overcome a large wave,
sometimes sacrifices are necessary.
And unavoidable decisions
are necessary as well.
I just prepared myself a
secondary solution...
to be ready for such a situation.
It was something I did for
everyone in TQ Group.
That is why I do not admit these charges...
put together maliciously to attack me.
I will lodge an appeal.
This case clearly shows the corruptions...
of conglomerates in this nation.
Also, we believe there
is no way to explain...
how they committed inhumane crimes...
for the sake of their business.
We considered...
the effects this case had on the society...
and we have the intention
of establishing...
enterprises with morals as
we announce the verdict.
Park Hyun Do is..
Sentenced to 22 years in prison.
Cho Min Young is sentenced
to seven years in prison.
Go Man Geun is sentenced
to four years in prison.
Lee Gang Sik is sentenced
to three years in prison.
Unavoidable decisions?
A secondary solution?
Why would you put money in your pocket...
to resolve a situation?
You should be giving money
to save your company.
Let's go.
If you ever get out,
don't ever take money...
from the powerless ones.
- Understood?
- Hey!
Go away, you jerk!
You jerk!
Go, you jerk!
I was about to leave.
You did very well, Ga Eun.
It's nothing.
It was an honor for me to
take part in this case.
Prosecutor Han.
My gosh.
I have a present. I almost forgot.
I see.
I sent a picture to you both.
You should check.
I think that can become a huge case.
Make a use of that...
and go get him.
Mr. Kim, that's awesome.
Hey, Mr. Kim.
- Sir!
- It's me, Mr. Kim.
- He's from Gunsan.
- When were you freed?
I was there for only a bit.
It's not like I killed someone.
Anyway, you pulled out a huge case.
You destroyed TQ Group.
I just had to scold them a bit.
Look at your spirit and confidence.
This is why I love you.
Anyway, what brings you here?
That's right.
I'm here because I need your help.
- Where?
- Yesterday,
I bought two clubs in the north of Seoul.
I need a manager.
How about Mr. Ku or Mr. Lee?
Those two lack the brain power.
Only you can deal with the Seoul slickers.
The conditions are the usual.
The basic pay plus...
whatever you want to take as an incentive.
Whatever I want?
(Chairperson Jang Yoo Seon)
(Resignation)
Personally, I don't want to accept this.
You're the most talented
executive we have left.
Can't you stay?
Regardless of my capabilities,
I have no right to stay.
You aren't the person you
were when you started here.
I need to spend a little time for myself.
I need some time to learn to be...
a decent person.
Okay. When you think you are decent enough,
come and see me.
Thank you...
for everything.
(Resignation)
Are you really going to leave?
Yes. I said I would.
Chief.
What? I'm not going far away.
We aren't parting forever.
Thanks for staying with us.
I liked it.
I felt proud too.
Thank you so much for everything.
Chief.
Are you really leaving?
Don't do that.
You're making me feel weird.
You're good at ruining the mood. Get going.
You jerk.
You'll work in Suyu-dong?
Yes, not so far from here.
You won't sneak off to Denmark, will you?
I'm so over with Denmark now.
I prefer Korea.
Seong Ryong.
Thanks so much for helping us out.
I mean it.
I should be thanking you.
You made me a decent human being.
This is getting too sad.
I can't deal with it.
I'll be too busy to come
around for a while.
I'll pay a visit once I
settle down and become free.
Take care.
Come back the second you
think it's wrong for you.
You'll have found a replacement by then.
No.
You're TQ Psycho, our mascot.
There's always an opening.
For the next one year,
don't call me TQ Psycho or Mr. Righteous.
I will think of you a lot.
Me too.
I think...
I'll never forget this place.
I should go.
Bye.
Chief Kim.
I just wanted to call you.
One last time.
What lovely weather.
(Chief Kim)
Political kingmaker and big shot Cha Gi Ho,
a former leader of the Sinkwang Party...
was arrested for bribery and tax evasion.
Mr. Choi, his right-hand
man and assistant...
was arrested for blackmail and abduction.
They committed numerous
crimes to influence...
political affairs and people,
and even threatened
family members for money.
They took gifts worth...
hundreds and thousands of dollars,
and did favors in return for payments.
You still haven't forgiven me.
Sorry, Dad.
Do you think one apology...
is enough to melt away my anger?
No.
I know that you will never forgive me.
But Dad, you know...
It's the first time I ever felt this way.
Now I think I can finally
live like a decent human.
Good for you...
for selling out your dad
to become a decent human.
No, Dad, I didn't sell you out.
In your stead,
I admitted our wrong to the public.
Asking for forgiveness is
the decent thing to do.
Not living like you...
is decent.
Hello, I am Jang Yoo Seon.
To ensure that TQ Group
is ran transparently,
we are hiring...
a CFO and accept
applications from everyone.
Through a fair process,
we plan to select...
a CFO who will lead us
morally and effectively.
I promise TQ Group will
become even more stronger.
(Director's Office)
This is old-fashioned.
(Choo Nam Ho)
Who cares about where and
how well they studied?
We want skills and amicability
and things like that.
The person you recommended
is complicated and...
Mr. Park, it's a temporary position.
Let's give him a shot.
If it doesn't work out, then fine.
Sorry.
Hello, honey.
No, I'm free.
Do you want me home early? Okay.
It's Friday. Dinner and
a movie sounds fine.
No, hang on, did I have plans?
Where's my phone?
Sir.
Right.
Let me check and call you back.
When did your wife and daughter return?
A month ago.
You must be so pleased.
I am.
You can go.
Thanks.
Was it nicer without them?
We hired...
a new contract worker to join our team.
Say hello.
Hello, everyone.
You all know me, don't you?
I won't be bringing your coffees anymore.
I'm here to add numbers. Thank you.
You're so unfriendly.
Good luck.
Don't throw used tissues around.
Look at all these trash.
Do you want to get buried in trash?
It's because the air is
terrible and I'm have allergy.
We should've moved to 17th
floor when they offered.
Chief, you regret not moving, right?
No. I like this place. It feels like home.
Right, General Manager?
Right.
I feel comfortable here.
I don't think I can work in
an office with sunlight.
It'd be too bright.
Mold and dampness became a real family.
Dear mold and dampness, stay here.
If you go to 17th floor,
you won't see me often.
What do you think?
Okay.
Everyone, I'm here.
- Goodness.
- Honey.
I passed the interview.
Starting today, I'm an accounting intern.
I'm an office worker now.
Give her a hand.
- Thank you.
- Goodness.
Clap.
- You're embarrassing me.
- Quiet.
You must be quiet in the office.
Honey, are you okay?
- She scared me.
- Is your voice okay?
Don't listen to her. Why
are you scaring her?
Say what?
I won't tolerate insubordination.
I won't tolerate you, period.
Don't worry. I'll make sure
the witness is protected.
Don't regret what you did.
Whistle-blowing was the right choice.
I'll get the proof from you
without anyone knowing.
Hi.
Enjoy.
Give us some garlic sauce.
Okay.
Isn't it time you quit
being a public defender?
You said you'd only volunteer for a year.
After I wrap up the case I have now.
- What's this?
- It's a CFO application form.
You are the person...
our company needs.
I'll think about it.
Next applicant, please.
Hello.
I'm Seo Yul. I applied for CFO position.
Well, your book...
should be nominated for Best Screenplay.
It has a great composition.
It's very coherent.
- I'm so sorry, sir.
- I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry.
Repeat after me.
- Ripping off has...
- A limit!
- Don't rip off...
- The weak!
That's right. It's okay
to pocket a bit of...
your boss' money.
But if you get caught taking money from...
the waiters and the kitchen workers,
you're dead.
- Yes, sir.
- You may go.
They're cute.
(Dome Nightclub)
Chief Kim Seong Ryong!
Yes? I'm Kim Seong Ryong.
I'm Prosecutor Park Yong Tae, FIUs.
I haven't done anything wrong.
I've been super good.
I guess you feel guilty.
I'm not here to arrest you.
Then why are you here?
I have a favor to ask.
A favor?
I'm investigating a public
enterprise accounting fraud.
I need someone...
who'll go undercover and get information.
Why are you asking me to do that?
Chief Kim Seong Ryong, please help me.
How can you trust me?
Do you know me? Do you know who I am?
Lawyer Seo Yul and
Prosecutor Han Dong Hoon...
recommended you.
Those jerks.
Please help me.
I'm sorry. No.
Chief, I beg you. Please help me.
No.
Chief.
(If something is not right, )
(I'll be back!)
(Chief Kim forever!)
(We all are leading
characters of Chief Kim!)
(We made Chief Kim together!)