All right, officers.
One beef and cheese deluxe, french fries
and orange-flavored beverage.
Thank you, my brother.
Knock it down for me.
Boo-yow!
All right, it is knocked down.
And for you, large man.
One plain wiener, no bun, no sauerkraut,
no chili, no mustard...
...no pickle, no cheese, no relish--
No tip, give it to me.
Excuse me to inquire...
...but this meager meal seems insufficient
for a man of your tremendous girth.
Well, I'm just trying
to drop a couple of pounds.
May I suggest you move to my country...
...where everyone is fashionably thin,
due to lack of food.
New diet?
I read about it in a magazine
at the dentist office.
-Men's Fitness?
-No.
-Esquire?
-Maxim?
-No.
-Sports Illustrated?
-Modern Bride, okay?
Hey. That's none of my business.
You better get married quick
because you're starting to show.
It happens to be a good diet
and I'm losing weight.
I'm going to the gym three times a week
and a half hour every morning on the bike.
Well, be careful with that.
I read an article that said those bicycles
wreak havoc on a pair of testicles.
What are we talking about, a little
numbness or that time I sat on my Taser?
Well, apparently, the angle of the seat,
it restricts blood flow...
...causing low sperm count
and/or possible impotence.
-Really? I never heard that.
-You ain't gonna read that in Modern Bride.
Pick up this month's copy
of American Balls.
Hey, how about we hit a couple of clubs up
after we get off, huh?
Have a few drinks, maybe find
some bad girls who wanna cop some pleas.
Or even better, please some cops?
[LAUGHS]
Do you listen to yourself when you talk?
No, thanks, I got an OA meeting.
You're kidding me.
Overeaters Anonymous on a Friday night?
That is pathetic.
Oh, I'm pathetic?
Which one of us lives with his grandma?
I'm over there because she's old and frail
and needs somebody to look after her.
She mows the lawn, Carl.
After I start it up for her
and push her in the right direction.
Fine. Whatever you need
to live with yourself...
...and your grandma.
I would shoot you right now, but I don't
have enough chalk to outline your body.
[SlNGlNG]
She's a brick
Uh, uh, uh, house, uh, uh, uh
She's mighty, mighty
Just letting it all hang out
Because she's a brick
Hmm, hmm, house, hmm, hmm, hmm
Shake it down, shake it down
Shake it down, down
Shake it down, shake it
Ma, do you have to eat that
in front of me?
Oh, I'm sorry, baby, want a bite?
What do you think I'm doing
on this machine here, making butter?
Oh, baby,
why are you punishing yourself?
Face it, you're a big-boned girl.
You're always gonna be a big-boned girl.
Bones don't jiggle, Mom.
You just gotta accept the fact
that you got your daddy's genes.
I mean, if you had a turkey leg in one hand
and the other hand down your pants...
...I'd swear he was risen from the dead.
God, this is moist.
Do I smell your double chocolate
blackout cake?
Fresh out of the oven.
Ha-ha-ha, give me.
JOYCE:
Mmm.
VlCTORlA:
Oh, Mom, this is incredible.
-This time, instead of milk, I used pudding.
-Mm-hm.
Well, bravo. That must be why
it's so smooth and creamy.
For God's sakes,
why are you doing this to me?
-What? What are we doing?
-What are we doing?
Never mind.
I've burned off my, uh, 12 calories.
Just gonna go to my OA meeting.
Oh, Mol, you're never gonna meet
a cute guy at the chub club.
I'm not going to meet guys.
I'm going for support.
Not that I don't get
more than enough right here.
Whoa, where'd that come from?
Where did that come from?
Are you kidding me?
Okay, I'm trying to watch my diet,
I'm trying to exercise...
...and you two are trying
to make me fatter.
You're not fat. You're big-boned.
And I'm just trying to get you laid.
Ugh.
Why don't you take her
to one of those lesbo clubs?
-Now, they seem to like the beefy gals.
-Hmm.
You really didn't have to come with me.
Hey, you said you wanted
to be supported.
-I'm supporting.
-Okay, ah--
-Where are you going? The meeting's here.
-Go ahead.
I'm gonna sneak into the little girls' room
and light up a fatty.
No offense, fellas.
-Hi, my name's Mike. I'm an overeater.
GROUP [lN UNlSON]: Hi, Mike.
I had a pretty fair week. I lost 3 pounds.
MAN 1 : Hey.
MAN 2: Yeah.
Then I took off my shirt
and I found it right about here.
Anyway, diet-wise,
I did have one tiny setback this week.
I was at the grocery store...
...and they were having a sale
on those fun-size candies for Halloween.
Uh, I picked up a bag, figuring I'm gonna
need something for the trick-or-treaters.
Before I know it, I'm standing
in front of the checkout...
...with 19 of the fun bastards
jammed in my mouth, trying to say:
"Plastic."
[LAUGHlNG]
Hallelujah, right?
Then, of course,
the self-loathing kicks in.
Voices in my head start telling me
what a loser I am...
...how no one's ever gonna love me...
...how I'm gonna spend the last few years
of my life alone in a dark apartment...
...my only companions,
six or seven cats...
...that made the mistake of wandering
into my gravitational field.
The bottom line is,
I know those voices are lying.
And I know all I gotta do
is work this program one day at a time.
That's why I start every morning
by getting on my knees...
...and asking God to give me
the strength to stay on my diet.
And then I pray that he gives me the
strength to get my fat ass up off the floor.
MlKE:
Anyway, thank you.
Hey.
Damn it, one of y'all got to inhale.
What are you doing here?
Now that your meeting's over,
you might wanna have some fun.
Sure. Wanna go get some TCBY?
Hell, yeah. Couple of single guys on a
Friday night, let's get all up in some yogurt.
Hey, I really liked your share.
Oh, thank you.
-You're pretty funny.
-lf everybody's laughing...
...they won't try to kill
and cook each other.
[MOLLY CHUCKLES]
-Molly.
-Mike.
Hey, there you are.
Where did you go?
Went looking for a snack machine and all l
found were these crackers up in the church.
Really dry.
Do you know of a good place around here
where I could get a pizza?
What do you think?
This is my sister, Victoria.
-Hi, Victoria.
-Hello, Victoria.
Officer Carl MacMillan, Chicago PD.
Whoa, you're a cop?
-Yeah, Mike and l, we're both cops.
-Ha, ha.
Great. I love cops.
Cops are great.
I'm not high.
Anyhoo, uh, I'm a fourth-grade teacher...
...and I'd love to have a police officer
come and speak to my class.
Oh, absolutely.
Just contact the department.
They'll send somebody right over.
Oh, all right.
Or you can give Officer Biggs your number
and he can come talk to your class himself.
Even better.
Oh, uh, okay. Well, are you looking for, like,
general information or scared straight?
Well, they're 9 years old,
so scare the hell out of them.
[MlKE CHUCKLES]
Kidding. Just be funny and charming
like you were in the meeting.
-Okay.
-Great. Call me.
-I will.
-All right.
Has it been a long time since I've talked?
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Tell me why we let them go.
The pothead had jungle fever...
...and you could've gotten the other one
with a taffy apple.
I'm not letting her go.
I just don't wanna come off as desperate.
-Yeah, but you are desperate.
-No. I'm lonely and miserable.
There's a difference.
And what is that difference?
Shut up. You live with your grandma.
I wish these uniforms were a little
more flattering, you know? Blousier.
Who you trying to fool?
I mean, you met her at an OA meeting.
She sticks her hand under there and doesn't
find a man bra, she's gonna be ecstatic.
You know, uh, I was thinking about
asking her to go to the aquarium with me.
-The aquarium? The first date?
-Yeah. Uh-huh.
-Let me ask you something.
-What?
You ever been on a second date?
[TOlLET FLUSHES]
-Hold it right there, fella.
-Yes, sir?
-You wanna go to jail?
-No, sir.
Then get over there
and wash your hands.
[CHATTERlNG]
All right, people, settle down.
I want you to give your attention...
...and your respect to Officer Michael Biggs
of the Chicago Pol--
Shut up!
Chicago Police Department.
-Officer Biggs?
-Okay.
-Uh, thank you.
-Mm-hmm.
First, I'd like to say,
there are a lot of misconceptions...
...about what it is a police officer
actually does.
My dad says you guys are all on the take.
-Gary, I told you not--
-No, no, that's okay.
Gary, that's one of the misconceptions
I was talking about.
On TV and in the movies, they like
to make you think there's corruption--
My mom says you guys only go
after people of color.
-Well, jeez, that's not true at all.
-You calling my mom a liar?
Uh, why don't we save
all of our questions for the end?
You know what? This is good.
I mean, questions lead to a give-and-take
and stimulate discussion.
How can you be a cop and be so fat?
You know, maybe we should save
the questions till after.
-Hey, I have a question.
-You don't.
-Oh, but I do.
-No, you don't.
What made you wanna become
a police officer in the first place?
Oh, that's a great question.
Well, I became a police officer
because my dad was a police officer.
He worked the same beat for 30 years:
A five-block radius in the Wicker Park area.
And since our last name is Biggs,
he used to refer to it as Biggs' Mile.
As a kid, I always thought
he was saying "big smile."
I remember watching him leaving.
His uniform would always be pressed
and his shoes shined like mirrors.
I'd say to him, "Dad, where are you going?"
And he'd say, "Biggs' Mile, son."
And since I thought he was saying
"big smile," I'd give him a big smile.
Anyway, everybody in that neighborhood
loved him because he kept the place safe.
And he treated everyone with respect.
He made police work look like a pretty noble
profession right up until the very end.
What happened? Did he die?
No, he fell in love with a prostitute,
divorced my mom and moved to Tampa.
-Tore the whole family apart.
MOLLY: Ahem.
I probably should've stopped
at "noble profession."
I really appreciate you doing this.
I think the kids got a lot out of it.
Hey, they seem like a good group,
except the one with the mouth.
He's on a hell-bound train.
Gary? Yeah.
I caught him sniffing the dry-erase markers.
That's not gonna end pretty.
[MlKE CHUCKLES]
Okay, well, um,
thanks again for inviting me.
You're welcome.
It was nice of you to come.
Oh, it was my pleasure.
So...
...what made you wanna become
a teacher?
[OBJECT CRASHES]
[KlDS SHOUTlNG]
I really don't remember.
I gotta go.
Oh. Oh, okay. Bye.
Bye.
[MOLLY CLEARS THROAT]
-Hey, would you like to go out with me?
MOLLY: Shut up!
Now, that was pathetic.
Really? It didn't look as smooth as it felt?
I'd lie to you if you want...
... but I thought our relationship
had grown beyond that.
Two meatball subs,
large curly fries and chocolate malt.
Welcome back.
Thanks, Samuel.
What is this world coming to?
Thirty-eight dollars to get lipstick
out of suede pants?
-Whoa, what the hell are you doing?
-I'm having dinner.
No, this isn't dinner.
This is suicide with meatball bullets.
Come on. Give that back.
You just lost 3 and a half pounds.
Oh, big deal.
My farts weigh 3 and a half pounds.
You don't have to tell me.
I ride in the car with you every day.
Samuel, throw this away and bring
my partner a chicken breast on wheat toast?
Throw it away? I don't think so.
I will airdrop it to my village.
There. Now, you may never have sex
without paying for it...
... but you're still on your diet.
Thanks.
Come here. Give me some love.
Sweet Jesus, it's like hugging a futon.
I don't know. I guess I've had food issues
for as long as I can remember.
Once, my dad had to write a check for $280
to the Girls Scouts of America...
...for "unaccounted for cookies."
[CHUCKLES]
God bless him, he never said a word.
Never made me feel bad about it.
Of course he weighed about
a thousand pounds himself, so....
[MOLLY SlGHS]
Anyway, I know I'm never gonna be
a size two.
I mean, and that's fine
because I happen to like who I am.
There's nothing wrong with me
as a person.
I'm smart, I'm funny, I recycle.
[CHUCKLES]
I just wanna learn to control my eating...
...you know, and not keel over
in a White Castle drive-through like my dad.
And it was his third lap.
That's it. Oh, and I would love to be able
to walk into a nightclub...
...without having every queen in the room
leaping on me like I'm a gay pride float.
[CHUCKLlNG]
Thank you.
-Okay, who wants to share next?
-Hi, Molly.
-I didn't see you there.
-Yeah, I lost another pound.
-I'm becoming a rail.
-Ha-ha-ha.
-Can I talk to you outside?
-Sure.
-ls everything okay?
-Yeah, yeah, it's fine.
I just, um....
Well, uh, ahem...
...I wanted to tell you that, uh....
I like fish.
All right.
What I mean to say is
I'm sort of an amateur ichthyologist.
So all types of fish?
-Hey, you know that word.
-I'm a teacher.
You'd be surprised at the words I know.
Anyway, I like to go to the aquarium
on my days off...
... because there's something soothing
about watching those giant creatures...
...float around each other,
all graceful and weightless.
Sounds like my water aerobics class.
[CHUCKLES]
That's funny.
Anyway, uh, uh, I was wondering
if you weren't doing anything, if we could--
Whoa! Oh!
-Are you okay?
-Oh, I'm fine.
You landed pretty hard.
Oh, no, no, I'm good,
but I don't think that table's up to code.
Oh, uh, is your finger supposed
to be pointed in that direction?
-Whoa.
-No, it is not.
Oh, that's bad.
I should probably skedaddle over
to the emergency room.
Yeah. Do you need somebody
to drive you?
Oh, no, no, no. Life of a police officer.
Tuck and roll. Duck and cover.
Don't vomit. Just get to the car.
Don't vomit.
You ever gonna call that OA girl back?
No, that, uh, that ship has sailed.
I'm just gonna move on.
-Mind if I tell you where you went wrong?
-Oh, would you?
Women don't wanna hear a grown man
going on about ichthyology.
It's got the word "ick" built right into it.
You know, if you went with me
just once...
...you would see how beautiful
and sensuous these creatures really are.
Ain't no lady in the world gonna whip her
undies off hearing that kind of jibber-jabber.
WOMAN [OVER RADlO]:
Got an 831 at 9425 Cicero Avenue.
Handle code two.
MlKE:
Car 79 in the vicinity.
WOMAN:
Roger, Car 79.
Thought about one of them
mail order brides?
Here we go.
Those women are very hot.
Back when they were commies, they all
weighed 300 pounds and had mustaches.
Democracy's what cleaned them
bitches up.
And here's another idea:
Maybe you could move to Japan.
A big man is like a god over there.
Do you ever actually stop to breathe or do
you have, like, a blowhole under your hat?
[RlNGS DOORBELL]
Seriously, yank your underwear up into your
crack and get you some sumo groupies.
-Mike.
-Molly.
What are you doing here?
Uh, somebody called the cops
and we're the cops.
Yeah, we called, like,
an hour and a half ago.
Did you guys get lost or stop to make out
under a bridge somewhere?
-Calm down, Mom.
JOYCE: Pssh.
Seriously, though, did you guys stop
to get pizza or something?
Wow, what are the odds, huh?
Odds, my sweet mocha ass.
This is a miracle of biblical proportions.
How do you figure?
God couldn't bring Molly to the mountain,
so he brought the mountain to Molly.
I'm the mountain, right?
You're the freaking Himalayas.
Get in there.
It's gonna be okay, Mom. It's just stuff.
Just stuff? Is that what you call
the diamond necklace your father gave me?
Oh, God, I'm so sorry.
Did you know he had to take a second job
to afford that thing?
And I had to give him a third job
to get it.
[SlGHS]
-You think you'll find our things?
-I doubt it. We barely found your house.
Hey.
We're gonna do our best
to recover your property.
-But we're gonna need to fill out a report.
VlCTORlA: They stole my water pipe.
Luckily, I was a Girl Scout.
Hi.
-Apple?
-Uh, no, thanks.
-They test our urine for fruit.
-Oh.
Okay, can I get a list
of some of the missing items?
Well, they took the TV, a couple of iPods,
uh, the computer, my mom's jewelry.
I need serial numbers off the TV,
the computer.
Any photographs you might have
of the property?
And would you like to go out
with me sometime?
What? Are you asking me out now?
That is correct, ma'am.
You had every chance to ask me out...
...and you chose to ask me out
in the middle of a crime scene?
I realize this is not the most opportune
moment, but I'm quite smitten with you.
I'd hate to see this moment pass by without
telling you you're a remarkable woman...
...with a lot of interesting qualities I find
both attractive and appealing, ma'am.
Okay. That was pretty cute.
So is that a yes or a no?
Is it gonna go on the report?
Depends on what your answer is.
I would love to go out with you.
Then, yes, I am writing that down.
She better be good to him.
[JOYCE GASPS]
What do you want? I'm a sensitive guy.
[English - US - SDH]