(Episode 1)
I'm here.
What is that?
You'll shock them. This is enough.
Didn't you bring your gun?
Kids these days are fearless, you know.
Where's our reinforcement?
What reinforcement?
We can get them between the two of us.
Didn't you ask for a reinforcement?
- Are you kidding me? - Why would I kid you now?
- Didn't you do it? - You said you did it.
What I meant was that you should do it.
- Darn it. - Give them a call now.
- Hello? - You surprised me.
We need a reinforcement right now.
- Oh, my. - Stay alert.
- I'll fire. - Darn it.
Give me a moment.
Everyone, be careful.
The first shot is a blank shell...
and the next one is real.
Right?
But what are you going to do?
We have over five guys.
That means at least five of you will die.
No. We're allowed to fire only four shots.
- Four shots? - Yes.
- It's up to me. Darn you. - Fine.
Hey, it's apparently four shots.
The four of you will die.
- My goodness. Hold this. - Okay.
How dare you tell me to come and go?
- Bring it on. - Jang Do Jang!
Where are you? I'm here.
Come out quickly wherever you are.
You are all dead.
Hey, it's raining.
Let's put an end to this and go home.
You jerk!
Darn it. There are a lot of them.
Where are you? Come out.
What are you looking at?
Help.
- Hold out. - I can't hold out anymore.
Wait, wait.
Move.
Hey, take this!
Darn it.
Take this.
Jang Do Jang.
You...
You jerk.
(Queen of Mystery)
(A complete victory for the experienced detective)
It must be a thief.
Things keep disappearing.
Check it again.
We're busy, you know.
My calculations aren't wrong.
Then it must've been your employee.
I called you to catch the culprit.
There's no evidence.
How can I catch the culprit...
when there's no evidence?
Did you find something?
Someone who's stealing something...
or anything suspicious.
Not yet.
Take your time then.
I'll go make a round.
What?
This is my first day of work here.
The first experience is important.
This is a great chance.
Good luck.
Well, sir...
How can you leave it up to this newbie?
Do you think it disappeared in the storage?
Only I...
have the access.
That means it disappeared in the store.
I'm telling you a thief stole it.
Then why isn't there a footage of someone stealing it?
There are so many surveillance cameras in the store.
You should find out who did it, Constable.
I'm not a constable, I'm a lieutenant.
I'm a head of a police station.
Goodness.
You're the new head?
I thought he was.
You look so young though.
You don't even look 30.
I'm not.
Stop.
Who are you?
This employee is strange.
Who? Which one?
This guy? He's my son.
He looks after the store when I'm not here.
He is very nervous.
Look. His body is tense.
Maybe he's tired?
He isn't like that other times.
So what?
My son is a bit timid.
Whenever this boy shows up, he gets tense.
He's shaking his hands a bit too.
Let's see.
She's right. He's like that on other days too.
But he doesn't look like he's stealing?
Just pay for your stuff.
Don't bother him trying to catch a thief.
That boy only uses his card to pay.
You're right.
Who pays with cash nowadays?
Everyone uses a card.
Really? Then...
I'll use my card too.
You can't pay with your library card!
Seodong District Library?
It's like this one, right?
(Seodong District Library)
- Yes. - I could tell right away...
because I go to the library often.
He used his library card to pay?
Nobody stole anything.
Your son just gave things away.
He knew he was being recorded,
so he pretended to pay with the card.
He came here only when your son was working because...
I'm home.
It's the same uniform as the boy was wearing.
Why you little... Come over here.
Darn you!
- Come over here! - Stop.
Was it you who did it?
Why did you do it? I give you allowance.
- Why? - Please! Stop!
Well...
I don't know. I'm frustrated too!
You're missing a button.
One of them is a different color.
Your shoes look big on your feet.
That's why you tie the shoelaces tight.
Where are your shoes?
I think you should talk to his teacher.
Maybe someone is bullying your son.
I didn't know because I was too busy working.
We have a school violence prevention team,
so don't worry.
Sir. Please help.
Will you give me a discount?
(Queen of Mystery)
(Seol Ok, the Queen of Mystery)
Mother. Breakfast is ready.
Okay.
Where's Ho Cheol?
He has a lot of work, so he can't come home.
Poor Prosecutor.
I hope he doesn't skip his breakfast.
I'm leaving.
Won't you have breakfast?
She doesn't eat breakfast?
Since when?
Since high school.
Bye, Seol Ok.
See you.
She's missing out.
It's too salty.
How will you open a store with this cooking skill?
I tried. Is it bad?
Won't you eat more?
No. I'm late.
Where are you going?
Do you think I'm an old lady who stays at home?
I have a seminar.
Have a good day.
Are you going somewhere today?
I'll go to the side dish store.
Okay.
Don't chitchat with classless women.
You'll embarrass your husband if you do.
Yes, Mother. Enjoy your seminar.
Okay.
- I'm sorry. - Gosh.
You all owe me one.
- Goodness. - I win.
Got it.
How's your daughter-in-law?
My daughter-in-law?
Think about it. She's a young thing.
You never know.
They seem to be doing really well.
They go grocery shopping and have tea together.
They don't go grocery shopping together.
I saw her together with a tall man.
A tall man?
He had a nice complexion.
Yes, he had great skin.
And he...
- smiles with his eyes. - That's right.
He looked young.
He looked like a college student from behind.
Isn't it Officer Hong?
(Police Substation)
This is Officer Hong.
You're on your way?
Okay. Where should I meet you?
People could see us, so I'll meet you at the locker.
There's a reason.
Yes, Officer Hong. I'll see you soon.
Stop. I win.
There.
You lose.
Gosh.
Why would she date a police substation officer?
Her husband is a prosecutor.
Don't you know prosecutors are above police officers?
That has nothing to do with cheating.
Cheating? Not everyone can cheat.
She has no education, no money.
She doesn't even have a good background.
She's lucky to have a prosecutor husband.
Men won't fall for her.
You don't know anything.
(Gyung Mi)
- Hello? - It's me.
If my mother-in-law comes by...
What should I tell her?
Make something up.
We both have to. Your mother-in-law's too sharp.
Say I went to get ingredients.
Why are you going to get ingredients?
I'm seeing Officer Hong again.
Really?
You're enjoying this.
This is too dangerous.
You can't dupe your mother-in-law...
I don't care. I don't care.
I'm so excited.
Try and think if there's anything fishy.
Don't regret when it's too late.
Your daughter-in-law has been going out a lot.
What?
That's because...
Does she take calls on the balcony in secret?
That's a sign.
That too.
No problem. They usually go in threes.
She has a friend who owns a lunchbox place.
Business seems to be booming.
She goes there every day to learn how to cook.
But her cooking never really improves.
It's salty.
Seol Ok? It's me.
Ask where she is.
Would you tell the truth if you were her?
Where are you?
The lunchbox place?
Okay. See you later.
She said she's at the lunchbox place.
You can't believe that.
Shall we go over there?
Yes, let's. I was getting bored of playing cards.
Let's continue next time.
- Let's go. - Come along.
She said she's at the lunchbox place.
- What an idiot. - Let's go and check.
I'll go and check the site.
The Bangtan Market locker case?
- I'll come with you. - No.
You must have a lot to do. Stay here.
What is he trying to do?
Don't you think he's like Sherlock Holmes?
The missing parcel case and the phone theft case.
Cases that even...
- detectives can't... - He just got lucky.
Getting on his good side won't earn you a promotion.
Don't waste your energy.
Are you going somewhere?
To patrol.
To check the sauna, more like.
Did she go to get groceries?
See? I told you something smelled fishy.
You just wait. I'll check for you.
Is that the police substation?
What are you going to do?
Wait and see.
Is Officer Hong in?
He's on patrol? Where to?
Bangtan Market?
They must be together.
What are you saying?
Why would Seol Ok be with him?
He went to Bangtan Market. Let's go.
Why would we go there?
To check if they are together.
What if they aren't?
Then they aren't together.
- Right. - We can get snacks while we're there.
The rice cakes the hunchback granny makes?
They're the real deal.
Aren't they?
The lady makes them with herbs she gathered herself.
Shall we go mugwort-picking when it's warmer?
It's from the left.
You don't need gloves.
We already checked for prints.
Hello.
Just in case the case is reopened.
The prints are all smudged or overlapping.
They won't be helpful.
The lockers are in the middle of the market.
I keep my bags here when they're heavy.
Do you live nearby?
No.
What a lot of effort.
I didn't do much. I just...
A waste of effort.
What?
I really didn't do anything.
The thief, I mean. He tried too hard.
Do you see something already?
I see a waste of energy and time.
A waste?
An unfocused and complicated method.
He's an amateur.
A professional wouldn't be so obvious.
A professional would break into a locker...
swiftly and easily.
He'd get a copy of a locker key...
and alter it to make a master key.
So he uses the master key to open the other lockers?
Yes.
Then I shouldn't look up people with similar records.
He's a complete novice.
He's never broken into a locker before.
At first, he thought it would be easy.
He put something sharp and pointed into the keyhole.
When it didn't open,
he used something else.
Something like a crowbar.
He forced it open with brute strength.
He must be strong...
if he warped the steel door.
He got better as he went along.
He opened the rest with much less effort.
Your right. The last locker just popped open.
He got better at it as he went from left to right.
So the criminal...
He opened them in order.
Why do you think he stopped halfway?
Who guards these lockers?
The market stalls, lockers,
and office are guarded by two security guards.
They go on patrol at 7pm after the market closes.
By the time they circle the whole market,
it's about an hour later.
Then the guards on patrol startled him.
They appeared before he was done.
Then it all makes sense.
The guard noticed nothing strange at midnight.
He found the lockers like this at 1am.
The criminal couldn't finish it in an hour.
What happened?
What did the criminal take?
That's the odd part.
He didn't touch the cash.
He left the money?
After all that hard work?
Yes. He left a laptop, MP3 player,
and a luxury brand wallet.
Is nothing missing at all?
No. Some ingredients for memorial service food,
powdered formula, and a ginseng gift set was stolen.
Why would anyone steal that?
That's what I don't get.
What could it be for?
I think the thief is...
Is?
Someone who, despite being poor,
never ever considered stealing...
because he's a decent person.
His father's death anniversary's coming up,
but the son had no money.
That's when he came across these lockers.
Do people use baby formulas for a memorial service?
Well...
This little boy...
had an older brother...
who got hurt while working at a construction site.
That is why he had to raise his baby niece or nephew.
The baby formula was for them.
What about the ginseng gift set?
He must've been living with his mother.
An unemployed young man who works to provide...
for his young nephew and mother...
would be in need of cash, not these.
You're right. You can buy these with money.
Why did he steal them?
This is definitely an amateur.
Don't you think some kids trashed this?
They didn't need it. They just did it for fun.
It's like stealing for fun.
No. Kids couldn't have done this.
This person isn't a professional,
but this person controlled...
the scene too well to be an amateur.
Then...
It's definitely an adult.
An adult?
A very...
dangerous adult.
- Let's take a break. - Yes.
Just once more.
I can't do it.
- My legs hurt. - Let's sit.
You can't sit anywhere on the streets.
- My gosh. - My legs hurt.
Goodness, my legs are giving out.
Hey, did you hear that?
Someone robbed the lockers.
A thief?
That's scary.
Let's carry our stuff around no matter how heavy it is.
Look at those two men...
with rough faces. Who are they?
They look like troublemakers.
- Are they thugs? - Quiet.
Could they be the thieves?
They would've run away already. They won't be here.
She's right.
Goodness, my beautiful face. Darn it.
Here's your coffee.
- Hey. - Yes?
My stitches ruptured.
I think it's infected.
- Give me the ointment. - The ointment?
That man.
This guy.
I can't see his face.
I have another one here.
Right here and here.
You're right. These are the same person.
He doesn't look like a type who shops for groceries.
Let's see.
Is this a thug?
He has a lot of scars on his face.
He's probably the action head.
Bosses these days don't do anything that harms them.
He does seem suspicious, lurking around the area.
Do you think he's our man?
You can take him in and interrogate him.
That'll be hard to do.
Why?
The office wants me to wrap this up.
It's not like this is a huge criminal case.
Such petty robbery won't bump up our performance.
It's not a petty robbery.
Did you find something?
This is...
Yes, this is?
a drug case.
What?
Let's go.
Wasn't it hot?
It's cool.
It's cool? That was hot.
Let's go.
So weird.
My back hurts.
That's odd. They said he went to the market.
Was it Bangtan Market? Isn't it Baebang Market?
I'm sure they said he went to a market, but...
Isn't this a police car?
It is.
- We found the right place. - We did.
We don't have to walk anymore.
We can wait in front of this car.
Oh, right.
I forgot to buy some rice cakes at the market.
- Let's go and get them. - Okay.
What if Officer Hong gets here before you return?
In that case, you can wait here.
I'll go and get them.
We have to have rice cakes when we're here.
- You're right. - I'll be back.
- Take some money. - I've got some.
- Okay then. - Let's sit here.
My goodness.
It was a hard day.
They robbed the locker from the left to the right...
and from the top to the bottom strategically.
Will kids plan this out for fun?
So diligently?
But none of the things missing are worth any money.
What he robbed are food ingredients for a ritual.
What did he take?
Give me a second.
He took frying powder to make pancakes,
starch, and flour.
What will kids do with those?
Teenagers are already full of energy.
Why would they want ginseng gift set so much?
He's an amateur when it comes to theft...
and he doesn't care about things or money.
If it's not about money or a prank,
why did he rob the lockers?
He was looking for something.
Looking for something?
Something so precious that's worth more than money.
Something so big.
Something so big?
Officer Hong, this is a drug case.
This is not an adult entertainment district.
Why would anyone put drugs in a market?
This is a delivery failure.
It's got something to do with drug trafficking.
Have you waited for long?
- Here you are. - Oh, my.
This is warm.
Smell it.
This looks good.
Ma'am.
I thank you for assisting me with my investigation.
I fell short of expectation, but I solved the cases...
thanks to your help.
However,
I think you're way off this time.
How can it be drug trafficking?
The ginseng gift set. Were they all powders?
Yes. Ginseng powder.
Starch, baby formula, flour.
Isn't it weird?
White powder.
Flour.
People call drugs crystal or flour.
Drugs?
The thief was looking for white powder which is...
worth 300,000 dollars per 1kg.
If it's pure enough, it goes up to 350,000 dollars.
Is that why he didn't care about cash?
Why would he care about a couple hundred bucks?
But still, how can anyone leave drugs...
that are worth thousands of dollars in a market?
It was a deal.
A quiet deal of a huge dealer and a small dealer.
It's not too quiet.
But unlike their plan,
there was a delivery accident.
They lost the key.
And they lost the delivery man as well.
They cannot find out where their stuff is.
That's why they tore everything down.
If this is a real drug case...
It's probably connected with gangs.
The gang member from the surveillance camera.
(Mother)
Yes, Mother.
Oh, are you still at the side dish shop?
Of course.
Is she at the side dish shop?
I can't wait anymore. Let's leave.
I had too many rice cakes.
- I'm thirsty. - Quiet.
I see. That's good.
I'll stop by with the ladies on my way home.
What?
Goodbye.
Gangs and drugs. That makes sense.
Right?
Ma'am.
It's him.
- My goodness, thank you. - Goodness.
Well...
Thanks so much for your hard work.
- Here. Open wide. - Thank you.
Are you here to grocery shop?
We're just strolling around.
He's alone.
I told you.
It's nice to see you all being friendly.
Friendly?
My legs hurt.
Where are you heading? I'll give you a ride.
No, it's okay.
You must be busy.
Goodness.
What?
No.
Clouds float again today
On the road to Seonwangdang
Flowers bloom
(Dong Ho's Lunchbox)
Is this it?
Thank you.
Mother, you're here.
Are these your friends?
Ladies, she's my daughter-in-law's best friend.
She owns this place. Say hi.
Hello, I'm Kim Gyung Mi.
She's the divorced...
Where's Seol Ok?
I didn't see her when I passed by.
She's in the kitchen. That's why you didn't see her.
Kitchen?
Is there's a kitchen inside?
Of course. It's not outside.
Mother!
- Mother. - What are you doing?
It's cold out, isn't it?
- Gosh, stop it. - You're too cold.
- You should try the new dishes. - Out of my way.
Mother!
- Mother. - Is she here?
- Mother. - What are you doing?
- I have a headache. - So what?
- Get out of my way. - It hurts.
Well... She's not here.
Where did she go?
Tell me. Where is she?
Mother. You're here.
Yes. Someone gave me a ride.
What about your friends?
They're outside.
Are you leaving?
Yes. I just wanted to see you. Bye.
Don't you want to taste the fish?
- It's okay. - It's a huge fish.
You fried my fish for sashimi.
My gosh.
Take it out!
(Dong Ho's Lunchbox)
I paid 200 dollars for that sea bream.
And you're drinking my liquor.
You don't even pour me a glass.
What's wrong with your mother-in-law?
She watches you and meddles with you.
Why can't she leave you alone?
Because her son's a prosecutor.
How much does he make?
Does he make more than I do?
Of course not.
I paid for my sister-in-law's graduate school.
He wouldn't have become a prosecutor without you.
Thanks to him I'm a prosecutor's wife.
Thanks to him you couldn't go to college...
and your mother-in-law looks down on you.
Who says she looks down on me?
I can tell when I see it.
It's so unfair.
Still, don't get a divorce.
Why not? You said I'm pathetic.
Just don't.
Do whatever you can to hang in there.
Do you regret getting divorced?
Regret?
Hey. I'm totally free.
I'm free from the in-laws and my family kicked me out.
I can't be any freer than this.
But don't get a divorce.
You'll enjoy the freedom all to yourself?
Are you going home? We just started.
- I need to go. - Leave that.
Let me, the lonely soul, take care of herself.
By the way, you have a parcel.
Yes!
(Police Officer)
I'll start studying tomorrow.
Thanks.
I'm sorry Sea Bream.
Why do you study when you won't even apply?
It makes me relieved.
You will when you pass the exam...
and you'll have to apply to pass.
You never know. Maybe I can take the exam this year.
What if you pass the exam?
Do you think he'll say yes?
I saw yakbab out here. Can I take it?
My mother-in-law really likes it.
She thinks I made it.
She says she doesn't like what I do,
but she keeps me around because of this yakbab.
Gosh. I can't believe you're on her side.
She pretends to be refined,
but she's just a mean old granny.
She'd have a fit if I passed the exam.
You're afraid you'll pass, aren't you?
This year will be the last one.
Please bear with me.
Just go home.
Bye.
Take the yakbab.
I made it for your mother-in-law anyway.
I hope you don't get a divorce.
I know.
I love you.
Goodness. She's insane.
It was a natural sea bream.
- Goodness. - My yakbab.
Tteokbokki and fried laver roll. Take out please.
- Okay. - Give me some soup first.
Okay.
- Be careful, it's hot. - Okay.
(Baebang 2 Police Substation)
What are you doing?
Did something happen to him?
He must've fought with his girlfriend.
Does he have a girlfriend?
I'm sure he does.
Hello?
At Bangtan Market?
Yes.
Today?
That locker?
Okay. Got it.
Sir. What happened with the locker case?
Of course, it should be resolved.
Officer Hong solves...
every case he looks at.
It's more complicated than I thought.
Such a fuss over a simple theft.
It's not a simple theft.
The detectives at the station say...
some kids did it, just for fun.
They don't need you to come over.
This is drug case that's connected to gangs.
- Drugs? - Drugs?
It's just a figure of speech.
Don't take things too seriously, sir.
I'm worried for you.
Hello?
Hello, ma'am.
I'm sorry I disappeared like that.
You must've had your reasons.
You don't need to explain.
Okay. Thank you.
So...
They're replacing the lockers today.
The merchants complained that it was an eyesore.
Today? What about what's inside?
That's a problem.
We can't keep them until the owners show up.
People came forward to claim what was in the top row.
I'm worried about the rest.
I think they'll be taken to the lost and found.
I think we can find out who did it.
What?
What are you doing? Let's do the laundry.
Hello?
(Unknown number)
I wish she'd give me her number.
What's the secret call about?
It's not a secret. It was a friend.
What friend? A boyfriend?
All Gangnam women have one these days.
Shall we do the laundry?
Yes.
Everything feels damp.
Let's wash them while the weather's nice.
All these?
It's nothing for two housewives.
Gosh, I'm exhausted.
Two housewives?
Mother, don't we need some groceries?
There's nothing to eat.
Make bibimbap with the leftovers.
Why go shopping?
Don't waste precious daylight.
Strip the covers first.
Okay.
Mother, don't you need to use the toilet?
Why? So you can call your friend back?
I'm very constipated.
I'll be in there a long while.
Do you want to go first?
I ate so little there's nothing to expel.
Just when I'm about to poop, if someone knocks,
it goes back up inside.
Okay. Go and get things done.
I'll go to the bathroom then.
Okay.
Wait.
Air the bathroom well afterward.
What was in there a while tends to stink.
Okay.
There's another reason they're against the pipeline.
The thief will come back...
to collect his things.
It's too much to give up on.
When?
- Today. - Today?
It'll get harder once the lockers are replaced.
He'll have to reveal himself at the lost and found.
If he couldn't get his things back then,
he will return today.
What if he did?
Then he won't show up.
But you can still catch him.
I can catch a thief who won't show up?
You'll catch the accomplice.
How can we catch...
The person who put things in the locker.
Bingo. One of them is the accomplice.
- I'll head over right away. - See you there.
No, it could be dangerous. Stay at home.
It's more dangerous for me here.
What?
Never mind. See you at the market.
Okay then.
Do you need all that to go on a patrol?
Just in case.
Are you going to Bangtan Market?
Somewhere nearby.
I think you're going to see the wrecked lockers.
Is it really a drug-related case?
I'm crazy curious.
We'll find out soon.
Could you please take me with you?
I found the lost cat,
sent the drunk man home,
and broke up a scuffle.
I'm not busy at all.
He didn't break into the rest of the lockers.
But...
one locker's claimed.
Is this the one?
People came forward to claim what was in the top row.
I'm worried about the rest.
How odd. Why is the key missing?
Is it being used?
The market's closed,
and the lockers will be replaced tonight.
This is the perfect time.
Where can I hide?
What is taking her so long?
Is she still in the bathroom?
How long will she be in there for?
Did she go somewhere?
Hold on a second.
Will her poop go back inside?
I'm a mother-in-law...
who worries about my daughter-in-law's constipation.
There's no way we can wash the beddings today.
It's freezing.
Why is it raining? I don't have an umbrella.
The shower won't last long.
Wait and see.
Jang Do Jang will come back here.
I really need to go.
- What? - I have to go.
How many times has this been?
Wear a diaper, will you?
My goodness.
- Get lost. - What?
Go home.
- I'll wait. - Go.
I'll wait for you at the entrance.
He's so unreliable.
Officer, I think the thief's here.
What was that?
Lady! Stop right there!
- Save me! - Get her!
Get her! She's the accomplice!
She's the one we're after!
- Go after her! - What?
Save me! Someone help me!
Are you sure about this?
Get her!
Officer Hong.
Are you okay?
- Who are they? - Why are the police here?
- Get them. - What?
- Maybe it isn't her. - This got complicated.
I'm fine. Get the thieves.
- Forget it. Let's get out of here. - What?
Run! Faster!
Hurry up.
It hurts.
Not that way. Let's go this way.
Wait, wait.
Let me sort this out.
Don't get too excited.
I won't.
Don't move!
Wait.
- Hands up. - Calm down.
- Let's do this peacefully. - Hands up!
What do you think you're doing?
Seodong Police Station, Ha Wan Seung...
What are you two doing here?
Are there really drugs in the locker?
How do you know that?
The thief will return tonight.
That's why you shouldn't be here in uniform!
I respect you, sir.
Don't respect him.
We put so much work into this...
and you might have ruined it!
Shoot.
Help him up.
You idiots.
Here it is. I found it.
My heart's still racing.
Why was I so shocked?
I was hiding to catch the thief.
Why was I so surprised to see him?
But then, he did look a bit...
You came back in time.
They're replacing the lockers tonight.
You must use your fists a lot.
Are you a boxer?
I don't think you wear gloves.
You must fight a lot with your bare hands.
Are you looking for something?
It's not that one.
It's 46.
That's the key you have.
It's a master key.
You opened 46, 47, and 48.
I bet it opens 49 as well.
It's not what you're looking for.
Could it be in 49?
You worked hard for nothing last time.
Did you get some expert help this time?
Calm down.
They fixed the surveillance camera.
I'll leave you alone.
I'm not with the police.
I was just at the market when...
Shoot.
(Queen of Mystery)
I'm Seodong's Drug Sniffer.
They put the stash all in one place...
and were dealing for the location.
Let's get them.
The Yakuza always pays up.
I'll get them on the scene. In person.
Let's stake them out.
Yes. You shouldn't be doing this.
You scumbag.
Who are you? Why were you hiding there?