Previously on Miracles.
I hope you feel better soon.
Write it down exactly as you saw it.
Six people in the past 25 years have witnessed this phenomenon.
My organization has interviewed them all.
But in every case, they have seen something significantly different.
Everyone's got parents. I just never knew mine.
For God's sake, it's killing him!
He healed people, I saw it.
He died healing me.
Help us.
- It's real.
- The darkness?
It wants..
What does it want?
Everything.
Wait! Tommy!
Look, I think what we've been doing is wrong.
Maybe it's better if we just..
call it quits.
People are getting hurt.
I dont want to do this anymore!
Please, don't make me do this. There's gotta be another way.
Okay.
Okay, you're right. You're right.
Just tell me when to go.
Who is it?
Mister Menagian- your landlord sent me out.
He's my uncle. I help him out sometimes after school.
What's the problem?
Uh, we're changing all the shower heads.
Putting in low-flow no extra charge to you.
What about my dishwasher? It's been leaking for a month.
He just said shower heads.
I've called five times. You want to come in? Dishwasher's first.
So, I guess I better move it out.
Are you new at this?
Kind of.
I don't mean to ruin your day, it's just..
when I don't even get a call back, it sort of turns into a thing, you know?
What?
Nothing.
I'm gonna need some help.
She was strangled with the tape measure.
- Detective Krantz.
- Yeah?
You better see this.
What have you got?
This is her journal.
So, who the hell is Paul Callan?
S01E06 Hand of God
Subs by Nixie & SubRaccoon
That's it. I'm done.
See you later.
Good game.
You work here?
More like a indentured servant.
Former resident too?
Father Calero says good things.
I didn't get your name.
Victor Krantz, Boston P.D.
Guess you already know mine.
Yes. Yes, I do.
Calero says that you're a guy that likes to help out.
You know a woman named Gretchen Albright?
No.
She's dead.
Sorry to hear that.
She was murdered in her kitchen around six o'clock last night.
Is there a reason you're telling me this?
Yep.
I suppose you want to know what I was doing around 6 o'clock last night.
Why not?
That's gonna be difficult.
I was hoping you wouldn't say that.
Where is easy, 1898 Keystone Street in Weymouth, an old victorian house.
Why is tricky.
Give it a shot.
I'm sitting alone in the dark, waiting for the walls to talk.
No kidding.
It's part of my job.
If you've got 3 or 4 hours, I could give you the short version.
People I work with, we investigate strange things.
I'm not liking what I'm hearing.
If it helps, I didn't kill anyone.
Maybe it does.
Oh, do the words "God is Nowhere" mean anything to you?
No.
Save some time tomorrow.
I'd like the long version.
Hi, kids.
Who is Gretchen Albright?
Don't you mean, who was Gretchen Albright?
Apparently, she was murdered last night.
The police have been here too?
Who do you think told them where you were?
A heads-up would have been nice.
Yes, and counter-productive.
The police can tell when you're expecting them.
It leads them down certain unfortunate mental paths.
Who was she, Keel?
Three years ago, Gretchen Albright was preparing a cake
for her youngest daughter's second birthday.
The glass mixing bowl that she was using
shattered in the sink, and she cut her hand.
Guests were arriving, so she wrapped a dishcloth
around the wound, and she went to greet the guests.
A few minutes later, she returned to the kitchen.
And it was then that she noticed the dishcloth.
And the words "God is Nowhere"
were scrawled in her own blood.
Detective Krantz asked me about that phrase.
What did you say?
I lied.
I'm not even sure why. I guess I was scared.
They probably saw the words in her personal effects,
journals, letters..
How did he connect the phrase to you?
They Googled "God is Nowhere", found an old article I'd written
in 1996 on hemography for "The Journal of Psychical Research"
Detective Krantz wanted to know what the phrase meant.
I said I thought it was rather self-explanatory.
If he talked to you, why would he need to talk to me?
He was being thorough, I suppose.
Why am I different?
What do you mean?
You interviewed six people like Gretchen.
They all saw "God is Nowhere" written in their own blood.
I saw "God is now here".
Why?
It's the kind of message that reveals the reader.
Isn't it?
Maybe. Maybe I read it wrong.
Where did Keel take off for?
He's out at Phycis lecture at Boston University
with some old friends.
He has friends?
Apparently there's some late breaking news
about the creation of the universe.
You didn't wanna go?
Well, sometimes I do, the lectures are fun,
but you know Alva, strip clubs till dawn.
You working late?
Yeah, I'm looking for the hemography files.
Alva keeps those in his office.
Really? Why?
I don't know.  I think he's been working on them.
Good night.
- Say hi to Matty.
- Thanks, I will.
So.. you broke in.
You lied to me!
If you wanted a key, you could've asked.
Every one of those six people who saw "God is Nowhere"
in their blood also saw me.
One of them even dreamed about my father.
Of course, you know all of this...
That glass is going to be difficult to..
Why didn't you tell me?!
It wasn't necessary.
I joined up with you to find answers..
answers you had right here in your files all along.
- And you found them.
- That's not all I found.
I spent a few hours tracking these people down, Keel.
Four of them are dead.
Dead?
Murdered, different ways, and all in the last week.
Gretchen Albright was the most recent.
You didn't know this.
No.. I did not.
Have you told the police any of this?
Not yet, but I will.
They haven't made the connection. I..
I figure it's better if they hear it from me first.
This could become very dangerous for you, Paul.
I think it already has.
Come in.
What the hell happened between you and Alva?
I show up, and there's broken glass everywhere.
He's not talking. What gives?
He's been lying to me since day one.
What are you talking about?
The "God is Nowhere" people, they've all dreamed about me in detail.
Real things. It's like they know my whole life,
even though we've never met and now they're being murdered.
Oh, my god.
I tried to track down the last two to warn them.
Danielle Franklin in Denver and some other guy.
His name was Kenneth Webster, but according to Keel's files,
he's changed his name and disappeared.
This doesn't make sense. Why would Alva keep all this from you?
I have no idea.
I just left a message for the police, told them everything I know,
but I think I may be the only one that can stop this.
So, where are you going?
Denver. He's already killed four people in five days.
Danielle Franklin's probably next, and she hasn't returned my calls.
Paul, this is crazy! You have no idea who is doing this or why.
For all you know, you could be on his list too.
Maybe I am.
You know, whether I like it or not, I'm linked to these people.
I feel like I need to be with them.
Why?
Because I know what it's like to be alone
in the middle of things.
Maybe I can answer some of Danielle's questions and..
maybe she can answer some of mine.
She knows my father.
Or she might.
In the transcripts I found in Keel's office,
she talks about three dreams she had.
The first is about me getting pneumonia when I was seven.
That happened. Back at St. Jerome's,
I spent two weeks in the hospital, almost died.
Second is about me getting in a car accident
and being healed by a boy.
She had that dream in 1983.
That's the third.
A man whose name is Paul Callan
is sitting at a table at a sidewalk cafe.
There's a fountain behind him. He's talking to a man.
That man is his father.
The man is saying something. Paul is angry. And then..
the water in the fountain turns red.
I've never even met my father.
I don't know a single thing about him.
Paul, if this woman knew anything more,
wouldn't it be in there, in those transcripts?
I don't know, Evie. She saw what I saw.
She's had dreams that have come true.
Can I tell Alva you're in Denver?
Don't tell anyone.
I don't like this, Paul.
I know.
Can I help you?
Yeah, um... I need a gun.
Okay, what are you looking for?
What's that?
That one? It's a Desert Eagle Jericho semi-auto.
That one next to it, that's a Glock 23, .40 caliber.
Wow. Okay, I guess that one.
The Jericho.
Need some ammo with that?
Yeah, I do.
How old are you?
19.
This is out-of-state.
Sorry, but according to federal law, I cannot sell you a handgun.
Would you like a rifle?
Have you seen Paul?
Paul says that you had information about him
that you deliberately withheld. Is that true?
- Yes, it is.
- Why?
Because Paul is on a spiritual journey,
this is something few of us undertake, and as in Paul's case,
it is not that one chooses, rather, one is chosen.
Well, that's very pretty. Why did you lie?
Evie, I'm sure you've read reports claiming that violent crime
on a worldwide basis is dropping.
Right.
But the actual level of random violence in the world is rising dramatically
child abduction by strangers, sniper attacks, suicide bombings.
Many, if not all of those people, claim to do their work
at the request of a higher being.
I was a cop! People kill people because they're drunk
a lot more often than because God tells them..
That may be true, Evie.
But Paul's particular problem isn't booze.
If Paul is in any sort of danger because of all this,
you had no right to keep that information from him.
What would you have me tell him?
That he's capable of great good or great evil?
The worst thing that could possibly happen is for Paul
to somehow believe that his path is predestined for evil.
Once that idea's been planted, it's almost impossible to uproot.
So, let's plant the idea that he's predestined for good.
Oh, but even those who walk the path of light
often come to a bad end.
J.F.K., Martin Luther King, Joan of Arc even John Lennon.
What if Paul tried to.. get involved with these people now?
We don't know.. who this killer is.
We don't know why he's striking now. We know nothing.
If there were anything to be gained from getting involved,
I'd be doing it.
But I've never seen anything like this before.
People are being murdered simply because
they all shared a paranormal experience.
Now is a time.. for keeping one's head down.
Paul Callan's not at his apartment.
Is there a problem?
Damn right, there's a problem. He left me a message.
Said there was gonna be another murder in Colorado.
I'd just like to find out why he's so sure.
Where is he?
He's on Transnational Airlines Flight 629 for Denver.
Are you Paul Callan?
Yeah.
Will you please come with us?
I know, I know, it's just that this is all turning out
to be harder than I expected.
I got classes five days a week this semester, mom.
Weekends are wall-to-wall homework.
Gary's crazy.
He hasn't seen me because I'm in the library all day,
and he's in Vicki's room every night.
A couple, nothing serious.
I don't really have the time.
I'll try. Look, uh, ma, I gotta go.
I miss you, too.
Well, tell dad I'll try to make it back for spring break.
Love you, too. Bye.
Why exactly are you convinced Danielle Franklin is in danger?
It's not gonna make any sense.
Yeah, it already doesn't.
Someone is murdering people who have all had a..
similar experience.
It's not a normal thing. It's a..
it's a thing called hemography, words..
written in blood.
Where? At the scene of the murders?
No, not a person writing words with blood
blood forming itself into words on its own.
The catholic church considers this a possible sign of a miracle.
And each of these people have seen this, uh, "Miracle"?
So have I.
Well, I can tell you right now, Mr. Callan,
this is sounding even worse than you thought it would.
Hi, this is Danielle.
Leave a message, and I'll call you back.
Please enter your 3-digit code to retrieve all current messages.
Hello, this is Detective Peter Bander
with the Denver police department,
calling for Danielle Franklin.
Please call me back at 555-0183 as soon as possible. Thank you.
Hi, I'm calling for Danielle Franklin. My name is Paul Callan.
The police should have already contacted you, but..
I really need to speak with you myself.
I'm flying into Denver today. My cell phone is 617-555-0152.
Please call me as soon as you get this message.
I never met her. That's the point.
She doesn't even know I really exist.
Then why did you fly halfway across the country
to come see her?
- To warn her that someone..
- Someone?
Someone may be trying to kill her. I've already told you this.
And while we're sitting here, it could be happening.
- Hello.
- Hello, Paul?
Yes, this is Paul Callan.
Oh, my god! It's me, Danielle.
I can't believe it's really you.
It's really me.
Are you in town?
Yeah, I'm at the downtown police station,
the one at Everly Parkway. Do you know where that is?
Uh, yeah. I can find it.
I can't believe I'm actually talking to you.
You even sound the same.
Same as what?
As you do in my dreams.
You're okay, aren't you?
Yeah, I'm fine. Why?
Uh, no reason. It's just, um..
I, uh, I had another dream about you,
a bad one.
Get here as soon as you can, okay?
It's important that we talk.
Yeah, I think so too.
I'll be right there.
Hi.
Danielle?
What do we got?
Danielle Franklin was killed by a single rifle shot to the head.
- Was it a sniper?
- Not exactly.
The distance was only 3 feet. So far, we have no witnesses.
She's dead.
If you hadn't stopped me, I could have..
- Could have what?
- Maybe I could have saved her!
- I'd like to leave now.
- Forget it.
I can't be a suspect. I've been here the whole time.
You seem to know a hell of a lot about a murder.
Before, it was just a theory. Now it's a fact.
For all we know, you're working with this guy.
Plan on being here awhile.
Who the hell are you?
Alva Keel. I have here a writ of habeas corpus for Paul Callan
petitioned by Ed Lorenson and signed by
the Honorable Judge William Pound.
Come on.
A writ? The guy's been here less than three hours.
I hope they were productive.
I'd thank you for getting me out of there
if you weren't the reason I was there in the first place.
As the matter of fact it was Evelyn who informed the police
about your flight and I'm glad that she did. Look..
I'm sorry about Danielle Franklin.
Really? If you'd have been straight with me, she'd still be alive.
Hey, I'm glad you're still here. We just caught the guy.
Couple of uniforms picked him up a few minutes ago.
Had pocket full of Danielle Franklin's credit cards.
We've alerted Detective Krantz in Boston.
We think there might be a link to the Gretchen Albright murder too.
I don't know how we're supposed to help.
I told you I've never seen the murderer before.
Just want to make sure.
Would it be possible for one of us
to have a conversation with him?
Absolutely not.
I've never seen him before in my life.
All right, gentlemen.
Thanks for your time.
Once he gets a lawyer, I'll petition for an interview.
- With me?
- Yes, of course.
Are you coming back to Boston?
I'm not sure.
Even if I do..
Are you having second thoughts about your new job?
I think maybe you and I are looking for different things.
I mean, I know why I'm doing this.
I want to know what happened to me, why I'm seeing things.
But you, I've got no idea why you even started S.Q.,
which makes the idea of teaming up with.. What?
What?
His current name is Hector Salgado.
Who? That guy they caught?
No, Kenneth Webster, the sixth man to see the words
"God is Nowhere", the only one still alive.
I assume you're planning to track him down.
Well, I'd advise against it. There's no point.
He never reported any special information of you.
Yeah, well, maybe that's changed. His file's pretty old.
I owe you an apology.
I never should have kept that information from you.
Then why did you do it?
I just felt that it would be detrimental to you.
Maybe it will be. That's my problem.
This is the most recent information we have on Hector Salgado,
two possible addresses. It will save you the time
and me the cost of breaking back into my office.
Why are you doing this?
In my attempt not to influence events, I influenced them greatly.
Perhaps a better method would be simply to act on instinct.
I can't stop you from acting on instinct.
Santa Fe, New Mexico, or Estacada, Oregon.
It's about 30 miles southeast of Portland, a one-zip-code town.
Thank you.
Can I give you a lift to the airport?
No, I'll get a cab.
Paul, things do have meaning, and eventually, they do add up.
As a child, I never believed that. My family life was chaotic.
Like most people, I believed that life was nothing more than
a long series of unrelated accidents, leading inexorably to the grave.
- And now?
- Now I do not.
At Cambridge, I was pre-med.
I was gonna become a surgeon, just like my father.
I minored in linguistics. My senior project involved
decoding bird songs, painstakingly transcribing notes
and patterns in the utterances of the english field raven
and thereby describing the basics of their language.
I have no trouble believing that whatsoever.
I spent days wandering the moors, recording ravens
in their natural habitat, and then transcribing their sounds.
On the fifth day, the sounds were different.
As I listened to my tapes that evening, November 21, 1985,
among the bird calls, I heard other sounds,
sounds that I eventually recognized as voices.
Among them, the voice of my mother.
You're kidding.
She had a nickname for me.
"Mango," a character in a children's book, a bloodhound.
Her reading to me from that book is one of the few fond
childhood memories I still possess.
She'd been dead for over a year when I heard her voice
speak my name on that tape.
No train.
And I didn't see God's name written in my own blood.
Doesn't take much to change the course of a life.
Sometimes a single word will do it.
And that's what led you to begin Sodalitas Quaerito.
It started me down a road, and that road led me here.
It led me to you.
It led me to you, Paul.
Hi. Mr. Webster?
My name's Paul Callan.
May I come in?
So.. you're Paul Callan.
That's right.
It's a nice place.
You think?
So, you're the one they all dreamed about?
You didn't?
No. I never did.
You need to leave.
You're a lot younger than I expected.
Am I interrupting something?
Yeah, he's gonna be here any second. You shouldn't be here,
unless you want to help.
I can help, whatever you need.
No, no, you have to leave.
If you're worried about the man who's been killing the others
you can relax.
The police arrested him in Denver a few hours ago.
No, they didn't.
Trust me. I've been in close contact
with the police for the last few days.
Get out.. now.
What are you doing in my house?
No!
Oh, God.
This is unit 11. We have two suspects in custody.
Ten-four. The ambulance is on its way.
I know who you are, Paul.
Who am I?
Tommy comes to me, too.
I almost finished it. I mean..
It's over for me. I know that.
I will never spend another free day as long as I live.
I've got to know it wasn't all for nothing.
I've got to know I did the right thing. I did.. didn't I, Paul?
I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
You've got to know.
Because it's up to you now.
The voice told me about them all.
A voice told you to do all this?
God's voice.
I know it's him because he told me he's here.
I saw it written in my own blood.
Just like you, Paul, "God is Now Here."
We're the good ones, right?
Man, we have to be or..
Oh, man, wait till my mom finds out.
You saw the words too.
Yeah.
Six months ago.
And then that kid, Tommy, he said he knew you.. or would.
And then a few weeks ago, God's voice came on inside my head.
He told me about the nine people who saw the words all wrong.
Every time I closed my eyes, he showed me
what they were going to do.. to everyone.
Now it's up to you, Paul.
Nine people?
There's three more out there.
Tommy calls them "The Darkness."
And god made it so clear,
"kill them all.. before they can get their act together."
I never knew God talked like that.
You shouldn't have stopped me back there, Paul.
Because if Ken Webster isn't dead, then that leaves four for you.
I hate this. I hate this. Oh, god, I'm so scared.
No.
Don't! Look out!
Now it's up to you, Paul.
- No.
- Tell my mom I'm sorry.
Apparently, two pounds makes all the difference.
The iron he used was graphite..
made in the last five years weighs two pounds, tops.
Go back to the irons our moms used..
real irons.. five pounds easy.
You'd be dead.
How's Mr. Webster?
He's in intensive care.
But we're hoping for a full recovery.
Either way, you saved his life.
We're done.
Let go.
Hey! Get off of him!
You took a few days off. That's healthy.
I understand that you were standing right there when it happened.
You saw it all.
Yeah, I did.
Before he killed himself..
Did the two of you talk?
A little.
What did he say?
Nothing. He was out of his mind.
I take it that you've decided to stay on.
No, I haven't.
So, what have you got?
Apparently, there's a Roshi at the Zen Center in Providence,
Rhode Island, who's recently developed the ability to levitate.
Two of his students have witnessed this event, and, um,
they actually say that he's attained a height of 19 inches
and is able to sustain this height for over.. one hour.
Subs by Nixie & SubRaccoon