What's your poison?
Tequila.
- No lime, no salt.
- Coming right up.
Man, I never saw anybody drink tequila
like that and still read the Bible.
It's exactly the kind of medicine
this town needs.
- You know what I mean?
- I know exactly what you mean.
Look, you fucking loser.
You owe us two grand.
We want our fucking money.
- Hit him!
- Pay up, fool!
Asshole!
Quit messing around
and pay us our damn money.
Back off, man. It's none of your business.
God damn it, get out of the way,
or we're going to beat you, too.
Hey, mister. Step back.
- That was good.
- Shit.
Hey, mister. Thanks a lot. I'm Billy.
Which way to the cemetery?
Up that way. Over the bridge.
You can't miss it.
My... My hat, mister.
My condolences.
I guess I could say a few words
for our dearly departed brother
from the book of Samuel.
"The Lord brings death and makes alive,
"he brings down to the grave and raises up.
"The Lord sends poverty and wealth,
he humbles, he exalts.
"He raises the poor from the dust,
and the needy from the ash heap,
"he seats them with princes
"and has them inherit a throne of honor."
Amen.
Excuse me.
You read from the Bible.
It was very kind of you.
Thanks.
You got a minute?
I'd like to introduce you to the family.
This is my father, White Deer.
And this is my son, Junior.
This is my daughter, Kiowa.
Everybody loved JJ.
Did you serve together?
- You could say that.
- Were you in his unit?
'Cause I don't see you in the pictures.
- You know, they say he drowned in a river.
- Yeah, right.
Take your hat off.
There's a heck of a nice bike out there.
Who does that belong to, you?
I don't believe we've met. John Reno.
A pleasure.
Are you... You a friend of JJ's, are you?
Yeah, well, he's a good man.
You going to stay with us long?
Maybe.
Well, I heard about
your little adventure in town, there.
Trying to help that druggie kid out?
I got to tell you, it's no offense,
but you're wasting your time.
Ain't much of your business.
Anyway, you need anything,
you let me know, all right?
You said you were from up north,
is that right?
Boy, boy, he's talking to you.
Peace, brother.
This is a time for mourning, not fighting.
Murph, not yet.
Let go of me.
And don't you ever touch me again.
Easy, darling, I'm not going to hurt you.
Prettiest girl in town,
won't give me the time of day.
How you figure that, Murph?
Look, I'm all broke up about JJ,
just like you are. He's a friend of mine.
Besides, I... I just want to warn you...
A lot of bad things happening
in this town to people right now,
especially folks who don't
mind their own business.
You understand? Saddle up, fellas.
Come see me at the dealership.
Hi, there. What can I get you, mister?
- I guess l'll settle for a room.
- Okay. Well, let's see.
Since we only get a few customers
each week, I think we can fit you in.
- Staying long?
- How much for a week?
Okay. Well, let's see. That's 50 bucks a day,
and one day free
for our seven-day special rate.
Let's call it an even 300.
You must be here for the funeral.
JJ was a good man. Great carpenter.
Used to help me with the little things
around here, whenever he had the time.
201.
If you need anything, just let me know.
Will do.
- Is that him?
- No fucking way.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, that's him.
That motherfucker.
Who's he think he's messing with?
Back off, hound dog.
- He's at the hotel, boss.
- He's at the hotel.
Why don't you thrill me
with your analysis, Murph.
What do you think he is? ATF, Fed, what?
It's kind of hard to tell.
The folks down at the funeral
said he's pretty harmless.
I mean, he reads the Bible, drinks tequila.
Pretty much keeps to himself.
I see.
He took us by surprise, boss.
It's not going to happen again.
It better not happen again.
So from now on,
it's just going to be business as usual
here on this great reservation.
Yeah, right. Business as usual, boss.
You just keep a goddamn eye
on our mystery man.
- What?
- The biker with the fucking Bible, Gomez.
Pay attention.
I want you to put a couple of men on him.
Especially tonight.
I don't want any problems,
not with this shipment,
and I don't want people thinking
I'm starting to lose my grip
on this miserable excuse for a town.
You understand?
- Sure thing, boss.
- Murph? Murph?
- Yes, sir, boss.
- Good.
Come on, Reno. Come over here and ride me
like the cowboy I know you are.
I'm here, darling. I'm going to saddle you up
like a quarter horse.
Shaved just like I like it.
You taste like a peach.
Heard you were a friend of JJ's.
- That's right.
- Well, that's real nice.
Funeral's over. He's dead and buried.
So what are you still doing here?
I've got my eyes on you. Remember that.
Stay out of trouble.
Oh, my lovely young bird.
Hurt, angry, lonely and nowhere to fly.
He didn't drown.
JJ knew something about Reno.
Oh, sweetheart,
I know how close you were to JJ.
He was like a father to you.
But you have to think
of the rest of the family now.
We have to be careful. Reno can do just
about anything he wants to in this town.
He didn't drown.
You're upset about JJ, huh?
Do you really think
that Reno tried to kill him?
- It's crazy.
- I just can't take it anymore.
But, Kiowa, if that happened to him because
of what we're trying to do, what about us?
JJ was right.
I mean, other Tribal Council members
might be on Reno's side.
That's crazy.
Let's see what happens. I bet JJ was right.
The Council meeting is getting ready
to start, so everyone come in.
Welcome, everyone.
This Tribal Council is in session.
We are finally ready to decide on two
proposals for this Council from last month.
I wanted to postpone
today's meeting, because of JJ.
We all loved him. He was one of the most
respected members of this Council.
Assistant Chief Lance suggested
we still discuss the Gaming 3 proposal.
The Tribal Council has carefully studied
and weighed the advantages
and disadvantages of both proposals.
We've had a proposal for the building
of a casino on the Tribal property,
by Lance's construction group.
This proposal would bring many new jobs
and much revenue for our people.
However, I'm very concerned with the many
negative aspects of this proposal.
For now, there's a very innovative
on-line gaming alternative,
proposed by the late JJ,
his sister Nancy and their family.
This proposal offers
more highly-skilled jobs
and training for our people,
and takes advantage of the gaming profits
without the negative aspects.
I will recommend this proposal
to the Council.
- And as you all know, my veto counts.
- Dan, we need to rethink this.
There is too much money on the table
for this tribe to lose.
I'm sorry. My decision is final.
- This is ridiculous.
- Yeah. Yeah, I know.
Don't worry about it. L'll take care of it.
So, how was everything?
Not bad.
Well, I don't know how to say this,
- but you don't look like a mean, old biker.
- Now, why is that?
For starters, you wear
funny-looking reading glasses,
and you read the Bible, and drink tequila.
And just the way you talk and treat people.
I heard about that fight this morning.
It's a really nice thing you did
for that kid, Billy, and all.
- So I don't want to be prying, but...
- Then don't.
Hey, dude. Dude, come here.
I heard you were still here, man.
I'm just... Just thought
I'd let you know that... There was...
Those guys you beat up, man?
They work for this guy, Reno.
The guy runs the whole town.
He's got everybody scared.
You know what I mean...
Reno, huh?
Yeah, man. These guys, they...
They drowned somebody in the river,
if you know what I mean.
I know exactly what you mean.
- You want some coffee?
- No.
- So what's on your mind?
- Everybody's favorite citizen, Reno.
- We have to do something about him.
- Well, it ain't that simple.
The last time I tried to have an investigation,
it was called off quickly, by that judge.
JJ's drowning was no accident.
Nancy, we're all going to miss JJ,
but accusing Reno
is not going to bring him back.
And it's only going to cause
more problems for you.
Come on, Sheriff.
Now, you be careful.
Stay out of Reno's way,
because he's a very dangerous man.
Come back anytime.
You have a nice day, okay?
That's it?
That's it.
Now, when I was a boy,
the government came and took me away
from my mother and dad,
and put me in what they call
a residential school.
They cut my hair off. My hair was long.
And I couldn't speak my language.
If I spoke my language, they would beat me.
That's why a lot of people my age
can't speak our language anymore,
because it was beaten out of us.
I am looking at the eagle up there.
You share the same fate.
You are destined to soar free,
above all others,
carried by the wind
and feared by those below.
Now, in our culture, four is a sacred number
because everything grows in fours.
The seed, the branches
and the fruit and the leaves.
And when we pray, we pray to the Creator,
we pray in four directions.
And the four winds come in four directions.
So four is a very sacred number for us.
Don't worry about it.
Mom will take care of it.
- You coming?
- I'm going to wait here.
Hey, there. L'll just take some of these.
So that day my Uncle JJ drowned,
he came here first, right?
- So what?
- I'm just asking.
Look...
He came in, got a case of beer.
And the Sheriff has already
asked me about that.
They said he was drunk when he drowned.
- Yeah, I heard.
- You know he didn't drink.
Who was the beer for, then? Reno?
'Cause Reno drinks beer.
- Hey, was Reno with him that day?
- Look, I'm busy.
- You're such a loser.
- You want to pay for that?
Good afternoon, miss.
Can I help you with those candy bars?
I heard that you
were at the Tribal Council meeting today.
What did the old fools have to say?
Anything interesting?
Hey, just let him go.
I asked you a question, little lady.
Anything interesting?
Yeah.
But it's above your kindergarten education.
That's wasn't very nice.
You need to tell
your mother something for me.
She needs to drop
that idiotic gaming proposal of hers.
Hey, that's none of your business.
Just let him go.
He's just fine.
- How old are you, sweetheart?
- Fifteen.
Nice, nice, nice.
How'd you like to come hang out at the pool
with me and the boys?
We sure would love to see you in a bikini.
Yeah... But you know what?
Maybe we don't even have to go anywhere.
Hey, hey. Come on, man.
Look, I don't think this is such a good idea.
- She's just a kid.
- What, are you going soft on us, Hoss?
Get over there and do your fucking job.
Since when did we become child molesters?
Just back off, man.
You just keep on riding, mister.
This ain't none of your business.
Everything you do from now on
is my business.
You fucking asshole.
We own this town, and the Sheriff included.
No, stop! He tried to helped me.
All right, man. Get out of here.
- I'm fine. I think so.
- Are you sure?
- L'll take you home. All right?
- All right.
You follow. Let's go.
- Why don't you come have some dinner?
- My mom's a really good cook.
Haven't had home cooking in a while,
especially not this good.
Hey, thanks for what you did.
Nobody stands up to Reno.
His family's got too many
connections in this town.
People like Reno,
you just got to stand up and fight back.
For some folks,
it's the only thing they understand.
So you travel around on your bike
all the time, and help people?
Yep. I tend to move around a lot,
and things just happen along the way.
- Doesn't it get lonely?
- Nope.
You know, you remind me so much of JJ.
- He was always helping people out.
- Yeah. And look what happened to him.
- Junior.
- Soon as I'm 18, I'm getting out of here.
There's no way I'm going to end up like him.
It's a real shame that in today's day and age,
we couldn't find the evil that took him.
My grandfather was born a free Indian,
before the reservations, before the Civil War,
before the railway, even.
Now they're poisoning our youth.
And for what? The white man's evil.
Alcohol, drugs and money.
Greed is the evil that killed my son.
He was a good warrior for our people,
and a great son.
Kiowa, honey? Why don't you
take our guest outside for some fresh air?
We can have dessert later.
And you, where's your family?
Well, my family is my friends and my faith.
Oh, and my bike.
Well, you have friends here, now.
So I guess that makes us family, huh?
It looks like it.
I know what you mean, though.
It's like you're searching for something
or someone you can never find.
You have a few years to figure it all out.
But sometimes the answer
is closer than you think.
Well, I never knew my father, you know.
JJ always took care of me,
like the father I never had.
I just miss him a lot.
It's just so unfair.
He's like here one day
and then gone the next.
I just don't understand it.
Sometimes things are better left alone,
not understood.
That's easy for you to say.
You just beat up anyone you want.
Don't you have a girlfriend?
White Deer is a wise old man.
- He's seen many things in his lifetime.
- Yeah, he likes you.
- You want to go say good night to him?
- Yeah, all right.
Put your weapons on the ground.
Put them on the ground! Now!
Nobody moves, nobody gets shot.
It's that simple.
Alex, jump down there and grab those bags.
Put them on the boat, one at a time.
Hurry! Let's go! Let's go!
Put it all on the boat, every single
one of them. Don't miss anything.
That's it.
Hold your fire, God damn it!
Boss, one's getting away!
Well, what are you looking at? Go get him!
Bullseye Bill.
Son of a bitch!
- Where's he now?
- On the way. Leave it.
- Where the hell is he?
- I think we lost him.
- The boss is going to kick our ass.
- Shut up.
What is this?
All right, that's enough.
Come on back to the boat.
Come get back here, and get on board.
Let's get out of here.
- I want to know who the runaway was.
- Sure thing, boss.
And who the hell is he?
And who else knows about the deal?
- Got some good news for you.
- That'd be a relief.
We found this.
It's pretty. What the hell is it?
Billy.
The Indian kid that owes us two grand.
Oh yeah, Billy.
Murph, I want you to take some guys
and find that runaway piece of shit,
and I want him dead. Understand?
You got it, boss.
I know just where to look for him.
Good.
Big night in Black River. It's Saturday night.
You mind if I join you?
- Go ahead. Have a seat.
- Let's do a shot first.
I've had this hotel for eight years now.
I used to hate the big city.
Now I kind of miss it.
Just trying to save enough money,
find me a good man
and get the hell out of here.
Thinking of you.
Go have a drink, have fun.
Did I buy you that outfit?
You can never spend too much
on a good-looking woman.
Right.
So what are we playing here, chief?
A little eight ball?
Stripes or solids?
No more killing.
- I cannot be involved in this anymore.
- Excuse me.
We got to be more careful.
Your methods, they're crude.
- They attract way too much attention.
- My methods, huh?
Why don't you just worry
about your end of the deal?
Let me worry about mine, okay?
Damn, I need some more limes.
L'll be right back.
Hey, little lady. Why don't you just put
that pretty little ass of yours
- down in this chair?
- And why don't you just have a seat?
- I've got to go to the kitchen.
- Better than that, how about in my lap?
- Now, come on.
- Excuse me, miss. Hold this.
- So, gentlemen, is there a problem?
- Yeah, you.
Bottom line, you know it and I know it,
is if I don't deliver this...
This casino to the boys up north
on a silver platter,
they're going to be pissed off.
And no matter what happens,
they're going to want their money.
You understand?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Corner pocket.
Yeah, I thought we had the Council with us
on that thing.
That casino deal,
that should have been ours.
Well, then why does JJ's family
control the project?
Did you or did you not tell me
if I got JJ out of the way,
the Tribal Council would be forced
to give us the project?
- Isn't that what you told me?
- Yeah, that's what I said.
All right. I hear what you're saying.
- Just let me see what I can do on it.
- Too late for that.
You see, now, I got to wipe out
the whole fucking family,
just to make my point.
That's what I'm talking about,
your methods, man.
Yeah. They're effective, every time.
Side pocket.
Thanks for coming.
I wasn't sure if you'd make it or not.
I want to show you something.
Look who decided to show up.
- Oh, good. Perfect timing.
- Hi, Dad.
So today, we have a very special guest,
and he's going to talk to us about the Bible.
So I want you to say a very friendly hello
to our family friend.
Hi.
All right. Do you know what this is?
The Bible.
I need these to see the words.
"Show me your ways, oh Lord.
"Teach me your paths.
Remember not the sins of my youth
"and my rebellious ways.
Good and upright is the Lord.
"Therefore, he instructs sinners in his ways.
"He guides the humble in what is right
and teaches them his way."
You see, the Bible, it's like a guidebook.
It helps us lead a good, honest life.
Mom, come down here! Hurry!
Oh, man, I didn't... I didn't mean to...
- I didn't know where else to go.
- Let's get him to the house.
You're lucky to be alive.
We got to get him to a clinic.
No, no, no. Wait, wait, wait a second.
Hold this.
Let's go, kids.
Go!
I knew about this drug deal going on,
down... Down by the river.
I was just hoping I could
make a score, you know?
But I didn't know Reno
was going to be there.
And I sure as shit didn't know
he was going to be killing everybody.
Shit.
Reno's guys, they were chasing me
through the woods, man.
My necklace! I lost my necklace! Fuck!
- Shit! Oh, fuck, it is them!
- Stay inside no matter what happens.
This is serious business, mister.
We don't want any trouble from you.
We're looking for an Indian, Billy.
He was shot, and we heard
he was around here somewhere.
He stole something from us.
We need to find him.
Go ahead and call the Sheriff.
You can use the phone inside.
No can do, mister. But you know that.
No, this is our problem, and
we're gonna deal with it ourselves,
the old-fashioned way.
Well, I'm sorry. Can't help you boys.
Well, it looks like we might have ourselves
a little problem here, now, don't we?
It was the kids that told us where the
bleeding Indian was by the old campground.
You should have seen
those little runts shitting themselves.
When I got a job to do,
nobody better stand in my way.
So you better back the fuck off
and move on, or else...
What you gonna do now, preacher man?
Well, I'm going to ask you
to beg the good Lord's forgiveness,
but not before I take this knee
and break that nose.
And you know what?
What?
There ain't nothing you can do about it.
Fuck you.
You don't know how to use that.
Well, that's one way of using it.
Okay! Okay! We get your point!
We get your point!
All right. Drop your pants.
- Wait a minute.
- Drop 'em!
Drop your pants. You, too. Go ahead!
Now, get out of here.
- Asshole!
- Fucker!
Be sure to take them someplace safe.
Don't worry.
Not even Reno knows of this place.
Our ancestors always spoke of a man
that would come from the north,
followed by the evil. Take care, my friend.
My prayers are with you.
This is it, isn't it?
I'm never going to see you again,
no matter what.
Sometimes it's better this way.
Let's go.
You got a choice to make.
We'll help you out.
But after you go to the doctor,
you have to testify against Reno.
Otherwise, you can go out there right now,
and deal with Reno yourself.
All right. Okay, fine. L'll do it.
Otherwise, I'm a dead man, right?
We've got an assault and battery,
here, at Route 61.
Sending in backup.
Witness reports that Reno's men were seen
leaving the area, so keep an eye out. 10-4.
Sheriff, we have Reno cold.
Billy was shot last night.
- You have what?
- You have to go and arrest him.
- He ain't exactly the best witness.
- Billy saw Reno commit murder.
Afternoon, folks.
You having a little pow-wow out here?
Hell, I wish I'd known,
I'd put an eagle feather in my hat.
- You got a van full of sick kids, Sheriff?
- What do you want, Reno?
Well, since you asked so kindly,
a couple of my men are thinking
about filing assault charges
against this one, here,
for beating the shit out of 'em.
I'm thinking about filing vandalism charges
for damage done to my vehicle
up on the Adobe Flats.
Hell, I've already talked to a judge.
Self-defense, as the Lord is my witness.
Well, let's talk about that, you and me.
Let's say we go have a drink at my bar
and talk things over.
- Sure, why not?
- Good. Follow me.
Y'all have a good afternoon.
Relax. Everybody relax.
I'm going to have a little talk
with my friend, here.
Have a little drink.
See if we can work something out.
Give me a beer.
And then give this man whatever he wants.
- Gracias.
- Tequila, straight up. No lime, no salt.
Look, here it is.
I don't give a fuck who you are
or where you came from.
I damn sure don't give a fuck
why you're here.
The way I see it, we got three options.
First is, I can just kill you now,
and be done with it.
The second, you can walk
out of this bar alive,
get on your iron horse, and ride out of town.
Never look back.
And when you're gone, you stay gone.
Third option, and for my money,
the most interesting, is
you could come to work for me.
Hell, I could use a man with your skills and
your... How did you put that, Gomez?
Your spiritual disposition.
Might even help my reputation.
What do you say?
First, your reputation is bad.
It's always going to be bad,
no matter who works for you.
Second, I don't like people that take
advantage of others for power and money.
And, third,
I don't like you, Reno.
Well, l'll take that as a "no."
Thanks for the drink.
- Don't walk away from me.
- Hold it.
Wait, wait, wait!
This holy man's day of reckoning is at hand.
Stop! I said stop, God damn it.
Nobody walks out on me.
Hold it! That's enough.
Now put your weapon down.
- Sheriff, what do you think you're doing?
- Put your gun down or l'll put you down.
Let's go find a little Indian boy to scalp.
Back in the bar. Move it.
Damn, that was stupid.
Now Reno's got me in his sights, too.
Yep.
I got to find your missing witness
before Reno does.
All right, Sheriff.
I knew you'd come back.
That's the gun they shot you with.
I got something else for you.
"All my enemies are driven back.
They shall fall and perish at thy presence."
Murphy, I'm not interrupting you, am I?
Did you make my call for me?
Yeah, yeah, I did, boss.
They'll be here tonight.
Well, good, good. That's grand.
It's about fucking time, too.
Should have done this a long time ago.
Sugar plum? Honey?
You don't mind if we
talk a little business, do you?
- All right.
- Move it!
So, what did my buddy up north
have to say?
Hurry!
Thanks for coming, partner.
Glad you're here.
The crew does look good.
I see you still got the twins with you,
and they are still riding their own material.
- Never leave home without them.
- Business going well, I take it?
- Everything going smooth up north?
- I got no problems here.
You know, the usual, some killing,
some fucking. Lots of hard partying.
- That's what pays off in this business.
- Every time.
My problem is, I got a witness.
He's just a local Indian boy named Billy,
but he saw one of my drug raids go down.
And just seeing it go down, it's no big
deal in and of itself, but this one got ugly.
It got messy in a hurry,
and somebody shot one of my men.
All hell broke loose, and everybody died.
You fucked up.
Killing dealers wasn't part of the plan.
Now, the Mexicans are
going to want payback,
and these Mexicans don't fuck around.
You took their money. You took their drugs.
You probably killed
somebody's fucking cousin.
What were you thinking?
- You still got the money and the drugs?
- Yeah, sure.
This is what we're going to do.
We're going to pin it on the Indian kid.
Put the money and the drugs on him.
Make sure the Sheriff finds him that way.
- Dead, with all the shit on him.
- That's a damn good idea.
- You think so, Reno?
- Yep.
I don't know, 'cause you still seem nervous.
Is there something you're not telling me?
A couple of days ago, this old boy comes
riding into town on a strange-looking bike.
He starts beating up my men,
shooting up my bar,
causing me all kinds of trouble
every day of the week.
Big, tall, rough-looking bastard.
Military training for sure.
And here's the weird thing.
He carries a Bible around with him
everywhere he goes.
Did you say he had a Bible?
How do you know it wasn't just a big book?
No, it was a Bible for sure.
My men even tell me he reads from it.
- Is it a tall guy, blonde hair, old Hog?
- Yeah. Yeah, that's him exactly!
Lmpossible, I knew a guy like that once,
but that guy's dead.
He's dead?
Well, you fucked up, because
he's alive, and he's kicking my ass.
I fucked up? Huh? I fucked up?
No, 'cause the way I see it, Reno, the only
one that's fucking up around here is you.
Drug dealers are dead. Business is dead.
You got a murder witness
running around free that should be dead.
And to top it all off,
we still don't have a fucking casino!
You got a nice place here, Reno.
I hope you don't mind if I live here
when you're dead.
Come on. Let's go, you pieces
of white trash. Going to Black River.
- I wonder if my kids are okay.
- They're in good hands.
White Deer is a wise old man.
You remind me of their father.
Every day I see their faces
and I think of him, and remember him
and how much they miss him.
- Really?
- He was killed by a biker gang.
Look, maybe something good
will come out of what I have to do here.
Just remember to make the most of it.
Can't you wait till morning? Please don't go.
It's a nightmare.
You must be Billy.
Nobody else could be stupid enough
to sit on my bike.
Yeah, I'm Billy.
Who the fuck are you?
- My name is Jarfe.
- That's a funny name. Jarfe.
You know, there's a funny story
that goes with that.
Well, my mother and father,
they were really bad drunks.
And the last thing she gave me
before she died giving birth to me
was this fucked-up name.
Now, long story short,
she's at the hospital, on a table,
legs up in the stirrups,
and I come popping out.
The nurse turns to her and says,
"What do you want to name him?"
Now, she meant to say "Jeff."
But she was just so drunk and beaten,
you know, the old man busted her jaw,
that it came out "Jarfe."
And then she died a few minutes later.
So, I guess you could say I came into
this world a little fucked up, huh?
Yeah.
All right, I want you to have this, right here.
I don't do drugs, Billy, they're bad for you.
Man, please.
If this is about the other night, please, man.
I promise I won't tell nobody.
I won't tell nobody, please.
Let me talk to Reno.
I talk to Reno, please, man.
You redskin fucks'll never learn.
This is a white man's world.
Not so fast.
You got an old biker staying here.
- Tall guy, blonde? Reads the Bible.
- Screw you.
That's the idea.
Listen, you dirty, little whore.
Maybe you'd like to have this
conversation in private.
- I'm not a whore.
- That's what they all say.
Hey, what's going on?
Hey, up against the wall, asshole.
- Is there a problem, officer?
- I said up against the wall!
I'm sorry, did you say something?
- Kiowa, come back here! Come back.
- No, I'm going to help him.
There he is!
Where do you think you're going?
- Billy's, uh...
- Yeah, I know.
- Dead.
- So are my two deputies.
And you're not going in there.
All right, Sheriff.
But under the circumstances,
l'll make an exception.
They're on the other side of town,
- by the bank.
- Thank you, Dan.
Put your tampon back in
and go let them know.
All right, let's go.
Come on.
He's coming! He's coming!
Hey man, over there.
You, go that way. You, go that way.
Not even God himself can save the
holy man of this piece-of-shit town from me.
L'll burn this fucking place to the ground.
Can't anybody kill this fucking guy? Go!
You gonna just sit there? Let's go.
Freeze! Nobody move!
Do you have any idea
how hard it is to find good help?
Your holy man ought to be dead,
and so should you.
I said, don't move.
Come on.
What you got?
They're all dead.
- All of them?
- Well, they look dead to me.
If not dead, really fucked up.
It's impossible. It can't be you.
It's me.
It's all there. The drugs and the money.
Your cousin judge
ain't going to help you now.
Fine.
THE END
Subtitles by: