You've said that you didn't kill Jae Hee at court, right?
That Jae Hee had an affair, and that person would have killed Jae Hee.
We can't be here. Your wife is here!
She's not my wife.
Then who is that woman?
Mom!
You just tell me who she was with. I'll catch him with my own hands.
I'll take you out of this place.
She went to Cha Min Jae's house because she suspected him the most.
After checking, Jae Hee started changing two years ago.
After that, she met him there.
I think Jae Hee's husband used his mother and lover to catch the person who killed Jae Hee.
All the men related to the students at the studio were suspected to be Jae Hee's lover
Then the reason why she set up a hair salon is because of Se Yeon, your husband?
Hello?
Do you know how long I waited for you? Why did you do that?
I thought of the insurance money.
We can payback all the debts then we can...
We can live without worrying about money, so how I could I appear?
Han Sang Hoon, he probably went through my things to find my fingerprint.
Kim Young Dae came looking for you, didn't he?
Are you sure my husband is Jae Hee's lover?
You chose the wrong person. Hwang Dong Seok.
Han Jeong Won's husband Chef Hwang Dong Seok.
Your husband...
Don't trust him, ever.
I need that money to save our Ye Rin.
Just live as a dead man.
So you agree with it?
He said to hand over all the insurance money except for the cost of Ye Rin's surgery.
Are you ready to leave?
Do you know you're trespassing?
Trespassing?
I'm the official wife
and you are his cheap mistress!
I told you to do only what I said.
Kim Young Dae.
Where is Kim Young Dae?
Let's talk.
Did you wake up?
Why did you kill? There was no reason to.
There was a time I went to Se Yeon's cafe.
But I got caught by the lady at the hair salon.
Don't hurt Se Yeon.
Don't worry about that. She's very important to me.
A few years ago, many people died of Malathion poisoning in China.
It was a fraud for insurance money.
What is that?
What have you done to our Ye Rin?
I'll tell the insurance company that Kim Young Dae is alive!
Tell them! Tell them your husband is alive!
I'll let you die in prison.
He said my lips smell like olive oil.
I'm that kind of person to him.
Mistress
Ye Rin! Smile!
Over there!
Not long ago we reported an uprise of insurance scams
Another insurance scam has taken place again.
A young daughter was administered a pesticide called Malathion to claim insurance money.
The culprit was arrested today.
14 hours ago
Episode 10
What did you do all night? You told the PD you were on broadcast, but you didn't answer your phone all night.
Do you know how worried I was?
What are you doing?
What are you doing!!
Are you like this because of this? What is this?
She liked me all by herself! I didn't care for her!
Then why did you try so hard not to lose the bracelet from Na Yoon Jeong?
Are you sure it's still nothing?
Hey! Speak up!
What about you!
You had an affair with him.
Yes, I did.
You knew about it, so you wanted me to be miserable by playing that video in the living room.
What kind of husband would be okay with seeing that?
I did it because I was mad!
Then how could someone who was that mad be happy when you found out I was pregnant?
You already knew everything!
Our baby...
does it not matter to you whose baby it is?
As long as the show goes on?
I don't care whose baby it is. I can raise it!
Stop being so greedy!
I've been meaning to say this for a long time.
Please make food that people can eat.
Not food that's just pretty to look at.
But you know, real food that satisfies.
The kind of food you used to make before.
- You were so happy when people enjoyed your food. - Isn't that right?
To come this far,
I've seen all kind of dirty things.
You know that best.
Now we can do the show
and enjoy our life together
Is that so wrong?
Honey, this isn't you.
This isn't the you I used to know.
Is Hwang Dong Seok at home?
What is it?
I just need to ask a couple questions.
You don't need to worry.
What's wrong with my husband?
Honey!
Let go!
Hwang Dong Seok, you're being arrested for the murder of Na Yoon Jeong.
You have the right to engage an attorney.
Framed
Hello?
Do you recognize this?
Where did you..
It was found in the victim's kitchen drawer
along with your husband's fingerprint impression.
My husband's fingerprint?
Yes.
I think the victim intentionally lifted it earlier
to plant it at Na Yoon Jeong's crime scene.
Don't call her the victim yet. My husband is not capable of killing anyone.
Do you recognize it?
If I recognize this, what will happen to Dong Seok?
Hwan Dong Seok and Baek Jae Hee were lovers. This was already revealed.
We've secured the CCTV video of him arguing with the victim at the restaurant. He had more than enough motivation to kill her.
As evidence, we found her cell phone in the kitchen drawer at his restaurant.
The last thing we need to find out is where did the victim lift Kim Yeong Dae's fingerprint?
There was no fingerprint found on this watch. It's possible the victim it wiped it off.
So we need your confirmation
if this belonged to your husband?
Yes.
It is my husband's watch.
So your husband is not a accused anymore since
Han Sang Hoon was not found at the site of the abandoned condo.
I wonder why my husband's fingerprint was planted at the crime scene.
Maybe to add more confusion to the case? A dead man's fingerprint can do that.
What did Dong Seok say? Did he confess to the crime?
He admitted his relationship with Jae Hee but...
denies all charges to the murder.
Dong Seok...
Why do you think he did that?
What are you saying?
What about my husband...do you really think that he killed someone?
I'll go.
Jeong Won!
Don't worry Se Yeon. I'll try to comfort her.
Thanks. I'll leave her to you.
By the way, did something happen to Ye Rin?
You don't look so good.
It's because...
yesterday, social workers came by from the Children's Welfare Services.
Children's Welfare Services?
Jang Se Yeon?
How do you do? You're Jang Se Yeon, right?
Yes I am.
We're from the Children's Welfare Services.
I would like to ask a few questions about your daughter.
What do you want to know?
What are you doing?
There is a bruise on her arm.
This is a needle mark. The nurse mistakenly pierced the needle in the wrong place.
Ye Rin's mother, can we please talk for a few minutes?
Ah..
I heard a pesticide substance was found within Ye Rin's body.
Her babysitter fed it to her little at a time.
Babysitter?
- Excuse me.- Don't worry, it's alright.
Do you still have any more pesticide left?
Say it!!
No... not any more.
Can you provide me the babysitter's contact number?
I can, but why do you want it?
You have insurance on Ye Rin, right?
What?
The pay-out amount is huge.
Did you have insurance on Ye Rin?
Yeong Dae wanted it so I filled out the application form but
he told me that later he changed his mind and bought only mine and his.
That was a good thing. You'll have some insurance money.
And don't worry too much about the investigation. It's probably nothing.
[Ye Rin's dad]
[The number you called, has been disconnected. Please check the number and call again]
It was inconceivable for us to think that
Hwang Dong Seok would plant a dead man's fingerprint at the crime scene.
Sorry to have bothered you.
If you came to apologize, it's okay.
I didn't have much time to think about it anyway.
Oh, that's right...your daughter...
To be honest, we came because of your daughter.
To begin with
after your husband passed away, you've received a huge pay-out from the insurance company.
What's that got to do with my daughter?
Ah..well...we received a request for an investigation.
An Investigation?
[You have a Life Insurance on Ye Rin, right?]
[Life Insurance Application]
What about this...
Did Kim Yeong Dae filled this out himself?
No, I did.
Did you filled this out for your daughter as well?
Yes. My husband thought it was a good idea.
- Mine was also filled out.- I see.
Your husband and Ye Rin's application were processed
but there is no insurance under your name.
That can't be right.
My application was submitted at the same time.
Oh, my husband set-up automatic of payments from his own account.
But this record shows
your insurance was terminated after one month, because there were no further payments made.
That can't be right.
[Insurance Contract]
You might think this is odd but
insurance does not cover pay-out on death of children.
You know more about the insurance than I thought.
I learned a thing or two about it while getting my husband's insurance pay-out.
But the payments on treatments are paid by the insurance on a regular basis.
That's what many criminals are after.
I'm not saying that you are.
Sa-Sang Hee...you're Sang Hee, right?
Don't you remember me?
We played together with Ye Rin at the playground.
Ye Rin?
Yeah, you..you remember me now, right?
I used to push your swing...right?
Sang Hee. Do you see that stick behind me? Can you hand that over to me?
Come over here...
Please...
Let's untie this quickly so that we can go play with Ye Rin.
Come here...come over here and help me.
That's right...keep coming.
You know Han Sang Hoon, right?
Yes. His daughter and mine were friends so we got to know each other.
It didn't seem like you were just casual friends.
We were close..
Lately, you've been distanced...what's the reason?
Did you know that he was an insurance investigator from the beginning?
No, I didn't know that at first.
But you found out later.
Is that why you stayed away from him?
You know that he's been missing, right?
Yes. I know.
You knew when he was missing.
Why do you keep asking me about him?
We heard from his co-worker that he's been missing
right after he'd gone to meet someone.
Who?
You.
[Ah Yeon's Dad]
Se Yeon, just listen.
Don't say a word.
Are the police there?
If they are next to you, just say, hello.
Hello?
Very good.
- Go out to the hallway to talk to me.- Ah...
Don't say anything.
Get out of there. Hurry.
- Oh...
Sorry. I need to take this call.
Hello?
- Is this really Sang Hoo?- Yes.
I just ran away from Kim Yeong Dae.
I found my cell phone but it's not working well.
- Hello? - Where are you?
I don't know. But right now, the most important thing is you.
Listen carefully to what I'm telling you.
You need to get out of there right now.
I heard everything from Kim Yeong Dae while I was kidnapped by him.
He is the one who called the police.
We have to prove that I'm alive.
Or else, you'll be accused of killing your husband for insurance money,
and killing me to silence me.
We need to move fast.
If you get arrested, we'll lose the opportunity to reveal the truth.
You need to get away from there immediately. You got it?
Why is she talking so long?
You think she ran away?
Her daughter is here. How could she..
She fed her daughter pesticide.
Of course she could run away to evade getting caught.
Wait here.
Check over there.
What should I do?
I know where Kim Yeong Dae is.
I'm got hurt a bit...
Could you come here?
Okay. I'll be right there.
Oh, where are you going?
Oh! Oh! Oh! Damn!
Jang Se Yeon! Stop right there!
Jang Se Yeon!
Jang Se Yeon! Get out of the car!
Jang Se Yeon! Don't do this!
Jang Se Yeon! Get out! Get out!
Jang Se Yeon!
It'll be hard to get away by car. Taking the public transit will be better.
No reception...
Hey, isn't that Jang Se Yeon?
Oh...oh...I think so.
Get close to her.
Stop the car.
Jang Se Yeon!
Get her! Go!
Sorry! Sorry!
- Get in there.- Okay.
Jang Se Ye-
You're making this bigger than it is! Get off!
Hello?
Were you able to turn the police away?
- Yes.- Really? You did well. I thought they'd chase you all the way.
They're not here. I've managed to turn them away.
Good job.
Very good...so now,
go home, pick up your bank book and withdraw the insurance money!!
You don't have much time, so hurry. The police will come after you again, soon.
Who are you?
Yeong Dae?
There are many good folks in this world.
What are you doing to me?
Careful how you act...people are watching you.
And what about you? What do you think you're doing to Ye Rin?
What do you mean...Park Jeong Sim--
You two are in this together. Right?
The most important thing Ye Rin. She needs treatments. Don't you agree?
I'm going to get you!
How can you...you're too busy running away.
And all that time, Ye Rin will be all alone.
I just need to prove that you're alive. Then the ridiculous charges of killing a husband for insurance money will be--
Hey, there's no proof of me being alive anywhere. Besides, in your situation, no one will believe you anyway.
Hwa Yeong said she saw you.
But she's your friend. They'll think that she's lying for a friend...
Okay...Go on, tell the police that you're running away because you were duped by Kim Yeong Dae and that he is alive.
Then, I'll get arrested shortly and you'll have to return
all of the insurance money...20 million won. Oh I forgot,..
you'll also be charged for insurance fraud. That means
all of payments for Ye Rin's treatments will be cancelled.
This is a good idea, right?
Be reasonable. If you entrust me with the money
I'll make sure Ye Rin gets her treatments.
And what if I don't agree? What if I can't?
Who do you think helped you at the hospital earlier?
Stop..stop right there!
Getting in the hospital is a piece of cake for me.
What are you trying to say?
What I'm saying is...
getting rid of a child without a trace is not even work for me.
If you ever hurt her...even as much as a strand of her hair
I'll chase you down all the way to hell!
Se Yeon..Se Yeon... do you really think that I'll hurt my own child?
But did you know...
even the animals will tare their offspring to pieces when driven to the edge?
There's no time. Go and get the money.
Se Yeon will never do that.
Everything says the same thing.
Family members and friends can do no wrong.
But Se Yeon is different.
Yes. I hear that a lot too.
Anyway, in case you hear from her
give us a call first. Okay?
(Lim Dae Soo, Seoul Police Division)
Excuse me. Where is the restroom?
Hi Se Yeon. It's me. Where are you?
The police came by. Let's meet up. Where are you?
Eun Soo told me briefly about what has happened to you.
Sae Yeon.
Did you buy Yeong Dae and Ye Rin's life insurance?
No matter what, I trust you. I'm sure you have your reason.
So tell us straight out, how we can help you?
So that jerk, Kim Yeong Dae
schemed all this to steal the insurance money from you.
It's not easy to kill a spouse and get the insurance money
so, instead, he feined his own death
Let's go and get the money from the bank first.
What for? If you're worried about Ye Rin, just discharge her from the hospital.
Ye Rin needs to receive treatments.
That hospital is best known for surgeries and treatments.
Are you going to give him the money?
No. I'm going to use the money for bait.
I'm going to get catch that jerk
and protect my Ye Rin.
I just arrived at the hospital.
Are you alright?
...oh...my fruit...
...over there, behind you...
...there too...
After that, I caught ten criminals all by myself.
Really? That's great. You're awesome!
You're the best!
Ahh...I'm embarrassed.
And then?
- I did some boxing too.- Boxing?- Wow...
That's why I'm not afraid of any criminals.
No wonder, the way you were chasing that apple...
you were really brave.
I'm very fast, huh.
Ah, I have to go now. Thank you so much for today.
Wait a minute! Your fruit basket...
Hey!
What are you doing?
A young lady left her fruit basket.
Fruit basket? What are you talking about!
What lady?
I told you to keep watch here.
Wasn't it Jang Se Yeon?
No.
Then who?
Did you get it?
I think I bought the wrong one; I was running...
Well. you were in a hurry.
Let's go.
oh, could you rewind a bit?
Yes, right there. Stop.
Stand by Jang Se Yeon's bank.
I think she went to get the money.
[Resident Registration]
Please wait a moment while I take care of this.
May I have your PIN?
Oh my gosh!! Why are they on the phone for so long?
I checked the home page...do you have something better?
About 10 million won...
Doesn't matter when it expires...how about the tax write-off?
Damn!
This is driving me crazy!
Why don't you call the branch manager?
It's all ready.
But this is a huge sum
my employee will escort you safely to your car.
Oh, it's okay, thank you though.
Thank you.
Yeong Dae!
Are you okay?
Did you get his picture?
It's didn't turn out clear.
- Yeah, Eun Soo...number 3 exit!- Number 3?...
- Hello? - Where are you?
Okay. we'll head there now.
- Did he get away?- I attached a tracer in the bag.
Hey,
Please untie me.
[Hotel]
[The second keyword is insurance fraud]
[Insurance fraud is on the rise as we have reported previously]
[This horrible scam has happened again]
[This time, a little girl was fed a pesticide substance called Malathion to claim the insurance money]
[Today, the culprit was caught]
[Reporter Kim, please tell us what happened in detail]
The way Ms. Jang's crime was caught is due to the hospitalization of her daughter Kim.
Kim who was being examined for acute leukemia and during the exam...
Pesticide with malic acid was found within her body.
You're saying that the pesticide was found in her body, right?
Yes, that's right.
There was another incident involving pesticide for insurance scam before.
There's a reason why this Ms. Jang incident is being brought to much attention this time is because...
we have discovered that this isn't the first time Ms. Jang committed insurance fraud.
Ms. Jang who is accused of killing her husband
received a little over 2 billion won.
But Ms. Jang's insurance fraud scam didn't end here.
She poisoned her daughter this time and tried to take the insurance money.
This is the second case of an insurance scam by a housewife.
The police found out about it today.
But I heard that she was able to get away unfortunately.
Yes, that's right.
When Ms. Jang realized she was being tracked down, she took the entire life insurance amount and ran away.
The second "Mother" insurance fraud incident
If that a**hole is still alive, we have to reveal the truth somehow.
Se Yeon, do you have a recording of your conversation with Kim Yeong Dae?
Yeah, I recorded our last conversation.
Give it to me.
But the voice was distorted, so you won't be able to tell if it's him.
Hangook University Hospital
Go home, get the bankbook, and go get the insurance money.
- We don't have time. Don't let the police...  - I really can't tell...
Don't worry. He's human being. I'm sure he left some type of trace somewhere whether it's CCTV or what.
Right. If we reveal that a**hole is still alive, Se Yeon...
You can clear your name of both murder and insurance fraud in one shot.
What do you want?
I'm the guardian of the patient in this room.
What? If you're Ye Rin's guardian...
Ye Rin...
Ye Rin, daddy's here.
What's happening? Kim Yeong Dae is alive.
Mistress
My wife tried to drown me.
You just have to reveal that Kim Yeong Dae is alive.
In Sang Hoon's notebook... I'm sure there's a clue that leads to him.
You'll have to help us.
Before anything happens to Sang Hoon, let's find him first.
We'll find Park Jeong Sim in that time.
If I had ended it then...
Things wouldn't be so dangerous like this.
♫ Will you just hold me tight? ♫
♫ Will you just quietly comfort me? ♫
♫ Because I don’t care whether or not you know my heart ♫