-Who are you?
-We are three wise men.
-What?
What are you doing creeping around
a cowshed at 2:00 a.m.?
That doesn't sound very wise to me.
-We are astrologers.
-We have come from the East.
-ls this some kind of joke?
-We wish to praise the infant.
-We must pay a homage to him.
-Homage? You're all drunk!
It's disgusting! Out! Come on, out!
Bursting in here with tales about
Oriental fortunetellers. Out!
-No, no, we must see him.
-Go and praise someone else's brat!
-We were led by a star!
-Led by a bottle more like! Go on, out!
-We must see him. We have presents!
-Out!
Gold, frankincense, myrrh!
Well, why didn't you say?
He's over there.
Sorry the place is a bit of a mess.
Well, what is myrrh anyway?
-lt is a valuable balm.
-A balm?!
What are you giving him a balm for?
It might bite him!
-What?
-That's a dangerous animal!
-Throw it in the trough!
-No, it isn't!
-It's a great big....
-No, no, no, it is an ointment.
Well, there is an animal called
a balm, or did I dream it?
So you're astrologers, are you?
Well, what is he then?
What star-sign is he?
-Capricorn.
-Capricorn, eh? What are they like?
Well, he's the Son of God.
Our Messiah.
King of the Jews!
-And that's Capricorn, is it?
-No, no, no, that's just him!
I was gonna say,
otherwise there'd be a lot of them.
-By what name are you calling him?
-Brian.
We worship you, Brian,
who are lord over us all.
Praise unto you, Brian,
and to the Lord, our Father. Amen.
-Do you do a lot of this?
-What?
-This praising.
-No, no. No, no.
Well, if you're dropping
by again, do pop in.
And thanks a lot for the gold
and frankincense...
...but don't worry too much about
the myrrh next time, all right?
Thank you. Goodbye.
Well, weren't they nice?
Out of their bloody minds,
but still, look at that!
Here. Here, that's mine! Hey! Hey!
Shut up!
Brian
The babe they called Brian
He grew
Grew, grew and grew
Grew up to be
A boy called Brian
He had arms and legs
And hands and feet
This boy
Whose name was Brian
And he grew
Grew, grew and grew
Grew up to be
Yes, he grew up to be
A teenager called Brian
And his face became spotty
Yes, his face became spotty
And his voice dropped down low
And things started to grow
On young Brian and show
He was certainly no
No girl named Brian
Not a girl named Brian
And he started to shave
And have one off the wrist
And want to see girls
And go out and get pissed
A man called Brian
This man called Brian
The man they called Brian
This man called
Brian
How blessed are those
who know that he's of God.
How blessed are
the sorrowful.
They shall find consolation.
How blessed are those of gentle spirit.
They shall have the earth
for their possession.
How blessed are those who hunger
and thirst to see right prevail.
They shall be satisfied.
How blessed are those
whose hearts are pure.
They shall see God.
-Speak up!
-Quiet, mum!
Well, I can't hear a thing.
Let's go to a stoning.
-You can go to a stoning anytime.
-Come on, Brian.
Will you be quiet?
Don't pick your nose!
I wasn't. I was scratching.
You was picking it while you
was talking to that lady.
-I wasn't!
-Leave it alone. Give it a rest.
-Do you mind? I can't hear a word.
-Don't you "do you mind" me.
-I was talking to my husband.
-Talk to him somewhere else.
-I can't hear a bloody thing.
-Don't you swear at my wife.
I was only asking her to shut up
so we can hear, big nose.
Don't you call my husband "big nose."
-Well, he has got a big nose.
-Could you be quiet, please?
-What was that?
-I was too busy talking to big nose.
I think it was,
"Blessed are the cheese makers."
What's so special about
the cheese makers?
It's not meant to be taken literally.
It refers to any manufacturers
of dairy products.
If you hadn't been going on,
we'd have heard that, big nose.
Say that once more,
I'll smash your bloody face in!
Listen, might be a bit
about "Blessed are the big noses."
Lay off him.
You're not so bad yourself, conk-face.
Where are you two from? Nose City?
One more time,
I'll take you to the fucking cleaners!
Language!
And don't pick your nose!
I wasn't going to.
I was gonna thump him!
Hear that? Blessed are the Greek.
-The Greek?
-Apparently, he's gonna inherit the earth.
-Did anyone catch his name?
-You won't thump anybody.
-I'll thump him if he calls me "big nose"!
-Shut up, big nose!
Right. I warned you.
I really will slug you so hard--!
It's the meek.
"Blessed are the meek."
That's nice, isn't it? I'm glad they getting
something. They have a hell of a time.
Listen, I'm only telling the truth,
you have got a very big nose.
Your nose is going to be three foot wide
across your face by the time I'm finished!
Who hit yours? Goliath's big brother?
-Right, that's your last warning.
-Do pipe down.
Silly bitch, getting in the way.
Break it up!
-Come on, let's go to the stoning.
-All right.
Blessed is just about everyone with an
interest in the status quo, right, Reg?
What Jesus blatantly fails to appreciate
is it's the meek who are the problem.
Yes, yes. Absolutely, Reg. Yes, I see.
Come on, Brian, or they'll have
stoned him before we get there.
All right.
Hey, get off her. That's disgusting.
Officer, intervene here.
Attempted rape going on. It's the chap
with the big nose's fault. He started it all.
I hate wearing these beards.
-Why aren't women allowed at stonings?
-It's written, that's why.
-Beard, madam?
-I haven't got time to go to no stonings.
He's not well again.
-Stone, sir?
-They've got them lying on the ground.
Not like these, sir. Look at this. Feel
the quality of that. That's craftsmanship.
All right. We'll have two with points
and a big, flat one.
Could I have a flat one, Mum?
Sorry. Dad.
All right. Two points, two flats
and a packet of gravel.
Packet of gravel.
Should be a good one this afternoon.
-Local boy.
-Oh, good.
Enjoy yourselves.
Matthias, son of
Deuteronomy of Gath...
-Do I say yes?
-Yes!
...you have been found guilty
by the elders of the town...
...of uttering the name of our Lord...
...and so as a blasphemer...
...you are to be stoned to death!
Look, I'd had a lovely supper,
and all I said to my wife was:
"That piece of halibut was
good enough for Jehovah."
Blasphemy! He said it again!
-Did you hear him?
-Yeah! Yes, we did!
Really.
Are there any women here today?
Very well. By virtue of the authority...
...vested in me--
Lay off! We haven't started yet.
Come on! Who threw that?
Who threw that stone? Come on!
She did! She did!
He did! He did! He did!
Sorry, I thought we'd started.
-Go to the back.
-Oh, dear.
Always one, isn't there?
-Now, where were we?
-I don't think it ought to be blasphemy...
-...just saying "Jehovah."
-He did! He did!
You're only making it worse for yourself!
Making it worse?!
How could it be worse?
Jehovah! Jehovah! Jehovah!
I'm warning you!
If you say Jehovah once more--
Right! Who threw that?
Come on! Who threw that?
Him! Him! Him!
-Was it you?
-Yes.
-Right--
-Well, you did say Jehovah.
Stop. Stop. Will you stop that?
Stop it!
Now, look. No one is to stone
anyone until I blow this whistle.
Do you understand?
Even, and I want to
make this absolutely clear...
...even if they do say Jehovah.
Good shot!
-Have I got a big nose, mum?
-Stop thinking about sex.
-I wasn't.
-You're always on about it.
Morning, noon and night.
"Will the girls like this,
will the girls like that?
Is it too big, is it too small?"
-Alms for a leper.
Alms for an ex-leper.
Bloody donkey-owners, all the same,
ain't they? Never have any change.
Here's a touch.
-Spare a talent for an old ex-leper?
-Buzz off.
Spare a talent for an old ex-leper?
A talent? That's more than
he earns in a month.
-Half a talent then?
-No, go away.
-Big nose, let's haggle.
-What?
All right, let's say you open at one
shekel, I start at 2000, we close at 1800.
-No.
-1750?
-Go away!
-1740?
-Leave him alone.
-All right. Two shekels, just two.
-ls this fun, eh?
-Look, he's not giving you any money.
Now piss off!
All right, final offer,
half a shekel for an ex-leper?
-Did you say ex-leper?
-That's right, sir.
Sixteen years behind
a bell and proud of it.
-Well, what happened?
-I was cured, sir.
-Cured?
-A bloody miracle, sir. God bless you.
-Who cured you?
-Jesus did, sir.
I was hopping along,
minding my own business.
All of a sudden, up he comes, cures me.
One minute I'm a leper with a trade,
next minute my livelihood's gone.
"You're cured, mate."
Bloody do-gooder.
Well, why don't you go and tell him
that you want to be a leper again?
I could do that sir.
I could, I suppose.
I was gonna ask him if he'd make me
a bit lame in one leg during the week.
You know, something beggable, but
not leprosy, which is a pain in the ass.
Brian. Come and clean your room out.
-There you are.
-Thank you. Thank--
-Half a dinare for me bloody life story?
-There's no pleasing some people.
That's just what Jesus said, sir.
Good afternoon.
Hello, officer.
I'll be with you in a few
moments, all right, dear?
What's he doing here?
-Don't start, Brian. Go clean your room.
-Bloody Romans.
Now, look, Brian. If it wasn't for them,
we wouldn't have all this.
-And don't you forget it.
-We don't owe the Romans anything.
That's not entirely true, is it, Brian?
What do you mean?
Well, you know when you
were asking me about your...?
-My nose?
-Yes, well, there's a reason it's like it is.
What is it?
Well, I suppose I should have
told you a long time ago, but....
Well, Brian...
-...your father isn't Mr. Cohen.
-I never thought he was.
Now, none of your cheek!
He was a Roman, Brian.
He was a centurion in the Roman army.
-You mean you were raped?!
-Well, at first, yes.
-Who was it?
-Naughtius Maximus his name was.
Promised me the known world,
he did.
I was to be taken to Rome,
house by the Forum...
...slaves, asses' milk...
...as much gold as I could eat.
Then he, having his way with me he had:
Like a rat out of an aqueduct.
The bastard.
Yes, and next time you go on
about the "bloody Romans"...
-...don't forget you're one of them.
-I'm not a Roman, Mum.
And I never will be.
I'm a kike, a yid, a hebe, a hooknose.
I'm kosher, Mum. I'm a Red Sea
pedestrian and proud of it!
Sex, sex, sex, that's all
they think about, huh?
Well, how are you then, officer?
Ladies and gentlemen,
the next contest is between...
...Frank Goliath,
the Macedonian baby-crusher...
...and Boris Mineburg.
Thank you, madam.
Larks' tongues. Wrens' livers.
Chaffinch brains.
Jaguars' earlobes.
Wolf-nipple chips.
Get them while they're hot. They're lovely.
Dromedary pretzels, only half a dinar.
Tuscany fried bats....
I do feel, Reg, that any
anti-imperialist group like ours...
...must reflect such a divergence
of interest within its power base.
-Agreed. Francis?
-Judith's point of view is very valid...
...provided the movement never forgets
it is the unalienable right of every man...
-Or woman.
-...or woman...
-...to rid himself--
-Or herself.
-Agreed.
-Thanks, brother.
-Or sister.
-Or sister....
Where was l?
-I think you finished.
-Right.
-lt is the birthright of every man--
-Or woman.
Shut up about women, Stan.
You're putting us off.
Women have a perfect right to play
a part in our movement.
Why are you always
on about women, Stan?
I want to be one.
What?
I want to be a woman.
From now on, I want you
all to call me Loretta.
-What?
-It's my right as a man.
Well, why do you want
to be Loretta, Stan?
I want to have babies.
You want to have babies?!
It's every man's right to have
babies if he wants them.
-But you can't have babies.
-Don't you oppress me.
I'm not oppressing you, Stan.
You haven't got a womb.
Where's the fetus gonna gestate?
You gonna keep it in a box?
Here, I've got an idea. Suppose you agree
that he can't actually have babies...
...not having a womb, which is nobody's
fault, not even the Romans'...
-...but he has the right to have babies.
-Good idea, Judith.
We shall fight the oppressors for your
right to have babies, brother. Sister.
-What's the point?
-What?
Why fight for his right to have babies
when he can't have babies?
It is symbolic of our struggle
against oppression.
Symbolic of his struggle
against reality.
-Get out there. Get out.
-It's dangerous out there.
Larks' tongues. Otters' noses.
Ocelots' spleens.
-Got any nuts?
-Haven't got any nuts.
-I've got wrens' livers, badgers' spleens--
-No, no, no.
-Otters' noses?
-I don't want any Roman rubbish.
-Why don't you sell proper food?
-Proper food?
-Yeah, not those rich imperialist tidbits.
-Don't blame me. I didn't ask to sell this.
-All right, bag of otters' noses, then.
-Make it two.
-Two.
-Thanks, Reg.
-Are you the Judean People's Front?
-Fuck off.
-What?
-Judean People's Front.
We're The People's Front of Judea.
-Judean People's Front, God!
-Wankers.
-Can I join your group?
-No, piss off.
I didn't want to sell this. It's only a job.
I hate the Romans as much as anybody.
-Are you sure?
-Dead sure.
I hate the Romans already.
Listen, if you wanted to join the PFJ,
you'd have to really hate the Romans.
I do.
-Oh, yeah, how much?
-A lot.
Right, you're in. Listen...
...the only people we hate more than
Romans are the Judean People's Front.
-Splitters.
-And the Judean Popular People's Front.
-Oh, yeah.
-Splitters.
-And the People's Front of Judea.
-Yeah. Splitters.
-What?
-The People's Front of Judea. Splitters.
We're the People's Front of Judea.
-I thought we were the Popular Front.
-People's Front.
Whatever happened
to the Popular Front, Reg?
He's over there.
Splitter!
I think I'm about to have
a cardiac arrest.
Absolutely dreadful.
-What's your name?
-Brian. Brian Cohen.
We may have a little job for you, Brian.
What's this then?
"Romanes eunt domus"?
"People called Romanes,
they go the house"?
It says, "Romans go home."
No, it doesn't. What's Latin for Roman?
-Come on.
-Romanus?
-Goes like...?
-Anus?
Vocative plural of anus is...?
-Ani?
-Romani.
-"Eunt"? What is eunt?
-Go.
-Conjugate the verb "to go."
-Ere, eo, is, it, imus, itis, eunt.
So eunt is...?
Third person plural, present indicative.
"They go."
But "Romans go home" is an order,
so you must use the...?
-lmperative!
-Which is...?
-Oh, -i.
-How many Romans?
-Plural, plural. Ite. Ite.
-Ite.
Domus? Nominative?
"Go home." This is motion
towards, isn't it, boy?
Dative! Not dative,
not the dative, sir!
The accusative! Accusative!
Domum, sir. Ad domum.
-Except that domus takes the...?
-The locative, sir.
-Which is...?
-Domum!
Domum.
-Understand?
-Yes, sir.
-Write that 100 times.
-Yes, sir. Thank you. Hail Caesar.
If it's not done by sunrise,
I'll cut your balls off.
Thank you, sir. Thank you, sir.
Hail Caesar and everything, sir.
Finished.
Right. Now, don't do it again.
Hey. Bloody Romans.
We get in through the underground
heating-system...
...up through into the main
audience chamber here...
...and Pilate's wife's bedroom is here.
Having grabbed his wife,
we inform Pilate...
...that she is in our custody,
and forthwith issue our demands.
-Any questions?
-What exactly are the demands?
We're giving Pilate two days to dismantle
the entire Roman imperialist state...
...and if he doesn't agree
immediately, we execute her.
-Cut her head off?
-Cut all her bits off.
Send them back on the hour, every hour.
Show them we're not to be trifled with.
And of course, we point out that they bear
full responsibility when we chop her up...
...and that we shall not
submit to blackmail.
No blackmail!
They've bled us white, the bastards.
They've taken everything we had.
And not just from us! From our fathers,
and from our fathers' fathers.
-And from our fathers' fathers' fathers.
-Yeah.
-And our fathers' fathers' fathers' fathers.
-All right, don't labour the point.
And what have they ever
given us in return?
The aqueduct?
-What?
-The aqueduct.
Yeah, they did give us that.
That's true, yeah.
And the sanitation.
Yeah, the sanitation, Reg.
Remember what the city used to be like.
I'll grant you the aqueduct and sanitation,
the two things the Romans have done.
-And the roads.
-Yeah, obviously the roads.
I mean the roads go
without saying, don't they?
But apart from sanitation,
aqueduct and roads--
-lrrigation.
-Medicine.
-Education.
-Yeah, yeah, all right, fair enough.
And the wine.
That's something we'd really miss, Reg,
if the Romans left.
Public baths.
It's safe to walk in the streets
at night now.
They know how to keep order.
Let's face it, they're the only ones
who could in a place like this.
All right, but apart from sanitation,
medicine, education, wine, public order...
...irrigation, roads, the fresh-water
system and public health...
...what have the Romans
ever done for us?
-Brought peace?
-Peace. Shut up!
I'm a poor man. My sight is poor.
My legs are old and bented.
-It's all right, Matthias.
-It's all clear.
Well, where's Reg?
Reg. Reg. It's Judith.
-What went wrong?
-The first blow has been struck.
-Did he finish the slogan?
-100 times.
In letters 10 foot high,
all the way around the palace.
Oh, great.
Great. We need doers in our movement,
Brian, but before you join us, know this:
There is not one of us who would not
gladly die...
...to rid this country of the Romans.
Well, one.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, there's one. But
otherwise, we're solid. Are you with us?
Yes.
From now on, you shall be called,
"Brian, that is called Brian."
Tell him about the raid
on Pilate's palace, Francis.
Right. This is the plan:
Now, this is the palace
in Caesar's Square.
Our commando unit will approach
from Fish Street...
...and make our way
to the northwestern main drain.
If questioned, we are sewage workers
on our way to a conference.
Reg, our glorious leader
and founder of the PFJ...
...will be coordinating consultant
at the drain head...
... though he will not be taking part in any
terrorist action, as he has a bad back.
-Aren't you gonna come with us?
-Solidarity, brother.
Oh, yes. Solidarity, Reg.
Once in the sewer,
timing will be of the essence.
There is a Roman feast later,
so we must move fast...
...and don't wear your best sandals.
Turning left here, we enter
the Caesar Augustus Memorial Sewer.
And from there proceed directly
to the hypocaust.
This has just been re-tiled.
So terrorists, careful with those weapons.
We will now be directly beneath
Pilate's audience chamber itself.
This is the moment
for Habakkuk to get out his prong.
Campaign for Free Galilee.
People's Front of Judea. Officials.
-What's your group doing here?
-We're gonna kidnap Pilate's wife.
-So are we.
-What?
That's our plan.
-We were here first.
-What do you mean?
-We thought of it first.
-Oh, yeah?
Yes, a couple of years ago.
-We did.
-You got all your demands worked out?
-Of course we have.
-What are they?
-Well, I'm not telling you.
-Pull the other one.
That's not the point.
We thought of it before you.
-Did not.
-We did.
-You didn't.
-We bloody did!
Bastards, we've been
planning this for months.
Well, tough titty for you, fish-face.
-All right.
-Why you sly--
Brothers! Brothers!
We should be struggling together!
We are.
We mustn't fight each other!
Surely, we should be united
against the common enemy!
The Judean People's Front?!
No, no, the Romans!
-Oh, yeah.
-Yes.
-Yeah, he's right.
-Look out!
Careful.
-Right! Where were we?
-You were gonna punch me.
Oh, yeah!
Brothers!
Get off!
-You lucky bastard.
-Who's that?
-You lucky, lucky bastard.
-What?
-Proper little jailer's pet, aren't we?
-What do you mean?
You must have slipped him
a few shekels, eh?
Slipped him a few shekels?
You saw him spit in my face!
What wouldn't I give
to be spat at in the face?
I sometimes hang awake at night,
dreaming of being spat at in the face.
Well, it's not exactly friendly.
They had me in manacles!
Manacles!
My idea of heaven...
...is to be allowed to be put in manacles
just for a few hours.
They must think the sun shines
out of your arse, sonny.
Lay off me, I've had a hard time!
You've had a hard time?
I've been here five years...
...they only hung me the right way up
yesterday! So don't you come around--
All right, all right.
They must think
you're Lord God almighty.
-What will they do to me?
-You'll probably get away with crucifixion.
-Crucifixion?!
-Yeah. First offence.
-Get away with crucifixion?! It's--
-Best thing the Romans ever did for us.
-What?!
-Oh, yeah.
If we didn't have crucifixion,
this country would be a mess.
-Guard!
-Nail them up, I say!
-Nail some sense into them!
-What do you want?
-I want you to move me to another cell.
Oh, look at that! Bloody favouritism!
-Shut up, you.
-Sorry.
Now, take my case.
They hung me up here five years ago.
Every night they take me down
for 20 minutes...
...then they hang me up again.
Which I regard as very fair
in view of what I've done.
And if nothing else, it's taught me
to respect the Romans...
...and it's taught me that
you'll never get anywhere in this life...
...unless you are prepared to do
a fair day's work for a fair day's--
Shut up!
-Pilate wants to see you!
-Me?
-Come on!
-Pilate? What does he want to see me for?
I think he wants to know which
way you ought to be crucified.
-Nice one, centurion. Like it, like it.
-Shut up!
Right. Right.
Terrific race, the Romans. Terrific.
-Hail Caesar.
-Hail.
Only one survivor, sir.
Throw him to the floor.
-What, sir?
-Throw him to the floor.
Now, what is your name, Jew?
-Brian, sir.
-Brian, eh?
No, no, Brian.
The little rascal has spirit.
-Has what, sir?
-Spirit.
Yes, he did, sir.
No, no, spirit.
Bravado, a touch of derring-do.
About 11, sir.
So....
-You dare to raid us?
-To what, sir?
Strike him, centurion, very roughly.
And throw him to the floor, sir?
-What?
-Throw him to the floor again, sir?
Oh, yes. Throw him to the floor, please.
Now, Jewish rapscallion....
I'm not Jewish, I'm a Roman.
-A Roman?
-No, no, Roman.
So your father was a Roman?
Who was he?
He was a centurion
in the Jerusalem garrison, sir.
Really?
-What was his name?
-Naughtius Maximus.
Centurion, do you have anyone
of that name in the garrison?
Well, no, sir.
Well, you sound very sure.
Have you checked?
Well, no, sir. I think it's a joke, sir.
Like "Sillius Soddus"
or "Biggus Dickus," sir.
What's so funny about Biggus Dickus?
Well, it's a joke name, sir.
I have a very great friend in Rome
called Biggus Dickus.
Silence! What is all this insolence?
You will find yourself
in gladiator school very quickly...
...with rotten behaviour like that.
Can I go now, sir?
Wait till Biggus Dickus hears of this.
-Right! Take him away!
-Sir, he--
No, no, I want him fighting
rabid wild animals within a week!
Yes, sir. Come on, you.
I will not have my friends ridiculed
by the common soldiery!
Anybody else feel like a little...
...giggle...
...when I mention my friend...
...Biggus...
...Dickus?
And what about you?
Do you find it risible...
...when I say the name...
...Biggus...
...Dickus?
He has a wife, you know.
You know what she's called?
She's called...
...Incontinentia.
Incontinentia Buttocks. Shut up!
What is all this?
I've had enough of this rowdy-rebel,
sniggering behaviour!
Silence!
You call yourselves centurion guards?
Seize him! Seize him!
Blow your noses and seize him!
You lucky bastard.
And the beast's head
shall be huge and black...
...and the eyes. They're of red,
with the blood of living creatures!
And the whore of Babylon shall ride
forth on a three-headed serpent...
...and throughout the land
shall be a great rubbing of parts.
And the demon shall bear
a nine-bladed sword!
Nine-bladed! Not two
or five or seven, but nine!
Which he will wield on all wretched
sinners. Sinners just like you, sir, there.
-And the horns shall be on the head....
-Through Hebediah, his servant...
...there shall in that time be rumours
of things going astray...
...and there shall be a great confusion
as to where things really are.
And nobody will really know
where lieth those little things...
...with the sort of raffia-work base,
that has an attachment.
At this time, a friend shall
lose his friend's hammer...
...and the young shall not
know where lieth...
...the things possessed
by their fathers...
...that their fathers put there only
just the night before, about 8:00.
Yea, it is written in the Book of Cyril...
...that in that time shall the turds....
-How much? Quickly.
-What?
-It's for the wife.
-Twenty shekels.
-Right.
-What?
-There you are.
-Wait a minute.
-What?
-Well, we're supposed to haggle.
-No, I've got to--
-What do you mean, "No"?
-I haven't got time--
-Give it back.
-No, no, no, I just paid you.
-Burt.
-Yeah?
-This bloke won't haggle.
-Won't haggle?!
-All right, do we have to?
-Now look, I want 20 for that.
-I just gave you 20.
-Are you telling me that's not worth 20?
-No.
Look. Feel the quality,
that's none of your goat.
-All right, I'll give you 19.
-No, come on, do it properly.
-What?
-Haggle properly, this isn't worth 19.
-Well, you just said it was worth 20.
-Oh, dear, oh, dear.
-Come on, haggle.
-All right, I'll give you 10.
That's more like it.
Ten? Are you trying to insult me?
Me, with a poor,
dying grandmother? Ten?
-All right, I'll give you 11.
-Now you're getting it. 11?!
Did I hear you right? 11?
-This cost me 12, you want to ruin me?
-Seventeen?
-No, no, no, no, "17"!
-Eighteen?
-No, no, you go to 14 now.
-All right, I'll give you 14.
-Fourteen!? Are you joking?
-That's what you told me to say!
-Oh, dear.
-Tell me what to say, please!
-Offer me 14.
-I'll give you 14.
-He's offering me 14 for this!
-Fifteen!
Seventeen. My last word, I won't take
a penny less, or strike me dead.
-Sixteen.
-Done.
Nice to do business with you.
-I'll throw you in this as well.
-I don't want it.
-Burt.
-Yeah.
-All right.
-Now, where's the 16 you owe me?
I just gave you 20.
-That's right, that's four I owe you.
-No, that's all right.
-No, I've got it here.
-It's all right, that's four for the gourd.
Four? For this gourd? Four!?
It's worth 10
if it's worth a shekel!
-You just gave it to me for nothing.
-Yes, but it's worth 10.
All right, all right.
No, no, no, no, it's not worth 10,
you're supposed to argue.
"Ten for that? You must be mad!"
Oh, well. One born every minute.
-Daniel.
-Job.
-Joshua.
-Judges.
-And Brian.
I now propose that all seven
of these ex-brothers...
...be now entered in the minutes
as probationary martyrs to the cause.
-I second that, Reg.
-Thank you, Loretta. On the nod.
Siblings, let us not be down on it.
One total catastrophe like this
is just the beginning!
Their glorious deaths
shall unite us all in a--
Look out!
Hello?
Matthias?
-Reg.
-Go away.
-Reg, it's me, Brian.
-Get off. Get off out of it.
-Stan?
-Piss off.
-Yeah, piss off.
-Bugger off.
Shit!
Coming.
Yea, verily at that time,
which is written in the Book of Obadiah...
...a man shall strike his donkey
and his nephew's donkey...
...and anyone in the vicinity
of either the nephew or the donkey.
My eyes are dim, I cannot see.
-Are you Matthias?
-Yes.
We believe you may
be hiding one Brian of Nazareth...
...member of the terrorist organization
the People's Front of Judea.
Me? No, I'm just a poor old man,
I have no time for lawbreakers.
My legs are grey, my ears are nulled,
my eyes are old and bent--
Quiet!
Silly person. Guards, search the house.
You know the penalty laid down by Roman
law for harbouring a known criminal?
-No.
-Crucifixion.
-Nasty, eh?
-lt could be worse.
-What do you mean, "could be worse"?
-Well, you could be stabbed.
Stabbed? It takes a second.
Crucifixion lasts hours.
It's a slow, horrible death.
Well, at least it gets you
out in the open air.
You're weird.
No, sir, couldn't find anything, sir.
Well, don't worry, you've not seen
the last of us, weirdo.
-Big nose.
-Watch it!
That was lucky.
-I'm sorry, Reg.
-Oh, it's all right. Siblings, he's sorry.
He's sorry he led the Fifth legion
to our headquarters.
Well, that's all right then, Brian.
Sit down! Have a scone.
Make yourself at home.
You klutz!
You stupid, birdbrained, flat-headed--
--with a great juicy melon behind.
My legs are old and bent,
my ears are grizzled, yes?
There's one place we didn't look. Guards!
I'm just a poor old man, my sight is dim,
my eyes are poor, my nose is knackered.
-Have you ever seen anyone crucified?
-Crucifixion's a doddle.
Don't keep saying that.
Found this spoon, sir.
Well done, sergeant.
We'll be back, oddball.
-Open up.
-You haven't given us time to hide.
Don't pass judgment on other people,
or you might get judged yourself.
What?
I said, don't pass judgment
on other people...
...or else you might get judged too.
-Who, me?
-Yes.
-Thank you very much.
-Well, not just you, all of you.
-That's a nice gourd.
-What?
-How much do you want for the gourd?
-You can have it.
-Have it?
-Yes. Consider the lilies.
-Don't you want to haggle?
-No. In the field.
-What's wrong with it, then?
-Nothing, take it.
-Consider the lilies?
-Well, the birds, then.
-What birds?
-Any birds.
-Why?
-Well, have they got jobs?
-Who?
-The birds.
Have the birds got jobs?!
-What's the matter with him?
-He says the birds are scrounging.
No, the point is the birds,
they do all right, don't they?
-Well, and good luck to them!
-Yeah, they're very pretty.
Okay. And you're much more
important than they are, right?
So, what are you worrying about?
There you are! See?
I'm worrying about what
you've got against birds.
I haven't got anything against birds.
Consider lilies--
-He's having a go at the flowers now.
-Give the flowers a chance.
-I'll give you one for it.
-It's yours!
Two then.
Look, there was this man,
and he had two servants--
-What were they called?
-What?
-What were their names?
-I don't know.
And he gave them some talents--
-You don't know?
-Well, it doesn't matter.
He doesn't know what they were called!
Oh, they were called
Simon and Adrian. Now--
You said you didn't know!
It doesn't matter,
the point is there were two servants--
-He's making it up as he goes along!
-No, I'm not!
And he gave them--
Wait a minute, were there three?
-He's terrible.
-There were three--
-He's still a traitor!
-Oh, get off!
Now hear this. Blessed are they...
...who convert their neighbour's ox,
for they shall inhibit their girth.
-Rubbish!
-And to them only shall be given....
To them only...
...shall be given....
What?
-Shall be given what?
-Oh, nothing.
-What were you going to say?
-Nothing.
-You were going to say something.
-I finished.
-Oh, no, no.
-Come on, tell us before you go.
-I wasn't going to say anything.
-No, you hadn't.
-What won't he tell us?
-He won't say.
-ls it a secret?
-No.
-ls it?
-lt must be, otherwise he'd tell us.
-Tell us.
-Leave me alone.
-What is the secret?
-ls it the secret of eternal life?
He won't say!
If I knew the secret
of eternal life, I wouldn't say.
-Leave me alone.
-Just tell me, please.
-No, tell us, master, we were here first.
-Rubbish!
-Five!
-Go away!
-Tell us, master.
-I can't go above 5.
-ls that his gourd?
-Yes, but it's under offer.
-This is his gourd.
-Ten!
It is his gourd.
We will carry it for you, master.
Master?
He's gone. He's been taken up.
-Oh, he has been taken up!
-Eighteen!
No, there he is. Over there.
Look!
-He has given us a sign.
-He has given us his shoe.
The shoe is the sign!
Let us follow his example!
-What?
-Let us, like him...
...hold up one shoe and let the other
be upon our foot...
...for this is his sign that all who
follow him shall do likewise!
No, no, the shoe is a sign that we must
gather shoes together in abundance.
-Cast off the shoes. Follow the gourd!
-No, let us gather shoes together.
-Let me!
-Oh, get off!
No, it is a sign that, like him,
we must think...
...not of the things of the body,
but of the face and head!
-Give me your shoe!
-Get off!
Follow the gourd,
the holy gourd of Jerusalem!
-The gourd!
-Hold up the sandal, like he has--
-lt is a shoe! It is a shoe!
-It's a sandal!
-No, it isn't! It is a shoe!
-Cast it away!
-Put it on!
-Now clear off.
Take the shoes and follow him!
Come all ye who call
yourselves Gourdenes.
Stop, I say.
Stop. Let us....
Let us pray.
Yea, he cometh to us
like the seed to the grave....
Master!
Hey, is there another way down?
Is there another path down to the river?
Please, please, help me! I've got to get--
My foot!
-Damn! Damn! Damn!
-I'm sorry.
-Damn! Damn and blast it!
-I'm sorry!
Don't you shush me. Eighteen years
of total silence, and you shush me.
-What?
-I've kept my vow for 18 years.
Not a single recognizable,
articulate sound has passed my lips.
Please be quiet
for another five minutes.
It doesn't matter now,
I might as well enjoy myself.
The times in the last 18 years
I wanted to shout and sing...
...and scream my name out!
Oh, I'm alive!
I'm alive! I'm alive!
Hello, birds! Hello, trees! I'm alive--
Get off! I'm alive!
Master! Master!
The master! He is here!
-The shoe!
-lt was the gourd!
The shoe has brought us!
Speak! Speak to us, master!
Speak to us!
-Go away!
-A blessing! A blessing!
-How shall we go away, master?
-Just go away and leave me alone.
Give us a sign.
He has given us a sign,
he has brought us to this place!
I didn't bring you here!
You just followed me!
It's still a good sign,
by any standard.
Master, your people have walked
many miles to be with you.
They are weary and have not eaten.
-It's not my fault they haven't eaten!
-There is no food in this high mountain.
What about the juniper bushes
over there?
A miracle! A miracle!
He has made the bush
fruitful by his word!
They brought forth juniper berries!
Of course they brought forth
juniper berries, they're juniper bushes.
What do you expect?!
Show us another miracle.
Do not tempt him, shallow ones!
Is not the miracle
of the juniper bushes enough?
-I say, those are my juniper bushes.
-They are a gift from God!
They're all I've bloody got to eat.
I say, get off of those bushes!
Go on! Clear off, the lot of you.
-Lord, I am affected by a bald patch.
-I'm healed!
-The master has healed me!
-I didn't touch him!
I was blind, and now I can see!
A miracle! A miracle! A miracle!
Tell them to stop it. I hadn't said a word
for 18 years till he came along.
A miracle! He is the Messiah!
-And he hurt my foot!
-Hurt my foot, Lord! Hurt mine! Hurt mine!
-Hail Messiah!
-I'm not the Messiah!
I say you are, Lord.
And I should know, I've followed a few!
-Hail Messiah!
-I'm not the Messiah!
Would you please listen, I am not
the Messiah, do you understand?
Honestly!
Only the true Messiah denies his divinity.
What? Well, what sort of chance
does that give me?
-All right, I am the Messiah!
-He is! He is the Messiah!
Now, fuck off!
-How shall we fuck off, Lord?
-Just go away! Leave me alone!
You told these people
to eat my juniper berries.
You break my bloody foot,
you break my vow of silence...
...and then you try and clean up
on my juniper bushes!
Lay off! This is the Messiah,
the chosen one!
-No, he's not.
-An unbeliever!
An unbeliever!
-Persecute! Kill the heretic!
-Yeah! Kill! Kill! Kill!
-Kill!
-Leave him alone!
Leave him alone!
Leave him alone.
Put him down. Please!
Brian?
Judith?
Look, there he is!
The chosen one has woken!
Brian!
Mother!
-Brian!
-Hang on, Mother!
-Hello, Mother.
-Don't you "hello, Mother" me.
-What are those people doing out there?
-Well, l....
Come on! What have you
been up to, my lad?
I think they must have
popped by for something.
Popped by?! Swelled by, more like.
There's a multitude out there!
They started following me yesterday.
Well, they can stop following
you right now.
Now stop following my son.
You ought to be ashamed of yourselves.
The Messiah! The Messiah!
Show us the Messiah!
-The who?
-The Messiah!
There's no Messiah in here.
There's a mess all right, but no Messiah.
Now go away!
Brian! Brian!
Right, my lad,
what have you been up to?
-Nothing, Mum.
-Come on, out with it.
They think I'm the Messiah, Mum.
-What have you been telling them?
-Nothing, l--
-You're only making it worse for yourself.
-Look, I can explain--
No, let me explain, Mrs. Cohen!
Your son is a born leader!
Those people out there are following him
because they believe in him.
They believe he can
give them hope.
Hope of a new life,
a new world, a better future!
-Who's that!?
-That's Judith, Mum.
Judith, Mother.
Show us the Messiah!
Now you listen here,
he's not the Messiah!
He's a very naughty boy! Now go away!
-Who are you?
-I'm his mother, that's who.
Behold his mother! Behold his mother!
Hail to thee, mother of Brian!
Blessed art thou! Hosanna!
All things to thee, now and always!
Now, don't think you can
get around me like that.
He's not coming out,
and that's my final word.
Now shove off!
No!
-Did you hear what I said?
-Yes!
-Oh, I see. It's like that, is it?
All right then, you can see him
for one minute, but not one second more!
-Do you understand?
-Yes.
-Promise?
-Well, all right.
All right, here he is then.
Come on, Brian, come and talk to them.
-But, Mum, Judith--
-Leave that Welsh tart alone.
I don't really want to, Mum.
-Good morning!
-A blessing! A blessing!
No, please. Please, please, listen!
I've got one or two things to say.
Tell us! Tell us both of them!
Look, you've got it all wrong!
You don't need to follow me.
You don't need to follow anybody!
You've got to think for yourselves.
You're all individuals!
Yes, we're all individuals!
You're all different.
Yes, we are all different!
I'm not.
You've all got to work it out
for yourselves!
Yes, we've got to work it
out for ourselves!
Exactly!
-Tell us more!
-No, that's the point!
Don't let anyone tell you what to do!
-Otherwise-- Oh, no!
-That's enough! That's enough.
That wasn't a minute.
-Oh, yes, it was.
-Oh, no, it wasn't!
Now stop that, and go away.
-Excuse me?
-Yes?
Are you a virgin?
I beg your pardon?
Well, if it's not a personal question,
are you a virgin?
If it's not a personal question?!
How much more personal can you get?
Now piss off.
-She is.
-Must be. Definitely.
Definitely. Definitely.
Morning, Saviour!
Lay your hands on me! Quick!
Now, don't jostle the chosen one!
Please!
Don't push that baby in the
Saviour's face! He'll touch it later!
I say....
Could he see my wife?
She has a headache.
You'll have to wait, I'm afraid!
She's very bad,
and we've got a luncheon!
Look, the lepers are queuing!
Her brother-in-law
is the ex-mayor of Gath.
Can I introduce you to the man who's
letting us have the mounts on Sunday?
-Hello.
-Don't push!
Now keep the noise down, please!
Those possessed by devils, try and keep
them under control a bit! Can't you?
Incurables, you'll just have
to wait for a few minutes.
Women taken in sin, line up
against that wall, will you?
Brian?
Brian! You were fantastic!
-You weren't so bad yourself.
-No, what you said just now!
-Quite extraordinary!
-What? Oh, that. Was it?
We don't need leaders! You're so right!
Reg has been dominating us for too long.
-Well, yes....
-lt needed saying, and you said it, Brian!
You're very attractive.
It's our revolution!
We can all do it together!
I think....
We're all behind you, Brian!
The revolution is in your hands!
What?
No, that's not what I meant at all!
You're fucking nicked, me old beauty!
Right!
Stop it!
Well, Brian, you've given us
a good run for our money.
A what?
And this time,
I guarantee you will not escape.
Guard!
Do we have any crucifixions today?
139, sir. Special celebration.
Passover, sir.
Right! Now we have 140!
Nice round number, eh, Biggus?
-Hail Caesar!
-Hail!
The crowd are getting restless, sir.
Permission to disperse them, please.
Disperse them?
But I haven't addressed them yet!
No, I know, sir, but--
My address is a high point
of Passover!
My friend Biggus Dickus has come
all the way from Rome to hear it!
-Hail Caesar!
You're not....
You're not thinking of giving
it a miss this year, then, sir?
Give it a miss?!
Well, it's just that they're
in a rather funny mood today, sir.
Really, centurion!
I'm surprised to hear a man like you
rattled by a rabble of rowdy rebels.
-A bit thundery, sir.
-Take him away!
I'm a Roman! I can prove it, honestly!
And crucify him well!
Biggus!
-I really wouldn't, sir!
-Out of the way, centurion!
Let me come with you, Pontius. I may be
of assistance if there is a sudden crisis!
Right! Now, item four: attainment of world
supremacy within the next five years.
-Francis, you've done some work on this?
-Yeah, thank you, Reg.
Well, quite frankly, siblings,
I think five years is optimistic...
...unless we can smash the Roman
Empire within the next 12 months!
-Twelve months?
-Yeah, 12 months.
And let's face it, as empires go,
this is the big one.
So we gotta get up off our arses
and stop just talking about it!
Hear! Hear!
I agree! It's action that counts,
not words, and we need action now!
You're right. We could sit around here
all day, talking, passing resolutions...
...making clever speeches,
it's not gonna shift one Roman soldier!
So let's just stop gabbing on about it!
It's completely pointless...
-...and it's getting us nowhere!
-Right!
I agree!
This is a complete waste of time!
They've arrested Brian!
-What?
-They've dragged him off!
They're gonna crucify him!
Right!
This calls for immediate discussion!
-What?!
-lmmediate!
-Right!
-New motion?
Completely new motion!
That there be immediate action....
Once the vote has been taken.
Obviously once the vote's been taken.
Can't act on a resolution--
-Reg, let's go now, please!
-Right! Right!
In the light of fresh information
from sibling Judith....
-Not so fast, Reg.
-Reg, for God's sake!
It's perfectly simple!
All you've gotta do is to go out
of that door now...
...and try to stop the Romans
nailing him up!
It's happening, Reg!
Something's actually happening, Reg!
Can't you understand?
-Yeah, hello.
-Another little ego trip from the feminists.
-What?
-Sorry, Loretta.
Read that back, would you?
Next.
-Crucifixion?
-Yes.
Good. Out of the door,
line on the left, one cross each.
Next.
Crucifixion?
Good. Out of the door, line on the left,
one cross each. Next.
-Crucifixion?
-No, freedom.
-What?
-Freedom for me.
They said I hadn't done anything
so I could go free and live on an island.
That's jolly good.
Well, off you go, then.
No, I'm only pulling your leg.
It's crucifixion, really.
I see. Very good, very good.
Well, out of the door.
Out of the door,
one cross each, line on the left.
Line on the left. Yes, thank you.
Crucifixion?
-Yes.
-Good.
People of Jerusalem!
Rome is your friend!
To prove our friendship,
it is customary at this time...
...to release a wrongdoer
from our prisons.
Whom would you have me release?
Release Roger!
Release Roger! Release Roger!
Very well, I shall release Roger!
Sir, we don't have a Roger, sir.
-What?
-We don't have anyone of that name, sir.
We have no Roger!
But what about Roderick, then?
Release Roderick! Release Roderick!
Centurion, why do they titter so?
Just some Jewish joke, sir.
Are they ragging me?
Oh, no, sir!
Very well. I shall release Roderick!
Sir, we don't have a Roderick either.
-No Roger, no Roderick?
-Sorry, sir.
Who is this--?
Who is this Roderick to whom you refer?
He is a robber!
And a rapist!
And a pickpocket!
He sounds a notorious criminal.
We haven't got him, sir.
Do we have anyone in our prisons?
-We've got a Samson, sir.
-Samson?
Samson the Sadducee Strangler, sir.
Silas the Syrian Assassin.
Several seditious scribes
from Caesarea.
Sixty-seven....
-Let me speak to them, Pontius!
-Oh, no!
Good idea, Biggus!
Citizens! We have Samson the Sadducee
Strangler, Silas the Assyrian Assassin...
...several seditious scribes
from Caesarea--
Next.
-Crucifixion?
-Yes.
Good. Out of the door,
line on the left, one cross each. Jailor?
-Excuse me? There's been a mistake--
-Just a moment, would you? Jailor?
-How many have come through?
-What?
How many have come through?
What?
You'll have to speak....
Speak up, sir.
He's-- He's d--
He's deaf-- Deaf as a post, sir.
How many have come through?
-Oh, dear.
-I make it 90--
Ninety--
Ninety-six, sir.
It's such a senseless waste
of human life, isn't it?
No, sir!
Not with these b--
Bastards, sir!
Crucifixion's too good for them, sir.
I don't think you could
say it's good, it's nasty!
It's not as n--
Not as nasty as something
I just thought up, sir.
-Now, crucifixion?
-ls there someone I could speak to?
-Well....
-I know where to get it if you want it.
-What?
-Don't worry about him, sir. He's de--
He's deaf and mad, sir.
Well, how did he get the job?
Bloody Pilate's pet, sir!
Get a move on, big nose! There's people
waiting to be crucified out here!
Could I see a lawyer or someone?
-Do you have a lawyer?
-No, but I'm a Roman.
How about a retrial?
We've got plenty of time.
-Shut up, you!
-Miserable, bloody Romans!
No sense of humour.
Sorry, bit of a hurry.
Can you go straight out,
line on the left, one cross each? Now....
Was it something I said?
Silence!
This man commands a crack legion!
He ranks as high as any in Rome!
Crucifixion party?
Morning.
Now, we will be on show as we go through
the town, so let's not let the side down!
Keep in a line, three lengths
between you and the man in front...
...and a good, steady pace.
Crosses over your left shoulders,
and if you keep your backs hard up...
...against the crossbeam
you'll be there in no time.
All right, centurion!
Crucifixion party!
Wait for it.
By the left! Forward!
You lucky bastards!
You lucky, jabby bastards!
Let me shoulder your burden, brother!
Thank you.
-Hey! Hey!
-What do you think you're doing?
It's not my cross--
Shut up and get on with it!
Come on!
He had you there, mate, didn't he?
That'll teach you a lesson!
All right!
I will give you one more chance!
This time I want to hear
no Rubens, no Reginalds...
...no Rudolph the Red-nosed Reindeers.
No Spencer Tracys!
Or we shall release no one!
Release Brian!
Yeah, that's a good one!
Release Brian! Release Brian!
Very well! That's it!
-Sir, we have got a Brian, sir.
-What?
-You just sent him for crucifixion, sir!
-Wait! Wait! We do have a Brian.
-Well, go and free him, straight away!
-Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Very well. I shall release Brian!
-Get a move on, there!
-Or what?
Or you'll be in trouble!
Oh, dear. You mean I might have to
give up being crucified in the afternoons?
-Shut up!
-That would be a blow, wouldn't it?
I wouldn't have nothing to do!
Thank you!
Are they gone?
We've got lumps of it around the back.
What?
Don't worry about him sir,
he's ma--
-He's mad, sir.
-Have they gone?
-Oh, come on.
-Yes, sir.
-Anyway, get on with the story.
-Well, I just never really liked them, so l--
Right! The motion to get on with it
passed with one abstention.
I propose we go without further ado.
May I have a second?
-Let's just go.
-Yeah.
-Bloody Romans!
-Watch it! Still a few crosses left!
Up you go, big nose!
I'll get you for this, you bastard!
-Oh, yeah!
-Yeah, don't worry. I never forget a face.
-No?
-I warn you.
I'm gonna punch you so hard,
you Roman git!
Shut up, you Jewish turd!
Who are you calling Jewish?
I'm not Jewish, I'm a Samaritan!
A Samaritan? This is supposed
to be a Jewish section!
It doesn't matter!
You're all gonna die in a day or two!
It may not matter to you,
but it matters to us. Doesn't it, darling?
Oh, rather!
Under the terms
of the Roman occupancy...
...we're entitled to be crucified
in a purely Jewish area.
Pharisees separate from Sadducees!
And Swedish separate from Welsh!
All right, all right, all right!
We'll soon settle this!
Hands up, all those who
don't want to be crucified here!
Right! Next!
-Look, it's not my cross.
-What?
It's not my cross,
I was holding it for someone.
-Just lie down, I haven't got all day!
-Of course. Look, I hate to make a fuss--
Look, we've had a busy day,
and there's 140 of you lot to get up.
-ls he Jewish?
-Will you be quiet?!
We don't want more
Samaritans around here.
Belt up!
-Will you let me down if he comes back?
-Yeah, yeah, we'll let you down.
-Next!
-You don't have to do this!
-You don't have to take orders!
-I like orders.
See? Not so bad once you're up.
-You're being rescued then, are you?
-It's a bit late for that now, isn't it?
No, we've got a couple of days up here.
Plenty of time.
Lots of people get rescued.
Oh, yeah.
My brother usually rescues me.
If he can keep off the tail
for more than 20 minutes.
Randy little bugger.
Up and down like the Assyrian Empire.
Hello. Your family arrived then?
Reg!
-Hello, sibling Brian.
-Thank God you've come, Reg.
I think I should point out in fairness
that we are not the rescue committee.
However, I have been asked to read
this prepared statement...
...on behalf of the movement.
"We, the People's Front of Judea,
brackets, officials, end brackets...
...do hereby convey our sincere fraternal
and sisterly greetings to you, Brian...
-...on this occasion of your martyrdom."
-What?
"Your death will stand as a landmark
in the continuing struggle to liberate...
...the parent land from the hands
of the Roman imperialist aggressors...
...excluding those concerned with
drainage, medicine, roads, housing...
...education. And any other Romans
contributing to the welfare of Jews...
...of both sexes
and hermaphrodites."
Signed, "On behalf of the PF.J.,
et cetera."
And I'd just like to add, on
a personal note, my own admiration...
...for what you're doing for us and what
must be, after all, for you, a difficult time.
-Reg! What are you going to do?
-Goodbye, Brian. And thanks.
All right, Brian. Keep it up, lad.
Terrific work, Brian.
Right. And:
For he's a jolly good fellow
And so say all of us
And so say all of--
You bastards! You bastards!
-Where is Brian of Nazareth?
-You sanctimonious bastards!
-I have an order for his release.
-You stupid bastards!
-I'm Brian of Nazareth.
-What?
-Take him down!
I'm Brian of Nazareth!
-I'm Brian!
Look, look, I'm Brian!
-I'm Brian and so is my wife!
-Right! Take him away and release him!
-No, I'm only joking. I'm not really Brian.
No, I'm not Brian! I was only--
It was a joke.
I'm only pulling your leg!
It's a joke!
I'm not him,
I'm just having you on!
Put me back!
Bloody Romans, can't take a joke.
The Judean People's Front!
Forward, all!
-Look out! The Judean People's Front!
-The Judean People's Front!
The Judean People's Front!
We are the Judean People's Front,
crack suicide squad.
Suicide squad, attack!
That showed them, huh?
You silly sods!
Brian!
Judith!
Terrific! Great! Reg explained it to me,
and I think it's great what you're doing.
Thank you, Brian. I'll never forget you.
So there you are!
I might have known
it would end up like this.
Just think of all the love
and affection I've wasted on you!
Well, if that's how you treat
your poor, old mother...
...in the autumn years of her life,
all I can say is:
Go ahead. Be crucified.
See if I care.
-I might have known.
-Mum! Mum!
I don't know what
the world is coming to.
Cheer up, Brian!
You know what they say?
Some things in life are bad.
They can really make you mad.
Other things just make
you swear and curse.
When you're chewing on life's gristle
Don't grumble
Give a whistle
And this'll help things
Turn out for the best
And
Always look on the bright side of life
Always look on the light side of life
If life seems jolly rotten
There's something you've forgotten
And that's to laugh and smile
And dance and sing
When you're feeling in the dumps
Don't be silly chumps
Just purse your lips and whistle
That's the thing
And always look on
The bright side of life
Come on!
Always look on the right side of life
For life is quite absurd
And death's the final word
You must always face
The curtain with a bow
Forget about your sin
Give the audience a grin
Enjoy it
It's your last chance anyhow
So always look on
The bright side of death
Just before
You draw your terminal breath
Life's a piece of shit
When you look at it
Life's a laugh and death's a joke
It's true
You'll see it's all a show
Keep 'em laughing as you go
Just remember that
The last laugh is on you
And always look on
The bright side of life
Always look on the right side of life
Come on, Brian! Cheer up!
Always look on the bright side of life
Worse things happen at sea,
you know?
Always look on the bright side of life
What have you got to lose?
You come from nothing...
...you're going back to nothing,
what have you lost?
Nothing!
Nothing will come from nothing,
you know what they say?
Cheer up, you old bugger!
Come on! Give us a grin!
There you are!
See? The end of the film. Incidentally,
this record is available in the foyer.
Some of us have got to live
as well, you know?
Who do you think pays
for all this rubbish?
They're not gonna make
their money back, you know.
I told them. I said to him.
"Bernie," I said,
"They'll never make their money back."