Subtitles by DramaFever
There are eight pain and sufferings
that humans go through.
Birth, aging, sickness, and death.
With these four...
Facing things you hate.
The pain of facing things you hate.
Saying goodbye to your loved ones.
The pain of saying goodbye
to your loved ones.
The pain of not getting what you want.
- Hello?
- Eun Ha Soo? I'll make it quick.
Come to the hospital, hurry.
The hospital?
- What happened? Did he go into surgery?
- Yes.
He can't go into surgery.
We should stop the surgery now!
- I'll start the anesthesia.
- Sure.
What is she taking so long?
We should stop the surgery.
- This is serious.
- What happened?
What took you so long?
I was going crazy.
- Come this way.
- What are you doing?
- Can't you see that he's in surgery?
- He needs her now.
If he has her nearby,
the pain will go away.
He can live again.
- Come to your senses, Manager Sung!
- Oh my goodness.
What condition is he in?
He's not in a critical condition, is he?
- We have to save him!
- Why are you doing this?
I will explain later.
Just let go of me for now.
Eun Ha Soo, let's go.
I said let go of me.
I said let go!
We will start now. Scalpel.
- What is it?
- He's going into cardiac arrest.
- Get it ready?
Five, six, seven, eight, nine...
- It's ready.
- Clear! Shock!
Charge.
One, two, three, four...
[Episode 10]
- How is he?
- He's making a quick recovery...
but he still needs to rest for now.
Why does that sign say, 'No Visitors?
The patient doesn't wish
to see anybody right now.
He can move around
so he asked his guardians
not to come in, either.
What is he doing?
I have to know how he is.
He should let us see him at least.
But it's a good thing that he regained
consciousness before the surgery.
What did you mean that his pain would stop
if Eun Ha Soo was by his side?
Well...
It's just hard to explain...
Why were you against the surgery?
Well, when he wakes up,
you can ask him yourself.
I'm not in a position to say anything.
I'm going to go ask the doctor
something and come right back.
Go home.
What about you?
I plan on taking her home
and coming back here.
I can take a taxi.
Get in. I have something
to tell you, too.
Do that. It's late,
so let him take you home.
So you're saying that
you've seen him like that, huh?
Yes.
I told him to go and see a doctor.
I thought you knew about it, too.
I didn't really care, so...
You two appear that way...
But I could feel that you worry
and care for each other.
I'm sure you two will get along fine.
He's so much like
my late father, you know.
So that might be difficult.
After my father passed away
I wished for a brother who
at least looked like him.
That's the difference between
whether you liked your father or not.
Don't you miss him, to be honest?
We're all like that, you know.
Whether you like the person or not
if the person leaves suddenly
you keep thinking about
the things you didn't get to say.
You're sorry for the feelings you didn't
get to work out with one another.
That's how I feel as well.
In any case, I'm grateful.
That there is someone
who worries about my brother.
And... he will get better.
Don't worry.
If he suddenly gets sick again
or something happens
- please call me.
- Sure, I will.
What? He disappeared from
his hospital room?
Where could he possibly go
in that condition?
Dae Han says he's about to go crazy.
He came over to see me.
He said he wanted see a psychiatrist.
The more time he spends
with Choi Shin Hyung
the more he feels that
he's like his late father.
Gosh, I even feel that way.
- Can you imagine how Dae Han must feel?
- But still...
No matter how much technology
has improved, he can't get that young.
God forbid, if he's really our brother,
what should we do?
We literally kicked him out in the rain.
We were teasing him like this, too.
What nonsense is that?
How can he possibly be
the late Chairman Choi?
Are we shooting a sci-fi movie or what?
I can't stand your pronunciation.
Either way, why did he disappear on us?
Does he have some kind of disease
we don't know about?
Like he's been diagnosed terminally ill?
- If so, why would he disappear?
- True.
Then maybe he has some kind
of contagious disease...
Like a rash that appears everywhere.
Did you forget that
he doesn't care about us?
- Wake up, sister-in-law!
- That's true.
It's better if he disappears
for good like this
but I have a feeling that
he'll show up again, huh?
What if he shows up with
a secret weapon next time?
He'll learn martial arts and use swords
against us like a kung fu master.
As  if he wants to kill us
like this and this...
Honey, it's me.
Gosh, aren't you having fun.
Where did he go?
He disappeared on me
while I was dozing off.
Manager Sung, how do you know
Choi Shin Hyung?
What are you talking about
all of a sudden?
You two seem very close.
It doesn't seem like you two
met a few months ago.
It's just that he's the
late Chairman Choi's son.
Plus, he asked that I take care of him
before he passed away.
That's why I was doing my best.
- Why? Does that bother you?
- That's not it.
To me, it looked as though
you were assisting my late father.
That can't possibly be true.
Your father passed away!
Seeing how you behaved yesterday
at the hospital left me wondering even more.
When you asked to stop the surgery
and when he was in the recovery room.
The way you worry that something
will happen to  Choi Shin Hyung...
wasn't just because of
my late father's request...
but you seemed very sincere.
Gosh, was I?
It's because I'm emotional.
I'll control my emotions next time.
You must have been really worried.
Is that really all there is?
Of course!
Why would I hide anything from you?
I like you, man.
I don't know if I was hallucinating
about my late father...
My heart tells me that
he's definitely my father
but my brain doesn't agree.
His blood is definitely identical
to my late father's...
But he can't be my father.
He says he isn't my father either,
so it's driving me crazy.
- If you feel he's your father, then he is.
- Pardon?
It's because they're so alike, you know.
Anyway, please find out
where Choi Shin Hyung might be.
If you find him,
please let me know right away.
Of course, I will.
- Is that why you called me here?
- Yes.
You could have called me
on the phone instead!
I should be running around
looking for him.
Gosh, that was for nothing.
Because he never trusted me.
Not even once.
Father.
Father, father!
I think you're my father. Father.
Daddy, can I eat sweet and sour pork today?
Here, eat this.
Not jjajangmyun,
but sweet and sour pork.
Why would you order sweet and sour pork
when you can't even finish this?
Eat up.
- I won't eat then!
- How rude.
We had a play about an old man
with a lump at kindergarten yesterday.
You didn't come.
All the other kids' parents
came to take pictures.
- They brought flowers, too.
- It was enough that your mom was there.
Daddy was busy working yesterday.
Go on.
No, I won't eat it.
Eat up!
Aren't you going to eat?
I said eat!
What's the big deal with this
measly sweet and sour pork, huh?
I couldn't even buy him this.
Why did I do that to you?
Why was I living like that then?
What kind of fortunate life
was I trying to live?
I thought it was right to live
like that at that time.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, my son.
[My dreams.]
[Be happy every day.]
[Make memories sometimes.]
[Learn to ride a bicycle again.]
[Try a parachute like my son.]
[Go on a trip with my son.]
[Make seaweed soup
on my son's birthday.]
[Choi Dae Han]
[Eun Ha Soo]
Are you okay?
I'm not doing well.
I'm too worried to sleep tonight.
[Choi Shin Hyung]
Redirecting your call...
- What's up?
- About Choi Shin Hyung...
I can't get in touch with him,
so I was wondering if everything was okay.
- He disappeared.
- Pardon?
I don't think he's in contact
with anybody right now.
I don't know if he has
a serious illness or...
Then...
You said he was someone who's
eventually going to leave.
What did you mean by that?
It was just a hunch.
I said that because I wouldn't
be able to stand him much long.
But I'm kind of worried now.
I have a feeling that
I had something to do with it.
I told him that I really liked you.
Maybe he didn't want
things to come between brothers.
That might be why he left.
It's really hard to have dinner
with you, huh?
You asked me to buy you dinner
all the time when we were in school.
Why are you bringing up
the past again?
I should have asked you out then.
I might have taken too long.
Stop it and eat.
I heard Choi Shin Hyung disappeared.
After a dispute with President Choi
he decided to go elsewhere for good?
I don't think that's what it is.
He seems to have a health issue.
He may want to be left alone.
More importantly, what was that
about President Choi?
He seems to be working
to revive Seohae Hotel.
Was that your idea?
Well, I thought if that went well...
then his place at the company
will be secure.
How long will you live as his shadow?
If something goes wrong,
you'll get hurt, too.
Walk away now.
I'll do a good job,
so we won't get hurt.
Do you really have feelings
for Choi Dae Han?
Are you serious?
He doesn't even see me that way.
Does it matter whether
I'm serious or not?
Are you okay? I'm not doing well.
I'm too worried to sleep tonight.
Why did you turn your phone off?
Where in the world did you go?
Are you really not
going to answer my calls?
I won't ever call you again.
- You still can't get a hold of him?
- No.
Gosh, what happened?
What if he left for
someplace far away?
What if he gets sick again?
In the morning of 48th day
of being young
he couldn't wake up for good.
How should I spend
this precious time I was given
so I may die without regrets?
Choi Go Bong!
Let's go back and
try aging the proper way!
- Where have you been?
- Well, here and there.
How could you just disappear like that?
We live together.
You should at least answer the phone.
Now that my phone
is turned on, call me.
How sick are you?
When did it start?
The doctor said you didn't have
any serious diseases.
- It was nothing.
- Why didn't you want the surgery?
Don't you know that
it could damage your heart?
You don't need to worry about that.
Then...
did you stay away because of me?
Eun Ha Soo is worried about you.
Call her now.
- Why should I?
- She's waiting for your call!
Don't just walk away
after you made her fall for you.
You know how irresponsible that is.
And if you go somewhere,
let me know from now on.
[Choi Go Bong has 22 days
to return on his payment.]
Did you have dinner?
This was in my room.
Why do you have this?
Give it to me.
- I said give it.
- No.
What are you going to do with it?
It's a keepsake from my father.
I want to keep it.
Go. I'm going to go to bed now.
When my father was around,
we were always number one.
- We have a problem now.
- That's why Seohae Hotel has to work.
And about Choi Shin Hyung...
it might damage your reputation
to have him work as a janitor.
I also started from that position
when my father was around.
Back then, his reputation
improved because of it.
Saying that he was
teaching his son properly.
It worked because
he was your father...
you two are half-brothers.
- Anybody will assume...
- So what are you proposing?
I really don't know how you feel
about Choi Shin Hyung.
Do you... acknowledge him
as your older brother now?
He was willing to take the fall
and go to prison for me.
It seems President Choi is
really starting to work now, huh?
They're asking for employees to apply?
Ha Soo, should we apply for this?
Well, we will have to
go out there to work.
Why not? It's near the ocean,
so it should be nice.
Plus, if President Choi works hard
it will save us interns, too.
He read them.
Why hasn't he responded
if he's read them yet?
Can we talk?
Since the work is off-site,
there are only few applicants.
I hope you can help out.
You've changed your mind, huh?
Why are you offering this to me?
To me, you're just like
the late Chairman Choi.
I'm sure that you've inherited
his business skills as well.
What grounds do you
have to say such things?
If you make it work
we will give you an appropriate title.
I told you to stay home.
Why did you come?
What am I, an old man?
People might think that
I have a serious illness.
'If it's something you really want to do'
'you will see a way.'
'If it's something you dread'
'you will see an excuse.'
As for Seohae Hotel...
I told you not to mention
that name, didn't I?
It's where my mother died.
My mother and I stayed there
while my father was too busy working.
It isn't some place for you
to speak so freely about.
That's why you should protect it!
If the hotel can't improve
its facilities immediately
you have to at least
make guests like it.
What can you possibly do
by sitting behind a desk?
During this critical moment,
you should be out there.
Go out there!
Go and find who we should
target to bring in!
Father.
Seriously.
There you go again.
My sister-in-law is quick, huh?
Seriously, Young Dal, too.
Since we're talking about it
In order to push away the idea
of reviving Seohae Hotel
their idea isn't good enough.
If we make a deal with luxury brand names
that haven't been imported yet
I think we can get
some attention that way.
That's also what I'm good at.
There's a fashion show of
premium designers in Italy next week.
I received an invitation.
I wasn't going to go...
but maybe I should then.
Go then.
Everything is about
who you know in this field.
Pay special attention to lobbying.
If I'm going to go,
we should go together.
Where can I possibly go
when the company is in a crisis?
It's not because of Hong Ji Yoon, is it?
A woman like her isn't fun.
We only live once, so we should
enjoy it as much as we can, huh?
Let's see what happens.
If this matter gets resolved well...
What are you going to do
about Choi Shin Hyung?
He's the one who gave us
the fake documents on Cruise Hotel.
Are you going to just leave him alone?
- There are this many?
- It won't be easy.
I will go over it with you.
Your management power depends on
how this Seohae Hotel turns out.
You showed confidence
to the board of directors...
so you must make it work.
I got it, so start.
What is this?
Is there something wrong, Aunt?
It's a sample of Meditel in America.
Oh my.
It can't be.
My late father definitely told me
that this was for Cruise Hotel...
If you continue to scam people
using my brother's name like that
I can send you to prison for real.
Oh my.
It hasn't been that long
since I was discharged.
You brought my brother down with
the secret accounting ledger I gave you.
You're trying to take over Daehan
any way you can?
Bring the original immediately.
- The deal has to be fair.
- If I give you the original...
You'll hand it over
to Jung Yi Gun...
and do you really think you two
will live happily ever after?
- What?
- Come to your senses!
It wasn't enough that you were scammed
to get married and got divorced?
How foolish are you to be used by men!
Is that what your brother taught you?
He didn't even eat much to support
his siblings until he passed away.
How can you possibly do this to him?
Who are you?
'Please stop breaking my heart!'
I mean my father in Heaven
would say that!
What do you possibly know?
What do you possibly know
about my turbulent life?
Go down further.
To the left.
- Seriously.
- Gosh, you lost it.
- Can I have more coins?
- I'm all out.
- Stop it.
- I wanted to get that stuffed dog.
This thing is built
so that you don't win.
Catch. Shin Hyung gave this to me.
Hello there.
Migratory birds follow the wind
to get to their hometown.
The ocean follows the waves
to get to the horizon.
I'm thinking of following
the blue sky...
and get to The Milky Way, Eun Ha Soo.
Can I do that?
[I'm okay. Sorry that I worried you.]
He didn't misspell one word.
The Milky Way, Eun Ha Soo.
Now I'm hearing things, huh?
Why does a grown woman
walk around alone at this late hour?
Where are we going?
I wanted to give you
a present to apologize.
You literally disappeared
and worried me to death.
How can you show up like this?
I'm not that easy.
A present won't make me forgive you.
It's pretty.
What do you think? Do you like it?
It's so pretty.
We can even see the constellations.
- Do you know the constellations?
- A little bit.
Way up there, it looks like the Orion.
Where? Huh?
- Where?
- Well...
Over there.
Is it the one that looks like
a crushed scoop?
Yes.
The legend about the
Orion constellation is of
an unfulfilled love between
a human and a god.
The Goddess Artemis
who fell in love with Orion...
was tricked by her brother and
ended up shooting an arrow to kill Orion.
Gosh, it's a tragedy.
What kind of ending will we have?
We've just started out, but you're
already thinking of how this will end?
It's because it's better not to start
if we expect a bad ending.
There's no way of knowing how it's going
to end unless you start something.
Well, that's not entirely true.
Why are you already
thinking about how it ends?
It could go on forever
and be beautiful...
like those stars.
Like The Milky Way, Eun Ha Soo?
I'll have a lot of work
to do from now on.
I'm saying this because
I'll be very busy.
If there's anything special
you'd like to do with me
write down five things.
Only five things?
That's all we can do together?
Well, at least for now...
It's your homework.
Will you write them down?
Fine.
What is your zodiac sign?
My zodiac sign?
- Not sure.
- When is your birthday?
November 5.
Let's see. If it's November 5...
your sign is Libra.
My sign is Libra?
Mine is Sagittarius, because
my birthday is in December.
Is it?
Your birthday is coming up soon then.
After you disappeared all of a sudden
where were you hiding?
How is Dae Han doing with Seohae Hotel?
You're worrying about your son
at a time like this?
They say blood is thicker than water,
and I can see why.
- What?
- It's about Dae Han.
Do you know how worried he was
after you disappeared?
I guess he gets bored
when I'm not around.
Stop worrying about your son...
and start to enjoy yourself.
Do the things you haven't done
and try all the foods you haven't tried.
What?
Every moment is precious.
What if the 48th day is really
the last day of your life?
How upsetting is that?
So do everything you couldn't
do before because of work.
It's not like you're short on money.
By the way, how much
do you like Eun Ha Soo?
You're not in love with her, are you?
You punk, seriously.
- There's nothing you won't say now, huh?
- We'll get into a car accident.
Drive properly, okay?
Hey there, are you going somewhere?
I'm going to apply for
a position at Seohae Hotel.
Why? Why would you?
I hear no one wants to do it.
It's about promotion the hotel,
so I'll probably learn a lot.
It would be better if I could contribute.
Thank you.
Both of you are thanking me.
When you disappeared from the hospital
President Choi thanked me
for worrying about you.
He did?
- Did he do that, huh?
- Yes.
- Go about your work .
- I'll get going.
Every moment is precious.
What if the 48th day is really
the last day of your life?
How upsetting is that?
So do all the things you couldn't do
when you were young.
So I was wondering if any of you
would want to go and work there.
It won't be higher pay and you may
have to work longer hours
But it could be a good opportunity
for someone who wants to learn.
First take a look at the plan
Manager Hong gave us and think about it.
It could be hard...
but if we cooperate,
we can at least try.
Well said.
Please follow me.
Welcome to Seohae Hotel.
- Why are you here?
- President Choi.
I came to see how well
you'll pull this off.
How dare you come here?
Let go.
Do you have any idea
how special this place is to me?
I asked him to come.
Why?
I'll tell you later.
- I'm sorry I didn't tell you earlier.
- Sorry for what?
You did the right thing, Manager Hong.
Good thing that you scouted
such a talent like me.
Let's go, okay?
He drives me crazy.
- Wow, it's nice.
- It's clean.
It's nice.
Even if it's dispatched work,
it's still nice to come this far.
I feel like I'm on a trip.
I'm all excited.
As if a sudden trip
leading to a love affair?
Listen to yourself.
You're definitely in love, aren't you?
Saying things you don't normally say.
You're so happy to see
Choi Shin Hyung here, aren't you?
I was shocked.
Why did you call him here?
You know very well
what this place means to me.
Choi Shin Hyung possesses
the late Chairman Choi's techniques.
Rather than letting your personal
feelings get in the way
you must focus on reviving
Seohae Hotel right now.
How do you not let your personal
feelings get in the way?
I'm more amazed by that.
It could be a sign that
you're full of emotions and innocent.
- What's so funny?
- No, he's just very funny.
What? Can't I be funny?
We do this to make a living.
We live to laugh.
Don't you think so?
- Is it or isn't it?
- What are you doing?
Is it or isn't it?
You're driving me nuts.
Stop it, seriously.
Seriously?
What are they doing?
Fighting or what?
Please stop!
Gosh, I'm tired.
How could you two play like little kids?
Men usually get into it
once they get started.
- Oh my.
- Gosh, that man...
I wonder who he takes after
to get so worked up like that.
To me, you two are so alike.
But it has been a while since
we played around together.
- Pardon?
- No, nothing.
Anyway, did you think about
your homework?
I thought about it,
but I just had too many.
I'll do whatever you ask for,
so choose wisely.
Why are you asking me that, though?
Are you going to leave after
we complete the homework or something?
Nonsense.
If not, why are you asking me
those questions?
That's because I feel like
doing that for you.
So stop the nonsense, and just tell me.
It's something very hard to do...
Come on, tell me.
After we go back, I'll text you
one by one every morning.
How am I supposed to wait that long?
Just tell me now.
No, I'm going to text you.
Gosh.
- It's not bad.
- Isn't it?
Let's demolish the lousy
Seohae Hotel immediately...
and start construction.
The premium brands are already
trying to get their store sites.
As President Choi and Choi Shin Hyung
are working on Seohae Hotel now
it may not be easy.
Why don't we send them
together overseas?
We can push forward with it
while they are away.
We're doing this for the sake
of the company, you know.
How can we do that?
It's always women that move men.
It will be an easy task
if we use this woman.
A woman?
Now we write our wishes in this lantern.
We ask the guests
to write their wishes down...
and we put it inside this case.
We will demonstrate how it's done.
Why don't we all write on
a piece of paper?
- What are you writing?
- You can't look.
- Don't look.
Now write your name on the case too.
Put the piece of paper
inside the lantern now.
Let's wish that your wishes
will come true.
I want to thank those who volunteered
to come out here today.
To me, I feel today will be
a precious day I won't ever forget.
I'm embarrassed to say that
for the first time...
I feel that I depend on you.
Thank you very much.
And... Eun Ha Soo.
Thank you.
What are you doing here?
I was just getting some air.
Now that you're here,
how do you like it here?
Now I look at it again, it's too good
to give it to someone else.
Isn't this your first time here?
Ah, that's right.
Our late father did a good job
building this.
Go inside.
You could catch a cold.
I like that he worries about me...
but it oddly makes me feel bad.
Was it a yellow lantern?
Ah, here it is!
Goodness, her handwriting is pretty.
What did she write?
I'm very happy now,
thanks to Choi Shin Hyung.
I wish this precious time
would last forever.
Aren't you going to tell me
what you wrote?
- I can tell from your expression.
- What? What is it?
- 'I wish I'd get married this year.'
- Hey.
- How many days are left in this year?
- If you like him, go for it.
Why take it slow?
Can I see you real quick?
Hey, you're here.
Man, you weren't even surprised?
What's all this, huh?
Is everything okay?
It'll take about two hours.
Is that okay?
Yes, I'm okay with that.
What is it?
- [Let's start.]
- Gosh, he even makes me do this now?
Choi Shin Hyung.
It's a movie I wanted to see with you.
I chose it on my own without asking you.
Do you like it?
Will it be okay even if it's boring?
Wait, isn't Alain Delon in this movie?
How did you know that?
Have you seen it?
No.
I haven't seen it,
but my late father really liked it.
I see. He did, huh?
I'm very happy now,
thanks to Choi Shin Hyung.
I wish this precious moment
would last forever.
How was it?
Was it interesting?
Subtitles by DramaFever