1
00:00:11,511 --> 00:00:15,470
<i>[Sirens Wailing]</i>

2
00:00:19,853 --> 00:00:22,549
<i>[Machine Gun Fire]</i>

3
00:00:27,527 --> 00:00:30,496
<i>[Gunfire Continues]</i>

4
00:00:34,000 --> 00:00:38,369
<i>[Sirens Continue]</i>

5
00:00:41,941 --> 00:00:44,842
<i>[Man On P.A., Indistinct]</i>

6
00:00:44,944 --> 00:00:47,936
<i>- [Sirens Continue]</i>
<i>- [Gunfire Continues]</i>

7
00:01:07,567 --> 00:01:11,526
<i>- [Man On P.A. Continues, Indistinct]</i>
<i>- [Gunfire Continues]</i>

8
00:01:13,239 --> 00:01:16,697
<i>[Sirens Continue]</i>

9
00:02:10,830 --> 00:02:12,923
Freedom.

10
00:02:13,032 --> 00:02:15,523
Free-dom!

11
00:02:18,138 --> 00:02:20,106
[Roars]

12
00:02:21,307 --> 00:02:23,275
[Roars]

13
00:02:30,550 --> 00:02:32,074
<i>[Woman]</i>
<i>What you want</i>

14
00:02:32,185 --> 00:02:33,948
- Here come the dishwasher!
<i>- Baby, I got it</i>

15
00:02:34,053 --> 00:02:36,180
- Here come the dishwasher!
<i>- [Continues]</i>

16
00:02:36,289 --> 00:02:38,348
[All Chattering, Laughing]

17
00:02:38,458 --> 00:02:40,449
Automatic. Dishmatic.

18
00:02:40,560 --> 00:02:42,619
- But no pay-a-matic!
- "No pay-a-matic!"

19
00:02:42,729 --> 00:02:44,890
[All Laughing]

20
00:02:44,998 --> 00:02:47,398
No pay- No money down!

21
00:02:47,500 --> 00:02:49,468
[All Shouting]
No money down!

22
00:02:50,737 --> 00:02:52,466
Mr. Freedom's coming!

23
00:02:54,407 --> 00:02:57,137
All right, don't nobody move!
Nobody.

24
00:02:57,243 --> 00:03:00,303
<i>[Continues]</i>

25
00:03:00,413 --> 00:03:04,509
Boy, that's the last time
you loot a Magic Mix Mart.

26
00:03:04,617 --> 00:03:06,847
I'm gonna set you right, boy.

27
00:03:06,953 --> 00:03:09,649
I ain't a-lootin', I'm a-shootin'.

28
00:03:10,356 --> 00:03:12,620
<i>Say your prayers!</i>

29
00:03:12,725 --> 00:03:15,125
<i>[Sirens Wailing]</i>

30
00:03:15,228 --> 00:03:17,992
Now, everybody,
let's all sing together.

31
00:03:18,097 --> 00:03:21,897
F-R-double-E-D, D-O-M spells -

32
00:03:22,936 --> 00:03:26,463
F-R-double-E-D, D-O-M spells...

33
00:03:26,573 --> 00:03:28,473
freedom!

34
00:03:28,575 --> 00:03:32,875
We fight for freedom
for one and for all

35
00:03:32,979 --> 00:03:35,106
It's you and me-dom

36
00:03:35,215 --> 00:03:38,048
And 10 foot tall

37
00:03:38,151 --> 00:03:40,449
Freedom, freedom

38
00:03:40,553 --> 00:03:42,987
And oh-can-you-see-dom

39
00:03:43,089 --> 00:03:45,182
We'll always beat 'em

40
00:03:45,291 --> 00:03:49,250
With star-spangled freedom

41
00:03:49,362 --> 00:03:52,331
Yeah! Freedom!

42
00:03:52,432 --> 00:03:54,400
Wow!

43
00:03:54,500 --> 00:03:56,468
[Beeping]

44
00:03:56,569 --> 00:04:00,300
Excellent, Freedom Four.
Terminate operation.

45
00:04:00,406 --> 00:04:02,931
Your presence is required
at Central Freedom.

46
00:04:03,042 --> 00:04:06,034
Your presence
is required at Central Freedom.

47
00:04:06,145 --> 00:04:07,874
Over and out.

48
00:04:07,981 --> 00:04:09,972
I gotta go, folks.

49
00:04:10,083 --> 00:04:11,948
<i>[Gunfire Continues]</i>

50
00:04:12,051 --> 00:04:15,316
But before I do,
here's a little souvenir from Freedom.

51
00:04:18,625 --> 00:04:20,923
<i>[Woman Screaming]</i>

52
00:04:50,723 --> 00:04:53,783
Thank you. So nice!

53
00:04:53,893 --> 00:04:56,020
Yes, that's divine.

54
00:04:56,129 --> 00:04:59,030
[Laughs, Giggles]

55
00:04:59,132 --> 00:05:01,032
Oh!

56
00:05:01,134 --> 00:05:04,194
Mr. Freedom!
[Giggles]

57
00:05:04,304 --> 00:05:07,205
How are you?

58
00:05:07,307 --> 00:05:09,741
Thank you. So nice.

59
00:05:09,842 --> 00:05:12,072
Yes, I'm fine.

60
00:05:12,178 --> 00:05:14,612
Oh, I'm sorry. And you?

61
00:05:14,714 --> 00:05:17,148
Oh, lovely.
[Giggles]

62
00:05:17,250 --> 00:05:19,150
So thoughtful.

63
00:05:19,252 --> 00:05:21,652
Oh, I'm sorry. Do you -

64
00:05:21,754 --> 00:05:24,882
Oh, you're so right.

65
00:05:24,991 --> 00:05:27,459
How sweet of you.

66
00:05:27,560 --> 00:05:29,687
Oh, I'm sorry.

67
00:05:29,796 --> 00:05:32,264
Dr. Freedom is waiting for you.

68
00:05:32,365 --> 00:05:34,265
This way, please.

69
00:05:34,367 --> 00:05:37,393
Oh, you're so right!

70
00:05:37,503 --> 00:05:40,472
Thank you!
[Giggles]

71
00:05:53,586 --> 00:05:57,181
<i>[Woman] Dr. Freedom, sir,</i>
<i>Mr. Freedom to see you.</i>

72
00:05:58,825 --> 00:06:02,727
- Freedom fights on all fronts.
<i>- Yes, sir.</i>

73
00:06:02,829 --> 00:06:05,730
- You have done your bit.
<i>- I've done my best, sir.</i>

74
00:06:05,832 --> 00:06:07,732
Yes.

75
00:06:07,834 --> 00:06:11,600
And you know that the world
is divided in two parts -

76
00:06:11,704 --> 00:06:14,867
On the one side is right...

77
00:06:14,974 --> 00:06:17,943
and on the other side is wrong.

78
00:06:18,044 --> 00:06:19,944
Wrong is red...

79
00:06:20,046 --> 00:06:21,843
and right is -

80
00:06:21,948 --> 00:06:25,714
- Red, white and blue!
- Yes.

81
00:06:25,818 --> 00:06:30,448
And in the middle we have
the maybes and the don't-knows.

82
00:06:30,556 --> 00:06:33,047
First, we have two objectives -

83
00:06:33,159 --> 00:06:35,423
make the Reds cry "uncle" -

84
00:06:35,528 --> 00:06:37,723
<i>- Uncle Sam!</i>
- Yes.

85
00:06:37,830 --> 00:06:40,492
Then maybe the maybes
and the don't-knows...

86
00:06:40,600 --> 00:06:42,932
will wake up and fight for right...

87
00:06:43,035 --> 00:06:46,402
for right is might,
and might is -

88
00:06:46,506 --> 00:06:49,202
- Freedom!
- Yes, sir.

89
00:06:49,308 --> 00:06:51,572
Our freedom.

90
00:06:51,677 --> 00:06:53,872
Now listen to me, boy.

91
00:06:53,980 --> 00:06:56,881
We have trouble in France.

92
00:06:56,983 --> 00:07:00,475
The Red commies
are infiltrating from Switzerland.

93
00:07:00,586 --> 00:07:03,111
- So we bomb Switzerland.
- Good thinking, boy.

94
00:07:03,222 --> 00:07:06,919
But we can't.
Not right now.

95
00:07:07,026 --> 00:07:09,586
Let me tell you about the French.

96
00:07:09,695 --> 00:07:13,028
They are 50 million...

97
00:07:13,132 --> 00:07:15,828
mixed-up, sniveling crybabies...

98
00:07:15,935 --> 00:07:18,961
who haven't stood on their two feet
since Napoléon.

99
00:07:19,071 --> 00:07:21,403
And that wasn't yesterday.

100
00:07:21,507 --> 00:07:24,237
And Napoléon wasn't even French.

101
00:07:24,343 --> 00:07:27,574
- He was Corsican.
- That's right, boy.

102
00:07:27,680 --> 00:07:31,343
So the French
are the white man's burden.

103
00:07:31,451 --> 00:07:33,681
<i>Our</i> burden.

104
00:07:33,786 --> 00:07:37,688
We've had to carry them
through two world wars already...

105
00:07:37,790 --> 00:07:40,759
and we're damn well gonna have to
carry them through the next.

106
00:07:40,860 --> 00:07:43,328
But I'd rather carry them.

107
00:07:43,429 --> 00:07:47,525
I'd rather carry them
than let the Red commies get to them...

108
00:07:47,633 --> 00:07:50,534
and that's what's gonna happen
if we don't move fast.

109
00:07:50,636 --> 00:07:51,967
<i>How come?</i>

110
00:07:52,071 --> 00:07:55,802
Anti-Freedomism is at a new high.

111
00:07:55,908 --> 00:08:00,470
Our group is demoralized
and they need a leader.

112
00:08:00,580 --> 00:08:02,844
They need you.

113
00:08:04,417 --> 00:08:06,544
I need you...

114
00:08:07,820 --> 00:08:10,118
in France.

115
00:08:10,223 --> 00:08:13,090
- But you have Captain Formidable there.
- We had.

116
00:08:13,192 --> 00:08:16,593
<i>- You "had"?</i>
- We had, boy. We had.

117
00:08:16,696 --> 00:08:19,995
Capitaine Formidable is dead.

118
00:08:20,099 --> 00:08:22,067
<i>- He's dead?</i>
- He was killed.

119
00:08:22,168 --> 00:08:27,333
I have reason to believe by someone
posing as a Freedom operator.

120
00:08:27,440 --> 00:08:31,171
This is, no doubt, the work
of Red China Man.

121
00:08:31,277 --> 00:08:33,177
<i>Red China Man?</i>

122
00:08:33,279 --> 00:08:35,577
But Captain Formidable, he -

123
00:08:35,681 --> 00:08:37,649
I know.

124
00:08:37,750 --> 00:08:40,218
I know, boy.
He was your buddy.

125
00:08:40,319 --> 00:08:43,049
You helped set up
the French Freedom organization with him.

126
00:08:43,155 --> 00:08:44,816
That's why I have chosen you.

127
00:08:44,924 --> 00:08:49,020
You know the country, you know the people,
you speak their language.

128
00:08:49,128 --> 00:08:52,586
Your mission is search and destroy.

129
00:08:52,698 --> 00:08:55,826
Insurgency and counterinsurgency.

130
00:08:55,935 --> 00:08:59,234
Revolutionary pacification.

131
00:08:59,338 --> 00:09:02,535
Take our story to the people.

132
00:09:02,642 --> 00:09:05,133
Win their hearts and their minds.

133
00:09:05,244 --> 00:09:07,804
You have full powers.

134
00:09:07,914 --> 00:09:12,044
I don't need to tell you
that if France falls...

135
00:09:12,151 --> 00:09:14,779
Europe is wide open.

136
00:09:14,887 --> 00:09:17,583
You must not fail.

137
00:09:17,690 --> 00:09:20,682
You shall be Mr. Freedom...

138
00:09:20,793 --> 00:09:22,761
for France.

139
00:09:25,331 --> 00:09:28,027
<i>Vive la France.</i>

140
00:09:28,134 --> 00:09:29,726
<i>Vive la France!</i>

141
00:09:59,131 --> 00:10:01,099
[Speaking Japanese]

142
00:10:27,593 --> 00:10:29,322
[Bell Dings]

143
00:10:29,428 --> 00:10:31,123
Hi, Freedom!

144
00:10:31,230 --> 00:10:32,857
Captain Formidable!

145
00:10:38,604 --> 00:10:42,267
Old buddy,
I see you wherever I go.

146
00:10:42,375 --> 00:10:45,344
I'll never forget you.

147
00:10:56,822 --> 00:10:58,790
[Bell Dings]

148
00:11:13,572 --> 00:11:16,871
Okay, so you're a broad. Don't think
that's gonna stop me. I'll bust you in a -

149
00:11:16,976 --> 00:11:19,342
[Yells]

150
00:11:19,445 --> 00:11:21,345
Okay, baby.

151
00:11:21,447 --> 00:11:23,415
So you wanna play.

152
00:11:26,085 --> 00:11:27,985
[Woman Grunting]

153
00:11:28,087 --> 00:11:30,351
- [Giggles]
- [Woman Grunts]

154
00:11:35,461 --> 00:11:37,361
So now you know, baby.

155
00:11:37,463 --> 00:11:41,900
I don't beat up a broad unless I have to.
But if I have to, I have to. Right? Right.

156
00:11:42,001 --> 00:11:44,902
Who sent you?
Who do you work for?

157
00:11:45,004 --> 00:11:47,131
For Freedom.
I was with Capitaine Formidable.

158
00:11:47,239 --> 00:11:49,264
Yeah. Prove it!

159
00:11:52,445 --> 00:11:55,346
Marie Madeleine. French girl.
Common-law widow of Captain Formidable.

160
00:11:55,448 --> 00:11:58,383
- Right.
- There's something else.

161
00:11:58,484 --> 00:12:02,318
We fight for freedom
for one and for all

162
00:12:02,421 --> 00:12:06,221
It's you and me-dom
and 10 foot tall

163
00:12:06,325 --> 00:12:09,886
Okay, baby,
let's start from the beginning.

164
00:12:12,331 --> 00:12:14,799
[Elevator Motor Resumes]

165
00:12:17,069 --> 00:12:18,969
So, what's with the jujitsu?

166
00:12:19,071 --> 00:12:21,471
Well, I wanted to make sure
it was you.

167
00:12:21,574 --> 00:12:24,600
Red China Man's been trying to infiltrate us.
He'll stop at nothing.

168
00:12:24,710 --> 00:12:27,406
Already with Capitaine Formidable,
he - he -

169
00:12:27,513 --> 00:12:31,574
- Don't talk about it if you don't want to.
- Oh, no, you gotta know.

170
00:12:31,684 --> 00:12:35,347
After Greece,
Capitaine Formidable was very tired.

171
00:12:35,454 --> 00:12:39,185
When Geneva backfired,
the Swiss got hold of him...

172
00:12:39,291 --> 00:12:41,657
and they brainwashed him.

173
00:12:41,761 --> 00:12:43,661
But I mean all the way.

174
00:12:43,763 --> 00:12:46,926
He fought it, so they drugged him.

175
00:12:47,032 --> 00:12:49,000
The works.

176
00:12:49,101 --> 00:12:52,366
And then he couldn't stop.
He went into a spin.

177
00:12:52,471 --> 00:12:56,373
And in the end,
he even began having doubts.

178
00:12:56,475 --> 00:12:58,636
- About what?
- Oh, you know.

179
00:12:58,744 --> 00:13:02,407
About Freedom. About everything.

180
00:13:02,515 --> 00:13:07,384
And that's when Moujik Man infiltrated us
disguised as a Freedom agent.

181
00:13:07,486 --> 00:13:11,616
He had his card,
his uniform, everything.

182
00:13:11,724 --> 00:13:15,626
And then he started to tell us about
how there was trouble in America...

183
00:13:15,728 --> 00:13:18,492
about how the Negroes
were going to revolt...

184
00:13:18,597 --> 00:13:22,158
and about how you <i>weren't</i>
going to bomb China.

185
00:13:22,268 --> 00:13:25,829
And then after the riots,
when you didn't take Paris...

186
00:13:25,938 --> 00:13:30,272
well, after all, Capitaine Formidable
started to believe him.

187
00:13:30,376 --> 00:13:33,209
And then, you know -

188
00:13:33,312 --> 00:13:35,872
[Man Screaming]

189
00:13:35,981 --> 00:13:38,313
Yeah, well, we weren't
ready for Paris.

190
00:13:38,417 --> 00:13:41,511
But if only I could have
talked to him, explained.

191
00:13:41,620 --> 00:13:45,852
- But, Jesus, to get taken in by Moujik Man -
- Oh, yes, it was awful.

192
00:13:45,958 --> 00:13:49,758
But you've got to try and understand
from here things look different.

193
00:13:49,862 --> 00:13:53,320
Like in Vietnam, for instance.
What's holding you back?

194
00:13:53,432 --> 00:13:57,061
I mean, don't get angry,
but to us it looks like a -

195
00:13:57,169 --> 00:14:00,627
Like what? Listen, baby,
there's us and there's them.

196
00:14:00,739 --> 00:14:03,333
We are Freedom, the real America.

197
00:14:03,442 --> 00:14:07,640
<i>They</i> are Red-ass, black-ass, Jew-ass farts
who can't even spell America.

198
00:14:07,746 --> 00:14:10,647
With them it's,
"You want wheat? Here's wheat.

199
00:14:10,749 --> 00:14:13,547
"You want Vietnam?
Go ahead, help yourself.

200
00:14:13,652 --> 00:14:18,214
What else you want?
Chicago? Texas? Be my guest."

201
00:14:18,324 --> 00:14:23,091
Listen, sweetheart, you wanna know
what America is? I'll tell you.

202
00:14:23,195 --> 00:14:25,595
What we got, we keep.
It's ours. We earned it.

203
00:14:25,698 --> 00:14:28,098
We fought for it,
and we're not givin' it to nobody.

204
00:14:28,200 --> 00:14:32,136
But if you let them have their way,
we'll be eating grass growing in the streets.

205
00:14:32,238 --> 00:14:35,435
Well, hell no!
Better burn it all up to scorched earth.

206
00:14:35,541 --> 00:14:37,668
Yeah, that's my policy.

207
00:14:37,776 --> 00:14:40,176
Back home, baby, when there's
too much milk, we dump it.

208
00:14:40,279 --> 00:14:42,679
When there's too much wheat,
we burn it. Yeah, right.

209
00:14:42,781 --> 00:14:45,147
If you can't sell it, you burn it.
That's the way.

210
00:14:45,251 --> 00:14:48,152
No money? Too bad. Beat it.
That's politics, baby.

211
00:14:48,254 --> 00:14:50,154
This ain't the Salvation Army.

212
00:14:50,256 --> 00:14:53,817
You wanna eat?
Okay, mister, work!

213
00:14:53,926 --> 00:14:56,827
Nothing for nothing.
Who ever gave us anything?

214
00:14:56,929 --> 00:14:58,829
Balls!

215
00:14:58,931 --> 00:15:01,991
Now that you're here,
nothing will stop us.

216
00:15:02,101 --> 00:15:04,535
Mr. Freedom, you're fantastic.

217
00:15:04,637 --> 00:15:07,071
Easy, girl.

218
00:15:07,172 --> 00:15:09,902
Everything in its own good time.

219
00:15:10,009 --> 00:15:12,807
Mr. Freedom ain't afraid of women?

220
00:15:12,912 --> 00:15:17,645
Cool it, sweetheart. You know what happens
to little girls who play with matches.

221
00:15:18,717 --> 00:15:21,015
Now you need all your strength.

222
00:15:21,120 --> 00:15:23,111
Later we'll see.

223
00:15:23,222 --> 00:15:25,190
<i>[Intercom Buzzes]</i>

224
00:15:26,492 --> 00:15:28,392
[Buzzes]

225
00:15:28,494 --> 00:15:31,952
<i>Ja. Nein. Ja.</i>

226
00:15:32,064 --> 00:15:34,464
<i>Nein. Ja.</i>

227
00:15:34,566 --> 00:15:36,466
<i>Nein.</i>

228
00:15:36,568 --> 00:15:38,468
You speak German.

229
00:15:38,570 --> 00:15:40,970
Okay, let's get to work.
Who's with us?

230
00:15:41,073 --> 00:15:44,042
Well, there's Vic Terrific,
Freddie Freak...

231
00:15:44,143 --> 00:15:46,236
Jacques Detergent, uh -

232
00:15:46,345 --> 00:15:48,245
How many in all?

233
00:15:48,347 --> 00:15:50,406
About 25.
But only the best.

234
00:15:50,516 --> 00:15:52,848
Yeah, well,
we took the Congo with less.

235
00:15:52,952 --> 00:15:57,355
France ain't the Congo,
but that is their problem.

236
00:15:57,456 --> 00:16:00,948
- We'll manage. When do I see them?
- Tonight. They're expecting you.

237
00:16:01,060 --> 00:16:05,190
- And how's the organization doing?
- Come on. I'll show you.

238
00:16:08,667 --> 00:16:11,659
- Marie Madeleine, 4-1-2.
- What's that?

239
00:16:11,770 --> 00:16:13,670
- Don't you know?
- Huh?

240
00:16:13,772 --> 00:16:15,672
Listen.

241
00:16:15,774 --> 00:16:20,507
<i>[Dispatcher On Radio]</i>
<i>44 Rue Lafayette. Fourth floor, left.</i>

242
00:16:20,612 --> 00:16:23,581
<i>Whip and leather man.</i>
<i>Whip and leather man. Urgent.</i>

243
00:16:23,682 --> 00:16:26,207
<i>[Woman On Radio]</i>
<i>Hello, Monique? Monique, I'll take it.</i>

244
00:16:26,318 --> 00:16:28,218
<i>I'll be there in five minutes.</i>

245
00:16:28,320 --> 00:16:31,221
- You've got to be kidding.
- Didn't you know?

246
00:16:31,323 --> 00:16:34,759
That's one of our Freedom operations.
Capitaine Formidable set it up.

247
00:16:34,860 --> 00:16:37,226
It makes a lot of money.

248
00:16:37,329 --> 00:16:39,729
And it's part of our intelligence service.

249
00:16:39,832 --> 00:16:42,232
- Like, look, there are 3,000 of us.
- Yeah?

250
00:16:42,334 --> 00:16:46,930
With an average of 10 tricks a night,
that makes 200,000 a week...

251
00:16:47,039 --> 00:16:49,064
800,000 a month...

252
00:16:49,174 --> 00:16:51,074
and we've got files...

253
00:16:51,176 --> 00:16:54,407
and after a couple of years
we get to know a lot of people.

254
00:16:54,513 --> 00:16:56,413
[Laughing]
Hot damn!

255
00:16:56,515 --> 00:16:58,540
[Dispatcher on Radio]
85 Champs-Élysées.

256
00:16:58,650 --> 00:17:00,550
- Who's that?
- Sadie.

257
00:17:00,652 --> 00:17:03,052
Sadie Madden.
One of our best agents.

258
00:17:03,155 --> 00:17:05,055
I'll bet she is.

259
00:17:05,157 --> 00:17:08,024
- Where are the files?
- At the headquarters.

260
00:17:08,127 --> 00:17:10,425
- Crazy, man.
<i>- [Dispatcher Continues, Indistinct]</i>

261
00:17:10,529 --> 00:17:15,057
<i>[Radio:Dispatcher] Need blonde, right-wing</i>
<i>intellectual,</i> 1 <i>5 years old, maximum.</i>

262
00:17:15,167 --> 00:17:19,069
<i>I repeat:blonde, right-wing intellectual,</i>
1 <i>5 years old, maximum.</i>

263
00:17:19,171 --> 00:17:20,763
[Mr. Freedom Giggling]

264
00:17:20,873 --> 00:17:23,842
[Chattering]

265
00:17:36,388 --> 00:17:38,515
[Speaking French]

266
00:17:49,034 --> 00:17:52,333
[French Continues]

267
00:17:57,709 --> 00:18:00,769
[Shouting In French]

268
00:18:00,879 --> 00:18:02,938
Monsieur Freedom!

269
00:18:03,048 --> 00:18:06,950
[Cheering, Whistling]

270
00:18:07,052 --> 00:18:10,317
Quiet, everyone! Please quiet down!
Quiet, everyone!

271
00:18:10,422 --> 00:18:13,823
- I present Teddy Drip-dry.
- Teddy.

272
00:18:13,926 --> 00:18:16,520
- Betty Bopper.
- Betty.

273
00:18:16,628 --> 00:18:20,120
- Hello.
- Corporal Dick Discount.

274
00:18:20,232 --> 00:18:22,928
Dick, old buddy.
How are you?

275
00:18:23,969 --> 00:18:26,130
- Johnny Cadillac.
- Yeah!

276
00:18:26,238 --> 00:18:28,399
- Roger Dropout.
- How do you do?

277
00:18:28,507 --> 00:18:30,475
- [Groans]
- [All Laughing]

278
00:18:31,643 --> 00:18:33,543
Sheila In.

279
00:18:33,645 --> 00:18:35,545
Hello. Hello.

280
00:18:35,647 --> 00:18:37,547
Jacques Detergent.

281
00:18:37,649 --> 00:18:40,209
[Chattering]

282
00:18:40,319 --> 00:18:42,913
- Grand Duc Eddie.
- Hello!

283
00:18:43,021 --> 00:18:44,921
[All Laughing]

284
00:18:45,023 --> 00:18:47,184
Yeah, yeah, yeah!

285
00:18:47,292 --> 00:18:49,783
- Freddie Freak.
- Freddie.

286
00:18:53,665 --> 00:18:56,225
The Fraternity Brothers.

287
00:18:58,370 --> 00:19:01,931
And Mr. Drugstore!

288
00:19:02,040 --> 00:19:06,204
[All]
For he's a jolly good fellow

289
00:19:06,311 --> 00:19:09,075
For he's a jolly good fellow

290
00:19:09,181 --> 00:19:13,515
For he's
a jolly good fellow

291
00:19:13,619 --> 00:19:18,079
That nobody can deny

292
00:19:18,190 --> 00:19:20,090
[Cheering]

293
00:19:20,192 --> 00:19:23,093
[Shouting]

294
00:19:23,195 --> 00:19:26,164
[All Chanting]
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!

295
00:19:26,265 --> 00:19:29,723
<i>Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!</i>
<i>[Cheering]</i>

296
00:19:31,270 --> 00:19:34,171
<i>- [Woman] Freedom!</i>
- [Rock Drumbeat]

297
00:19:34,273 --> 00:19:37,242
<i>[Cheering, Whistling]</i>

298
00:19:40,913 --> 00:19:43,882
<i>[Cheering Continues]</i>

299
00:19:46,518 --> 00:19:49,043
Ladies and gentlemen...

300
00:19:49,154 --> 00:19:51,554
we are proud...

301
00:19:51,657 --> 00:19:53,625
and deeply moved...

302
00:19:55,294 --> 00:19:59,094
to present to you tonight
for the first time in Europe...

303
00:19:59,198 --> 00:20:05,068
in his all-star one-man show...

304
00:20:05,170 --> 00:20:07,832
[Cheering, Whistling Continues]

305
00:20:07,940 --> 00:20:12,570
Mr. Free - Mr. Free -

306
00:20:12,678 --> 00:20:15,738
Mr. Freedom!

307
00:20:15,847 --> 00:20:17,906
Voilà!

308
00:20:18,016 --> 00:20:20,382
Aah! Yeah!

309
00:20:20,485 --> 00:20:22,385
<i>[Drumbeat]</i>

310
00:20:22,487 --> 00:20:27,049
Freedom!

311
00:20:27,159 --> 00:20:30,128
[All Cheering, Hooting, Whistling]

312
00:20:40,572 --> 00:20:42,540
<i>[Cheering, Whistling Subside]</i>

313
00:20:44,009 --> 00:20:46,705
I'm not going to talk about myself.

314
00:20:46,812 --> 00:20:49,303
I guess you know who I am anyhow.

315
00:20:49,414 --> 00:20:52,406
[Cheering, Applauding]

316
00:20:54,820 --> 00:20:57,948
No, I'm going to talk about you...

317
00:20:58,056 --> 00:21:00,115
and why we are fighting.

318
00:21:00,225 --> 00:21:03,524
<i>If you're here tonight,</i>
<i>it's because you love Freedom.</i>

319
00:21:03,629 --> 00:21:07,326
<i>And if you love Freedom,</i>
<i>Freedom loves you.</i>

320
00:21:07,432 --> 00:21:11,300
<i>We're one big, happy family,</i>
<i>and we're going on a crusade.</i>

321
00:21:11,403 --> 00:21:13,701
<i>You're the salt of the earth.</i>

322
00:21:13,805 --> 00:21:17,639
<i>You have faith in me,</i>
<i>and I have faith in you.</i>

323
00:21:17,743 --> 00:21:21,110
<i>The fate of the free world</i>
<i>is in your hands.</i>

324
00:21:21,213 --> 00:21:24,307
<i>[Cheering, Applauding]</i>

325
00:21:24,416 --> 00:21:29,752
There are two dangers, my friends, and
your own Stendhal understood them well.

326
00:21:29,855 --> 00:21:32,153
The Reds and the blacks.

327
00:21:32,257 --> 00:21:35,021
All right, you're French,
but you're white!

328
00:21:35,127 --> 00:21:37,527
This is the free world.

329
00:21:37,629 --> 00:21:40,462
<i>We are surrounded by a red sea-</i>

330
00:21:40,565 --> 00:21:42,999
<i>a red sea ofblood.</i>

331
00:21:43,101 --> 00:21:46,502
<i>Let us build a wall</i>
<i>of dedicated men...</i>

332
00:21:46,605 --> 00:21:48,539
<i>a white wall of freedom!</i>

333
00:21:48,640 --> 00:21:50,540
You are my white guards!

334
00:21:50,642 --> 00:21:52,974
[Cheering]

335
00:21:53,078 --> 00:21:56,809
<i>We love everybody,</i>
<i>but love is a two-way street.</i>

336
00:21:56,915 --> 00:21:59,349
<i>Love me, love my dog. Right?</i>

337
00:21:59,451 --> 00:22:01,351
<i>[All]</i>
<i>Right!</i>

338
00:22:01,453 --> 00:22:04,616
<i>The anti-this, the anti-that,</i>
<i>thejealous, the misfits, the failures-</i>

339
00:22:04,723 --> 00:22:06,816
we're not afraid of anybody.

340
00:22:06,925 --> 00:22:09,826
An eye for an eye,
a tooth for a tooth.

341
00:22:09,928 --> 00:22:13,125
What do you do with mad dogs?
You put 'em out of their misery.

342
00:22:13,231 --> 00:22:15,665
That's all I have to say.

343
00:22:15,767 --> 00:22:19,328
- [Cheering]
- Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!

344
00:22:19,438 --> 00:22:22,236
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!

345
00:22:22,341 --> 00:22:24,172
Freedom! Freedom!

346
00:22:25,544 --> 00:22:28,172
I like Freedom!

347
00:22:28,280 --> 00:22:31,147
<i>- [Cheering, Applause]</i>
- Me too!

348
00:22:31,249 --> 00:22:34,150
Yea!

349
00:22:34,252 --> 00:22:36,152
Yeah, I was poor.
Dirt poor.

350
00:22:36,254 --> 00:22:38,154
I was born poor.

351
00:22:38,256 --> 00:22:41,157
My father worked in the sewers.
Then came the depression.

352
00:22:41,259 --> 00:22:44,558
They closed down the sewers.
No more school.

353
00:22:44,663 --> 00:22:48,759
All I had to wear was one suit,
nothing but patches. But clean.

354
00:22:48,867 --> 00:22:50,767
We ate meat once a year.

355
00:22:50,869 --> 00:22:53,337
My Palm Beach was Hell's Kitchen.

356
00:22:53,438 --> 00:22:57,067
I've been working since I was seven years old.
There's nothing I didn't do.

357
00:22:57,175 --> 00:23:00,542
I washed clothes, I shined shoes,
I picked cotton.

358
00:23:00,645 --> 00:23:04,672
I was a boxer, a dishwasher,
a striker and a strikebreaker. Yeah!

359
00:23:04,783 --> 00:23:08,412
I worked on the railroad.
I sang the blues. I played the piano.

360
00:23:08,520 --> 00:23:11,648
I was an engineer, an efficiency expert,
a male nurse and an informer.

361
00:23:11,757 --> 00:23:14,282
I was everything!
Yeah. You're right.

362
00:23:14,393 --> 00:23:16,793
It's rough,
and it's tough where I come from.

363
00:23:16,895 --> 00:23:20,296
But if you got what it takes,
we'll take what you got, and then some!

364
00:23:20,399 --> 00:23:24,961
What do you need? A pencil? Some paper?
A screwdriver? A piano? You got it.

365
00:23:25,070 --> 00:23:27,971
You want two pianos?
Here you are. Two pianos.

366
00:23:28,073 --> 00:23:31,474
Now, goddamn it, let's hear some music.
If it's good, great. The sky's the limit.

367
00:23:31,576 --> 00:23:33,567
If you can't play, beat it.
Who's next?

368
00:23:33,678 --> 00:23:35,976
- What do you say?
- What do you say!

369
00:23:36,081 --> 00:23:39,778
Then one day I got my chance...

370
00:23:39,885 --> 00:23:42,945
and I grabbed it where it counts.

371
00:23:43,054 --> 00:23:45,989
- And that's how I got to be...
- Got to be!

372
00:23:46,091 --> 00:23:48,491
- Mister...
- Freedom!

373
00:23:48,593 --> 00:23:51,994
[Cheering, Applauding]

374
00:23:52,097 --> 00:23:53,997
This ain't no fairy tale.

375
00:23:54,099 --> 00:23:57,227
Empty hands, empty pockets?
That's not my style. What do you need?

376
00:23:57,335 --> 00:24:00,964
- You don't know?
I'm gonna tell you what you need.
- Thank you!

377
00:24:01,072 --> 00:24:04,166
To begin with, I'm gonna tell you
what the land of freedom's all about.

378
00:24:04,276 --> 00:24:06,176
<i>No, you're not dreaming.</i>

379
00:24:06,278 --> 00:24:08,473
<i>Because that land exists.</i>

380
00:24:08,580 --> 00:24:11,674
<i>Ladies and gentlemen,</i>
<i>you've been living like pigs.</i>

381
00:24:11,783 --> 00:24:14,445
<i>Open your eyes.</i>
<i>Open your hearts.</i>

382
00:24:14,553 --> 00:24:17,078
<i>[Upbeat]</i>

383
00:24:50,388 --> 00:24:51,787
<i>[Whistle Blows]</i>

384
00:24:51,890 --> 00:24:54,791
<i>[Marching Band]</i>

385
00:25:11,276 --> 00:25:13,870
- R! Y!
- Y!

386
00:25:13,979 --> 00:25:17,346
- Victory!
- Victory! Victory!

387
00:25:17,449 --> 00:25:19,747
Support our boys in Vietnam!

388
00:25:19,851 --> 00:25:22,820
<i>[Marching Band Continues]</i>

389
00:25:27,325 --> 00:25:31,261
<i>[Mr. Freedom]</i>
<i>Harlem. Fifty percent of the kids are</i>
<i>illegitimate. How about that? Batter up!</i>

390
00:25:31,363 --> 00:25:35,493
<i>Yeah, but when they get married, man,</i>
<i>they get married! Oh, love that hat!</i>

391
00:25:35,600 --> 00:25:39,036
<i>And dance? That's what I call rhythm.</i>
<i>Rock it to me, baby! Ha-ha! Yeah!</i>

392
00:25:39,137 --> 00:25:44,074
<i>Harlem. Harlem is more than a slum. It's more</i>
<i>than a ghetto. It's a drama, a human drama!</i>

393
00:25:44,175 --> 00:25:47,508
<i>But that, too, is part</i>
<i>of fabulous, swingin'New York!</i>

394
00:25:47,612 --> 00:25:51,070
[Audio: Channels Changing]

395
00:25:51,182 --> 00:25:52,843
Now I use Shake 'n' Bake!

396
00:25:52,951 --> 00:25:55,852
<i>- [Man Speaking, Indistinct]</i>
<i>- [Crowd Laughing]</i>

397
00:25:55,954 --> 00:25:59,947
<i>[Machine Gun Fire]</i>

398
00:26:02,694 --> 00:26:05,288
<i>[Upbeat Continues]</i>

399
00:26:13,238 --> 00:26:15,798
<i>[Mr. Freedom]</i>
<i>The sexual revolution, the new frontier...</i>

400
00:26:15,907 --> 00:26:18,740
the promised land,
the permanent revolution!

401
00:26:18,843 --> 00:26:20,743
Never before on the face of the earth!

402
00:26:20,845 --> 00:26:24,372
It's not for next year.
It's not for tomorrow.

403
00:26:24,482 --> 00:26:29,112
It's for right now!
It's for one and for all, and all for one!

404
00:26:29,220 --> 00:26:32,348
Yeah! Step right up!
It's free, and it's Freedom!

405
00:26:32,457 --> 00:26:36,120
And there is only one Freedom,
and it's your Freedom, and it's mine...

406
00:26:36,227 --> 00:26:38,787
and Freedom is -

407
00:26:38,897 --> 00:26:41,331
- [All] Freedom!
- [Cheering, Applauding]

408
00:26:49,541 --> 00:26:55,104
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!

409
00:26:55,213 --> 00:26:58,273
Freedom! Freedom!
Freedom! Freedom!

410
00:26:58,383 --> 00:27:00,681
[Crowd]
For one and for all

411
00:27:00,785 --> 00:27:02,685
It's you and me-dom

412
00:27:02,787 --> 00:27:05,153
And 10 foot tall

413
00:27:05,256 --> 00:27:07,588
Freedom, freedom

414
00:27:07,692 --> 00:27:09,887
Oh-can-you-see-dom

415
00:27:09,995 --> 00:27:11,792
We'll always beat 'em

416
00:27:11,896 --> 00:27:15,832
With star-spangled freedom

417
00:27:15,934 --> 00:27:18,459
[Cheering, Applauding]

418
00:27:19,404 --> 00:27:21,531
[Snoring]

419
00:27:23,808 --> 00:27:25,776
<i>[Knocking]</i>

420
00:27:28,480 --> 00:27:30,778
<i>[Knocking]</i>

421
00:27:30,882 --> 00:27:32,850
[Hammer Cocks]

422
00:27:39,190 --> 00:27:41,090
Who is it?

423
00:27:41,192 --> 00:27:43,160
[Woman]
It's breakfast, sir.

424
00:27:50,969 --> 00:27:54,302
Good morning, monsieur.
Where I put it?

425
00:27:54,406 --> 00:27:56,374
[Gasps]

426
00:28:18,363 --> 00:28:20,331
Strip, baby.

427
00:28:21,766 --> 00:28:23,734
Yeah, you.

428
00:28:38,383 --> 00:28:40,351
Ooh!

429
00:28:44,789 --> 00:28:46,757
Poof!

430
00:28:48,760 --> 00:28:51,126
Shoo! Mmm!

431
00:28:52,230 --> 00:28:54,824
All right, now eat.

432
00:28:55,867 --> 00:28:58,836
- Oh, but I am not hungry.
- Eat!

433
00:29:01,906 --> 00:29:04,033
A-ha-ha!

434
00:29:07,746 --> 00:29:09,646
- Mmm.
- Not that.

435
00:29:09,748 --> 00:29:12,216
The eggs.

436
00:29:29,701 --> 00:29:32,727
Uh -
[Groans]

437
00:29:32,837 --> 00:29:34,805
[Chuckles, Gasps]

438
00:29:37,609 --> 00:29:40,578
[Gulping]

439
00:29:43,915 --> 00:29:46,145
[Choking]

440
00:29:56,795 --> 00:30:00,754
I knew damn well
I didn't order the eggs.

441
00:30:36,568 --> 00:30:40,129
[Radio: Frequencies Tuning]

442
00:30:40,238 --> 00:30:43,207
[Organ: Hymn]

443
00:30:45,777 --> 00:30:49,076
[Radio: Man]
Mr. Freedom. Mr. Freedom!

444
00:30:49,180 --> 00:30:52,479
If you are a man,
come and see me.

445
00:30:52,584 --> 00:30:55,246
Métro Trocadéro.

446
00:30:55,353 --> 00:30:58,322
Signed, Moujik Man.

447
00:30:58,423 --> 00:31:00,448
I repeat.

448
00:31:00,558 --> 00:31:03,459
Mr. Freedom! Mr. Freedom!

449
00:31:03,561 --> 00:31:08,931
If you are a man,
come and see me, Métro Trocadéro.

450
00:31:09,033 --> 00:31:11,297
Signed, Moujik Man.

451
00:31:11,402 --> 00:31:14,667
[Organ: Hymn Continues]

452
00:31:14,772 --> 00:31:16,865
[Frequencies Tuning]

453
00:31:16,975 --> 00:31:21,241
[Woman] The film you are now watching
is sexy and suspenseful. Thank you.

454
00:31:22,280 --> 00:31:24,248
[Radio Off]

455
00:31:25,283 --> 00:31:27,808
Mister, may I make your room up?

456
00:31:27,919 --> 00:31:30,410
<i>[Marching Band]</i>

457
00:31:33,024 --> 00:31:34,992
<i>[Continues]</i>

458
00:31:46,304 --> 00:31:48,636
<i>[Ends]</i>

459
00:31:48,740 --> 00:31:50,640
<i>[Bell Chimes]</i>

460
00:31:50,742 --> 00:31:53,973
<i>[Woman On P.A.] Money is everything.</i>
<i>Yes, girls, money is everything.</i>

461
00:31:54,078 --> 00:31:56,546
<i>Make some money today!</i>

462
00:31:58,716 --> 00:32:00,616
<i>[Bell Chimes]</i>

463
00:32:00,718 --> 00:32:03,983
Oh, Mr. Freedom!
Hi, Mr. Freedom!

464
00:32:04,088 --> 00:32:06,181
[Sighs]

465
00:32:06,291 --> 00:32:09,124
- It's Mr. Freedom!
- [Squealing] Mr. Freedom!

466
00:32:09,227 --> 00:32:12,822
Oh, Mr. Freedom!
Hi, Mr. Freedom!

467
00:32:12,931 --> 00:32:14,990
Welcome, Mr. Freedom!

468
00:32:15,099 --> 00:32:17,260
I was just standing there
and he gave me his card!

469
00:32:17,368 --> 00:32:20,963
Well, Mr. Freedom. Delighted.
How are you?

470
00:32:21,072 --> 00:32:22,972
Permit me?

471
00:32:23,074 --> 00:32:25,838
- Well, how is Dr. Freedom?
- Terrific.

472
00:32:25,944 --> 00:32:29,038
I'm sure.
And, uh, Batman and, uh, John Wayne?

473
00:32:29,147 --> 00:32:32,048
They're okay. But tell me,
how are things going here?

474
00:32:32,150 --> 00:32:34,050
Oh, business as usual.

475
00:32:34,152 --> 00:32:37,781
The French have a certain culture,
a folklore, if you prefer.

476
00:32:37,889 --> 00:32:41,347
They have their language.
They're industrializing themselves.

477
00:32:41,459 --> 00:32:44,690
Well, they could be a great people,
but they, uh -

478
00:32:44,796 --> 00:32:47,356
they understand very little
about democracy.

479
00:32:47,465 --> 00:32:49,865
I'm bringing our story to the people.

480
00:32:49,968 --> 00:32:52,937
<i>- [Bell Chimes]</i>
- I try to plant a few ideas, but it's, uh -

481
00:32:53,037 --> 00:32:55,062
it's not easy.

482
00:32:55,173 --> 00:32:58,267
Well, at any rate
it's time that you got here.

483
00:32:58,376 --> 00:33:02,813
Um, there are some who say
that, uh, freedom is slavery.

484
00:33:02,914 --> 00:33:04,814
<i>[Woman On P.A.]</i>
<i>Freedom is slavery!</i>

485
00:33:04,916 --> 00:33:08,408
Perhaps they'd rather be
the slaves of, uh, Moujik Man.

486
00:33:08,519 --> 00:33:10,544
Some even want free elections.

487
00:33:10,655 --> 00:33:14,557
I try to guide them,
but it's a hopeless task.

488
00:33:14,659 --> 00:33:16,559
[Women]
Hopeless. Hopeless.

489
00:33:16,661 --> 00:33:19,391
They distort everything.
They demonstrate.

490
00:33:19,497 --> 00:33:22,398
They make disgusting,
unpatriotic remarks.

491
00:33:22,500 --> 00:33:25,401
[Laughing]
Prophets of doom.

492
00:33:25,503 --> 00:33:28,904
Dissent is fine, of course,
but within limits.

493
00:33:29,007 --> 00:33:32,408
What the enemy doesn't understand
is that democracy is based on debate.

494
00:33:32,510 --> 00:33:34,910
<i>[Woman On P.A.]</i>
<i>Yes, democracy is based on debate.</i>

495
00:33:35,013 --> 00:33:37,914
They see in every protest
a collapse of morale...

496
00:33:38,016 --> 00:33:40,007
and a diminishing resolve.

497
00:33:40,118 --> 00:33:44,680
On one hand we have the warlords,
Super Frenchman and his Super Ministers...

498
00:33:44,789 --> 00:33:47,189
who'd, uh -who'd, uh, have us dead.

499
00:33:47,291 --> 00:33:53,025
On the other hand, we have the rabble, the
F.A.F. Terrorists who, uh -who terrorize us.

500
00:33:53,131 --> 00:33:55,031
[Coughs]
The who?

501
00:33:55,133 --> 00:33:58,193
The F.A.F. Terrorists. Haven't you heard
of them? The French Anti-Freedom?

502
00:33:58,302 --> 00:34:01,100
- They're Red?
- No, they're mixed-up kids.

503
00:34:01,205 --> 00:34:03,105
<i>[Woman On P.A.]</i>
<i>F.A.F. Are mixed-up kids.</i>

504
00:34:03,207 --> 00:34:05,368
Society and the family nucleus
are disintegrating...

505
00:34:05,476 --> 00:34:08,877
and Moujik and Red China Man
are taking advantage of this.

506
00:34:08,980 --> 00:34:13,883
They get these poor kids all worked up
and they believe that they're anti-Freedom.

507
00:34:13,985 --> 00:34:16,545
They're the ones
who got Captain Formidable.

508
00:34:16,654 --> 00:34:19,088
It's possible.
It's not exactly clear.

509
00:34:19,190 --> 00:34:21,351
Uh, have you seen his team?

510
00:34:21,459 --> 00:34:23,859
Yeah. Last night.
They looked good.

511
00:34:23,961 --> 00:34:26,088
- They know why they're fighting.
<i>- [Bell Chimes]</i>

512
00:34:26,197 --> 00:34:28,097
Oh, lovely, uh - uh -

513
00:34:28,199 --> 00:34:31,100
<i>[Woman On P.A.] New! Fresh! Fabulous!</i>
<i>Try some Freedom today!</i>

514
00:34:31,202 --> 00:34:34,171
<i>Well, now, uh, right over here</i>
<i>we have our cultural services.</i>

515
00:34:36,074 --> 00:34:39,874
And over here we have
our ideological services.

516
00:34:39,977 --> 00:34:41,877
These are our most recent models.

517
00:34:41,979 --> 00:34:45,278
They're doing extremely well.
We've shipped them all over the world.

518
00:34:46,717 --> 00:34:49,481
<i>Dr. Freedom sent me</i>
<i>your secret weapons.</i>

519
00:34:49,587 --> 00:34:53,455
<i>I'll give you a set now and send</i>
<i>the rest along to the Freedom Center.</i>

520
00:34:53,558 --> 00:34:56,425
The instructions are on the inside.

521
00:34:56,527 --> 00:34:59,428
But tell me, Mr. Freedom,
what is your plan of operation?

522
00:34:59,530 --> 00:35:02,761
- [Woman] He's got a plan!
- Well, operation-wise, I kick off on my own.

523
00:35:02,867 --> 00:35:06,166
<i>- [Bell Chimes]</i>
- On "F" Hour, I'll give you a blast. Okay?

524
00:35:06,270 --> 00:35:09,296
Set me up a summit with Super Frenchman.
I've got some news for him:

525
00:35:09,407 --> 00:35:13,673
If he digs, <i>"comprendez,"</i> okay.
If not -

526
00:35:14,812 --> 00:35:17,508
Yes, but observe some sort
of protocol with Super Frenchman.

527
00:35:17,615 --> 00:35:20,448
- He's a man of the world.
- So am I, Pop.

528
00:35:20,551 --> 00:35:22,451
<i>- [Bell Chimes]</i>
- So am I.

529
00:35:22,553 --> 00:35:24,453
[Woman] So he is!
[Sighing]

530
00:35:24,555 --> 00:35:26,455
Miss Westmoreland.

531
00:35:26,557 --> 00:35:28,457
Please call Super Frenchman for me.

532
00:35:28,559 --> 00:35:30,754
Uh, Super Frenchman, Your Excellency.
Yes, Your Excellency.

533
00:35:30,862 --> 00:35:32,830
- Yes, Your Excellency!
- Right away, Your Excellency!

534
00:35:35,766 --> 00:35:39,395
<i>[Woman On P.A.] Super Frenchman,</i>
<i>Monsieur Freedom to see you.</i>

535
00:35:43,374 --> 00:35:45,865
<i>[Super Frenchman, Echoing]</i>
<i>Mr. Freedom...</i>

536
00:35:45,977 --> 00:35:50,141
<i>I am very happy to see you.</i>

537
00:35:50,248 --> 00:35:52,341
Okay, okay, don't knock yourself out,
Super Frenchman.

538
00:35:52,450 --> 00:35:54,350
I don't beat around the bush.

539
00:35:54,452 --> 00:35:58,752
Moujik Man and his killers
got Captain Formidable.

540
00:35:58,856 --> 00:36:02,019
You'll hand 'em over.
They're on your turf, no?

541
00:36:02,126 --> 00:36:04,026
It's either them or me.

542
00:36:04,128 --> 00:36:07,256
<i>- That is to say-</i>
- They're a danger to our investments.

543
00:36:07,365 --> 00:36:10,300
Give me carte blanche,
and I'll clean this mess up for you.

544
00:36:10,401 --> 00:36:13,302
In addition,
you get a special surprise bonus.

545
00:36:13,404 --> 00:36:15,304
<i>What special bonus?</i>

546
00:36:15,406 --> 00:36:18,307
I'm gonna give you
an atomic trolley bus.

547
00:36:18,409 --> 00:36:20,309
I will establish democracy
in France.

548
00:36:20,411 --> 00:36:23,039
And furthermore,
I'll get rid of your Reds.

549
00:36:23,147 --> 00:36:25,047
You with me or against me?

550
00:36:25,149 --> 00:36:29,313
<i>The affairs of France</i>
<i>are managed by me...</i>

551
00:36:29,420 --> 00:36:32,321
<i>without outside interference.</i>

552
00:36:32,423 --> 00:36:35,790
<i>But leave your phone number</i>
<i>at the desk.</i>

553
00:36:35,893 --> 00:36:38,885
<i>I'll call you if I need you.</i>

554
00:36:38,996 --> 00:36:42,397
If you need - Hey!
Where are you going, you balloon!

555
00:36:42,500 --> 00:36:45,230
I'm warning you!
Watch out, fatso!

556
00:36:45,336 --> 00:36:49,204
'Cause Freedom's on the march! Yeah!
Open your eyes! Your time has come, man!

557
00:36:49,307 --> 00:36:52,834
Super Frenchman, I'm warning you!

558
00:36:54,145 --> 00:36:56,238
As for your playmates -

559
00:36:59,550 --> 00:37:01,950
Aah! I have lost my willpower!

560
00:37:02,053 --> 00:37:03,953
So have I!

561
00:37:04,055 --> 00:37:05,784
So have I!

562
00:37:05,890 --> 00:37:07,949
[Cackling]

563
00:37:08,059 --> 00:37:11,358
That's 'cause my glasses
are hypnotic!

564
00:37:12,430 --> 00:37:15,228
And you, you wanna
see something freaky?

565
00:37:15,333 --> 00:37:17,233
<i>Yes. What have you there?</i>

566
00:37:17,335 --> 00:37:20,304
- [Groaning]
- [Laughing]

567
00:37:21,806 --> 00:37:25,435
Super Frenchman,
I give you just 48 hours!

568
00:37:25,543 --> 00:37:29,274
Moujik Man, you are next!

569
00:37:29,380 --> 00:37:31,245
[Growling]

570
00:37:31,349 --> 00:37:35,308
<i>[Women Singing In Foreign Language]</i>

571
00:37:58,442 --> 00:38:00,410
[Chuckles]

572
00:38:08,019 --> 00:38:09,919
[Gasps]

573
00:38:10,021 --> 00:38:12,956
Captain Formidable!

574
00:38:13,057 --> 00:38:16,185
Correct! [Chuckles]
Give the man a cigar!

575
00:38:16,294 --> 00:38:18,762
[Laughing]

576
00:38:23,968 --> 00:38:25,868
Moujik Man!

577
00:38:25,970 --> 00:38:29,929
In person! But of course!
[Laughing]

578
00:38:31,809 --> 00:38:34,642
Hello, Mr. Freedom.

579
00:38:34,745 --> 00:38:36,645
How are you?

580
00:38:36,747 --> 00:38:39,875
Have you had a good trip? Hmm?
[Laughing Continues]

581
00:38:41,952 --> 00:38:43,852
Ohh!

582
00:38:43,954 --> 00:38:46,149
Look, cowboy, no gun.

583
00:38:46,257 --> 00:38:48,725
- Very funny.
- I am helpless.

584
00:38:48,826 --> 00:38:53,024
Okay, Moujik Man.
So you did it, huh? You bastard!

585
00:38:53,130 --> 00:38:55,428
I didn't,
and you know I didn't!

586
00:38:55,533 --> 00:38:58,434
You know it hurts me
as much as it did you.

587
00:38:58,536 --> 00:39:01,937
But just to see your expression,
I got to laugh!

588
00:39:02,039 --> 00:39:03,939
Don't make such a face!

589
00:39:04,041 --> 00:39:06,805
Hey! Hands off.
I'm not kidding around.

590
00:39:06,911 --> 00:39:10,745
If it wasn't you,
it was one of your F.A.F. Stooges.

591
00:39:10,848 --> 00:39:12,748
- My stooges? [Laughs]
- Yes.

592
00:39:12,850 --> 00:39:17,981
Listen, they are just a bunch of kids.
Red China Man's got them all hopped up.

593
00:39:18,089 --> 00:39:21,149
But these things happen.
What can you do?

594
00:39:21,258 --> 00:39:25,422
Besides, who asked you to send him
your little sweetie pie?

595
00:39:25,529 --> 00:39:29,158
My what?
What are you trying to say?

596
00:39:29,266 --> 00:39:31,166
Not me, Freedom.

597
00:39:31,268 --> 00:39:33,395
Moujik, how dare you.

598
00:39:33,504 --> 00:39:37,201
Captain Formidable
was a great human being!

599
00:39:37,308 --> 00:39:39,469
Don't make me cry.

600
00:39:39,577 --> 00:39:41,477
Besides, he was a sham!

601
00:39:41,579 --> 00:39:44,707
- Haven't you got any feelings?
- Well, look who's talking!

602
00:39:44,815 --> 00:39:46,715
The butcher! The policeman!

603
00:39:46,817 --> 00:39:48,717
- Me?
- Yes!

604
00:39:48,819 --> 00:39:50,912
You shut up, you -you -

605
00:39:51,021 --> 00:39:53,251
you imperialist!

606
00:39:53,357 --> 00:39:55,257
Me?

607
00:39:55,359 --> 00:39:57,953
Why, you reactionary!

608
00:39:58,062 --> 00:40:01,964
Hey, you watch out. You watch out,
Moujik Man. Watch what you're saying.

609
00:40:02,066 --> 00:40:03,966
- You too.
- You too.

610
00:40:04,068 --> 00:40:05,968
Then you too!

611
00:40:06,070 --> 00:40:07,970
I could squash you!

612
00:40:08,072 --> 00:40:10,131
I could triple squash you!

613
00:40:10,241 --> 00:40:12,266
- You want war?
- Do you?

614
00:40:12,376 --> 00:40:15,868
Then keep your little buddies out of it!

615
00:40:15,980 --> 00:40:18,414
I can't! It's your fault!
You started it!

616
00:40:18,516 --> 00:40:20,416
Yeah, and I'll finish it.

617
00:40:20,518 --> 00:40:22,816
Oh, don't be so sure.

618
00:40:22,920 --> 00:40:25,821
They've got everything to lose.
They can't afford to fight.

619
00:40:25,923 --> 00:40:28,824
- Neither can you.
- Neither can you.

620
00:40:28,926 --> 00:40:32,327
Okay, so you work it out with them.

621
00:40:32,430 --> 00:40:34,728
- You.
- No! You!

622
00:40:34,832 --> 00:40:36,732
Never.

623
00:40:36,834 --> 00:40:40,065
No rewards for aggression.

624
00:40:40,171 --> 00:40:42,571
- Hypocrite.
- Watch your language.

625
00:40:42,673 --> 00:40:47,235
Oh, now listen, listen, listen, Freedom.
Now, be reasonable.

626
00:40:47,344 --> 00:40:51,440
Now you want to start in on France.
You are putting me on the spot.

627
00:40:51,549 --> 00:40:53,449
You know that.

628
00:40:53,551 --> 00:40:56,452
I can't just drop the French.
I will have to fight.

629
00:40:56,554 --> 00:40:59,717
- What will I look like if I don't?
- What do you look like now?

630
00:40:59,824 --> 00:41:01,724
I didn't start anything.

631
00:41:01,826 --> 00:41:06,024
Captain Formidable was here as an adviser
to lead the French to peace.

632
00:41:06,130 --> 00:41:09,657
But the road to peace
is not through concessions and retreat.

633
00:41:09,767 --> 00:41:12,327
The path I follow
is the path of honor.

634
00:41:12,436 --> 00:41:15,337
Fine, fine, fine. Lovely.

635
00:41:15,439 --> 00:41:18,101
But what does your honor need?

636
00:41:18,209 --> 00:41:20,575
- Paris.
- You want Paris?

637
00:41:20,678 --> 00:41:24,341
Oh, no. It's not possible.
Versailles, if you want. There is a bus -

638
00:41:24,448 --> 00:41:26,348
No, no, no.
I can't abandon Paris.

639
00:41:26,450 --> 00:41:28,645
Now you're out of your mind!

640
00:41:28,752 --> 00:41:31,118
What about me?
You don't realize!

641
00:41:31,222 --> 00:41:35,659
I'll tell you what we can do.
I will tell you. Come on.

642
00:41:35,759 --> 00:41:40,025
We can set up
two zones of influence.

643
00:41:40,130 --> 00:41:42,223
Left bank and right bank.

644
00:41:42,333 --> 00:41:45,530
The Seine is practically
a natural frontier already.

645
00:41:45,636 --> 00:41:49,868
- I will take the- the left bank.
- Which one is the left bank?

646
00:41:49,974 --> 00:41:51,874
This one!

647
00:41:51,976 --> 00:41:54,171
<i>- I want the left bank.
- [Gasps]

648
00:41:54,278 --> 00:41:57,008
- What do you want the left bank for?
<i>- [Crashing]</i>

649
00:41:57,114 --> 00:41:59,912
[Together]
Red China Man!

650
00:42:00,017 --> 00:42:02,611
That's right!
Go right ahead!

651
00:42:02,720 --> 00:42:04,620
Give him everything!

652
00:42:04,722 --> 00:42:07,020
Negotiate with imperialism!

653
00:42:07,124 --> 00:42:12,426
Your secret plan to split up the world
will fail miserably!

654
00:42:12,530 --> 00:42:15,590
Listen here!
You have just arrived!

655
00:42:15,699 --> 00:42:17,792
He is a crazy fool.

656
00:42:17,902 --> 00:42:21,338
He is capable of anything.
We have got to use reason.

657
00:42:21,438 --> 00:42:25,204
If you think you can reason with him,
then <i>you</i> are crazy...

658
00:42:25,309 --> 00:42:27,209
a traitor and a coward!

659
00:42:27,311 --> 00:42:29,211
Freedom is hopeless.

660
00:42:29,313 --> 00:42:32,214
If you talk to him,
you play his game.

661
00:42:32,316 --> 00:42:34,546
He must be eliminated!

662
00:42:34,652 --> 00:42:36,677
I told you, don't mess with Freedom.
Huh, Chink?

663
00:42:36,787 --> 00:42:38,550
You see, strategically-

664
00:42:38,656 --> 00:42:41,625
We call it having
horse manure in your eye.

665
00:42:44,662 --> 00:42:48,257
He who beholdeth the mote
in his brother's eye...

666
00:42:48,365 --> 00:42:53,894
perceives not the beam
that is in his own eye.

667
00:42:55,439 --> 00:42:58,966
...1967, item 80.

668
00:42:59,076 --> 00:43:01,977
- Mom, please.
- Jesus, I don't know how I should take that.

669
00:43:02,079 --> 00:43:04,479
<i>[Red China Man] I told you.</i>
<i>He doesn't understand anything.</i>

670
00:43:04,582 --> 00:43:06,482
Listen, you keep out of this!

671
00:43:06,584 --> 00:43:10,418
Anyway, goddamn it,
I didn't come here to be insulted.

672
00:43:10,521 --> 00:43:12,421
I'm the victim of aggression.

673
00:43:12,523 --> 00:43:15,788
You're the aggressor,
the true enemy of the people.

674
00:43:15,893 --> 00:43:17,793
Even the Chinese people -

675
00:43:17,895 --> 00:43:20,796
It isn't me.
It's <i>you,</i> Red China Man!

676
00:43:20,898 --> 00:43:24,231
You took over the power by force.
You are usurpers!

677
00:43:24,335 --> 00:43:26,235
<i>You talk about democracy!</i>

678
00:43:26,337 --> 00:43:28,965
You don't even know
what that means!

679
00:43:29,073 --> 00:43:30,973
Your country's a mess!

680
00:43:31,075 --> 00:43:32,975
The people are starving!

681
00:43:33,077 --> 00:43:34,977
They're revolting!

682
00:43:35,079 --> 00:43:40,881
Your democracy
is just consolidated dictatorship...

683
00:43:40,985 --> 00:43:44,079
and slavery incorporated!

684
00:43:44,188 --> 00:43:46,088
Hey, Chinkie!

685
00:43:46,190 --> 00:43:50,024
Confucius says
he who laughs last laughs best.

686
00:43:53,797 --> 00:43:58,200
[Laughing] Perhaps we should
put the poor man out of his misery!

687
00:43:58,302 --> 00:44:00,702
- We can't do that!
- Why not?

688
00:44:00,804 --> 00:44:03,671
The most elementary rules
of hospitality forbid it.

689
00:44:03,774 --> 00:44:08,575
Red Maria, give me a hand.

690
00:44:08,679 --> 00:44:11,477
- Moujik Man?
- We'll move him upstairs. Okay?

691
00:44:11,582 --> 00:44:13,777
Maybe sweet-talk him
or something.

692
00:44:13,884 --> 00:44:15,784
And then let him escape.

693
00:44:15,886 --> 00:44:20,414
But don't let him out of your sight.
He may take all this the wrong way.

694
00:44:24,828 --> 00:44:26,796
Shh!

695
00:44:30,167 --> 00:44:32,135
[Grunts]

696
00:44:34,672 --> 00:44:38,574
[Groaning]
Oh, the cowards.

697
00:44:38,676 --> 00:44:41,338
They got me from behind.

698
00:44:41,445 --> 00:44:43,413
Oh, my head.

699
00:44:44,448 --> 00:44:46,439
Are you married, Freedom?

700
00:44:46,550 --> 00:44:48,450
What's it to you, baby?

701
00:44:48,552 --> 00:44:50,577
Hey, you're wild.

702
00:44:50,688 --> 00:44:53,589
Your name should be Mr. Fantastic!

703
00:44:53,691 --> 00:44:55,750
That's right, baby.

704
00:44:55,859 --> 00:44:58,794
And that's only a starter.

705
00:44:58,896 --> 00:45:02,059
If it wasn't for my busted head...

706
00:45:02,166 --> 00:45:04,430
you'd see what fantastic is.

707
00:45:04,535 --> 00:45:06,833
Mmm, that's not hard to believe.

708
00:45:06,937 --> 00:45:10,202
Well, you've got the build of it anyhow.

709
00:45:10,307 --> 00:45:14,175
Now, are you able to walk?
You'd better get out of here.

710
00:45:14,278 --> 00:45:16,337
Up we go.

711
00:45:16,447 --> 00:45:21,350
It's not because of Moujik Man.
It's Red China Man who's out to get you.

712
00:45:21,452 --> 00:45:23,420
[Grunting]

713
00:45:27,558 --> 00:45:29,526
There.

714
00:45:46,110 --> 00:45:48,738
- Come on.
- How do you get out of here?

715
00:45:48,846 --> 00:45:50,746
By the roof. Hurry up.

716
00:45:50,848 --> 00:45:53,146
Come on! Hurry up!

717
00:45:53,250 --> 00:45:55,218
Up you go.

718
00:46:11,535 --> 00:46:13,662
What, are you out of your mind
or something?

719
00:46:13,771 --> 00:46:16,638
No, "tootsky."
It's the end of the line for you.

720
00:46:16,740 --> 00:46:19,470
Too bad, Maria, I can't trust you.

721
00:46:19,576 --> 00:46:21,976
You're Red, baby,
and you're rotten.

722
00:46:22,079 --> 00:46:24,070
- Freedom, no.
- Yes.

723
00:46:25,749 --> 00:46:30,482
Red China Man, you're next!

724
00:47:21,038 --> 00:47:22,938
Shh!

725
00:47:23,040 --> 00:47:24,974
It's me.

726
00:47:25,075 --> 00:47:27,066
Ah, it's you, lover.

727
00:47:27,177 --> 00:47:29,372
I was so terribly worried.

728
00:49:13,684 --> 00:49:15,709
What's your name, mister?

729
00:49:16,887 --> 00:49:18,787
They call me...

730
00:49:18,889 --> 00:49:20,789
Freedom.

731
00:49:20,891 --> 00:49:23,086
Mama! Mama!
It's Mr. Freedom!

732
00:49:23,193 --> 00:49:25,093
Oh, Mama, I'm scared!
It's Mr. Freedom!

733
00:49:25,195 --> 00:49:27,095
Shh.

734
00:49:28,198 --> 00:49:30,723
Now you mustn't be scared,
my big boy.

735
00:49:30,834 --> 00:49:32,768
He's sweet, Mr. Freedom.

736
00:49:32,869 --> 00:49:34,894
If you're good, you can wear his uniform.

737
00:49:35,005 --> 00:49:37,303
I don't care about his old uniform.
I don't like him...

738
00:49:37,407 --> 00:49:39,307
and he'll kill me, Mr. Freedom.

739
00:49:39,409 --> 00:49:41,741
Darling, you do like him.
Everybody likes him.

740
00:49:41,845 --> 00:49:44,746
- He's sweet, Mr. Freedom.
- He's not a bit sweet.

741
00:49:44,848 --> 00:49:48,284
- He's mean, and - and he kills everybody.
- Only bad people.

742
00:49:48,385 --> 00:49:51,980
No, he kills everybody.
Nobody likes him. He wants to kill us.

743
00:49:52,089 --> 00:49:54,114
Shut up. I've had enough.

744
00:49:54,224 --> 00:49:56,124
- Mama. Mama.
- Mama.

745
00:49:56,226 --> 00:49:58,126
- Take him out, please.
- Mama!

746
00:49:58,228 --> 00:50:00,788
Mama, what the hell are you doing?
Get him out of here.

747
00:50:00,897 --> 00:50:04,060
Take my hand.
And you, Marie Madeleine -

748
00:50:05,369 --> 00:50:07,769
what the hell are <i>you</i> doing?

749
00:50:07,871 --> 00:50:10,101
- He's a fascist.
- Go on. Get out.

750
00:50:10,207 --> 00:50:12,607
Busybody. Little brat.

751
00:50:19,683 --> 00:50:22,516
- Come on, you.
- He was afraid of me.

752
00:50:22,619 --> 00:50:25,486
No. Come on.
Take off your old uniform.

753
00:50:25,589 --> 00:50:28,820
It'll keep you from sleeping,
and besides, it scratches.

754
00:50:33,930 --> 00:50:37,297
- Voilà.
- You hear that? He called me a fascist.

755
00:50:37,401 --> 00:50:39,835
Oh, he's only a kid.
What does he know?

756
00:50:39,936 --> 00:50:43,804
- He said nobody likes me.
- Everybody likes you.

757
00:50:43,907 --> 00:50:45,841
They love you.

758
00:50:46,877 --> 00:50:49,744
He said some terrible things.

759
00:50:49,846 --> 00:50:54,545
You know why?
It's on account of me. He's jealous.

760
00:50:54,651 --> 00:50:57,245
It's his Oedipus complex.

761
00:50:57,354 --> 00:51:00,118
Come on, baby.
Beddy-bye.

762
00:51:01,158 --> 00:51:04,821
- What if we're wrong?
<i>- What if who's wrong?</i>

763
00:51:04,928 --> 00:51:07,089
Me, you - all of us.

764
00:51:07,197 --> 00:51:10,598
<i>- Freedom.</i>
- What are you talking about?

765
00:51:10,700 --> 00:51:13,396
<i>Well, in the old days it was much simpler.</i>

766
00:51:13,503 --> 00:51:15,801
<i>It was springtime.</i>

767
00:51:15,906 --> 00:51:19,637
<i>It was a new country.</i>
<i>Everything was clean.</i>

768
00:51:20,677 --> 00:51:23,237
<i>The wind blew across the prairie...</i>

769
00:51:23,346 --> 00:51:25,974
<i>warm and sweet like-</i>

770
00:51:26,083 --> 00:51:28,244
<i>like apple pie.</i>

771
00:51:28,351 --> 00:51:31,752
<i>America was... American.</i>

772
00:51:31,855 --> 00:51:34,949
<i>And then the others came.</i>

773
00:51:38,528 --> 00:51:41,292
- What others, dear?
<i>- Oh, you know.</i>

774
00:51:41,398 --> 00:51:44,424
<i>The foreigners, the niggers.</i>
<i>All them.</i>

775
00:51:44,534 --> 00:51:47,094
The foreigners?

776
00:51:47,204 --> 00:51:49,672
But the niggers - they didn't
really want to come, did they?

777
00:51:49,773 --> 00:51:51,673
<i>Right. Who needed 'em?</i>

778
00:51:51,775 --> 00:51:54,335
<i>We should have let 'em rot</i>
<i>in their crummy, scummyjungles.</i>

779
00:51:54,444 --> 00:51:56,935
<i>We shouldn't even have let 'em in.</i>
<i>Locked 'em out.</i>

780
00:51:57,047 --> 00:51:59,572
<i>Minded our own business.</i>

781
00:51:59,683 --> 00:52:01,981
<i>But no.</i>
<i>In Europe and Asia...</i>

782
00:52:02,085 --> 00:52:05,384
<i>you had to start knocking each other off,</i>
<i>so we had to feel sorry for you.</i>

783
00:52:05,489 --> 00:52:07,423
<i>We had to keep saving you.</i>

784
00:52:07,524 --> 00:52:11,426
<i>You could start your wars all right,</i>
<i>but you needed us to finish 'em, right?</i>

785
00:52:11,528 --> 00:52:14,019
<i>Right. What did it get us?</i>

786
00:52:15,132 --> 00:52:17,566
Gratitude? My ass.

787
00:52:17,667 --> 00:52:19,965
- Ah, I wouldn't say that.
- You wouldn't, huh?

788
00:52:20,070 --> 00:52:22,664
Well, I would.
I'll tell you what we got out of it all.

789
00:52:22,772 --> 00:52:25,263
Your clappy, crappy sicknesses.

790
00:52:25,375 --> 00:52:27,309
Your doubts. Your hate.

791
00:52:27,410 --> 00:52:29,310
You infected us.

792
00:52:29,412 --> 00:52:32,745
Now nobody believes
in nothin' anymore.

793
00:52:32,849 --> 00:52:35,317
Nobody loves nobody.

794
00:52:36,353 --> 00:52:41,017
And crown thy hood
with brotherhood

795
00:52:41,124 --> 00:52:45,117
Balls. Coexistence. You crap all over us,
and then you want to coexist.

796
00:52:45,228 --> 00:52:47,924
Well, Freedom Incorporated
says up yours!

797
00:52:48,031 --> 00:52:50,522
You want to coexist?
Coexist with this!

798
00:52:50,634 --> 00:52:53,660
What are you getting so nervous about?

799
00:52:53,770 --> 00:52:56,432
What do you mean?
You heard him, didn't you?

800
00:52:56,540 --> 00:52:59,100
Now nobody likes us.

801
00:52:59,209 --> 00:53:02,144
Oh, you're not going to listen
to that stupid kid.

802
00:53:02,245 --> 00:53:05,806
- Hey. Come here, you.
- I don't feel good.

803
00:53:06,850 --> 00:53:11,150
Okay. Get your beauty sleep.
You gotta recuperate.

804
00:53:24,868 --> 00:53:26,836
<i>[Organ]</i>

805
00:53:31,908 --> 00:53:33,876
<i>[Continues]</i>

806
00:53:49,726 --> 00:53:52,194
<i>[Ends]</i>

807
00:53:52,295 --> 00:53:54,263
Look.

808
00:54:03,673 --> 00:54:07,200
It's nothing. Don't worry, baby.
You're tired.

809
00:54:18,188 --> 00:54:20,918
No, it's more than that.

810
00:54:25,862 --> 00:54:29,298
I'll get some Mercurochrome.

811
00:54:29,399 --> 00:54:31,333
It'll sting.

812
00:54:32,369 --> 00:54:34,337
No, it won't sting.

813
00:54:34,437 --> 00:54:36,530
I'll put a Band-Aid on it.

814
00:54:36,640 --> 00:54:38,540
It's too big for a Band-Aid.

815
00:54:39,609 --> 00:54:42,373
It's deep.

816
00:54:42,479 --> 00:54:44,447
Okay, but we gotta do something.

817
00:54:46,316 --> 00:54:48,250
There's nothing you can do.

818
00:54:48,351 --> 00:54:50,319
Gotta do something.

819
00:54:58,161 --> 00:55:00,129
Give me your hand.

820
00:55:04,334 --> 00:55:07,132
Lift yourself up, baby.

821
00:55:07,237 --> 00:55:09,205
Attaboy.

822
00:55:12,575 --> 00:55:14,668
There. You feel better?

823
00:55:14,778 --> 00:55:18,111
I don't know.
It's a punishment.

824
00:55:18,214 --> 00:55:21,206
Oh, you're out of your mind.
You're just tired.

825
00:55:21,318 --> 00:55:23,286
It's just tired blood.

826
00:55:23,386 --> 00:55:25,445
You think it's tired blood?

827
00:55:25,555 --> 00:55:27,921
Look. It's stopping.

828
00:55:28,024 --> 00:55:32,085
- I'll change the bandages.
- No. I'm gonna die.

829
00:55:32,195 --> 00:55:34,220
I want to put on my uniform.

830
00:55:34,331 --> 00:55:37,528
No. You're gonna slop it all up.

831
00:55:37,634 --> 00:55:39,602
I want to sleep.

832
00:55:39,703 --> 00:55:43,537
- I'm beat.
- What you need is some energy food.

833
00:55:43,640 --> 00:55:46,370
- I'll fix you some farina.
- [Groans]

834
00:55:46,476 --> 00:55:49,502
Listen. I'll make you
a real American breakfast.

835
00:55:49,612 --> 00:55:51,580
Wait.

836
00:55:58,455 --> 00:56:00,355
I'm not hungry.

837
00:56:00,457 --> 00:56:02,891
Oh, you love Corn Flakes.

838
00:56:02,992 --> 00:56:04,960
Eat. You'll feel better.

839
00:56:08,932 --> 00:56:10,957
Not too much milk.
Makes it soggy.

840
00:56:11,067 --> 00:56:14,332
- Like that?
<i>- Oui.</i> That's good.

841
00:56:18,041 --> 00:56:20,009
There.

842
00:56:21,811 --> 00:56:23,938
Come on. Open up.

843
00:56:25,415 --> 00:56:27,383
Yummy, yummy.

844
00:56:29,285 --> 00:56:31,651
And it's good for you.

845
00:56:31,755 --> 00:56:33,723
Another one.

846
00:56:34,858 --> 00:56:36,758
[Garbled]
No more.

847
00:56:36,860 --> 00:56:41,024
Oh, yes. Come on.
Eat another one for... democracy.

848
00:56:41,131 --> 00:56:45,192
- And another spoonful for independence.
- That's enough.

849
00:56:45,301 --> 00:56:49,169
It's almost all gone.
One more for freedom!

850
00:56:54,511 --> 00:56:58,641
- I ate it all up.
- There! My big baby.

851
00:56:58,748 --> 00:57:01,717
Was it good?
You look better already.

852
00:57:03,119 --> 00:57:05,747
Okay. There's no time to lose.
Now we strike back.

853
00:57:06,923 --> 00:57:08,857
But first I have to call Dr. Freedom.

854
00:57:08,958 --> 00:57:13,019
Aha! So, Mr. Freedom,
you want to escape.

855
00:57:13,129 --> 00:57:15,063
An old Chinese proverb say...

856
00:57:15,165 --> 00:57:19,101
he who picks up rock
drops it on foot.

857
00:57:19,202 --> 00:57:21,102
That is what reactionaries do.

858
00:57:21,204 --> 00:57:24,230
- Their repressions -
- Red China Man!

859
00:57:24,340 --> 00:57:26,467
- I'm lost.
- He switched the antenna.

860
00:57:26,576 --> 00:57:28,737
He did the same thing
to Capitaine Formidable.

861
00:57:28,845 --> 00:57:32,281
No wonder you've been feeling lousy.
He's been brainwashing you.

862
00:57:32,382 --> 00:57:34,282
- [Gasps]
- That son of a bitch.

863
00:57:34,384 --> 00:57:36,545
- Where's the antenna?
- Huh?

864
00:57:36,653 --> 00:57:39,383
There. Upper-left -

865
00:57:39,489 --> 00:57:42,617
No time to lose.
To our dentist!

866
00:57:42,725 --> 00:57:45,285
[Whirring]

867
00:57:48,465 --> 00:57:50,365
Good work.
You have the other antenna?

868
00:57:50,467 --> 00:57:52,435
[Mr. Freedom Grunting]

869
00:58:09,919 --> 00:58:11,819
Got it.

870
00:58:11,921 --> 00:58:14,412
- Wow.
- Okay?

871
00:58:18,995 --> 00:58:20,963
What did you do that for?

872
00:58:22,298 --> 00:58:24,493
No witnesses.

873
00:58:24,601 --> 00:58:28,731
- But he was working for us.
- Security first. We can't trust anyone.

874
00:58:28,838 --> 00:58:31,739
Now let's get going.
Call the gang together- for freedom!

875
00:58:34,511 --> 00:58:37,503
If you won't fight freedom,
well, we will.

876
00:58:37,614 --> 00:58:39,809
We'll do the fighting.
You just give us the guns.

877
00:58:39,916 --> 00:58:43,818
You want guns, my friends.
We say bad peace is better than a good war.

878
00:58:43,920 --> 00:58:46,115
You are broke.
You need more than weapons and arms.

879
00:58:46,222 --> 00:58:49,919
I help you all I can.
I will send adviser and technicians.

880
00:58:50,026 --> 00:58:52,460
I will raise your standard of living.

881
00:58:52,562 --> 00:58:55,360
And after you have everything,
you battle if you want.

882
00:58:55,465 --> 00:58:59,868
- [All Groaning]
- Don't misinterpret Marx
and play into hands of Freedom!

883
00:58:59,969 --> 00:59:03,427
- We want weapons!
- Like you, my heart bleeds for Red Maria.

884
00:59:03,540 --> 00:59:08,568
So make her a beautiful funeral,
with strikes all over and marches.

885
00:59:08,678 --> 00:59:10,942
Meanwhile, I'll go speak with Freedom.

886
00:59:11,047 --> 00:59:14,574
<i>It's too much! He knocks off Maria,</i>
<i>and we're to march in a parade?</i>

887
00:59:14,684 --> 00:59:17,812
No! Not anymore!
Eye for an eye! Tooth for a tooth!

888
00:59:17,921 --> 00:59:21,652
[Singing "La Marseillaise"]

889
00:59:35,371 --> 00:59:37,339
[Ends]

890
00:59:40,343 --> 00:59:42,311
[All Shouting]

891
00:59:45,081 --> 00:59:47,811
<i>[Man]</i>
<i>Freedom!</i>

892
00:59:47,917 --> 00:59:49,817
<i>[Gunshot]</i>

893
00:59:57,060 --> 00:59:59,756
<i>[Gunshot]</i>

894
01:00:03,499 --> 01:00:07,993
[Screaming]

895
01:00:12,075 --> 01:00:14,043
[Gunshot]

896
01:00:15,244 --> 01:00:17,212
[Gunshot]

897
01:00:20,350 --> 01:00:22,318
[All Shouting]

898
01:00:27,690 --> 01:00:30,124
[Speaking French]

899
01:00:34,530 --> 01:00:37,328
- [Men Shout]
- [Screaming]

900
01:00:39,035 --> 01:00:41,003
[Screams]

901
01:01:02,859 --> 01:01:05,123
<i>[Loud Whistle]</i>

902
01:01:06,229 --> 01:01:08,197
[Whistles]

903
01:01:11,501 --> 01:01:14,629
Yeah. Yah. Yah.
Watch out. Here is the boss.

904
01:01:14,737 --> 01:01:19,538
<i>- [Mr. Freedom] Good morning, everybody.</i>
- [All] Good morning, Mr. Freedom!

905
01:01:19,642 --> 01:01:24,636
<i>Friends of Freedom, a shameful</i>
<i>attempt has been made on my life.</i>

906
01:01:24,747 --> 01:01:26,772
[All Groaning]

907
01:01:30,486 --> 01:01:32,750
We shall not give in either to threats...

908
01:01:34,157 --> 01:01:36,557
or to aggression.

909
01:01:36,659 --> 01:01:39,184
We shall attack!

910
01:01:39,295 --> 01:01:42,753
[All Shouting]

911
01:01:44,067 --> 01:01:46,467
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!

912
01:01:46,569 --> 01:01:49,197
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!

913
01:01:51,307 --> 01:01:54,333
Good. This is our program.

914
01:01:54,444 --> 01:01:56,378
We start with cold war.

915
01:01:56,479 --> 01:01:58,379
<i>We demoralize the population.</i>

916
01:01:58,481 --> 01:02:01,143
<i>We harass, we terrorize,</i>
<i>we sabotage.</i>

917
01:02:01,250 --> 01:02:04,185
<i>If they understand their lesson,</i>
<i>we negotiate.</i>

918
01:02:04,287 --> 01:02:09,418
<i>I am ready to go anywhere to talk to anybody</i>
<i>under whatever auspices to make peace.</i>

919
01:02:09,525 --> 01:02:11,459
And suppose they're stubborn?

920
01:02:11,561 --> 01:02:14,758
<i>[Mr. Freedom]</i>
<i>Then... phase two!</i>

921
01:02:14,864 --> 01:02:16,764
<i>Psychological warfare.</i>

922
01:02:16,866 --> 01:02:20,233
<i>Systematic destruction.</i>
<i>You all know your objectives.</i>

923
01:02:20,336 --> 01:02:22,304
<i>Heads up, eyes right, mum's the word.</i>

924
01:02:22,405 --> 01:02:26,102
<i>Synchronize your hearts.</i>
<i>It's</i> 11:1 <i>0. Freedom time!</i>

925
01:02:26,209 --> 01:02:28,109
<i>Forward for Freedom!</i>

926
01:02:28,211 --> 01:02:30,975
<i>- And may God be with us!</i>
- [Cheering]

927
01:02:33,182 --> 01:02:35,082
<i>Freedom! Freedom!</i>

928
01:02:35,184 --> 01:02:38,176
Now, I have here, ladies and gentlemen...

929
01:02:38,287 --> 01:02:40,881
certain items that if they were for sale -
but they aren't -

930
01:02:40,990 --> 01:02:43,458
you couldn't buy for love or money, no.

931
01:02:43,559 --> 01:02:45,993
Now, a once-in-a-lifetime offer.

932
01:02:46,095 --> 01:02:49,223
We eliminate the middleman,
direct from the Freedom Factory to you.

933
01:02:49,332 --> 01:02:52,995
And I'm not talking about one.
I'm not talking about two little items.

934
01:02:53,102 --> 01:02:57,562
I'm talking about the whole entire
complete Freedom Kit!

935
01:02:57,673 --> 01:03:00,642
In specially designed handy
Freedom leatherette.

936
01:03:00,743 --> 01:03:03,803
What do you say? Okay?
Take it away!

937
01:03:03,913 --> 01:03:06,040
- Take it away!
- Yes, sir!

938
01:03:06,149 --> 01:03:08,777
Don't forget it, and you won't regret it.

939
01:03:10,319 --> 01:03:14,915
I have here a little spray
that's just a little special.

940
01:03:15,024 --> 01:03:19,051
Just shake her, spray her
and, brother, enough for an acre.

941
01:03:19,162 --> 01:03:23,792
One little can this size, and there won't be a
leaf left in Central Park for the next 10 years.

942
01:03:23,900 --> 01:03:25,959
- Yeah!
- Yeah!

943
01:03:26,068 --> 01:03:29,037
<i>And here,</i>
<i>for the first time in Europe...</i>

944
01:03:29,138 --> 01:03:31,402
<i>the pen that goes boom.</i>

945
01:03:31,507 --> 01:03:33,805
<i>Looks just like an ordinary ballpoint pen.</i>

946
01:03:33,910 --> 01:03:36,777
It writes. It even leaks.
[Chuckles] Yes, sir.

947
01:03:36,879 --> 01:03:38,813
But watch out.

948
01:03:38,915 --> 01:03:40,883
<i>There's this little ball on the top.</i>

949
01:03:40,983 --> 01:03:43,349
<i>But there's the difference.</i>

950
01:03:43,452 --> 01:03:46,580
<i>Now watch this.</i>
<i>You don't push it.</i>

951
01:03:46,689 --> 01:03:49,214
- [Clicks]
- You turn it.

952
01:03:49,325 --> 01:03:52,988
- [Clicks]
- And, baby, va-va-voom.

953
01:03:54,564 --> 01:03:57,158
<i>[Explosion]</i>

954
01:03:57,266 --> 01:03:59,700
[All Cheering]

955
01:04:02,672 --> 01:04:06,472
Just the equivalent of 4,000 pounds ofT.N.T.
That's all.

956
01:04:06,576 --> 01:04:10,706
The pen. Complete with
delayed-action percussion cap...

957
01:04:10,813 --> 01:04:14,749
plus two-week supply
of super-F defoliator...

958
01:04:14,851 --> 01:04:17,843
plus a secret surprise gift weapon.

959
01:04:17,954 --> 01:04:19,888
It's all in the Freedom Kit...

960
01:04:19,989 --> 01:04:24,449
that Dicky Discount will have
at your disposal at the rear exit!

961
01:04:24,560 --> 01:04:26,585
Now, our program.

962
01:04:26,696 --> 01:04:29,028
Our end, fine.

963
01:04:29,131 --> 01:04:31,031
If not -

964
01:04:31,133 --> 01:04:33,124
[All]
If not?

965
01:04:33,236 --> 01:04:36,569
- If not, then this!
- [All] What is it?

966
01:04:36,672 --> 01:04:39,698
- The big one!
- [All] The big one!

967
01:04:40,710 --> 01:04:43,201
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!

968
01:04:43,312 --> 01:04:45,212
Freedom! Freedom!

969
01:04:45,314 --> 01:04:47,646
<i>[Gunshots]</i>

970
01:04:53,356 --> 01:04:55,381
[Shouting]

971
01:04:57,226 --> 01:04:59,854
Yes! Freedom!

972
01:04:59,962 --> 01:05:01,930
<i>[Mr. Freedom Shouting]</i>

973
01:05:07,136 --> 01:05:10,037
[All Shouting, Screaming]

974
01:05:10,139 --> 01:05:13,233
- [Man] Freedom!
- [All Shouting]

975
01:05:15,611 --> 01:05:17,579
<i>[Bottles Clanking]</i>

976
01:05:24,787 --> 01:05:28,052
The cold war.
Demoralize the population!

977
01:05:28,157 --> 01:05:30,853
[Man Shouts]

978
01:05:30,960 --> 01:05:33,360
- Freedom!
- Freedom!

979
01:05:36,866 --> 01:05:40,233
[Muttering In French]

980
01:05:42,705 --> 01:05:44,900
Hey. You want to see something?

981
01:05:49,445 --> 01:05:53,074
<i>- [Screaming]</i>
- Cold war, phase two.

982
01:05:53,182 --> 01:05:55,150
Harass the population.

983
01:05:55,251 --> 01:05:58,311
<i>- [Screaming Continues]</i>
- [Chuckles]

984
01:05:59,789 --> 01:06:02,519
<i>[Laughing]</i>

985
01:06:02,625 --> 01:06:05,526
<i>Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!</i>

986
01:06:05,628 --> 01:06:07,960
Wait.

987
01:06:11,400 --> 01:06:13,368
[All Shouting]

988
01:06:17,073 --> 01:06:19,803
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!

989
01:06:20,910 --> 01:06:22,878
Now, watch this.

990
01:06:26,916 --> 01:06:29,111
[Makes Noise, Chuckles]

991
01:06:29,218 --> 01:06:31,948
It is exactly 5:51.
Hello, big papas and little mamas.

992
01:06:32,054 --> 01:06:34,887
Hello, all you pals of Freedom.
I announce with great pleasure...

993
01:06:34,991 --> 01:06:37,425
the contest Cold War
on Radio Freedom!

994
01:06:37,526 --> 01:06:42,429
But to begin with, who is Mr. Freedom?
Well, my friends, first he was born poor.

995
01:06:42,531 --> 01:06:45,295
Dirt poor.
His father worked in the sewer.

996
01:06:45,401 --> 01:06:48,495
<i>Then came the depression.</i>
<i>They closed down the sewer.</i>

997
01:06:48,604 --> 01:06:52,165
<i>He had only one suit.</i>
<i>Nothing but patches, but clean.</i>

998
01:06:53,209 --> 01:06:55,473
The big one.

999
01:06:55,578 --> 01:06:58,308
- Very good.
- The tank.

1000
01:07:01,050 --> 01:07:03,018
Fifth column.

1001
01:07:07,490 --> 01:07:09,458
The hole.

1002
01:07:12,728 --> 01:07:14,719
Eighty-eight...

1003
01:07:15,831 --> 01:07:17,799
and 62.

1004
01:07:20,836 --> 01:07:22,804
Our Freedom Mouseketeers.

1005
01:07:23,839 --> 01:07:25,807
- Want some ice cream?
- Later.

1006
01:07:25,908 --> 01:07:29,344
Okay, chief.
And here's the Materializer...

1007
01:07:29,445 --> 01:07:33,347
making possible to send agents by express
tubes throughout the whole of France.

1008
01:07:33,449 --> 01:07:35,417
[Shouts Salute]

1009
01:07:35,518 --> 01:07:37,486
[Shouts Salute]

1010
01:07:46,662 --> 01:07:49,222
[Chattering]

1011
01:07:49,331 --> 01:07:51,891
Freddie. How's the survey going?

1012
01:07:52,001 --> 01:07:53,969
Would you like to listen in, boss?

1013
01:07:55,871 --> 01:07:58,237
<i>[Man]</i>
<i>Well, politics-wise he's got some good ideas...</i>

1014
01:07:58,340 --> 01:08:01,707
<i>but psychologically-wise,</i>
<i>Mr. Freedom made a couple of mistakes.</i>

1015
01:08:01,811 --> 01:08:03,802
<i>- [Man #2] Mistakes?</i>
<i>- [Man #3] Psychologically-wise?</i>

1016
01:08:03,913 --> 01:08:07,349
<i>Listen, mister. I'll tell you what he is.</i>
<i>He is a lousy, yellow, stinking mad dog.</i>

1017
01:08:07,450 --> 01:08:09,850
<i>- That is what he is.</i>
<i>- [Man #1 ] I wouldn't go that far.</i>

1018
01:08:09,952 --> 01:08:11,920
<i>[Man #2]</i>
<i>So you're anti-Freedom. So you're against.</i>

1019
01:08:12,021 --> 01:08:14,854
<i>But you gotta be for something.</i>
<i>What's your program?</i>

1020
01:08:14,957 --> 01:08:18,154
<i>[Man #3] What are you talking about?</i>
<i>Freedom is the enemy, so we are against him.</i>

1021
01:08:18,260 --> 01:08:20,160
<i>[Man #2]</i>
<i>But you can talk to him, negotiate.</i>

1022
01:08:20,262 --> 01:08:23,959
<i>[Man #3] Make a deal with him,</i>
<i>it's a deal with the devil. You take</i>
<i>his dishwashers, he'll take your soul!</i>

1023
01:08:24,066 --> 01:08:28,503
<i>- [Man #1 ] Who's talking about soul?</i>
<i>- [Man #3] Look. It is not the quantity.</i>
<i>It is the quality oflife.</i>

1024
01:08:28,604 --> 01:08:31,596
<i>- Do you want to become a zombie?</i>
<i>- [Man #2] The truth is, friend-is-is...</i>

1025
01:08:31,707 --> 01:08:34,335
<i>Freedom's just a big kid,</i>
<i>kind of Boy Scout.</i>

1026
01:08:34,443 --> 01:08:38,311
<i>- He wants to do good.</i>
<i>- [Man #3] His program's fine overall,</i>
<i>but he doesn't understand us.</i>

1027
01:08:38,414 --> 01:08:40,382
<i>- He'll never understand us.</i>
<i>- [Man #1 ] What's that?</i>

1028
01:08:40,483 --> 01:08:43,975
- Good. Enough.
- Christ. What kind of a percentage
does that give us?

1029
01:08:44,086 --> 01:08:46,816
Percent.

1030
01:08:46,922 --> 01:08:52,189
First returns in Paris:
12%, uh, for Freedom.

1031
01:08:52,294 --> 01:08:55,092
76% against...

1032
01:08:55,197 --> 01:08:57,893
and, uh - 12 - 21 don't know.

1033
01:08:58,000 --> 01:09:01,697
[Shouts] They don't know?
All right. They'll find out!

1034
01:09:01,804 --> 01:09:03,704
I'll teach them.

1035
01:09:03,806 --> 01:09:06,969
This is only Paris,
and these are only the first returns.

1036
01:09:07,076 --> 01:09:11,012
Yeah. Wise guys, huh?
I'll wise-guy them.

1037
01:09:12,081 --> 01:09:14,515
All right. While we're waiting,
double your prices!

1038
01:09:14,617 --> 01:09:17,051
Mr. Freedom! Mr. Freedom!

1039
01:09:17,153 --> 01:09:19,485
A messenger from Moujik Man.

1040
01:09:27,596 --> 01:09:30,588
To be delivered in person.
Are you Mr. Freedom?

1041
01:09:30,699 --> 01:09:32,826
- No, I'm Santa Claus.
- Receipt, please.

1042
01:09:36,105 --> 01:09:38,130
<i>[Man]</i>
<i>Right, guys.</i>

1043
01:09:38,240 --> 01:09:40,868
- Open it.
- Look out. Maybe it's a booby trap.

1044
01:09:40,976 --> 01:09:43,536
<i>[Man]</i>
<i>Hit it with a Freedom ray.</i>

1045
01:09:43,646 --> 01:09:46,080
- [Electrical Hum]
- Okay.

1046
01:09:52,821 --> 01:09:55,153
[All]
Captain Formidable!

1047
01:09:55,257 --> 01:09:58,590
Watch it.
There is a card. Tornado.

1048
01:10:01,730 --> 01:10:03,630
"My deepest condolences.

1049
01:10:03,732 --> 01:10:07,896
I share your grief.
Signed, Moujik Man."

1050
01:10:08,003 --> 01:10:11,871
They froze him.
Hey, that's beautiful.

1051
01:10:11,974 --> 01:10:14,568
That's pretty goddamn thoughtful of him.

1052
01:10:14,677 --> 01:10:17,373
Hey. There are some instructions.

1053
01:10:19,882 --> 01:10:21,782
"Keep in a cool place.

1054
01:10:21,884 --> 01:10:24,045
"Can be preserved indefinitely.

1055
01:10:25,154 --> 01:10:27,987
Resuscitate only under doctor's orders."

1056
01:10:28,090 --> 01:10:30,957
Jesus. Poor guy.

1057
01:10:31,060 --> 01:10:34,188
- Okay. Stick him over there
for the time being.
- Right, men.

1058
01:10:34,296 --> 01:10:37,322
- 6:00 p.m., Freedom.
- This is it!

1059
01:10:37,433 --> 01:10:40,129
In one hour, my ultimatum expires.

1060
01:10:40,236 --> 01:10:43,262
You, go to Super French Man.
Bring back his answer.

1061
01:10:44,607 --> 01:10:50,273
To Super French Man.
Five, four, three, two, one, boom.

1062
01:10:54,550 --> 01:10:57,110
What do you hear from the front?

1063
01:10:57,219 --> 01:10:59,881
Well, I think I see daylight.

1064
01:10:59,989 --> 01:11:03,584
We can be prudently optimistic.

1065
01:11:03,692 --> 01:11:09,562
Where forces are deployed, our first
operations have been crowned with, uh...

1066
01:11:09,665 --> 01:11:11,758
enormous success.

1067
01:11:11,867 --> 01:11:15,735
The F.A.F. Terrorists are infiltrating
pretty much everywhere...

1068
01:11:15,838 --> 01:11:17,738
but are not supported by the people.

1069
01:11:17,840 --> 01:11:23,039
So they murder, they plunder
and generally carry on.

1070
01:11:23,145 --> 01:11:27,605
- Jesus Christ.
- They made a big, big fuss over Red Maria.

1071
01:11:27,716 --> 01:11:31,812
In Paris,
there were 500,000 at her funeral.

1072
01:11:31,920 --> 01:11:33,854
That no-good bitch.

1073
01:11:33,956 --> 01:11:36,356
- Look, I will run it for you.
<i>- Mr. Freedom say there are-</i>

1074
01:11:36,458 --> 01:11:39,450
[Dirge]

1075
01:11:52,207 --> 01:11:54,903
I've seen enough.
It's starting to get on my nerves.

1076
01:11:55,010 --> 01:11:57,342
Who was she, for Christ's sake?
Joan of Arc?

1077
01:11:57,446 --> 01:11:59,414
Call Marie Madeleine.

1078
01:12:01,083 --> 01:12:03,210
At ease.

1079
01:12:03,319 --> 01:12:05,310
- Get Marie Madeleine.
- Marie Madeleine!

1080
01:12:05,421 --> 01:12:09,721
Five, four, three, two, one, boom!

1081
01:12:09,825 --> 01:12:11,793
[Gunshots]

1082
01:12:15,464 --> 01:12:16,988
Save the machine!

1083
01:12:17,099 --> 01:12:19,067
- [Shouts]
<i>- [Gunshots]</i>

1084
01:12:22,338 --> 01:12:24,806
Where's my combat mask?

1085
01:12:24,907 --> 01:12:26,875
<i>[Gunshots]</i>

1086
01:12:28,110 --> 01:12:30,078
<i>[Machine Gun Fire]</i>

1087
01:12:34,216 --> 01:12:36,514
Change the cables!

1088
01:12:36,618 --> 01:12:38,415
<i>- [Machine Gun Fire]</i>
- [Screaming]

1089
01:12:39,521 --> 01:12:42,786
[Machine Gun Fire]

1090
01:12:43,992 --> 01:12:46,790
[Grunting]

1091
01:12:46,895 --> 01:12:48,863
[Groans]

1092
01:12:48,964 --> 01:12:50,932
<i>[Machine Gun Fire]</i>

1093
01:12:55,704 --> 01:12:58,229
<i>[Machine Gun Fire]</i>

1094
01:13:08,550 --> 01:13:12,008
- [Indistinct]
<i>- [Machine Gun Fire Continues]</i>

1095
01:13:18,660 --> 01:13:20,628
[Shouts]

1096
01:13:22,631 --> 01:13:25,361
- What's the body count?
- Grand Duc Eddie, Roger Dropout...

1097
01:13:25,467 --> 01:13:29,028
- Detergent -
- It's a woman.

1098
01:13:35,644 --> 01:13:38,238
[Woman]
It's Marie -

1099
01:13:39,281 --> 01:13:41,181
[Groans Softly]

1100
01:13:41,283 --> 01:13:44,616
Marie Madeleine!
She was a spy!

1101
01:13:44,720 --> 01:13:46,688
<i>[Mr. Freedom]</i>
<i>Who?</i>

1102
01:13:48,791 --> 01:13:52,887
Marie. You've let me down.
How could you?

1103
01:13:56,064 --> 01:13:59,329
You'll never understand anything.

1104
01:14:02,271 --> 01:14:04,705
So you never loved me.

1105
01:14:04,807 --> 01:14:06,775
[Chuckles]

1106
01:14:07,910 --> 01:14:10,435
How could I have missed you?

1107
01:14:13,415 --> 01:14:16,316
So you're the one who killed
Captain Formidable.

1108
01:14:16,418 --> 01:14:19,615
Yes, you moron,
and I'm proud of it.

1109
01:14:19,721 --> 01:14:22,087
[Shouts]
You're proud of it?

1110
01:14:22,191 --> 01:14:27,219
Okay, bitch!
You're gonna pay for that!

1111
01:14:37,072 --> 01:14:39,040
Marie!

1112
01:14:41,477 --> 01:14:43,445
No.

1113
01:14:51,954 --> 01:14:54,252
<i>[Man]</i>
<i>Mr. Freedom!</i>

1114
01:14:54,356 --> 01:14:58,087
<i>The Anti-Freedom have intercepted</i>
<i>your messenger!</i>

1115
01:15:03,332 --> 01:15:05,527
<i>- [Chimes]</i>
<i>- [Materializer Clattering]</i>

1116
01:15:07,936 --> 01:15:10,564
Messenger reporting
from the Anti-Freedom!

1117
01:15:26,655 --> 01:15:29,818
[Clears Throat]
Freedom.

1118
01:15:29,925 --> 01:15:32,223
The answer from Anti-Freedom
headquarters.

1119
01:15:32,327 --> 01:15:34,295
What does he say?

1120
01:15:46,508 --> 01:15:49,671
[Screams]

1121
01:15:49,778 --> 01:15:54,442
French Anti-Freedom, Red China Man,
Moujik Man, everybody!

1122
01:15:54,550 --> 01:15:58,008
Say your prayers!

1123
01:15:58,120 --> 01:16:00,611
Announcement.

1124
01:16:00,722 --> 01:16:03,782
French Anti-Freedom has refused
to negotiate. This is it.

1125
01:16:03,892 --> 01:16:06,759
End of cold war,
beginning of escalation.

1126
01:16:06,862 --> 01:16:10,161
- [All Shouting]
- Battle stations!

1127
01:16:10,265 --> 01:16:12,893
- [Mr. Freedom] Mont-Saint-Michel.
- Mont-Saint-Michel!

1128
01:16:13,001 --> 01:16:15,367
- [Woman] Mont-Saint-Michel.
- [Man] Mont-Saint-Michel.

1129
01:16:15,470 --> 01:16:20,373
- Mont-Saint-Michel.
- Five, four, three, two, one, zero.

1130
01:16:20,475 --> 01:16:23,774
[Explosions]

1131
01:16:26,815 --> 01:16:29,545
<i>- [All Cheering]</i>
- [Laughing] Samaritaine store!

1132
01:16:29,651 --> 01:16:31,551
- Samaritaine!
- [Woman] Samaritaine!

1133
01:16:31,653 --> 01:16:33,712
- Samaritaine!
- Samaritaine.

1134
01:16:33,822 --> 01:16:38,623
<i>Cinq, quatre, trois, deux, un, zéro!</i>

1135
01:16:38,727 --> 01:16:40,991
<i>[Explosions]</i>

1136
01:16:47,703 --> 01:16:49,967
<i>- [All Cheering]</i>
- Mont Blanc!

1137
01:16:50,072 --> 01:16:51,664
- Mont Blanc!
- [Woman] Mont Blanc!

1138
01:16:51,773 --> 01:16:54,241
- Mont Blanc!
<i>- [Mr. Drugstore] Mont Blanc!</i>

1139
01:16:54,343 --> 01:16:58,837
<i>Cinq, quatre, trois, deux, un, zéro!</i>

1140
01:16:58,947 --> 01:17:01,780
<i>[Explosions]</i>

1141
01:17:01,883 --> 01:17:04,477
- Bull's-eye!
- [All Cheering]

1142
01:17:07,089 --> 01:17:09,455
<i>- [Man] All right! Freedom!</i>
- Hurrah!

1143
01:17:09,558 --> 01:17:11,458
Hurrah!

1144
01:17:11,560 --> 01:17:14,154
- The bridge at Tancarville.
- Pont Tancarville.

1145
01:17:14,262 --> 01:17:16,162
- Pont Tancarville.
- Pont Tancarville!

1146
01:17:16,264 --> 01:17:19,791
<i>- [Mr. Drugstore] Pont Tancarville.</i>
<i>- Trois, deux, un, zéro.</i>

1147
01:17:31,246 --> 01:17:34,443
<i>[All Cheering]</i>

1148
01:17:34,549 --> 01:17:37,109
<i>[Whistle Blows]</i>

1149
01:17:37,219 --> 01:17:39,187
Freedom break.

1150
01:17:39,287 --> 01:17:41,687
[Mr. Freedom]
Thank you. You've been magnificent.

1151
01:17:42,758 --> 01:17:45,386
I'm very happy to announce...

1152
01:17:45,494 --> 01:17:47,428
that we've destroyed...

1153
01:17:47,529 --> 01:17:50,157
- at least half of the country.
- [Cheering]

1154
01:17:50,265 --> 01:17:52,233
<i>[Gunshots]</i>

1155
01:18:02,210 --> 01:18:04,178
[Whistles]

1156
01:18:04,279 --> 01:18:06,247
Silence!

1157
01:18:08,250 --> 01:18:12,880
I hope that now they'll understand
that aggression does not pay.

1158
01:18:12,988 --> 01:18:16,549
I'll speak to the nation.
I'll grant them a truce.

1159
01:18:16,658 --> 01:18:20,458
- Then I'll take an inspection trip.
<i>- [Applause]</i>

1160
01:18:26,101 --> 01:18:28,194
Let's go. Let's go.

1161
01:18:33,408 --> 01:18:37,811
You've heard a lot about him
these past few days.

1162
01:18:37,913 --> 01:18:40,882
In a few moments,
we'll have the honor...

1163
01:18:40,982 --> 01:18:44,748
of introducing him to you in person.

1164
01:18:44,853 --> 01:18:47,253
Ladies and gentlemen...

1165
01:18:47,355 --> 01:18:49,823
Mr. Freedom.

1166
01:18:53,395 --> 01:18:56,523
I speak to you as a friend.

1167
01:18:56,631 --> 01:18:59,532
You suffer. I suffer.

1168
01:18:59,634 --> 01:19:03,161
You cry. I cry with you.

1169
01:19:03,271 --> 01:19:06,206
And yet, at the same time,
I rejoice...

1170
01:19:06,308 --> 01:19:11,109
for it is in suffering that we are born
and our alliance will be born.

1171
01:19:12,314 --> 01:19:16,307
The steel of our friendship
will be forged in fire...

1172
01:19:16,418 --> 01:19:18,818
and tempered in blood.

1173
01:19:20,355 --> 01:19:23,017
I give you my solemn word.

1174
01:19:23,125 --> 01:19:26,322
Everything that I have destroyed...

1175
01:19:26,428 --> 01:19:30,023
I will rebuild better than before.

1176
01:19:30,132 --> 01:19:33,295
You want peace.
We want peace.

1177
01:19:33,401 --> 01:19:36,837
But your leaders do not want peace.

1178
01:19:36,938 --> 01:19:40,169
I grant a 24-hour truce.

1179
01:19:40,275 --> 01:19:45,008
I beg you,
for your sake and for mine...

1180
01:19:45,113 --> 01:19:48,310
don't force me to go all the way.

1181
01:19:49,785 --> 01:19:51,685
Help me...

1182
01:19:51,787 --> 01:19:53,687
and I'll help you.

1183
01:19:54,723 --> 01:19:56,987
Amen.

1184
01:20:00,195 --> 01:20:03,028
<i>[Chanting In Distance]</i>

1185
01:20:05,567 --> 01:20:07,159
[Chanting In French]

1186
01:20:38,934 --> 01:20:44,531
[Singing In French]

1187
01:20:52,347 --> 01:20:55,874
<i>[Man Speaking French]</i>

1188
01:21:29,551 --> 01:21:31,781
[Cheering]

1189
01:21:33,121 --> 01:21:35,089
[Shouting]

1190
01:21:55,610 --> 01:21:57,578
<i>[Radio:Static]</i>

1191
01:22:02,817 --> 01:22:04,944
<i>[Radio:Static]</i>

1192
01:22:11,226 --> 01:22:13,194
<i>[Beeps]</i>

1193
01:22:15,830 --> 01:22:17,798
<i>[Faint Beeping]</i>

1194
01:22:33,715 --> 01:22:36,741
<i>[TV: Women Sing, Faint]</i>

1195
01:22:42,991 --> 01:22:45,653
<i>[Radio:Static, Beeps]</i>

1196
01:22:54,669 --> 01:22:59,003
[TV: Crowd Singing "L'Internationale"]

1197
01:23:18,326 --> 01:23:20,851
[Stops]

1198
01:23:20,962 --> 01:23:22,930
<i>[Beeps]</i>

1199
01:23:44,052 --> 01:23:46,020
<i>[Radio:Static]</i>

1200
01:24:01,336 --> 01:24:03,827
[Groaning]

1201
01:24:08,276 --> 01:24:11,643
They came back.

1202
01:24:15,183 --> 01:24:19,517
We couldn't do anything.

1203
01:24:21,423 --> 01:24:24,517
F - Freedom.

1204
01:24:27,695 --> 01:24:30,425
They took...

1205
01:24:30,532 --> 01:24:33,592
the big one.

1206
01:24:33,701 --> 01:24:36,465
[Groans]

1207
01:24:36,571 --> 01:24:40,268
Good-bye, Free -

1208
01:24:43,778 --> 01:24:47,908
Good old Dick.
You're dying for Freedom.

1209
01:24:49,017 --> 01:24:52,145
Peace be with you.
So be it.

1210
01:24:53,588 --> 01:24:55,556
Amen.

1211
01:25:10,338 --> 01:25:13,102
Lousy frogs.

1212
01:25:17,112 --> 01:25:19,512
Don't worry.
I got another one.

1213
01:26:00,355 --> 01:26:03,518
Okay, you had your chance...

1214
01:26:03,625 --> 01:26:05,923
and you muffed it!

1215
01:26:06,027 --> 01:26:08,621
You asked for it...

1216
01:26:08,730 --> 01:26:13,667
and you're gonna get it!

1217
01:26:15,069 --> 01:26:18,038
<i>[Loud Explosion]</i>

1218
01:26:26,014 --> 01:26:27,982
<i>[Fires Crackling]</i>

1219
01:27:10,558 --> 01:27:14,050
- [Clicks]
- [Beeping]

1220
01:27:14,162 --> 01:27:16,756
So, how did it go?

1221
01:27:16,864 --> 01:27:18,764
The enemy...

1222
01:27:18,866 --> 01:27:21,164
destroyed his own country.

1223
01:27:22,203 --> 01:27:24,103
I had to throw the big one.

1224
01:27:24,205 --> 01:27:27,800
I know, son, and I'm proud of you.

1225
01:27:27,909 --> 01:27:30,673
But to tell you the truth,
it was only a medium one.

1226
01:27:30,778 --> 01:27:33,269
I wasn't able to give you a big one
at the time.

1227
01:27:33,381 --> 01:27:35,975
- But we didn't lose, did we?
<i>- Heck no!</i>

1228
01:27:36,084 --> 01:27:39,417
<i>Little skirmish maybe.</i>
<i>But not any war. Not by a long shot.</i>

1229
01:27:39,520 --> 01:27:42,045
Well, nothing's signed yet anyhow.

1230
01:27:42,156 --> 01:27:45,250
I know, but they're bastards.

1231
01:27:45,360 --> 01:27:49,262
Ungrateful. Treacherous.
Different.

1232
01:27:49,364 --> 01:27:51,491
You can't imagine what they're like.

1233
01:27:51,599 --> 01:27:55,091
Look. You did what you could.
It was their fault.

1234
01:27:55,203 --> 01:27:58,104
They don't need us.
So who needs them?

1235
01:27:58,206 --> 01:28:02,472
They're not ready for Freedom.
They want to follow false gods, let them.

1236
01:28:02,577 --> 01:28:04,909
Let dogs eat dogs.

1237
01:28:05,013 --> 01:28:08,278
Wait till Red China Man
gets his hooks into them.

1238
01:28:08,383 --> 01:28:12,046
They'll soon come crybabying to us. Yes.

1239
01:28:12,153 --> 01:28:14,849
And we shall not be found wanting. No.

1240
01:28:14,956 --> 01:28:18,414
We shall open up our arms. Yes.

1241
01:28:18,526 --> 01:28:20,494
Forgive and forget.

1242
01:28:20,595 --> 01:28:22,586
That is Christ's way...

1243
01:28:22,697 --> 01:28:25,063
<i>and that is our way.</i>

1244
01:28:25,166 --> 01:28:27,430
[Mr. Freedom]
Amen. But if-

1245
01:28:27,535 --> 01:28:29,594
Look, son. Hear this.

1246
01:28:29,704 --> 01:28:31,763
There are many ways to skin a cat.

1247
01:28:31,873 --> 01:28:34,364
It's "F" Hour here at home.
We're on the move!

1248
01:28:34,475 --> 01:28:37,603
Things are going our way.
We're knocking 'em off like flies.

1249
01:28:37,712 --> 01:28:43,446
We have a commitment.
This land shall be a fortress of freedom.

1250
01:28:44,485 --> 01:28:48,421
I need you by my side,
and I have a surprise for you.

1251
01:28:48,523 --> 01:28:51,458
- You're promoted.
- You know, sir...

1252
01:28:51,559 --> 01:28:53,550
my arm -

1253
01:28:53,661 --> 01:28:56,596
Do not look back.
Do not brood.

1254
01:28:56,698 --> 01:29:00,361
You need a change of scenery.
Take a little vacation.

1255
01:29:00,468 --> 01:29:03,301
Rest up. Meditate.

1256
01:29:03,404 --> 01:29:06,737
Now, son, let us sing together.

1257
01:29:06,841 --> 01:29:12,177
F-R-double-E-D, D-O-M
spells boom, boom

1258
01:29:12,280 --> 01:29:16,876
- F-R-double-E-D, C-O-M spells freedom
- [Mr. Freedom] Fight for freedom

1259
01:29:16,984 --> 01:29:19,282
We fight for freedom

1260
01:29:19,387 --> 01:29:21,582
- Fight free -
<i>- [Dr. Freedom] For one and for all</i>

1261
01:29:21,689 --> 01:29:24,249
- [Groans]
<i>- It's you and me-dom</i>

1262
01:29:24,359 --> 01:29:27,021
<i>And</i> 1 <i>0 foot tall</i>

1263
01:29:27,128 --> 01:29:31,087
[Groaning]
Freedom for-

1264
01:29:31,199 --> 01:29:33,326
- [Groaning] For-
- <i>We fight for freedom</i>

1265
01:29:33,434 --> 01:29:36,267
<i>- For one and for all</i>
- Freedom.

1266
01:29:36,371 --> 01:29:39,340
- [Dr. Freedom] It's you and me-dom
- Fight for-

1267
01:29:40,475 --> 01:29:42,409
[Dr. Freedom]
Freedom, freedom

1268
01:29:42,510 --> 01:29:45,035
And oh-can-you-see-dom

1269
01:29:45,146 --> 01:29:47,376
We'll always beat 'em with

1270
01:29:47,482 --> 01:29:51,043
Star-spangled freedom

1271
01:29:51,152 --> 01:29:52,278
<i>[Whistle Blows]</i>

1272
01:29:52,387 --> 01:29:55,914
<i>[Marching Band Continues Song]</i>

1273
01:30:21,249 --> 01:30:26,118
<i>[Chorus] We fight for freedom</i>
<i>for one and for all</i>

1274
01:30:26,220 --> 01:30:30,714
<i>It's you and me-dom</i>
<i>and</i> 1 <i>0 foot tall</i>

1275
01:30:30,825 --> 01:30:35,626
<i>Freedom, freedom</i>
<i>and oh-can-you-see-dom</i>

1276
01:30:35,730 --> 01:30:40,429
<i>We'll always beat 'em</i>
<i>with star-spangled freedom</i>

1277
01:30:40,535 --> 01:30:45,097
<i>- F-R-double-E-D, D-O-M spells</i>
<i>- [Two Bass Drum Hits]</i>

1278
01:30:45,206 --> 01:30:49,802
<i>F- R-double-E-D, D-O-M</i>
<i>spells freedom</i>

1279
01:30:49,911 --> 01:30:54,610
<i>We fight for freedom</i>
<i>for one and for all</i>

1280
01:30:54,715 --> 01:30:59,345
<i>It's you and me-dom</i>
<i>and</i> 1 <i>0 foot tall</i>

1281
01:30:59,454 --> 01:31:04,084
<i>Freedom, freedom</i>
<i>and oh-can-you-see-dom</i>

1282
01:31:04,192 --> 01:31:08,686
<i>We'll always beat 'em</i>
<i>with star-spangled freedom</i>

1283
01:31:08,796 --> 01:31:13,233
<i>- F-R-double-E-D, D-O-M spells</i>
<i>- [Two Bass Drum Hits]</i>

1284
01:31:13,334 --> 01:31:17,964
<i>F- R-double-E-D, D-O-M</i>
<i>spells freedom</i>

1285
01:31:18,072 --> 01:31:22,566
<i>We fight for freedom</i>
<i>for one and for all</i>

1286
01:31:22,677 --> 01:31:27,341
<i>It's you and me-dom</i>
<i>and</i> 1 <i>0 foot tall</i>

1287
01:31:27,448 --> 01:31:32,351
<i>Freedom, freedom</i>
<i>and oh-can-you-see-dom</i>

1288
01:31:32,453 --> 01:31:34,478
<i>We'll always beat 'em</i>

1289
01:31:34,589 --> 01:31:39,492
<i>With star-spangled freedom</i>

1290
01:31:40,828 --> 01:31:44,320
<i>Yeah! Freedom!</i>

1291
01:31:44,432 --> 01:31:46,764
<i>Wow!</i>

