resynced for HDRip by: catang-isip
A JUNG ./[WOO FILM PRODUCTION
LET'S FILM PRODUCTION
EUNGYO
I have never seen a moon so beautiful.
I believe she was watching the same moon.
But to her
The moon wouldn't have looked so beautiful.
Every person sees a different vision
of a same object.
Who are you?
I'm Eungyo.
How did you get in here?
There's a ladder by the fence.
I've always wanted to
sit in a chair like this.
Does it belong to you?
You came down from the woods?
Where do you live?
Next to the laundromat.
I'll get going now.
Goodbye.
The term 'National Poet' sounds crude.
It is such a blessing to be able to
learn from such a great teacher.
I don't think age matters
once you're past 20.
I'm too old to be called a prodigy.
In my case,
I think I'm just the right age
To present Heart to the world with confidence.
I will try harder in the future
And there will be much suffering involved.
Too salty?
Now you can write your own stories.
The Heart is topping charts everywhere!
By the way,
I've been commissioned a story.
What?
I would like to concentrate on that, so...
Remember the girl who was sleeping on your porch?
I gave her a ride
from her school by chance
And she was looking for a part-time job.
Isn't she in high school?
She said that she does
all the housework at home.
Tell her to come this Saturday afternoon.
Hello.
Sorry!
It's okay.
Let me do it.
- No, it's fine. I'll do it.
- No, I'll do it.
Don't worry.
Be careful.
Bummer!
What does 'bummer' mean?
Uh, it means thank you very much.
And your name is...
It's Seo Eunpa.
- Thank you, Eunpa.
- Now can I get a hug?
Of course.
Thank you very much.
When I clean the top window,
my fingers go wriggly.
Reminds me of dance lessons...
I use to take dance classes
until 7th grade.
Can you tighten it some more?
How are you going to breathe?
And the skirt?
This short?
Shorter.
They'll be able to see your panties!
All right, this much...
Grumpa, Your pencils are all stumpy.
Would you like me to sharpen them?
Let them be.
Sharp pencils are woeful.
What's so woeful about them?
What do you think?
Grumpa.
If pencils are sad
because they're sharp...
Does that mean
all sharp pencils are sad?
Is that...
poetry?
Images one derives from an object...
Is often as far apart as heaven and hell.
When I think of pencils
I see a boy running to school.
He loved the sound of his pencil case
rattling inside his school bag.
When the boy couldn't afford
to go to school any more
The rattling sounded
as if the pencils were crying.
So to me,
the pencils means tears.
When you say
'Grumpa, please sharpen my pencil'
I hear this instead.
'Grumpa, please wipe away my tears.'
Grumpa ?
It's me, Eungyo.
Grumpa.
What are you doing here
at this time of night?
Can't you see I'm wet?
Scolding me first...
Grumpa
Can I stay the night?
What?
Please let me stay.
I can't go home tonight.
Let me see your face.
Someone has slapped you.
Who is it?
Is it someone you know?
My mom.
Your mother?
She does that sometimes.
But only to me...
I usually go to my friend's house
when something like this happens.
Let's get you changed first.
Follow me.
Grumpa.
Can I tell you something?
I'll take you home
when the rain stops.
Can I tell you something?
Can I?
What?
I said, can I tell you something?
Yes.
I remembered.
Your poem in the textbook.
'Camellia ', right?
A little bird by the camellia grave.
A sad bird with red beaks.
A little bird who left crimson tear marks.
It was in my last exam.
By the way...
For me...
Pencils remind me of mom.
When I was young,
She used to shave her heels
with my pencil knife.
Crouching...
She doesn't do it any more
Now that she works in a public bathhouse...
Now it's running sore
So you have to use a dryer.
I don't know what's worse.
That's why I think
the pencil sharpener is sad.
Or is it the heel sad?
That's poetry.
Sad pencil...
Sad heel...
Grumpa!
What do you think about my feet?
Bummer!
Bummer?
You are thanking me
For dropping your blouse?
Grumpa...
Let's have breakfast.
Hello.
What are you wearing?
It's Grumpa's. .
Very comfortable.
Where is he?
I don't know.
Is he in the study?
Grumpa! Did you sleep well?
He doesn't eat bread.
I said he doesn't eat bread.
There is some in the freezer.
It's mine.
I think he'll want to eat it.
What do you know?
Then you think
you know him that well?
Of course.
Really?
Grumpa.
Ta-da!
Home-made club sandwich.
Looks good, doesn't it?
Stuff in the refrigerator
turned into work of art.
Try it.
Yes.
Sir, you don't eat bread.
This isn't bread.
It's a sandwich.
I'll bring some coffee.
Sir, she's a high school girl.
Yes she is.
What's wrong with that?
What?
No, nothing...
The roll of thunder was deafening.
How could you be so calm?
I was scared to death.
You must have a lot on your conscience.
That's why I was hiding in.
I found you near my waist in the morning.
Not much of a place to hide...
By the way,
I saw the tattoo below your neck.
Fascinating.
You mean the henna?
It's not a tattoo?
It rubs off after a few days...
You can stop coming to his house now.
Why?
I won't be paying you any more.
That's strange.
He asked me come twice a week.
What?
He gave me the key to the front gate
because the ladder's too dangerous.
Hey!
My mirror!
Clumsy girl.
Why do you need a mirror in the woods?
It's an Anna Sui princess mirror!
Anna Sui? What's that?
I'll buy you a new one just like it.
Mom gave it to me on my birthday.
I'll buy you one.
I'll buy you the same one.
It's not the same!
What the...
It may look the same to you
But to me,
It's as different as heaven and hell.
It was her first birthday present to me!
The same one isn't the same!
What are you talking about?
Why shouldn't it be same?
Sir?
Sir!
Sir; be careful!
Watch your feet!
Under your foot! Right there!
- Do something!
- Slowly... slowly...!
Right there! Under your foot!
Be careful!
That's it; sir!
Sir; put the mirror in your pocket.
In your pocket! Your pocket, sir!
Sir!
Slowly, slowly...
Take my hand, sir.
Here you go.
Your mother gave it to you..
It must be precious.
Why did you do that?
You could have been hurt!
Grumpa.
Grumpa!
Remember what you've asked me before?
What?
About the henna on my chest.
Uh, yes.
I knew then that you want to try it.
No, no.
You don't mean what you say!
You are curious about teenagers' activities,
As I am about grown-ups'.
- I really don't want to.
- Come on.
Lie down.
Rest your head on my leg.
Your leg?
How else would I draw?
Unbutton your shirt. One...
Two, three.
Grumpa. Your chest is really smooth.
Is it?
Stop moving.
I can't draw properly.
Close your eyes.
All right.
I guess grown ups are ticklish as well.
I have ticklish ankles.
Just below the ankle.
You know the shallow part.
Don't...
I could easily wrap my fingers
around Eungyo's ankle
Her heel slipped between my fingers
And she giggled.
Her fragrant head rested be/ow my chin
And my lips were already buried
in her hair.
She sighed like a pair of bellows.
Grumpa, you can open your eyes now.
Look. It's the same one as mine.
So it is.
I held you close in my arms.
I caressed your hair;
your shoulders, your waist
And I put my ear to your chest
listening to your heart beating.
You were so heartbreakingly beautiful.
Can you do me a favor; Eungyo?
No, I think I have the flu.
Can you bring me some medicine?
Just some aspirin.
Hello?
Anybody here?
How is your flu?
You!
What are you doing to him?
What?
He isn't who you think he is, okay?
He's a noble person!
How do you know
what he means to me?
What are you saying?
What did I do?
How do you know
what he means to me?
Jerk off, you motherfucker.
What did you say?
Jerk off?
Did you call me motherfucker?
What did you call me?
I could just...
You are putting him in danger.
In danger?!
If you hadn't messed around
with that mirror,
Yes, the mirror!
If you hadn't cried over that mirror
He wouldn't have risked his life.
You were the reason I dropped it!
What's so special about that mirror?
It's just one of thousands from a factory.
You can buy the same one over and over.
What's all the fuss about?
I told you it was
a birthday present from Mom!
So what?!
You think it's filled with
her love or something?
Here.
I'd forgotten you were an engineering major.
Engineering major?
He told me about the first time you two met.
What did he say?
It took you 10 years to realize
that all stars aren't the same.
What do you think 'that' means here?
Yes?
A star.
This is the best example which illustrates
modernity and self-sufficiency of modern poetry.
It's meaningful that this poem
emphasizes originality especially .
Sir.
Comparing something as beautiful as a star
to a goose feed or prison wall
is considered poetic sentiment?
Do I know you?
I don't believe we've met.
My name is Seo Jiwoo.
Sophomore, department of inorganic engineering.
I don't know who told you
that stars are beautiful.
Stars aren't beautiful or ugly.
Stars are just stars.
To lovers, stars may look beautiful
But to a hungry person
It may look like a tasty snack.
If you are in inorganic industry,
The star may seem full of pesticide.
Sir...
Inorganic means materials
like ceramics and minerals.
Not inorganic food.
What else he tell you?
About the time he went to prison.
How he learned to fix cars in there.
He can take a car apart
And put it together again.
What did he tell you about me?
I don't know.
Is there something I shouldn't hear?
Or something you want me to hear?
So this is The Heart.
I want to read it.
Can I borrow it?
Hey, did you... read it?
What?
I mean The Heart.
Your novel?
No, I've been busy with mid-term exams.
Don't read it if you haven't started yet.
It's just a vulgar commercial novel.
Hey, hey!
What do you think you're doing?
What's the fuss?
He puts his writings in here.
It's too far.
You've seen him writing?
It's hard for him to go back and forth.
This is the perfect spot.
No, don't, don't!
He hates it when things are out of place.
He doesn't like changes.
What's the use of wasting this pretty chest?
It's been there since before you were born.
It's older than you!
So what if it's older than me?
Help me move it. It looks better there.
Go away.
Move!
You think I won't do it?
Don't! What the...
Go away, now.
Move, I said!
Don't.
I told you to move.
What's wrong with you?
I warned you!
Go away!
Here he is!
Get away from there
Now, move!
Grumpa!
I cleaned your library all day.
- You did?
- Yes, I didn't do much...
Grumpa, about that chest...
I wanted to move it for your convenience
But he won't let me.
What are you doing?
Eungyo, let it be.
Every wooden furniture
likes to take root in a certain place.
It's been there since before you were born
It won't do to uproot it.
I'm sorry.
Sir, the meeting date
has been set.
It'll be on Monday over lunch.
I made a reservation
at your favorite restaurant.
Who's coming?
County officials and people
from Camellia Literature Museum.
I want to go as well.
May I please come?
Now you are pushing it too far.
Why shouldn't I come?
I can go after school
And you can give me a ride.
- It'll be around six.
- Yes!
They have great food there.
Really?
Let's go, just you and me.
By the way...
Have you read The Heart ?
The Heart?
You read it?
Yes.
How did you like it?
I was pleasantly surprised!
It was good.
How about you?
It's a genre novel but not just that.
It's poetic, and shows
-deep introspection of human being.
- Sir...
But I don't think he likes it.
He called it a vulgar commercial novel.
I didn't mean that, sir.
A parent never discards his off springs,
No matter how troublesome they may be.
Have a drink.
Maybe you'd like to say a word...
Do you know how old
the girl from Camellia was?
You mean the girl
who saved you from the communists?
She was seventeen...
Just seventeen.
About the Literature Museum, sir.
I'll get going now.
You haven't eaten at all.
Are you leaving already?
Where are you going?
This dinner is in your honor...
Is it something urgent?
Perhaps meeting your girlfriend?
Shall I show you something?
Here, sir?
Sir, you got a tattoo?
Still trendy and stylish.
Wow, that's cool.
Wait till I'm dead
if you want to build that literary museum.
But you'll have to wait a long time.
Thank you for coming, sir.
I'll call you soon.
Good bye, sir.
They just cant wait for me to die.
You don't build a museum
about a living person.
I'm leaving.
Why does Seo Jiwoo follow him
around like a dog?
- What do you mean?
- What does he hope to get from him?
Recognition! Just Recognition.
Recognition?
What else does he need?
Grumpa!
There's still 20 minutes left...
You've been waiting for me?
Well...
Have you been to a place like this?
No.
This is a great place to hang out.
It's divided into different themes...
Excuse me.
Who ordered quince tea?
- I did.
- Grumpa did.
Bummer!
Sorry? Is something wrong?
Just saying thanks.
Thanks?
Yes, there's nothing wrong.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome...
Have a good time.
Grumpa!
'Bummer' is an expression we use
When we are surprised or amazed,
startled or astonished.
That's when we use it.
It doesn't mean thank you?
No...
Bodhi!
It's a Buddhist expression
meaning you have been enlightened.
Bodhi!
Why? Have you been enlightened?
This is how a teacher scolds his student
when she tries to test her teacher.
Whatever.
What the hell...
Is he home?
Sir; are you here?
You didn't answer the phone.
I have some news.
We decided to call it
Camellia Memorial Hall.
We took out 'Literary Museum'
from the title.
And they want to display
your handwritten manuscript...
Fine.
The county office people will be thrilled.
Is Mr. Seo Jiwoo here?
Bestselling authors are always busy.
So how well is The Heart selling?
Over 800,000 copies.
Mr. Seo made a tidy sum from the royalties.
800,000 copies.
We printed 30,000 copies more last week,
So it's 830,000 copies to be exact.
Usually popularity and seriousness don't mix.
But fortunately I think Mr. Seo
has managed both.
You know about his latest short story?
A short story?
It's one of his best writings.
The literary circle is buzzing about it.
It's that good?
What's the title?
You should read it.
The title is Eungyo.
Eungyo?
It's the name of a high school girl.
Sir, I'll get going now.
Sir, good to see you.
Where are the literary magazines?
It's over there
at the New Arrivals sections.
They're really popular for some reason.
Yes, right there.
Sir; I'm here.
Would you like a cup of tea?
I'm afraid that
you might have poisoned it.
Do you have anything to say?
I did it because...
It was too beautiful.
What?
You did it because?
The moment I saw your manuscript,
I couldn't let such beauty waste in the chest.
I had to let the world know...
You call that an excuse?
How dare you, a thief, mention beauty!
You are the one
who made me who I am.
What?
You were the one who offered
to ghostwrite The Heart.
You wanted to do it.
You wrote it for fun!
I considered it your salary.
You have no talent
but you kept me company
So I wrote it for you as gift.
Are you regretting it now
that it's become a bestseller?
You want to tell everyone
that you wrote it?
The tension is driving me crazy.
I don't know who I am any more.
Am I Seo Jiwoo or Lee Jeokyo's mask?
What did I ever get, living as your mask?
Money?
You want it back? The royalties?
Shut your mouth!
Why should this one
be any different from The Heart?
- Stop it!
- People won't understand
The relationship between a 70-year-old man
and a high school girl isn't love. Never!
It's a scandal, sir...
A dirty scandal!
You know you won't be able to
publish it under your name.
You know it!
A story about a national poet
having sex with a minor?
Dirty scandal?
- Sir, you are an old man.
- You say it's dirty?
Why won't you admit it?
Son of a bitch.
Never show your face here again.
Your eyes are frightening.
I feel sick listening to your voice.
You are a thief.
You never had any potential.
I never liked that look
in your eyes, like a wolf.
What are you staring at?
I'll gorge your eyes out.
You dare to call it dirty?
You say this is a dirty scandal?
You bastard!
I know you're in there.
I don't know
why you won't let me in.
I can't concentrate on my studying,
and I'm going to mess up my exams...
Why does it hurt so much?
I don't know
why it hurts so much...
I could easily wrap my fingers
around Eungyo's ankle.
Her heel slipped between my fingers
And she giggled.
Her fragrant head rested be/ow my chin
And my lips were already buried
in her hair.
She sighed like a pair of bellows.
I held you close in my arms.
I caressed your hair;
your shoulders, your waist
And I put my ear to your chest
listening to your heart beating.
You were so heartbreakingly beautiful.
Did you read it?
Eungyo reads Eungyo.
Do all writers do this?
Stealing other people's stories,
using names without permission.
I'm sorry.
Did you really write this?
How did you find out his henna?
He told me about that.
He told you?
He told you about it?
You two don't keep secrets
from each other?
What is he to you?
My beloved and respected teacher.
A father figure.
Then you tell him
everything as well?
Yes.
I am so pretty in the story.
Thank you.
Why are you doing this?
You are doing this
because you like me?
I'm lonely, that's why.
Will you tell him about this?
It's about time they called...
They will never pick a genre novelist
or a best-selling author.
Finally!
Winner of annual Literary Award
Eungyo by Seo Jiwoo!
Really?
Really. Eungyo is the winner.
I won the annual Literary Award?
I told you would win.
The judges have gone to dinner.
Wow...
Has Mr. Lee Jeokyo read Eungyo?
Yes.
What did he say?
He told me this.
'It's like you went through my mind...'
It's scary
I thought he couldn't make it?
What's going on?
He's here.
Look.
The 35th Literary Award winner is
Eungyo written by Mr. Sea Jiwool
I am honored to introduce
a special guest today
He is here to give
a congratulatory speech.
I believe this is
his first public appearance.
Mr. Sea Jiwoo has called him
a father-figure
He is known for aesthetic combination of
lyric poetry with realism.
The true poet of his generation!
Mr. Lee Jeokyo.
I, Lee Jeokyo, am an old man.
Roethke referred to getting old...
as wearing the leaden weight of
what I did not do.
Just as your youth is
not a prize for your efforts
My agedness is not
a penalty for my faults
Eungyo is like sweet rain upon a dry land.
It will be hard to
write a story more beautiful,
more truthful, or more replete.
Happy birthday, Grumpa!
I got you a cake and a present.
Grumpa, your windows are so dirty.
Would you like me to clean it
as a birthday present?
Eungyo's here.
You don't seem happy to see me.
Of course
I'm glad to see you.
Grumpa.
Here's salt.
Looks really good.
Look at this, Grumpa!
Looks good.
I've also brought candles.
Let's just light one.
What?
Light just one candle.
Okay.
Our famous writer is here.
Sir...
Happy birthday.
I'll get going now.
He's diabetic.
He can't eat cake.
Mr. Seo!
Come here.
Have a drink before you go.
Try it.
Let's see..
How's my salad, my soup?
It's very good.
It is, isn't it?
Grumpa, do you know
when they started drinking wine?
A 4,000-year-old wine bottle
was found in Georgia.
It's almost as old as human race.
Why do you keep asking him
questions instead of me?
Don't bother him.
You never have good answers.
It's easier when he explains things.
You are too... loose.
A typical engineer!
I don't know
how he became a writer, do you?
What's wrong with majoring in engineering?
Did you write poetry like him?
Like Grumpa?
I wanted to write poetry.
I desperately wanted to.
You started writing novels
because you couldn't write poems?
Then poetry is the highest level?
Poetry is higher.
Did you know that
Me, Seo Jiwoo the genre novelist,
People scorned me
But now they worship me.
Just because I won a prize.
The mighty critics
who never once called me
Now can't get enough of me.
So you are noble, so what?
So you are a national poet, sir,
So what?
The key is to succeed.
No matter what!
I'm no longer a mask.
I'm Seo Jiwoo and...
I'm really going to succeed, sir.
I have a quiz for you.
I want you to be
my student in next life.
Why do you think I do?
That's the quiz?
To make him
do my laundry and cooking.
I'm drunk.
I'll go to bed now.
Eungyo should go home now.
Didn't you say you have
breakfast meeting tomorrow?
Go to bed.
It's not a breakfast meeting...
It's a lecture...
Yes, sir, good night.
I can do without some sleep.
I'm still young.
Sir, thank you very much.
You turned an engineer into a writer
Who didn't know anything about stars.
Thank you, sir.
Happy birthday Grumpa.
Good night.
I should go to bed.
Good night, Eungyo.
Here? This shallow part?
You are ticklish here?
Here, and here...
Don 't...
How much do you care for me?
How much...
Do you know why
teenage girls have sex?
Because you care for me...
You came back
because you care for me.
I'm lonely, too.
That's why.
Who fiddled with the engine?
The handle has no control.
You are lucky to be alive!
Is it because the car is old?
No...
Someone loosened it.
Loosened it?
Yes.
If someone loosened it,
it means he did it on purpose.
If he did,
he meant to kill you.
Who messed with this car?
And it's fairly recent.
Look here, no oil marks.
See how dangerous
an amateur job can be?
People think internet is
all they need to fix a car.
Did you think I'd let
that old man get to me?
I can see inside your head!
I know all about it, old man.
Fuck“.
My beloved, respected teacher
How could he do this to me?
After all I've done...
No son could have been more loyal.
You have one new message.
I...
killed... Sea Jiwoo.
Grumpa,
You are wasted.
My mom...
Her heels are cracking again
like a tree bark...
she's shaving it
with a knife again.
Crouching down.
I was watching her
When it suddenly came back to me.
Remember the night
I came here?
That moment...
That air...
That temperature...
That humidity...
That warmth...
Some things can never be felt
no matter how hard you tell.
Even if you had told someone,
a third person can never describe it.
An engineer...
Who thinks all mirrors are the same...
How could he know...
Eungyo belongs to you...
You wrote Eungyo...
Thank you...
Thank you for making me
so pretty in the story.
I didn't know I was so pretty.
I had no idea.
I didn't know anything
like an idiot.
I was just a big-headed idiot.
I was so stupid.
Good bye, Grumpa.
Good bye
Eungyo...