We said 5:50 pm
The plane is twenty minutes late.
- Hi.
I have to pick up my test
results before 7 p.m.
- Can you call me as soon
as you have them? - Yes, don't worry.
Guess where I found it?
- In the car?
- Yeah. In the glove compartment.
I think that it climbed in, in the garage.
But why didn't it climb into Pawel's car?
He always leaves lots
of filth lying around.
Mice don't like clean places,
do they?
- You killed it?
- What could I do?
Just imagine the mess if
a client found it.
Do something with your hair.
You know, if l spoke
a little better English,
- I would have taken this run, but...
- Don't worry.
See you.
Bye- Bye bye.
Yes?
- It's in the centre. 7 Wilcza Street.
- Thank you.
The presented solution
on the diagram 6
ls based on the basic
generator piston movement
with forced translation vibrations
accompanied by the piston movement
is used to steer the flow...
the section of the
cylindric piston surface
with the sinusoidal
rings marked with the line...
Hello?
- Ania?
- Yes. What did he say?
Don't worry. Everything is OK.
It'll be alright.
Will they operate?
No, he doesn't operate
,-'just got some pills.
I need to take medicine.
That's all?
He said it'll now be easy to cure.
It's better than we thought.
Just medicine? That's all?
He'll explain it to you
better than me.
And we need to talk about
that medicine.
Dad, my client is back,
I need to go. Bye.
What are you doing here?
You were meant to be at the Marriot?
- How do you know?
- Your dad told me.
- Are you going or waiting?
- I've an hour or two.
Can you smell anything in the car?
Yeah, you smell pretty well. Do you want
to go to the bar? It's on me.
I don't have time, I need to study.
What happened?
- What are you up to?
- I'm cleaning the car.
- Straight from the Kitchen.
Have you eaten. - No.
I only have 10 minutes
I'm with the Spaniards today.
They are doing a discotheques tour.
You speak any spanish?
I manage.
Have I told you I know Marco
He is the Chef here.
Sorry I don't have time.
Yeaah...
It needs to be served
in the restaurant for you. Doesn't it ?
I'm not hungry.
You lost my number?
No. I'll call.
So we go to the restaurant, ok?
- And?
- Can you talk?
What do you want to tell me about
the medicine.
Nothing, there are side effects.
- I wouldn't be able to drive.
- For how long?
I'll be taking them till the end
of my life.
I'm so sorry.
Alright, alright.
Good evening...
- Ania?
- Good evening...
- How's your father?
- He's ok. Thank you.
- Have you been here a long time?
- Half an hour or so.
I've got a client. I'm in a hurry.
Have you seen anyone
suspicious down there?
No, I saw a couple of hotel guests.
What? Somebody stole a bath robe?
- Somebody lost a diamond necklace?
- No.
We have a dead man in there.
Ok, you can go.
Send your father my regards.
I will. Bye.
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
But don't worry.
I'll do everything I can to
help you finish your studies.
I thought of employing someone,
you know...
Yes, to make us go bankrupt
in a month!
We need to pay off the car.
Dad, I can't talk right now,
I've got a client on hold. Bye.
Yes, I am his driver.
Yeah right. I can't believe it.
Is it really your job?
Yes. Just a second, he is not
in the car. I'll call him.
There is no point.
Since he likes to leave messages,
then I have one for him,
that's your job, right?
Tell this asshole,
he didn't get it, ok...
Wait, he's coming.
I am not a whore and I don't want
to see his face ever again,
tell him that now he is
to leave me alone...
You're not asleep?
I took my pills. I can't sleep.
Are ok? You were at the Bristol?
- How do you know?
- Modrak called.
- What did he want?
- He asked ff! talked with you?
- Did he tell you exactly what happened?
- He's looking for some guy.
Have you thought it over,
for the job?
Listen dad, I don't know,
I can't give you an answer like this.
I'm taking the exam next week.
I only did it for my studies.
You know what happens if we stop,
even for one day.
You know I hate doing it.
I hate these people.
I don't either. ,-'just love the oars
Just like you.
Dad, listen. If Modrak calls back, could
you ask him more about what happened?
- Why would he call back?
- He will. I have to go. Bye.
Good evening. You're not allowed
to park here.
Alright, I'll pick up my client
and I'm off.
Alright.
- Good night.
Pa we! Wore/ski speaking.
It's me. I am calling you with
a favor. It's about an address.
Ania! Are you lost?
The client is looking for a hotel...
With toilets... made of metal,
does that say anything to you?
- What's going on in those restrooms?
- Please, I'm in a hurry.
Nope, doesn't ring a bell
- Who is that?
- Someone in the street.
Doesn't matter, if anything comes
to mind, call me...
- I'll send you an sms.
- Thanks. 'til next time.
Goodnight.
What an idiot!
What a fucking idiot!
Speak, you idiot!
It's Chlodna street
corner of Elektoralna.
Stop the car.
But we're almost there.
Stop here, now.
Asshole.
I am sorry to disturb you,
my name is Ania.
- I am calling you on behalf of Sacha.
- I don't know any Sacha.
- This is the number he gave me.
- He's still in Po/and?
He's got serious problems.
He needs help.
He means money.
The rest, I don't see how he
will give it back...
I helped him once already.
I'm not interested.
Hello?
I am sorry. But he answered.
He told me you are an excellent driver.
He's rather nice.
- I don't think so.
- You were right. Modrak called back.
He thinks you may help
his investigation.
I don't see how.
They are still looking for the guy.
The client has been beaten to death;
he refused to open the safe.
Go to bed, Dad. I will be late. Bye.
Yes.
Good evening, this is Modrak.
Your father gave me the number.
I am sorry to disturb you.
Sir!
What's going on?
No, nothing.
I need to see you.
It'll only be two minutes.
I am on duty...
Where are you?
We keep on moving.
I don't know where we'll be next.
What district? What's the address?
- Wola. Mlynarska.
- I'm coming.
Yes.
Modrak here. I'm almost there,
where are you?
We just left.
- Where are you?
- On Chiodna.
- Listen, I can't talk.
- I'm losing network.
- You know this place?
- Are your two Spaniards inside?
Yes. They stay exactly one hour
at each place.
- I'm free tomorrow.
- So am I.
- We could go out to dinner?
- No...
- It's on me.
- We'll split it.
Deal.
Do you have a cigarette?
Maybe I'll go and get
a pack of lights.
Excuse me for insisting somewhat,
but it's urgent.
I'm on duty...
I told you :
I came across a colleague.
A security guard walked by.
And a couple. In their fifties.
- Strange.
- Why?
No, nothing, I'm thinking aloud.
You're sure?
I have an impression
I've seen him before.
He's a pickpocket, not a criminal.
Did you find him?
He has no clothes.
The police thinks he's still
in the hotel.
I think he's outside. He left.
- That's one hell of a car.
- It's dad's.
How long do I know you?
A few years now.
Yeah. And by then,
you didn't drive cars...
You stole them.
Yeah. I was young.
I helped you.
- You helped my father.
- That's true.
- And now, I could help you.
- That's good to know. Excuse me...
I can't miss a thing.
The police might get in touch with you
within the next couple of days. Call me.
Thanks.
He called me a while ago, too.
They are looking for some guy.
Homicide.
- Did he show you any photos?
- No.
Fucking asshole...
Calm down, leave him alone.
He's with me. Leave him alone.
What's going on? Who are you?
I'm sorry, it's a misunderstanding.
We're on our way. Sorry.
Idiot.
Do you have anything to say, boy?