Here's some
for 37 cents.
Here's some for 32.
31.
I think that's it.
Don't they have
any generics?
This is their
generic.
I never heard
of that brand.
Get this one.
You're paying
for advertising.
Tuna.
We should get tuna.
Please,
no more tuna, OK?
It's got protein.
We need protein.
Beans have protein.
Beans make you fart.
We got a convertible.
I'm getting it
for myself.
One burrito and one large slush.
$21.67.
Can you fill this up?
21.67.
This next one's
a WSTT special request.
It goes out
to Ernestine..
Jesus.
I forgot
to pay for this.
You could have
gotten caught.
What if somebody saw?
The laws are medieval
down here.
Know what the minimum age
for execution is
in Alabama?
What, 16?
10!
A cop's behind us.
A cop?
There's no problem.
There might be.
There's no problem
until there's a problem.
Just relax, please.
Is he still there?
Yeah.
Goddamn it!
Calm down.
A cop's behind us,
that's all.
There's nothing's wrong.
Uh-oh.
What?
His lights are on.
Fuck!
Fuck. Goddamn it!
What do we do?
It's probably
nothing, OK?
It might be
a taillight.
We don't have
money for bail.
We don't need bail.
Nothing's happened.
We're getting pulled over!
You stole something!
You're finished.
Shut up, all right?
All right, here he comes.
Show me your hands!
Jesus.
Get 'em up!
Get 'em up! Up!
Now put your hands
on your head
and get out of the car!
Out of the car!
Go!
Yeah, yeah, I'm sure..
It's number 3 and 5
Ridiculous!
All this over a can of tuna.
Keep quiet!
All right, bye.
I think we may
get a confession.
I just heard that someone shot
Jimmy Willis.
He's dead.
Oh, my God!
Who would do
such a thing?
Hello, Bill.
I'm Sheriff Farley.
Hi.
Do you know why you're here?
Yeah. Sorry.
It was a stupid thing to do.
Have you been made
aware of your rights?
Yes.
You're willing
to waive that right?
Yes. I'll cooperate fully.
I'll sign a statement
or whatever
makes this easier.
Good.
Good!
That's.. That's good.
Stan had nothing
to do with it.
Did he help you plan it?
No.
I mean, it wasn't planned out.
It just, like, you know,
it just happened.
Did Stan try to stop you?
No.
I mean, he was..
Why? Is that a big deal?
Aidin' and abettin'.
Aiding and abetting?
That's a major thing?
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
An accessory?
Are you guys kidding?
I didn't help.
I didn't plan it.
You didn't try to stop it.
I didn't know
it was happening.
I found out later,
in the car.
Why didn't you
get out..
call the police then?
He's my friend.
Well..
your friend has put you
in a lot of trouble.
What's going
to happen to Bill?
Nothing..
unless he's convicted.
Of course, if he is..
we're going to run
enough electricity through him
to light up Birmingham.
We were friends at NYU.
We both applied and
got scholarships to UCLA.
We figured the weather
and the scenery
would be nicer
in the South.
What about
the tuna fish?
Then I forgot about the tuna,
and then we left.
Did he catch you
with the tuna fish?
Is that how it started?
He didn't say anything.
But he knew about it?
I don't know.
Let's talk about that
for a moment.
You paid for the groceries.
And then what?
We went out to the car,
and that's it.
When did you shoot him?
What?
When did you
shoot the clerk?
I shot the clerk?
Yes. When?
Hey, Dean,
we need you out here.
I'm in the middle of
a damn confession here!
Whoa!
Wait a minute!
What's the matter?
You know what this
is all about?
Yeah. They're fucking with us.
You don't believe them?
They don't execute
for shoplifting.
You think we're being booked
for shoplifting?
You're being booked
for shoplifting.
I'm being booked for accessory
to shoplifting.
No. Stan,
I'm being booked for murder,
and you're being booked
for accessory to murder.
It's time to make
your phone calls.
Goddamn it!
Could you contact
your parents?
How? Call the Chilean consulate?
They'll send a guide
into the mountains looking for them?
We need an attorney,
a great attorney.
Do you know any
great attorneys?
No.
I'm calling my mother.
Hello, Ma?
We're in Wahzoo.
It's in Beechum County,
Alabama, Ma.
Not.. Not too good, Ma.
We, uh..
we've been arrested.
Ma? Ma, please.
First of all,
we didn't do it, all right?
Murder.
Ma.. Ma. Plea.. Ma.
Ma, it's a mistake.
We must look like
the guys who did it.
What we think
is happening is..
Shut up.
We think they're
setting us up.
You know how corrupt it is
down here.
They all know each other.
The Klan's here!
They're inbred!
They sleep
with their sisters.
Some of them do.
Ma, we got to get an attorney.
It's going to cost
a lot of money.
How much would
an attorney cost?
A decent one?
$50,000-$100,000.
50,000-100,000.
I know, Ma. I know!
Can we use any attorney?
I think so.
He thinks so.
Oh, he is?
Well, that's a great idea!
You think
he'll do it?
What?
We got an attorney.
My cousin Vinny!
Yeah
Did he sing this,
or did he sing that?
What is that?
I thought
she was that
But this
sinister collection
Use your own
reflection
The trial.. survival
Get into my telescope
Yeah
How's your business?
Where is he from?
Get into my business
They tried
to tie you down
The ball and chain
They tried
to make a move
So they changed
the game
Every time you're up
They try
to tear you down
I'm tellin'you
right now
The sinister
collection
Infection,
objection..
What?
Nothing.
You stick out like a sore thumb
around here.
Me? What about you?
I fit in better than you.
I'm wearing cowboy boots.
Oh, yeah. You blend.
I bet the Chinese food
here is terrible.
I don't see anything
out of whack.
The wheels went off-balance after
we hit that mud.
That's not it.
Put it on a rack
and take a look.
What's wrong?
What?
What's the problem?
Nothing.
The car was shimmying a little.
You got mud in your tires.
I got mud in my tires?
How do you get mud
into the tires?
That's a figure of speech.
The mud gets
inside the wheel,
throws the balance off.
You ever hear
of mud in the tires?
No.
She never heard of it.
She knows everything
about cars.
Now, see, down here,
everybody gets stuck
in the mud.
Yep, we're famous
for our mud.
You're famous
for your mud?
How's your Chinese food?
You keep asking
about Chinese food.
Can't you tell
they don't have Chinese restaurants
around here?
Everybody will know
you're a tourist.
What are you,
a fucking world traveler?
Stop the death penalty!
Our jail was condemned
this morning.
That's why we're
bringing you
to the State Corrections Facility.
Ha ha ha!
Unlock the gate.
Go on through.
You know what happens
in these places?
Yeah, I know what happens
in these places.
Sometimes
there's a big guy named Bubba
no one wants
to tangle with.
He'll protect you if you
become his sex slave.
There's only
two of us here.
What about those cots?
What if they put somebody
else in here?
Stan..
shut up.
OK.
Hey, hey, hey!
Here.
We got somebody for you.
You must be Stan.
How you doing?
Why'd they bring
you in here?
I just got in.
I asked for the new guys,
and they brought me here.
Hey, he's sleeping.
Cute little guy.
Maybe I'll just
start with you,
let him sleep a little bit.
I don't want to do this.
Hey, I don't blame you.
If I was in your situation,
I'd want to
get through this
as quickly and with as little pain
as possible,
so let's try our best to make it
a simple in-and-out procedure.
What's the matter?
Relax. Relax.
Relax.
Maybe we should spend
a couple of minutes together
to get acquainted
before we, uh..
you know,
before we get to it.
What's wrong with you?
I don't want to do this.
I understand,
but what are your alternatives?
My alternatives?
Yeah.
To what? To you?
I don't know..
suicide, death.
Look, it's either me or them.
You're getting fucked
one way or the other.
Hey, hey, hey.
Lighten up, OK?
Don't worry,
I'm going to help you.
Gee, thanks.
I think a modicum of gratitude
would not be out of line.
You think
I should be grateful?
Yeah. It's your ass, not mine.
I think you should
be grateful.
You should be down
on your fucking knees.
I didn't know
it was such an honor.
I'm doing a favor here.
You're getting me for nothing.
That's one hell of an ego.
What the fuck
is your problem?
I did not come down here
just to get jerked off.
No, no.
I'm not jerking you off.
I'm not doing anything.
That's it.
You're on your own.
I'm just taking care
of sleeping beauty.
Back off!
Vinny! Hey, Vinny!
Vinny?
Vinny Bag-of-Doughnuts!
How are you?
This is Vinny?
I don't know where to start.
Have you had any
murder cases before?
No. This will be my first.
Your first.
Yeah.
Well, what kind of
cases have you had?
Assault and battery,
armed robbery..
you know.
No.
Well, I expect he's done burglary,
grand theft auto,
drugs.. right, Vin?
No.
Nothing like that, either.
What kind of law
do you practice?
Well, up till now,
personal injury.
Well, you're a trial
attorney, right?
I mean, personal injury trials?
This will be my first foray
into the trial process.
I haven't had
to go to court yet..
knock on wood.
You haven't had to go to court yet.
How long have you
been practicing?
Almost six weeks.
Vin, you graduated from law school
six years ago.
What have you
been doing since?
Studying. For the bar.
Six years?
Mm-hmm.
That's a lot of studying.
Well..
to be honest with you,
I, uh..
I didn't pass
my first time out.
That's OK.
You passed the
second time, right?
I'm afraid not.
Three times a charm?
Not for me it isn't.
Nope. For me,
six times was a charm.
Six times.
Ahem.
A little informal, aren't we?
I was just, uh..
Not wearing
a coat or tie.
Oh! Sorry.
Well, approving an attorney
from out-of-state
is a pretty informal matter.
I just have
a few questions.
OK. Fire away, Judge.
Where'd you go
to law school?
Brooklyn Academy of Law.
Is that an accredited
law school?
Uh..
Oh.. yes.
How long have you
been practicing?
Oh, about, uh, six, uh..
almost 16 years.
Any murder cases?
Lots of them.
Quite a few, yes.
What was the outcome?
Uh, you know..
win some, lose some.
This is not the forum
to be cavalier.
Oh, of course.
Now, let me see..
most recently
I had a ax murder,
which I won
on the grounds
of temporary insanity.
Want to hear the facts?
No.
What else?
Let me see, what else?
Heard of Son of Sam?
The fellow who received
orders to kill from a dog?
That one.
You defended him?
Well, no, not exactly.
I defended the first guy
they arrested,
and, uh,
he was found innocent
and set free and, uh,
they caught the real guy.
Well..
we don't have any serial killers
in Beechum County,
but what we do have
is as sophisticated
a system of justice
as the rest
of the country.
Oh, I'm sure.
Being from New York,
you might have the impression
that law is practiced
with a certain degree
of informality down here.
It isn't.
Right.
I tell you this because
I want you to know
that when it comes
to procedure,
I'm not a patient man.
I advise you, sir,
when you come into my courtroom,
you are to know
the letter of the law.
I react harshly
when you don't.
You should.
New Yorkers
don't get special treatment.
They shouldn't.
You won't.
You'll be given
no leeway whatsoever.
I expect you to know this information
in my courtroom.
Oh, right.
You willing
to accept those terms?
Right. No problem.
Just this?
This is going to be great.
Vinny's first case.
So, what can I do to help?
Nothing?
No.
What the fuck is that?
Want to sit at the counter?
Hey.
How you doing?
Listen, uh, what's the story
with this incredibly,
remarkably loud whistle
at 5:30 in the morning?
It's the steam whistle.
Uh-huh.
Over at the sawmill.
Tell folks it's time to get up.
You can hear it for miles.
Y'all want something?
Yeah.
Breakfast?
You think?
Uh, good choice.
Two.
Excuse me.
You guys down here
hear about the ongoing
cholesterol problem
in the country?
What.. What's this over here?
You never heard of grits?
Sure. Sure, I heard of grits.
I just actually never
seen a grit before.
Honey, you going to try it?
You first.
What is a grit, anyways?
It's made out of corn.
Them hominy grits.
Hominy.
Hmm.
How do you cook it?
You simmer it in water
15-20 minutes,
put it on the plate,
and add butter.
So? You going to eat it or not?
Ha ha ha.
Is your attorney here?
I am the attorney.
Oh. Jim Trotter III,
District Attorney,
Beechum County.
Vincent La Guardia
Gambini I, Brooklyn.
Nice to see you.
Yeah.
Vin.
Hey.
All rise for his honor
Judge Chamberlain Haller.
The Court of Beechum County
is now in session.
Be seated.
First case.. The People
of the State of Alabama
vs. William Robert Gambini
and Stanley Marcus Rothenstein.
Stein. She called me Stine.
Just..
Counselor,
your clients are charged
with first-degree murder.
How do they plead?
Your Honor..
Don't talk to me
sitting in that chair.
But he told me to sit here.
When you're addressing
this court,
you will rise
and speak to me in a clear,
intelligible voice.
Ahem. Sorry.
My clients, uh..
What are you wearing?
Huh?
I'm, uh, wearing, uh..
clothes.
I don't get the question.
When you come into my court
looking like you do,
you not only insult me,
but you insult the integrity
of this court.
I apologize, sir,
but this is how I dress.
Next time you come
into my courtroom,
you will look lawyerly.
And I mean you comb your hair
and wear a suit and tie.
And that suit
better be made
out of some kind of cloth.
You understand me?
Uh, yes.
Uh, fine, Judge. Fine.
Good. You may continue.
How do your clients plead?
Uh, my clients
are caught completely by surprise.
They thought they were
getting arrested
for, uh, shoplifting
a can of tuna.
What are you telling me..
that they plead not guilty?
No. I'm just trying to explain.
I don't want to hear
explanations.
Alabama has its procedure,
and that procedure
at this point in time
is to have an arraignment.
Are we clear on this?
Yes, but there seems to be
a lot of confusion here.
Mr. Gambini.
See, my clients, uh..
Uh, Mr. Gambini.
All the way?
All I ask from you
is a very simple answer
to a very simple question.
There are only two ways
to answer it..
Guilty or not guilty.
Well, Your Honor,
my clients didn't do anything.
Once again, the communication process
has broken down.
It appears to me
that you want to skip
the arraignment process,
go directly to trial,
skip that,
and get a dismissal.
Well, I'm not about to revamp
the entire judicial process
just because
you find yourself
in the unique position
of defending clients
who say they didn't do it.
Now, the next words
out of your mouth
will be "guilty"
or "not guilty."
I don't want
to hear commentary,
argument, or opinion.
If I hear anything
other than "guilty" or "not guilty,"
you'll be in contempt.
I don't even want to hear you
clear your throat.
I hope I've been clear.
Now..
how..
do your clients..
plead?
I think..
I get.. the point.
No..
I don't think you do.
You're now
in contempt of court.
Would you like to go
for two counts of contempt?
Not guilty.
Thank you.
Bail will be set
at $200,000.
Preliminary hearing will be set
for 9:30 a.m. Tomorrow morning.
Bailiff, please take
Mr. Gambini into custody.
His bail will be set
at $200.
Come with me, please.
All rise as the judge leaves.
You have to bail me out.
You know that, right?
Let's go.
They're going to nuke
this guy Norton this weekend.
Looks like it.
You got one
huge responsibility
taking on this murder case.
You screw up,
and those boys get fried.
I know.
So you think you know
what you're doing?
Yeah, I think I know
what I'm doing.
'Cause you didn't
look like
you knew what you were doing today
in that courtroom.
Why is that?
Well, it's a lot
of procedure, that's all.
I'll learn it as I go.
Learn as you go?
Yeah, yeah.
Didn't they teach that
in law school?
No, that's not
what they teach you.
They teach you contracts, precedents,
interpretations,
and then the firm that hires you,
they teach you procedures.
Or you could go
to court and watch.
So why don't you
go to court and watch?
Because between
your father's garage
and working nights,
when was I supposed to go?
I thought maybe this summer
I would take off
a couple of months.
But it ain't
no big deal.
Are you sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
I don't know
how you can be so sure
when you don't know
what it is
you're supposed to know.
It's a procedure.
Like rebuilding a carburetor
has a procedure.
When you rebuild
a carburetor,
first you take the carburetor
off the manifold.
Supposing you skip
the first step,
and while you're replacing
one of the jets,
you accidentally drop
the jet.
It goes down the carburetor
and goes into the head.
You're fucked.
You just learned
the hard way
that you got to remove
the carburetor first, right?
That's what happened
to me today.
I learned the hard way.
Actually, it was a good
learning experience for me.
Is there any way
I could help out
in this procedure situation?
Yeah. Keep bailing me out.
There is one problem.
We can't afford
to keep bailing you out.
I already cashed in half
the traveler's checks.
I didn't want
to cash them in,
so I tried hustling
the money,
but I got stiffed.
What do you mean
you got stiffed?
'Cause I'll always
come back to you
if it ain't none
of your business, baby
You'd better
keep it..
Hey. Vincent La Guardia Gambini.
His name's J.T.
J.T.
I believe you and Lisa
played a game of pool
for $200, which she won.
I'm here to collect.
How about if I just kick your ass?
Oh, a counteroffer.
That's what we lawyers..
I'm a lawyer..
we call that
a counteroffer.
This is a tough decision here.
Get my ass kicked
or collect $200.
What do you think?
I could use
a good asskicking,
I'll be very honest
with you.
Hmm.
Nah, I think I'll just
go with the 200.
Over my dead body.
You like to renegotiate
as you go along, huh?
OK, then, here's
my counteroffer.
Do I have to kill you?
What if I just kicked
the shit out of you?
In your dreams.
No, no. In reality,
if I was to kick
the shit out of you,
do I get the money?
If you kick
the shit out of me?
Yeah.
Yeah. Then you get the money.
What happened, rear ended?
No, I fell.
Oh.
OK.
Let's see if we agree
on the terms.
The choice now is
I get my ass kicked..
or option "B"..
I kick your ass
and collect the 200.
I'm going
with option "B"..
kicking your ass
and collecting $200.
Are we going to fight now?
Yeah. First, show me the money.
I have the money.
All right.
Show it to me.
I can get it.
You can get it?
All right. Get it.
Then we'll fight.
Did you fall in your place
or somebody else's?
My place.
Shit.
He blew the arraignment.
It's a simple procedure.
He just had to say "guilty"
or "not guilty."
We could have done that.
So? What are you saying?
What am I saying?
You saw what happened in there.
You want to stay
with him after that?
Shit, I don't want to fire him.
He's family.
And my mother,
the way her health is now..
I appreciate that,
but should you die
for that?
Wouldn't your mother be more upset
if you died?
Given the chance,
he could do a good job.
No, you're wrong.
Knock it off. Let's go.
Stan, listen to me.
You have to see
the Gambinis in action.
These people love to argue.
They live to argue.
My parents argue, too.
That doesn't make them
good lawyers.
Stan, I've seen your parents argue.
Trust me, they're amateurs.
Is that a drip I hear?
Yeah.
Weren't you the last one
to use the bathroom?
So?
Well, did you use the faucet?
Yeah.
Then why didn't you
turn it off?
I did turn it off.
If you turned it off,
why am I listening to it?
Did it occur to you it could
be turned off
and still drip?
No. If you turned it off,
it wouldn't drip.
Maybe it's broken.
Is that what you're saying?
Yeah, that's it.
It's broken.
You sure?
I'm positive.
Maybe you didn't
twist it hard enough.
I twisted it just right.
How could you be so sure?
If you will look
in the manual,
you will see
that this particular model faucet
requires a range
of 10 to 16 foot-pounds of torque.
I routinely twist
maximum allowable torqueage.
How could you be sure
you used 16 foot-pounds
of torque?
Because I used a Craftsman
model 10-19,
laboratory edition,
signature series
torque wrench,
the kind used by Cal Tech
high-energy physicists
and NASA engineers.
Well, in that case,
how could you be sure that's accurate?
Because a split second
before the torque wrench
was applied
to the faucet handle,
it had been calibrated
by top members
of the State
and Federal Department
of Weights
and Measures
to be dead-on balls
accurate.
Here's a certificate
of validation.
Dead-on balls accurate?
It's an industry term.
I guess the fucking thing
is broken.
We got to move.
Then I heard two loud bangs
like firecrackers.
I looked up and saw
two young men
run out
from the Sac-O-Suds
and jump into a green car
with a white
convertible top
and drive off
like the dickens.
Mrs. Riley,
are those two young men present
in the courtroom today?
Yes, sir. They are.
Could you point them out
for me, please, ma'am?
They're sitting
right there.
Uh-huh. Now, uh..
Mrs. Riley,
is this the car?
Yes, sir. It is.
Thank you, ma'am.
Oh. Let the record show
Mrs. Constance Riley
identified
the defendants' car.
I was making my breakfast.
I saw them two boys
go into the store.
Then later, I heard a gunshot.
Looked out the window.
They was running out,
got into the car,
and drove off.
Is this the car?
Yes.
It is.
Thank you, sir.
You saw those two boys
run out of the Sac-O-Suds
and take off in this car?
Yeah, they peeled away.
Car was all over the road.
I asked him if he did it,
and he said,
"I shot the clerk."
I asked him again,
and again he said,
"I shot the clerk."
Your Honor,
no further questions.
Mr. Gambini.
Yes?
Do you have anything
to add?
Thing? What thing?
Not for me to say.
Uh, no, sir.
You can stand down.
Do you have
any other witnesses?
No.
The court finds
sufficient evidence exists
for this matter
to go to trial.
I'm setting this matter for trial
this Monday, February 2nd,
10 a.m.
Mr. Gambini?
Stand up.
Didn't I say the next time
you appear in my courtroom
that you dress appropriately?
You were serious about that?
Why didn't you ask them
any questions?
Questions?
Ask who questions?
You knew you could ask questions,
didn't you, Vin?
Maybe if you'd put up
some kind of a fight,
you could have gotten
the case thrown out.
Hey, Stan, you're
in Ala-fucking-bama.
You come from New York.
You killed
a good old boy.
There is no way
this is not going to trial.
What the fuck
is going on here, Vinny?
You fucking up
this case or what?
It's just procedure.
I'm bound to fuck up a little.
A little?
You're thrown in jail.. twice.
Hey. I know I was in jail.
I don't need you
to point it out to me.
You're my fiancée.
You're supposed
to stand by your man,
Encourage me a little bit.
Is that what you want?
Yeah.
Oh, I'm sorry.
You were wonderful in there.
The way you handled that judge,
Oh, you're a smooth talker.
You are, you are.
All right, knock it off.
You think I like
fucking up, is that it?
You ragging on me
is not going to give me
any great spontaneous knowledge.
Yeah?
Shut it!
Fuck.
You done reading?
Yeah.
You want to go to bed?
I don't know.
I don't feel good.
You shouldn't feel good.
You haven't slept much in three days.
That's part of it.
You know what it is?
I'm, uh, I'm really scared.
You should be.
How the fuck
did I get into this shit?
"Oh, sure, no problem.
I could win the case."
I already got myself
sent to jail twice.
I could win this thing, though.
I know I could
if I could keep my ass awake
and out of jail long enough.
You know what I think? Honestly?
I think that
once you're out there
and you're doing
your thing out there,
I think you're going
to be really great.
Really great.
If..
you don't fuck up.
If this was a conspiracy,
they'd have to get
all those people to lie.
You think that's
what's happening?
I think we should meet
with the public defender,
see what he's like.
If he's honest..
then we should go with him.
All right.
That's death row in there.
It is?
The chair ain't working
like it used to.
The guy we fried last week..
took us three attempts,
and his head caught fire.
There's no money
to get it looked at.
It'd be cheaper
to get it fixed
than keep running up
them extra electric bills.
Hi, Stanley.
My name is John Gibbons,
and I'm, um, an attorney
in the public defender's office.
Hi.
Hey.
Now, evidence against you
is pretty strong,
so, um..
why don't you tell me
your side of the story?
Hey, Vin.
Hey. Billy.
How are you?
How do you feel, OK?
Hanging in.
Where's Stan?
Uh, Stan, he's..
he's not coming.
Stan..
he's, um..
well, he wants to go
with the public defender.
Listen, Vin..
I'm going with
the public defender, too.
I'm sorry, all right?
I'm sorry.
I didn't know what little experience
you had with this.
What, are you scared?
Yeah, I'm scared.
Maybe I could have
handled the preliminary better.
I admit it.
But what's most important
is winning the case.
I could do it.
I really could.
Let me tell you how, OK?
The D.A.'s got
to build a case.
Building a case is like
building a house..
each piece of evidence
is just another building block.
He wants to make
a brick bunker.
He wants to use serious,
solid-looking bricks,
like these. Right?
Right.
Let me show you something.
He's going to show you
the bricks.
He'll show you
they got straight sides.
He'll show you how they
got the right shape.
He'll show them to you
in a very special way,
so they appear to have everything
a brick should have.
There's one thing
he won't show you.
When you look at bricks
at the right angle,
they're this thin.
His whole case
is an illusion,
a magic trick.
It has to be an illusion
'cause you're innocent.
Nobody..
I mean nobody..
pulls the wool over the eyes
of a Gambini,
especially this one.
Give me the chance.
One chance.
Let me question
the first witness.
If after that point,
you don't think
I'm the best man for the job,
fire me then and there.
I'll leave quietly,
no grudges.
All I ask is
for that one chance.
I think you should
give it to me.
He thinks you should
give it to him?
What was he before,
a fucking comedian?
If he doesn't ask
the right questions,
your lawyer will, right?
No. He'll fuck things up.
There's more
to cross-examination
than knowing what to say.
It's knowing
what not to say.
Let's say he asks
all the possible questions
and the witness
has all the answers.
He ends up proving
the prosecution's case.
How did he ever
talk you into it?
At my cousin Ruthie's wedding,
the groom's brother
was that guy Alakazam.
You know
who I'm talking about?
The magician
with the ponytail?
Right.
Well, he did his act,
and every time
something disappeared,
Vinny jumped on him.
It was like,
"It's in his pocket!"
Or "He's palming it,"
you know?
"There's a mirror
under the table."
He was like,
"Wait a second."
It's joined in the middle,
and there's a spring around it.
"It pops it open
inside the tube."
It was like Alakazam's
worst nightmare.
Vinny was just being Vinny.
He was just being
the quintessential Gambini.
There goes
the quintessential Norton.
Lookie here, J.T.
Hey-hey,
little Yankee boy.
Look here what I got.
What is it?
$200.
Bring it here.
Let me see it.
Hmm.
How do I know
that's not a bunch of 1 s
with a 20
wrapped around it?
It's 200 bucks.
Fan it out.
Show it to me.
Yeah. Right.
Does that freight train
come through
at 5 a.m.
Every morning?
No, sir.
It's very unusual.
OK.
I made a lot of money
winning most of my cases.
Thank you, Shirley.
My clients
were guilty as hell.
Finally, after getting
this one fella
off some very serious
charges for the fourth time,
my conscience got to me.
Wouldn't I be better off
serving justice
by putting the guilty
in jail?
That's what I'm doing,
and I'm a happier man for it.
How about you?
Well, I got a bullshit
traffic ticket.
I went to court.
I got the cop on the stand
and argued until
he admitted he was wrong.
And, uh.. the judge,
this, uh, Judge Malloy,
all the while,
he's laughing and smiling,
then afterwards he asks me
to go to lunch with him.
Then he says to me,
"you'd be a good litigator."
I didn't know
what he was talking about.
I don't know
what a litigator is.
I never thought
of becoming a lawyer,
but this Judge Malloy,
who's from Brooklyn, too..
I mean, he did it,
so all of a sudden,
it seemed possible.
So I went to law school.
Then from time to time,
he would come by,
see how I was doing,
if I needed anything.
He was a nice man.
To go out of his way
like that for me, you know?
He wanted his son
to follow in his footsteps,
but he became
a musician or something.
I remember,
when I graduated,
he was so proud of me.
That's quite a story.
Yeah.
So, we got some case
ahead of us here.
Oh, yeah.
How do you feel about it?
Oh, well, I..
I'd like to have
the murder weapon.
Other than that,
I feel pretty good.
You do?
Oh, yeah.
Hmm.
What are you doing
this afternoon?
You're going hunting?
That's right.
Why are you
going hunting?
Shouldn't you be out
preparing for court?
I was thinking
last night..
if only I knew
what he knows, you know?
If he'd let me
look at his files.
Oh, boy.
I don't get it.
What does
getting his files
have anything
to do with hunting?
You know, two guys out in the woods,
guns, on the hunt.
It's a bonding thing,
you know?
Show him I'm one of the boys.
He won't let me
look at his files,
but maybe he'll relax enough
to drop his guard
so I can finesse
information from him.
What am I going to wear?
What are you
going to hunt?
I don't know.
He's got a lot of stuffed heads
in his office.
Heads?
What kind of heads?
He's got a boar, a bear,
a couple of deer.
Whoa. You're going to shoot a deer?
I don't know. I suppose.
I'm a man's man.
I could go deer hunting.
A sweet, innocent,
harmless, leaf-eating,
doe-eyed little deer.
I'm not going
to go out there
to wimp out, you know?
The guy will lose
respect for me.
Would you rather have that?
What about these pants I got on?
You think they're OK?
Oh!
Imagine you're a deer.
You're prancing along,
you get thirsty,
you spot a little brook,
you put your little deer lips
down to the cool,
clear water..
Bam!
A fucking bullet
rips off your head!
Your brains
are laying on the ground
in little bloody pieces!
Would you give a fuck
what pants
the son of a bitch who shot you
was wearing?
I'd sure like
to look at your files.
You would?
Sure.
You got a Xerox machine
over there?
Uh, no.
Oh. That's OK.
I'll have
my secretary do it.
Shirley,
can you xerox
all the files
on the Gambini/Rothenstein case
for Mr. Gambini?
Yeah.
Thank you, sweetheart.
What's all that?
Trotter's files,
all of them.
You stole his files?
I didn't steal
his files.
Listen to this.
I'm just ready
to finesse him.
I got him going.
He offers to have
his secretary
copy everything
for me.
That's very impressive
finessing.
That's not all.
He's letting us use
his hunting cabin
when he gets back.
It's in the woods,
it's quiet.
He sleeps
like a baby there.
Terrific.
You're a hell of a bonder.
What's this?
You, uh,
reading this book?
Yeah.
Do me a favor, OK?
Don't read this book.
OK?
Thank you very much.
All right.
Don't you know why Trotter
gave you his files?
I told you why
already.
He has to.
By law, you're entitled.
It's called disclosure,
you dickhead.
He has to show you
everything,
otherwise it could be
a mistrial.
He has to give you
a list of witnesses.
You can talk to them.
He's not allowed
any surprises!
They didn't teach you that
in law school?
Now let me
ask you this..
how many different levels
of thickness
have you gone through?
What did you
have for breakfast?
Well..
What's that brown.. stuff?
Huh?
Yesterday you told me
that freight train hardly ever
comes through here
at 5 A.M. In the morning.
She's supposed to come through
at 10 after 4.
Can you participate
in an endeavor
in which
the ultimate decision
might be death
by electrocution?
Ma'am?
I think it should be
up to the victims' families
rather than the courts.
Uh-huh.
Uh, the defendants
in this case
are charged with robbing
a convenience store,
and then in a most
cowardly fashion,
shooting the clerk
in the back.
Now, if sufficient
evidence is offered
to prove these facts,
you think you could,
uh..
Fry 'em.
She'll do.
Hmm.
Mr. Gambini.
Come in, come in.
I just got a fax
from the New York State Office
of Judicial Records.
They have no records
of any Vincent Gambini
ever trying any case
in the entire state
of New York.
Uh..
you're not going
to find any records
of Vincent
La Guardia Gambini
practicing in any courts.
I just told you that.
You don't understand.
See, 20 years ago,
I became an actor.
There was this prominent
stage actor in New York.
His name
was Vincent Gambini.
Maybe you heard of him.
No.
Doesn't matter.
Anyway, I had to change my name,
which I did, legally.
So now I practice law
under my legally changed
stage name.
What name is that?
Jerry Gallo.
You can still
call me Gambini.
I'm sorry.
What name
did you tell him?
Jerry Gallo.
Jerry Gallo?
The big attorney?
Yeah.
Think that was
a smart move?
Yeah, well, the man's a seriously
accomplished lawyer.
He checks up on him,
his name will
show up all over.
His name
was in the papers.
Yeah. I saw that.
You didn't read
the articles?
No.
Too bad.
Why's that?
'Cause he's dead.
What's the matter
with you?
I don't know.
You're acting like you're nervous
or something.
Well, yeah, I am.
Why? I'm the one
under the gun.
The trial starts tomorrow.
Want to know
why I'm nervous?
I'll tell you why.
I'm in the dark
with this legal crap.
I don't know
what's going on.
All's I know is
you're screwing up,
and I can't help.
You lent me
your little camera.
I'm watching you
go down in flames,
you're bringing me
with you,
and I can't do
anything about it.
And?
I hate to bring it up.
I know you got
enough pressure already,
but we agreed
to get married
when you won
your first case.
Meanwhile, 10 years later,
my niece, my sister's daughter,
is getting married.
My biological clock
is ticking like this,
and the way
this case is going,
I ain't never
getting married!
Lisa,
I don't need this.
I swear to God
I do not need this now.
I got a judge
that's just aching
to throw me in jail,
an idiot who wants
to fight me for $200,
slaughtered pigs,
giant, loud whistles.
I ain't slept
in five days.
I got no money,
a dress code problem,
and a little murder case,
which in the balance holds
the lives of two innocent kids,
not to mention your..
biological clock.
My career, your life,
our marriage!
And let me see!
What else
could we pile on?
Is there any more shit
we could pile on to the outcome
of this case?
Is it possible?
Maybe it was a bad time
to bring it up.
What the fuck is that?
This is very romantic.
Out here
in this field..
under the stars..
quiet..
no one around for miles.
It's very romantic.
I don't see no stars.
Oh. Oh.
Oh. Honey,
move way back. Way..
I got to get up.
Let me..
This fucking jacket!
Hang on.
Fuck.
Ho.
You OK?
What was in that pink
plastic thing?
It's your suit.
What is my suit
doing in the trunk?
I had it cleaned.
I thought
it would be nice,
go in there
with a nice clean suit.
I have 30 fucking minutes
to shower,
get a new suit,
and get to the fucking
courthouse.
You shower.
I'll get you a suit.
Hey-hey,
little Yankee wuss!
Lookie here. Ha ha ha!
I got your $200.
You going to kick
the shit out of me now?
Here he comes.
Mr. Gambini,
are you mocking me
with that outfit?
Mocking you? No.
I'm not mocking you, Judge.
Then explain that.. outfit.
I bought a suit.
You've seen it.
Now it's covered in mud.
This town doesn't have
a one-hour cleaners,
so I had to buy
a new suit.
The only store
you could buy a suit in
has got the flu.
Get that?
The whole store got the flu.
I had to get this
in a secondhand store.
So it's either
wear the leather jacket,
which I know you hate,
or this.
So I wore this..
ridiculous thing
for you.
Are you on drugs?
Drugs? No.
I don't take drugs.
I don't like
your attitude.
What else is new?
I'm holding you
in contempt of court.
Oh, there's
a fucking surprise.
What did you say?
What?
What did you just say?
What did I say?
What?
Uh, Your Honor..
counsel,
members of the jury.
The evidence in this case
is going to show
that at 9:30 in the morning
of January 4th,
both defendants, Stanley Rothenstein
and William Gambini,
were seen getting out
of their metallic green
1964 Buick Skylark
convertible..
with a white top.
The evidence
is going to show
that they were
seen entering
the Sac-O-Suds convenience store
in Wahzoo City.
The evidence
is going to show
that minutes after they
entered the Sac-O-Suds,
a gunshot was heard
by three eyewitnesses.
You will then hear the testimony
of the three eyewitnesses
who saw the defendants
running out of the Sac-O-Suds
a moment after the shots
were heard,
getting into their faded
metallic green
1964 Buick Skylark,
and driving off
in great haste.
Finally, the state
is going to prove
that the defendants
Gambini and Rothenstein
admitted, then recanted
their testimony,
to the sheriff
of Beechum County.
Now let's get down
to the lick log.
Your verdict is going
to depend on what you think
of the sworn testimony.
Not what I think.
What I think don't count.
You're the jury.
It's your job to decide
who's telling the truth.
Truth.. that's
what verdict means.
It's a word comes down
from old England
and all our
little old ancestors.
Now, we're going to be
asking you to return a verdict
of murder
in the first degree
for William Gambini
and a verdict
of accessory to murder
in the first degree
for Stanley Rothenstein
for helping Gambini
commit this heinous crime.
Counselor,
you wish to make
an opening statement?
Counselor!
What?
It's time to make
your opening statement.
Come on, Vin.
Uh..
everything that guy
just said is bullshit.
Thank you.
Objection, Your Honor.
Counsel's entire
opening statement is argument.
Objection sustained.
The entire opening statement
with the exception of "thank you"
will be stricken
from the record.
The jury will
please disregard
counsel's entire
opening statement.
And you, Mr. Gambini,
you'll not use that kind of language
in my court. You understand?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Putz.
Counselor.
Your statement, sir.
Well, now..
Uh, ladies and gentlemen
of the j-j-j..
of.. of.. of the j-j-j..
Ahem!
Jury! Um..
on.. on..
on..
January f..
4th of this year,
my client did indeed,
uh, visit the Sac-O-Suds
co.. um..
con.. um..
um.. uh..
uh.. c..
convenience store.
But.. But!
He didn't, uh..
Kill anyone.
He.. He, uh.. um..
uh..
ahh!
We.. We intend to prove
that the p..
p-p-p-p..
prosecution's case is
circumstantial and.. and.. and..
ohh..
uh..
coincidental.
Thank you.
That's it?
What about everything
we talked about?
I get a little nervous.
A little nervous?
I'm getting better.
I heard a gunshot,
so I looked out
the window,
and I seen them
two boys run out,
get into their car,
and drive off like maniacs.
The tires screeching, smoking,
going off on the curb.
Is this the car?
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
Your witness.
All right.
Mr., uh..
T-T-T-T-T..
uh..
uh, Tipton.
Now, when you viewed
my client,
how.. how.. how
far away were you?
About 50 feet.
Do you think
that's close enough
to make an accurate,
uh, I..
I-I..
identification?
Yes.
Mr. Tipton, I see
you wear eyeglasses.
Sometimes.
Would you care to show those
eyeglasses to the jury?
Thank you. Now,
Mr. Tipton, were you
wearing them that day?
No.
Ha! You see,
you were 50 feet away.
You made a positive eyewitness
identification
and.. and.. and..
yet.. you were not
wearing your necessary
prescription eyeglasses.
They're reading glasses.
Uh..
well..
um.. Mr., uh.. uh..
uh..
could you tell the court
what color eyes
the de-defendants have?
Brown.
Hazel green.
No more questions.
Mr. Gambini,
your witness.
Ahh! He's a tough one.
Yes.
Mr. Tipton,
when you viewed the defendants
walking from their car into
the Sac-O-Suds,
what angle was
your point of view?
They was kind of
walking toward me
when they
entered the store.
And when they left,
what was your point of view?
They was kind of
walking away from me.
So you got a better shot
of them going in
and not so much
coming out?
You could say that.
I did say that.
Would you say that?
Yeah.
Is it possible
the two youts..
Uh, two what?
What was that word?
Uh, what word?
Two what?
What?
Did you say youts?
Yeah, two youts.
What is a yout?
Oh, excuse me,
Your Honor.
Two youths.
Is it possible
the two defendants
entered the store, picked 22 specific
items off the shelves,
had the clerk
take money, make change,
then leave?
Then two different men
drive up in a similar..
Don't shake your head.
I'm not done yet.
Wait till you hear
the whole thing.
Two different men drive up in
a similar-looking car,
go in, shoot the clerk,
rob him, and then leave?
No. They didn't
have enough time.
How much time
was they in the store?
Five minutes.
Are you sure?
Did you look at your watch?
Oh, I'm sorry.
You testified earlier
that the boys went
into the store,
you'd just begun
to make breakfast,
you were ready to eat,
and you heard a gunshot.
So, obviously, it takes you
five minutes to make breakfast.
That's right.
Do you remember
what you had?
Eggs and grits.
I like grits, too.
How do you cook yours?
Regular, creamy,
or al dente?
Just regular, I guess.
Regular.
Instant grits?
No self-respecting
Southerner uses instant grits.
I take pride in my grits.
So, Mr. Tipton,
how could it take you
five minutes
to cook your grits
when it takes the entire
grit-eating world
20 minutes?
I don't know.
I'm a fast cook, I guess.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't hear you.
Did you say you're a fast cook?
That's it?
Are we to believe
that boiling water soaks into a grit
faster in your kitchen
than anyplace
on the face of the earth?
I don't know.
Well, perhaps the laws of physics
cease to exist on your stove.
Were these magic grits?
Did you buy them
from the same guy
who sold Jack
his beanstalk beans?
Objection!
Objection sustained.
Ignore the question.
Are you sure about
that five minutes?
I don't know.
You've made your point.
Are you sure about
that five minutes?
I may have been mistaken.
I got no more use
for this guy.
You're fired.
I want him.
Come on, now.
Move it.
Don't worry. I'll find a way
to bail you out.
Don't. I'll stay in prison tonight.
Maybe I'll finally
get some sleep.
Hey. How you doing?
Hey, Mr. Crane,
what are these pictures of?
My house and stuff.
House and stuff.
And what is this
brown stuff on the windows?
Dirt.
What is this rusty,
dusty, dirty-looking
thing over your window?
It's a screen.
A screen!
And what are these
really big things
right in the middle
of your view
from the window of your kitchen
to the Sac-O-Suds?
What do we call
these big things?
Trees?
Trees, that's right.
You shout them right out
when you know.
Now, what are these
thousands of little things
that are on trees?
Leaves.
Leaves!
And these bushy things
between the trees?
Bushes.
Bushes. Right.
So, Mr. Crane,
you could positively
identify the defendants
for a moment
of two seconds
looking through
this dirty window,
this crud-covered screen..
these trees..
with all these leaves
on them..
and I don't know
how many bushes.
There's, like, five.
Uh-uh. Don't forget
this one and this one.
Seven bushes.
Seven bushes. So..
what do you think?
Is it possible you just saw two guys
in a green convertible
and not necessarily
these two particular guys?
I suppose.
I'm finished
with this guy.
Mrs. Riley,
when you saw the defendants,
were you wearing
your glasses?
Yes, I was.
Over here, dear.
Would you mind putting
your glasses on
for us, please?
Whoa!
How long you been
wearing glasses?
Since I was 6.
Have they always
been that thick?
Oh, no. They got
thicker over the years.
So, as your eyes have gotten
more and more out of whack
as you've gotten older,
how many levels of thickness
have you gone through?
Oh, I don't know.
Over 60 years..
maybe 10 times.
Maybe you're ready
for a thicker set.
Oh, no.
No, I think they're OK.
Maybe we should
make sure.
Let's check it out.
Now, how far were
the defendants from you
when you saw them
entering the Sac-O-Suds?
About.. 100 feet.
100 feet.
Would you hold this, please?
Thank you.
Sorry.
Excuse me.
OK.
This is 50 feet.
That's half the distance.
How many fingers
am I holding up?
Let the record show
that counsel's holding up
two fingers.
Your Honor,
please, huh?
Oh.
Sorry.
Now.. Mrs. Riley,
and only Mrs. Riley..
how many fingers
am I holding up now?
Four.
What do you think
now, dear?
I'm thinking of getting
thicker glasses.
Thank you.
Hello.
You did good
today, Yankee.
I like the competition.
You like competition, too?
Makes things kind
of fun, doesn't it?
I'm enjoying myself
so far.
Well, I got a little surprise
for you tomorrow.
What? You know you have to disclose
all your evidence.
I just got it
myself tonight.
I'll disclose it
first thing tomorrow.
Judge's going to have
to admit it.
Should I be worried?
I sure would be
if I were you.
Honey, where did you read
about all that disclosure shit?
Let me show you.
Why?
I'm a special automotive instructor
of forensic studies
for the Federal Bureau
of Investigation.
How long you been
in that position?
18 years.
Your Honor,
may we approach the bench?
If you wish.
Ahem. I object to this witness
being called
at this time.
We've been given no
prior notice he'd testify,
no discovery
of tests conducted,
or reports
he's prepared.
As the court is aware,
the defense is entitled
to advance notice
of any witness,
particularly those who will
give scientific evidence,
so we can prepare
for cross-examination
as well as have the report
reviewed by a defense expert
who might then be able
to contradict the veracity
of his conclusions.
Mr. Gambini,
that is a lucid, intelligent,
well-thought out objection.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Overruled.
Now..
Mr. Wilbur.
These are photos
of tires belonging
to the defendants' car.
And these are photos
of the tire marks
left by the assailants' car
as it fled the convenience store.
Are you familiar
with these?
Yes, I am.
Could you elaborate,
please, sir?
We compared the tire marks
outside the convenience store
with the rear tires
of the defendants' car.
They're the same model
and size tire.
Michelin model XGV,
size 75-R, 14-inch wheel.
They're the same size
and model tire.
Anything else, sir?
Yes, indeed.
The car, leaving
the convenience store,
spun its rear tires
dramatically
and left a residue of rubber
on the asphalt.
I analyzed a sample
of that rubber.
I also took a sample
of rubber from the rear tires
from the defendants' Buick
and analyzed that, too.
What equipment did you
use to find this out?
A Hewlett-Packard 5710A
dual column gas chromatograph
with flame analyzation
detectors.
Uh-huh.
Is that thing
turbo-charged?
Only on the floor models.
Now, Mr. Wilbur,
what was the result
of your analysis?
The chemical composition
between the two samples
was found to be identical.
I.. dentical!
No further questions,
Your Honor.
Thank you, Mr. Wilbur.
The court will take
a 60-minute recess for lunch.
I respectfully request
a full day's continuance
to go over all
this sh.. stuff.
Request denied.
Thanks a lot.
Mr. Gambini.
Yes, sir.
I'd like to speak
to you in my chambers.
You're a dead man.
I'm a dead man?
That's right.
I just faxed new york
and asked them what they knew
about Jerry Gallo.
You know what
they replied?
Did you say Jerry Gallo?
I did.
Gallo with a "G"?
Jerry Gallo's dead.
I'm aware of that.
Well, I'm not Jerry Gallo.
I'm Jerry Callo!
C-A-L-L-O.
All right.
Let's get this
cleared up right now.
Hello. This is Judge
Chamberlain Haller.
Can I speak to the clerk?
OK, I'll be here.
He's going to call back
after 3:00.
That gives you
a stay of execution..
Unless by some miracle
you happen to win this case
in the next 90 minutes.
Why don't you go to lunch?
Thanks.
I got my pictures back.
Oh, good.
What did the judge say?
He said he found out
that Gallo's dead.
He found out.
What'd he say?
Lisa, I'm trying to think
about the case now, OK?
I'm sorry.
Can I help?
"Can I help?"
No, you can't help.
I wish you could,
but you can't.
Look how
you're looking at me.
What's that look
supposed to mean?
I'm a piece of shit
'Cause I can't figure out
how you can help?
OK. You're helping.
We'll use your pictures.
Ah!
These are.. I'm sorry.
These are going to help.
I should have looked
at these before.
This is our first
hotel room.
That'll intimidate Trotter.
One of me from behind.
And I didn't think
I could feel worse
than I did a couple of seconds ago.
Thank you.
Good one of
the tire marks.
Could we get
any farther away?
You shoot this
from up in a tree?
What's this?
It's dog shit.
Dog shit! That's great!
Dog shit. What a clue!
Why didn't I
think of that?
One of me reading.
Terrific.
I should've asked you
sooner for these pictures.
Holy shit!
You got it, honey.
You did it!
The case-cracker!
Me in the shower!
Ha ha! I love this.
That's it!
That is it!
I'm out of here.
Lisa!
I'm sorry.
Fuck.
I know I'm missing something.
I'm missing something.
Did you find anything?
Very, very little.
Something?
Nothing.
Is it possible
that two separate cars
could be driving on Michelin model
XGV 75-R-14s?
Of course.
Let me ask you this.
What's the best-selling
single model tire
being sold in the
United States today?
The Michelin XGV.
And what's
the most popular size?
75-R-14.
The same size as on
the defendants' car?
But two faded green 1964 Buick Skylark
convertibles?
Excuse me.
What I'm asking you
is if
the most popular size
of the most popular tire
is on
the defendants' car.
Well..
yeah.
Yes.
Um..
thank you.
No further questions.
Uh, the witness
can stand down.
Counsel?
Uh, Your Honor,
the prosecution rests.
Mr. Gambini..
your first witness.
Mr. Gambini?
I will ask you
one more time
and one more time only.
If I ask you again..
Your Honor, uh..
please, uh, can I have
a five-minute recess?
My next witness is not
in the courtroom now.
Three minutes.
No more.
Sheriff, do me a favor.
Please trace this.
It's not my job.
You do your own
investigating.
I only have
three minutes.
Lisa, listen.
Please, I'm sorry, OK?
I need you to come back
into the courtroom,
and I need the phone.
Come on now. Stop it.
I need the phone.
Let's make up.
We got to go
back inside.
Everybody's
waiting for us.
Shut up.
Give me this phone.
Fuck you!
What is it with you
with that mouth?
Mr. Gambini?
Yeah. How are you?
Tell me why.
Lisa, I need your help.
I don't give a shit.
Leave me alone.
Come on. I found it.
You'll see.
Aah!
Your Honor,
the defense calls
as its first witness
Ms. Mona Lisa Vito.
I object, Your Honor.
This person is not
on the witness list.
This witness is
a expert on automobiles
and is being called
to rebut the testimony
of George Wilbur.
Your Honor, would you please
instruct the bailiff
to escort Ms. Vito
to the witness stand?
Hold up
your right hand.
Do you swear
to tell the truth,
the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth,
so help you God?
Yeah.
Ms. Vito..
uh, you're supposed
to be some kind of expert
in automobiles,
is that correct?
Is that correct?
Would you please answer
the counselor's
question?
No. I hate him.
May I have permission
to treat Ms. Vito
as a hostile witness?
You think
I'm hostile now,
wait till tonight.
Uh, do you two
know each other?
Yeah, she's my fiancée.
Well, that would certainly
explain the hostility.
Your Honor,
I object to this witness.
Improper foundation.
I'm not aware
of her qualifications.
I'd like to, uh,
voir dire this witness
as to the extent
of her expertise.
Granted.
Mr. Trotter,
you may proceed.
Mm-hmm.
Oh.
Ms. Vito, what's
your current profession?
I'm an out-of-work
hairdresser.
"Out-of-work hairdresser."
Now, in what way
does that qualify you
as an expert
in automobiles?
It doesn't.
In what way
are you qualified?
Well, my father was a mechanic.
His father
was a mechanic.
My mother's father
My three brothers
are mechanics.
Four uncles on my father's side
Ms. Vito, your family's
obviously qualified,
but, uh, have you ever
worked as a mechanic?
Yeah, in my father's
garage. Yeah.
As a mechanic?
What did you do
in your father's garage?
Tune-ups, oil changes,
brake relining,
engine rebuilds,
rebuilt some trannies,
rear ends.
OK, OK, but does
being an ex-mechanic
necessarily qualify you
as being expert on tire marks?
No.
Thank you. Goodbye.
Sit down and stay there
until you're told to leave.
Your Honor,
Ms. Vito's expertise
is in general
automotive knowledge.
It is in this area
that her testimony will be applicable.
If Mr. Trotter wishes
to voir dire the witness
as to the extent of her
expertise in this area,
I'm sure he's going to
be more than satisfied.
OK.
All right.
Now, uh, Ms.. Vito?
Being an expert on general
automotive knowledge..
can you tell me
what would the correct
ignition timing be
on a 1955
Bel Air Chevrolet
with a 327-cubic inch engine
and a four-barrel carburetor?
That's a bullshit question.
Does that mean that you
can't answer it?
It's a bullshit question.
It's impossible to answer.
Impossible because you
don't know the answer!
Nobody could answer that.
Your Honor,
I move to disqualify Ms. Vito
as an expert witness.
Can you answer
the question?
No. It is a trick question.
Why is it a trick question?
Watch this.
Chevy didn't make
a 327 in '55.
The 327 came out in '62.
It wasn't offered
in the Bel Air
with the four-barrel carb
till '64.
However, in 1964,
the correct ignition timing
would be 4 degrees
before top dead center.
Well..
uh..
she's acceptable,
Your Honor.
Your Honor, this is a picture
taken by my fiancée
outside the Sac-O-Suds.
Do we agree on this?
Yeah.
Thank you.
I'd like to submit
this picture
of the tire tracks
as evidence.
Mr. Trotter?
No objection,
Your Honor.
Ms. Vito, did you
take this picture?
You know I did.
What is this picture of?
You know what it's of.
Ms. Vito..
it has been argued
by me, the defense,
that two sets of guys
met up at the Sac-O-Suds
at the same time
driving identical
metallic mint-green
1964 Buick skylark convertibles.
Can you tell us by what
you see in this picture
if the defense's case
holds water?
Ms. Vito, please
answer the question.
Does the defense's
case hold water?
No.
The defense is wrong.
Oh, Jesus.
Are you sure?
I'm positive.
How could you
be so sure?
Because there is no way
these tire marks
were made by
a '64 Buick Skylark.
These marks were made by
a 1963 Pontiac tempest.
Objection, Your Honor.
Can we clarify to the court
whether the witness
is stating opinion or fact?
This is your opinion?
It's a fact.
I find it
hard to believe
that this kind
of information
could be ascertained
simply by looking at a picture!
Would you like me
to explain?
I would love
to hear this.
So would I.
The car that made these
two equal-length tire
marks had positraction.
You can't make those marks
without positraction,
which was not available
on the '64 Buick Skylark.
And why not?
What is positraction?
It's a limited
slip differential
which distributes
Power equally
to both the right
and left tires.
The '64 Skylark had
a regular differential,
which anyone who's been
stuck in the mud knows,
you step on the gas,
one tire spins,
the other tire does nothing.
Is that it?
No. There's more.
See? The left tire mark
goes up on the curb
and the right tire mark
stays flat and even.
Well, the '64 Skylark
had a solid rear axle,
so when the left tire
went on the curb,
the right tire
would tilt out
and ride along its edge.
But that didn't happen.
The tire marks
stayed flat and even.
This car had an independent
rear suspension.
In the sixties, there were two other
American-made cars
that had positraction
and independent rear suspension
and enough power
to make these marks.
One was the corvette
which could never be confused with
the Buick Skylark.
The other had
the same body length,
height, width,
weight, wheel base,
and wheel track
as the '64 Skylark,
and that was the 1963
Pontiac Tempest.
And because both cars
were made by GM,
Were both cars available
in metallic
mint-green paint?
They were.
Thank you, Ms. Vito.
No more questions.
Thank you very,
very much.
You've been a lovely..
Lovely..
witness.
Uh, Mr. Trotter,
would you like
to question Ms. Vito?
Mr. Trotter?
Mr. Trotter!
Uh..
oh, uh, no.
No, no, Your Honor,
no further questions.
In that case, Your Honor,
I'd like to recall
George Wilbur.
Ms. Vito, uh,
you can stand down.
You realize you're
still under oath?
Yes, sir.
Uh, Mr. Wilbur,
How did you like, uh,
Ms. Vito's testimony?
Very impressive.
She's cute, too, huh?
Yes, very.
Mr. Gambini?
Sorry. Sorry, Your Honor.
Uh, Mr. Wilbur,
in your expert opinion,
would you say that everything
Ms. Vito said on the stand
was 100% accurate?
I'd have to say that.
Is there any way
in the world
the Buick that the defendants
were driving
made those tire tracks?
Come on. You could say.
It's OK. They know.
Actually..
no.
No. Thank you.
No more questions.
Your Honor,
I call Sheriff Farley.
You may stand down now,
Mr. Wilbur.
Sheriff, you realize you're
still under oath?
Yes, sir.
Uh, Sheriff Farley,
um..
what did you find out?
On a hunch,
I took it upon myself
to see if there
was any information
on a '63 Pontiac Tempest
stolen or abandoned recently.
This computer
readout confirms
that two boys who
fit the defendants' description
were arrested
two days ago
by Sheriff Tilman in
Jasper County, Georgia,
for driving a stolen metallic mint-green
1963 Pontiac Tempest
with a white
convertible top
and Michelin model
XGV tires,
size 75-R-14.
Is that it?
No.
A.357 magnum revolver was found
in their possession.
- Oh!
Uh, Sheriff Farley,
just to refresh
the court's memory,
what caliber bullet
was used to murder Jimmy Willis?
.357 magnum.
The defense rests.
Mr. Trotter?
Your Honor..
in light of Ms. Vito's
and Mr. Wilbur's testimony,
the state would like
to dismiss all charges.
Yes!
Aah!
All right!
Yeah!
Order in the court!
Yeah! Yeah!
Order here.
Have to get out
of here by 3:00.
Make sure the bags
are in the car.
I'm sorry to have
ever doubted you.
For this, I apologize.
Under the circumstances..
you were great.
I just wanted
to say thank you.
You're welcome.
I hope we can do it
again sometime.
Fine job,
Mr. Gambini.
Thanks.
Y'all come back
and see us.
I'll see you.
Vin.
Bill.
You're welcome.
Vin, I..
Bill, listen.
Take your time.
Pick the right words.
Get back to New York.
Give me a call.
Thank you.
OK.
Vinny, you did
a terrific job.
Thanks. Thanks.
You got an open invitation
anytime you want
to come down here.
We'll get us
a deer next time.
If I don't leave now,
I might never
be able to leave.
Mr. Gambini,
I have a fax here
from the clerk
of New York.
I owe you
an apology, sir.
I'm honored
to shake your hand.
"Win some, lose some."
Your courtroom manner
may be rather
unconventional,
but I got
to tell you,
you're one hell
of a trial lawyer.
Thank you, and, uh,
you're one hell
of a judge.
Oh, sorry.
Bye, now.
Bye.
What the hell was that
all about back there?
I had a friend send
a fax to the judge
confirming the very impressive
legal stature of Jerry Callo.
What friends you got
in the Clerk's Office?
Your friend.
My friend?
Judge Malloy.
So what's your problem?
My problem is I wanted
to win my first case
without any help
from anybody.
Well, I guess
that plan's moot.
Yeah.
You know, this could be a sign
of things to come.
You win
all your cases,
but with somebody
else's help, right?
You win
case after case,
and then afterwards,
you have to go up to somebody,
and you have
to say thank you.
Oh, my God!
What a fucking nightmare!
I won my first case.
You know what this means.
You think I'll marry you.
What, you're not going
to marry me now?
No way. You can't win
a case by yourself.
You're fucking useless.
I thought we'd get
married this weekend.
You don't get it,
do you?
That is not romantic.
I want a wedding
in church
with bridesmaids
and flowers.
Oh, how many times
did you say that spontaneous
is romantic?
Hey, a burp is spontaneous.
A burp is not romantic.
SubText:
MiTA.326