And now the purple dusk
of twilight time steals across
the meadows of my heart.
High up in the sky, the
little stars climb, always
reminding me that we're apart.
You wander down the lane and far away,
leaving me a song that will not die.
Love is now the stardust of yesterday,
the music of the years gone by.
1954.
You don't get years like that anymore.
It was my favorite year.
Look.
Look at that Buick.
See, that's what I'm talking about.
In 1954, a Buick was a Buick.
It didn't look like a Chevy, which
looks like a Pontiac, which you
can't tell apart from an Olds,
like today.
This is the way people dressed in 1954.
Smooth?
Somewhere there's music,
how faint the tune.
Somewhere there's heaven,
how high the moon.
In 1954, television was live
and comedy was king.
Comic stars like Milton Berle,
Sid Caesar, and Jackie Gleason
kept America in front of their TV sets.
I was the freshman writer on "The Comedy."
Cavalcade," starring Stan "King" Kaiser,
Saturday nights at eight.
There.
There I am.
That's me.
Benjy Stone, the guy carrying
the guy with the sword.
The guy with the sword is Alan Swann,
the greatest movie idol of all
times and my personal hero.
That week, Alan Swann was the guest star
on "The Comedy Cavalcade."
This is where we wrote the show.
30 Rockefeller Plaza.
30 Rock, we called it.
Here I was, two years after
being asked to leave Brooklyn.
College, and already I was
earning more money per week
than the entire fourth floor
of my mother's apartment house
on Ocean Parkway in Brooklyn.
Anyway, 1954, the week Allen Swann was
the guest star on "The Comedy Cavalcade,"
was a major turning point for me.
It changed me.
How high the moon.
Hold it!
Good morning.
Good morning Good morning.
Stay friends!
Good?
You talking to me, Sy?
Look who I'm asking.
Sorry I'm late, Sy.
The food.
Gimme my food!
The coffee shop was jammed.
Fine, thank you, Sy, and you?
Really?
No, I didn't think so.
What is this, tea?
I didn't order tea!
That's Herb's.
He had the tea and dry toast.
This is yours, Sy.
Extra-large coffee, six sugars.
Lightly toasted bagel, heavy
butter, just a schmear of cream
cheese, grape jelly, right?
Wait a minute.
Where's my crumb cake?
They were out.
Sidney put in a bear claw.
Alice, what are we seeing?
Clips from Swann's movies.
Clips from his crap.
Roll 'em, Herb!
This is "Captain
from Tortuga."
"Captain from Crap."
This is from "Rapture."
You call what Swann does acting?
That's not acting.
It's kissing and jumping
and drinking and humping.
I don't know why we're wasting
our eyesight on this crap.
Swann's never going to show up anyhow.
They'll find him, Sy.
What happened?
He landed fine last
night, that much we know.
So where is he?
Where else?
Drinking and humping.
Hello.
Hi.
Crap!
This is crap!
That was the best part!
There is no best part.
Swann never made a
decent movie in his life.
Sy, that one, "Defender
of the Crown," is a classic.
Crap.
And so is "Captain
from Tortuga."
Crap.
And what about
"Swords of Glory?"
- Crap.
- "Amarillo."
- "Sands of the Sudan."
Crap.
Benjy, you want to see
movies, get a job as an usher.
The rest of us are here to write
professional showbiz comedy.
In your case,
semi-professional.
What's the matter, Herb?
You can't talk to a person like
a regular, normal human being?
No.
Come on!
King wants us to
see a run-through
of the Boss Hijack sketch.
Hey, Janine!
When you gonna let me get into your box?
Hey, kid.
Read your bullfighter sketch last night.
You liked it?
Dozed off halfway through it.
Hey, come on, don't get
the wrong idea, kid.
It's not that it wasn't funny,
it's just that it wasn't funny.
Sy, I read that sketch.
I thought it was terrific.
Then maybe you should
be head writer, Alice.
I couldn't take the chance.
What chance?
That I'd become like you.
Hold it!
Ho!
K.C.!
Lil, Mr. Silver wants to see
Helen's costume for the Three.
Musketeers sketch.
Now he wants it?
When I'm up to my ass here in threads?
So, let's just have
a quiet dinner tonight.
Danny's Hideaway?
Yeah.
Lil!
We'll split a Chateaubriand, medium rare?
I got it.
Careful with the tiara, kid.
You break it, you bought it.
Then a hansom cab ride
through Central Park.
From there we hop over to
the Algonquin for a cordial,
and we end the night at your place.
What do you think?
Benjamin, why would I
want to go out with you?
Every time you come near me,
you embarrass or humiliate me.
I mean, what do you want from me?
Sex.
What is the time?
I don't know.
Don't you have a watch?
No.
I'm not allowed to wear a watch.
Why not?
Hi.
Do you have the time?
It's 9:25.
Are you late for something?
Always.
And I'm never quite sure for what.
People.
I hate to break up the Last Supper,
but I wouldn't mind
seeing a run-through.
Sorry to tell you this, but
King threw out the monologue.
Leo, that monologue was good.
Check that!
Perfect!
I wrote it!
Here's where Sy Benson draws the line.
Sy, don't do anything crazy.
King's got to be taught.
First comes the word,
and the word was funny!
The monologue stays, or I go.
Sy, maybe we can compromise.
No compromise.
Sy Benson has his integrity, his pride.
King does that monologue word
for word or I walk.
I walk!
Monologue's in.
- Morning, King.
- Hello, Stan.
- Hey, good morning.
King!
About the monologue.
But Sy!
Do you smell something?
It's coming from the script!
It's your monologue!
What a stinkburger.
K.C.!
Paul!
Boom!
I hate it, it's not funny, it's out.
Hey, babe, we're not married to it.
Monologue's out.
Sy Benson.
A tower of Jell-O.
K.C. I think I went a little
too far with Sy just now,
really hurt his feelings.
I got to get him something.
Here's 100 bucks.
Get him something.
Tires are nice.
Get him a set of tires.
Call my brother in the
Bronx, he'll tell you where.
Boss Hijack sketch, from the top.
K.C.
Electrics and cameras, please.
Cameras.
Whitewalls.
Whitewalls?
Here we go.
Five, four, three, two, and copy!
Who owns the gray '51 DeSoto?
The new guy, Harris.
You're parked in Boss Hijack's spot.
You better move.
The Boss has got some temper on him.
How bad can it be?
We're lucky we're on
the second floor here.
It slowed him down.
Somebody parked in my spot.
Move your car.
That blackout has got
to come a beat sooner.
Screams.
I guarantee you screams.
Well, now all we need
is another 27 minutes
and we got a show this week.
I'm coming in, Sy.
Herb!
Swann here yet?
He's on his way.
Alfie went to pick him up,
and then he's, he's...
Not here yet, right?
Great.
You look real nice today, Alice.
Did you like the shoes I sent you?
Yeah.
Then why'd you send them back?
They were the wrong size.
And they were used.
Come on, come on, roll this thing.
Benjy, lights!
Is this guy gonna be funny?
Jumps around nice, but
is he gonna be funny?
Good God, it's Renfield.
I thought he was dead.
So he is.
Very good with a sword, though.
Good morrow to you, ladies and gentlemen.
He's plastered!
So are some of the
finest erections in Europe.
If I were truly plastered,
could I do this?
Signor Bumbacelli,
would you hold my sword?
Well, we know he can do that.
It's still ticking.
Alfie.
Alfie!
What happened?
To begin with, there was
some difficulty at the airport.
Mr. Swann here had
been reclassified.
Reclassified?
Yeah.
As freight.
Boy.
Then Mr. Swann wanted
to make a couple of stops...
Alfie, I told you to
take him right to the Waldorf!
Now I gotta slam your
brakes on, Mr. Silver.
When I'm driving Mr. Swann,
he's chief of the car.
And when the chief says he
wants to make some stops,
Alfie Bumbacelli makes the stops.
And that's what I live by.
Well, at least we've got
plenty of time to replace him.
Dump him!
Leo.
Isn't there some way?
I mean, the man is a legend.
Stan, what do you think?
I don't know.
He is a legend.
One of the biggest stars ever.
He's one of a kind.
A guy like this is irreplaceable.
Replace him, Leo.
You can't!
Too risky.
He's out.
King!
You're right.
This is too risky.
You can't take a chance
with something like this.
Look, King, you're a big star now,
and I'm sure you always will be.
But suppose... just
suppose, and I know
this is never going to happen...
But suppose someday
you wind up like this.
I hope nobody does to you
what you're doing to him.
Dump him.
Who are you to talk to me
like that, you little Jiminy.
Cricket pest bastard?
All right, he gets one more chance.
- No!
- Yes!
Yes!
But now you, you're going
to be responsible for him.
Swann better be at every rehearsal sober,
or it's your ass, you understand?
Now, see, Sy?
This kid's got balls.
Oof!
A week's salary Swann takes a dive.
Hey!
Swann dive!
Ba-dum-bum!
You're on.
Double the lad's bet for me, you toad.
OK, now, pick a card, good, any card.
Priscilla.
Come here.
And now put it back
in the deck, anywhere.
How long you workin' here?
Here.
About a year.
You look real nice today.
Thank you.
Here, write your address on here.
Put it on my desk.
I'm gonna send you some steaks.
Is that your card?
Yeah, that's my card!
Mr. Silver, Boss Rojeck and
his lawyer are in your office.
It's about the Boss Hijack sketch.
Hey, where are you going?
With you.
What for?
To meet Boss Rojeck.
Stan.
What's the matter with you?
You think he's here because he
likes the Boss Hijack sketch?
You think he likes being made a fool
out of by you in front of 20
million people every week?
I don't know.
Stan.
He's here because he wants us
to drop the Boss Hijack sketch.
Think so?
Let's go find out.
All right, all right.
Maybe you better change first.
Why?
Well, that outfit might set him off.
Mr. Rojeck, sir,
I think you've made
a wise decision to come here.
I think these gentlemen
will be able to talk to us...
about our problem in a mature way.
I'm sure they'll see reason, sir,
and there should be
no problem whatsoever.
Myron Fein.
I'm Leo Silver.
This is King Kaiser.
What do you say, Myron?
My client, Karl Rojeck.
Karl?
It's not Boss?
Stan!
Gentlemen.
We'll all be sitting
down, Mr. Rojeck.
I'm sure we're all aware
that my client, Mr. Rojeck,
is one of the most respected
labor leaders in America today.
That's why they subpoenaed him.
Stan!
Mr. Kaiser, a subpoena
is not an indictment.
Now, it has come to our
attention that on two
separate occasions...
September 4th, 1954, and
September 18th, 1954...
A character referred to as
Boss Hijack was portrayed
on your television program.
We feel that this
character to a great degree
is based upon my client.
That's you, Karl.
Well, according to our lawyers,
your client is a public
figure and as such
has already forfeited
certain rights of privacy.
Granted.
However, even though Mr.
Rojeck concedes that point,
he feels that the
portrayal of said character
is slanderous and defamatory
and done with malicious intent,
therefore abrogating the
public figure defense
and rendering it...
to wit, actionable.
Did you say that, Karl?
What a guy.
That's it.
I want to clear some things up here.
This is a stupid show.
And that is a stupid, stupid suit.
And I don't want to see it no more.
Hey, take it easy, Karl.
I mean, if you really don't
want to see it no more,
then don't watch.
Stan!
Let me explain something to you, Karl.
We're going to keep on doing the sketch.
You know why?
Because it's funny.
And in my business, you never cut funny.
Funny?
Let me tell you about
the business I'm in.
I'm in the removal business.
Now, if I were to feel
that this stupid thing
from this stupid show is
bothering me, I'd remove it.
You see, it's gone.
And I feel good.
Now, that's how the
removal business works.
Do I make myself clear?
I think everyone
understands, Mr. Rojeck.
Should we leave?
No, no, wait, wait, wait.
I'm not clear about a
couple of things here.
What you're saying is that
in this removal business,
if something bothers you...
Like, like say this...
Then you remove it.
- Stan, that is a cashmere coat.
- Like that!
Stan!
You know, you're right.
You do feel better.
I like the removal business.
I want you.
Come on.
Come and get me.
Come on, come on.
A fight is rounds.
This is Round One.
So the first time I drive him is, what?
Right before the war.
1938.
That makes it 16 years.
Yeah.
We go way back.
You drive anyone else?
Sure.
But when Mr. Swann's in
town, I drop everything.
Upstairs, boys, all right?
La, la, la, la, la, la!
Oof!
Wonderful to be alive.
Make sure you don't fall.
What is our estimated time of arrival?
Go ahead and lash me, you swine!
You'll not loosen my tongue.
That's from "Captain From Tortuga"!
Excuse me.
Had this made special
for when he travels...
Calls it his 'drunk suit.'
I have to remind him to
work on some tear-away shoes.
Good idea.
My god, I'm blind.
I cannot see.
Help me get him into the tub.
I got him.
This is probably more than $35 a night?
Tried Try $250.
$250 a night?
Well, what's that mean
to a guy like Alan Swann?
Nothing... when
you ain't got nothing,
it don't mean nothing.
What are you talking about?
You're looking at tap city in there.
That's his stockpile.
Grab 'em, will you?
These must be his drinking socks.
Who's this?
That's Tess, his daughter.
Daughter... I didn't
know he had a daughter.
Where is she?
She's in Connecticut.
He always has one secret bottle hidden
somewhere for emergencies.
We got them all now.
Nah, that guy never actually shot him.
You see, they were
supposed to have this duel,
and I think it was over that Peron dame.
Anyhow, they both showed up drunk...
Alfredo!
And Swan sort of shot himself.
Alfredo, my dear old chum.
Tell me, how in the name
of God did I get here?
Begin at the airport.
This is Benjy Stone, one of the writers
from "Comedy Cavalcade."
How do you do?
Alfredo, we should pop
in and see these people.
Yes.
Plenty of time
tomorrow, Mr. Swann.
And since this is your first
time working in television,
they've asked me to stay with you
and help you over some
of the rough spots.
Like showing up?
That's one, another is not passing out.
An honest one.
Signor Bumbacelli,
we'll be two for dinner.
Telephone The Stork Club.
You sure you mean
The Stork Club, Mr. Swann?
Certainly.
It's been a year and a half, surely
they've repaired the wall
and the bandstand by now.
Would you like to talk about
the sketch before you leave?
On an empty stomach?
No, we'll talk over dinner.
Me, you The Stork Club?
Well, after that rather eloquent speech
you made earlier this
morning, I didn't think you'd
mind having dinner with me.
You heard that?
But you were out.
There's out and there's out.
I'd like I'd like to reservation.
Well, Stone, what sort
of heroic idiot am I this time?
A musketeer idiot.
I read that on the airplane...
Very funny, very good.
I wrote that.
Did you?
Bravo, Stone... bravo.
OK, Mr. Swann, table
for two at The Stork Club.
Let's move it.
Comedy is such a mystery to me.
I feel the way Edmund Kean did.
The great English actor?
On his deathbed, Kean
was asked how he felt.
He answered, dying is
easy, comedy is hard.
Thanks, Mr. Charles.
Mr. Swann... A pleasure to see you, sir.
Pleasure to be seen.
Benjamin Stone, my colleague.
Alan, you're looking
absolutely marvelous.
- As do you.
- Proper jacket.
Much.
We must talk.
Thank you.
Mr. Swann.
Alan, good to see you.
Call me, will you?
Surely.
I'll call you.
Welcome back, Mr. Swann.
Curt.
Can I get you something?
Perhaps... Curt, who
is that gorgeous-looking
creature over there?
No, Mr. Swann,
this is exactly
the way it started last time.
In that case, we'll just order dinner...
For now.
Victoria was the one
I should have married.
Apart from being the finest
actress I've worked with,
she was the most gracious and intelligent
woman I've ever known.
Was it true the two of
you lived together while you
were filming "Rapture"?
Lord knows, I was married
to almost all her friends.
Why did you marry so many of them?
Stone, I didn't marry any of them.
They married me.
Excuse me, Mr. Swann.
I'm Alvin Horn.
My wife, Ann, and I are celebrating
our 40th anniversary.
Congratulations, sport.
You certainly have more
staying power than I.
It would mean so much to her
if you could stop on your way
out and just say hello.
Why wait?
Lead me to the fair Ann.
Stone, in a few minutes, I
shall require a diversion.
Mr. Swann, my wife, Ann.
Mr. Horn, may I have this
dance with your beautiful wife?
Of course.
Wonderful.
Come back here!
Is it always like this?
Somebody stole my girl!
"To the question..."
'what were you doing
naked, in Central Park,
in Bethesda Fountain at
3:00 in the morning?'
Swan replied, 'the backstroke.'"
Now is this your idea
of watching him, Benjy?
The police are treating
it like a parking ticket.
It's no big deal.
No big deal?
We got kids watching this show.
We're talking generations
to come, here...
We're discussing morals, here!
You're not qualified
to discuss morals, Sy.
Up your whole with a mello
roll, Alice, and yours too,
Herb!
Leo, it gets me sick to
think we've got to put up
with some washed-up
jabroni who's
going to be running around Central Park
with his schlong hanging out.
My dear fellow, what I choose to do
with my schlong is my business.
How's business?
Never better.
Stone, good morning.
Good morning.
'Morning all.
'Morning.
Good morning.
When King gets here, we'll read
through the musketeer sketch.
My assistant, KC Downing... Mr. Swann.
How do you do?
Hello...
If there's anything you
need, I can take care of it
for you.
Anything?
Within reason, I...
Well, let's begin with some tea
and see where that leads us.
Tea.
Do you drink bags?
I mean, do you... I mean, are these OK...
Tea bags?
Surely, surely.
Now... Good morning, Mr. Kaiser.
What do you say?
Leo.
And... good
morning, Mr. Swann.
Hey, where's the musketeers set?
OK, it isn't here.
That's where it is.
And they won't deliver it.
Rojeck did it.
Now you happy?
Rojeck?
Yeah.
I've got a great idea.
Let's just wrap, drop the
Boss Hijack sketch this week.
Get me that set, you understand?
I want that set.
All right, I'll do it.
I don't care if you have to
rent trucks, find drivers...
Stop hitting me with that...
Get that set here!
Build a set!
Steal a set, I don't care!
Nobody's going to tell
King Kaiser that...
OK, I'm going to go back
there and get my script.
And then I'll come back here and
we'll read through the sketch.
And then we'll work out
the set problem, OK, Leo?
OK, everybody, let's take 10 minutes.
"Cavalcade."
Benjy Stone!
Telephone!
Hello?
Benjamin, darling.
Ma.
Did you watch the show Saturday night?
No, we watched wrestling instead...
Of course I saw the show.
Well?
Well, what else?
It was brilliant, darling.
Just one thing... Who
is this Benjy Stone?
Ma, don't start in.
Do you think... Sh!
You think I'll ever see the name Benjamin
Steinberg... a real name... go
by King Kaiser's face one day?
Look who's talking,
Mrs. Belle "Cari-oca."
Carroca... Carroca.
Carroca, Carroca.
Rookie, shush.
See, now you upset your stepfather.
Ma, could you just call
him 'Rookie, ' and not
my stepfather all the time?
Benjamin, darling...
Rookie, dust.
Before your beloved father
passed away and eventually
died, he said to me, Belle,
after I go, get someone
to be with, someone nice... A pal.
So you went out and found
a Filipino bantamweight
named Rookie Carroca?
Rookie Carroca who held the
title for well over six months.
Until Manny Serpa turned
him into a guava jelly
at the Garden.
Serpa butted him.
I'll fight Serpa today
and take him apart.
Do you hear what you started here?
Ma... What?
Was there a reason you called?
Only to remind you that you're coming
here for dinner tomorrow night.
No... Ma, I can't make it.
Alan Swann's on the show
and they made me his keeper.
Alan Swann from the movies?
Yeah.
Rookie, Alan Swann from the movies.
So bring him along.
Bring Alan Swann to Brooklyn?
Well, why not?
What are you ashamed of?
Everything.
And Benjamin, when you get here,
be nice to my Rookie.
He likes you.
Yeah, and I like him.
I tell you what, I'll
bring him a present.
Does he need a new machete?
Eyes... it's
always in the eyes.
You... I would like
a word with you.
Benjamin, we're in the middle of an
interesting conversation here.
I bet it's real interesting.
What's the subject of this
interesting conversation?
These eyes.
They're Merle Oberon's eyes.
Merle Oberon's?
And what's Merle doing for eyes...
Using Katharine Hepburn's?
Excuse me, Alan.
Benjamin, what is the matter with you?
Me?
If you're going to fall for every movie
star who comes on the
show, what kind of a future
are we going to have?
The same as we have now... None.
Wait... give her a head start.
It gives her the illusion
she's being chased.
These cans say, 'crushed.'
Where the hell are the pineapple girls?
Hey, I'm sorry.
I acted like a jerk.
You're being too easy on yourself.
And where did you get the
idea that we have a future?
We have an understanding.
What understanding?
That I am hopelessly in love with you
and you couldn't care less about me.
Yeah... yeah, you
could say that.
Well, maybe this will change your mind.
This belonged to my grandmother
and I want you to have it.
Benjamin, I can't take that.
Fine... how about a car?
Benjamin, the ring.
It was glass.
Sanctuary, sanctuary!
Sanctuary, my ass.
I'm sorry, ladies, there was a...
Benjamin, would you get out of here?
No, not until you
tell me exactly what was
going on between you and Swann.
Look, just get out of here.
Hey, I'm in here.
Wait... I was saving
this for later.
What are you doing?
What's he doing?
- I'm proposing.
- What?
What?
I'm proposing that we live
together, and if we like it,
we get married.
Come on, say yes.
God.
My god.
All right, if that's too
tough, just nod your head.
You get the hell out of here.
Please, give me a word, a sign, a sound.
That's not the sound I was looking for.
All right, the hell
with it, I'm coming out now.
Stone... time for lunch.
What?
I... Just going to the lavatory.
This is for ladies only.
And so is this, ma'am.
But every now and again, I have to
run a little water through it.
No, Stone, I insist...
Lunch is on me.
I... I got it.
Thoughtful.
Stone, I want you to know
that, this morning, I
had absolutely no idea that I
was in the process of inserting
myself into an arrangement
which already existed
between you and Miss Downing.
Would it have made any difference?
No.
Are you in love with the girl?
I think I am.
I don't know what she wants.
Romance, Stone...
That's the only thing
we can be sure they all want.
I've never met anyone like her.
She never met anyone like you.
Use that... cultivate it.
Right there is where I lost you.
Stone, women love the intrigue.
They enjoy unraveling
the mystery that is man,
but you must allow them the
freedom to discover you.
Is that what you do?
No, I don't have that luxury.
The women who are interested
in me know exactly who I am
and what they want.
And nine times out of 10, they get it.
That's some curse.
You'd be surprised.
You see, no matter what I do, I can never
fulfill their expectations.
Could I... Could I have...
So, this is the Benjy
Stone version of dinner
and a movie?
Doesn't Sy's office take
on a whole different feeling
at night?
Yeah, it gets worse.
OK, here we go.
These are all dim sum...
Chinese dumplings.
These are pan-fried.
Those are steamed... they're
good just with vinegar.
Chili sauce... stay
away from this, baby.
A couple of drops of this and your tongue
dials the fire department.
You know how to use these?
To make a sweater, yes.
OK, I'll show you.
Look... balance is
everything... one
goes there, the other
one on top like that.
Now do exactly as I do.
Dim sum are too hard
to eat with chopsticks.
Don't make yourself crazy.
OK.
You really know this stuff.
Katherine, Jews know two things...
Suffering and where to
find great Chinese food.
What?
Too loud... what, what?
No, no, it's just... It's really nice.
You know, you're just sitting
there having your dinner,
wearing men's clothing...
Well, sort of.
I mean, that I really like this guy.
I like this guy much
better than the other guy.
What other guy?
You know, the guy in the tiara.
The mosquito who bothers
you in elevators.
The person who runs down
the hallway with scotch
tape all over his
body... the human fly.
Ew!
Do you think... Do not think...
No, I was just going to say,
do you think there are funny
people and not-funny people?
Yes, definitely.
On the funny side, there are the
Marx Brothers... except Zeppo,
the Ritz brothers...
No exceptions,
both Laurel and Hardy,
and Woody Woodpecker.
On the unfunny side, there is
anybody who has ever played
the accordion professionally.
And me.
You know, everybody who works
here is funny, except me.
No, you're funny.
Really?
When?
Well, I'm sure you could be funny.
How?
You can tell a joke.
Anyone can tell a joke.
Not me.
Yes, you can.
I'll teach you.
I'll tell you a joke and
you tell it back to me, OK?
OK, I'll try.
First rule... never
tell a joke sitting down.
You have to be on your
feet and use your hands.
This guy walks into a
psychiatrist's office.
He has a duck on his head.
The psychiatrist says, can I help you?
The duck says, yeah,
get this guy off my ass.
OK, now you try.
OK, here goes.
A man... Hold it.
'This guy'... it's
better than 'a man.'
OK.
Sorry.
And use your hands.
Right.
Sorry, go ahead.
This guy walks into a doctor's office...
Psychiatrist.
Psychiatrist...
Right, OK, sorry.
OK, I got it.
I got it.
This guy walks into a psychiatrist's
office wearing a duck... What?
Wearing a duck?
No.
He has a duck on his head.
I told you I wasn't very good at this.
No, it's my fault. It's... It's good.
Yeah?
OK.
This guy walks into a
psychiatrist's office
with a duck on his head.
And the guy says to the psychiatrist,
will you help me, because
I have a duck on my head?
What is that for?
Accordion lessons.
Well, that ends the dinner
portion of the evening.
Now it's time for the movie portion.
Lord Drummond.
Lord Drummond!
Drummond.
If it would put you at ease,
I could turn my back again.
Sh!
You will this day, taste my steel.
Then leave us not dally, Drummond,
for today, I have an engagement
to mount the throne of England.
Over my dead body.
Quiet.
As you wish.
Are going to keep doing this?
Sir John!
Benjamin!
Sh!
I guess this is the kissing
portion of the evening.
I am Arrogant!
He's Arrogant!
And I am Porthole!
He's Porthole!
And I am Swann!
He's Swann!
It's one for all and all for one.
And me for you and tea for two!
Break it up!
Everybody, OK, all right.
Now hold it!
Hold it!
Hold it, hold it!
Wait, I want to say something.
Alan... I want
to tell you that I
was a little worried about you.
Only a little?
I would have thought my reputation
warranted major concern.
Yeah, you're right.
I was going to dump you.
But I'm glad I didn't,
because well, I've seen all
of your films and I'm a fan.
And here we are, working together,
and it's been nice, because you're funny.
You're really funny.
Praise indeed, sir.
And may I say that other than one
remarkable season with an
English repertory company,
this is the most fun and
the hardest work I've
done since the world was young.
That's great, really.
But one other thing...
You're going to show up
tomorrow, too, right?
Right, Swann?
Right, Porthole.
But our needs must take
leave of you, for Stone
and I journey to dine in some
far-off land called Brooklyn.
Well, that's it.
Big day, tomorrow... show day.
Have a good night.
See you at 10:00 AM.
'Night.
Goodnight.
Good night, then.
Take it easy.
Thank you, everybody.
Nice work today.
Do it that good on the show tomorrow.
You all right?
It's all right, I'm OK.
It's no problem, it's nothing.
The thing fell, it's nothing, really.
Go home.
Go home, really.
- You're sure you're OK?
- I'm OK.
I want you to get some rest.
Now everybody go home.
I'm all right.
I promise you I'm all right.
Come on, let's go home.
Come on.
My god.
It was an accident, Leo.
Rojeck.
That's it, I'm not going to let
you do the Boss Hijack sketch.
It's an accident, Leo, an accident.
And we're doing the Boss Hijack sketch.
Stan!
Leo!
Thanks for caring.
By the by, Stone, where is this Brooklyn?
Another world.
Hop in.
Mort, come on, honey.
Uncle Morty, how odd to find you here.
Why?
I just caught the 7:45
elevator down from six.
I assume Aunt Sadie is here also?
Not yet, but she'll be.
Uncle Morty, say hello to Alan Swann.
I didn't catch the name.
Alan Swann, Rookie "Cari-oca."
Carroca.
There was a lethal
bantamweight called Carroca.
You're looking at him.
I saw you fight in San Diego.
Sailor Donovan?
Right.
Took him out in three.
Two.
Who knew the
China-man was a fighter?
To me, he doesn't open a mouth.
Still in the fight game?
In a way.
I married Benjy's mother.
Benjamin, darling, how
wonderful to have you to home.
I gotta get back to my meatloaf.
Mr. Swann, may I
present my mother,
Mrs. Belle Mae Steinberg
Carroca of Brooklyn,
New York and Miami Beach, Florida for two
weeks each and every winter.
Benjamin, why didn't you tell
me your mother was so lovely?
For me?
No, for me.
Mr. Swann... Alan, please.
And what may I call you?
How about 'yours'?
Alan, on behalf of everyone
here, I would like to welcome
you to our humble chapeau.
Two years at the Sorbonne,
she still gets it wrong.
- Al...
- Ma!
What?
It's not 'Al.'
if I bring Capone or
Jolson, then it's Al.
Jolson's coming?
Alan, I want you to feel perfectly
free to do whatever you would normally
do in your own apartment.
Something to drink before dinner?
Some soda water?
Rookie!
A glass of seltzer!
Pick it up!
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Excuse me, Mr. Swann.
I hate to impose, but I wonder
if you would mind signing...
An autograph... certainly.
If you don't mind, make it
to Sadie and Morty Kronsky...
That's with a 'k.'
The rest is the way it's usually spelled.
That's probably Aunt Sadie.
Why don't you go open
the door for your wife?
Thank you, Mr. Swann.
Al... Thank you.
Your seltzer.
A little liver?
No, thank you.
Sadie, you look beautiful.
What a lovely dress.
You like it?
I only wore it once.
Come and get it!
Dinner is served.
Rookie, your Meatloaf
Mindanao was superb.
Thanks.
That takes two days to prepare, you know.
Really?
Tell me, what was that
rather pungent taste?
Parrot.
And they're not easy to work with.
They put up some squawk.
I can imagine.
What was that dish?
Filipino pork and beans.
Where was the pork?
You can't!
There's Jews here.
So I guess if you want to be technical...
What's the difference?
So, Mr. Swann, now
that we sat nice,
broke bread together,
shared a glass of wine,
I feel I know you a little.
Morty, I feel I know you even better.
Good.
Then you won't mind if
I ask you a question?
Uncle Morty... What are you worried?
It's not personal.
What was I, born in Minsk or Pinsk?
I know my way around.
Morty, ask your question.
That paternity wrap, a couple years ago.
Morty!
Did you shtup her?
Morty, shut up!
Did you go all the way?
- What?
- Morty!
- Uncle Morty, you are...
- What?
My god.
It's all right.
All right... It's all right.
Morty, I hope this doesn't
lessen your opinion of me,
but the answer is no.
You see, people like me, we're targets.
I'm blamed for a lot of things I had
absolutely nothing to do with.
On the other hand, because of who I am,
I get away with murder in other areas.
I suppose it all balances out in the end.
Does it really, Swanee?
Ma, he's an actor, not a river.
Swanee, can I talk frank to you?
Certainly, Belle.
Take a good look here.
This this... this is good.
Sitting around with people you love.
Some you just like, others,
maybe you could live without,
excuse me.
Sharing stories, sharing warm...
This is real life, Alan.
And this is what you need...
A home and a family and children?
Hey, who knows?
Unfortunately, Belle,
that part of my life
hasn't worked out too well.
Though I did produce a
perfectly glorious little child.
Her name is Tess.
See, you're a daddy,
and this I didn't even know.
So where is she?
She lives with her mother in Connecticut.
I haven't seen her in over a year.
A year?
Shame on you, Swanee.
Yes, you're right, Belle.
Shame on me, indeed.
Well, time to go.
What a divine evening.
We must do this again, real soon...
Say, at the turn of the century?
Rookie, Sadie, Morty.
Goodbye, Mr. Swann.
Belle.
Alan.
Oy vey.
Mr. and Mrs.
Kessler... apartment 4B.
God bless you, Mr. Swann.
Mr. and Mrs. Berkowitz,
apartment 2A... we love you.
Nathan and Lily Cantor,
second floor front... pleasure
to have you in the building.
Scalfoni, 1I...
You're the best.
How did you get into the building?
I'm the super.
Goodbye!
Doctor Bumbacelli...
My medication.
Your medication.
Mr. Swann... Big day tomorrow, show day.
And you know, I'm supposed to watch.
Good, watch this.
Want to see it again?
Stone, you can either
watch me or join me.
One of them's more fun.
You were a hit in Brooklyn.
Want to try the Bronx next?
No.
1030 Park Avenue... the Downings.
Please, no.
Let's not go there.
Why are we going there?
Why, to reweave the
fabric of your relationship
with the fair KC, that's why.
This surprise visit should do it.
I... I don't
think so, Mr. Swann.
KC Downing's parents
are having a big party.
Besides, they're not going to
let us up in that building.
Excellent.
Ever done any mountaineering?
Now all we have to do is
to get from here to there.
It won't work.
It worked perfectly well in
"A Slight Case of Divorce."
That was a movie.
This is real life.
What is the difference?
No.
It's stuck.
What we need is something like a rope.
Let's not do this.
Stone... I've done it 100 times!
Always had a stuntman.
Perfect.
Wait!
Wait, wait, wait!
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
Let's just go back to the way we came
and go through her front door.
Dull!
Boring!
Old hat.
Stone, the cardinal rule...
They always a big entrance!
I assure you this.
Does anybody die in these movies?
Die?
Of course not... it's just fun!
Fun?
Fun!
He thinks this is fun!
I'm going down. Now.
When I arrive, I shall
hold the rope taut,
and you can just shimmy down.
I'm not shimmying down anything.
It's too dangerous.
Nonsense!
Not when you've been
instructed by Niblick.
Who the hell is Niblick?
Niblick is my Sherpa
guide from the Himalayas.
The Himalayas... the Himalayas!
Look, there's the door.
Come on, let's go give it a try.
It's open!
My god.
I killed him.
I'm supposed to take care
of him and I killed him.
God!
The bond issue was a fraud.
The company went bankrupt.
They looked solid, but
they went belly up.
Excuse me, have you seen that film...
"Defender of the Crown"?
Just like that...
The film... "Defender of the
Crown"... have you seen it?
Starring... what's
that guy's name?
Alan... Alan... Swann.
Yeah, Alan Swann!
Bill, I think Alan Swann's beneath us.
Well, of course he's
beneath us, he's an actor.
No, I mean, I think Alan.
Swann's beneath us right now.
Look!
Harry, get the hell out here!
Alan Swann is hanging from...
Something from the roof!
- Pull!
- Pull him up!
Pull!
That's it, here he comes.
Good evening, do you have a light?
Help me, help me!
Terrace?
Well done.
We've just dropped in
to see the Downings.
There are no Downings here.
No Downings here?
No.
The Downing's are downstairs on 14.
Close, Stone, very close.
Mr. Swann, I think
I'm going to be unwell.
Stone, ladies are unwell.
Gentlemen vomit.
Alfredo, you needn't wait.
We shan't need the car anymore.
We're going to throw up in
the park and then walk home.
Mr. Swann, may
tell you something?
Benjy Stone is not who he seems to be.
Who is, Stone, who is?
But I'm not even Benjy Stone.
I'm Benjamin Steinberg.
I changed my name because
I thought it wouldn't
look good on the screen.
I'm a phony.
Because you changed your name?
What's in a name?
A rose by any other name
would wither and die.
I'll give you a name... Clarence Duffy.
Clarence Duffy?
Who's Clarence Duffy?
He's a young man from
the west of Scotland...
Middle-class, Irish
descent, whose father
was a grammar school teacher.
His mother looked after her garden,
her husband, and her only son.
At the age of 18, he joined the Navy.
One year later, he
jumped ship in Liverpool,
has notions of becoming an actor,
finishes up in English "B" movies.
Six months later, Lou
Goldmark of Paramount Studios
announces his find, a
dashing new English actor
to star in Paramount's
next big adventure film...
"Swords of Glory."
Clarence Duffy.
One and the same.
And you're not Allen Swann.
Yes, I am.
And you're the only
living soul who knows it.
It dies with me, Clarence.
At least you're an actor.
Actors are supposed to make up names.
It's not just making
up a name, Stoneberg.
The studio made up an entire life for me,
and I let them do it.
And now I can't tell where the
bogus one ends and the real one
begins.
Nothing about me is what it seems to be,
even the reason I'm doing your
"Comedy Cavalcade" program.
It's not because I wanted to.
It's a deal I made with my new partner,
the Internal Revenue Service.
If I do the show and give
them half the proceeds,
they promise not to throw
me out of the country.
Well, that dies with me, too, Duff.
Tonight, your mother
said, "shame on you,"
and she was right.
I'm fed up with people letting
me get away with things,
and everybody does...
My friends, my agent,
my manager, my doctors...
my former wives, even my daughter.
Haven't we walked enough for one night?
No... The horse, Stoneberg!
No, no, no, no!
No!
You'll get 30 years for this.
Hey!
No!
Tess!
Who's Tess?
Tess is his daughter.
Tess is his daughter in Connecticut!
He went to Connecticut
on the day of the show.
The bastard went to Connecticut!
He's in another goddamn state!
I got to go down to the show
and tell Leo so he can fire me.
I'm a dead man.
Can't I can't go like this.
I have to get dressed.
Don't forget your sweater.
Take me back.
Great.
Air day and our guest
star is no-show.
Hey, Leo, he's on the
cover of "TV Guide" this week.
Leo!
Why is this sketch in here?
We did this sketch last
week, but it's right in here,
right in my script.
Now, why, Leo?
Why?
Why is it in my script?
That is last week's script.
That's why it's in there.
And now, you'll find this week's script
in your dressing room, Stan.
That's good.
That's good, Leo.
OK.
They're serving tongue at
lunch today, are they, Leo?
No tongue on show day.
Twice, they served tongue on show day,
twice the opening sketch died.
No tongue, get it?
No tongue.
Tongue... death!
Benjy, you were supposed
to be watching Swann.
I was.
I even stayed in his suite last night.
But when I woke up today, he was gone.
He said he was going to see Tess.
Irish dame... figures.
They love their booze.
She's 12.
Fine, now we can throw in statutory rape.
Tess happens to be his daughter.
Alfie, where is he?
He's in his dressing room.
Drunk.
He's taking a nap.
I'm going to see what
kind of an nap he's taking.
- I don't think so.
- Yeah, better let him rest.
He's got to be ready
for a run-through in an hour.
Can he make it?
He'll make it.
Look, I know it's none of my business,
but will you tell them to go easy on him?
I mean, it ain't been his best day.
OK.
Is he OK?
He's all right.
You should have seen her...
12 and already a heartbreaker.
So what did he say to her?
He never got out of the car.
And he don't say another
word for 86.4 miles.
I clocked him.
I didn't look in the rear view, neither.
I give him his privacy.
All right, we open
on a tight to King and Cubby.
And then we widen out...
We're set to open the house.
15 minutes, everyone, 15 minutes.
How you doing, Alan?
Look, I don't want you
to worry about a thing...
Bad rehearsal, good show.
We've got a great cast.
We got a great crew, and it always works.
Just remember, we're
going to have fun, right?
And you, you look great.
What's he wearing this for?
The musketeer sketch.
You in the right outfit?
I am.
Then what am I doing in this?
I don't know.
Wait, which sketch is first?
The first sketch that I'm
in is the musketeers sketch.
I'm in that, too.
OK, I'm in the wrong outfit.
And look how I find out.
I've got to find out from this guy.
Who were the geniuses who
are supposed to tell me
which sketch comes first on my show,
and which outfit I'm supposed to be in?
Where are they?
Somebody tell me what sketch comes first!
Wardrobe!
Lil!
Listen to this.
He thinks he's in the wrong costume.
Every week, same
thing... he's so crazy.
God.
Somebody help me with my costume?
Take it off!
No!
- Come on, take it off!
- No, leave me alone!
The Hijack sketch!
What, what, take what off?
The Hijack sketch comes first.
Which one?
The Hijack sketch.
It comes first.
I knew it.
I knew it, Leo.
Don't worry about a thing, pal.
Fine, OK.
- I knew it.
- Yeah, yeah.
Good.
California?
You can't write comedy in California.
It's not depressing enough.
You look great.
How do you feel?
I feel surprisingly well, Stone.
Thank you.
So well, that I am going
to make a prediction.
Now, usually, it takes me two
or three takes just to warm up.
But tonight, I predict, we'll
get it on the first take.
We always get it on the first take...
We have to.
You do?
Sure, this is live television.
Live?
Live.
What does 'live' mean?
It means at the exact moment
you're cavorting and leaping
around that stage over there,
20 million people are seeing it.
Wait a minute.
Mr. Swann, you're white.
You mean it all goes into the camera lens
and then just spills out
into people's houses?
Yeah.
Why did nobody have the goodness
to explain this to me before?
It's nothing to
worry about, Mr. Swann.
Our audiences are great.
Audience, what audience?
Audience?
You knew there was an audience.
What did you think those seats were for?
I haven't performed in front
of an audience for 28 years.
Audience?
I played a butler.
I had one line!
I forgot it.
Look, don't worry.
This is going to be easy.
For you, maybe, not for me.
I'm not an actor, I'm a movie star!
Five minutes to air.
Ready for the Boss Hijack sketch.
Shut up!
Look, you can do it!
I need time to think.
Holy mother.
I need time to think!
Is that think or drink?
Yes!
He's got the jitters.
Ladies and gentlemen, a scant
second ago, Alan Swann had
a full-fledged anxiety attack.
An inch away from a
complete nervous breakdown,
and this one has the nerve to
describe it as 'the jitters'!
What are you doing?
Drinking and leaving.
There he goes again.
The musketeers sketch
is on after the Hijack sketch.
I'm not doing the muscatel sketch.
The musketeer sketch.
I'm not doing either!
Wasn't that Alan Swann leaving?
Obviously, he's still in
the throes of 'the jitters.'
Get out of my way, Sy.
Not until you pay up.
Opening dancers.
Benjy, what happened?
Swann's gone.
Can't speak, talk later.
You little smart-ass
son of a bitch bastard!
You're through here!
I'm telling King!
Sy!
Where's KC?
Everything OK?
Good.
Thank you, Harmonaires.
Thank you.
This is places, people.
Come on, people, let's hurry up.
Dancers, opening dancers, you should
be in your starting places.
Hurry along, thank you.
Who are you?
Yeah.
You're Phil somebody, right?
Yeah, I know you.
Go ahead.
You're doing a good job, Phil.
Sy, Sy, I'm sorry.
Help! Help!
Help!
We need some help here.
Look, Sy, you shouldn't
sneak up on a guy like that.
I know you can't hear me,
pal, but when you wake up,
I'm going to give you a nice raise.
Get him some first aid.
What a putz.
Terrible, terrible.
Alfredo!
Alfredo.
Alfredo, I... you're not Alfredo.
Mr. Swann.
My god, it's Stoneberger.
Will you ever let me alone?
As soon as you finish the show.
I'm not doing the show.
I want to go to the Waldorf!
You have to do the show.
If you don't, they'll deport you.
It doesn't matter.
That's a sad sight.
You're a sadder sight.
All you end up doing is making
anyone who cares for you
unhappy.
You know what they
say about me, Stoneberg.
You can depend on Alan Swann.
He will always let you down.
Did you tell Tess that?
That's right.
You couldn't get out of the car.
Alfie, take this bum to the Waldorf.
Ladies, ladies, let's go, let's go.
Nancy, you have a nice show.
Sy, didn't I tell you not to sneak up...!
Mr. Rojeck wanted
you to have that.
And that.
We have 10 seconds to go.
Just in case anybody has to...
Nine, eight, seven, six, five...
This is NBC, the
National Broadcasting Company.
Cue music, ready one.
Up, ready two.
Cue announcer.
Two!
Ladies and gentlemen,
it is Saturday night at 8:00.
The National Broadcasting
Company presents.
"The Comedy Cavalcade."
82, 81...
Starring King
Kaiser with his special guest
star, Alan Swann!
Now let's roll film.
Take it!
When you eat lunch too
quickly, as this fellow had,
then you're apt to be cranky,
'cause your stomach feels bad.
Stone.
I'm afraid.
That's why couldn't get out of the car
to see my Tess, my child.
Alan Swann, afraid?
"The Defender of the Crown"?
"Captain From Tortuga"?
"The Last knight of the Round Table"?
Those are movies, damn you!
Look at me.
I'm flesh and blood,
life-size, no larger.
I'm not that silly goddamned hero.
I never was.
To me, you were.
Whoever you were in those movies,
those silly goddamn
heroes meant a lot to me.
What does it matter
if it was an illusion?
It worked.
So don't tell me this
is you, life-size.
I can't use you life-size.
I need Alan Swann's as
big as I can get them.
And let me tell you something.
You couldn't have convinced me the way
you did unless somewhere in
you, you hat that courage.
Nobody's that good an actor.
You are that silly goddamned hero.
Keep it down, back
here, we're on the air!
Come back, go get some help!
You're fired!
Boss Hijack!
- Who owns the gray '51 DeSoto?
- The new guy...
Harry.
You parked in Boss Hijack's spot.
You better move.
What the hell is that?
Help!
You're lucky we're on the second floor...
It slowed him down.
You're very lucky we're
on the second floor,
it really slowed him down.
One, where's King?
Cue King.
Cue him.
Well, what's it going to do?
Slow him down.
Murder!
Holy, Jesus.
Boss Hijack...
One!
What is this?
What's happening?
Three!
Don't come in here.
Two!
One!
What's happening?
What the hell is happening?
What the hell's happening?
Rojeck's men are killing King.
What is Swann doing in the balcony?
Get a light on him.
In the
balcony... he's in the balcony.
Take three... good!
Porthole!
Swann?
Will you hold my sword?
Thank you very much.
The police.
You heard me.
Loosen up on three,
loosen up and... three!
God, this makes me happy.
Two!
Do as I told you!
What took you so long?
Ladies and gentlemen, Alan Swann.
Two.
And one.
The way you see him here, like this,
this is the way I like to remember him.
I think if you had asked Alan
Swann what was the single most
gratifying moment in his life,
he might have said this one,
right here.
The next day, I drove up to
Connecticut with him and Alfie.
This time he knocked on the door.
And when he and Tess saw each other,
it was like they'd never been apart.
Like Alfie says, with Swann,
you forgive a lot, you know?
I know.