My mother always said,
"Follow your dreams
and you'll always be happy."
My father always said,
"Don't listen to your mother.
She's not a well woman."
But she was right.
And these dreams
have brought me
On this particular day
To the beautiful country
of Romania.
Dad doesn't approve
of what I do,
So when I told him I was going
to Romania on business,
he said, "I went to Romania
once. I hated it."
I said, "Dad,
that was world war II.
There were Nazis
shooting at you."
He said, "Yeah,
but you get a feel."
But it's beautiful here.
It's got valleys
and castles,
Way too much cheese
and towns whose names roll off
your tongue like poetry.
OK, so it's a little
off Broadway,
but it's where I got to be.
Blimchuck. I have
to find Blimchuck.
Idea? No?
Blim--blim--where
movie--we're making--
See, I made a--I came here
through Flukshoon,
And then I had
to make a left by Peel
to get to blim-Blimchuck?
No?
Does it look like
I don't know where I'm going?
Well, I do.
Just not how to get there.
Which is the story
of my life, actually.
And the reason why
My wife and I are separated.
Am I getting ahead of myself?
Yeah, I do that.
Blimchuck?
Blim--do you know
where Blimchuck is?
That was... smart.
So, why am I here?
What do I do?
Well, I'll give you a hint.
It's called
by several names.
Animal names, actually.
Some say leech.
Some say vulture.
Some even say
scum-sucking pig.
No, I'm not a lawyer.
I'm an agent.
Yeah. Ever since I was
a kid, give me 5 minutes,
I could talk anybody
into doing anything.
Jesus Christ.
You're absolutely right,
Samuel.
This is delicious.
And I've been missing it
all these years.
So, about my bar mitzvah.
Anything you say.
And that's what it takes
to handle talent.
The power of persuasion.
When you're dealing
with a sensitive artist,
you have to inspire trust.
Cut the crap!
Jay, I told you.
I know I told you.
You told me
it was a club date.
It is a club date.
It's a club
and it's a date.
It's just booked
for a special occasion.
It's a wedding!
In the daytime.
Jay and the Americans
doing a wedding!
We're following
a limbo contest!
Listen to me.
My biggest thrill is
discovering someone special
And taking them
as far as they can go,
Like my new singer,
who, trust me,
Is going to be
the next Whitney Houston.
Nissan is the car
That you love
To drive
All right, so the auto show
isn't exactly Carnegie hall,
But if you want to make it
in show business,
You gotta pay your dues.
You can't do that.
That's the third time
in the last couple of months
That you've tried
to cancel my credit card.
Come on, I'm leaving
on a very important
business trip to Europe
and I need
that credit card.
My secretary sent that cheque
2 weeks ago.
She did--
Carol, you sent
that check, didn't you?
Shit, yeah.
See that? 2 weeks ago.
The fact that
it wasn't easy to get here
Makes it that much sweeter.
All the sacrifice
and the time away from home
And when they put my star
On the Hollywood Walk of Fame,
I'm going to thank my son,
who never lost faith in me.
Nick, don't look
at me that way.
I've got everything
riding on this.
It's my actor in a big movie.
Then I'm gonna take him down
to the Cannes film festival,
And all the big boys
are gonna be there.
Schwarzenegger,
Van Damme,
Stallone, you know?
Seagal--
Steven Seagal?
Yeah. You like him?
He's really scary.
I mean, in real life.
How do you know that?
I saw it on
Entertainment Tonight.
That's all TV garbage.
They make that stuff up.
Wow, so, do you think
you can sign him?
I'm a little hot
right now with Justin,
so you never know.
So my dad could be
Steven Seagal's agent?
Yeah.
And why not?
Because anything's
possible now.
It's just what I was
telling my wife Serena
before I left.
This is a big client
in a big movie.
It's the beginning
of a roll for me.
Nothing ever changes
anything, Sam.
We have been separated a year.
It's still your work,
your work, your work.
Nicky understands that.
Yeah, meanwhile I'm the one
Who goes to
father-and-son night.
You know,
his science project melts
before you ever see it.
Look, look,
he's reading Variety,
so he's got something
to talk to you about
when you call.
Serena... come on.
I love him
and he knows that.
Sam, people know
you love them
when you put their needs
ahead of your own.
So, we talked it over
and like 2 rational people,
we came up with a solution.
Sam, I'm moving to Chicago.
What?
I'm sorry.
It's about Nicky.
You know, he needs
more family support
and my folks can really
help with that.
We'll move in with them.
And he's not doing
so well in school.
They have this great tutorial
programme back there...
Or let's just talk
about the fact
I--I can't get an acting job
in New York anymore, so...
I'm gonna teach drama
at my old high school.
I'm sorry.
I really need to do this.
So, that's my life
and the reason
I'm in Romania--
Broke, separated
and plugged up with cheese.
I discovered an actor
who's gonna turn it all around.
His name is Justin Allen,
my first client in a movie,
and the rest, my friends,
is soon to be legend.
This is so exciting.
What is?
To be here.
Big movie.
Oh, yeah.
And I hear that
Justin's doing good.
Good? Great!
Really?
Oh, the camera loves him.
I'm telling you,
they applauded the dailies.
I've never seen
anything like it.
Partlow!
Is there a problem, sir?
No. I'm screaming
for my health.
Have you read the script
for this movie recently?
The description
of the villain?
Well, I--
It says, right in
the stage directions.
It says--Stephanie?
Stephanie!
It says, "And there
on the hill...
"stands the dreaded
barbarian army
"led by a villain
so ferocious
"that the entire
Christian army turns
"and runs...
save one boy,
"whose heroism
can be measured
By the enormity
of the foe he faces."
That was very good.
So, what the hell is this?
"A villain so fierce
he makes an entire army
turn and run"?
Partlow...
what were you thinking?
Be scary.
Stephanie,
get them out of here.
He gave a great audition,
Larry.
It's not like
we didn't try.
We saw at least 100 guys--
Then see 500,
OK? See 10,000.
See every guy in this
godforsaken country,
'cause if this scene
doesn't work,
then you don't work
ever...
in this town again.
In Blimchuck?
Excuse me?
Sorry. Sammy Kamin.
I'm Justin Allen's agent.
Welcome.
Thank you.
Justin is brilliant.
He's the only good thing
in this whole
messed-up picture.
Thank you.
The camera loves him.
He's gonna have
a hell of a career...
unlike you.
Last night,
I spit up blood.
Really?
Yeah.
Where's Justin?
You're firing me?
Yeah. Well...
I'm sorry.
I discovered you.
You weren't even
thinking about acting
when I found you.
You were delivering
my newspapers.
I got you this movie.
I--I named you!
My name was always Justin.
Schmell.
Justin Schmell.
I think they named
their town here after you.
Sam, I think what Justin
is trying--
Hey, dad, dad, please.
I feel bad...
but, honestly,
I think
I can do better.
You think you can do
better than me?
I met some people
from a big agency.
Which one?
Does it really matter?
Justin, we're
ready for you.
Look, I have to go.
No. Hey, hey, hold it.
Hold it a second.
You seriously think that
you can do better than me?
I brought you your
favourite ice-cream cake.
I packed it in dry ice.
It sat on my lap
the entire trip.
I can't have any more kids
because of this cake,
And you think that
you can do better than me?
Well, guess again,
Mr. Schmell.
Justin, our camera's ready.
OK.
Hold it, hold it,
Justin, please.
Come on,
what are you saying?
Don't do this.
For the sake
of your career.
You'll get lost
at a big agency.
They got everything but a heart.
Come on, don't--you don't
want to do this, do you?
Hey, look, Sammy,
I'm really sorry...
But, hey, good luck
with everything else.
They grow up so fast,
don't they?
Hey, Don.
Yeah?
You're next.
Goddamn it.
I don't believe this.
Didn't see that one coming!
Oh, shit!
No! No!
Oh, come on, god,
just give me 5 minutes,
Please!
Oh, it's not how
I want to die.
Come on, god, please.
Can you hear me?
Hey! This is just
a negotiation.
Work with me here,
please!
We're just 2 guys
talking, you know?
I don't accept this.
I don't want to die
like this.
I have a son.
I don't want him to think
that I'm a failure.
Please.
Well, there's good news
and there's bad news.
The bad news is...
I'm dead.
The good news is
that god himself
picked me up
and personally carried me
to heaven.
Aw, shit.
Wrong heaven.
Definitely wrong heaven.
Hello?
My name is Sam Kamin.
Formerly Kaminski,
if you get my drift.
I'm in the wrong place.
Is there a concierge
or somebody I can talk to
because there's been a mistake.
Does anyone here speak English?
Perfect.
Either I'm in heaven
or the Miami airport.
It is heaven, sir...
Heaven on earth.
You're at the Ministeria
Monterritomaoui.
I am Monsignor Papesco.
Monsignor?
Oh, thank god.
I thought I was dead.
As did we,
but you are not,
by the grace of god.
Yes. I saw him.
I saw god.
He appeared to me.
He pulled me
out of the wreck.
I was in a car crash
and I looked up,
and these huge hands
reached down
and pulled me out.
That's it.
I'm so stupid.
I was a caesarean.
It was a flashback.
No, no, it didn't feel
like a flashback.
It felt real.
God is real, my son.
But why?
Why did he save me?
This is an important question.
You should seek the answer.
Where?
Each man's search is his own.
It's fate, I guess.
If things are meant to be,
they're meant to be.
Can I ask you
a personal question?
I mean, you choose
to live like this, right?
What's with these clothes?
The robes are
kind of comfortable.
It's the no-underwear thing
that I--
I don't understand.
I'm not used to being exposed
to the wind like this.
You know,
I'd like to be alone.
I'd like to walk alone.
I feel like
I just want to...
walk alone.
OK?
Thank you.
God...
It's Sammy Kamin.
You know,
we haven't spoken
since I did Fiddler
in high school,
but there's something
I really have to know.
Why me?
Why, with all the good people
in the world to save,
did you choose me?
God...
Come on...
If you're up there,
please...
give me a sign.
Thank you.
Oh, keep talking, baby.
Daddy's coming.
I'm coming! I'm coming!
Don't hang up!
Where the hell's my car?
Who's this? Oh, Hertz?
I don't know when I can
have the car back. I--
I'll call you back.
Either god is in
the salvage business,
or Bigfoot took my car.
Hey!
Somebody!
If you say
fee fie fo fum,
I'm gonna make in my pants.
Sam?
Max.
You saved my life.
It was you.
Thank you.
Sam! Sam! Sam!
Samoh mio!
My name is Maximus Sanferescu.
I'm so happy you're well.
You speak English.
English, German,
Francais, Latin.
Now I speak to Sam.
Hello, Sam.
Sam, hello!
You eat.
I'm not that hungry.
I had a late gruel.
Eat.
I'll just pick.
Sam.
Tonight we speak
of many things.
We speak of Mr.
William Shakespeare.
Shakespeare?
You know who he is?
Sure. He wrote
a lot of good stuff.
To be or not to be.
Yes! Yes!
What light through
yonder window breaks?
Very good, Sam.
To thine own self
be true.
Hey, to Mr. S.
We do more.
More?
More.
OK.
What is a man?
What has he got?
If not himself,
then he has not.
Shakespeare?
Sinatra.
If a man begin with certainty,
He shall end in doubt--
Bacon.
When a problem comes along,
You must whip it,
whip it good. Devo.
I like it!
We do more.
Where did you learn
all this stuff?
The monsignor teach me.
Are you a monk?
No. I like to talk
too much.
The monsignor say
better for me
to help the monks.
Sam, read to me in English.
Read to you?
You know, it's
a little late
and I'm tired, so...
I think I'm gonna go.
Stay.
Please.
Another time.
I mean, I'm mending.
So I'm gonna go.
Listen, thanks
for saving my life.
I wouldn't know what to tip
for a thing like that.
So I'll--I'll
see you around.
Go, Sam.
I'll tell you what.
I'll come back tomorrow.
OK? And we'll
have some fun.
We'll go into town.
I'll buy you lunch.
I cannot leave the monastery.
Why?
Because last time
when I go to the city,
people follow me.
They throw rocks at me.
They call me devil grotesque.
What does that mean?
The freak from hell.
Do you have family?
My mother and my father
bring me here when I was 15.
They left me.
Why?
They say I'm possessed
by the devil
Because I grow too much
too fast.
Do you ever see them?
No.
They try to come
many times,
but I will not see them.
Maximus.
Max.
Maybe your parents were
trying to protect you.
You know, I mean,
people...
threw rocks at you.
They ran away from you.
They--they shouted...
devil grotesque...
just because
all they know...
...is what they see.
And what do they see?
They see the biggest,
hugest,
scariest-looking guy
in the whole wide--
Sam, you have stopped talking.
Do you still want me
to read to you?
You read to me?
Hey, you saved my life.
It's the least I can do.
What does that mean?
You are my friend.
"Shall I compare thee
to a summer's day?
"Thou art more lovely
and more temperate.
"Rough winds do shake
the darling buds
of may..."
So here I am in Romania,
reading bedtime stories.
Usually you read bedtime stories
about a giant.
But I'm reading them
to a giant.
And as I watched him sleep,
it all became clear.
I finally realized
what god had saved me for.
Yeah?
I got him.
I got the guy.
What guy?
The villain.
He's enormous.
How big?
Try this. 7 1/2 feet.
But he can play 8.
Can he talk?
Talk? He recites Shakespeare.
Do you mind? This is
a private call, OK?
And if you see the waitress,
tell her I'd like
a little more decaf.
It sounds too good
to be true.
Partlow, you can't
let this guy get away.
He's unbelievable.
He's once-in-a-lifetime--
Partlow!
How soon can you
get him here?
I'll have him
for you Thursday.
Come on, you sweaters.
Max, I gotta tell you,
I love this simple life.
Yes, I'm now
a man of the land.
But after a while,
doesn't this get
a little boring for you?
What are you gonna do
with the rest of your life,
Mooch around
with the animals here?
How much can you
play with the cows
and talk to the sheep?
Come on.
I like the animals. They
don't look twice at me.
I understand that, Max,
But there's a big world
out there.
Places to go,
people to tower over.
Listen, you should not
hide away from it
Just because you think
you're too big.
I can help you.
No, I can.
I can help you do something
much more interesting,
much more exciting.
No, Sam.
I told you,
I cannot leave from here.
This is my home.
Here. This one.
I'll get this.
Got it!
Here it is.
OK.
You ready for the dismount?
Yes.
I don't like heights.
This is why I stopped
growing in fifth grade.
Here we go.
Just another few inches.
OK, Max.
Max?
Yes?
Never mind.
Great.
All right,
here you go.
Thank you, Sam.
No problem.
You do for me,
I do for you.
You lift me up,
I pick you an apple.
You save my life,
I show you the world.
Ba ba bing,
Ba ba boom.
What?
Ba ba bing,
Ba ba boom. Say it.
Ba ba boom.
Great. OK.
Hey, Max, listen.
I know this is gonna
sound crazy,
but I'm just gonna say it.
I could put you in the movies.
What is movies?
Shakespeare wrote stories, right?
Hamlet, Othello,
Henry V.
I like that one.
A lot of fighting.
Don't be scared.
I'm not scared.
When you read these stories,
do you see what the
characters are doing
in your mind?
Yes.
Great.
That's perfect.
See, movies are...
they-they're stories.
That's all.
Big stories on a screen.
Light, colour,
music, sound.
They're lifelike,
only bigger and better.
You love these movies?
Yes. And that's my job.
I find people to be in movies.
They pay for this?
They're so stupid.
You've been talking to
my father, haven't you?
Let's go, Sammy.
I don't want to be late.
Late for what?
There's nothing to be late for.
More gruel?
More churning?
Yeah, can't be late
for churning.
The room is spinning.
You're a little tipsy.
Ah, tipsy.
Wait.
Have another one.
Come on.
The monsignor say,
one glass for eating,
one glass for sleeping.
This is my last night here.
Come on, live a little.
There you go. OK.
OK, Max, last thing
about being an actor.
I know what you're thinking.
You're thinking,
"I'm too tall, Sammy."
Right? "I'm not
the right type, Sammy."
But let me tell you something.
On a movie screen,
everybody is 40 feet tall.
No!
If you want to be
an actor, say the word.
No. No more actor,
movie, 40 feet.
So stupid.
All right, that's it.
I'll stop.
I tried.
I'll just go back to America,
And I'll leave you alone.
America.
That's my home.
America is very far.
Oh, yeah.
Galoop is in America.
Who's Galoop?
Never mind.
Wait, wait, wait a second.
What's Galoop?
Galoop is where she lives.
She goes so fast.
Galoop, galoop,
galoop, galoop.
Wait, are you
talking about a horse?
Lillianna.
Hey, look at--
is that you?
Yes.
Who is that, your sister?
No.
The girl I love.
This is from
last time I see her.
We grow up together
in the village of Lunca.
She kissed me.
I am 14.
Behind the fountain
of the virgin
at the end of the road
near my house.
22 years, Sam.
I can still feel
her lips on mine.
I send her letters.
I make her poems.
But I can never, ever
see my Lillianna again.
"Lillianna Otarro,
231 Desert View Place,
Gallup, New Mex--"
Galoop.
"My dearest Lillianna,
"the monsignor has
taught me English now
"so that I can write
I love you
"in the language
of your new land.
"He has also taught me
to love god,
"who I trust to protect you.
"I can no longer
send you photos of me
because it is not allowed."
"But remember always
the boy whose soul
will love you forever."
"Maximus."
What does that mean?
We will always have the sunset,
Lillianna and me.
You could have more, Max.
Now listen to me.
Listen carefully.
I can walk away from here
and leave you forever
to talk to the cows,
play with the monks.
Whatever you want to do,
that's your decision.
But before I do,
I want you to do
something for me.
And please don't say no.
Because what you decide next
Will determine whether or not
You'll ever see
Lillianna again.
All right? Great.
This is bad.
It's OK. No one will be
in there but us.
Are you sure?
Promise. I told them
that you're a very famous
American film star.
You want to watch
the movie alone. Like Elvis.
Who's Elvis?
Never mind. Come on,
it-it's starting.
This is very bad.
Don't worry about a thing.
OK?
Let me see. Perfect.
When you pass
the guy at the door,
You say,
"Thanks, man,"
'cause that's what
movie stars say.
Let's go to the movies.
This is very,
very, very bad.
Don't worry about a thing.
Why I listen to you?
Come on.
It is my great honour.
Thanks, man.
He is so big.
Larger than life, Max,
Just like you.
Once you're up there,
you never die.
You live forever
on the silver screen.
You don't want
to see Lillianna
Because she doesn't know
what you look like,
am I right?
You never told her,
did you?
Once you're up there,
the whole world
would love you.
And if the whole world
loves you,
how could she not?
No more devil grotesque.
Now, el supremo.
Il huge-o movie stario.
The newspapers will say,
"Romanian superstar
comes to America
to reunite with the
woman that he loves."
Max, trust me.
Cut!
More Christians!
We're still rolling.
I said--
Oh, my god.
Good morning.
Big enough for you, sir?
Vanquish mine enemies.
The guy's spectacular.
I mean, look at him.
He's huge.
You want him?
Yeah, we want him.
You're making the
right decision. Great.
Here are my terms.
5-day guarantee
at double scale
and a pair of first-class
tickets to America.
Are you crazy?
He sits on a horse.
He says one line.
OK, one day at scale,
one coach ticket to America.
How about no chance?
Do you know what
makes a hero?
The villain.
The villain makes the hero.
The size of the villain
determines the size
of the hero.
Without Goliath,
David is some punk
throwing rocks.
Am I making sense?
He's making sense.
The sight of my guy
on that horse
saying that line--
what is that line?
Vanquish mine enemies.
Unbelievable.
I wrote it.
Fantastic.
Pay him what he wants.
Oh, the Schmells.
Hello, Schmells.
I thought I fired you.
I have other clients.
No, you don't.
Run along. I'm in the middle
of a negotiation here
and you've got to
get ready for puberty.
So, what is scale here?
What do we get?
A day, 70,000.
70,000?!
Romanian money.
It's about $100.
I'll throw in a plane ticket.
Deal. Thank you very much.
Cut, cut, cut, cut!
That's not the rehearsal.
I need a charge, gentlemen!
A charge!
This is their hill,
And you want it to be
your hill.
Charge up it!
We got a problem.
What's the problem?
He can't get on the horse.
What do you mean,
he can't get on the horse?
What I mean is,
he can't get his leg
over the damn horse.
We're gonna have to bring
a winch in here,
lift him up
and lower him on it.
You OK with that, Max?
No, I cannot do this.
I'm very scared.
You're gonna be fine.
Really, it's gonna be OK.
I gotta get him back
to wardrobe.
They're going nuts.
OK, go with
the nice girl.
There you go.
It's gonna be OK, Max.
Be all right.
Please, don't tell me
there's a problem,
Because I'm developing
an aneurysm.
It's OK.
What we need
is something
to loosen him up.
You know, just a relaxer.
That I can do.
Hello.
Nick, how are you?
Dad!
Did I wake you up?
No. I'm just leaving
for school. Are you back?
No, I'm...
still in Romania.
But I'm coming home soon,
And I got so much
to tell you.
Did you meet with Seagal?
No, not yet
but he promised me
that he'd do it.
That's too bad,
Because he's starting
a movie in Vegas.
Yeah, I read about it
in Variety.
A new movie?
Is it an action movie?
I'm guessing, dad.
Actually, I have to go.
Glen's picking us up.
Who's Glen?
He's my math teacher.
Mom went to high school
with him.
Oh, well, that's good.
He took us to a Bulls game.
Does he have good seats?
No.
Oh, good. Good.
Dad...
I don't like it out here.
I miss my friends.
I miss you.
Listen,
you're where you
have to be, Nick
and I'm where
I have to be.
Do you understand that?
I guess.
I gotta go.
He's honking.
The movie. Do you know
the name of the movie?
Coming to my birthday?
Of course I'll be there.
OK, the name of the movie
is Double or Nothing
and it starts shooting
in Vegas in a week. Bye.
Yes!
Quickly, quickly.
Max, I have new--
Hey, Sammy!
I'm no scared no more.
Oh, no.
I'm big singer.
Right.
Everybody looks so tiny
from here.
What did you give him?
I told them to
bring him a bottle.
You gave him a whole bottle?
A whole bottle?
Yeah.
He's not supposed--
I'd love it if he could
stop laughing.
He's supposed to be mean.
Hey, boss.
I'm flying.
The flying he's enjoying,
'cause he flew once.
He did Peter Pan in stock
with Jamie Farr as Hook.
It was a fabul--
Just shut him up
and get him on the horse.
Gotcha.
You look fabulous
up there, Max.
OK, one line.
Just say the one line.
OK, you ready?
It's magic time.
OK?
Here we go.
OK.
There he is.
OK, stunt people,
step up.
Ready to charge and fight.
Justin, are you ready
for your cue?
All right,
lock it up!
Sound!
Roll camera.
Giant, giant.
Raise sword.
Action.
To be or not to be,
that is the question.
I'll get it.
Max...
Vanquish mine enemies, Max.
Vanquish mine enemies.
Say it.
Look mean.
OK.
OK, he's back.
There he is.
He's all yours.
And...
Action.
Give him the line.
Vanquish mine enemies.
Say the line.
O god of battles!
Oh, shit.
Steel my soldiers' hearts,
possess them not with fear!
Pluck from them their hearts!
Cut it, cut it, cut it.
Cut!
What the hell was that?
I'm guessing Henry V.
Very good, Sam.
Henry V.
Listen, with
the right editor,
That's some good
stuff in there
where they can cut it--
I'm gonna roll this camera,
he's gonna say that line.
I don't care how
you get him to say it
but he's gonna say it,
because he's gonna sit on
that horse until morning.
Camera ready?
Camera ready to roll.
Max, this is it now.
You really have to do it
if you want to go to Galoop.
I don't feel well, Sam.
What's the matter?
I'm spinning.
Lock it up!
Sound! Roll camera!
Vanquish mine enemies, OK?
Very... very... tipsy.
Vanquish mine enemies.
Justin, ready for your cue.
Action!
Line!
For Lillianna, Max.
If you ever want
to see her again,
say the line!
Vanquish mine enemies!
Keep rolling!
Justin!
Begone, foul demon,
for I am the swordmaster!
Cut. Print.
Yes!
You did it, Max!
Did you see that?
No digital stuff,
no computer.
That's how my giant prepares.
That's his process.
You are an actor.
I feel better now.
You, sir...
are a genius.
Thanks, man.
Now we go see Lillianna?
Yeah.
Can we see Galoop, Sam?
No, Max,
not from here.
But that's my hometown.
Incredible!
See, Max, New Yorkers
have seen everything.
No one here looks
twice at you. See?
What is that building?
Max, that's the
Empire State Building,
one of the biggest
buildings in New York.
That's where King Kong
got killed.
King Kong?
Oh, it's a fantastic movie
about this sleazy promoter
who captures this huge gorilla,
brings it to New York,
where he goes nuts
'cause he loves this girl.
And...
Lousy movie, sad,
it was terrible.
How he got killed?
It was a climbing accident.
He was-- you know what?
Forget I brought it up.
Come on, we got things to do.
You haven't cast
the part yet, right?
When's the latest I can
get him to Las Vegas?
Friday?
Oh, I--I could get him
to Las Vegas by Friday.
Trust me.
Don't cast this part
until you've seen my giant.
Believe me,
he's that special.
OK? All right, I'll
get him there by Friday.
Good-bye.
All right, Max.
We gotta go.
How much?
$52.50.
$52.50?!
How many hot dogs
did he have?
Well, 20 hot dogs--
20 hot--?!
I was on the phone
for a minute,
for god's sake!
And one soda.
Jeez, this is like
owning a Saint Bernard.
Yeah, the dog lady married
the alligator man this weekend.
Well, you know,
she's a bitch
and he works for scale.
No, no. I--
it's a joke, yeah.
Oh, no. They're doing well.
Listen, I gotta
call you back, all right?
An old friend
just walked in.
Hey, Eddie.
How ya doing?
Hey, Sam.
Long time.
Hey, you look terrific.
You look the same.
So what do you need
from the novelty world?
Listen, I--what?
I just signed
some singing pigs.
They're amazing.
Now, who would have thought
a beautiful tenor voice
Would come out of a body
like that?
Who would have thought?
Unbelievable.
Maybe some other time, huh?
All right, OK.
Eddie, listen,
I need a favour.
I need some work
right away,
like today right away,
For a new client of mine.
Very special guy.
Right up your alley.
I'm taking him to Las Vegas
to meet Steven Seagal
on a movie.
Come on.
No, this is on the level.
All right,
what's he do?
Well, he's big.
They're all big.
No, I mean he's...
he's really big.
This is an amazing story.
He's Romanian.
Lived most of his life
in a monastery.
Monastery?
In his hometown,
they call him
devil grotesque.
What's that mean?
I don't know.
Something from hell...
but whatever it is,
it's not good.
You got a picture?
I got better than that.
Max?
Say hello
to my old friend Eddie.
Eddie, this is Max.
Hello, Eddie.
I just wet myself.
All right.
Did I tell ya?
Jesus, he's got
a head like luggage.
He's got his own climate,
for Christ's sake.
He's unbelievable.
He's amazing.
Wait a second.
This is perfect.
I got a great job for him.
Yeah, where?
- Cleveland.
- Cleveland?
Yeah, yeah.
They're looking for a monster
to wrestle a bunch
of circus midgets.
We got him a guy but
nowhere near as big as this.
That's not what
I'm looking for.
I thought money's what
you're looking for.
2,500 a night?
My giant doesn't wrestle.
Well, neither do they.
They fake it, Sam.
I mean, your guy's
an actor, right?
Yeah, but this is ridiculous.
Oh, oh, oh. I get it.
This is beneath you.
This from a man
who represented a guy
who hand-farted the
William Tell overture.
Hey, he was an artist.
This guy is a religious man.
I'm not doing that to him.
Sam, I thought
you needed the money.
I do, I'm strapped.
But there are other ways
To make it, Eddie.
Hey, you're right.
The post office is hiring.
See ya around.
Yeah, I'll see ya.
Say hello to Steven Seagal.
Give him my best.
Here we go, Max.
How's that, better?
Yes.
OK.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Sam?
Yeah?
Why are you being
so nice to me?
I like you, Max.
You're my friend.
Do you have many friends?
A few.
And you put them in the movies?
No, Max.
It's my job.
I do it 'cause it
makes me feel good.
If I can make you
into someone important,
it makes me important.
Do you understand that?
OK, good night.
You have woman?
Go to sleep, Max.
She's gone.
Yeah.
And you have child.
Nick.
And mother and father.
Oh, yeah.
You'll meet them tomorrow.
And they love you?
Yes.
And this doesn't make
you feel important?
It would make me
feel important.
Thank you, Sam,
for liking me.
OK, Max. Here it is.
The house I grew up in,
Casa de Guilt.
He's here.
Sammy?
Sammy.
Hiya, ma.
I shoulda made more.
You have a nice appetite.
I like that.
He saved my life, pop.
Yeah? Good.
Did you see how he sucked
down that herring?
Like a pelican in one of those
National Geographic specials.
Pass him the stuffed cabbage.
No, grandma,
not the cabbage.
He gets gas,
he could wipe out
3 of the 5 boroughs.
Jerry, come on.
Don't be stupid.
Don't say things
like that, huh?
Sam, don't call
your nephew stupid.
Jerry's funny.
Why don't you sign him up?
He'd be funnier than
half of your clients.
So how is your business, Sam?
I'm glad you brought
it up, Uncle Nate.
There is a big opportunity
That has just come up--
Do you know Bruce Willis?
I'm talking to
Uncle Nate here, Jerry.
It's just a simple question, Sam.
Yes, I know Bruce Willis.
I happen to be
heavily invested
in Planet Hollywood.
What did you do, run up
a big bar tab there?
Oh, nice.
Funny, pop.
That's very funny.
Anyway, this enormous
opportunity's come up--
You know, my cousin Aaron
was also quite tall.
Do you mind, mom?
Please, I'm trying
to discuss business
with Uncle Nate.
I have a question
for your friend.
Yes, aunt Pearl.
I'm just curious.
How big is your--
Pearl!
Well, I'd like to know!
Would you get her out of here!
What did I do?
Don't we all want to know?
- No.
You must know.
I don't know!
Pearl, what's the matter with you?
I'm awfully sorry.
My sister-in-law's
a very lovely woman...
but she has a summer house on Pluto.
I go to Galoop.
He makes all
his own clothes, pop.
Yeah, he made this himself.
He made it?
Yeah. Guess what on.
An Obermeier, the old
pedal operated kind.
I collect Obermeiers.
Why don't you two
go downstairs?
You can show him
the sewing machines,
And I'll talk to Uncle Nate.
But it's not another loan.
This time, it's a very
good investment.
This guy is going
to be a very big star.
What's he gonna star in,
Death of a Giant Salesman?
I may sell Cadillacs,
but I'm not a schmuck.
All right.
Wait, wait, wait.
Forget the 10,000.
$5,000 would be great.
Please.
Sammy.
If you had told me
that your son
needed braces on his teeth,
I'd reach in my
pocket like lightning.
But look at yourself.
Where are you?
Where is your family?
You're running around
with a glandular case,
making a fool of yourself.
You're my favourite nephew
and I love you...
but enough already.
Enough.
Pearl, get the car!
Sammy?
Come here, come here.
Here, honey, take this.
Listen, it's almost $200.
Mom, mom, please,
I don't need your money.
We'll be fine.
No, no, please.
The Cleveland Municipal auditorium
And Paroni brothers
Sporting entertainment
Present...
Geek night!
We'll do this. We'll
make the money.
We'll go right to Las Vegas.
And Galoop?
Absolutely.
You're on, Sam.
Batman on steroids.
Oh, yeah. It's terrific.
It's great.
He's coming!
Yes, he's coming!
Are you ready for the geeks?
Geeks! Geeks! Geeks!
Go over to the ring, Max.
Geek! Geek! Geek!
Ladies and...
Gentlemen.
In this corner,
Standing 4 feet,
8 inches each,
which, when stacked
end to end,
Makes a total of 28 feet tall,
The 7... sweet little angels!
You're mine.
I'll rip that ugly mug
right off your shoulders,
you tall goon!
Look at this, Max.
See, they-- they just
keep rolling.
Just throw them around
and have a good time.
Have fun with them.
OK, Max? Are you OK?
Then we'll get the money,
we'll go to Las Vegas...
and galoop.
And in this corner...
your worst nightmare.
Direct from satan's toilet,
in his wrestling debut--
Mothers, hide your children!
From the horrifying...
devil grotesque,
the freak of hell!
What are this?!
It wasn't me.
You told them devil grotesque?!
I didn't!
I swear I didn't!
Hey, get over here.
What's the matter?
They love this.
You told them devil grotesque.
That's what you told me.
Yes, but not to tell them.
Oh, who cares?
He does. It hurts
his feelings.
Oh, yeah, like
he's so delicate.
Please, they're hurting him.
Oh, no, no, no.
He's just a great actor,
just like you said.
Bullshit! That's not
what we talked about.
I'm pulling him out.
No, you can't do that,
Sam. Wait a minute.
You see those fine
gentlemen down there?
What's up?
You have a contract
with them.
You break it
and they're gonna break
something of yours.
That's it. It's over.
No, Sam!
I'm pulling him out.
No more. It's over!
Over!
Ring that bell.
You told them devil grotesque?!
I did not.
I did not tell them.
We have a forfeit.
Devil grotesque cannot continue.
No devil grotesque.
Let's go!
Come on. These guys
are not happy with us.
Why did you tell them?
I did not tell them.
I told Eddie and...
You said trust me,
I trust you.
You can trust me, Max.
No, you tell this.
It's just words.
It doesn't mean anything.
It's like show business.
No, Sam! It's me!
Devil grotesque.
You believe this about me.
Max!
Max. Max!
You don't even know
where you're going.
I go home to Romania,
Not to see you never,
no more.
Max!
Come back here.
Come here.
Listen, that was my fault.
I take full responsibility.
Whatever you spent,
I'll pay you back.
I promise.
Get him back in the ring.
I can't do that.
Really?
Now find your freak
and get him back in there.
He's gone.
I'll get you
somebody else, OK?
Let's talk about this.
Just give me 5 minutes,
huh? Please?
Give him 5 minutes.
5 minutes.
Now you gonna fight,
freak?
Yes.
I'm sorry!
Vanquish mine enemies!
I asked god to forgive me
for raising my hand
in anger.
I'm sorry, Max.
I shot my mouth off about...
devil grotesque
and I'm really sorry.
I asked him
to forgive you, too.
What did he say?
He say OK.
Hey.
Dad!
Get over here.
Oh. Oh, Nick,
I'm so glad to see you.
Happy birthday.
It's not until next week.
But I brought you
an early present.
This is Max.
Hello, little Sammy.
Hi.
Listen, is mom home?
Yeah, she's inside.
Great. Listen,
why don't you two guys
play nicely together while
I talk to mom, all right?
OK, I'll be right back.
Hey, you guys want
to play now?
He's on my team.
Just a minute.
Hi.
I happened to be in Chicago
and thought I'd drop by.
What happened to your face?
Mickey Rourke.
Who's that?
Oh, that's my new client.
It's a long story.
Can I come in and
tell you about it?
I get you.
Come on, meet him.
Not right now.
Max is an amazing man.
Yeah, I'm sure.
Maybe later.
So who's Glen?
He's a nice guy.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah, he's just a nice guy.
What do you want, Sam?
Serena, listen.
I have to get him
to Las Vegas. My giant.
There's a movie
that's shooting there.
Nicky actually told me
about it.
I spoke to
the casting director.
If I can get Max there--
No money, Sam.
Did I say money?
What else would you
be talking about?
Not money. You did not
hear me say the words
"I want money."
I'd recognize my voice.
I did not say I want money.
I need the rings.
The rings.
They were my father's
and they were given to me.
For safekeeping.
To be given to your son.
They're called heirlooms.
I need to borrow them.
They're Nicky's.
I'm broke.
OK? I have nothing.
I am busted.
I'll get 'em back to you.
You know the funny thing, Sam,
I thought you came here
because you missed us.
That's why I thought
you came with...
your giant.
Serena, Serena.
I miss you.
Of course I miss you.
Mom?
Give dad the rings.
I don't need them.
You buy something, Sam?
Yeah, bus fare.
Taxi!
Come on.
An adult and a child
for Las Vegas, please.
I'm kidding.
2 for Las Vegas, please.
Galoop, Sam.
First Vegas, then Galoop.
But you say--
Max, please, please.
2 for Las Vegas.
Galoop.
Give us a second, please?
Come over here.
We have to go to Las Vegas first.
We go to Vegas first.
It's on the way to Galoop.
The movie is in Las Vegas,
And we don't want
to be messing around.
I want to see Lillianna first.
Sit down.
Are you famous yet?
I don't know.
What did we say?
We said you'd meet her
when you were famous.
That was the agreement.
When will I be famous?
OK, we'll call her.
OK? We'll call her.
We'll tell her
that you're here,
That you're on your
way to see her, OK?
We can do?
Max, this is just a letter.
This is just her address.
There's no phone number here.
We no can call?
We'll call information.
Right? We'll call Information.
Is she still living here?
When was the last time
she wrote to you?
She don't write.
She don't write?
No.
Never?
And you've been
writing to her for...
22 years.
In Galoop... in Gallup,
Miss Lillianna Otarro,
231 Desert View Place.
It's a good thing you have
a relationship with god, Max.
We may need his Rolodex.
What?
An L.J. Otarro
on Wonder View Terrace.
All right,
let's try that.
Could you connect me?
Thank you.
Max, don't get
your hopes up.
It may not be
the right person.
You never know about
these things, you know?
Hello.
Who's calling?
One second, please.
Do you want to talk?
No, no, no, no, no.
Is this Lillianna Otarro?
Yes.
Are you from Romania?
I have a giant surprise
for you.
I'm calling for your old
friend Maximus Sanferescu.
He's in Chicago right now
and yes, he is,
but he's on his way to
Las Vegas to be in a movie.
Yes, he's an actor.
Please hang up.
This is a recording.
He's crazy about you.
I agree.
He remembers that kiss.
Right, behind the
fountain of the virgin.
Well, you didn't forget
it either, did you?
Well, he would like
to come visit you.
Oh, that's a bummer.
Oh, for how long?
Couple of days.
Well, listen, Lillianna,
We will call you
and we'll--we'll hook up
in Gallup, OK?
It was lovely talking
to you, too, Lillianna.
I will tell him. OK.
All right. Good-bye.
Here.
She wants to see me?
Yes, but she's gonna be gone
for a couple of days.
But she want to see me?
Yeah, Max. How could
she not? Come on.
And the kiss, Sam?
What she say about the kiss?
That she'll never forget it.
Come on.
Oh, Sam.
Yep, that's what she said.
I'm so happy.
Isn't that nice?
- Sam?
- Yeah.
Tell me again. What
she say about the kiss?
Max, you know what she said.
That she never forget.
That's right.
Thank you.
Max? Max, wake up.
What?
I want you to see something.
Look.
It is miracle.
The miracle is we got here.
Wait till you see
the buffets, Max.
Do the words
"all you can eat"
mean anything to you?
Hey, hey, hey!
This is show business, Max.
And... cut!
That's a cut!
OK, great.
OK, come on, guys,
gather around.
Steven, that was really
great, but I think
We can do just a little
bit better, don't you?
No.
OK, that was perfect, everybody.
New deal.
We're moving on.
What do you mean,
"cast"?
It wasn't cast
a couple of days ago!
Please.
But I called!
We came all this way!
I asked specifically,
"Do you need a big villain?"
'Cause that's what I got!
I got the biggest!
We don't need, capisce?
Case closed.
- Can I at least show him to you?
- No.
Let me show him to the director.
Don't bother him.
We're in a meal penalty.
You tell me I'm wrong
and I go away.
But if Steven Seagal
finds out
That you blew this opportunity,
it's on your head.
How big is he?
Around 8 feet and he can act.
You got a script?
No lines.
The bad guy's just an action part.
Excuse me.
That's perfect, 'cause,
now, what do you need?
You need a big, scary guy
and that's what I have.
The biggest and scariest
guy of all time,
and he's sitting
right over there.
Max, stand up!
All the way up.
Don't slouch.
How about that, guys?
Big enough?
He's unbelievable!
Oh, yeah, you see?
He's big.
Mr. Seagal, this is...
a pleasure to meet you.
I'm Sam Kamin.
I'm Max the giant's agent.
You... have your
elbow in his salad.
Sorry.
Steven, what do you think
about him as the bad guy?
The fact of the matter is
that he's much bigger than me
and as you know,
that's not good.
- Good.
- May I, sir?
Isn't that actually the point?
I don't think so.
No, see, I have this theory
about heroes and villains--
I know. Look, let's
not forget about Roy.
I mean, the fact
of the matter is
we did offer him
the part.
That's right.
There's Roy.
Who's Roy?
Steven's best friend.
He's our head stuntman
and he's got the role.
Come on, he's a stuntman.
With all due respect,
probably a great one,
but now, stuntmen stunt.
He acts! My giant
can do Shakespeare!
Shakespeare.
Every word.
I've always wanted
to do Shakespeare.
You would be a great
Shakespearean actor.
Matter of fact,
you and Max together
in this movie...
would be great
doing Shakespeare together.
Can you see it?
No. This is
a story about a man
who's trying
to stop terrorists
from blowing up
the Las Vegas strip.
Now if you'll excuse me--
But, sir...
You don't see how Shakespeare
can fall into that script idea?
- No. - Oh, come on!
It's easy!
You got this huge villain,
the world's biggest terrorist.
He's huge.
- Scary.
- Oh, scary.
And he's planting bombs
all over the strip, right?
But he's sending
messages to you...
in Iambic pentameter.
Great.
If he can eliminate you...
with the Shakespeare...
See, he can be "to be"
and you are "not to be"
because he doesn't
want you to be.
Right.
But you have to stop that, see?
Because he loves Shakespeare
and blowing up stuff.
Max, do Henry V.
What?
Do Henry V!
He's...
You don't like it, Sam.
Remember?
We got to get back to work.
Wait, wait, wait,
wait a second.
Max, listen to me.
You got to do it
like you did before.
If you don't do it now,
you can kiss
Galoop good-bye.
Please! Now is the time--
Sammy was your name,
right? We got to go.
Please.
Do it.
O god of battles!
Steel my soldiers' hearts,
possess them not with fear!
For he who sheds
his blood with me
shall be my brother.
Screw Roy.
Roy is out.
Roy's gone.
OK. See you around.
Thank you very much, man.
Max, great!
Mr. Seagal, first of all,
Thank you from the bottom
of my heart. This is...
Will you just give me
5 minutes? You'd make me
the happiest man in the world.
You got it.
Hello?
Is this Nick Kamin?
Yeah. Who's this?
Hi. This is Steven Seagal.
How are you?
Nice try, dad, but his voice
is a little bit raspier.
No, this is
Steven Seagal, really.
Oh, really, Steve?
Great, 'cause I want to
tell you a couple of things.
You're a huge wimp
with a big, stupid ponytail.
Yeah, and have you ever
heard of acting lessons?
You really might
want to try taking some.
Oh, by the way,
when you talk,
try clearing the phlegm
out of your throat.
Just spit it up already.
Well...
Thank you very much.
You know, I can see
that your father's
raised you very well.
You're a very polite
young man
and I'm hoping that we can
get together someday soon.
Oh, pretty cool.
Hanging out with Stallone
so I can understand
you both less?
So let's get rid of the mumble.
OK. God bless you.
Bye.
Dad?
Wow.
What did he say?
He loves me.
Dad?
Dad.
Shit.
- Mr. Kamin.
- Yes. Hi.
I've been asked to take you
to Caesar's Palace.
You'll be meeting
with the producers
tomorrow evening at 10:00.
Look over these papers.
W-2, social security,
And these forms are
for the insurance exam
we need to do for doing
any stunt work.
That's up first thing
in the morning.
Insurance exam? We don't
have a deal yet.
It's not my area, sir.
I guess it's what
you talk about
tomorrow at 10:00.
Yeah. Thanks a lot. Bye.
Steven! I can't tell you
how excited we are.
This whole thing is
such--it's amazing,
So we love it.
Thank you.
See ya.
Mr. Kamin.
Wow.
Yes. Hey, there he is.
I do good, Sam?
You did great, Max.
Yes!
You're in a movie, Max!
You're gonna be in a movie!
And then we're
gonna go to galoop!
Come on, let's
hit those buffets!
He's got fingers
as big as pickles.
You want to meet him?
His head touches the ceiling
and he's gonna be
in this big movie
with Steven Seagal.
And when did you start
growing like this?
14.
And how old are you now?
36.
Good. Well, I'll
see you in a minute.
But you're not saying
he can't do the movie?
No. I'm merely saying
I can't sign off
on these insurance forms.
Given his EKG, the exertion
could be dangerous.
How can this be?
This guy is
as strong as an ox.
He's a giant,
for god's sake.
Exactly.
Mr. Kamin, have you
ever seen an old giant?
What?
They have a hormonal imbalance
that causes a heart condition.
I believe Max has one.
Are you a heart specialist?
No, but I intend
to fax his EKG
to a heart specialist
and I'd like to--
Listen,
don't bother, OK?
Because I don't buy it.
"Ever see an old giant"!
What is that,
a trick question?
There are always
second opinions.
And I'm gonna get one.
And I'm sure you'll find
your way to a doctor
who, for the right fee,
will give you his signature
on these insurance forms.
No. I will just find
a better doctor.
Hey, Max.
How you doing?
Hello?
Is this Lillianna Otarro?
Yes.
I spoke to you
the other day.
I'm calling for
Maximus Sanferescu.
A 3-week guarantee
At 2,500 a week?
I think that's a nice offer.
I said
I'll think about it.
All right, so we'll
come up to 3.
3 grand a week,
a month guaranteed.
And a bump if it goes
to a TV series.
You've heard of
The Incredible hulk?
Do you know what
Ferrigno made on that?
We see a huge career
for this guy.
I'll think about it.
What, you think we need
this guy or something?
No, I understand.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Wait a minute.
Hold on. The point is...
...we want him.
I mean, the image of
this big, stupid beast
spouting Shakespeare--
"Big, stupid beast"?
Well, he looks stupid.
He speaks 5 languages.
How many do you speak?
Hey, settle down--
Don't call him stupid!
I'm sorry. It was
a slip of the tongue.
Look, Sam...
Sammy...
I'll be honest with you.
The deal is
Steven wants him.
He's nuts about him,
So just tell us
what you want.
5 grand a week?
10?
50.
A million.
What?
Come on, Sam.
Talk to me.
I just need to do
what's best for my giant.
Mr. Kamin.
Doctor. They told me
you were... working late.
First of all...
I apologize.
I was way out of line
with what I said before.
I--I was just stunned.
It's OK.
There are some things
that I need to know.
Sure. Sit down.
Life expectancy.
The books say
35 to 50 years.
You see, they suffer
from cardiac enlargement.
Ventricular hypertrophy.
Bad heart.
That's right.
Well, what about
a new one, you know?
I mean, a heart transplant.
His heart's the size
of a catcher's glove.
You won't find one
to replace it.
He's aware of this,
you know.
What?
Yes.
He wrote "sick heart"
across his questionnaire...
Asked me how long
I thought he had left.
And what did you tell him?
That he should be
with family.
What did he tell you?
That you're dying.
They always say that.
Tell me the truth.
Come on, Max,
tell me the truth.
Do you feel like you are?
Sometimes.
Why did you do this?
Why did you let me
drag you across the country?
To see Lillianna.
You could have told me,
Max, you know?
You should have told me.
I'm sorry, Sam.
Can we still see Lillianna?
Please?
I'll be all right.
Trust me.
Hello.
Hi. It's me.
Hi, Sam.
How's it going?
Not so good.
What's wrong?
I don't know.
I just...
...wanted to say hi.
Just wanted to hear
your voice
and to see
how you're doing.
How are ya?
How ya doing?
What's going on
with you, Sam?
You sound strange.
My giant's dying.
What?
Yeah.
Ever see an old giant?
You've lost me, Sam.
I know I have...
and I don't want to.
And do you--
do you really want this?
Do you want to just
give up on us, huh?
Where are you?
I'm at an airport.
I'm on my way
to New Mexico
to try to convince a woman
who knew Max 20 years ago
to come visit him
because that's what he wants
and I don't know
if I can.
Serena, my whole life...
I've been able to talk
people into doing things
and I don't think
it's working anymore.
What can I do for you, Sam?
I don't know.
You got a magic wand
lying around?
You could wave it...
Say a couple of--
No. There's no magic wands.
Well, there better be,
Because I'm about to need one.
Wonder View Terrace.
All right.
Don't forget to lock up
when you're done.
OK. Bye-bye, Lillianna.
See you next week.
Miss!
We grew up together
in the village of Lunca.
She kissed me...
by the fountain of the virgin
at the end of the road
near my house.
22 years, Sam.
I can still feel
her lips on mine.
Miss...
Keep away from me.
I have pepper spray.
Wait. Hey,
let me explain.
Keep your distance.
Keep away.
Wait.
Don't shoot that.
Go away.
Please, don't do this, Lillianna.
How do you know my name?
I'm a friend of
Maximus Sanferescu.
You're the one
who was calling?
Yes.
Max is very sick...
...and he needs to see you.
I know he is sick.
He's very sick.
He's obsessed with me.
Do you know how many letters
I've gotten from him
in 20 years?
Maybe 1,000...
until I told
the post office
to start destroying them.
It's called stalking.
Does he know
it's against the law?
I could get you
both arrested.
Let me explain,
please.
Explain why the church
doesn't do something
about this perverted priest.
Explain that to me.
Wait a second.
He is not a pervert.
He's not even a priest.
He's a good man.
He's a wonderful man
who's in love with you
and he's always been
in love with you.
He remembers kissing you.
I never kissed him.
In Lunca?
Behind the fountain
of the virgin
at the end of the road
near his parents'
house? Right?
That was 20 years ago.
I was a kid. There's
nothing to talk about.
Wait...
Lillianna, he's
an unusual person.
If you would let me explain,
you'd understand.
All I'm asking
is for you to give me
5 minutes, OK?
Just 5 minutes.
You come into this restaurant--
in public--
Sit down, have a cup
of coffee with me
and listen to what
I have to say about Max.
There are things
that you don't know
that'll make all the
difference in the world.
Please.
5 minutes?
What do you say?
I don't want to.
Get away from my car.
'Allo?
Max, it's me.
Sammy!
Did you see her?
Not only
did I see her,
I'm bringing her
to the hotel.
She's coming?
Any second.
What did she say?
Now, listen,
In 20 years, people change.
You understand?
So don't be surprised
if you find her a
little bit changed.
What do I wear?
Stay away from
vertical stripes.
What if she don't like me
when she see me?
She will like you,
Max.
Trust me.
I'll see you in
a few minutes, OK?
All right. Bye.
Lillianna,
I'm gonna tell Max
that you're here, OK?
Thanks.
Hey...
Are you ready?
She's here?
She's here.
I'll bring her in, OK?
Yes.
Lillianna,
You wanna... come in?
Come in.
He won't bite.
Lillianna...
Maximus...
Max, Lillianna would like it
if you spoke English.
Yes. Please.
Yes. English.
We all speak English.
Listen, if you two
would like me to go--
- No.
I'll be happy to stay.
I'll just...
be right there.
You look different.
And you.
I grow.
Yes.
Too much.
You are still my Maximus.
Why you never write to me?
I wanted to,
But... my--
father.
Father was so strict.
I'm sorry.
I thought you forgot me.
No.
You remembered?
Everything.
Goat boy and the treasure?
The treasure?
Yeah. The goat.
Mine jump up.
The goat.
That was so funny.
When the machine
cut his legs off?
That was so sad.
I wrote to you
every day.
I sent you poems.
I remember every one.
Say one.
Whichever you like best.
Max,
why don't you do
one of your favorite poems
for Lillianna?
Wouldn't you like to hear
one, Lillianna, from Max?
Yes, please.
I've longed to hear
one in your voice.
No. My accent.
Is beautiful.
Nothing about me
is beautiful.
Please.
How do I love thee?
Let me count the ways.
I love thee to the depth
and breadth and height
My soul can reach.
I love thee with
the breaths, smiles, tears
For all my life.
And if god chooses,
I shall love thee better
after death.
You are happy,
Lillianna, in your life?
You're alone?
You are married.
He is a good man?
He doesn't seem to know it,
but he's a good man.
He just doesn't
feel good enough.
Even with your love?
You deserve better man.
Lillianna,
you remember the kiss?
Behind the fountain?
Yes.
I will never forget it.
I still dream of it.
I'm so sorry, but...
We will always
have the sunset.
Just know...
I will never forget you.
I'll be right back.
Do you want me to go
to the airport with you?
No. I think you should
stay with him.
Do you have to go
right away?
It's Nicky's birthday.
Yeah.
That was unbelievable.
That was really amazing.
The kiss, however,
I didn't see coming--
Sammy.
Yeah?
Right.
Thank you.
That meant everything to him.
And me.
And me. You know,
what you did for him...
That's the man
I married.
I've missed you.
Hey, Serena...
You're my Lillianna.
I'm gonna love you forever.
There's one
big difference.
She didn't
love him back.
Spell, please.
Big back end?
Thank you.
I'll tell him. Good-bye.
What is "big back end"?
What?
The man
from the movie said,
"3-pic deal. Option TV.
Big back end."
What does this mean?
It means you're a star
of the silver screen, Max.
The biggest I ever had.
Seems like a perfect time
to leave, doesn't it?
Come on, pack up.
But the movie, Sam.
The movie's
the easy part, Max.
It's the deal that's hard.
So, I'm in Romania,
with a truly gigantic
movie star
whose one appearance
in a little-known European
movie skyrocketed him
to a 3-picture deal
in Hollywood.
But he got out
while he was still on top.
Good morning.
Sanferescu?
Max?
Max, wake up.
No!
No! Why you do this
to me, Sam?
Why?! Why you
bring me here?!
This is not my home!
They leave me!
Why, Sam?! Who tell you
do this to me?!
I told you lots of times,
I don't like this place!
My mother had a saying:
Never go to sleep angry.
Go home.
Mama.
Mama!
Dada.
I saw Max twice
over the next year.
The last time,
to say good-bye.
It's funny to think
that someone could die
because his heart was too big,
but that was Max.
The thing is,
he wanted to be small
and I wanted to be big.
But what we both
were looking for
had nothing
to do with size.
Because I'm not the tallest guy
in the world,
But in the eyes of my family,
I've become a giant.
Vanquish mine enemy!
Begone, foul demon,
For I am the swordmaster!