This is the time that we have to think of our royalty future.
With the royal wedding ceremony for the crown prince.
So, this girl is Prince Inn's fiance.
Would you marry me?
I am sorry about that you proposed to me.
If you talk too much, you will get in trouble.
Such a silly prince! You think you can intimidate me?
I am not intimidate you.
If you don't believe me. Try then!
Being a cheerful and sweet person sometimes
not aggressive and unruly
I've always been like this.
I've met you who is a girl-heartthrob.
I've known you that you are cold-hearted
but also lovely sometimes.
It's so weird that you come to change my world.
You make me tremble.
Is this love?
Are we on the same page?
Do you feel like me when we are near?
Please tell me that beneath such a dreamy
that means I love you.
English Subtitle by ingfakirata
Watch for free on my Youtube channel
This couple seem to get along well.
Queen mother...
Take it easy, they are going to marry.
He seems really want to know that who will be his bride.
I didn't expect to meet the prince there.
How about that family?
You seem like you work so hard.
You should let it be.
Don't stress.
Ok.
But... do it softly please.
P'Put!!
Why you don't pay a mortgage?!
It's several months!
Where's the money?
Mom!
We could talk outside. There is customer.
I'm sorry.
Never mind.
But stop hit me and you could talk.
No, I can't.
Let's talk later.
No, I can't wait.
This is the big problem!
Our house will seize definitely.
You probably open the massage shop at roadside there.
Calm down.
His muscle is still hurt.
P'Put!! Why you don't care about anything!!
I really ask you, there were many customer last month. Where is the money?!
They came here because they were hurt, so I didn't even ask them about money.
I saw them feeling better. I was very happy.
Have you ever thought that anyone will help us?
What should I do?
I have idea.
I will find more customer.
We have to work more and we will get more money.
I will also create a new massage oil recipe and sell it on social media.
I have no idea.  You deal it yourself!
It's good? You might feel comfortable that why you're falling to sleep like this.
Oh no... I haven't done it yet.
Here you go.
It's still warm. I will give it to you.
Oh... the smell is so good.
It's safflower tea.
Really good for your health.
Just 100 baht per pack. Buy 7, get 2 free.
I am willing if you want to be a membership with us.
I'm not a direct seller. I just suggest you to buy it.
I'm sorry because my mom wants more membership.
I want to meet your parent, can you tell them for me?
My parent?
Sure, you are so lovely. I will tell them. Just a moment please.
Just a second! Don't go anywhere.
It seems she is a good girl.
Yes, the fiance is a good girl and lovely as well.
Did you tell them?
Yes, Your Majesty.
This is symbol necklace of the royalty that the ex-King gave us as evidence for the promise.
I think you will also have it.
- Necklace?
- Yes.
Although I've known you that you are really his descendant.
But you have to confirm it with this necklace.
It probably be that the ex-royal guard
didn't give it to you.
Because
you ran away from home for so long.
You would like to say that I am a bad son. I don't mind it.
The nacklace.
I remembered that my dad ever give me the necklace when Kaning was born.
Where is it now?
Where is it? I forget it.
Forget what? You give it to me.
Such a rare item like this. I keep it in the safe at the bank.
Yes, you're right! It's in safe at the bank.
Yes.
We have to tell this to the fiance.
Wait! Please wait!!!
Sit down please, the principal secretary.
Sit down please.
I think we should not tell her now. If we do that she might be shock for sure!
Like her dad and I now.
Yes! I got shock!
Give us the time for tell her a few days.
So, 3 days after this. I will come back again.
Don't forget your necklace.
The necklace?
You will come back here within 3 days.
No problem!
You are the fiance who is going to marry with Prince Inn.
What?!
Just 3 days left, you will meet the fiance.
I am so excited.
Bhutin is going to have a celebration soon.
So, do you know about Prince Nakhun and Princess Krissana?
It's almost 3 days. He is coming.
Do you remember where it is?
Or you pawn it?
Dad! What are you doing?
I remember it!
Really!!! Where?
On the roof.
Dad! Mom! I had a nightmare!
Why??
No. It won't happen again. I'm here.
I had dream about none-face prince
he imprisoned me at the tower for talisman worship.
Oh dear, it's alright. Everything will be okay.
P'Put, don't let her wear your dad's necklace.
You've always had a nightmare when she wears it.
It might be here!
I didn't come for a long time. So messy!
It might be lost.
Don't have a nightmare anymore please!
Mom! I found it!!
Mom!!
I found the nacklace!!
Oh, you have prepared this much. Are you ready?
What's matter?
If you are ready. Shall we go?
Where are we going?
You come here early. I didn't talk to my daughter yet.
I thought she already prepared the stuffs. So she'd know about the wedding.
The wedding?
What does it mean?
Is there a secret?
So, I would like to tell her myself.
I am a royal principal secretary of the Bureau of the Royal Household of Bhutin.
I would like to tell you that
you are the fiance who is going to marry with Prince Inn
who is the crown prince of Bhutin.
What?!
No one want to tell me!
Dad!
Sit down.
I wanted tell you but it's so sudden.
Dad! Mom!
But I am still too young!
Don't be moody! Calm down!
This engagement is from your grandfather and the ex-King made a promise with each other.
You should to do it.
What? I don't understand how I can marry with someone who I've not known before.
Impossible!
No, I don't want it. I can't do it!
Kaning!
- I don't do that!
- Calm down!
Both of your grandfather and ex-King were best friends. They made promise that they would like to let their descendants marry each other.
But I'm still student.
I have my own dream to study in art major. I also want to be a famous cartoonist.
Dad! You want me give up on my dream?
No way! Moreover, Prince Inn also has...
I'm sorry about that you proposed to me.
If you talk too much. You will get in trouble.
What's matter?
Nothing.
But I won't marry him.
Dad! Mom! I don't want to do it.
I won't marry him!
- Kaning!
- No!
Mom? What's wrong with her?
So, you really come from Bhutin?
I've ever told you but you didn't believe me.
Do you believe me now?
It means all of us have Bhutin blood.
Moreover, your sister is Prince Inn's fiance.
Oh!!! The fiance!!!
It's not true!!
Let's divorce.
You're a nightmare!!
So, we have no money for mortgage?
Keep calm, we will get through it.
You!!
You've always said like this.
I've done this for you all the times.
We are at the end of our rope.
No, not yet. It's not end at all.
To let Kaning marry him, isn't the end?
I'm not good enough. Our family would be better than this if I worked diligently.
Mom?
Let's divorce.
Let's divorce as you've often asked me.
I will handle the debt myself.
Let Kaning be with you.
And use your lastname.
She doesn't need to marry with that promise anymore.
Are you sure what you've just said?
In the past, I proposed you to divorce.  But you never accept it .
But today...
You've said it yourself.
Such a crazy!!!
Think carefully
I will throw it in the towel.
I will stay with friend. Not Indefinite. (Kaning)
For the marriage, I need to sleep on it.
This is Bhutin's archer athlete. She is so pretty.
Kaning?
If you don't hurry you won't finish your work.
Kaning!!
What?!
Let's go! but where is it?
Kaning, what's wrong with you today?
No, nothing.
You!!! Prince Inn is coming!!!
Prince!!! Prince!!!
Look at them!
What the hell they are doing.
Stop!
Prince! Prince!
I think so, they are punching above their wieght.
- He is looking at me? He likes me!
- Nope! He is looking at me.
Hey! Stop!!!
He did it! Because you just splashed the water on his face!
- Don't point at me!
- You know
Hi-Class people have always associated with each other. They don't ever make friend with us.
Remember it!! Don't be nonsense!
He is looking at me!
Stop!!!
Prince, how about Minnie?
Do you still keep in touch?
Please leave me alone for awhile.
Hey! Are you okay?
Inn?  Prince?
You?
Stop!
- Yes, Your Highness.
- Come here.
What's matter, Your Highness?
You can speak informal.
You already know it, did you?
Know what?
No! Such a creepy!
Your necklace, what does it mean?
I am glad that you wear this necklace.
I also have it.
Prince, I need to marry you because of my family.
I hope you don't mind me.
You will go through difficult times.
Would you marry me?
I will take care of you.
Don't do that.
What's wrong with you?
Do you really want to be a princess?
No, I don't.
But you still don't know
what you will face with in the palace.
Such a crazy prince!!!
This is True Insider show.
And today we will talk about the hot topic in our social first.
That about Prince Inn who is the popular among women including my partner here also.
Yes, It seems like a sad news more than good, P'Put.
Because he suddenly came back this time for his royal wedding ceremony.
This matter is talk of the town and people also want to know it through mass media and SNS right now.
Everyone is talking about this and we will find more details for you.
We have to handle it prematurely.
Yes, Your Majesty. I will order the Bureau of the Royal Household handle it immediately.
What's wrong? Are you worry about the wedding?
Don't forget it. This is purpose of your grandpa.
And our royalty never break any promises.
Moreover, it's promise that your grandpa gave it to his best friend.
We can't deny it! Do you understand?
Excuse me, Your Majesty. It's time for your dinner.
Hey! Do you know that Prince Inn is going to marry?
- Screammmmmmmm!!!!
- Unbelievable! Who's that? Where does she live?!!!
- Calm down. This is a hot news now. You will know soon.
Kaning!
I have a hot news to tell you!!
You are so overacting like you will be his princess.
What?!
His princess?? Don't tell me that you all already know it.
What I should do.
Stop!!
Kaning! Don't be nonsense with both of them.
So how did you know that he is going to marry?
Look here! Who's spread this rumor? This is rumor! It's not true! He is still young. No Way!!!
- He is mine!
- No, he is mine!
He is your? When?
It's just a rumor!!
You are right! I'm so upset!
Inn?
About the news, is it true?
Did you change your status that just being friends become couple?
I didn't know.
When are you going to marry?
Are you spread the rumor?
You really want to be princess, do you?
No, I didn't
But you don't believe me for sure, Your Highness.
I told you don't say 'Your Highness' with me
Why? Your Highness.
Your Highness, Sir, Prince...
You don't like it? Your Highness.
Where are you going?
Your Highness.
I do it quite well today.
How about you, Inn?
I'm going there today.
Minnie? Are you ready for this Olympic? How about your confidence?
I am confident.
I give all my life for this Olympic.
So Bhutin people probably have the first Olympic athlete in history?
Sure, I am very confident.
Minnie? Please wait!
You have to work hard.
We have many things to do with this comeback.
And you must go to the palace often.
Yes, mom.
Just wait, we will get everything back.
When will you pay me the debt?
Including the interest, Do you know how much of it?
- Who's that?
- Sia Khajorn, he come to massage.
Dad's friend? So I will help him.
No, don't do that.
Don't worry, I will pay it for sure.
Right now I have no money but I will have it soon.
For the sake of our friendship.
Friendship?
Dad! Dad!!
If I didn't see you as friend, I will kick you with both of my feet as well!!
P'Put?
Who is your friend?
This is your daughter? She is pretty. Let she works with me, I can clear all of your debt.
She looks good!
Don't touch my daughter!!!
How dare You!! You are broke now!
How dare you!!
Mom?!! Dad?!!
Wait! Wait! Wait!!
Her Majesty Queen Rachawadee would like to meet the fiance.
Could you please go to Bhutin?
No matter what your decision is.
Don't worry. We will get through this.
What is your decision about this marriage?
If I marry him...
would my family be better off?
Do you remember me?
Yes, I do. Lady Krissana.
I need your help.
For you...
I can help everything you need.