(Episode 110)
Why are you all here?
We all have something to say to you.
Take a seat, Mr Kim.
Sit.
What is...
going on?
You.
You still don't remember what you told me when you were drunk, do you?
What did I say?
I can't say this...
because I'm scared. Jae Min, tell him.
I heard you are including...
the premium exhibition hall as a part of Chinese tourist course.
Did I say that?
You told me this when you were drunk.
How much money were you promised from SS Global for doing that?
What are you talking about?
I have nothing to do with them.
You're taking money from them as I have.
Do you have evidence?
Do you have any evidence that I have anything to do with that company?
You must work there, too.
I don't.
I just gave them my name.
This is a huge crime.
Just use the money.
My gosh.
When did she record this?
I don't think that is what's important now.
This recording proves my mum's innocence.
I am not afraid any more.
I'm going to whistle-blow.
Will you join me...
or will you do your own thing?
Make a wise decision.
What will you get out of this?
I'll at least get my conscience back.
You never cared about your conscience.
Once she speaks up,
you'll undergo an investigation.
Just admit to your wrongdoing...
and side with us on disclosing Mr Oh's corruption.
We'll give you the weekend to think.
Let us know if you change your mind.
You all are making a fool out of me.
We're giving you a chance.
It's your last chance.
My goodness.
Did I really say that?
Hey.
I've never been this nervous before.
Why do we have to lie to make this happen?
Also,
what's this story about the Chinese tourist course?
That's not a lie.
My brother-in-law heard it.
- Il Mok did? - Where at?
At his part-time job as a server.
He heard Mr Oh and Mr Kim talk about that a while ago.
That's why Mr Oh was determined to get you so badly.
If we establish the on-site day care centre,
his source of side money will be gone for good.
Will Mr Kim...
take our side?
He now knows that we know of his secret.
There is nothing else he can do other than siding with us.
I really hope he does.
Will you be okay?
Of course. I'll find a part-time job.
You don't need a part-time job.
Even if you do get another job, do it after you give birth.
It'll be too hard for you.
Many pregnant women work until right before they are due.
You did that.
They won't let this pass.
What are the choices I have?
Yes.
That's the only way.
- Excuse me, I have a question. - Yes, welcome.
I want to work here.
Who can I talk to?
There's an office down the aisle.
Thanks.
I'm so sorry to ask,
but what's the hourly wage?
Honey.
Hey, Honey.
What are you doing here?
I'm looking for a part-time job.
You know what?
I saw Rita drinking by himself on my way here.
What happened?
We took our last shot with Dung Kim today.
I see.
I think I will be...
whistle-blowing soon.
You don't need to look for a part-time job already.
You know that I have to be prepared for everything.
I have to do something before I find another job.
If I never land a full-time job,
I'll start a small business.
If we take out a business loan to open up a small shop,
I'm sure we won't starve.
This is really sad.
You're a great cook.
And I'm adorable.
We'll get so many customers.
Adorable?
You're right. I'll do my best and...
Why, what is it?
- Sky just moved. - What?
Was that a kick?
Sky's more powerful than Min Ho.
I was really surprised.
Min Ho?
Wow.
All right.
We have nothing to worry about thanks to our dear Sky.
- Of course. - Yes, of course.
Let's go!
- Go. - Go!
Min Ho, are you having fun? We're here.
- You're here. - Yes.
- Here. - What's this?
Jae Min, cook for us.
We got ingredients for curry.
My goodness. Listen to her.
I really don't want to cook tonight.
Do you ever cook?
Stop it, Jae Min.
I cook when I want to.
I feel bad for people who don't have a younger sister-in-law.
I'm that man!
Don't worry, brother-in-law. You've got me, the beautiful one.
Of course, Mi So.
Mum.
I think Eun Sol likes Min Ho.
- Really? - Really?
What did she say?
She said this today.
- What? - What did she say?
- Why are you smiling? - What happened?
What happened with Eun Sol?
What about her?
How many jump ropes can you do?
I'm not sure.
I can do more than 10.
Really?
Jump like this.
Cross it over like this.
Bang Geul, wait for me.
No!
Eun Sol.
Be careful.
Are you okay, Eun Sol?
Min Ho is so cool.
Min Ho, that's great! Give me a high-five.
- That's great news. - Congratulations, Min Ho.
No, wait.
Let's not get all too excited.
She's right. We can't be excited at this stage.
Right?
Bang Geul, how did her face look when she said...
she liked Min Ho?
"Min Ho is..."
"so cool."
We did it, Ye Eun.
Congratulations, Min Ho.
Does Eun Sol like me?
Yes. Didn't you catch Bang Geul's face?
No woman makes that face about someone she doesn't like.
- Yes. She's right. - Yes!
Was there something special about how Bang Geul looked?
I'm not sure. She mostly looked hungry to me.
- What? - What?
I thought she looked hungry, too.
Aren't you hungry, Ga Ram?
Honey.
Take these.
Do you want me to set tables now?
Would you want...
Eun Sol's husband to sit around while she prepares food?
I wouldn't want that.
Eun Sol, will you take the chopsticks and spoons?
Be careful.
Eun Sol.
Park Eun Sol.
Yes, what?
Take the chopsticks and spoons.
Okay.
Eun Sol, what's on your mind?
Nothing.
Aren't you going to bed yet?
Mum, which one is prettier?
Both.
But still. Pick one for me.
- This one. - Okay. I'll wear this tomorrow.
To where?
We're going to play together at the playground.
- Will Min Ho be there? - Yes.
Good for you, Eun Sol.
Yes.
What is it?
Honey, it seems like Eun Sol likes Min Ho, too.
What? Wait.
She liked Woo Seong.
Min Ho must have done something very impressive.
She's choosing clothes for tomorrow...
to look pretty for Min Ho.
This isn't good.
Don't girls need a bit of attitude when it comes to relationships?
It's not like they're getting married.
Why the attitude?
No, this isn't good.
I'll teach Eun Sol about relationships.
My goodness.
(Bukhansan Restaurant)
We don't have enough side dishes.
Professor, Professor.
Those two are back.
- Really? - Yes.
Do you want me to take these?
Yes. Thanks for your help.
- Yes, Sir. - Sure.
- Hello. - Hello.
Menu, please.
Welcome. Sure.
What do you want to tell me?
Ms Joo is determined...
to whistle-blow.
Why haven't you stopped her?
They are all siding together.
I couldn't do anything.
Who do you mean?
Ms Lee and Ms Joo turned out to be sisters.
Really?
That's why Jae Min has been picking a fight with me.
Anyway.
You are not affiliated with SS Global on papers,
so the disciplinary committee won't bring you in.
But that's not the case for me. I may get fired.
You have to let me at least make a living.
Of course.
I'll give you something.
Thank you, Mr Oh.
Even if a disciplinary committee is held,
I will keep my mouth shut.
Thank you.
Instead, I'll make sure your punishment is...
minimised.
Thank you. Let's eat.
So Rita asked for money.
Hey, that guy is leaving.
Is he?
Yes. It's just as I expected.
Think of this as a small investment.
Think about our future.
It's a great chance for us to get rid of Mr Kim, too.
I'm glad he asked for money from his end.
Yes.
Jae Min, let's sit.
What happened?
Rita asked Mr Oh for money...
for keeping his mouth shut in front of the disciplinary committee.
So he won't side with us.
But Mr Oh said something strange.
What do you mean?
I heard him talk on his phone in front of the restaurant.
He's glad Rita asked for money...
and that he can get rid of him as well.
Is he glad that he asked for money?
What is he thinking?
He wouldn't mention who was on the other side.
I was hoping to hear that.
I need to meet Dung Kim on Monday.
- Dad. - Uncle.
- Let's go to the playground. - Let's go.
We're meeting Yu Ra and Eun Sol there.
Shall we go?
- You're here. - Hello.
Oh, my.
- Hi, Eun Sol. - Hello.
Hello.
Hi, Min Ho.
Hi.
Go on, Eun Sol.
I want to ride it, too.
Wait.
Bang Geul and I are riding this right now.
Okay.
Wow, look at how chic Min Ho is.
Yes.
That must be my blood.
Eun Sol.
Remember what I said.
Do not forget what I have just told you.
All right.
Eun Sol.
You can't let Min Ho know that you like him. Okay?
No. I want to tell him that I like him.
Eun Sol.
You ruined everything!
Eun Sol!
This is a historical moment.
It is. I'm a little dumbfounded myself.
My goodness.
Hey.
- It's a bee. - You're adorable.
- She's adorable. - This is a bee.
It'll be difficult to persuade Sang Gu and Yu Ra's mums, right?
It won't be easy.
They think of shared babysitting centre...
as an academy.
I understand. Their kids are all grown up.
They wouldn't want to take a part in a day care centre with infants.
I'm sure dads can't convince them.
We should be there on the next meeting.
Sure.
Wouldn't it be hard for Ms Joo? She's almost due.
Yes. You can send Il Mok instead.
I'm doing fine.
It looks like your stomach does not get bloated up.
- Right. - Mine bloated after six months.
I suddenly got so huge.
Did you give Min Ho a natural birth?
You know what? Min Ho weighed 3.8kg.
- That must've been hard. - That sounds painful.
Eun Sol weighed 3.1kg.
Bang Geul weighed 3.3kg.
Excuse me.
If you're going to talk about that, you should just go to a cafe.
It's a bit awkward for me.
What's awkward about pregnancy? You were born from a woman too.
Why are you eating instant noodles instead of a proper meal?
I was too lazy.
Did you all see Lee Min Ho advertising a rice cooker?
He even set out the whole table. How considerate!
Right, that was so awesome.
Wouldn't it be so awesome...
if a guy like that sets out a table for me?
- She's so excited already. - I can eat...
at least 10 servings.
I want to serve those 10 servings to Lee Min Ho myself.
I'll eat those 10 servings sitting next to him.
- Next to him? - Yes.
I'd face him.
- I said, "Are you leaving?" - Good job.
Wait.
- What's with him? - I don't know.
It must be something good.
- Let's go. - Okay.
He didn't have to give me this much.
I should make a move now.
I'm home.
- You're back, Mi So. - Yes.
Mum, Eun Sol told Min Ho that she likes him today.
Really?
- What happened? - Eun Sol...
- Yes? - My goodness.
Ga Ram, come to me.
Come.
- It's Dung Kim. - What?
- Hello? - I decided to go with you.
Will you whistle-blow with us?
Yes, I will.
Tell Ms Joo to get started on Monday.
I don't think I can step up.
Okay. I'll see you on Monday.
Dung Kim says he's going to take our side.
I just saw him sitting in front of a store.
He looked really happy.
- Why is he happy? - I don't know.
He must have gotten the money.
What money?
He asked Mr Oh for money...
for keeping his mouth shut.
Why is he suddenly siding with us?
This is...
fishy.
Right?
Why haven't I heard from the kids?
Did something happen?
I hope everything is okay.
What should I do?
I promised her that we wouldn't visit them.
I can't visit them because Ms Lee's watching.
Why am I so itchy?
Ms Ok, I'm going to go to a bath house.
You should go and relieve your stress.
You've been working hard here.
Oh, sure.
I might be late.
Don't wait for me.
- Don't worry. - Sure.
Goodbye. Goodnight.
I won't let this pass.
Hey.
- Hey, Ms Lee. - Oh, my.
Ms Ok.
What are you doing here?
Why are you here?
My goodness. We should've just come together.
You're right.
Let's go.
- Let's go. - Come on, guys.
- Mum. - Mum.
Where are you guys going?
We wanted to get some fried chicken.
We had something to discuss.
My goodness.
You don't have the time to call in and tell us about what's going on,
but you have the time to eat fried chicken.
Well, we've been a bit busy.
We were really worried about you. You guys are awful.
- I'm sorry. - We were wrong.
You can all go ahead. We're leaving.
Let's go, Ms Ok.
- Come with us. - Let's go.
You guys can go.
- No, let's go. - I don't want to eat.
Let's go.
My goodness.
Bang Geul, eat up.
Min Ho, eat.
Okay.
We were wrong.
- Don't be angry. - Let's eat.
You should eat some.
I decided...
to tell the company about my wrongdoings.
Mum. What did you do wrong?
I was really greedy.
I need to tell them that I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
She has Ms Ok, Ms Lee and us.
Things look promising thanks to your recording.
Really?
Yes. It's all thanks to you two.
This is so great.
Why didn't you tell us before?
We're sorry, Mum.
Let's eat, Ms Ok.
It looks like...
that recording really saved them.
This is great.
They said nothing will happen to Ye Eun now.
You can sleep well from today.
I will.
Recently, I could barely sleep.
My goodness.
Give me your back.
It's okay, Ms Ok.
We couldn't discuss anything with Ye Eun's family...
because of our mums.
We'll do it tomorrow.
We were too inattentive...
after they went through such a huge incident.
It's nothing hard to call them and talk to them about this.
You're right.
But I could see them lighten up...
when we said nothing will happen to Ye Eun.
I was...
a bit touched.
Nothing will happen. Let's just believe that.
I'm going to see a member of the disciplinary committee today.
You should wait.
Dung Kim said he'd help. Let's talk to him first.
I heard Dung Kim asked Mr Oh for money.
Why would he help me?
It's weird. That's why we want to see him.
Mi So will call him.
Mr Kim seems to be late.
You're right. I'm worried.
He has to come in soon.
Hello? Marketing Team One.
Yes, Mr Kwon. What's up?
What? What are you talking about?
Did you say Dung Kim quit? Why would he do that?
Did Mr Kim quit?
Did Dung Kim really quit?
(Working Mum Stay Home Dad)
I told you.
That small amount of money was an investment for our future.
They can't do anything without Mr Kim around.
Isn't this absurd?
He said he'd help, but he suddenly quit.
Mi So, let's go on a date.
A date?
I wanted to chat with you.
I'm sorry, Mi So.
I think I'll do something that will make you mad.
Ms Ok, if things go well,
- I think we can get Mr Kim. - Really?
What are you talking about?
Why did Ms Joo summon a disciplinary committee?