Morning, Anita.
Good morning.
- Mr Robert!
- Théodore.
Worked all night again?
There you go.
Can I see that one?
What's all this?
I wasn't aware.
He's not her kind.
She's ruining her image.
I'll take this too.
See you tomorrow.
Take it easy!
There you go.
- Another preview tonight?
- You got it.
Which actress this time?
- Solange Duvivier.
- lsn't he the lucky one!
Any chance of a photo?
He'll try!
"Duvivier's boredom
is for all to see!"
You're speaking
of France's top actress!
You get paid more to be nasty?
That's twice this year,
there was April already.
Well it's twice too much,
we'll not let this rest!
Heard of the dog and the lamppost?
Like the artist and the critic:
one shines, the other pisses.
Do me a favour, piss off!
Violette...
Stéphane Bertrand, please.
No, give me his voicemail.
I'm calling about the screen test
for Violette Duval,
Wednesday at 1 0.
We're cancelling,
the role's too minor.
Plus, it's TV,
she wants to do more cinema.
Sorry, she's not interested.
Adeline...
Of course I want to go.
Where? At the school?
What time?
I can't tonight,
it's Solange's preview.
Don't take it like that.
Of course my daughter matters,
but tonight is out.
We can go see her teachers,
one by one.
But tonight, I really can't.
Good evening.
Presenting a new film
is always very moving.
I'd like to thank my director,
Jean Belair,
my producer, Charles Dassault
and the whole crew
for a job well done.
Someone else I'd like to thank,
who is by my side daily,
as friend, advisor
and of course my agent,
Dominique Bhé.
Thank you, Dominique.
Enjoy the film.
Solange!
MY STARS
Morning, Anita.
I'm nervous every time,
aren't you?
No, not me.
Who's your agent?
- Dominique Bhé.
- Wow!
You're so lucky.
Mine's useless.
The bare minimum.
Think Dominique is taking on?
No, I don't think so.
Marie, your turn.
Marie Janson, welcome!
How's your dad?
So who's your dad?
See you round.
Ciao, sweetie!
Bye, darling.
Hello!
Violette Duval?
What brings you here?
The screen test.
What an honour.
Should've rolled out the red carpet!
Missed the plane for Hollywood?
Sorry?
No TV, just cinema.
Think you're Solange Duvivier?
I never said that.
Mélanie, your turn.
I don't get it...
Well, get this.
The Oscars are that way!
Goodbye.
Give my regards to Spielberg.
I must be dreaming!
He's of Gipsy origin.
There's a new centre in Bucharest.
His parents left him
at the gate with a note.
He's almost two.
Bravo for the association.
I really admire you.
I wouldn't be able.
We're ready,
whenever you are.
His name's Augustin,
like my dad.
Must be an omen, no?
Think you'll go?
Got to talk to Bruno.
Hi, gorgeous!
Got the adoption photos.
He's so cute!
When do we go?
What's the rush?
Let's think about it.
We're both busy,
it's not the right time.
So when's the right time?
Let's discuss it, I gotta go.
Big kiss.
Let's say he's progressing.
As my Gran used to say: "Men
are crabs, they walk backwards!"
Was she a philosopher?
No, a fishwife!
IT'S LOVE!
Can I have a word?
No autographs.
It's about lsabelle.
No interviews.
- I'm not press.
- Then who?
Isabelle told me all about you.
I don't get it, who are you?
She never mentioned me?
No.
She never told you?
Not a word?
My mistake, I'd presumed that...
Sorry, doesn't matter.
Hold on!
What's all this about?
If lsabelle never told you,
it's not up to me.
Let's say...
It's kind of delicate.
Thank you.
You're off to Formentera
next weekend,
but I've a surprise for her
so could we switch?
"Switch"? I don't get it.
I thought that...
she'd already told you about us.
About "us"?
I don't mind
her seeing other men,
but next weekend...
You are dating lsabelle?
A rather simplistic view
of our relationship...
But yes, I am.
You and lsabelle!
Surprising, but she's so discreet.
She says she's seeing her agent.
You're sick. Really sick!
Let's drop this whole thing.
We're in Berlin the weekend after,
I'll surprise her then.
Don't tell her we spoke,
I'll tell her myself
tomorrow night.
Tomorrow night?
At Fouquet's.
Never been?
A pity, it's tops.
My apologies.
This is on me.
Hold on, not so fast.
Let's sort this out.
Sit back down.
Sit down.
I was wondering if Formentera
could be put off
till the weekend after?
Sure, no problem.
See you later, big kiss.
Here.
Yes, Bruno?
Sorry, I forgot.
That weekend I'm in Berlin.
Berlin?
Yes, at the festival,
with my agent.
You free tomorrow night?
I think we need to talk.
Tomorrow night...
No, I'm dining out.
With your agent?
- At Fouquet's?
- How did you guess?
Never mind, I get it.
You get what?
That we're through.
I'm nobody's fool.
Have fun, my regards to your agent.
Think I just got the shove.
The shove?
Well he is a rugby-player!
Sorry, not funny.
Victor!
Hi, Victor.
What a preview!
I was so happy for her.
The film's wonderful!
What do you want?
That article in Cinémagazine.
She must have right of reply.
I'll give you right of reply.
Beat it!
Hey, don't take it like that!
I'm saying this for her.
Asshole!
Sorry about the racket.
It's that fan again.
What does he want now?
Sticking his nose in, as usual.
You haven't eaten.
Not hungry.
You say I've put on weight.
That's just it.
You don't breakfast,
then you nibble all day.
You've a busy schedule.
Press conference at noon,
interviews from two till four,
photo session till five-thirty
and the gala evening
starts at eight-thirty.
Do I have to go?
It's in your honour.
For the retrospective.
Retrospective?
I'm not even dead.
Got anything more boring?
The Minister for Culture
will be there.
I knew you'd come up trumps!
I think I'd prefer the red silk one
with the crew neck.
They repainted the press room,
this will be much better.
He seems to be coming more often.
We must do something.
Like me to take care of it?
No, he's a leech, but harmless.
RESERVED FOR
ClNÉMAGAZlNE STAFF
It's not normal behaviour.
I know there's a problem.
It wasn't always so,
but since my wife and daughter left
it's got worse,
I don't know what to do.
I thought it best to see someone.
You did right, Mr Pelage.
So JR, what's up?
He's become a couch potato.
I'm so busy, I can't cope.
He watches cookery on TV,
the Gourmet channel.
Interesting.
TV soothes feline anxiety,
it's been proven.
But he eats like a horse.
Buy low-cal, he's too fat.
It's too expensive.
You can't have it every way.
Your pet's health is at stake,
he could get diabetes.
He's in depression.
Needs a psy-cat-analyst.
A what?
A shrink for cats.
- That exists?
- Sure, we all have neuroses.
Why not your cat?
The actresses carry the film.
Three women with the same secret
who overcome their differences
to pull together.
I wrote the lead role
for Solange Duvivier.
But for the other two
I wanted the opinion
of a man who knows.
Thank you for your trust.
I'll read it right away.
Call Nathalie,
cancel dinner tonight.
There's a problem
on Béatrice's shoot.
Who messed up my photos?
Who's this kid? She's pretty.
Is she with us?
Yes, I think Fabien handles her.
Makes a nice trio.
Was this your idea?
You'll go places!
I'll call Patrice.
I'm sure he'll love it.
Get me Patrice Leduc, please.
Fish, we know,
but Connétable sardines?
Connétable sardines in olive oil
on fresh bread.
Nothing better!
Connétable for connoisseurs!
Three in math.
Lucie, your mom's right,
it's not on!
Algebra sucks, I don't care!
Well I do.
I never studied,
I made my own way.
Think I like cleaning?
You can do better.
Like being an actress!
Yeah, very funny.
Starring in the new
Patrice Leduc film will be
Solange Duvivier,
Isabelle Séréna,
and newcomer Violette Duval...
He chose them?
All three of them!
Amazing!
I'd really like
to go to art school.
But Mom is against the idea.
And you?
Yeah, why not.
Think I've got talent?
That I'd make the grade?
Yeah, why not.
'Cos otherwise, I could do porn.
They want babes for a video.
Starts with a gang-bang
and ends in a zoo.
Cool, no?
Yeah, why not.
- What's up?
- I'm leaving!
Car or bus?
We're eating,
why leave now?
Why not!
Hi, Mom.
Hi, sweetie.
- Bye.
- Bye, darling.
- Hi.
- What's up this time?
Heck, I don't know.
Things were fine,
then she stormed out!
I think she's in teenage crisis.
Do you two talk enough?
Robert...
Durand is to head
a subsidiary down south.
He's asked me to be his PA.
I don't believe it!
That guy's always
had his eye on you...
I said I'd think about it.
You can't leave.
You can't do that.
We're separated, Robert.
Not even married. Remember?
But we said we were separating...
to think things over.
That it was temporary,
just for a while.
It may be for a bit longer.
You never forgave me
for taking that job.
When Cleanhouse closed
you could've set up your own firm,
but you took a night-job
at the bottom of the ladder.
And for what?
To be near your actresses.
Give me a little time
before you answer.
Please.
I made an appointment
at Lucie's school.
You can count on me,
I'll be there.
Fine.
Like your fringe,
makes a nice change.
Thanks.
Had it done two months ago.
Goodnight.
Hello.
The plumber.
And your name is?
Got a call for the water
in the dressing rooms.
My location manager's not here yet.
Fine, don't need him...
Sorry, I can't let you in.
Access is for crew only.
Your manager asked me to come.
Mister...
A name ending in "a"... or "i".
Mr Emmanuelli?
Right! It was urgent.
Sure, but I have strict orders.
He won't be long, if you...
But I have other clients waiting.
So, what do we do?
I don't know.
Fine, I'll come back later.
But I have to bill the visit.
1 50 euros... Fine by me.
Won't be docked from my pay.
First time on set?
Good start.
Emmanuelli will love it.
- He's Corsican, no?
- Right.
Hold on! Will it take long?
Nice, but we'll have
to move the hydrant.
Perfect,
whenever the actresses are ready.
If you need anything, just ask.
Thank you.
You're very kind.
So, then...
"Good luck on this new shoot.
Your biggest fan, Robert"
Her valuables were at risk!
I know, but that trainee is a dork!
I'll step up the security.
We had leeches in the past,
but he beats all!
Sorry I'm late.
Good day, Solange. Hello.
It's outrageous!
A fan got into my trailer.
Wow! Thought I was the only one.
That was always your problem.
I've the same fan as you.
That's wild!
Mr Pelage.
Sorry, he's sulking.
It's our first visit
to a psy-cat-analyst.
No, "zoo-psychiatrist".
I don't analyse animals
on a couch.
I just try to understand
and treat
the behavioural problems of cats.
So, name and date of birth, please.
Pelage, Robert.
27 March, 1 964.
No, I meant your pet.
Of course.
Sorry.
JR was born January 1 2, 1 999.
- JR is written "J"
- "R", thank you.
Dr Mulot mentioned depression.
For how long?
For the past few months.
Yes?
Since my wife and daughter left.
We've separated,
but it's temporary.
To think things over.
Cats are very prone
to separation anxiety.
Was he close to your wife?
Yes, very close.
Early on, they were...
inseparable.
I see.
Have you tried speaking?
In such cases
it's crucial to verbalise.
I've tried, but she says
she needs space...
No, I meant JR.
Sorry. Of course.
Right.
First off,
I'll do some clinical tests
to see what treatment
I can suggest.
Sometimes, we have
to resort to medicine.
Tranquillizers...
But be warned,
medicine alone won't do.
Cure really depends
on your behaviour.
At first, it didn't bother me
but now he's always hovering.
Victor will blow a fuse.
It began with my series.
I was so proud to have a fan.
Now I find it a pain.
He's everywhere.
I might find him in my bed.
Or in the queue.
Sorry?
I changed number twice,
but he found it each time.
He even got into our trailers.
What next?
Our living rooms?
We must do something.
But what?
The police.
No point.
Without a crime, they're powerless.
Not if we file a complaint.
They can't lock him up.
They can restrain him.
If I must, I'll call Nicolas.
Security is his thing.
So the press chimes in? No!
- Shouldn't bother you.
- Meaning?
You're already front page.
More for your ass
than your movies...
You know what my ass says?
No, but I know what it does.
Overtime.
Maybe watch your own ass.
It needs work.
I don't flash it around.
No one wants to see it!
So what about the police?
It's easiest, I'm in favour.
Do as you like.
I'm telling you, it's pointless.
Me too, I'm in favour.
Robert Pelage?
Lieutenant Bart.
I'd like a word.
Captain, I can't believe it!
I'm just a Lieutenant.
I admire them, support them,
I go to no ends!
- Maybe you overdo it?
- No, love has no limits.
They want you to stop.
You'll have to cool it.
They filed a complaint.
This is serious.
Took it for a cushion.
Even Violette, you say?
Didn't she win the César award?
No, that was lsabelle.
Sorry, movies aren't my thing.
I'm more into football.
I don't understand.
I really don't.
So, what's with these actresses?
What's so special about them?
They're simply perfect.
They're exceptional.
Solange is class,
refinement, elegance.
Isabelle, is beauty, sensuality.
And Violette... youth, freshness.
Can you imagine all that
in one woman?
Yes, but they are three,
awkward and influential.
So just leave them be
and we'll all be happy.
I gotta talk to them.
He left 1 0 messages!
My voicemail was full.
He was hovering all morning.
Victor couldn't get rid of him.
I told you it was pointless.
It's even worse.
He wants to talk.
Instead of criticising,
suggest, for a change!
More daft ideas?
I'd rather not.
A pity.
If only your lQ equalled
your bust measurements.
Okay, that'll do!
Are you going
to hold that against me forever?
Wasn't my fault the film bombed.
Leaving the director didn't help.
I fell for the cameraman.
Your speciality.
At least I have a life,
not like you.
- Excuse me, ladies...
- Not now, dammit!
I have an idea.
As the police aren't acting,
maybe we could.
Since he says he loves us,
we could play along.
No, we can't stoop to that.
For once, I agree.
We've better things to do.
No, we have to wait.
He'll calm down in the end.
Not finishing your dessert?
No...
- Morning, Théodore.
- Mr Robert...
- There you go.
- Thanks.
See you tomorrow.
SOLANGE DUVlVlER
SETTLES HER SCORES
- What's all this?
- It came out today.
They could call
before publishing such rubbish!
What am l?
A madwoman who trashes cars!
Do they think I'm Sid Vicious?
They say they got threats from us.
It's crazy.
Who'd do such a thing?
I'll call the police!
No, wait.
Show him in.
We should be at the studio.
We'll be late.
Make up some excuse.
Go on, show him in.
Victor, I gotta talk to you.
It's an outrage!
She should sue them for slander!
Miss Duvivier will see you.
Really?
- But l...
- This way.
Hello, come in.
Thank you, Victor.
Have a seat.
I presume you read it too.
You didn't pussyfoot around.
I didn't think they'd publish,
that they'd ever suspect you, l...
How'd you know it was me?
So it was you.
I wanted to be sure.
I'm really sorry.
I know you're mad,
but I did it so they...
Yes, but I can do without
such publicity.
I guess you'll call the police,
file a new complaint?
No, I don't intend to.
Macaroon?
No, thanks.
So, Robert...
I'll make a deal.
I'll turn a blind eye
on one condition:
that you cool it.
No more hovering at my gate,
harassing Victor,
or trashing journalist's cars.
A deal?
- I'm so glad we spoke.
- Me too.
I'll call the magazine
and explain.
Thank you so much.
Just one thing,
I'd like you to replace the car.
But I could never
afford to buy a car!
Doesn't have to be a new car.
Second-hand is fine.
- Is that your car?
- Yes, my Twingo.
I like Twingos.
It'll do nicely.
I'll see to it.
But that's my car!
What'll I do?
Documents inside?
Yes, I mean, no.
You can't do this!
See you on set, Victor.
Wait!
Hold on!
My Twingo.
You stole his Twingo?
Just borrowed, Violette.
That's wild!
I can't believe it.
Don't know what came over me.
A sudden brainwave and I improvised.
But what'll you do with it?
I don't know.
Keep it a while.
Let him walk!
Driving is such fun,
I'd never tried.
Don't have your licence?
No, what for?
I have Victor.
This may seem strange but...
behind the wheel
I felt free.
My heart was pounding...
Haven't had such fun in ages.
- Even got stopped by the cops.
- No!
And?
And, nothing.
They asked for my autograph.
She'll never wear that.
Fame brings people
who want to manage your life.
I met Victor 20 years ago
he was playing a minor role.
We hit it off and when my driver
took ill, he replaced him.
Gave up his acting career
to become my assistant.
But if you're not careful,
your whole life slips away.
No sweetener, Victor.
You can go home.
I won't be needing you.
But Solange...
Thank you, Victor.
See you later.
He's so nice, so perfect,
but such a damn bore!
Where is he?
He knows it's today!
Christ, she'll kill me!
Dammit!
Use it whenever,
I'll be keeping it a while.
Thank you, Madame.
Just call me Solange,
I'm so tired of "Madame".
I feel like the Queen of England!
Answer.
Hello...
Is this Robert's mobile?
Yes, who's calling?
His wife.
It's his wife.
Sorry, he can't talk right now,
he's in the shower,
he'll call back.
You're pretty good
at improvising yourself!
So, is he coming?
No, he has...
an emergency at work.
Emergency!
What, a dust attack?
Okay, perfect, let's go for it!
I can't believe you did that.
It's so puerile.
Well, you should know.
Here, get a load of this.
- A little souvenir.
- What's that?
His mobile.
Tons of contacts.
Check out Séréna.
But that's my country house.
And my parents'...
This guy is sick.
Where'd he get all this?
He's even got Bruno's number
and the rugby club.
The bastard, I get it.
Well, we don't.
The day he left,
Bruno met this guy.
Said I was two-timing.
I thought it was an excuse
for backing out,
or moving on,
you know, like crabs!
You've lost us.
It's a fishwife's thing,
I'll explain later.
Where's she off to?
Sorry!
Hi, there.
Just dropped by,
am I disturbing?
What's he doing here?
On the prowl.
I don't need any lessons from you!
Sorry about yesterday,
something came up.
You'd never believe what happened.
Try me.
I had...
a major car problem.
How'd it go with the teacher?
Dear Robert, I'd like to meet.
I thought we could dine together.
See you at nine at Fouquet's,
lsabelle.
A dinner invitation,
can you imagine?
What's her game?
What does she want?
Obviously a trap.
Isabelle Séréna invites.
What'd you do?
You'd have to go.
But you're right.
I'd better not.
Enough trouble as it is.
Good evening, Sir.
Hello, I've an appointment
with lsabelle Séréna.
- This way, Sir.
- Thank you.
Sir...
Like an aperitif?
- No thanks.
- Very well.
Have you ordered?
Try the Gourmet Menu,
it's divine.
Christophe!
Two Gourmets.
And for the wine?
- You choose, Christophe.
- Thank you.
So, Robert...
I guess my invite surprised you,
but I wanted to understand...
what goes on in your head.
Here, right now, it's...
pretty complicated.
Shall we go?
Where?
A drink at my place?
Hold on, I don't get this.
You invite me for dinner,
now you're asking me over.
What's going on?
Then, just forget it.
I was enjoying our chat,
I wanted to continue,
but I guess I was mistaken.
Hold on, don't just go!
- I bid you good night.
- Okay, your place!
Then I'll call a cab.
Sir.
Do you take instalments?
I enjoy our evenings out,
but not that violent rubbish!
It's not rubbish.
Next time, I choose the movie!
What's up?
Nothing.
Then can we go, please?
Sure.
What an evening!
Make yourself comfortable.
Like a whisky?
Sure.
From your association?
Yes.
- His name's Augustin.
- Like your dad.
So cute,
you want to take them home.
Thanks.
So why don't you tell me about you?
Have a seat.
Not much to know.
I have a wife, a daughter...
I didn't see you as married.
We're not actually married,
but it's as if.
Been together long?
We're not really together.
She's no longer with me.
But I'm still with her.
- Maybe you'll meet someone else.
- No...
- There is no one else.
- Why not?
That's just how it is.
Like in that film with Solange,
when her adoptive daughter
asks her what love is
she replies:
"The day it happens, you know."
It's the same for me.
I know.
Hi there!
- Am I disturbing?
- Not in Toulouse?
Missed the plane.
This is Robert...
We've met.
So it's still going on?
Your two-timing charade.
- It's not what you think.
- Enjoyed dinner?
- Let me explain...
- Stay out of this.
We'll settle it man to man.
Come here, you.
My specialty, is the head butt.
Get it? Or must I explain?
Are you mad?
I said scare him,
not break his face!
Sorry, I guess
I just got into the role.
Shit! No keys.
Police! Don't move!
Hey, it's me!
Pelage?
- What're you playing at?
- Are you crazy!
What're you doing here?
Sorry, thought you were a burglar.
You look like a tramp!
A mishap, I lost my keys.
Help me open the window.
I can't, that's burglary.
No it's not!
It's my home.
Come on, I'm hurting all over.
Hello.
Bream...
- What luck!
- Wonderful.
Indeed they are.
These are not red sea bream...
No, they're gilthead bream.
I was in the vicinity,
so I stopped by.
I've got good news for you.
Your actresses have decided
not to press charges.
They're pressing me instead.
- What do you mean?
- They're out to get me.
To take revenge.
Sure you're not being paranoid?
You don't know them.
This is doing your head in.
You need a change of air.
The France-ltaly game!
How about it?
Football? No thanks.
You'll see, you'll love it.
Sure it was him?
Maybe it was a business dinner?
Odd for a cleaner.
A "surface technician".
Well, she was quite a surface.
It's better that way.
I prefer to know.
I knew something was going on
he didn't dare tell me about.
But I'm glad...
I'm even happy for him.
Honestly, really happy for him.
So what did she look like?
A sex bomb.
That's wild.
What a stunt!
Yes, pretty good,
I must admit.
Just hope he didn't break his nose.
No, he'll be okay.
A tough cookie, our Robert.
He won't be back in a hurry.
I found him almost touching
last night.
- Not falling in love?
- No...
It was just pleasant.
We talked, he listened.
Men tend to ogle me, not listen.
I talked to Bruno about adoption
and I told him I'd had enough.
But you'd organised your trip,
even learnt Rumanian.
No, I'm still going.
I meant him. I dumped him.
- What!
- No loss, balls for brains.
I want a man to share my life,
not just my bed and page one,
who'd speak of me
like Robert of his wife.
Enthusiastic, kind.
A guy who acts,
able to get emotional about
something other than rugby!
Simple, no?
Mr Pelage.
- Hello, doctor.
- Hello.
JR isn't with you?
No, he couldn't get away.
But I can't work
without the patient.
I can tell you the symptoms.
He's not very well.
He can't sleep.
That's rare.
Cats usually sleep 1 6 hours a day.
Yes, but he can't.
He's really on edge.
His hands, I mean his paws,
are sweaty.
No appetite.
For JR, that's worrying.
So I was wondering if you could
prescribe something,
tranquillizers,
sleeping pills...
I'd need to know a bit more
about his problems.
They're top actresses,
movie stars.
You must know them,
Duvivier, Séréna.
Right, not just anybody.
- They're out to get me.
- Of course.
What would you do?
I'd see a psychiatrist.
This is a tranquillizer,
for cats and humans.
But it's just for now.
Next time come with JR.
Thanks, see you Monday.
Right, with JR.
Welcome to "My ldol"!
What's going on?
The idea is that actors
go meet their fans.
For my programme,
I chose you.
What's all this?
How did you get in?
By the door.
Who forgot his keys at lsabelle's?
Another of your tricks?
Well, I'm sick of it!
You just tell the viewers
you're happy to see me.
Why's my furniture outside?
To make room to shoot.
Got any beer?
What's he doing here?
- And JR? Where's JR?
- Who?
- My cat on the couch.
- Outside, I'm allergic.
- Outside?
- In the garden.
Should he be so fat?
The nerve! Come on, out!
No more fans, no more idols,
no more shooting,
no crew, no technicians...
Beat it or I call the cops!
And you, get your ass out of there!
Wait!
You can't just leave me like this!
Do a little spring clean!
Might cheer you up.
Goodnight!
But that's my Twingo...
My Twingo!
Fuck them!
Fuck them all!
I have to act.
They're going too far.
Do they think
they can walk all over me?
Even Violette Duval's in on it.
She's a rising star.
Yes, of course.
After all I've done for her!
Indeed...
Couldn't they have stayed put?
On the screen.
Why did they have
to break into my life!
With regard to JR's treatment...
I know!
I'll go get my Twingo.
Right, good idea...
You're a great help,
see you on Monday.
But next time bring the cat...
See you Monday.
Bloody hell!
It always works in the movies.
So, you broke into a trailer
and a car.
But it's my car.
Then why break into it?
The keys were in the trailer.
The one you were burgling?
Right, so I could start my car.
If the keys were in the trailer,
why the car?
I'd no keys for the trailer.
Got the car documents?
They're in the trailer.
Then how can you prove it's yours?
By getting into the trailer.
That, Sir, is called burglary.
But I had to steal it back
to prove it was mine.
Solange Duvivier stole my car
and left the keys in her trailer.
- Solange Duvivier?
- Right.
She stole your Twingo?
Exactly, you got it.
I see...
Look, you broke the law
by burgling a car and a trailer...
This is too much!
They steal my car,
break my face, wreck my home
and it's me who gets arrested!
Christ, what next!
Can I have a word?
Seems he's an old hand.
The actresses already
filed a complaint,
but didn't press charges,
for harassment, intrusion...
I get it, another crackpot.
Right.
- Seeing a psychiatrist?
- Sorry?
Have you consulted a psychiatrist?
No, why?
I saw a psy-cat-analyst, but...
The term is "psychoanalyst".
No, she's a psy-cat-analyst.
I went for my cat...
Enough. Just lock him up.
What came over you?
Just wanted some fun.
How was I to know
there'd be a storm?
But how did you organize it?
It was a day off,
so I asked the crew.
But you'd never believe
what I found at Robert's.
In his office
he has our every photo and article
even a diary
with our appointments.
That's crazy.
Does he work for the ClA?
He'd even cancelled a try-out
I was to do for TV.
Of all the nerve!
That must make you so angry.
No, I think he did right.
If I'd got it
I wouldn't have worked with you.
I'm beginning to think
I have a lucky star.
Well, his name is Robert.
- Who'd like more cake?
- Me.
Everything must go.
Solange, it's delicious.
Yes, you're such a good cook.
I can hardly boil an egg.
Haven't cooked for years,
but I've always liked it.
It's fun, and it's relaxing.
Only, Victor is in a sulk.
Usually, when I have guests,
he cooks.
How about some fizz to celebrate?
- But you don't drink.
- So they say.
Tonight, it's champagne!
I propose a toast.
To Robert,
who brought us together.
To Robert!
Came as quick as I could.
A nice mess you're in.
I'll try and get you out.
But I can't promise.
The harassing cleaner
- What's that?
- Today's paper.
"The police caught the harasser
of movie stars red-handed.
"The actresses had already filed
a complaint against Robert Pelage.
"lt appears the crazy fan
is a cleaner at their agent's."
He works at the agency?
That's how he had
the low-down on us.
As Violette would say:
that's wild!
Hey, buddy!
Where have you been?
- Robert Pelage?
- Yes.
It's Mr Martial.
I've always been
very satisfied with you
but the talent agency is furious.
We'll have to let you go.
JOB NEWS
Dad, you've got to find a job.
You think it's that easy.
There you go, buddy.
Now JR is drinking whisky?
It's tough for him too.
Why not set up
your own cleaning company?
I'd need money and who'd lend?
You could at least try.
You always say
you didn't have the choice.
Today you do.
It's sink or swim,
I'd rather you swam.
You've no wife, no job
but you have a daughter
and she's sick of it!
Well, I never.
- Mr Pelage?
- Hi, Anita.
You can't just walk in!
He only receives by appointment!
I won't be long.
Sorry to bother you,
I'll be brief.
You don't know me,
I was your office cleaner.
- Please, Sir...
- It's okay, Joanna.
Now I've been fired,
but the casting was my idea.
Without me, you'd have never
co-starred lsabelle and Solange
and missed out on Violette Duval.
I wanted you to know.
Goodbye.
Joanna?
See you later!
It won't be forever.
We'll keep in touch,
call each other.
You took such good care of me,
I'll never forget it.
But today
I need to find myself anew,
to refocus on my desires,
my urges,
to take my life in hand.
Life and I had lost touch
with each other.
You too need some time out.
See your family again.
I almost forgot!
For you.
Macaroons.
One last time.
Miss Duvivier's secretary speaking.
Your agent.
Your plane.
Augustin is progressing daily,
even saying a few words in French.
We spend hours together,
getting to know each other.
And oddly,
I think I've met someone.
Augustin adores him.
He's a French doctor working here.
I've never felt so good
with any man...
I feel he's Mr Right.
The day it happens, you know.
I'm so happy for you.
You deserve it.
My Gran used to say:
"Men are like oysters.
Not many pearls!"
Dominique?
How are you?
Thanks for coming.
Lovely to see you.
I wanted to make you an offer.
I'd like to be your agent.
With pleasure.
Victor?
Hello, Violette.
Two?
Two.
I hired him.
I needed a new assistant.
Joanna was getting so messy.
And telling lies too.
Thank you, Victor.
He was so down after the break-up
with Solange, I had to.
So, I have a screenplay
for you to read.
The director had chosen
Marie Janson and now...
he's hesitating.
He wants to meet you.
It's a great role.
Thank you.
- It's not sure.
- No, I mean
for choosing me to work
with Solange and lsabelle.
I'd wanted to talk to you
about that too.
I'm lost for words.
We bought all new stuff.
And...
I brought back your Twingo.
When Dominique told us
they fired you,
we had to do something.
And he said the casting
was your idea.
That's wild!
He gave us this for you.
He insisted they give you
a severance package.
Thank you.
It's good, it'll help you
get off to a new start.
Someone got there first.
My wife's moving south
with my daughter.
She's leaving me
for good, for someone else.
And...
you're just giving up?
Not like with my suitors.
You had them running.
She's right.
You have to put up a fight!
Symbolically, of course.
She's made up her mind.
She won't change it.
So, going to sit there
and watch your life get away?
It's time you woke up
and did something.
Robert,
a woman needs a man who'll commit.
I'm not sure I can.
Well, you did it for us.
You were different.
You were distant, untouchable.
You can't love someone who's near?
Is that why your wife left?
My specialty is the head butt.
Create Your Own Company
Ladies' Follies
A few months later...
We're delighted to be here
to present this film
of which we're very proud.
A lot happened during the shoot
that you won't see on screen.
There's one person
we'd especially like to thank,
not here tonight,
but we dedicate the film to him...
Robert.
Good evening.
Two Gourmet Menus
and for the wine, you choose.
Thank you.
Thank you Madam,
enjoy your evening.
Fancy place, this is a first.
So?
What did you have to ask me?
Could I take...
Lucie to a drawing exhibit
on Saturday?
Robert...
You didn't invite me here for that?
Right.
I set up my own cleaning firm
and just got my first contract.
It's not the job I'd dreamed of,
but I've had my fill of dreams.
The life I want is this one
with you.
I know I wasn't up to par,
that I was pretty useless,
or let's face it,
downright stupid.
But I've changed, I'm a new man.
- I even saw a psy-cat-analyst.
- "Psychoanalyst".
No, in fact's she's a...
Forget it.
For me, you've always been,
but for real I want you to be...
my wife.
To Robert... Zidane
Subtitles: Peter Leonard
Subtitling: C.M.C. - Paris