So I've been thinking
a lot about it, and...
I'd really like to start calling you
"Shorty" in public.
By the way, my office is throwing
a party tomorrow, and I would...
- I'd really like for you to be there.
- Well, I have a photo shoot,
but I think I could
come after that.
Oh, yeah,
well, that sounds good.
Who's that?
Hmm?
It's my doctor.
Uh, D-Dr. Cover.
Doc-Doctor Wyland Cover.
He's my oncologist.
- He's an oncologist.
- Hey,
you guys know
anything about cats?
Yeah, I'm trying
to score some points with Daisy,
so I promised to watch
her cat tonight.
They carry disease,
they're obsessed with my nipples,
and they are unwelcome
in this loft.
Did you just say that cats are
obsessed with your nipples?
I've told you this story before.
I think I would have remembered
that story.
No cats.
Come on, bangs,
you sons of bitches.
- Here, let me do 'em, Jess.
- What?
- Nick, Nick, stop.
- Stop, you're gonna ruin it.
- I'm not gonna ruin...
I was... I was making
'em look prettier.
- No, you weren't.
- Then they look perfect as is.
Can I ask you a question?
Absolutely... we having
this thing right now?
- Do I look okay?
- Do you look okay?
- Yeah.
- Hell yeah!
I want to put it on you.
On? Put it on me?
Yeah, on... I stand by that.
I'd like to put it on you.
What is wrong, Jess?
I've been at this new school
for a week now
and I still haven't made
any friends.
There's, like,
a clique of teachers,
and they run the school.
♪ You keep bumpin' me
against the wall ♪
♪ Yeah, I know
I let you slide before ♪
♪ Hey, but until you seen me,
trust me ♪
♪ You ain't seen bouncin' back ♪
♪ You keep bumpin' me
against the wall ♪
I just want them to like me.
I know it sounds dumb, but...
Leave it to me.
I'll fix it.
You're Nick Miller's girl now.
You're my old lady.
- What?
- Whatever you need, you got it.
Why are you talking like
a James Taylor song?
I don't know.
Hey, either of you guys
know anything about cats?
Oh, my God, Schmidt has
the greatest cat story!
- Ugh, I was there... it's disgusting.
- You shut your damn mouth, Jess.
Thought it was cute...
Oh, grow up!
Nothing came out.
♪ Who's that girl? ♪
♪ Who's that girl ♪
♪ It's Jess ♪
3.02 - Nerd
Sync and corrected by Elderfel
www.addic7ed.com
You know what? I've never
actually seen you this happy.
- Who are you?
- I don't know, it's weird.
I've never seen you smile.
Ever.
This is the first time.
It's not bad.
- I mean, it's not great.
- Yeah, I agree.
Somewhere right in the middle.
- Hey, can I ask you something?
- Of course.
Hypothetically speaking,
what if you met somebody
that you... that you liked,
uh, just as much as Jess?
Schmidt, stop.
Okay, you picked Cece,
so let Elizabeth go.
Initially I said
"hypothetically," so just...
Do you know a place I can get
cheap school supplies?
I only have $15
and a halfie...
$15 and a halfie.
- A halfie?
- Yeah, it's a half.
It got ripped, so it's a half.
No one's gonna accept
that as currency.
Hey, what's up, guys?
- Did you press the button?
- I thought you pressed the button!
What is wrong with you?!
- What did you do when you walked in?
- Talked to you.
Guys, I'm gonna go pick up
Daisy's cat.
You know, you don't just ask anybody
to take care of your cat.
That's a very serious thing,
so I decided
I'm gonna go over there
and I'm gonna ask Daisy
to be my girlfriend.
- You are?
- Whoa!
- Yeah.
- Major move!
- Good stuff.
- Look at you, man.
So I'm just gonna go over there
and I'm gonna tell Daisy,
"Listen, my heart is a two-man bike,
and I want you in the rear."
What do you think?
Winston, don't say that.
You want her in your...?
You can say "the rear."
You don't want her in your rear.
No, don't say
"the rear" at any time.
- You guys are just jealous.
- What?
You guys are gonna steal
my swag.
I wouldn't even know how
to begin to steal a swag.
- I thought you pressed the button.
- I've been way over here.
- I-I haven't pressed...
- I'll press the button.
Last night,
I rectified our budget
while taking a long soak
in my new Jacooz.
My elbows are as soft as babies.
I love a soft elbow.
How about you bring
that noise over here.
Good meeting.
Great, well...
Uh...
- Foster's such a dork.
- He needs to get laid.
I got laid.
This morning.
From my boyfriend.
So...
coitus no-one-interruptus.
That... because we finished, so...
Why are you talking to us?
- You have owl eyes.
- Yeah.
Hey!
Trust me.
What's up, teachers?
Who wants free school supplies?
- What are you doing here?
- Point to the ones who don't like you...
- I can handle this myself.
- I'm fixing it for you.
And then she... Yeah.
Say, listen, why don't you guys
come to my bar later for free drinks.
Teachers don't pay.
We'll think about it.
Okay, they'll think about it.
Bye.
Oh, my God.
- That was genius.
- It's a no-brainer.
Whoa, that's an amazing move,
sex partner.
Sex part...
With the promotion, uh,
I got a new office,
so I don't have to look at Bethany's
mismanaged eyebrows all day.
Do you like it?
It's a perfect two-thirds replica
of Don Draper's
office from Mad Men,
and you're my sexy Peggy.
Good God,
at least shut the door.
My tiny credenza is in the way.
Hey, Elizabeth,
are you gonna be coming
to the party tomorrow night?
Party? What party?
The big office party.
Schmidt,
did you not invite her?
I was just about to
invite you to go.
Cool, it's a date.
- Bye, baby.
- Bye.
Mwah, mwah.
How... how dare you interfere
with my personal life,
you crone.
I don't...
I don't kick up a fuss
when you massage yourself
with your yoga ball.
Oh, I'm sorry,
were you gonna invite Cece?
Beth, please. I am in love
with both of these women.
Do I feel bad
about lying to them?
Yes. I'm a Sagittarius.
Congrats on your new office.
Gina gave birth on that carpet.
Consider this closed.
Right, so, yeah, um...
Um, so, Daisy, what I was
really trying to say...
is, uh...
Is your shower running?
Yeah, I was just about
to take a shower.
- What's going on?
- Okay.
Um, Daisy, I think
what we have is real,
and, uh, I want us
to be exclusive...
just you and me in the rear.
Yeah, that sounds great.
Awesome, um...
Sorry, that's mine.
So, Furguson gets
his wet food in the morning,
dry food at night.
Somebody in there?
No.
No treats after midnight.
"Oh, my name is Principal Foster,
and this is
the Jacooz."
"The Jacooz."
He's so nice, don't you think?
He's such a nice boss.
Y'all want some drinks?
- Yeah, okay.
- Yep.
- Yeah. Thank, thank you.
- Thank you.
What do you think?
I think it's going really well.
Okay, I just realized
what's happening.
It's high school over there,
and they're the cool kids,
and you're the nerd.
I was never a nerd.
♪ On western wings
the fowls doth fly ♪
♪ On briny swells
the fishes doth swim ♪
Oh, like you were so cool.
Stall!
Nick! Nick! Nick!
The Miller Sack Pack.
- Miller Sack Pack?
- They made shirts.
You know what? I'm not
explaining my coolness to you.
I was cool. Listen to me.
You want to be in with them?
Roll with the punches,
go with the flow.
Make fun of your boss a little bit.
Don't follow your instincts.
I wouldn't sing.
But most importantly,
follow my lead.
And by "follow my lead,"
I mean drink.
And I mean drink...
a lot.
Drinking to be cool, Nick?
That's not a real thing.
That's the only thing in
the world I know to be true.
Schools are for fools!
They are.
Sometimes firemen are women!
Sometimes! Sometimes!
Hey, there she is.
Ol' Toilet Pants,
the girl who bet herself six dollars
she could dance in a toilet bowl.
♪ Oh, hey, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ What's going on? ♪
I'm cool.
You are cool,
but you still got to go to work,
'cause you're running late,
so up and at 'em.
Hey, Nick, I got to talk to you.
I have a real problem.
- Oh, my God. Did you kill Jess?
- No, no, no, no.
She just got really drunk last night,
and she passed out.
Hey, guys.
- Are you crying, buddy?
- No.
Hey, did he kill Jess?
No, I didn't kill Je...
Okay, remember
when I was so hungover,
I almost missed
my flight for Christmas?
Ah, count it down.
- Three, two, one.
- Two, one.
♪ I believe I can fly ♪
♪ I believe
I can touch the sky ♪
♪ I think about it
every night and day ♪
♪ Spread my wings
and fly away ♪
♪ I believe I can soar ♪
♪ Soar... ♪
- I'm up, I'm up, I'm up.
- Oh, she's awake.
That was beautiful.
Where are my tights?
Uh, in the bathroom
where you barfed.
You sounded
really good there, man.
- Start the band.
- What did you do to her?
I just told her that I thought
drinking would make her cool.
What are you,
a 14-year-old hockey player?
You're supposed to protect her,
not encourage her.
Okay, I am protecting her.
She's my old lady now.
- By turning her into you?
- I'm not...
Yeah, Daisy cheating on me.
Wait, we're using real honey?
So sticky.
Hey, babe!
What a nice surprise!
I came to tell you
that you can't come with me
to the party tonight.
They just told me that it's
employees only. No sig oths.
Just say "significant others."
Maybe you have that kind of time,
but I'm on a tight sched.
Looks like we're gonna go late
here anyway, so no worries.
All right... Shorty.
All right, bring in the bees!
Oh, wait.
The bees are real, too?
Oh, hell no!
Nick, I need your help, okay?
Now, I am no plumber,
but I'm 99% sure that there
was a guy in her bathroom.
So, she agreed
to be exclusive with you...
while the guy she is
obviously sleeping with
was washing his size 15
ding-dong in the shower.
And now you're taking care
of her cat.
Those are the bullet points,
yes.
You know what you got to do
to get yourself out of this situation.
Break up with Daisy!
Yeah. Yeah, I mean, you're
making some very good points.
You know, break up with Daisy.
That's an option.
I was thinking, like,
I'll kill her cat.
Winston.
Yeah, I'm-I'm gonna
kill her cat first.
- Hey.
- I'm gonna kill you.
Hey, it's little Toilet Pants.
Hey, Toilet Pants!
♪ Toilet Pants! ♪
Please stop shouting.
You are so awesome.
I want to show you something.
Oh!
Oh. Oh. Oh.
You're one of us now.
You never have to drink
out of a paper cup again.
Fun mugs.
This one makes me look
like I have a...
- mustache.
- Mustache.
Mustache.
- What's up, Winston?
- Oh, hey, Nick.
You know, I couldn't figure out
the best way to kill Furguson,
so I decided
to just let him choose
how he wants to die.
If only I could get him
to leave that damn sunbeam.
- You're gonna murder a cat?
- Yeah.
- This is a joke, right?
- No.
- This is one of your pranks?
- An eye for an eye, Nick.
A cat for a cat.
But what's the other cat?
My heart.
Where's that big flashlight
you can hit people with?
Also, do we have any meat pieces
that might distract a dog?
Winston,
don't do anything stupid.
- Jess, what are you doing?
- Oh, yeah, yeah. Cool, cool. It's nothing.
We're just breaking
into Foster's backyard,
and we are gonna put
our butts in his Jacuzzi.
You're gonna put your butts
in his Jacuzzi?
- Isn't it awesome?
- Uh, no, it's not awesome. It's a crime.
It's a very stupid crime,
but it's a crime.
Hey, do you have any makeup
or costumes that might
make someone look like a bush?
You are about to commit a felony.
Oh, my God, Nick!
You said roll with it!
You're not the kind of person
who could break
into the principal's house
and get away with it.
You're the kind of person
who gets caught,
and it ends up on the Internet
in a funny way.
My God!
That is the cutest cat!
Uh, don't get attached.
Okay, both of you,
knock it off!
Winston!
Look, Nick, you're right.
I'm a nerd.
I've never fit in.
If I met you in high school,
you never would have even
noticed me.
That's just because
I didn't go to class.
- I wouldn't have seen you.
- I know it's stupid, but I'm doing it.
- I'm not letting you go.
- Oh, you're not letting me?
No.
If for some reason
I don't come back tonight,
I'll be at the Appleton Suites
under the name Suzuki Sinclair.
- Ask for Charles.
- Don't... Hey, hey.
We're not done with this conversation,
young lady!
- Well, we are done!
- Oh, yeah, then where are you going?!
- I'm getting a flashlight!
- Oh, a hammer, huh?
- Hey, Winston, Winston.
- Good way to go. Thr...
- Don't hurt that cat.
- Uh-huh.
- Hey, Furguson? Furguson?
- You scared him. Don't do this.
- Furguson?
- Winston!
Winston, Winston,
stop what you... Stop!
Don't do that scary walk!
Do not do that scary walk
that you do that scares me!
Hey, Jess? Jess?
Je...?
Winston, don't kill that...!
Jess!
I don't know what to do!
- Oh, good Lord.
- What's wrong?
Nothing. You know what?
Let me show you the stairwell
where they got the idea
for the escalator.
Shorty! My love.
My only love.
I'm sorry. I just... I quit that job,
and I had to see you.
How emotional.
Let's go talk about it in private
in a perfect two-thirds replica
of Don Draper's office.
You stay here.
I'm gonna get you a drink.
No, no, no, please,
you-you... you stay here.
- So...
- Oh, God, what?
They're both here.
The gas has been spilled.
All we need is a match.
What, are you narrating a book?
Here it comes.
The long nap.
Oh, wow. Tell you what,
man, we both need to just
cool off and have a drink.
You smoke?
I'm just kidding.
But, man,
that'd be cute if you did.
What is wrong with me?
It...
Oh, Furguson.
So, listen, I've been dreaming
about this fantasy, and I think
this party might be
the perfect place to try it out.
Okay, but I can't get wet.
No water. So, listen, you and I
are gonna be sexy strangers.
Yeah? Now, your stranger is
the early-to-bed type,
and your job has you
on Hong Kong time.
But the most important thing is,
you're the first person
to leave the party.
Whew. I like.
- Wait, is that Cece?
- Is that who?
Huh? No.
- Cece. No.
- No, Schmidt, that's definitely Cece.
Sorry, in between modeling jobs,
she does catering.
You mind if I go over there
and say hello?
I think it's only right.
Eh.
- Hey.
- Hey, I know you told me to stay
in the office,
but Beth insisted that I...
Stay away from that woman.
She is patient zero
in this office
for spreading HPV.
Here. Put on this apron.
No, why-why would I do that?
That's crazy.
My boss was asking, so I
told her you were a caterer.
So... just... It's a good idea.
- Okay.
- Just... Yes.
You really want me here,
don't you?
So badly.
Can we just come back
when we have a plan?
Are you afraid?
No, I'm not afraid.
Rose, give me a boost.
Here's Rose.
I got you.
Oh, my... Oh, my God.
You got to help me a little.
That's a hell of a grip, Rose.
I see the Jacuzzi!
Didn't stick the landing!
You're doing great.
I'm gonna do a loop
to not attract suspicion.
- All right.
Schmidt. I'm right here.
Oh. Do I know you?
Right.
The fantasy.
Boy, I got to go.
I have a 5:00 a.m.
conference call with...
the Asians.
Are you leaving soon, stranger?
You mean "Corporal"?
And, no, I'm gonna stick around
and throw down one more beer.
Sweet.
Oh, hey.
Don't tell me you're leaving.
Whew, great news.
My boss is in her office
completely passed out.
- We finally have the night to ourselves.
- Thank God.
It's getting a little weird here,
right?
Dressed up like this.
That Elizabeth?
Okay, look, Cece,
I-I got to tell you something.
Does Elizabeth... work here?
Yes.
Hey.
We were just talking about you.
The food was good.
Yeah.
I was thinking of
taking some home.
You deserve it.
Okay, well, I'm heading off.
The Asian markets
wait for no one.
Wow.
She was ice cold to you.
I'm gonna go get a drink.
What a night.
- I got this!
- Open the damn gate!
- Everything's under control!
- Jess, hey!
Don't move! I'm coming over!
Rose, move!
Jess, hey. I'm coming.
- I got you.
- Whoa, hey, Rose!
Ease up on the throttle.
Those are my precious goods.
Did you follow me here?
Here I come!
- Nick.
- Hey.
Hey, Jess. Jess, hey.
You okay?
- Yeah.
- I'm sorry I tried
to stick my nose in this.
I just...
I just... I came here
because I'm your old man now.
And if you're gonna do something
that's obviously very stupid...
then I'm gonna do it with you.
Oh.
Oh, my God.
- You go there.
- Ow.
- What's going on out here?
- Hey.
- Who are you?
- No, I-I used to live here.
I was just doing a visit
around the neighborhood.
That's my old bedroom
right there.
That's a bathroom.
To you maybe it is.
But to me and my four brothers,
- that's a home.
- Nick.
Nick, I can't let you do this.
Mostly 'cause you're so bad at it.
- Is that you, Ms. Day?
- Yes.
It is. I'm so sorry.
I trespassed on your property.
And I would not be surprised
if you fired me.
I think I know
what's really going on here.
You heard about
my new... Jacooz.
And you wanted a taste.
♪ And say a little prayer
for right ♪
♪ You know that if we are
to stay alive ♪
Come on in, kids.
The water's hot!
♪ Doo-doo-doo-doo-doo ♪
♪ Doo-doo-doo... ♪
Hey, babe.
Thanks for watching him.
He can be a real pain
in the ass, huh?
Yeah...
Was there a dude
in your shower yesterday?
Yes.
Hmm.
How do you know him?
From sex.
But it was from sex before
you and I were exclusive.
Have you had sex with him since?
No.
Oh, wait. Yes.
Last night.
Look, um...
I really liked you, Daisy.
You know, I wanted this
to be a thing, but, uh...
I deserve better.
And so does Furguson.
Hmm?
I'm keeping the cat.
I got your cat!
Well, Schmidt, you win.
They both really love you.
So... enjoy your office.
- Hey! Toilet Pants!
- Oh!
Toilet Pants!
Thanks for taking the bullet
for us the other night.
How long were you stuck
in that Jacuzzi for?
I don't really want
to talk about it, but, um,
at one point, he did grab
my foot with his toes
like it was a hand.
What are you doing tonight?
'Cause we got a liquid
form of Ecstasy,
and we're gonna grade
papers together. What?
I would love to,
but I actually think
I'm gonna hang out...
with my old man.
That's... weird.
Cool.
- See you.
- Weirdo.
Hi.
So I hear you're interested
in joining the Sack Pack.
I might be.
Then perhaps this will
wet your whistle
of what's fun
about being a member.
- Just leave it.
- Yeah.
You are terrible at Hacky Sack.
I think I'm retiring.
Yeah, I just want to say...
I would've noticed you.
Want to go do it
in the teachers' lounge?
- Yes.
- You do?
Oh, I'm gonna do it
with a teacher!
Shh.
Okay, something is
definitely coming out.
I think we should go.
Sync and corrected by Elderfel
www.addic7ed.com