LITTLE NICHOLAS ON HOLLIDAY
... so now we are
of this school at the end,
I can inform you proudly
we again...
true to Jules Ferry ,
dirty beast to have overtaken in his den
,
in the shadows lurks
and is responsible for all the evil
and all wars,
the beast named
Ignorance.
Constantly we have the noble sword
lifted her of teaching,
and thus fulfilled the mandate
and ours
beautiful and amazing institute
the Republic School !
Because, as courage and virtue are the two legs
where the man his name
worthy to rest
he owes that solely...
his schooling. ..
... And hoping that you
will think about these words
I wish you, dear children,
happy holidays!
Do not forget to make your home work!
Hello, guys, calm down...
Thank you, Mr. Director.
And Bouillo... Mr. Dubon,
where you go on holiday?
Ah no, this year I stay in Paris.
Nice home, very quiet.
That's a real vacation.
Mama?
- Yes, sweetheart?
Where are we going this year
go on holiday?
I have not yet
discussed with dad.
Every year, mom and dad arguing
about where we go
... Because it is better because...
- And every year it's a hassle
No, we're going to...
- To the sea.!
No, we go to the mountains!
- We go to the sea!
I do not know why they do that every time,
because ultimately it is always the same
We go to the mountains!
- We go to the sea!
Come on!
What?
Shoot!
- Yeah, yeah...
But this time it's gone very differently
than usual
I warn you right away,
this year. we go to sea and not otherwise.
That & apos; s good.
- Excuse Me Please?
I think it's good. We go to sea.
And mama goes along.
Mommy Mommy, that's omi
They always want a kiss from me
- Kiss..!
The only omi never gives a kiss,
dad .
Do not bother especially, omi, I'll look
another chair, another newspaper.
Oh, kiss!
Dad finds it particularly irritating
when the conversation is about Georges
... Who I ran into yesterday?
Georges!
Georges is a gentleman who has met mom
when she was little
and she was almost married to,
before she met Dad
Apparently he was very handsome,
very rich and very intelligent
He is still so terribly attentive,
that luscious hair...
And when they talk about him, then
she always ends her sentences with a sigh
Yeah big boy,
I know you'll be a man.
And I hope that I
may experience yet.
Oh, I'm not worried about it, omi.
You bury us all!
A sweet, sweetheart?
- But I think it's fine as Omi's
That's again enough candy, anyway.?
- Dad's right.
You should not eat too many sweets,
you know.
Come on, the last.
The last!
But that was the last but one.
You see, huh?
& Apos; yet a sweet, honey & apos?;
I have warned you anyway ?!
I think it's through that pipe that poor lad is ill.
Here you get within
almost no air!
It is true that smoke
not it will do much good.
Omi take on holiday?
Really no!
- Why is that?
The word & apos; Omi & apos; and the word & apos; & apos holidays;
in the same sense it & apos; s contradiction in terms.
Good, excellent.
Then we pay a young girl.
A young girl, for what?
- To fit Nicholas!
Who will guard him
if we & apos; at night to go out?
And who makes sure that he gets his breakfast
if we & apos; s morning to sleep in?
So that will be one franc 50 per hour,
no one franc 70
it is much more expensive during the holidays.
Yup? So one franc 70...
three times,
three times a week and then...
Yes, yes, it's not fair, what you do.
It's not fair and repulsive!
And old people all summer
leave in the city
with that tremendous heat without someone to talk to
, that you do not find repulsive?
Prima! I am willing to take an adult
on vacation. But not omi.
Hello, Marie-Edwige.
- Hello.
I can not talk to you long
because I'm going on vacation so.
And... where are you going?
- To the sea.
We go to Chamonix,
to Hotel du Grand Soleil.
You can write to me if you want.
Yes, then...
Happy holidays!
Marie-Edwige,
would you marry Nicholas
captain who is on a warship
and who earns a lot of money?
Yes!
... I'll meet you, sir
but again not satisfied!
Dear Marie-Edwige,
since the last time
we've seen each other,
have I thought about you all the time...
And now stop, that's enough!
We're going on vacation without omi!
Hemeltje sweet!
Is it really too much to ask to open a window
do for some fresh air?
Or would you like to see us melt?
No, but now I ask you
what we do here, this is hopeless!
If there is only one way in France.
Oh my goodness...
I'm sorry that I'm doing this holiday.
- Mommy!
I'm hungry.
- Hold on, Nicholas!
I do not want to be annoying, but if
cooler was not put in the trunk,
I could give a banana to Nicholas.
- Oh yes, a banana!
No! We would go picnicking,
so we have a picnic!
And for this we must first of this file!
Hopla!
Beware, beware still on!
Soon we are all sick!
Yes! Dad, you're the best!
That's what I call at least make a decision.
Look! They all do our post!
What is this now?
It is a cow.
That's a cow.
Never seen before?
- Hey, hey, Nicholas!
That's what happens when you think
you're smarter than the rest...
Why did you bring us back here?
This is unbelievable!
- You see that it has been blocked for ?!
Oh, come on! Come on, do something!
Where are you going now ?!
Look at what you do!
- Do not you worry, I can do this.
And there, daddy, that's not a good place for a picnic
?
That's what I told him. Okay.
Sorry.
Fine, thank you, sir.
Can you come, please?
There is a problem.
You have not reserved a room for omi!
- Nicholas, please.
Apparently there is no room
reserved for mom.
What is this nonsense ?!
I'm sure I have booked three rooms
, two with a connecting door.
I just called the agency,
they say no.
For me anyway reserved
but two rooms, not three.
I do not understand.
- It makes sense. I have sometimes.
If I have to do what I do not want to,
I think I did it,
but I did not do it.
Well, here is another place for me
or I go back home?
Nicholas shares his room with Mommy,
arranged.
The phone call, you want to pay now or
I put it on the bill?
On the account.
- Very Well.
What is that heavy suitcase!
Honey, I think it
is a fantastic holiday.
Mommy! Mommy!
Walk me not for the feet!
Ms.
... Sir... - Thank you, ma'am.
Just arrived? Nice to meet you.
Colonel Dubourtoumieux.
- Pleasant.
You should know that this morning...
- Well, are you coming?
Aye! Ladies...
He might colonel,
but at home he is not the boss.
Well, one again.
Georges Except, of course.
- Mom, what do you want as a starter?
What raw?
- Ah, that was once a man. A real...
Elegant, refined,
courteous, generous,
charming! Remember how he was sporting
, sweetheart?
You might want beetroot, celery salad
?
He even won a gold medal,
the French tennis champion.
From Normandy, Mom.
And it was ping pong.
Also good.
- Yup.
Excuse me, I might borrow
the salt, please?
But of course!
- Danke schön
Also, mustard, pepper, maybe.?
- Nein, danke
What.?
- Give her immediately Alsace and Lorraine.
Come on, that is lackluster.
Well, we will order?
What do you want, Nicholas?
- No pull.
Is anyone there?
Is anyone there ?!
Omi snore, I can not sleep.
Omi sleeps, it sounds like a tractor.
- Concentrate on sleep
than it succeeds within five minutes.
So, hup.
What was wrong with him?
- Nothing At All. Go to sleep.
I can not concentrate on sleep,
for now it sounds like a tractor
whose engine is stalling,
only omi stores never finished.
Bowl.
- Oh no!
But he can not sleep...
The seven, seven,
heard you
Of the seven leap
He says I can not dance
But I can dance like a nobleman
That's one...
Dear Marie-Edwige, I hope
that you have a nice holiday
Here's the good weather every day .
At least, almost every day
In any case,
I have a lot of friends
Blaise, walking I do not for the feet!
You've Blaise, who is not on vacation
because they live here
Hotel Beau Rivage, hello?
Blaise, do not walk in my way!
Then there is Crépin, who cries all the time
Crépin, why are you crying?
- They took my shovel!
- They do not want to play with me!
Crépin, why are you crying?
- I do not know!
You have Djodjo
Djodjo and his parents
came here
because their is no sun .
Hi, my name Djodjo
and I come from Stratford-upon-Avon,
the city of Shakespeare.
From what? From whom?
- From Shakespeare.
Sjekkie muscle?
- Ah, diseased muscle...
No?
- No no.
And then you have Fructueux who eats everything
Even if it lives...
... even if it is dirty...
... and even if it already by someone else
is eaten
And then you have Côme ,
who always wants to be right
and that is really annoying
- But four times per day
and every six hours, which is the same.
- No, that's not the same.
That's the same! How So?
I'm not going to say.
Dad is very happy that he is on vacation
That is to see,
because he laughs much more often than other
Um,  Guten Tag...
Hello.
- If you do not swim?
Yes, but not here.
Sweetheart!
- Mama...
is exactly as otherwise
- And.?
Except that she has never had a bathing suit
But why do you have a bathing suit?
Are you going to swim right now?
Coincidentally, this cap and this swimsuit
a unique set
I bought at the & apos; Young Designers & apos;
Of the New Gallery.
If this must be unique then,
because I hope it...
No, but it might be best...
- Yes, of course it can!
& Apos; A unique set, for a unique woman & apos;.
With my friends I play,
we quarrel,
We're not talking to each other,
and it's really cool
Wait for me,
I can not run in the sand!
Kiss.
Wait a minute, boys, this is
if not succeed.
Build your castle,
or any structure whatsoever,
you start with the foundation.
I will show you.
It is my profession, I am an architect.
Look at that!
Can we now play with?
- Sure guys, it's there for.
But...
Look, this is for Aunt Olga.
Mama?
- Yes, sweetheart?
What & apos; vacuum & apos; in the second person plural
of the pluperfect?
The second person plural,
that's you...
So is history...
you stofzuigden,
and the pluperfect
is it...
& apos; you have vacuumed & apos ;?
No, & apos; & apos ;. dust sucked
No.
No, & apos; & apos ;? gestofzogen
Stofgezuigd?
Listen Nicholas,
you should come out for yourself!
Your mother is right: if you want to be independent
, you just save you.
Exactly.
Would not it be good if I
a ticket send to Mr. Moucheboume?
Come on, you do not go now
think of your boss, we are on vacation.
Yes, but it is thanks to the good relationship I have with Mr.
Moucheboume
that's possible, that holiday.
- But he did not leave paid out.
What do I write? Mr. Moucheboume,
dear Mr. Moucheboume...
Oh no! You're not kidding!
- I just ask for your opinion,
it should not be subject in any case
.
What does that mean, topics?
- That means spineless
and docile, like a slave.
You go back to sleep,
I'm fine.
& Apos; Dear sir Moucheboume,
I hope it goes well with you.
We celebrate with you a wonderful holiday.
Greetings family
and thanks.
Sincerely & apos.;
And?
It's good...
Not to topics?
It is a design?
- No.
No, topics...
That means... you're doing very obsequious.
Ah, okay. Oh...
No, you can not say that it is, huh?
Yes, and still warm, right?
- Hell yeah. Yeah...
Sure...
Say, who is that heckler?
It is a film producer,
an Italian.
He's working on a movie.
But anyway, I'd like your opinion.
If you were to send a card to your boss,
how would you begin?
Mr. thingy, dear sir thingy,
or my dear sir thingy?
Chances that do not arrive.
- How Come?
This is not because I'm the boss here.
Yes, but imagine...
- Even if I do that will not arrive.
I understand, but imagine
that you are no longer in charge.
No, I am always the boss.
- But only to help me,
if you were not the boss...
- I understand it very well.
If you were me...
- Are you a boss?
No.
- Then I can not be. I'm a boss.
Yes, but if you assume...
- No, but there is nothing to take.
They will not arrive, that's all.
The boss here, that's me.
But... - No.
No.
Four fünf, sechs, sieben
Wo ist denn mein Freund geblieben
Ist niece here ist nicht da
Ist wohl in America
Bravo!
- What is this?
You could reserve a table.
- Do not worry!
That'll be fine.
There is certainly still room.
Well, that was... Come on, boy.
Auf Wiedersehen
Walk me not for the feet!
Look, there's still room behind.
Go and ask if we thereby may sit.
Are you sure?
I do not believe that there really is so much space...
You just ask them politely
to slide a bit, that's all.
They have no desire to move on...
- Hey, Broekie!
Broekie! Broekie shit!
- Excuse Me Please?
They called us because you like a hare
ran off as soon as there was a fuss!
Do not you know who I am?
Bemique!
Bemique,
of Anatole France school!
Those tadpoles in the café
Mrs. Lantern!
That warps into the spaghetti in the canteen!
And the Office of the math teacher!
We had sawn in half!
- We were suspended for three days!
Bemique!
- Broekie! Come sit with us
we'll push on.
Yes, come!
Is this the first time you come here?
- Yup.
Normally we go... to the mountains.
This was a good choice, here is better.
There is nothing like the sea!
And say what you want, the prices are reasonable.
- Like?
Yes! And you can say what you want
but the weather is not worse than elsewhere.
Since we have arrived, it is indeed almost every day was beautiful.
And it will continue! You do not really here
to the Côte d & apos; to desire Azur.
Besides, the Côte d & apos; Azur
is vastly overrated anyway. Do not you?
Just look how sweet they are, those two!
Boy, & apos; t be love at first sight!
- Yes, those two get married fixed!
You see, my dear, one less worry.
He is under the tiles.
Nicholas, you take Isabelle
to your husband?
No! No! No!
You are now the real
linked.
Dear Marie-Edwige,
our love is in danger
Mom and dad have decided
to me forcing to marry
But do not worry, I will do everything
to stop that terrible plan .
That pulls up, you know.
- Sure.
It is but a speck and,
that never lasts very long.
My parents want to force me to marry.
- They can not do at all!
Well. Forced marriages
still exist.
And even if you're big, they're still
your parents who decide who you marry.
You should just be a priest.
Because you are not allowed to marry.
I do not think Marie-Edwige
that's okay.
I know what! You must ensure that the parents of the girl
you no longer want.
Because then they cancel the marriage.
- And how do I do that?
For example, I know my sister
courtship had a boy,
and when my parents saw that he drank,
if my sister never see him again.
Yes, parents are always worried that their daughter
going to marry an alcoholic!
I'm not an alcoholic?
These are chocolates with liqueur.
My mother said I was not allowed to come to
because alcohol is in.
If you eat this,
you drunk at dinner.
And what happens?
Oh, baby...
Say, we heard that the little one was sick.
He has abdominal pain.
Fixed gesnoept too.
Snoepertje, how can that be?
My poor honeybun...
Poor darling...
The failed. They are super worried.
She even called him her darling...
- No!
I swear.
We have to go, I made reservations for 8 hours.
- We can not leave yet Nicholas.
No, that poor baby.
But Isabelle can stay with him.
However, sweetheart?
- Of Course!
Do not worry, darling,
Isabelle stays with you.
And we come back immediately after eating.
Come on, calm but out.
Kiss.
Kiss?
I'll explain. It's like this:
the parents of the girl always look
or the parents of the boy have money.
If the parents of the boy really have a lot of money
, you want the girl's parents
anxious that their daughter marry this guy.
But if the parents of the boy
not have much money, then yes
prohibit the girl's parents
her to see the boy
and they say he is badly brought up, but that
it is not, it is because he is poor.
What? Should you crying so?
- No, the sun is shining in my eyes!
So, what should I do?
- Let them believe that you are poor.
Okay, Nicholas?
- Yes...
Since it appears not. What is up?
Do not have a nice holiday?
Yes, but & apos; t be sorry
that it is the last...
The last? Why the last?
- The problems of dad.
He says that after this holiday
can not.
Does he have problems, your dad?
- Yes, since he was fired from his job
because his boss, Mr. Moucheboume
,
who left with all the money.
- He left with the cash?
Yes, and even with his secretary.
- Yup?
Yes, but Dad said it was not very
because we had money put aside
that we could use it until he had a new job again.
So I asked what they
that money we put aside.
Dad laughed, but not mom.
- How Come?
Because Omi had gone to the casino with
aside money
And when dad was completely white.
Wow.
- And since come almost every week
men in gray suits knocking at our home.
We can not move,
then it seems we are not there.
But... what does your dad than
to get food?
Well, sometimes he steals.
- He Steals?
He must. Sometimes my mom says
nothing to eat,
so then my dad goes to the supermarket
and then he steals food.
And sometimes we go to bed without supper.
And I dream & apos;
night I eat a plum cake.
That was my favorite tail,
at the time we were not poor.
Please. Bon Appetit.
- Thank you
Please, enjoy!.
Good evening. We share the table?
Um, actually...
- We have already begun.
Does not matter. Enjoy it.
- You too.
Look, there is still room behind.
- Sorry, I can not.
Broekie! Come in anyway.
We'll get out.
Come, come.
If yes.
What you take?
Lobster or crab?
Go ahead, I invite you.
- I still do not.
Yes, why?
- Because I think that's fine!
And we want our children to have a good
vacation without worry.
Come on, for better times!
Okay, cheers.
What do you say, Nicholas?
- This does not smell good.
What a beautiful ring...
- Yes, a family heirloom,
I've had it for years.
And you would not want to sell him?
- Never in my life!
And that adorns you, though!
You do not lose your self-respect because
rotbazen who have no conscience!
That's pretty hard... You know, the
are people too, just like all the others.
They have their weaknesses, but also their qualities. Even So?
Exactly, but still...
- In any case, you always defend him.
Yes, well! You accept everything from him.
I really need to say
that Mr. Moucheboume,
the boss of my husband...
No, we do not know.
- Indeed, they do not know.
They do not know...
I have to admit that I admire
for your courage and your integrity.
Thank you, but...
Yes! And I'll say something.
When we were in school,
you were not my best friend...
I know.
- If you & apos; t ask me today, you're it.
Similarly .
- And you and I, we stay together.
Shall we finish the evening in the casino?
- No!
I mean, we have a lovely evening
and let's enjoy the moment.
Meals.
- Thank u.
I love to do!
It is very much.
I do it gladly.
Better weather than yesterday, huh?
- Sorry, we don & apos; t speak French
Ah, no French...
Excuse me..
Are you from this area?
- Verzeihung, ich kein spreche Französisch
I said,  you are from the  area.?
Now I talk in English while...
Well, never mind, never mind.
What do you want?
- There are still here real Parisians.
I come from Normandy. What would you like to order?
- Very nice, Normandy.
I will say that I am not a Parisian
. I come from the Franche-Comté.
My mother, who was...
- You can still think for.
Hello.
- You go fix swim in your secret place.
Yes. Would you like to participate?
Yes.
I understand. It is magnificent.
And it is especially very quiet.
But you must remain silent, this is my secret.
- I swear word.
Do you naturalism?
- Eh, naturalism...?
Yes. I love the nature,
everything, the trees, the...
- That & apos; s beautiful. I do too.
Ah, I understand, naturalism...
Will you?
Come on! You're not scared or something?
Am I afraid?
No, certainly not. Well no.
I'm coming.
- I'll see you at the rocks.
Come on over, the water's lovely!
Look who's here.
Beautiful day.
- Aye!
It will not take long, but well...
- Would you mind?
Wait, I'll help you.
It's good, thank you.
- You're welcome.
We wish you a good day.
- You too.
Greetings to your wife.
- I will definitely do.
Kiss.
There is a solution: make them go away.
- That they leave?
Yes, because they see your parents no longer
and forget marriage.
We need to find something they are afraid of,
because they go there like a hare.
I know what.
- No, I know what!
What do you know?
- I do not know, but what did you say?
We put a snake in their bed.
- A snake?
What are these snakes?
- Those are vipers.
Vipers?
- If they are here, the mother is not far.
And you what?
How to catch a viper?
- You see what?
Is there a snake?
What... What do you see then?
Say something!
I'm certainly not afraid, but you might well have come up with something better than
catch a viper.
Have an already caught?
Hey, guys,
there is a snake here until...
Are they friendly, vipers?
- After a bite, you are within 5 minutes dead.
The snake! Turn around, guys!
What should we do now?
Eggs! Which are still there.
We hide them in the room of Bemique
and when they come, packed with snakes!
- Yes, good idea.
Oh, no...
& apos; It's strange, he did not reply.
- Who?
Mr. Moucheboume.
And I clearly had this address put on it.
Maybe mislaid.
Or worse, has as & apos; s office
pummel him just
done in the trash,
that happens often...
If I send another one there now...
- Is it done talking about that card?
Really, this is just too childish!
- Childish?
I do not understand what is childish to that.
- You're right, it's not childish.
Thank you.
It's subservience.
Slowly from the helicopter.  Pronti
Yes, slowly... Come, come.
Slow... Brilliant!
Come, come, come...
Sei bella sei superba...  So!
With the lips forward. Very good!
Sei fantastica, sei sublimation
Sei superba... Via! Sei sublimation... Via
Dio quanto amo questa donna
Is she pretty? I can not hear you!
Is she beautiful ?!
- Yeah, sure, she is very beautiful!
Bellissima bellissima
You are my actress,
you're my star!
Yes, the champagne, let it flow, let it flow...
& apos; Dear sir Moucheboume...
I hope it goes well with you.
We celebrate with you a wonderful holiday.
Greetings family
and thank you.
Yours & apos;.
What a wretch...
& apos; Mr. Moucheboume,
Because of the indifference and contempt
you compared me has shown,
despite all these years
loyal service from my side,
I see no other way out,
than this to offer my resignation,
immediately and not negotiable
And while I'm working, you should know
I've always hated
that hysterical hyena laugh of you & apos;.
Boss! A whiskey!
I have no whiskey.
Then, a glass of cider...
Yes, that's very good.
Sure.
Look at, since he's like,
I will give him.
Mr. Moucheboume.
Hello?
- My good man, so good
Yes, thank you?.
- Fine, very fine.
I wanted to thank you for your postcard.
That does me good
Yes, that really touches me
Not everyone is so thoughtful.
So yes, I want to say.
- But it was not necessary...
Yes! It's very important!
Because we all work hard and you'll
not always have time for this kind of thing, right?
Besides, equip nice because I have
big plans for you when you return.
Do you have plans?
- Yes. Big plans
But they will
when you get back, okay
For now, enjoy it!
Happy holiday!
Thank you, sir Moucheboume.
Goodbye, Mr. Moucheboume.
Look there! Look there!
Mr. Bemique? Mrs. Bemique?
The door!
But first you must swear
that if something goes wrong,
you never tell my parents
it was my idea.
I swear word.
Look good,
this is the direction of the shower.
And that is the direction of the water
to the sewer. Crépin, come here.
If we connect two pipes
together, they will be surprised
if the next time they take
shower.
Come on, get to work.
- I'm on hold.
Thank you.
Here.
You should & apos; m lost.
Bracelet Marie-Edwige.
That I searched for a few days.
Thanks.
But... why do not you say something?
Because...
I'm shy.
Actually, Isabelle is a crazy girl
The rest of the afternoon we went together
and it was really enjoyable .
Hey, look!
The boys were in the beginning
not so happy...
What is she doing here?
- Why did you take her?
We do not play with girls.
- When it comes, we do not talk to her.
But they changed quickly feel
And then they all wanted her
show what they could
Hey, Isabelle, look!
Isabelle, look!  Look
Hey, look, look!
Isabelle, look!
It does not even hurt!
Okay, see you tomorrow.
- Yes, tomorrow.
She is lucky, Marie-Edwige...
Nicholas, you take Isabelle
to your husband?
Yes!
The shower!
This is the first time something like this happens.
I swear, it's the first time.
I do & apos; t not, I check everything.
- The bill!
I have not counted the scrambled eggs.
Damn, do not believe it!
What is that, as & apos; s thing?
- This is the distributor.
The mechanic was called. It's a friend.
He will make him quickly.
The sheets are changed.
- And we have repaired the pipes.
See?
Everything is cleaned from top to below
.
No, no, no!
But stop, stop it!
No, no, no, no!
No!  Non è possibile
This is incredible. I've been three times
read the same sentence.
Would you briefly at the man say he
is not alone on this beach?
I?
- Yes you.
That makes no sense.
They must have a permit.
A license which,
ruin our vacation?
It will not really last long.
In movies they never work very long.
Silence please, please!
Baby,
I love you, you know that, right?
But what did I say?
Did I tell military?
No! Exactly! I said more mysterious,
more sensual, more wa-ter-like...
If we do it again? Are you ready?
Camera!
Action!
No! No, stop it!
Stop it!
Who pulls me now something ?!
Okay, that's enough.
But darling...
I said mermaid, not jellyfish!
Again.
Sorry to interrupt
middle of this... whatever it is...
Head in & apos; t water.
... But you make quite a lot of noise.
Camera!
Hello, I'm talking to you!
I do not know who you are, sir, but this is not Cinecittà
! This is Mers-les-Bains!
Stop yelling like a polecat
because the people here are on vacation.
Is & apos; t clear?
You see, it is not so difficult.
Excuse me,
I am the personal assistant
Mr. Massimo Massini,
the famous producer with whom you...
had a short meeting,
and Mr. Massini
apologizes to. He was not aware of the noise
he caused.
He lets say it him very sorry.
Five minutes longer, then I was gone.
And I can tell you that...
To apologize, Mr. Massini
want to invite you
at the party that he organized tonight
in the Mocambo club.
He would like to see them anxious.
What is he thinking!
- Why not, come on.
Maybe it's what? Just tell
Mr. Dinges we will think about it.
What? We have not been out once
in this holiday. Now you do.
And that little black dress of the funeral
Aunt Simone
that was good for you. Did you join?
Uncle Albert was getting compliments.
- Say Yes, he had lost the plot,
he held me for the young aunt Simone.
- Does not matter, & apos; t got you beautiful.
Yes, a funeral dress
for an evening at the Mocambo,
that is not particularly suitable either ?!
Have him or not?
- Yes, I have it with me.
Dad?
How did mommy and you meet?
Have I ever told you?
- No.
It was during a ball.
- A ball?
No one dared to ask your mother.
She was so beautiful and that shocked everyone
off and then I collected all my courage
and went to her.
- And have you danced?
Oh yeah, all night.
So long that they had to throw
us out to make us stop.
And you go dancing tonight?
- Yeah, sure!
Look how beautiful is your mother.
Well, shall we go?
Can I watch TV tonight?
- No TV. Nine hours to bed, as always.
Not too long, huh. Kiss?
I have the whole evening to dad
and mom thought
I told myself that they were lucky
they are so in love
and they establish a good night
would
I feel this is going to be nothing.
Shall we not go back?
Relax anyway, we would have
good night and we'll have that too!
Will you dance, baby?
- Hold on, do not be silly.
I get a glass for you,
then you feel more secure.
Wait here, I'll be.
Ma'am! You're there. Massimo
absolutely want to see you, but you will come along.
Maestro
- s
Madam.!
Thank you. My husband is just as...
- I insist!
Champagne for the woman who is more expressive
,
more articulate,
and convincing than I have ever met!
That seems a bit exaggerated, huh.
- No, I never exaggerate.
Life itself overreacting.
Drink anyway!
But I must always be careful with alcohol...
- Drink anyway!
What does a glass of champagne?
- It costs nothing, sir.
& Apos; s a private party of Mr. Massini.
- Ah, very good.
Then two glasses of champagne happy.
Thank you.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Her hair is magnificent:
a lot of relief and contrast.
It works beautifully on screen.
- Keep agree with that fiddling!
She is certainly not a commodity, ¶?
No, indeed, not really.
- Sit down, ma'am.
When I saw you at the beach today,
was truly a revelation.
I said to myself:  donna che
This is a woman! I need her!
Why, her will I need?
Yes, for my film!  Quale altra cosa
Yes, what other  cosa
What other  cosa,  eh no?.
For & apos; & apos ;, my film which film?
Excuse me, excuse me, excuse me.
This is private, sir.
Yeah, but I have
at my wife there.
It's private.
Yes, but my wife is.
Sweetheart!
It is a beautiful story,
quella di una donna... molto forte,
molto bella, molto molto innamorata...
Cause eh, I will explain, we are
er...
Non sono  actress.  No. No  actress.
That's not important!
Absolutely not,  niente
What counts is the temperament, character...
But why  niente,
not  niente.
I've done a little theater
when I was young at the lyceum,
but if you compare that...
Do you think I'm an amateur?
A sucker? A  piece of shit
No, not at all.
- I produced fifteen movies!
In Rome they call me on the street after
Maestro, Maestro
American actresses from Hollywood by plane
to audition with me!
I? I do not even get!
This lasts for a year, you hear it?
One year I've been looking
to the heroine of my film.
And today I found her:
that is you.
Volcano wife, the wife Storm,
the mother, the sister, the beloved,
all in one body!
Dance with me!
That's my wife.
Come on, that's my wife!
- Okay, that's enough!
Sweetheart!
Why is not Mommy there?
She wanted to stay.
- Why So?
She liked it.
- Do not you?
No, I do not.
But she comes back when she has had enough?
You know, Nicholas, with mom and dad,
occasionally...
No, because in the beginning...
fine...
or that you believe...
you imagine that...
but it's not as simple as
life so you want different things
and not necessarily at the same time so...
Yes, so try to fit you,
your compromises...
Mrs. ,
promise me to think about my proposal
.
You can be a star,
a big star!
I promise. I'll think about it.
That's enough! Naughty rascal!
Give me some time,
I have to think about.
We scrambled eggs
excluded.
And the cake either. Hey, baby?
And if you want to come back again,
then you get the blue room
which has sea views.
- So it's true? You leave?
What a pity!
- Yes & apos; t be sorry.
Once a stubborn, always a stubborn, eh?
Come here, man, I liked it.
Yeah, me too.
And I hope it will be okay, right?
With what?
- Yes uh...
weather!
- Well yes, it pulls up.
Hey, that it attracts?
- Yes, it does go up, it does not take long.
There is plenty of cases, the beautiful weather
is coming, that is coming back.
It's really unfortunate that you're leaving, but yes.
Especially now that the good weather is coming.
It's crazy, but I find no
portfolio or checks.
Oh no?
No.
Oh no.
What annoying, say.
- Yes, this is very annoying.
Stand up.
It seems that we still
a few days stay longer.
I have to call the bank to ask for new
checks.
Prima.
I Put it on the bill?
With good bills, good friends.
You know, when I grow up I'm
captain on a ship
and I earn a lot of money.
And then we go to a lot of wonderful places
,
like Tahiti or Le Havre.
At least...
if you want.
Okay?
You know, I'm a little thirsty.
Perhaps you want to get a cocktail for me at the bar?
A fruit cocktail.
With pineapple and coconut.
What are you waiting for? Sweetheart?
How is it for you to be a star?
I believe you paid a lot attention to
something only a rumor.
Excuse me, excuse me.
- He has yet offered a role...
Sorry...
- but maybe,
I do not know how to say it,
it all went so fast.
I realize not completely
all what happens to me.
Here, darling, your cocktail.
Thank you, honey, that's sweet
but I'm in an interview!
It is certainly true that you carry with you
things that you ignore, and suddenly,
one day, then someone, or actually a man
reveals you to yourself and become
another woman, another person.
That person who slept deep inside,
and who only waited on
to thrive,
to come to life.
And that's really nice to feel that finally
,
to have a new life...
Oh no...
But...
nobody...
Tonight,
before the end of the holiday,
a big masked ball
Hotel Beau Rivage
Tomorrow we go away and then
we will never see each other.
No, it is not inevitable!
- What is a disaster?
That life forces us to something we do not want.
As beetroot meal, for example...
But we can do something about it.
- What?
We go to the fort, on the edge of the forest
. No one will find us
and we can calm and happy life.
I do not know.
Why, are you afraid?
- No it is not.
What is it?
You are not free.
& Apos; Best Marie-Edwige,
I know this letter your
grief will do... & apos;
No, & apos; much grief
but unfortunately,
I make it out...
forever & apos;.
- You sure?
& Apos; for I do not love you...
but Isabelle & apos;.
So now your name.
They will not be very happy.
- Yeah, so.
Join me now ?!
Mummies, what a good idea!
No,  is the context
due to sunstroke.
Devils, that & apos; s...
You scared me.
- And? Looks good, huh?
Mrs....
Sir?
Come dance.  Scusi...
No more rabbits.
And I can not find them.
There is no more in this wild forest.
Health.
I do not sleep anymore.
I do not eat more!
Come with me!
Let's go, right now!
Rome will be at your feet!
After Rome, Hollywood!
Where are you going?
- I'm going to see where Nicholas is.
Yes, is good.
We just need a little tidying up.
Yes.
Help  agree!
Watch out!
- You still arrested him reversed!
& Apos; It's finished! Will you eat?
I'm coming.
I am trying to candles to stabbing.
& Apos; Dear mom and dad, with Isabelle
I decided to flee together
live where nobody can find us.
In the beginning, I did not get married,
but I changed my mind.
Do not be sad,
because we are very happy. Nicholas & apos.;
When Isabelle was the same on her bed.
And she has her briefcase along
with her clothes.
This was bound to happen.
Yes, with what he has to endure because of you,
is logical he flees!
And with my daughter in the bargain!
- What must endure my son?
Stop this with the charade!
You let your family live in poverty.
What? I let my family live in poverty?
Exactly!
Everyone knows that you're broke.
I broke?
- Yup.
Stop! When Nicholas and Isabelle
fled,
we must find them as quickly as possible.
- You are right.
We need to start a search.
- I'll call the police.
Yes, hurry up. Out of the way!
Tell!
Where are they?
The first one says they are to
the old fort on the edge of the forest,
who gets a bash!
- Come on!
We take my car,
that much faster.
Thank you, Commander. Do it quickly.
Yes, on the bill!
Nicholas!
Ma'am,
wait for me!
Nicholas!
Halt!
Well, we drive them into a corner, then
can not withdraw them.
You, this way,
and you, come with me!
Isabelle?
- Nicholas?
Hey, you! What are you doing?
I said, on a line!
- Of course, but I'm...
buts Nothing! Obey!
- But I...
No, I...
But I... - Come on! Hurry up!
Shoot! Hurry up!
I'm cold.
- Yes me too.
Are we going back?
RISK TO LIFE
Ma guarda, va a fare una gentilezza
all personel
Ma almeno aspetta...
- Nicholas!
No!
No, shut up, Massimo!
I beg you, do not say a word.
Since our evening I am no longer myself.
It is as if the heavens opened
me.
Rome, Hollywood, champagne,
the lazy life,
you're irresistible.
That you indeed for everyone.
But...
I'm not going with you, Massimo.
No.
Because I know you, Massimo.
And I know what kind of guy
you have been.
I've met anyone so when I was 20.
His name was George.
He was clever, funny, ambitious...
But it was too much.
He did everything he was all.
And I...
& apos; t is simple,
but I no longer existed.
And then there was this other guy who was there
a sudden, without noise, without fanfare...
He was shy, awkward,
a bit irritable, but .. .
but I... how do I say...
him...
I felt myself.
So I chose him.
And that is the choice I want to make today
again.
Because in the end...
I love him.
No, do not insist! This is my decision,
I hope you respect that.
Thanks for the great things you
said, but I believe I have to go now.
And I think it is better that we do not see each other
. Farewell.
Fiddlesticks!
What kind of a beast!
Stand, bunny.
Come to Daddy.
Stay back, bunny!
What should imagine this!
There's not a fortress at all!
They have kept us fooled.
If that child had a father
which was less strict,
things like this would not happen.
I think Nicholas has just the father
he needs.
In any case, I chose that for him
and I like the drop
no reflection on my choice.
Come, I'm tired.
Kiss?
Walk me not for the feet!
You come yet?
- Yup.
I do not want to return home!
- I'll just leave you here!
I do not want you to leave me here!
- Eight hundred,
nine hundred, thousand, eleven hundred and twelve
, please.
My grandmother always said:
& apos; He who pays his debts,
enriched themselves & apos ;.
- That's right.
Well, then, goodbye but, hey.
- Yeah, see you then.
No grudges?
Okay, no grudges.
Ah, the phone!
That's still 53 francs.
Yes, yes, yes, but...
Wait, I'll handle it.
- No it is not.
I just...
- Quiet. Would you & apos; t do it for me.
How much is it?
53, exactly.
Very well. 50...
No thank you, I do not like.
When I get back I'll write every day.
Your promise?
Here.
Then you can always think of me.
What are you doing?
And you?
Come on, over three days, they come back.
That will take another century.
Vacation is fine, but it's always good
to come home, huh?
What are you doing?
- Yes, I relax.
No, there's no time for that.
We must unpack the suitcases, bring to the basement
sleeves get off, replace carpet,
you can not rest now.
But we certainly do not hurry.
- Tomorrow you'll be back in the office
And then I have to do everything alone.
No way! Do you hear me?
They may, however, she is tired.
& apos; Dear Isabelle,
here life goes on,
but I think you all the time... & apos;
Hello, Nicholas.
Hello.
Did you have a nice holiday?
- Yup. And you, you had a nice holiday?
Did you get my letters?
I had made a mistake in the address.
But did you really write me?
- Yup. And several times even.
That's nice.
You have become golden brown.
If you want you can play with me Thursday.
& apos; Isabelle, I hope the good
are you
Here is the weather
. with a few clouds.
For tomorrow they expect downpours
with a few sunny spells
Signed: Nicholas & apos;
Dear Isabelle,
I know that you will do a lot of sadness...
but I've been thinking...
we better stop writing.
Forever.