Nina was only away for 3 years.
Nina, you're looking well.
London must agree with you.
- The prody girl returns.
- It's been a long time, girlfriend.
But in that time everything has changed.
Dad used the restaurant as
collateral for a bet?
In his defence he was up to his eyes.
- He knew what he was doing.
- He was desperate.
"The Taj" meant everything to my dad.
Now, Nina's cooking up a plan to
save the restaurant.
Got the competition coming up.
Sanjay's in the final.
And all she needs,
is a little competition.
He wanted to win that trophy
for the third time.
Just imagine "The Taj"...
competing again.
Just imagine?
- Who are we up against?
- OK: The "Bengal Tiger".
Pussycat...
- Unless it's under new management.
- It is.
Last year's winners.
And then last, "The Jewel in the Crown".
- It's in the bag.
- Oh yeah, it's in the bag.
Let's eat.
Now, Nina's cooking up a storm...
How dare you come back here and
start disrupting our lives?
...spicing up the competition...
- It's delicious.
- It's terrible.
...and stirring up trouble.
Sanjay's a black belt curry master.
So what? Nina is a curry ninja.
Get ready for a romantic feast
rich with the taste of life,
love and spices.
- Well?
- It's better.
I hope you're firing on all
cylinders tonight, Sanjay.
Always follow your heart.
That's lovely.
It's now or never, Nina.
- Catchy title.
- Aye! And we're gonna blow them away.
Always measure the spices first, pettit.
Six cloves.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
Eight chillies.
Half a tea spoon of turmeric.
Keep it stirring.
Keep it moving.
Cover every inch with the sauce.
There's no need to rush, Nina pettit.
Always take your time.
That's the difference between
winning and losing.
Now, close your eyes.
Taste it. Taste it in your heart.
No matter what the recipe says, pettit,
always follow your heart.
Best chicken xacuti this
side of Maryhill.
One day, pettit, you're going to be
the best cook in Glasgow.
Nina Bina
(hindi: dear).
You look awful.
So do you.
It's been a long time, girlfriend.
I'm so sorry, darling.
We are here today to say goodbye
to a very special man.
Mohan Shah was a devoted husband
and a loving father to all of his children.
Especially his Nina.
Out of sight, but never out
of her father's heart.
Many times Mohan said to me:
"Nina will come home, Raj.
She'll come home soon.
Then I'll be in Heaven."
Nina?
I knew you'd come.
Kary...
Ma'...
He's gone, Nina.
Your dad's gone.
- She's far too thin.
- Oh, she's home now and her mummy
will fatten her up.
- Do you think she's...
- got a man?
- I doubt that.
You know what? With one thing and another,
things may be different between the two of you, Sanjay.
- You know what they say...
- Forgive and forget.
They say a wedding's lucky, the first
year after, that is.
- Oh yes.
- We ran out of samosas.
Aha, the prody girl returns.
Hello, Sanjay.
Your mother asked me to help out.
I'm really sorry about your dad, Nina.
Right, samosas... I'm on it.
- Who's that?
- Ah, it's Lisa.
- Maybe you should have a wee word
with your brother. - 3 years is a long time.
You're gonna have a lot to talk about.
It's dead hot in there.
- Here, let me do it.
- It's OK, I can...
How's London?
Still frying burgers?
- I'm sorry I was late.
- It's no scan of minors.
You don't have to explain it to me and
it's too late to explain it to him.
How's med school?
I've checked that in. (?)
I'm working for Raj now and
I pure love it.
It's only a means to an end. I'll have my own
cash and carry superstore before I'm 30.
- Kary, darling, come in a minute.
I wanna set myself up with my share
of the rest of the restaurant money.
What restaurant money?
Mrs Bandita's gout's been giving up gyp.
I said you'd have a wee look at it.
- Her own doctor's worse than useless.
- You know I'm not a doctor.
Yes, but you've read all the books. That's
better than most of them around here.
Alright, ladies?
Who's first?
- How you're doing?
- OK.
Lisa.
I'm sorry if I was a bit weird before.
I didn't really recognise you.
Why would you! I left in second year.
I hope I've changed since then.
Thanks for helping out today.
No problem.
I remembered you, though.
- Say "Chapati".
- Chapati.
Dear Mr. Mohan Shah,
We are delighted to inform you that
"The New Taj" has been selected...
One more win, Nina,
then we'll have it.
The bloody hattrick!
No other Scottish curry house
has ever done it.
Best bloody restaurant
this side of Maryhill.
- Is she alright?
- Yeah.
What did you mean before?
About the money? What money?
- The money we get from the sale.
- What sale?
- "The Taj".
- Kary, hurry up. We're gonna be late...
- Janice will be... Sorry.
Kary, come on. We gotta go,
-  Sorry. We're off.
- No Kary, no.
Let me get this straight, dad used the
restaurant as collateral for the bet?
- Not exactly.
- He used half of it.
Oh, well, that's alright then.
Had me worried for a minute.
Was he out of his mind?
I must say I agree.
It looks like that, pure lunatic.
But, in his defence, he was up
to his eyes, he owed thousands.
I guess he thought he had
nothing to lose.
- Is it legal?
- Word: Aye. (?)
Her dad's got a pure Rottweiler
of a lawyer.
Well, then we'll get out own Rottweiler.
This can't be right.
A bet's a bet, Nina.
- He knew what he was doing.
- He was desperate.
Your dad took advantage.
Nobody forced him...
- I need to talk to Jule.
- Well, he's in Benidorm.
Golfing, and probably shaging.
Anyway, it's not my dad you
need to talk to.
It's me.
- I've got to take this. Come on.
- No, Kary...
- We're dead late.
Good morning, Glasgow.
It's "Drive Time with Murli" on "Korma Radio".
This afternoon promises to be
bright, promises, promises.
That's good news for poor
miss Khan from Maryhill,
who's cat's been missing for a week.
Flights coming in from Mumbai
have been delayed.
So don't bother going to the airport.
But we hope that won't delay the
arrival of India's Nº 1...
Three, four and step.
Two, three, four.
And change,
and change.
Stop!
No, no, no!
Gandhi, you're moving like
a 5 o'clock princess.
Fish, think West End Wendy,
not muscle Bloody Mary.
I hope you're not spying for
the opposition?
Nina Bina, meet my
"Chutney Queens".
Thank you all.
That's the torture over.
See you later then.
- Maybe, maybe not.
- 8 p.m., the usual place.
Come on, Shriv.
Duty calles. (?)
- You're a dark horse.
- That's rich coming from Black Beauty.
So?
- What do you think? Seriously?
- No, you've got something, definitely.
Just as well.
Because very soon,
"Mogul Productions",
that's "Mogul Productions Mumbai",
not "Mogul Productions Maryhill",
will breeze into town to cast their
new Bollywood blockbuster
"Love in a Wet Climate".
- Catchy title.
- Aye! And we're gonna blow them away.
Me, me, me... That's enough
about me. What about...
Me?
Where do I start?
Do pros and cons. That always sorts
the men from the boys.
Well, I would, if there were any
pros to do.
God, how did this happen, Bobbi?
- "The Taj" meant everything to my dad.
- Not just your dad.
He'd entered the competition.
Nobody knew.
- He's through to the final.
- Great! (?)
Now we can do pros and cons.
He didn't want to sell, did he?
He wanted to win that trophy
for the third time.
Just imagine "The Taj"...
competing again.
Just imagine?
Come on...
Congratulation to
Mr. & Mrs. Patil,
who are celebrating their 25th
wedding aniversary.
But first, a reminder of the big event
coming up next monthon "Korma TV".
"The Best of the West" curry competition.
Hold me back!
You're my first today.
I'm honoured.
- Raj.
- Nina, you're looking well.
London must agree with you.
Well, if you'll excuse me, I'd better be off,
I got a million and one things to do.
Got the competition coming up.
Sanjay's in the final.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- He must be with a very good chance.
- Well, that depends who he's up against.
But believe you me, he'll be
a hard act to follow.
Now, if you need anything,
and I mean anything,
you let Kary know. Let me know.
- Thank you, Raj.
- Nina...
How long have you been working here?
Long enough. You can't live
off thin air.
Your dad left a groove in the
pavement outside "Jule's".
Why didn't anyone tell me
what was going on?
How were we supposed to do that? You phoned
a couple of times a year if we were lucky.
Half the time we didn't even
know where you were.
Thank God for Raj.
- Yeah. He didn't waste a minute, did he?
Beggars can't be choosers.
It's more than it's worth.
I don't care. I'm not selling
"The Taj" to them.
Well, then it's a good thing it's not
just up to you.
I don't believe this!
This is all dad's fault.
Don't you dare come back here and
start handing out blame!
Don't you dare! If there's blame to be
handed out you should be looking in a mirror.
I'm not the one who bet "The Taj"
on a bloody horse!
No, you're right. You didn't.
You had nothing to do with any of this.
You didn't humiliate him.
You didn't break his heart.
And what about my heart?
He only ever wanted what
was best for you, Nina.
We both did.
- No.
You wanted me to shrivel away
with a man I didn't love.
How could I do that, ma'?
We all do things we don't want.
- Why?
- There is no "why".
Do what you want, Nina.
You always do.
What are you doing?
What I was supposed to do.
He was the one who always
said "listen to your heart".
He should've listened to his bloody heart,
then it might not have packed up on him.
How could he?
We were gonna do this together.
We were gonna win the
hattrick together.
How could he go and just...
...die?
I thought you were Kary.
- Sorry to disappoint.
- Who said you did?
Fancy a beer?
Jinks!
Just as well, your dad wasn't here
to see that. That table is a temple.
"Not a bloody bottle-opener!"
To Mohan Shah.
"The best bloody cook
this side of Maryhill."
To Mohan Shah.
- God, this is weird.
- You just lost your dad.
You're about to lose your restaurant.
You're gonna feel a bit weird.
I haven't lost my restaurant just yet.
What if, I could persuade my
new business partner
not to jump into bed with the first dodgy
geezer that offers her a knock-down price?
What's wrong?
Well... No.
You can't ask me to do that.
It wouldn't be right.
Your mum's been really good to me,
- and Kary's my...
- Yeah, I know.
Look, it's not personal.
It's business.
Doesn't make sense to rush into anything.
We could get a much better price.
We won't.
My dad didn't want to sell.
He wanted to win that competition.
So that is exactly what
I'm gonna do.
Stop slurping!
- Kary, act your age.
- Not your shoe size.
Ma', there's something
I have to tell you.
That's the last of the marigolds. I thought
you should have them over here.
- They're dad's favourites.
- I know: that's why Lisa ordered them.
She's a real gem that lassie.
You should snap her up before
somebody else does, you know?
- She'd be mad, he's just pure embaressment. (?)
- Morning everyone.
Thought my ears were burning...
- You know what they say, Lisa?
- No, what do they say?
What's by you, won't get by you.
Is that not right, Suman?
D'you want some tea?
Thanks.
Did you tell them?
Tell them what?
Dad had a secret.
Do you mean his gambling?
Everybody knew about that.
Dad had entered "The Taj" into this year's
competition and he's through to the final.
- Too bad, it's not our restaurant anymore.
- Yes, it is.
It'n not done and dust until we sign.
So we've...
I've... decided to go ahead
and compete in the final.
And Lisa's agreed.
- I sent the acceptance forms off this morning.
- Oh, my God! You're gonna be on telly?
Hundreds of people are
gonna see you!
- My pals are gonna be drop dead jealous.
- Hold your horses, we may not win.
You had no right.
How dare you come back here and
start disrupting our lives?
Haven't you caused yet enough heartache?
- Ma'!
Suman, it will be good for the restaurant.
We can put the price up.
- Thanks very much! I thought we were partners?
- Hey, don't blame her. This was all my idea.
- No it wasn't. I can make up my own mind
- And why is that?
What makes you think you can
do this without dad?
It was his cooking that won
the trophies, not yours.
Raj can be that, but trust me
Sanjay's no slouch in the kitchen.
You're just gonna end up
humiliating us all over again.
Kary, wait a minute.
That went well.
And to cap it all, through the
whole flaming meal
his eyes were there.
I should never have worn that little top.
Actually, at one point I had to lift his chin up.
I did, to make him look at my face.
End of the night: Y'know, he tried to
kiss me. I wasn't going to ask him in.
And I put my hand up just to
sort of stroke his face.
The wig.
- He wears a wig?
I thought it was a bad dye job as well.
But no, I put my hand on. It was like that,
his head moved and the wig...
It's not worth it. Stay in the house,
watch the telly,
with a cup of tea.
Happy, please.
- Hello, darling.
- Hiya.
I'll just go and put the
cattle on then...
Ma', don't be upset, please.
It's for dad.
It's to give him back a little bit of pride.
What's wrong with that?
Pride comes before a fall,
remember that?
You are so like your father.
Here we are, tea's up.
Do you want a wee cup, Nina?
No, I'm fine, thanks, Mamie.
I'll just go and get some biscuits.
And what if you lose?
You've risked everything.
If Raj wants "The Taj" badly enough,
he'll still be around.
Don't be too sure of that.
Raj won't always be here.
Not if we keep turning him down.
Slainte!
(Gaelic: Cheers!)
Good, let's get out of here.
- So why did you leave?
- I woke up and I...
I knew I couldn't go through with it.
It was a terrible thing to do, though...
to do a bunk on the day of your wedding.
- Pretty brill, alright.
- I know, I didn't mean to hurt anyone.
It's just that I freaked out,
you know?
I mean they had it all mapped out for me.
Marry Sanjay, have lots of little Sanjays.
We'd have "The Taj" and "The Jewel".
They saw us as this power
cooking couple.
"The couple that cooks together,
stays together."
I just didn't love him.
- No such thing.
- As love?
There isn't, it's just a big con.
See, your dad taught you how to cook,
my dad taught me: never gamble with
something you're not prepared to lose.
Once you realise that
you get along fine.
The other way's just a
recipe for disaster.
Can you cook?
I can make a mean fried egg and
burn sauce sandwich.
- I don't do indian...
- Well, apart from my brother.
I've always admired your dad's
chicken xacuti.
Me too...
Race you to the bike.
Oh, ma', don't, please...
I don't want you
to do that just yet.
Funny, isn't it? Nobody's ever
asked me what I want.
Your dad never asked me much.
But then, he never told me
much, either.
He thought I didn't know
what was going on.
I knew exactly what was going on.
I was married to him for 30 years.
Ma'...
Ma', I cannot find the peanut butter,
and Kary's finished all the bread.
Come on, sweetheart.
Don't tell, please.
I'm not supposed to be going back
to dancing. Dad banned me.
Why?
I don't know. After you left
he went all funny.
Are you any good at it?
Holly shit!
I've been offered a place in the county
team. That's a big deal, you know.
- I'm sure.
- I've turned it down.
Do you think he's still here, Nina?
I don't know...
Maybe...
I hope so...
Please, don't tell. I don't want
anybody to know, 'right?
- OK.
- Especially, Kary. He's been such an arse.
He's bought lots of new clothes, dead
expensive. He's trying to impress Lisa.
But he's going about it
all the wrong way.
- And since when are you such an expert on romance?
- I've got eyes. I see things.
I've told you a secret.
Now you need to tell me one.
I don't have any secrets.
"Mohan Shan. Award winning recipes"
Garlic purifies the blood and
keeps the skin glowing.
Frying garlic lightly enhances
its therapeutic action.
The golden brown colour of this dish
signifies optimism and will dispell gloom.
- This is so better be worth it.
- Thanks.
- OK, who are we up against?
- OK: The "Bengal Tiger".
Pussycat.
- Unless it's under new management...
- It is...
- "Bimal's Balti and Dosa House".
- Last year's winners.
And then last, but never least...
"The Jewel in the Crown".
- It's in the bag.
- Oh yeah, it's in the bag.
Who's Lorna?
Nina + Lorna = True love
Decembre 1988
I don't know...
I've no idea...
Lorna...
Lorna Mallen!
I remember Lorna.
Captain of the school hockey team.
Big blue eyes.
Tall.
Legs right up to her oxsters.
I am schocked!
I wouldn't have thought
she was your type.
She wasn't my type.
I was 9.
I had a crush on the world and his wife
when I was 9.
- Me too.
- Look how I'm going!
-  Is that nice?
- Yeah, go faster.
- No...
Green and green.
And the difference is..?
Winning...
and losing.
You've got pure cheek. You're
supposed to pay with nothing for them?
- Janice, not now, just put it on the account, OK?
- You'll get no more credit here.
- It's OK, Janice. I'll sort it.
- But Kary...
It's OK, I'll handle it.
- What is her problem?
- You should've cleared this with me first.
- Is there a problem here?
- No Sanjay, no problem.
I'm just getting Nina her change.
Gee, thanks.
Nina.
Maybe we could go out sometime.
For a drink or something.
- I know this really good club.
- I don't think so.
- What's the point of raking up old ground?
- No old ground, fresh start.
Maybe we could just talk about "The Taj".
See, I've got some plans, really big plans.
Well, I'm afraid they might have to wait
for a bit, Sanjay. We're not ready to sell.
- I'm sorry.
- Since when?
Since Lisa and I decided not to.
"The Bengal Tiger."
"Bimal's House."
"The Jewel in the Crown".
I've used all 20 of my Weight Watchers
points already today.
Know thy enemy.
Right,
go on.
I need you to know the difference
for when you taste mine.
It's delicious.
It's terrible. They didn't marinate
the meat long enough.
The longer you marinate it,
the more tender it becomes.
Taste that...
Well?
- That's better.
- What's better about it?
I don't know.
Go on...
It's not so overpowering.
Good, you're getting it.
OK, now I'm gonna show you
how it's really done.
Put it on.
Not yet.
Right, let's see if I can remember
how to fly this thing.
It's all about chemistry.
And the chemistry has to be right.
Your turn.
OK, slow down. Don't beat it into
submission, just coax it.
Gently.
Pretty good.
OK, OK, you need to wash it out
with cold water, immediately.
- Don't rub it, you'll make it worse.
- Oh what, now she tells me?
Here.
OK?
OK, let me see how that is.
Let me see.
Yeah, you'll live.
You sound like my doctor.
Thought that was meant to be me.
What happened?
- Just got some plutonium in my eye.
- Chilli.
- Cold water. You need to wash it out.
- Is there an echo in here?
You'll live.
- Still not talking to me then?
- Just. Still up for going out later?
What choice have I got?
And, by the way, you owe me 10 quid.
At least he's not taking
it out on you.
He wouldn't dare. He needs
me too much.
ginger
turmeric
garam masala
garlic
cumin
coriander
Mmm.
- This is shit.
- What?!!
Kary was right. I can't
do this without my dad.
No, Mamie, I don't mind;
I need to keep busy.
- Ma'?
- Just a moment.
You were right.
Beggars can't be chosers.
Let's go see Raj.
I'll call you back.
Ready, Nina?
Here's to us, in business
and in pleasure.
I'll call the lawyer and
we'll sign tomorrow.
Now, I'll say one thing to you, Nina,
you sure know how to keep a man dangling.
Nina, we both know how hard this is for
you and what "The Taj" means to you.
Don't worry, we'll take good care of it. And
your mother can stay for as long as she likes.
It will always be your home.
- Thank you, Raj.
Good. Now, let's eat.
Nina, I hope that full plate is not
a reflection on the food?
Oh, no, it's lovely, Raj. It's just
that I'm not very hungry.
Lovely? Geez! Down with faint
praise, huh?
Come on, Nina. You could bee more specific
than that. Tell us what you really think?
Don't rush it, mind you.
Take your time.
Wouldn't want you to make
another snap decision.
Well?
Technically, it's very good.
Technically?
- But there's something missing.
- Missing?
- Nina...
- All the ingredients are there...
I can taste all the flavours;
it's just there's something...
I don't know...
Ha!
It's the chemistry.
It's not quite right.
You know, maybe it's a good thing that
you won't be cooking in the competition.
After all, I wouldn't want my
public ass kicked twice.
You know, maybe we should employ you, Nina.
Then you could come and cook for us.
I don't cook for anyone
except for my dad.
Well, that's a shame.
You don't want to be on
the winning team, Nina?
I've always been on
the winning team.
We've won twice before.
Remember?
That was then.
And this is now.
No sale 'till after the competition.
You're just like Mohan.
Red rag to a bull.
Alright, have it your way.
May the best man win.
Or woman.
Cheers!
Hiya, girls.
Hey, I thought you were rehearsing.
"Night and day." - We are.
- We're just gonna do it in front of the mob.
- That may give us the extra push that we need.
Over the nearest cliff,
preferably.
Coming?
Yeah.
Not dressed like that.
Nina!
- Oh, it's you...
- Don't worry, little brother.
I won't cramp your style.
I'm here with Bobbi.
You two won't even know we're here.
Does that come with an off switch?
Good evening, Glasgow.
Sorry to be on time. (?)
- Nina.
- Sanjay.
Sorry to interrupt, but do you
fancy sharing a cab?
- Coming.
- You may be.
- Janice and I are...
- I can see that.
We are married.
I'm fed up waiting, I don't want you
to do anymore because I pure love you.
- We sneaked away.
- To Gretna.
- Dead predictable.
- Dead romantic.
Nobody else knows.
Except Lisa.
- She's been terrified to tell her dad, he's a...
- Deadweight. He's a pure bum.
"Another one bites the dust."
So, beer?
I'm pure tired.
I'll go to bed.
I thought you and Kary were...
Oh, what a relief! What a relief!
Mrs. Khan's cat, the wee nipper
has been spotted in Dundee...
Last night, I was lucky to be
a guest of the "Bengal Tiger" in Bearsden.
Oh, the food was gorgeous!
Don't forget, we only have a week left
before Scotlands biggest event,
"The Best of the West" curry competition.
What?!!
I really want this...
me and you...
I've never felt like this before.
Let's tell everyone.
I've gotta go...
I can't do this just now, Lisa.
Hey, you lot, show's over.
People to go, places to see.
Bobbi, can you do the Pocahontas tomorrow?
Alright, bring the video.
See you tomorrow.
So tell all, my sweet chilli bean.
I didn't mean for this to happen.
What do I do?
- Go with your heart.
- And lose everything?
Not everything. You didn't think twice
about that when you ran away...
I know, but I missed them, Bobbi.
I missed you.
All I ever wanted to do was come home.
Aye, you're home now.
Why can't you just say it?
Because... If I say it, then
there's no going back.
I can't.
Not here. Not under their roof. My mum
would never be able to accept it.
I don't want to have to run again, Bobbi.
You can't plan for love, Nina Bina.
It just sneaks up on you...
When you least expect it.
- Hello.
We're gonna have to stop meeting like this.
- That's original...
Or steady and reliable. Depends
which way you look at it.
I'd give anything to be more like you.
With my dress sense?
Deceit is not an option.
Do you love her?
- I thought you did a runner on me.
- Not yet, but I'm thinking about it.
Of course you are. That's what
you always do.
Look Lisa, let's just get on
with the cooking for now.
- What's this?
- Costumer feedback forms.
Was the food:
A. To die for,
B. Okayish,
or C. Pure disgusting?
And you, please, write legibly.
Kiss my...
Hi, I'm sorry to bother you, I
was looking for Priya Shah.
There was a dance practice
tonight but she didn't show.
She's inside. Come in.
Better not.
Just tell her Ravi bumped. (?)
Ravi.
Are you hungry?
I always thought he had a fabulous--
- Everybody, this is Priya's friend, Ravi.
- Hello, Ravi.
- I hope you're not all waiting for me.
- At last! Where have you been? We're starving.
Oh dear, the food must be cold by now.
Welcome, young man.
Priya, don't be rude.
Offer your friend a chair.
Ready, Nina?
To begin with,
everybody's favourite, the house
speciality: chicken xacuti.
The chicken is marinated in
over 20 herbs and spices,
and cooked slowly in sweet
fresh coconut juice.
Tender lamb chops
with garam masala
cooked in a rich tomato and onion sauce.
King prawns:
simmered in special spices and then
charcoal grilled to perfection in the tandoor.
(tandoor = indian clay oven)
"Jeera aloo": potatoes cooked in
roasted cumin seeds
with fresh wild mushrooms,
toasted almonds and curry leaves.
Pilaw rice infused with golden saffron.
And then finally,
My assistant, Lisa,
has prepared chapatis.
Individually designed especially
for each of you.
Enjoy!
Well done, Nina.
These prawns
are my favourite.
Kary, pass the rice down.
Spicy...
Hiya.
The entertainment's arrived.
- Nina, more chicken xacuti
- No way.
I couldn't dance for a boolly with
blockbuster on a full stomach.
We couldn't force one single
mussel down our guts .
- The audition's in an hour.
- Come on...
- Hey, you OK?
- Hmm... You?
It's now or never, Nina.
Come on, Priya, read all the comments.
This one's Ravi's: "The sauce on
the lamb was too sweet."
And he wasn't that into lentils.
They're still stuck in his teeth.
- Difficult crowd tonight.
- You've got to be cruel to be kind.
Oh, don't listen to them.
It was lovely.
- Great.
- It's alright.
Truth? Sanjay's a black belt
curry master.
If you want to win, you'll have
to be in the top of your game.
So what? Nina's a curry ninja.
She's not scared of a bum like Sanjay.
Bring it on!
What would dad say?
Your dad would say:
"You're so close to winning now that
you can't let anything stand in your way."
That's not what he'd say, Nina.
You know exactly what he'd say.
"Follow your heart."
Thanks.
Dad's still here, you know?
Oh, sweethart.
Oh, pettit.
Cheer up, sleepy Jean,
Oh, what can it mean
To a daydream believer
and a homecoming queen?
Cheer up, sleepy Jean,
Oh, what can it mean
To a daydream believer
and a homecoming queen?
Cheer up, sleepy Jean,
Oh, what can it mean
To a daydream believer
and a homecoming queen?
- Wish me luck.
- Luck!
Go, and be wonderest.
Come on, Bobbi. Gotta get
the boys on the bridge.
Bye!
Whoa!
- Have you changed the batteries?
- Twice.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
A beautiful monument
to eternal love.
You don't believe in love.
Your dad said some king spent 22 years
building it for his queen.
Dead queen.
It's a monument to grief.
Same thing. If he'd come from Nashville,
he would have written a song about it.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
Look at me.
We should throw that dull thing out.
- It's broken.
- It's not broken.
It just needs new batteries.
Nina, what do you think?
Keep stirring.
Keep it moving. Cover every
inch with the sauce.
Taste it.
Taste it in your heart.
No matter what the recipe says, pettit,
always follow your heart.
"Baste every 5 minutes,
using the succulent juices from
the bottom of the roasting dish.
Remember. Every 5.
Leave it any longer and
the meat will dry out.
It will taste like bloody shoe leather.
Not that I've tasted shoe leather.
Apart from Raj's bloody chicken xacuti.
that is. Which is a crime against humanity,
and shoes."
Bring a large pan of water to the boil.
"Bring a large pan of water to the boil."
Measure the rice.
"Measure the rice."
No need to weight up.
"Use your heart, pettit,
not the scales."
It's not "The Taj" that Sanjay's
interested in.
You know that, don't you?
Love isn't the be-all and end-all,
Nina.
I don't believe that.
I can't believe that.
You could have learned
to love Sanjay.
- Then you'd never have left.
- Ma'...
Look:
You know, dad used to tell me about
your honeymoon at the Taj Mahal.
And all the time that he talked about it,
he had this,
this look on his face. That's how I want
someone to look when they talk about me.
It's not Sanjay's fault, but
he could never look like that.
You are stunning.
- What?
- It's yours.
Thank you.
Hold me back!
Make sure tonight you don't miss the finale of
"The Best of the West" curry competition,
going out live on "Korma TV".
Look at this. Please, stand up.
Let's have a look.
I had forgotten how
beautiful these are.
I'd completely forgotten.
I hadn't.
- So, have you decided yet?
- No, she hasn't.
It's gotta be special.
We don't have much time.
The clock's ticking.
Maybe we could just pick up a few fish suppers
on the way and curry them when we get there?!!
- Do haggis for curries?!!
- Tender baby lamb...
simmered in a  ginger
and garam masala,
followed by "pomigrani" chicken
with rose petals.
- And a light ginger sherbet for desert.
- Your wedding banquet!
Of course. That's what he'd want.
And maybe, chicken xacuti?
"Best chicken xacuti this side of Maryhill."
- Bobbi, where is he?
- He'll be here, I promise.
We're still inside, Kary.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Got a flat tire...
Where's Priya?
Not every family do get to have
a champion dancer.
I'm glad you kept on going.
Come.
Oh, what the hell...
There's something I need to tell you, ma'.
I'm married.
Her name's Janice, and
I pure love her.
Well...
It seems I have a lot to
learn about love.
My children seem to understand it
much better than I do.
Any more bombshells?
Come on, let's go. We're gonna be late.
I don't wanna miss being on the telly.
Let's go.
It's right here.
1, 2, 3.
Chicken xacuti!
You're looking wonderful.
Well I hope you're firing on
all cylinders tonight, Sanjay.
Nina's cooking a wedding
banquet fit for a king.
That's just what I want to hear.
We should go?
5, 4, 3, 2.
Good evening, Scotland
and Mumbai!
And welcome to this final of
"The Best of the West".
We've got quite a feast to
serve up tonight
and I sincerely hope you have will the
stomach to make it to the final course!
Hold me back!
And in the blue zone...
"The Bengal Tiger" from Bearsden.
Mum, this is Janice.
Don't be angry with him, Miss Shah.
It was all my idea.
I pure love him.
- And in the yellow zone...
Good.
...are going to entice us with a spicy chicken roll,
flavoured with mixed indian pickles,
stuffed with fresh garden spinache.
And in the green zone...
Sanjay Kahnna
of the "Jewel in the Crown".
Sanjay has promised us the
Maharaja's banquet.
His speciality being lamb
smoked with cloves and cinnamon.
A taste that promises to melt
our hearts and light our fire.
- Hold me back!
And in the orange zone...
The Shah of "The New Taj".
Inspired by the whispering
palaces of Jaipur,
Nina Shah has prepared a wedding
banquet fit for queens.
Will she entice the judges with
the tender baby lamb chops?
So, ladies and gentlemen,
let the battle commence.
That'll never happen, you know.
- The two of you. Not like that.
- Like what, Sanjay?
Come on, her mother will
never allow it.
She won't run away again.
D'you know why?
Because this time she's got
something to stay for.
I won't be too sure about that.
She's not gonna risk it.
She'd lose everything.
D'you really think she wants
to lose her family again?
Even for love?
Chances of that are piss and pooh.
That's lovely.
Fit for a king.
OK, stole the lemon.
Here we go.
20 minutes of cooking time remaining.
What?
Kiss me.
We're on national television...
We are.
Hold me back. What's going on
in the orange zone?
She must have forgotten some
very crucial spices.
Oh, dear, there goes another one.
Nina.
She's gone, ma'.
Then why are you still here?
Don't make the same mistake I did.
I loved your dad but I always knew...
in my heart of heart of hearts,
he wasn't the one.
Raj?
Trophies don't matter.
The only thing that matters is love.
Go on, hurry up.
And don't you let that girl
out of your sight again.
Welcome back, girls. I hope
you've got your mangoes.
Oh, hold me back,
that was a narrow escape for
the "Taj" ladies, let me tell you!
Right, you've got 30 seconds so let's
get your finishing touches on that.
You don't have to cook the pickles,
you can buy that in a shop. Come on then!
Come on, get going, get going!
Right, you got 10, 9, 8, 7,
6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
Hold me back!
All our contestants have
worked hard and
have been very ambitious with their dishes.
"Korma TV" is proud to have Scotland's
top chefs as our judges today.
They take their duties very seriously.
The smells in the studio are divine.
4 contestants, 4 judges and
4 outstanding dishes.
A close call between "The Jewel"
and "The New Taj", let me tell ya.
Nina Shah's mogul menu was
beautifully prepared
with each and every one of the delicate
flavours complementing each other perfectly.
But Sanjay Kahnna confounded our senses
with a meal of sheer technical perfection.
A difficult choice between perfection
and heavenly delight.
But, in true fairytale style,
the heart wins out
and tonight's award goes to the
"Pursuits of Heavenly Delight"!
Kiss me.
It must be the garam masala.
Hold me back...
Slate 1, take 1.
"Love in a Wet Climate"