Andre and Spindle-shanks
are having an intimate relationship.
Voila.
Have you any objection?
Who, me?
No, none at all.
Have you told him
the other thing,
the most important?
-No, he hasn't.
-What's the other thing?
The other thing
is that I'm pregnant.
-What?
-We're going to have a baby.
Is that possible?
Of course! It's normal,
isn't it, Mr. Armand?
Well, yes, it is, because
if you and he...
What a mess, Andres.
Don't be afraid.
It's not your responsibility.
I'm not asking for anything.
You can go to Murcia
whenever you want.
-Right now.
-Ninette, it's not that.
In that case,
take off the bandage
and put on your jacket
and the tie with polka dots.
I'm going to show you Paris.
We'll walk by the Seine,
we'll have dinner
on the damn bateau-mouche,
we'll go to the Louvre
and at night
to the Moulin Rouge.
Ca va?
Ca va.
Allez.
-Bonjour, Mme. Bernarda.
-Bonjour, Mr. Armand.
-Bonjour, Mr. Pierre.
-Bonjour.
Andres is feeling much better,
we thought we'd go out for while.
No, you can't leave here.
-No?
-No.
Hello, dad. Hello, mom.
Hello, Ninette.
Why aren't you at work?
Haven't you heard the news?
No, I was going to take
Mr. Martinez to the Louvre.
The Louvre? Forget it.
Good morning.
It's a miracle!
Mr. Martinez isn't limping.
He's cured.
Armando brought me
a special ointment.
I put it on and that fixed it.
I don't even need the bandage.
I heard you say
we can't go out. Why?
C'est la greve.
La greve.
-Ah, la greve.
-La what?
La greve.
The general strike.
No one thought
it could actually happen.
Oh, no?
This isn't Spain.
Electricity, gas, theaters,
transport, the mail,
tous fermes.
No taxis, no subway, no stores,
no cafes, rien de rien.
That's why you shouldn't go out.
It isn't worth it.
-Aren't the river boats working?
-No, they're not.
I rang a group of Spanish friends,
republicans like us,
and they're coming here.
I've bought "chorizo"
and "salchichon"
so we can have some proper food.
We're going to have
a wonderful afternoon.
And I'll play the pipes.
Dad, mom,
I'm pregnant.
By whom, ma cherie?
By Mr. Martinez.
Did you hear that?
Yes, she's pregnant
by Mr. Martinez.
I'm going to prepare the food.
-Mr. Pierre...
-Yes?
You're an admirable man.
I really mean that.
You think so?
Absolutely.
And very European.
You mean because of Ninette's joke?
I'm used to it
and I prefer that
to having her
reading novels all day.
-Dad...
-Yes?
It isn't a joke.
No?
This time it's true.
I'm pregnant by Mr. Martinez.
Are you saying
that this gentleman,
-in my own house, dared to...
-I let him.
We did what's natural
between a man and a woman.
-I can explain...
-Be quiet! And sit down!
Don't say a word!
Bernarda.
I heard everything.
Child, is that what
you call reading?
And what do you have to say?
-Me?
-Yes, you.
It's your fault, you brought
that scoundrel here.
Be quiet!
-Ninette, assieds-toi.
-Dad...
Assieds-toi!
Now, listen carefully.
We're all going to talk
man to man,
and very clearly.
What I'm going to ask
is very simple.
Quel horreur!
I don't believe it!
It's always the same.
Why don't you Scots fuck off?
We're sick of your music!
Merde!
MURCIA, A YEAR LATER
You said the minimum order
was 50, right?
No, it's not 50, it's 100.
I told you that, 100.
Are you deaf or what?
If I were only to print one,
Which would you recommend?
The ones with the gold border
or the ones with the lamb?
My niece Turitas
is making her Communion.
Her real name is Virtudes,
Virtuditas,
but we call her Turitas,
and as I'm studying...
Don't tell me your life story.
Both the Good Shepherd
and the Dove are very popular
and the price difference
is very slight.
In favor of which?
The ones with the gold border
are cheaper.
100, with gold borders,
for Tortitas...
-Turitas.
-Well, whatever,
they're 25 pesetas less
than the Good Shepherd.
I'll have those.
And little girls love gold trimming,
don't they?
I don't know about Torootas,
but today little girls like Elvis.
Sunbathing in the nude again?
-First, I'm not in the nude.
-No?
No, and second,
sunbathing is very healthy.
With the windows open.
Of course, darling. It's bad
to sunbathe through glass.
And you lose ultraviolet radiation.
Leave that, I'll tidy up later.
Look, when I lived on my own
Melchora had the house
clean and tidy.
Why isn't it like that now?
Because your mother fired her.
They didn't get on well.
Mom never wanted servants.
She prefers to do it all herself.
To do it all herself, badly,
you mean.
Dad's shoes.
Andres! When the windows
are open it's cooler!
Yeah, and the view's better
from the barracks,
especially for that captain
with his field glasses.
Stop exaggerating.
Exaggerating?
What about your mole?
-He's told the whole club.
-Quoi?
The mole you have there.
Who told that captain
about your mole?
You know what it is?
At first, you let me work
in the store.
We put up the sign
''On parle francais",
the tourists came,
I spoke to them in their language...
You flirted with all the customers.
-That's not true.
-Yes, it is.
In one month,
you sold 540 catechisms.
That's never happened in Murcia,
not even during Lent!
Yes, Maruja?
The manager says
can you go to the printer's,
something's happened
with that gadget.
He told you already
but you didn't listen
and now what'll they do?
Tell him I'm on my way
and not to touch the Minerva.
Well, hurry up. You know him.
He'll get nervous
and screw everything.
Say what you like,
I was useful in the store.
-You needed an assistant.
-That's why I got her.
But Maruja doesn't speak French.
And she's common and unfriendly.
That's what you need in a store.
Someone unfriendly
who doesn't chat.
"A catechism?
Here's a catechism."
"-Haven't you got another?"
"-No."
"Got a St. Damian?"
"Yes, here's one.
Pay up and go away."
I don't want us to get angry.
But it's not fair.
You don't let me do anything
and I'm bored.
If you had real children,
not imaginary ones,
you wouldn't be so bored.
It was a utopian pregnancy,
psychic, emotional.
The doctors explained it.
Yes, they explained it
three months after we got married.
I really thought I was pregnant.
You know that what I'd like most
is for us to have a baby.
Yes. A boy, blonde, blue eyes,
who weighs exactly
3 kilos 400 grams at birth.
And for that we have to...?
Wait for Cancer to be
in conjunction with Saturn
so the baby is born
under the protection of Jupiter,
-the most favourable planet.
-And... well...
You can laugh, but you know
nothing about astrology.
-I'm going out.
-Where?
I have to do an errand
for Dona Remedios.
When's your mother coming?
In a few days.
Good afternoon, Maruja.
-Good afternoon.
-What are you doing?
Labelling rosaries, can't you see?
-Hot, isn't it?
-lf you say so.
-No, that's how it is.
-Then that's how it is.
Like I say,
that's what it is about spring.
I don't know what it is about spring.
It stirs the blood.
It stirs the blood
because the heat begins.
Spring is the start of summer,
and in summer, you know.
I know what?
It's warmer than winter.
Where's Don Andres?
Upstairs?
Balancing those whatsits.
No, no, forget it.
Maruja,
what color is your soutien-gorge?
-My what?
-And your petite culotte?
What color is your underwear?
What a nerve!
Go upstairs. Go on.
Good God!
Hello.
-What are you doing?
-You can see.
How's business?
-Bad.
-Why's that?
My in-laws won't go to Mass,
they've kept their ideas
and my customers know it.
When Pierre played
the "International" on the pipes
the police were here
in five minutes.
And?
They took the pipes away.
Why are you here?
Mr. Pierre invited me to supper
again, as Mme. Bernarda is in Madrid,
to talk about France,
creme de tomate,
omelette au fromage,
rognon de veau saute....
Our French cooking.
I've brought him dessert.
Yeah, take the Camembert
into the kitchen.
-How do you know what it is?
-How do you think?
Since they transferred you here,
you spend more time in my house
than in yours.
That's because your family like me,
they're nice and they invite me.
It seems to bother you.
-Where's Ninette?
-She's gone out.
Where?
On an errand for her mother and...
Why do you care where my wife is?
That wealthy Dona Remedios
and your mother-in-law
are up to something.
It's very odd.
It's the third time they've gone
to Madrid in two months, isn't it?
-Don Andres!
-Yes, Maruja?
They've come for that thingy
for something or other.
-Ah, the check!
-Yes.
It's in the top drawer
of the writing desk.
Tell the supplier
to sign the receipt.
All right.
"They've come for that thingy
for something or other."
And you know what it is.
You're smarter than I thought.
By the way, that Maruja...
How can she be so unfriendly?
She's not unfriendly.
She's decent.
Maruja, it's gone 8:00.
I'm just finishing.
Be careful you don't fall.
I'm used to it.
Is anything wrong?
Are you all right?
Yes, there's nothing wrong.
Maru, has the Archangel Gabriel
arrived yet?
Yes, Don Andres, he's right there,
on the table.
You know what, Maru?
Right now, in the store,
there are only the three of us.
You, the Archangel Gabriel and me.
And the Archangel
is made of plaster.
He doesn't feel a thing.
You understand, Maru?
Yes.
There are just the three of us
and he sees nothing.
Exactly, nothing.
You asked if anything was wrong.
Yes, something is wrong.
You're magnificent, Maru.
Magnificent, magnificent.
Don Andres, what will people think?
There's no one here.
What will you think, Don Andres?
I don't think, Maru.
Don Andres! Be careful
with the third button, it's loose.
How can anyone think
looking at this,
and at this mouth that's saying,
"Eat me, Andres, eat me".
Andres, this is crazy.
I'm not French, I'm Spanish,
and very, very Spanish.
-What does that matter?
-It doesn't,
because I'm very Spanish
and I'm crazy about you.
-What?
-Yes, crazy.
Don't you know you get me going
every time you take off
your workcoat?
Sweet Jesus!
What's going to become of us?
Holy Virgin!
Coming!
Who is it?
It's that priest.
He's come to talk to Mr. Pierre.
Don Roque.
Do up your buttons.
-What did you tell him?
-That you...
You were in the basement
and I was doing those account things.
They're called delivery notes.
My father-in-law is out.
Tell Don Roque
to come back in an hour.
No, Mr. Pierre is here.
He went up the main stairs.
He's all twitter-twitter
with the birds.
He's here?
He could have caught us!
This is very dangerous.
We should rent an apartment.
Are you crazy?
In my name,
you won't appear anywhere.
I rent it, you pay for it.
On the outskirts.
Now, go on, he's waiting for you.
Hey! Why does that priest
want to see your father-in-law?
He's called Don Roque
and don't grab on to me.
To get him to go to church,
of course!
I've told him,
"Go to Mass!
Is that so hard to do?"
Don Roque, you're welcome!
Feel right at home.
Thank you, my boy.
You feel right at home too.
-How are all the family?
-They're all fine, thank you.
-I'm delighted to hear that.
-Go on up.
Thank you.
You married my daughter,
didn't you?
No, Fr. Rebolledo married
your daughter.
Rebolledo?
Forgive my mistake,
but all of you go round
dressed up in the same uniform.
Here we go.
Well, what do you want?
I know you're very anti-clerical,
but even so I've come to ask you
for a recommendation.
For Paris?
No, not for Paris,
for here, for Murcia.
Tell me.
Well, I've got a godson,
very smart, 20 years old, Alfonsito,
who doesn't want
to continue studying law.
I wanted to get him
into the garage where you work.
As a mechanic?
No, in the office.
I could ask Frutos, the union rep,
but he's always putting me off.
So I prefer to ask you,
among other reasons
because you've become
the master there, right?
No, I haven't.
The masters are the masters.
They respect me, that's all.
"They respect you."
Don't be so humble.
In the Confianza Garage
what Mr. Pierre says is gospel.
You mightn't read it,
but your word is gospel.
Having been out of Spain
for a long time
and being on the wrong side,
my friend, that's a great thing.
But people are so used
to seeing us
and we've asked so many favors,
that nobody pays us
a blind bit of notice,
and that's the truth.
Apart from all that,
you've done a lot of silly things.
I mean, giving Franco,
for us, "the little commander",
a royal welcome into the churches.
Come on!
Well, the stupidities you commit
behind the Iron Curtain
are considerable too.
Father,
do you want me to get
your godson a job or not?
Of course.
You've done a lot of silly things,
end of story.
Send Alfonsito to the office
on Monday, at 9:00.
I'll see what I can do.
I really appreciate that.
Well, Mr. Pierre,
I won't bother you anymore.
No, no, I'll go with you.
I'm going to the newspaper stall
for "L'Humanite",
the newspaper I subscribe to.
What the Church sends me,
without being subscribed,
is the "Workers' World",
and recently it's very good.
Very good!
Andre...
What?
Mom's opening a business.
So that's it.
What is it, a doughnut stand?
Mom's become good friends
with Dona Remedios.
Something I don't understand.
I'll explain it.
Dona Remedios has been
a vegetarian for thirty years.
She won't even taste a chop.
Like crickets.
She happened to meet mom
and mom gave her
an address in France
where she could order
some weeds or other,
and she advises her
about vegetables.
Anyway, they've become
great friends
and between them
they're going to open a boutique.
A what?
A fashion store.
Beside the Plateria,
in the best area.
With the way she looks,
your mother is opening
a fashion store?
Have we all gone mad?
She won't be selling her dresses.
They'll be ones she's ordered
from Paris and Madrid.
And it won't be just dresses.
There'll be underwear,
nightdresses,
jupons, porte-jarretelles....
Porta-what?
Garters.
The thing you used to wear.
Well,
mom won't be the only one
working with Dona Remedios.
I'm going to help.
Not a chance.
You selling panties and briefs
to all the sex maniacs in town?
-Forget it.
-It's been decided.
Decided?
Yes.
Another thing, the store
will be called "Ninette"
and underneath
"Modes de Paris''.
Are you saying my wife's name
will be displayed in a street?
Yes, Andres.
I say it won't.
I say it will. It's done.
When are you going to open?
I don't know.
In a few weeks.
The painters are in at the minute.
Why?
Because you'll be in the store
most of the day.
Don't forget that I'm used...
I was used to working
and I get depressed doing nothing.
You know that.
No, in theory, I don't think
it's a bad idea.
And I can't demand that you stay
in the house all day.
That's obvious.
Well, then?
I don't know.
If you want that maid to come back,
I'll persuade mom that Melchora
is essential for you.
I don't need anyone in the house.
It'll be more peaceful.
Mon amour.
I'm going to love you
much, much more.
The light.
Listen, the name Ninette
in modern letters.
Nothing gothic or English.
D'accord.
ARTILLERY BARRACKS
I know a real lady shouldn't have
eau-de-vie for breakfast, but...
But you're not a real lady, cherie.
How was Madrid?
Great, great.
By the way, Ninette told me
you agree about the boutique.
-Is that true?
-Yes.
After she told me,
I thought about it
and it's just what this city needs.
Think about this, Bernarda.
With your head for business,
I think this idea of Paris fashions
will be a great success,
and the advantage is
if anything should go wrong
the one who loses money
is Miss Rabbit-food.
That's good thinking.
Excuse me, Don Andres...
Yes, Miss Maruja?
Nothing, it's...
It's 8:55 and I've opened the store.
I'm going down to the basement
to count those thingies,
so someone will have to
attend the counter.
Yes, I'll be down now.
You can start the inventory,
and please bring up
the accounts ledgers
and leave them in the back room.
No, if you want those big books
go and get them yourself.
They're a dead weight
and I end up with a sore back.
All right, I'll see to it.
You'd think
I was that strongwoman
who pulls cars with her teeth.
Really!
Mais voyons!
Qu'est-ce que c’est que ca?
Isn't she rude?
It's just her character.
Character, my foot!
You can't have someone like that
in the store.
You should fire her today.
The cheek of her!
I can't fire her. There's
a labor ruling that prevents me.
-Mr. Pierre, isn't that so?
-According to the legislation,
you can't fire a worker
for being unpleasant.
Did you hear how she answered him?
He has to put up with it.
There is a very good law,
one of the few things
done well in this country,
that defends the worker
against the capitalist boss.
In this case, me.
Incroyable.
It's incroyable,
but that's how it is.
Now, let's go
or we'll be late for work.
But first,
a toast.
-Why?
-To...
Ninette,
"Fashions from Paris".
To Ninette.
Are you out of your mind?
Forgive me, Andres, I'm sorry.
Don't be angry.
You don't think!
I got upset when I saw that
your wife was smooching you.
Well, you have to put up with it.
That's the problem with these things.
I can't put up with things.
Andres,
this thing can't go on like this.
Nothing irreparable
has happened between us yet.
Yes, but I have a feeling, my love,
it could happen any minute.
Yes, well, until it happens,
let's not get tragic.
Prepare the prayer books
for the Clarisas,
not the thingummy-jigs.
-You know something?
-What?
She knows everything.
And she's pretending.
Remember, she's French,
you know, brazen.
-Good morning.
Well, Armando!
-Good evening.
-Are you looking for Don Andres?
Yes.
Upstairs, in the "bureau"
with those thingies.
The orders.
Have you got the time?
My watch has stopped.
Yes, of course.
It's 8:15.
Almost 8:20.
Thank you, you're very kind.
Armando, you needn't be so formal.
Listen,
-Maruja.
-Yes.
That checked blouse is lovely.
Yes, it's new.
It looks great on you.
I've never worn it before.
Listen!
Isn't that a coincidence?
Recreation.
Speaking of recreation,
are you busy tonight?
Maybe I am.
Maybe I'm not.
It depends.
Armando!
Pink.
Pale pink.
To be honest, I can't complain.
Mari Merche is delightful.
She's pleasant, polite,
always willing to bring me anything,
a glass of water at night...
And if she has to argue
with her mother because of me,
she does it
and takes my side.
-Shit!
-You're lucky!
But I can't stand her.
And what's worse,
I'm getting a thing about her.
That's it, that's it.
But if she and I weren't married
why would I dislike her like this?
By the way,
we really miss Ninette's coffee.
She goes to bed early now,
she's busy at the store.
Poor thing.
Are we playing or not?
Cut.
What a pity.
It's me, Ninette.
Entre.
Listen,
I wanted to talk to you
before the game finishes.
By the way,
they haven't played for ages.
They only meet once a month.
-Why?
-You know Andres.
He said that his friends
only came to see me,
that they never used to get
dressed up to play cards,
that they wear lots of cologne
and the store stinks afterwards.
Listen,
I still think we have to fire
that Maruja.
It's my maternal instinct.
Mom, if Andres is flirting
with Maruja
it's because he feels dominated
by all of us.
But he isn't dominated.
You still let him smoke
and read the newspaper.
Yes, but he thinks he is,
and that's why he wants
to take off that girl's blouse.
You have to get angry
and sort this out.
You can't let that go on
in your own home
or forgive your husband
just like that.
A woman who isn't able to forgive
isn't a real woman,
and I'm not the one who has
to get angry, she is.
And I've taken steps
to make sure that Maruja
gets really angry.
What steps are those?
When she spies on me,
which is almost always,
I kiss and cuddle my husband.
Then she gets furious.
And when a Spanish woman
gets furious,
I'm told no one can
put up with her.
And Andres won't put up with her.
And if your system doesn't work?
Bon,
there's no divorce here.
That's why men cheat
on their wives.
Men like to complicate their lives
so as well as having
their wives pester them
they look for other different women
to pester them too.
Masochism, you know?
Where did you learn that?
Reading,
observing
and listening to people
in the Galeries Lafayette.
Well...
Look, life goes past in a flash.
You blink...
and you're my age, forty.
And at forty,
you're in the reserves,
especially if you take away 15,
like I do.
You have to make the most of time.
If it were me,
I'd kill both of them
with a shotgun.
Good night, Ninette.
Bonne nuit, maman.
One last hand?
No, that's enough.
Look at the mess you've made!
Next time, put out a bit of ham.
A bit of ham! You should have
played a bit better.
Listen, next time,
don't wear so much cologne.
This place stinks.
One likes to be clean.
Everything annoys him.
When is Ninette opening the store?
We don't know yet.
We'll see.
Tell her from me
that I'll be her first customer.
-Sure.
-And give her a kiss.
-My regards to Ninette.
-I'll tell her.
And learn to play.
Hello.
Hello, mon amour
Port...
Porte-jarretelles.
Give me a kiss.
Why?
Because I need it.
Weren't you angry with me?
No.
Well, yes.
The other day I was in a bad mood.
But it would be unfair.
-I'm sure she's sorry.
-Who?
Maruja.
Maru, as you call her.
She's a nice girl
and very hard working.
You have to keep her forever.
What? I'm going to fire her.
You can't.
The labor laws don't allow it.
To hell with the labor laws!
Who bothers about them here?
Andres, it's best if she doesn't go.
You may be on your own soon
and you'll need company.
Why do you say that?
Because my parents are moving
to an apartment near the store.
No, they needn't move out.
And I'll be out all day.
Maruja can't possibly leave.
Don't you realize that
It could be dangerous?
Why?
Just suppose,
and it's only supposing,
that that girl
fell in love with me.
I wouldn't be surprised.
You're a very attractive man.
Tres sympathique.
And you've got a wonderful smile.
It wouldn't matter.
What's your idea of morality?
Do you think Murcia is Babylon
and everyone here
can do as they wish?
But I'm not jealous, mon amour.
Well, you should be.
You're right,
but you're mistaken.
-I can't hear anything.
-Maybe it's broken.
By the way,
when will you give me
one of those birds?
I told you, they're not mine,
they're my son-in-law's.
You give me one and if he misses it
tell him it flew away.
He won't believe it.
You want the bird inside its cage.
Of course. Do you expect me
To carry it on my finger?
Anyway, what I like most
about birds is the cage.
We have to go
and play at the club.
No.
Why not?
Because.
I don't want to be seen so much
In public with you.
It harms me.
And we went
To the soccer game last week.
What about me?
Doesn't this relationship harm me?
People are evil minded.
And priests are getting
a bad reputation these days.
Since we started wearing civvies,
you wouldn't believe what they say.
I know what they say.
Among other things,
that one day
you'll be able to get married.
By the Church, of course.
Indissoluble matrimony.
God prevent such a misfortune!
Bonsoir!
-Good afternoon.
Maruja,
I've never seen anyone
who suits a uniform as much as you.
Oh, la la!
-Bonsoir, Ninette.
-Bonsoir, papa.
-Ninette.
-Don Roque.
Bonsoir a tout le monde.
-Mme. Bernarda.
-How are you?
Bernarda,
what's happened to you?
Nothing.
This model came from Paris,
I liked it and I put it on.
Isn't it tres jolie, mon pere?
"Trays jolly".
These are the bags.
Like them?
"Ninette. Fashions from Paris."
Very nice.
Are you the Spaniard?
Yes, Andres Martinez.
Ninette.
I am sure, mademoiselle,
that you'd like to kiss me.
Why is the door closed?
We're balancing the books.
What did you want?
Why the urgent call?
Are you happy?
Happy?
Yes, really happy.
Well,
no.
Sit down.
Look, Armando,
there are women who like glamour,
indirect lighting.
They're usually mysterious,
a little unstable
and spend a fortune
on perfume and clothes.
Then there are others,
docile, simple, home-lovers,
who adore waxing the floors,
who move their lips a little
when they read
and who, when they kiss you, are
wondering if the tap is turned off.
Those women are a drag,
but they're there.
They have their good side.
Maruja...
She is both those kinds
of women together.
You follow me?
Frenzy and slippers.
What you have to do
is marry her right away
before someone else gets her.
There are lots of men after her
because she's a real looker too.
Get married and take her to Paris.
Armando, love is like fruit salts.
If you miss out
on the first effervescence,
it tastes like hell.
She said that last night.
About fruit salts?
No, about getting married
and going to Paris.
I took her out for dinner
last night
and then for a walk
on the outskirts.
Well,
it's the third time we've been out.
And it's true, she's a looker.
And her kisses, Andres.
They're
never-ending.
You never said anything
about those little outings.
She doesn't want anyone to know.
You know what they're like here.
She says she's crazy about me
and that this is terrible...
...and what's to become of us.
Did you see
how she's dressed today?
That's for you!
Today,
today, Nanking.
Nanking blue.
Go on.
Cold, dominating...
Watch this.
What are you doing?
Packing for the trip.
What trip?
That's my case.
Of course.
You're coming too.
Me? Where?
To Paris.
We've got lots of thing to buy.
You for your store
and I for mine.
What store?
Look, Andre,
"La Fuensanta" is very
old-fashioned, like the house.
No one comes in.
Dad's been offered
the Citroen dealership for Murcia
and this place
could be the car showroom.
Dad will run the technical side
and you, the commercial
and administrative side.
Dad doesn't want
to go back to Paris
because he loves Murcia,
so we'll look after everything.
-But...
-We'll buy things for the boutique,
clothes and disc brakes,
all those things.
And it'll be our honeymoon.
We'll walk along the Champs Elysees,
the Bois de Boulogne...
We'll have dinner
on the bateau-mouche.
Et on dinera
sur le bateau-mouche...
ou dans le Quartier Latin.
Bien sur.
Since it opened,
all the best hotels
have tried to imitate it.
Kings, princes
and other celebrities,
musicians, painters,
have stayed here.
That's a Tintoretto.
-Oh, no!
-What did he say?
Coco Chanel lived in our room.
Every room has got a fireplace
and pink lampshades
to enhance the ladies' complexions.
-Do you like it?
-Yes, tell him it's fine.
Everything is at hand,
the floor, the walls, the telephone...
It's her!
Yes, it's her.
Ninette, I can see the Eiffel Tower,
and the Seine,
and the boats.
That must be Montmartre...
Ninette, please,
don't do this to me.
Mon amour, it's spring,
the best time in Paris.
The heat is beginning.
The breeze is gentle,
from the north west.
And everything is as good
as when we used to sit
on the stairs at night.
Remember?
Of course.
And Aries is entering
the moon's house today.
C’est le moment.
Translation: D. Mac Closkey
Subtitles: LASERFILM