It will be so much more cruel than before.
Is it bad that we are living together?
Can't we bring her to our house?
How far are you planning to go?
Hey!- Come live in my house.
What?I locked my heart tightly in there.
I only thought about
what would be precious to Woo Hyun.
Don't you want to live with your mom too?  The one at my house.
How did I not know this?
Sung Yeol!
You missed me, right?
I missed you more.
Woo Hyun!
I know that it's shameless but please accept me.
Are you crazy?
Do you not know where this is? Get out.
I can't leave now.
Get out right now.
Go back.
I don't here alone and
even with just being responsible for Seul Bi is plentifully difficult.
Don't even you be like this.
You heard right. You were just thrown away again.
Hwang Sung Yeol!
If you don't leave, I'll leave.
Woo Hyun, please!
You... really...
Since you're here today, just stay.
Episode 15 Hurt? The times that I gave you more (pain) but I'm more hurt by it!
Why did you not tell me?
If there was an issue you should have told me first...
I'm your father.
Since you're my dad I couldn't tell you.
Since even you will be in pain then.
Let's think about what we have to do.
Subtitles brought to you by The Let's Love Team @ Viki
At times this is medicine.
I'm...
really sorry.
Hello.
Ah, yes. Hello.
Really? I understand.
Yes. Goodbye.
Hey, Hwang Sung Yeol! You rascal... !
It will get colder very soon.
I wonder if he brought some thicker clothes.
I have to discuss it with Sung Yeol's dad
and while you're here don't make any issues with Sung Yeol.
Woo Hyun, you should go back tomorrow.
Because of me, I don't like that it's become more difficult for you.
Aiyoo, you're too much. I came here to protect you.
I know but
are you outside because it feels strange to be here? I'll come outside too.
Stop. Don't come out. I don't want to get pegged (as not doing the right thing) from the first day.
I can't let you catch cold by yourself.
Oh, my Seul Bi is completely full of loyalty...
I am a bit. ...is what you thought I would say, right?
If you're sick I have to do all the store work by myself. Plus, I have to go to school by myself.
You can't. Don't ever get sick. Even if someone gets sick it'll be me.
Then hurry up and get inside.
Sung Yeol hasn't come home yet.
He left with Ahjussi, so don't worry.
Close the window and hurry up and go in.
One, two-- Sleep well.
Sweet dreams. Sleep well.
Are you okay?
Let's go.
Subtitles brought to you by The Let's Love Team @ Viki
I'm sorry.
I'll look for a solution.
Will you throw your own son back out on the street?
Or will you let just the two of them live alone again?
What do you want me to do?
How can the fellow who entrusted his son to you know that?
But
when you throw your own son out like that I'm afraid how bad Sung Yeol must have it.
Aish!
Hey... seriously.
Who are you?
You little thing, already with the (alcohol)...
Come here.
Hey, you... so disgustingly, put it back in.
Jerk.
So dirtily.
Bastard.
You're worse.
For such a cold punk your hands are warm.
Aiyoo, you cute punk. If you were this cute all the time how nice would that be.
Let's not fight in our dreams.
I'm tired.
Isn't sleep in the floor uncomfortable?
Since I'm together with you I'm okay.
♫  My love, my everything
♫ My angel from heaven
♫ My two eyes, my world
♫ You stole them all
♫ Little star~
♫ Tonight~
♫ All night, I will watch over you
Dream about me.
Shut up.
♫ Close your eyes... (and listen carefully to my story) ♫
Thanks for being by my side.
♫ Before my story ends, you will dream ♫
♫  Little star~, tonight~ ♫
♫ All night, I will watch over you ♫
HEY!
Are you crazy?
You almost killed me by squeezing me.
Why is your room so cold?
That bastard...
This is good for curing hangover.
I tried cleaning it...
You didn't have to do that.
Thanks for taking me in.
I will do even better if you take Woo Hyun in, too.
See you then.
Sung Yeol already left. He could've gone with us.
You don't have to tell the world that we are living together.
Living in same house and having a same mother is not a bad thing.
It is nothing good, either.
We can't be friends now.
Humans are so complicated.
Talking about humans again.
Oops, my mistake.
It is better to have Sung Yeol as a family than a stranger.
You guys knew each other well.
You can't share family members.
You said family is always on your side.
You said you don't share them, but you can be together with them.
Yes, I told you that wise saying to you,  who has a good memory.
I was so hungry while waiting for you.
I guess the cure worked.
You easily got drunk by drinking water with a same cup that was for alcohol.
I guess you take after your mother.
I don't want to take after anyone; including you and mom.
Right. Don't be like me.
I'm trying.
Woo Hyun must have his reasons.
I know it will be hard, but let's try to get along.
He is your friend, too.
He's not my friend.
Come.
Hey!
Wait, wait! I'm almost done!
Give me my wage; 31500 won (approx. $31.5).
My wage is 5210 won, but why do you always exclude 210 won?
Don't come again from now on.
Don't work if you don't want 5000 won.
Boss...  - Go away!
You can't pretend you're happy, but you can pretend you were surprised?
Your work ended early today.
What happened? Is it because of your boss?
That bastard...
I will revenge him.  - Why would you do that?
Hmm?
I am really good at that.
Democratic and capitalism.
Find the connection between globalization and nationalism...
Yo Han, Chun Shik, talk to me about whether you guys are doing well or not.
First, compare the social ideas nowadays with
democratic, capitalism, nationalism...
Please do it with the perspective of society today.
Second, apart from today's social ideas,
No cell phones during class. You didn't know that?
You can have it. I will just buy a new one.
Is that so? I will take it anyways.
You should open a store for cell phones now.
Hand in the career paper next time. That's it.
Teacher!
You live with Sung Yeol.
Doesn't Sul Bi live with Sung Yeol, too?
Isn't that right?
How about you study hard with that curiosity?
What is Sung Yeol to you?
He's my son.
Daebak!
Son?
Come.
Lee Sul Bi. You're blessed.
What did you do?
Living with boys - is that your specialty?
Sleeping together is same as living together.  It is not like what you guys think, though.
There is a reason for that.
A dog that was chasing a chicken is now fixing a barn.  (It is a saying in Korean, and it is actually "a dog that was chasing a chicken is now looking up at roof".)
So idiotic.
Shut your mouth before I beat you up.
I was only telling the truth...
I didn't allow you to talk with me.
I know your sad because of Sung Yeol.  Then why are you mad at me? You should be mad at Sul Bi.
Isn't all you have to do is get along with Sung Yeol?
What do you do now? You tried everything to get Woo Hyun.  But look at you now.
Is she your real mother? Or a new one?
Oh sorry. I think I hurt your feelings.
Good job.
Good job?  - You should go around babbling like that i the future too.
It is hard for me to talk about them.
Take this back, and don't you dare care about me.
You should go on an audition if you want to become a singer.
Why are you doing that in karaoke?
You know I don't keep secrets.
You are threatening now?
You use money or threaten...
Ah, you don't have friends.
I had a hard time until now. Because of her.
If you were threatened. You must have done something to get threatened.
That fits you better than being a singer.
Don't you feel glad to see this?
Why do you always hide your feelings?
Young Eun was looking for you because she was worried about you
And you also pushed me down the stairs because you wanted to be closer to Young Eun again
That's not it. You wouldn't know.
Your eyes are sweating
Human tears are warm too
Mom she keeps making fun of me!
What was with those ahjusshis?
Those men? They were a CEO and manager of an agency.
All my effort was ruined because of you.
Is that the only agency? Do you want me to open an agency for you?
Am I funny to you? Is my dream amusing?
I know too that I don't have any talent
But if I don't things like that, do you think I would ever be able to stand on a stage?
With no money or connections,
Is it not ok to have a dream?
You without a dream is more pathetic than me.
Be careful with that side of your shoulders. Don't use it too much and if it gets worse, go take an X-ray
Thank you.
Oh! Is Sung Yeol's mom really the ethics teacher?
It was all the school was talking about
I should've known... Whenever it came to Sung Yeol, she reacted totally differently.
Wait, then isn't the ethics teacher Sung Yeol's step-mom then?
Everything's suddenly going so badly for Sung Yeol...
Why? Because she's not the birth mother?- Yes.
My mom said that only one new thing that's bad is a new mom (step-mom)
It's a joke. Apparently now step-mom's are better
What's the difference between a birth mother and a stepmother?
I guess, well, closer or less close... why are you taking this so seriously...?
What's up with him?
2,100 won, please.
Is there anything else you need?
Give me 31500 won (about $30)
This is recording well right?
Even if it's a student, if they lose hard earned money,
do you think they would feel good?
Should I officially report you to the labor department?
Who?
Who are you?
210 won (about $0.19) per hour for five hours a day
31500 won (about $30) for one month
Are you going to admit it or not?
I'll give this to Joo Ah
Next time when you pay your part-timers,
Start with "Good job" or "Thank you"
To our kids.
Yes.
It looks like humans are often born to hurt each other
Scar?
The sweat that comes out of eyes is warm because the human is warm right?
Sweat that comes from eyes are normally warm.
If your tears were cold too, it'd be more sad wouldn't it?
There's nothing you don't know.
This isn't a commercial
I'll go help at the store a little before I go. Could you keep it a secret from teacher though?
You're lying now.
If Teacher told you not to come to the shop, I'm okay. Go.
Still, it'll be hard by yourself.
I have Ki Soo and Chun Sik so don't worry.
Bring her home carefully
Go.
I'm a thing that hurts you
I'll stop by at the bookstore before I go. I had something to buy but I completely forgot.
We can go together.
No, I can go by myself. I'll be right back.
Subtitles brought to you by The Let's Love Team@Viki
800 won.
You even took out a loan to save Woo Hyun's store?
The loan and the interest I'll work it well and repay it.
That's not what I'm talking about right now. You should have at least discussed it with me.
What am I to you? Why do you keep disappointing me this way?
I couldn't look the other way and I couldn't discuss it with you.
How could I be so shameless as to even ask?
How can I know what else you're hiding from me?
Honey, honey, I'm sorry. I'm not hiding anything else form you, really.
Those words right now are the most unbelievable.
You even helped them with the Ddeokbokki shop?
You wanted to help them too.
Is then and now the same?
That's the money that Dad worked all night and earned with difficulty.
That wasn't your father's money.
It's the money I saved so difficultly while living apart from my son
thinking to get a small house.
In the end you were thinking of throwing me and my father away and living with your son.
While thinking that why did you reveal to the kids that I was your son?
Since you are my son too.
Then I'd better reveal that Woo Hyun is your biological son too.
Fine. Reveal it as quickly as you can
so that at least at school I can look at him comfortably.
You knew, right? About Sung Yeol and the ethics teacher.
That you didn't tell me that kind of big news? Were we only of that kind of relationship?
Has the affection cooled?
Hey, the ddeokbokki will cool. Hurry up and go.
But anyway, Seul Bi and Sung Yeol in one house.
Would it be all right?
If a man and woman keep looking at each others' faces they say that even ugly things appear pretty.
Hey, then to you I must forever look pretty since I see you everyday.
Hey, that's not true!
Not true my butt.  What's he talking about?
Go well and come back safely.
How did you come?
Sung Yeol told me that you were busy and to come help you.
Even your lies show on your face.
What should I start with?
Go help Joo Ah.
Congrats on your first day of work.
Thanks. Isn't it sad to live in someone else's house?
It's not sad but it is a little difficult being watchful of their notice.
Living in someone else's house is like that normally. You have to be the first to wake up and the last to sleep.
There is really nothing you don't know.
You have no reaction even though you're the main character of this huge announcement. Isn't that intriguing?
If you've come just play your game.
What's your dream?
I just tried asking wondering what kind of dream a guy who studies so well has.
Lee Seul Bi, here.
The thing is...
I'm sorry.
I'll see you at home later.
Hey, it sounds just like the conversation of newlyweds.
See you at home later.
You'll have to help me.
Subtitles brought to you by The Let's Love Team
Eat a lot. Hwang Sung Yeol says that he'll treat us properly today.
Aren't you going to take the order?
Yes. What shall I get you Customer?
What's that picture?
Jealousy, betrayal, love triangle.
From there to there. Bring it all.
Yes.
Customers are Seul Bi's and my way to feed ourselves. Let's hold it in.
♫ If you wanna be my love? (I wanna be your star)♫
♫  In even one day I want to see you so many times,  ♫
♫  That I love you, that you're the only one,  ♫
♫  If you'd hug me prettily,  ♫
♫  Everything will change,  ♫
♫ If you wanna be my love...♫
Oh, yes.
Hey, let's set the date.
Hey, because of you we did earn some good money.
Hey, thanks.
It's $74 but I'll only take $170.
Get it from your mom since this is your mom's store.
What does that mean?
Your mom is this store's owner. Didn't you know?
Is that true? Did Teacher help us?
Since you're her biological son she spent a lot of money.
So what? It doesn't matter who the owner is. Calculate it properly.
I'm her son on her family registry so isn't this much okay?
Let's go.
Hey, Hwang Sung Yeol. Don't you get the sense that this is really petty?
I'll show you what being really petty is. Aren't you coming?
Woo Hyun, I'll leave first.
I'll see you at home.
Have you really decided to make things difficult for Woo Hyun?
I'm thinking to go to the end.
I don't know what will be the end of that path so don't ask.
You give pain to Woo Hyun, and you hurt as much as he does.
No, I don't hurt at all.
Are you okay?
You're not crying. You're quite sturdy.
You normally smiled like that, warmly and sweetly.
Walk carefully.
I'm sorry for lying earlier.
Woo Hyun's shoulder seemed to hurt him. I couldn't leave him to work alone.
Even if you lie I'm not going to send you any longer.
It would be nice if Woo Hyun could try living with his mother.
He always longed for her.
How many days or months it will be,
it's in your hands.
Subtitles brought to you by Let's Love Team @Viki
Sung Yeol, let's eat!
I don't care, I'll just eat later.
You eat first, I'll just eat later.
Both of you sit.
I don't know what happened to you two, but in this house, don't make it uncomfortable for everyone.
This isn't a place where only you two live
Let's have dinner together
And don't try to live off only ramen
Let's try share the tasks. There's no one comfortable here. Got it?
Yes.
Did the store do well today?
Excuse me?
Yes. It was busy today.
That's a relief.
The store... I'll work hard to get it back
I can't repay the debt right now but
I have to pretend to ignore it even if it's a cowardly thing to do
Please wait a bit.
For a mom, it was the naturally thing to do. I would've done the same.
Everything,
Honestly, everything is uncomfortable and weird
I'm uncomfortable too, here.
I can't smile here
Even though I didn't know if my mom was ever going to come, I liked that house because I was waiting for her.
Sung Yeol can't forget his real mom either.
It must be the same for you
You guys are only 18
I'm running towards the end of a cliff
And Sung Yeol.
If Sung Yeol falls first, I will definitely catch him. Don't worry too much.
What if you fall first?
I can't fall. I have people to protect.
Thank you for taking me in
Are you okay?
Let go, I'll do it.
That's right! Sung Yeol is my son.
Aigoo...
Why are you like this?
Let go.
Ah, let's go.
It's okay.
I heard that humans drink alcohol when they're sad
The ahjusshi, teacher, and Sung Yeol all seem unhappy because of me.
Even if everyone else in the world is unhappy because of you, there will always be one person, one person who's happy because of you.
Who's that?
Me! Me!
Me too! Me!
You are hurt, why didn't you tell me?
It's all better now because you worried about me. It's fine
Pain in your body will heal over time but when will aches in your heart heal?
You, and Sung Yeol, too.
Hey, Hwang Sung Yeol.
Let's talk.
You go in first.
Don't fight.
Out of all the sports, basketball, soccer, and running, the reason why I have to do this today
Forget it
If I win, the relationship between Teacher, you, and me will definitely stay a secret.
If I win, I'll reveal Seul Bi's secret.
What's your secret with Seul Bi?
Whatever she's hiding, wouldn't you know better?
♫ Recently, it seems like I'm living in a dream every day ♫
♫ I’m still not used to this kind of life ♫
♫ When I’m with you, the stars twinkle even during the day ♫
♫ I don’t want to meet anyone else but you  ♫
♫ Without you, I don’t want to do anything  ♫
♫ Even when I’m with my friends, I’m always thinking about you ♫
♫ You’re too much for me  ♫
♫ You’re too good for me  ♫
♫ Anyone can see you’re beautiful, everyone wants you, I can’t believe you’re my girl  ♫
♫ Baby baby baby, you’re too much  ♫
♫ Baby baby baby, oh~ girl ♫
♫ Today and tomorrow, I’ll be always loving you  ♫
Now shut your mouth. Forever
If you had to win with that much purpose, there must be something about Seul Bi
In front of each other, let's not fight, because of you Seul Bi, is hurt.
♫ It was the beginning of fall, ♫
♫ when it was cold but not really cold  ♫
♫ You seemed like you’d be cold  ♫
♫ but you were wearing short clothes  ♫
♫ The season passed  ♫
♫ and today the sunshine is warm  ♫
♫ Spring has come...  ♫
Wh-what's the matter?
Are you hurt somewhere?
Some painkillers...
Painkillers?
Here...
I'll do it.
Sung Yeol and prepare it, we knew that you were having a hard time.
Really?
Sung Yeol, thank you.
Not bad
I'll eat well.
This-- Woo Hyun.
Stop it!
What are you doing right now?!
Is that all you can do?
Being like this you...
This is all your fault
So, please stop now. Think of me
Are you okay?
Why did you just eat it. You can't even say you can't eat it?
Sorry. The only thing I gave you was allergies.
Just rest.
When you were six and crossing the busy street,
you crossed alone to get to your grandma's
As soon I caught you I hit you.
Saying how even without you things were difficult but why were you adding to my hardships?
The fact that I was a divorced, single mom having to take care of you alone,
It was really hard and embarassing.
As if you knew my feelings, you would cry yourself to sleep
I was afraid that if I kept you, you might have died
It's hard.
It sounds like a weak excuse to me
You're right. It's an excuse.
You have to live
and I have to live, too.
You would've been hurting too
Instead of me
I should've taken the pain for you
I realized that late, Woohyun
But,
Since, you're hurt
it's nice that I can see you for a long time
I'm really bad aren't I?
What do you think will change if you keep this up?
If you keep getting mad, both of you will just keep getting hurt more
And also, don't bother Woo Hyun anymore. I won't let it go anymore
Don't come close!
What are you?
What exactly are you hiding?
There's nothing I'm hiding
Perhaps, are you-
Shut your mouth.
I have nothing to do with the mess you and Teacher are in
Weirder and weirder things are happening. It's because of you isn't it?
Hey, hey, hey! What's wrong with you?!
I'm sorry.
Go away! Leave!
Let me see you even like this
No, please!!
Please don't let anything happen to us