(GENTLE MUSIC)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
(SLEIGHBELLS TINKLE)
(CROSSING BELL CLANKS)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
If you want to build a rocket
and send a man into space,
don't come to me.
You don't want to know.
I'm not your man.
If, however, you have any questions
regarding the quality
of a fine pair of pants...
I'm getting a migraine.
Pants - that's what I know.
I know pants.
Oh, I had a day.
"Then he says to me,
“What about chines?"
Those Hebrew slaves
from Ancient Egypt...
Dad...
Yeah, I know chinos.
Those slaves were in Disneyland...
Mom?
Compared to working in...
Then he asked about jeans!
Dad? Mom?
I grew up on jeans.
I'm sure being whipped
while you're building a pyramid...
Then he says overalls.
Now he's insulting me.
Those slaves didn't have to book
the Himmelmanns nonstop to Boca...
Mom? Dad?
Pavarotti knows singing.
I know pants!
NARRATOR: North was positive
he was having a coronary.
"I said, “Do you know who I am?"
Now, as a rule, 11-year-olds
don't experience cardiac events.
“In case you've forgotten,
this is who I am.”
But for North,
this was a very stressful time.
"“I'm number six!"
North was having
a difficult time with his folks.
Dad!
It was putting a damper
on what was in all other respects,
a very successful life.
How successful?
Well, look at the year he'd had.
Photosynthesis - the process
by which carbohydrates are formed
in the chlorophyll
contained in tissues of plants
exposed to sunlight.
(Sings) ♪ If I were a rich man
♪ Dibba dibba dibba dibba
dibba dibba dibba don
♪ All daylong, I'd biddy biddy bum
♪ If I were a wealthy man. ♪
Hey!
MAN: Bravo!
An outstanding year
by anyone's standards.
But did North's folks
appreciate how special he was? Hardly.
Dad?
“I'm number six.
“L was inspecting pants
before you started wearing them,
"“Mr Vice President Only Because
Your Father Owns The Company."
God forbid the Himmelmanns
should stop over in Atlanta.
"“I've forgot more about belt loops
than you'll ever know!"
See this rash?
You see it? Himmelmann!
“Let me tell you this."
Dad!
“L am only this year's recipient
of the coveted Mr Inseam Award!"
Well, that shut him up.
Dad, do you know what
that stupid Winchell did to me today?
I saw some blood
in my stool this morning.
(Shrieks)
North! Are you OK'?
North'?
What's the matter?
Loosen his pants.
No, no.
No, I'm OK. I'm alright.
I'm alright.
I'm OK.
But North wasn't OK.
This parent thing was starting
to affect every aspect of his life.
It's turning into the wind.
What sense does that make?
It's not a...
Maybe it's supposed to show us
where the wind was.
What are we supposed to do
with that information'?
To be or not to...
Line'?
Be!
Oh.
(CROWD CALLS OUT)
Ball four!
Six in a row.
Time out.
(RUEFUL MUSIC)
How you doing?
I don't get it.
A child is born, he's given a life,
but then, he's appreciated
by everyone except the folks
who gave him that life.
It's just not right.
Uh, let me rephrase the question.
How's the arm?
Mr Blackman, I've got some problems
that I have to work out.
Problems?
You? North'?
So while everyone speculated
as to what could possibly be bothering
last season's most valuable player,
North left the field and headed
straight for his secret spot.
Yes, North had a secret spot.
You know the kind of spot
I'm talking about -
a place that's just ordinary
to everyone else
but for some reason,
is special only to you
because, no matter where it is,
this is the spot where you can go
and feel that you're away
from everyone and everything,
the spot where you can do
your best thinking,
the one place where you can reflect upon
what was, mull over what is
or just sit back, close your eyes
and change the world
into whatever you wish it could be.
Now, it's my guess
that even North couldn't remember
when his spot first revealed
its special powers to him.
Nor did it even matter at this point.
What was important was
whenever he sat in that huge armchair,
he looked like any other kid
just waiting for his parents
to finish their Easter shopping.
And he was sitting on that very spot
the first time I saw him.
Why don't they like me?
What did I do wrong'?
(MAGICAL MUSIC)
You OK, kid?
Yeah.
Good. 'Cause I only got
a 10-minute break.
And my back is killing me.
The last thing I need is to listen
to somebody else's problems.
You hungry?
No, thanks.
Good. 'Cause I'm starving
and this is my last carrot.
So... who are you?
I'm North.
I've seen your name on maps.
Very impressive.
Who are you?
I'm the Easter Bunny.
Third floor, toys.
Oh.
At least until Sunday, that is.
And then what do you do?
Whatever I want.
Independently wealthy.
Fourth of July, I might be Uncle Sam.
Christmas, maybe Santa Claus.
My life's a holiday.
How about yours?
Not lately.
I had a real bad game today.
How bad'?
I walked nine Panthers
and hit my coach's wife with a wild pitch.
That's bad.
What, have you got something
on your mind?
Well?
What is it?
I thought you didn't want to hear
anyone else's problems.
Do you always believe
everything a stranger tells you?
Come on, spill.
Ah, you wouldn't understand.
Try me.
It's my folks.
Yeah. What about them?
I don't know.
All they care about is themselves.
Selfish folks.
That is rough.
They don't know what a good thing
they got in you, right?
Exactly. And they're the only ones.
You should hear
what all the other parents say about me.
North's room is always clean.
(HORN HONKS AND TYRES SQUEAL)
North always looks both ways.
North never spoils his appetite.
North ﬂosses.
Holy mackerel!
Your folks are sitting on a goldmine.
Tell me about it.
You realise, of course,
that you're not alone.
What do you mean?
Look, kid,
just because I'm in a bunny suit
doesn't mean I haven't stumbled
across a basic truth now and then.
The feeling
of being insufficiently appreciated
is a common childhood lament.
I'm not common!
Of course you're not.
But I bet
that even Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart,
who wrote a symphony
by the age of three,
had more than a few evenings then
with an angry parent yelling,
“Stop banging on that damn piano
"“and go to bed, Mozart!"
Yeah, fine!
But Mr Mozart's dead and I'm alive.
So I'll bet right now I'm in more pain
than he is.
Hard to argue with that one.
At this point, I'd even settle
for Mozart's parents.
Well, unfortunately,
you don't get to make that choice, kid.
The one thing that we cannot control
in this life is who our parents are.
You're dealt the hand,
you're stuck with it.
It's not like baseball
where if you don't like one team,
you become a free agent
and get a better deal elsewhere.
Another team...
This is real life, kid.
The rules are different.
Listen, I got to get back upstairs.
If you want my advice -
and I know you didn't ask for it -
go home, make up, and goodbye.
And that was it.
Nothing special.
I just left him there
in that secret spot of his.
Just him and his thoughts.
(Voice echoes) Free agent.
What a scoop!
A kid becoming a free agent
then offering his services
as a devoted son
to the highest-bidding set of parents!
It's brilliant, North! Mwah!
Simply brilliant.
Look, this still isn't for sure yet.
You know, this could be my Watergate.
Winchell, you put out a two-page
leaflet with a circulation of 90!
It might even land me the Pulitzer.
I told you because you're my friend,
not because you're editor
of the school newspaper.
I'm a journalist, North.
So'?
So you never said this conversation
was off the record.
Winchell, I need time to think.
Alright, alright! I'll hold the story.
But, North, a few more displays
like that Panther game
and some of the more attractive parents
might start doing some thinking
of their own.
That damn Panther game!
And, North, that geography test
we took today...
What about it?
You got a 34.
Huh'?
Chicago is in Africa?
Mexico is an island
off the coast of Montana?
Where did you get this?
I'm ajournalist, North.
I can't reveal my sources.
Besides, how I got this test
is not important.
Why you got this grade is.
Your instincts are correct, old buddy.
You need new parents
and you need them now.
Unless...
Unless what?
Unless you haven't got the guts
to go through with it.
Winchell, I've got more guts
than anybody in this town!
And you know it.
Yeah? Talk is cheap.
I just feel that I owe it to my parents
to give them one last chance.
What can I say?
You came to me, you sought my counsel.
The rest is up to you.
No. No, that's OK.
Thanks anyway.
Yes, North wanted to give his folks
every chance
to keep the family together.
He tried to reach his mom
but she was too busy
re-routing the Himmelmanns.
That left Dad.
Pants. Can I help you?
Hello. My name is North.
Can I talk to my dad?
What number?
Number six.
Looks like that five iron
is going to be a little...
(JOLLY BAVARIAN MUSIC)
Number six!
(SMOOTH LATIN MUSIC)
Phone call for you.
Get a number, would you?
It's your son.
Oh. Alright, just a minute.
Is that piping holding up?
Very well, Mr Vice-President.
Now he's an expert on piping!
Hello.
Hello, Dad. Can I talk to you?
Yes.
Oh, we need these by 5:00.
I only got two legs here!
North, I'm swamped.
Could we discuss this over dinner, son?
But, Dad...
Alright, we'll discuss it over dinner.
Yeah. Right. Dinner.
Well, that's that.
(SOLDIERLY MUSIC)
OK, guys, let's roll.
Zoe, you take the south side.
Adam, here are yours.
Winchell!
Winchell! Winchell!
Here you go.
I've made my decision.
Don't tell me, let me guess.
How did you know'?
News travels fast.
Apparently.
I'm proud of you, kid. You got a lawyer?
Why? Do I need one?
North, this is America.
Everyone needs a lawyer.
Lucky for you, I happen to know the best.
Arthur Belt. He's done some work
for me pro bono.
Move it!
Where will I find him?
Don't worry. He'll find you.
We've got a paper to get out!
(SIREN WAILS)
(TYRES SQUEAL)
Hello, North. Arthur Belt, at your service.
Here.
The lawyer?
YOUR lawyer.
Now, from now on, we are in a team.
Do what I tell you and before you know it,
you'll have the world's best parents.
What do you say, kid?
Sure you can squeeze me in'?
What? Oh, the ambulance-chasing thing.
That's nothing.
I just use it to beat the traffic.
You should try it some time.
Now, kid, are we a team?
Yeah, I guess so.
Hey, hey, hey! You KNOW so.
Yes, North was actually
going to go through with it
and challenge the entire concept
of family as we know it.
The effect was immediate.
Kids now faced their parents
with a confidence
they once could only dream about.
What a great idea. North is a genius.
Jeffrey, don't be ridiculous.
Now, where did I put
that phone number for Arthur Belt?
Did I say 'ridiculous'?
"What I meant to say was,
“You look very handsome today, Jeffrey."
You realise North will never pull this off.
He's North. He can do anything.
Come on, Andy.
His folks are going to fight it.
Yes. They won't take this lying down.
Then the media circus began.
How do you feel about this?
Ls Winchell's story accurate?
Can we take that as a yes?
North, think you can pull this off'?
No comment.
North, if you are successful,
how will your actions
affect Mothers' Day?
No comment!
In 1793, the cotton gin was invented.
North, could you please tell us
the name of the inventor?
It...
Oh. Under strict advice from counsel,
I must respectfully say no comment.
Finally, North's day in court arrived
and the world was watching.
All rise for the Honourable Judge Buckle.
All sit for the Honourable Judge Buckle.
Now, then, let me remind you
this is a trial, this is not a hearing.
Even though both sides
will be saying things I will hear,
it is still not a hearing.
No doubt, you'll all hear
the same things I'm hearing.
That's your privilege.
However, once both sides
have been heard,
then it's my job to pass judgment.
Obviously, you can all pass judgment
too, but it won't count.
That's because I am the one
who is the judge.
Have I made myself clear
to the plaintiff?
Yes, Your Honour.
It is quite clear to the plaintiff.
Have I made myself clear to the defence?
Your Honour, the defence rests.
There's nothing left for me to do
but make myjudgment.
And in my judgment,
any folks who sleep
through a trial like this
don't deserve to have a wonderful
upstanding son like North!
I rule in favour of the plaintiff.
Yes!
The system works.
North, you're a free man.
(GAVEL BANGS)
Hold on.
(Sings) ♪ Israel was in Egypt land
♪ Let my people go... ♪
Hold it. Hold it down!
Everybody! ♪ Go down, Moses... ♪
Hey, hey, hold it down!
♪ Go down, Moses... ♪
Hey, it's a court of law.
Even though I have made a judgment,
the trial is not over.
I still have to make a ruling.
Now then, today is...
BAILIFFI July 1.
Today is July 1.
And it is my ruling that North
chooses new parents by Labor Day
so he begins school
with his new family.
If he does not choose new parents,
he has the option of returning
to his original parents.
However, if he is not physically
in the arms
of either his new parents
or his original parents
by noon on Labor Day,
he will be remanded to an orphanage.
And if any of you has ever seen
'The Little Rascals',
you know that's no day at the beach.
Orphanage?
Not to worry.
I'm telling you, kid - from now on,
the world is your oyster.
Even though North
didn't really care for oysters,
he couldn't help but take Arthur Belt's
enthusiasm as a positive sign.
North Free Agent Draft.
Good morning.
Yes, his eyes are blue.
Soprano.
Super Mario 3.
The backstroke.
Yes, he believes
in God and evolution.
Don't even get him started
on the Warren Commission.
Oh, everyone wants you, kid! Everyone!
You've got a first-class ticket
to every city in the world.
Now, I have to advise you -
don't spread yourself too thin.
It's important you learn
as much as you can
about all the parents you audition,
because once you sign, that's it.
They're your new folks forever.
You understand?
You bet.
That's the spirit.
Let's get cracking!
(HAPPY MUSIC)
So North was on his way.
It was the Fourth of July.
This year, Independence Day
had a special meaning for North.
He was a free man
and on his way
to search out the life
he felt he so richly deserved.
WOMAN ON P.A.: Flight 768,
nonstop service to New York,
is now boarding at gate seven.
('THE YELLOW ROSE OF TEXAS'
ON CAR HORN )
Oh, boy!
Look at that boy!
Look at him, Pa!
Well, hey! Howdy, North.
I'm Pa Texas. Here's Ma Tex.
Howdy.
And welcome to the great state of Texas.
Uh... howdy.
(EASYGOING COUNTRY MUSIC)
(cow MOOS)
I know what you're thinking.
Big car, right'?
Well, it did cross my mind.
Everything I own
is the biggest and the best.
That's why we'd like you
to become our son.
'Cause you're the best.
To the best.
(THEME MUSIC FROM 'DALLAS' )
(HORSE NEIGHS)
Home, sweet home.
This can all be yours, son.
The main house, guesthouse,
livestock, oilwells.
Rumour has it you like baseball.
It's my favourite.
You know, I used to own
the Houston Astros.
Really? What happened?
Just this morning,
I signed them over to you.
Oh, gee, don't get me wrong -
they're a fine organisation -
but aren't we rushing things just a little?
Pretty fair shooting there, Gabby.
Thanks, boss.
(MAGICAL MUSIC)
Hey!
What are you doing here?
Well, I've finished up all my chores.
I figured I'd get a little shooting in.
No, I mean...
Have you ever been an Easter Bunny'?
Easter Bunny'?
Careful, son. Gabby's killed men
for less than that.
Oh.
Sorry.
No harm done.
So, what you two cowpokes
got planned for tomorrow'?
Well, I reckon
we'll wake up early and eat.
Then we'll dig for oil and eat,
and then we'll rope some doggies
and bust a few rumps,
and then maybe grab a bite to eat.
You like Tex Mex?
Uh, sure. I'm a huge fan of any food
that straddles two borders.
(Laughs) That's my boy!
But can I ask you what the deal is
with all this eating?
Oh, simple -
remember before when I told you
everything I own
is the biggest and the best'?
Well, you're already the best.
Now there's nothing left
but to make you the biggest!
Don't fret about not being able
to clean your plate.
Why, pretty soon, that stomach of yours
will stretch and stretch,
and your capacity for food
will just grow and grow.
Excuse me,
you say that like that's a good thing
to have happen to your stomach.
N is.
Why?
Well, then you'll be like Buck.
Who?
Our first son.
Biggest boy
this big State's ever seen.
Why, he could eat more in one day
than anyone else
could eat in a whole month!
That's why Buck hated February.
Where is Buck?
He died in a stampede.
Oh. I'm so sorry.
Well, needless to say,
it was a mighty big loss.
Now we'd like to show you how much
we're looking forward
to having you as our new son.
Ready, Pa?
Ready, Ma!
(Sings) ♪ We had a son
♪ Who was trampled by a ton
of longhorns
♪ But you're here, Cutes
To fill his boots
♪ As flat as they may be
♪ You'll yell 'yippee-yi-yo'
at the rodeo till the day's done
♪ Then you'll make a lot of pals
with buffalo gals
♪ Just leave some for me
♪ Hey there!
♪ We'll barbecue steaks and skin
♪ We'll feed you pumpkin pie
♪ Till your can's bigger than
♪ The big old Texan sky
♪ Yee-ha!
♪ You'll grow tall and play football
Be famous!
♪ You'll grow more
Own a chain of stores
♪ Marry Betty Lou
♪ Oh, North, North
♪ Grow more! ♪
Another rib, son?
(POIGNANT MUSIC)
You OK, cowboy'?
Yeah. Just thinking.
Texas nights
are sure good for thinking.
(Softly) Yeah.
I was thinking if I stay here,
I'll always be living in the shadow
of someone else.
What kind of life would that be'?
And from what I hear about Buck,
what kind of shadow would that be'?
Yeah, he was a big one.
Mighty hard being your own man
when they're always
comparing you to somebody else.
Yeah. Right.
I mean, I left home
because I had parents
who didn't appreciate who I was.
So why would I want to be
with new parents
who could only appreciate me
if I was someone else?
You might be
onto something there, son.
You know, down here in these parts
we got a saying -
“Sometimes when
you're panning for gold,
"“you gotta try more than one stream."
We really wish you'd reconsider.
I'm sorry, but it
wouldn't be fair to any of us.
Well, thanks for the opportunity, North.
Oh, sir?
Yes, North'?
(Sighs) I think it's only right
that I give you back the Astros.
Well, thanks, son. That's a class gesture.
Well... goodbye.
So long, pard.
We'll miss you.
Hold on there, son.
Just a little something to remember
your old buddy Gabby by.
Hope it brings you good luck.
Thanks!
So North resumed his search.
And though
he got to the airport by noon,
out of respect for Ma and Pa Tex,
in true cowboy tradition,
he chose to wait eight hours
so he could fly off into the sunset...
"with no knowledge at all
of what was going on back home."
BOY: How much longer do we
have to put with this indignity?
How much longer
must we tolerate these injustices?
The subservience!
KIDS: Yeah!
It's humiliating, my friends.
It's demeaning.
Right on!
Now is the time to say no!
Now is the time to say,
“Just because you were born
25 or 30 years before me
“doesn't make you smart,
it doesn't make you right...
"“..it just makes you OLD!"
(All cheer)
It just makes you
smell worse in the morning!
(All cheer)
Now is the time to band together
and let our parents know
that we're at the dawn of a new era -
the era of our liberation!
(All applaud loudly)
An era made possible by a kid
who had the guts to fight
for the power we now possess!
And now the man
whose brilliant legal mind
shone the light
on the pathway to freedom -
Mr Arthur Ulysses Belt Esquire!
(All cheer loudly)
Thank you.
I am but a humble servant,
standing at your ready,
to assist in this noble cause!
Viva el Norte!
ALL: Viva el Norte!
But like I said,
North didn't know about any of this.
He was on his way to Hawaii,
to meet what he hoped would be
his brand-new parents.
(HAWAIIAN MUSIC)
Governor and Mrs Ho'?
Aloha, North.
Welcome to our island paradise, North.
Aloha.
We got a big day planned for you.
Waki-Waki will take you to the house,
to change.
OK.
Aloha!
'Aloha'?
I thought that meant 'hello'!
Ah, in Hawaii,
'aloha' means 'hello' AND 'goodbye'.
Doesn't that get confusing?
Only when you're firing someone.
Oh. Well, aloha!
Isn't he great?
(RELAXING HAWAIIAN MUSIC)
You know, North, if you settled here,
you'd be many years younger because
of the difference in time zones.
Which means you won't die
as early as you would
if you lived on the mainland.
That's a plus!
Another thing, North -
living in Hawaii, it's much easier
to get into a good college.
How's that'?
Here in the islands, we have
only 12 letters in our alphabet.
Really?
That's right.
Five vowels.
W, .E, , T, .0,' .U, _
Seven consonants.
H, ' .K, I, ' M, ' N, ' p, ' .W, _
Well, I didn't know that.
Well, sure! Just think about it.
'Waikiki' 'Honolulu'...
'Kona Pali', 'Mauna Lani'...
Well, that's very interesting,
but how does that
help me get into college?
Well, since we don't use
the letters 'B', 'C', 'D' and 'F',
you're pretty much guaranteed
to get straight 'A's.
What do you think?
Well, I like what I see.
But I do have one question,
just for my own peace of mind.
What is it?
Well, I hope I'm not being insensitive,
but...
you wouldn't have a dead kid
whose shoes you want me to fill, right?
Dead kid'?
North, Hawaii is a lush and fertile land.
In fact, there's only one
barren area on all of our islands.
Unfortunately, it's Mrs Ho.
But if all goes right,
you will be our first child.
Wow. What a great day.
You know, this might really work out.
As far as I'm concerned, there's just
a few minor details to discuss.
You know, bedtimes, sleep-overs, your
views on snacks - that sort of thing.
Well, what are we standing here for'?
Let's go inside
and push a few numbers around, huh?
See what we come up with.
(FAST-PACED TRIBAL MUSIC)
ANNOUNGER'. Ladies and gentlemen,
Governor and Mrs Ho.
(All cheer)
(Speaks Hawaiian)
Ladies and gentlemen,
fellow 50th-Staters,
I am thrilled to announce
that we have reached
an agreement in principle
which allows me
to introduce to you today
a young man who in the coming years
will be to Hawaii
what the peach is to Georgia,
what the apple is to New York,
and what the wind is to Chicago.
Now, without further ado, please
give a big, warm Hawaiian welcome
to our new pride and joy -
our son, North!
(All cheer)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
What is that'?
Son, that'll be in every airport,
along every highway...
My crack?! My crack is gonna
be shown in every airport?!
Now, son...
What gives you the right
to show my crack on every highway?
See, the truth is, North,
I'm the Governor of a state
that's running a little low on self-esteem.
After 35 years of statehood,
people still don't treat Hawaii
like we're part of the country.
Sure, there's a star on the flag,
but why didn't anyone show up
during Hands Across America?
We waited for days, and not even
a call to say nobody was coming.
It's just plain inconsiderate.
He's right.
People from the mainland
just don't care about Hawaii.
They come here with their knobby knees
and their pale kids,
and they eat our food
and watch our whales
and say 'Aloha!', like they really mean it.
7-10 days later they drop us like
a sack of rancid poi and go home!
And we're supposed to feel good
about ourselves?
Excuse me, but what does this
have to do with my crack?!
Oh, don't you see, North,
if you lived here in Hawaii,
people would be
more inclined to settle here.
So they can be close to my CRACK?!
North, North... you're
very important to us.
I don't know.
I need some time to think, OK'?
One, two, three, fourjacks!
Come on, guys, don't just stand
there. Get your body in motion!
You might just like it.
And squat down, hup, and...
Now, what is the point'?
Gabby?! What are you doing here?
They say for every hour you exercise
you add an hour to your life.
Who needs all that extra time
if you're just gonna spend it exercising?
You see where I'm going
with this, Junior?
Who's Gabby?
He's a ranch hand from Texas.
Not familiar with the gentleman.
So, how's it feel
to be Hawaii's new first son?
Well, I'm not so sure
that's what I want to be.
Why not? Beautiful climate.
Can't beat the fashion.
Yeah, I know, but I don't think
I should settle for parents
who have to show
my most private crevice on a billboard
to make them feel better
about themselves!
It's refreshing to meet a kid
who has such strong convictions
about his crack.
( METAL DETECTOR BUZZES )
Whoa! Whoa!
(Sighs)
Dig, man -
the way I always figure this deal is,
it's the parents who are
supposed to make the kids feel better,
not the other way around.
Yeah.
Hang in there, kid.
You'll find what you're looking for.
I hope so.
Although he came up short
in both Texas and Hawaii,
North felt no anxiety,
as he still had eight weeks
till his Labor Day deadline.
PILOT: Welcome to Juneau, Alaska.
Please remain seated
until the plane comes to a
complete stop in Anchorage, Alaska.
To accompany our skid,
we will be showing you
another full-length feature film.
Our friend had a dream,
and that dream is becoming a reality.
Meanwhile, as North
was skidding his way to Anchorage,
things were heating up at home.
Winchell's inspirational speeches
had created a groundswell.
And all across the land,
kids were continuing to hold
their parents at emotional gunpoint.
Anything else, son?
Yes.
How's my room coming along?
I'll have it spotless by dinner.
Viva el Norte.
And as of next Monday,
no parent will be permitted to see
an R-rated movie
unless accompanied by a kid.
Yeah, right.
Arthur, do I detect a note of melancholy?
It's just that North
still hasn't found new parents.
Maybe he never will.
Maybe this free agency thing
will just blow up in our face!
I'm surprised at you, Arthur.
Do you think I would actually embark
on an endeavour of this magnitude
without a contingency plan?
Contingency plan?
Oh, good. I love those.
One Coca-Cola.
Right here.
And one Sex on the Beach.
Aren't I naughty?
To our future.
And what a future it is!
According to the latest polls,
parents are so nervous
that 78% of them say they will vote
however their kids tell them to.
And since those kids will do
whatever YOU tell them to...
well, I, ah...
(Chuckles) What I mean is...
That's right.
I'm lying here with the next
President of the United States.
(Laughs gleefully)
I'm happy for you, Arthur.
I'm sure you'll make a FINE
commander-in-chief.
Hey, dollface, could you
concentrate on my lower back?
It's where my tension builds up.
ANNOUNGER'. Flight 24 from Hawaii
by way of Juneau
is now arriving at Gate 7.
CONTROLLER'.
Pressure 119-91, 11 feet.
STEWARDESS: Bye-bye.
Hey, great landing, guys.
You really got that skid thing
down to a science.
Thanks for the kind words, North.
Not saying we haven't dented terminals
occasionally,
but after a while, you get the hang of it.
Thanks.
(All laugh)
North's first impression of Alaska
was a positive one.
The air was clean,
it was breathtakingly beautiful
and best of all, it was far away
from everyone and everything.
So there was nothing
to distract these people
from concentrating on
life's most precious commodity -
the love of a good family.
(Huskies bark)
(BUSY MUSIC)
Whoa, whoa!
Here you go, North -
a nice cup of hot cocoa.
And to go with that,
our State dish - Eskimo pie.
Thank you.
Well, hey, what do you know'?
The salmon are running.
I'm gonna get a couple of poles
and go fishing with my boy.
Great! I love fishing.
OK.
(FISHING POLES ENTER HOLE)
(Whistles merrily)
(Both whistle)
(Whistles)
(All whistle)
Ah, this is the life. Right, son?
Sure is.
Do you like Christmas, North'?
Who doesn't'?
You've never had a Christmas
till you've had an Alaskan Christmas.
Right - since our days
last for months at a time,
you can just imagine the festivities!
Why, opening the presents
takes three weeks alone, right, Ma'?
Oh, this all sounds great,
but what's the catch'?
Well, what do you mean?
I mean, what's in it for you?
Nothing-Really?
No dead kids? No low self-esteem?
No frozen skeletons in your closet?
(Both laugh)
We have pride, North.
And we're proud of our pride.
We wouldn't ask anything of a child.
We want you to follow your dreams
and be the best North you can be.
We know you'll be a source of great
pride to the entire Eskimo community
for many, many years to come.
(Chuckles)
Oh, jeepers creepers!
That reminds me.
Oh, Dad, let's go! Time to flow.
OLD MAN: Coming!
Time to what?!
OK, buckle up! It's a long walk.
Who's that'?
North, this is your new grandfather.
Hello, North.
Hello. What do you mean,
it's time to flow'?
Well, when an Eskimo gets too old
or weak to contribute to society,
the whole family gets together
and everybody walks to the ocean.
That's right.
Then the revered old Eskimo
is proudly placed on an ice floe
and sent out to sea,
so he can die, with dignity.
And pride.
Alright, everybody. Let's go.
But, wait a minute!
Just because he's old doesn't mean
he can't belong to the family.
Well, it's our tradition.
I promise you, North, Grandpa wants this
just as much as anyone.
Right, Grandpa?
Yeah, right. I... I've been
looking forward to this.
As the family
made their long trek to the sea,
North took the opportunity
to get close to his new grandpa,
which was easy since he had
a tremendous affection for old folks.
He found them to be warm,
understanding,
and most importantly,
way too tired to yell.
Knowing that his time with Grandpa
was limited, North tried to take in
all this wise old man had to offer
about life in the tundra.
And another thing.
Up here, if your mother says,
“Don't make a face because it could
freeze in that position",
you better take her seriously.
Jeez. Can't you
hang around a little longer?
There's so much you can teach me.
( BUZZ! )
Next!
ALL: Goodbye.
Yeah, yeah. OK, OK, OK.
Goodbye, goodbye. C'mon, let's go.
Only got four months of sunlight here.
Move it!
Next! Come on, let's go.
(Presses buzzer) Come on! Come on!
Should've done this before.
I got a civilisation to run here.
Can you move it along, please?
Thank you.
(Presses buzzer) Next! Let's go.
Don't act like you don't know
what's going on.
Well, goodbye, North.
Are you sure you have to go?
Oh, don't worry about him, North.
He's had a great life,
and he's happy to set sail...
before he starts
embarrassing himself.
Take it from us, North - when drool
hardens, it's not a pretty sight.
"But...
“But, but, but..." Come on!
Let's go, pal. You know
where you're going. Take a walk.
Come on, move it along. Let's go!
Yeah, bye-bye-bye. Fine. Thank you.
Goodbye, Dad!
BYE, Dad!
(Sadw) 'Bye.
Listen, if there's a change in policy
in the next couple of weeks,
feel free to track me down.
What did he say?
Hey!
What do you say we grab a ride home?
That's a great idea!
(ATMOSPHERIC MUSIC)
Oh, North. Don't worry about Grandpa.
He'll be OK.
Yeah.
Can I ride on top?
Why, sure. It's the best view.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Landscape sure is beautiful up here.
Hey! It's you.
No, it's not.
Oh.
(Breathes in and out)
Smell that fresh air.
No smog up here.
How could they do that'?
Not even my original parents
would send my grandpa away like that.
Hey, son! How's the view up there?
Great. Thanks.
(Softly) 'Son'.
You know, I don't want
to overstep my bounds,
but unless I'm mistaken,
you're that fella North.
And unless I'm further mistaken,
you have a deadline of Labor Day,
which is a week from tomorrow,
to choose new parents.
And unless I'm mistaken even further,
you still haven't found
what you're looking for.
How could Labor Day be next week'?
I just got here!
You walked from your house to
the ice floes, right? Yeah.
A seven-week walk,
even with the wind behind you.
No wonder
we stopped for lunch 49 times!
Ah, don't feel bad.
It's that six months of daylight thing.
It throws everybody off.
I myself only showered 12 times
during the '70s.
Oh, man. I'll never find new parents.
Unless I misinterpret the ruling,
you can always go back
to your original parents.
Oh, yeah.
That's just what I want to do.
Return to the people who haven't even
tried to contact me in over 8 weeks!
Take me to the airport!
There's lots to do and not much time.
You got it. Hyah!
So a now desperate North,
with time running out,
raced towards an uncertain future.
Understandably, he was upset his parents
hadn't called in two months.
What he couldn't know, however,
was his parents hadn't
done much of anything in two months.
As curator
of the Smithsonian Institution,
it is my distinct honor
to unveil the newest addition
to our illustrious
Hall of Achievement.
At 78 consecutive days and counting,
the longest simultaneous coma
in medical history -
ladies and gentlemen, North's folks.
(All murmur)
I'll now take questions.
Yes.
How can you equate a medical oddity
with man's landing on the moon?
With all due respect to the
achievements of the 'Apollo 11' crew,
the sociological impact
of what these folks did
dwarfs those of Mr Armstrong et al.
But all they did was faint.
And, in so doing,
shifted the familial bounds of power
throughout the world.
“Throughout the world"? This thing
is getting bigger than we thought.
Bigger than YOU thought. That's why
you're only gonna be President.
Continuing process of new status...
Wait. I just thought of something.
What if they awaken
in the next eight days,
begging and pleading
for North to come back?
Oh, my God!
What if North goes back to his FOLKS?!
Arthur. Don't you know
that that's an impossibility?
That I would use all of my power
to prevent a thing like that
from happening?
Oh. OK.
What do you say
we grab some Chinese?
Maybe the MSG will calm you down.
Despite North's concern
about his approaching deadline,
he did take solace in the fact
that the Lord needed only six days
to create the entire universe.
Certainly a kid of his calibre,
given two extra days,
should be able to find
two measly parents.
Greetings, North.
I'm thy new father.
And this good woman,
who art my wife,
art thy new mother.
And these art thy new brothers
who art named Ezekiel.
who art named Art.
Hey! Hey, this looks great!
I have always dreamt of a life
without the ever-present nuisance
of electricity.
Uh... uh... just let me grab something
from the plane.
I seem to have left my butter churn
in the overhead compartment. (Laughs)
(Yells) FLOOR IT!
While it was not
like North to make snap judgments,
there were only seven days left.
He had a world full of potential
parents to evaluate.
(GONG CLASHES LOUDLY)
(People chant obediently)
MAN: Long live the North Dynasty!
(People respond)
Give him the emperor cut!
(GONG RESOUNDS)
(AFRICAN TRIBAL MUSIC)
( MAN YELLS LIKE TARZAN )
(Speaks tribal language)
You seem like very nice folks.
But to be totally honest with you,
if I lived here, I'm not sure
I'd get much homework done.
(CANCAN MUSIC
PLAYS BRIGHTLY)
(Man and woman laugh)
(Dogs bark wildly)
(Laughs) (Laughs)
Quiet, Harry! Quiet.
I think he's trying
to tell us something.
(Mumbles and grunts
unintelligibly)
(Sings)
♪ Whack, whack, whack-a-doo! ♪
(Laughs like rooster)
(Man grunts like horse)
(Woman hums)
WOMAN: Oh, my Catholic God!
With three days to go before
his 12:00 noon Labor Day deadline,
North, the little world traveller,
arrived in New York today
to interview his final set of parents -
Ward and Donna Nelson,
who, along with their two children
Bud and Laura,
live in the quaint upstate town
of Bedford.
When contacted earlier at his office,
Ward, the local paediatrician -
who, we understand,
still makes house calls, said,
“My family and I
would like nothing better
“than to see North's long journey
finally be rewarded
“with a warm and loving home,
“and we hope
we can provide it for him.”
(UPLIFTING MUSIC)
Thanks.
Hi, North! Ward! Bud! Laura! He's here.
He's here! (Chuckles)
Hi, North.
Hi!
Hello.
Welcome to our home, son.
Come on in.
Are you tired? Hungry?
Mum made chocolate-chip cookies.
Do you like Nintendo?
Yeah.
REPORTER'. Today at Mount Rushmore
thousands of angry parents gathered
to voice their opposition
to the bill that would lower
the voting age to seven.
According to Arthur Belt, the rising
politician who drafted the bill...
Oh, wait.
They were talking about me.
Relax, Arthur.
Soon you'll hear your name so much,
even you'll be sick of it.
I highly doubt it.
(PHONE RINGS)
Talk to me.
It's Al with the sleeping dogs.
Yeah? What about 'em'?
Looks like they counted
their last sheep.
So it does.
How long will it take
to get Operation Xerox into place?
Less than a minute, boss.
Go to it. Al'?
Yeah, boss'?
Don't be surprised if there's
extra zeros in your next pay.
Thanks, boss. I appreciate it.
And Al'?
Yeah, boss?
Don't be surprised if there isn't.
I understand.
(Both yawn and groan)
Good morning!
Where are we'?
Oh! Where's our son?
Oh. Can we see our son?
Absolutely. Just follow me.
We've got a limo waiting
with coffee and some nice, hot Danish.
Oh, that sounds good.
I seem to have worked up an appetite.
Honey'?
I could eat.
Right this way.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Hike!
OK, Laura, sack the quarterback.
Come here! Hey!
Oh!
BUD: Touchdown! Yeah!
You faked me out of my socks, North.
Come and get it!
Oh, here we go.
It's great having you here.
I've always wanted a brother.
Now I have two big brothers!
I know we're excited
to have North as part of our family,
but he hasn't decided
if he wants to stay with us.
North, you've got to stay.
Yeah.
DONNA: Help yourself, everybody. Dig in.
Mum, can we go
to the carnival tomorrow'?
Yeah! Can we'?
I don't see why not.
Ward?
Sounds good to me.
North...
we miss you so much.
Please forgive us.
We made... so many mistakes.
We... we should have appreciated you
more.
If only you could give us
just one more chance.
We love you, son.
We love you very much.
(Sobs)
CUT!
Very nice! Very, very nice!
Touching! Moving!
And yet not over-the-top!
(Whispers) Keep it rolling.
So... crazy summer, huh?
Oh, terrible.
Very disturbing.
Look. I know what you're going through.
But even if North doesn't come back,
you can always adopt!
Just the other day I met this adorable
little boy, seven years old.
His name was Hugh.
Maybe you can adopt him.
Maybe Hugh can be your son.
We don't want Hugh.
He's NOT our son.
We want North.
I understand. It was insensitive
of me to even bring it up.
Uh... you folks want some more coffee?
Nah..that's OK.
Not for me.
I still don't understand why we can't
speak to North in person.
L...l think that would be a big mistake.
North is very angry right now.
He's very sensitive.
You show up unannounced -
this thing could blow up in your face!
It would kill me to see that happen.
So my suggestion is
you lay low for a while.
You'll be escorted to the plaza.
I told Jean-Pierre to give you
all the room service you want.
And, as North's best friend,
I'd be happy to show them this tape
to pave the way for you.
Oh!
Thank you, Winchell.
Oh, yes.
You're a real friend.
I do what I can.
Bring the car for North's folks.
Yes, sir. Consider it done.
You know... you're doing very well
for a sixth-grader.
Yeah... l got a few breaks.
How...'? I was wo...'?
Adam, take the tape down to editing.
(Sighs)
LAURA: Colonel Mustard...
WARD: Yeah?
In the study with the rope?
I don't have any of those.
Neither do I.
BUD AND NORTH: Me either.
Let's see.
Colonel Mustard... in the study...
and here's the rope!
OTHERS: Alright!
WARD: Good job, kitten!
LAURA: Can we play again?
No, it's bedtime. Tomorrow's a big day.
You don't want to be tired
for the carnival.
Mum's right. It's bedtime right now.
OK.
Goodnight, Mum
Goodnight, honey.
Goodnight, North.
Goodnight, Mum. Goodnight, Dad.
Brush your teeth before you go to bed.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Sorry to bother you so late. I've
got something for a kid named North.
What is it?
An urgent message
from his original parents.
I'll see that he gets it.
Thank you.
North, honey'?
Yeah?
Can you come here for a minute?
Coming!
What is it'?
North, a man left this tape for you.
He says it's a message
from your parents.
From my parents?
Do you mind if I...'?
Of course not.
Would you like to be alone, North'?
No, that's OK.
WOMAN ON VIDEO:
After what you've been through,
what would you like to tell your son?
We don't want you.
How can you say that? He's your son.
He's not our son.
Aren't you bothered by the prospect
of never seeing your son again?
Nah. That's OK.
Isn't this a gut-wrenching,
torturous emotional experience?
Not for me.
He's not our son.
We don't want you.
(MELANCHOLY MUSIC)
North, honey, are you OK'?
Is there anything we can do for you?
Yeah. Let me be your son.
Finally North had new parents.
Parents who made him feel wanted,
secure and loved.
Yet something was still wrong.
The Nelsons
were everything he was looking for,
so why couldn't he embrace them?
North needed answers.
(TRAIN HORN BLOWS)
North, we just don't understand
why you're leaving.
Neither do I.
You're all nice people.
I'm really gonna miss you.
But I've just got to be alone.
We're going to miss you too.
And so will Oliver.
North'? Here.
In case you get hungry on your way
to New York.
Thanks, Mom.
I mean, Mrs Nelson.
'Bye.
(MELANCHOLY MUSIC)
So, with just 24 hours
until his Labor Day deadline,
no hope of parents and the prospect
of living in an orphanage looming,
North felt he only had
one option left.
He would disappear.
Can you spare some extra change?
Oh!
Here. Maybe it will bring you
more luck than it brought me.
Hey! It's got a hole in it!
What good does this do me?
Yes, he would disappear.
And where better to do that
than amidst the teeming,
faceless masses of the naked city?
(SEEDY MUSIC)
(STREET NOISES,
PEOPLE SHOUT)
Shut up!
I can arrest you both.
He's heading into the park.
Don't worry, boss.
I'm just looking for
the right time and place.
So long, Al.
What was that all about?
Well, it seems that our young friend
has had a change of heart.
Change of heart'?
He's left the Nelsons
and decided to grace our fair city
with his presence.
Oh, no!
Well, this ruins everything.
Arthur, please. Use your head.
This is a godsend.
It is'?
Of course.
As we speak,
grown-ups across this great land of ours
are feeling humiliated.
They blame North for all
their frustrations.
Do you realise how many
of those angry parents
would like nothing better than to do away
with our little friend?
And do you know the one catalyst
that can give a political movement
true cohesion?
That's right. A martyr.
You're a genius! I mean, it's brilliant.
It's absolutely Winchellian. It...
But for North to be a martyr,
doesn't he have to be killed
by an angry parent'?
Well, maybe we'll get lucky.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(GUNSHOT)
As North ran for his life
he couldn't help wondering
how a dream of finding the perfect
parents had become a nightmare.
(GUNSHOTS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(Gasps for breath)
(CAROUSEL MUSIC)
(GUNSHOT)
Ah! Ah!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(CAROUSEL MUSIC)
Damn it!
(FOREBODING MUSIC)
(MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
Psst! North, over here.
Adam! What are you doing here?
Listen to me very carefully.
I'm not here. You never saw me.
We're not even having this
conversation right now.
Got that'?
Got what?
Perfect.
So, what are we not talking about?
This.
What?
I don't see anything.
Exactly.
What you don't see is a tape
of the conversation
Winchell had with your parents.
I saw it.
No, you didn't.
Oh, I forgot. I didn't see it.
You did see it. This is what
you didn't see when you saw it.
I see.
I don't think you do.
Look at the tape.
So, how did you find me?
Winchell.
He bugged the Nelsons' phones.
Winchell!
Shh!
(Whispers) He's everywhere.
I've been working for him since you left.
You know, some guy
was chasing me with a gun.
He was shooting at me.
That didn't have
anything to do with Winchell, did it?
(Whistles)
Oh, man! So, why are you doing this?
I'm not, but if I was, it's because
I think Winchell's gone too far.
Also, you were always
good to me, North.
You never picked me last.
You never made me play right field.
I'll never forget that.
Thanks, Adam.
(SIREN WAILS)
Oh, man. Adam, I just
don't feel safe anywhere.
Adam? Adam?
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC)
Could I have a hot dog with just mustard?
That'll be $1.
Out of five. 2-3-4-5.
There you go.
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC)
Where did you get this?
Some bum bought a hot dog
about an hour ago. Why?
No reason.
(Together) Aah!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(HONKS HORN)
(HONKS HORN RAPIDLY)
(GUNSHOT) Aagh!
(TAXI I '(RES SKID)
Won't see him no more.
Watch, watch, watch there, you!
Excuse me...
Move it, kid!
C'mon, move it!
(LAUGHTER AND APPLAUSE)
Which reminds me of this man
who walked into a bar -
he sits down next to
a very beautiful young lady...
Before you know it,
the conversation turns to sex.
"He says to her, “My darling,
do you smoke after you make love?"
She says,
“I don't know. I never looked.
"“But I'll tell you one thing -
my smoke alarm never went off!"
( LAUGHTER)
Goodnight, folks, you've been great!
Thank you.
(UPBEAT JAZZ MUSIC PLAYS)
You the kid with the tape?
Y-yeah.
Good. Come in.
I wanna try my new VCR.
How did you know'?
What's that, kid?
I just came to you
'cause I thought you looked familiar.
Of course - I'm almost famous.
Joey Fingers. Nice to see you.
And you are?
I'm North.
Always been
one of my favourite directions.
Mallomar?
No, thanks.
That bad, huh'?
What'?
No kid ever refuses a mallomar
unless he's wrestling with
some pretty heavyweight problems.
(Switches on TV)
North - we miss you so much.
Please forgive us.
We made so many mistakes.
We should've appreciated you more.
If only you could give us
just one more chance.
We love you, son!
We love you very much.
Beautiful! Works like a charm.
Got some pretty nice folks there, kid.
Huh?
I said you got
some pretty nice folks there.
Yeah. I guess so.
What do you mean, you guess so'?
Well, I mean...
And what do they mean
by give us one more chance?
I thought they didn't love me.
What are you, nuts?
That's just the thing - they didn't
always pay that much attention to me.
So, I left them, to find some
new folks who'd appreciate me more.
I searched the whole world,
but nobody was good enough.
Not even the Nelsons, who I just left.
And they weren't bad folks.
Maybe there's something wrong with me.
Ah, there's nothing wrong with you.
And I'm sure the Nelsons
weren't bad folks.
They just weren't your folks.
You see those people out there?
That audience?
They paid attention to me.
They listened to every word I said.
They laughed, they screamed,
they applauded. They loved me.
But do you think that audience
is gonna make me a cup of tea
if I'm not feeling well?
Are they gonna help me when I get
in a fight with my best friend?
Or - God forbid - I get in girl trouble.
Who am I going to turn to?
I'll give you a hint -
it's not that audience.
Oh, my God. What have I done?
I'll tell you.
You've realised something that takes
most people a lifetime to figure out.
Some people
never figure it out at all -
that a bird in the hand is always greener
than the grass
under the other guy's bushes.
L...it's a metaphor
used mostly by gardeners
and landscape people in general.
Hey, kid...
Hey, kid. Where are you going'?
Home. I miss my parents.
How are you going to get to the airport'?
You got a car?
No - I'm 11.
Alright, then - we'd better take mine.
(PLANE RUMBLES OVERHEAD)
Thanks for everything, Mr Fingers.
Make it Joey. And you're welcome.
And remember, kid - if you can't
stand the heat, stay out of Miami.
What does that metaphor mean?
What metaphor?
You ever been down there in August?
Your balls stick to your leg
like crazy glue. Goodbye.
And so,
North finally found the parents
he'd always been looking for.
Much to his surprise,
they were his own.
With a song in his heart
and a smile on his face,
North prepared
to board the final plane
bound for the loving arms
of those very parents.
Where do you think you're going?
I'm going home!
Not on this plane, you're not.
Why not?
It says here you're dead.
But... I'm not!
How can I be sure?
I'm standing here talking to you.
I know, and that scares me.
Since I don't scare easily,
you can imagine how it will affect
the other passengers.
But I'm not dead!
Sorry, I can't take that chance.
Hey, it's North - he's alive!
What's he doing here?
This plane's headed to his hometown.
He's trying to return to his parents.
It'll ruin everything. Let's get him!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(Kids yell angrily)
Stop him!
Hey, kid - hop in!
What are you -
some kind of guardian angel?
Well, I guess you can say that.
'Cause in a manner of speaking,
we at Federal Express feel
that we are guardians.
Guardians of important packages
and priority communiques.
(Wearily) Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Just get me home, will ya'?
Well, if you absolutely, positively
have to be home by tomorrow morning,
you've come to the right truck.
(Honks horn)
Man, you don't let off
for a second, do ya'?
I have no idea what you're talking about.
(Mimics Joey) “I have no idea
what you're talking about.”
Just tell me what to do, OK'?
Get in.
Federal Express, huh? OK, thanks.
Oh, Al... Can I have a word with you?
Oh, sure, boss.
Remember when you told me
North was dead?
Yeah.
Uh, just curious -
what did you base that on?
I can only assume
that you think this is blood, Al.
And if I had an IQ below 24,
I suppose I might think the same.
But the stain in this cap
comes from borscht.
Borscht'?
Yes, borscht.
A beef-based soup, Russian in origin,
most frequently served chilled
with a dollop of sour cream.
I make a good borscht.
And I'd love to sample it someday.
The point I'm making here, Al,
is that unless North's head
was filled with
this traditional Slavic delicacy,
HE'S NOT DEAD, YOU IDIOT!
Oh, no! There's been...
Not now, Arthur.
Alright, alright. This just calls
for a slight change in plans.
I'll take it from here.
Alright.
Sign on the fourth line.
What time is it?
Normally, my answer would be
no later than 10:30,
but thanks to that jackknifed truck
on the highway,
I'm sorry to say it's almost 10 off 12.
We'll... we'll be happy
to refund your, er...
No, that's OK.
Mom! Dad! I'm home!
Mom!
Where are you guys?
Mom? Dad'?
Mom?
(DRAMATIC MUSIC) Mom?
Hello, North - happy Labor Day.
I trust your summer
was an enjoyable one.
Where are my folks?
Oh, they're in a safe place.
Where the hell are my parents?
North - did you say the word hell?
My, the summer's really broadened you.
Winchell, I've got exactly
10 minutes to find my parents.
If you don't tell me where they are,
I'll show you how much this summer's
broadened me, you little asshole!
Why are you smiling?
I was just thinking
what a beautiful,
heartwarming scene it'll be
when you're reunited with your parents
at that secret spot of yours.
How do you know about my secret spot'?
I'm a journalist, North. It's my job
to know about these things.
And as much as I'm enjoying
this little chat,
shouldn't you be on your way?
After all, you're down to...
nine minutes.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC RESUMES)
Where is he?
Winchell said he'd be here by now.
Don't worry - I'm sure he'll be here soon.
Soon may not be good enough!
Let me remind you.
I've been sent here by the court
to ensure that your son
is physically in your arms by noon.
How much time is left?
Six minutes.
And that's my own clock,
from my own house.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC RESUMES)
Ugh!
Maybe we should go look for him?
Honey, honey...
What if we leave here
and North shows up and we miss him?
Relax, honey.
Winchell's a man of his word.
Ugh!
He has less than one minute!
Right - you wait here.
I'll go look for him.
Good idea.
Bad idea.
A reminder - the ruling stipulates
North must be
in the arms of both parents.
That's two parents, four arms.
If you leave,
we're down to one parent, two arms.
The math speaks for itself.
MOM! DAD!
BOTH: North!
(CLOCK TICKS)
( HEARTBEATS )
(Gasps)
Hey... You still here?
Yeah... I must've fallen asleep.
C'mon. I'll give you a ride home.
And then you were a beach bum,
and then you drove a sleigh
and then you were a comedian
who said my parents
were the best parents for me.
(Chuckles) I said that'?
Yeah.
I must be a pretty smart guy.
What's that'?
Oh, nothin'.
Just something I've always had.
You know - for good luck.
Yeah, well, maybe good luck for you...
I bet that eagle's whistlin'
a different tune.
Here we go - 35 Maple Drive.
(SOOTHING MUSIC)
Thanks a lot, mister.
Don't mention it, kid.
And remember - be it ever so humble,
there's no place like home.
With the possible exception of Vegas
when Sinatra's in town.
'Bye.
North!
North?
Mom! Dad!
Where were you?
We were worried sick!
I fell asleep in the mall.
Uh...
We called the hospitals,
we called the police...
Uh, we looked everywhere.
You did?
'Course we did.
We love you so much, North.
If anything ever happened to you,
I don't know what we'd do. (Kisses)
I love you guys too.
C' mun .
You hungry, honey'?
A little bit.
A little bit'? A little bit!
OK, a lot.
OK.
I'll tell you what - you run
upstairs, put on your pyjamas,
we'll bring something up
and tuck you in.
OK.