"Sing no more ditties,"
More!
"Sing no more,
Of dumps so dull and heavy,
The fraud of men was ever so,
Since summer. . .
first was leafy.
Then sigh not so,
But let them go,
And be you blithe. . .
and bonny,
Converting all . . .
your sounds of woe,
Into Hey. . .
nonny, nonny !''
My lord.
I learn in this letter. . .
that Don Pedro of Aragon. . .
comes this night to Messina !
He is very near by this.
He was not three leagues off
when l left him.
How many gentlemen
have you lost in this action ?
But few of any sort, and none of name.
I find here that Don Pedro
hath bestowed much honor. . .
on a young Florentine
called Claudio.
He hath borne himself. . .
beyond the promise of his age,
doing in the figure of a lamb,
the feats of a lion !
Is Signior Mountanto
returned from the wars or no ?
I know not that name, lady.
My cousin means
Signior Benedick of Padua.
O, he's returned;
and as pleasant as ever he was.
I pray you, how many hath he
killed and eaten in these wars ?
But how many hath he killed ?
For indeed l promised to eat
all of his killing.
He hath done good service.
And a good soldier too, lady.
And a good soldier to a lady.
But what is he to a lord ?
A lord to a lord, a man to a man;
stuffed with all honorable virtues.
It is so, indeed:
he is no less than a stuffed man.
You must not, sir,
mistake my niece.
There is a kind of merry war
betwixt Signior Benedick and her:
they never meet but there's a skirmish
of wit between them.
Who is his companion now ?
He hath every month
a new sworn brother.
He is most in the company
of the right noble Claudio.
Oh, Lord !
He will hang upon him like a disease.
He is sooner caught than the pestilence,
and the taker runs presently mad !
God help the noble Claudio !
If he have caught the Benedick,
it will cost him a thousand pounds
ere a' be cured.
I will keep friends with you, lady.
Do, good friend.
You will never run mad, niece.
No, not till a hot January.
Don Pedro is approaching !
Good Signior Leonato,
are you come to meet your trouble ?
The fashion of the world
is to avoid cost, and you encounter it.
Never came trouble to my house
in the likeness of Your Grace.
My lord.
I think this is your daughter.
Her mother hath many times
told me so.
Were you in doubt, sir,
that you asked her ?
Signior Benedick, no !
If Signior Leonato be her father, she would not
have his head on her shoulders. . .
for all Messina,
as like him as she is.
I wonder that you will still
be talking, Signior Benedick. Nobody marks you.
What, my dear Lady Disdain !
Are you yet living ?
Is it possible Disdain should die. . .
while she hath such meet food
to feed it as Signior Benedick ?
Courtesy itself must convert to Disdain
if you come in her presence.
Then is Courtesy a turncoat.
But it is certain l am loved of all ladies,
only you excepted;
and l would l could find in my heart that l had not
a hard heart; for truly, l love none.
A dear happiness to women: they would
else have been troubled with a pernicious suitor.
I thank God and my cold blood,
l am of your humour for that.
I had rather hear my dog
bark at a crow. . .
than a man swear he loves me.
God keep your ladyship in that mind . . .
so some gentlemen or other shall 'scape
a pre-destinate scratched face.
Scratching could not make it worse
an 't such a face as yours were.
Well, you are a rare parrot teacher.
A bird of my tongue
is better than a beast of yours.
I would my horse had the speed
of your tongue ! But. . .
keep you away, i' God 's name.
I have done.
You always end with a jade's trick.
I know you of old.
Signior Claudio and Signior Benedick,
my dear friend Leonato
hath invited you all.
I tell him we shall stay here at the least a month.
Let me bid you welcome, my lord:
being reconciled to the prince
your brother,
I owe you all duty.
I thank you.
I am not of many words,
but l thank you.
Please it Your Grace lead on ?
Your hand, Leonato;
we will go together.
Benedick,
didst thou note the daughter
of Signior Leonato ?
I noted her not,
but l looked on her.
Is she not a modest young lady ?
Do you question me for my simple,
true judgment ?
Or would you have me speak after
my custom, as a tyrant to their sex ?
No; I pray thee, speak
in sober judgment.
Why, i' faith, methinks
she's too low for a high praise,
too brown for a fair praise,
and too little for a great praise.
Only this commendation
l can afford her,
That were she other than she is,
she were unhandsome;
and being no other than as she is,
l do not like her.
Thou thinkest l am in sport.
I pray thee tell me truly how thou likest her.
Would you buy her
that you inquire after her ?
Can the world buy such a jewel ?
Yea, and a case to put it into.
But speak you this
with a sad brow ?
In mine eye she is the sweetest lady
that ever l looked on.
I can see yet without spectacles
and l see no such matter.
There's her cousin,
and she were not possessed
with a Fury, exceeds her. . .
as much in beauty as the first of May
doth the last of December.
But l hope you have no intent
to turn husband, have you ?
I would scarce trust myself,
though l had sworn the contrary,
if Hero would be my wife.
Is't come to this ? Shall l never see
a bachelor of threescore again ?
Gentlemen,
what secret hath held you here
that you followed not to Leonato's ?
He is "in love".
'With who ?'
That is Your Grace's part.
With Hero, Leonato's short daughter.
Amen if you love her;
for the lady is very well worthy.
You speak this to fetch me in, my lord.
By my troth,
l speak my thought.
And in faith, my lord,
l spoke mine.
And, by my two faiths and troths,
my lord, l spoke mine.
- That l love her, l feel.
- That she is worthy, l know.
That l neither feel how she should be loved
nor know how she should be worthy,
is the opinion that fire cannot melt
out of me.
I will die in it at the stake.
Thou wast ever an obstinate heretic
in the despite of beauty.
That a woman conceived me,
l thank her;
that she brought me up,
l likewise give her most humble thanks.
But that l will hang my bugle
in an invisible baldric,
all women shall pardon me.
I will live a bachelor.
I shall see thee, ere l die,
look pale with love.
With anger, with sickness or with hunger,
my lord. Not with love.
Well, as time shall try !
"In time the savage bull
doth bear the yoke."
The savage bull may;
but if ever the sensible Benedick bear it,
pluck off the bull's horns
and set them in my forehead !
And let me be vilely painted
and in such great letters as they write !
''Here is good horse to hire."
Let them signify under my sign "here you may
see Benedick the married man.''
Benedick, repair to Leonato's:
tell him l will not fail him at supper;
for indeed he hath made great preparation.
Examine your conscience.
And so l leave you.
Hath Leonato any son, my lord ?
No child but Hero,
she's his only heir.
Dost thou affect her, Claudio ?
O, my lord, when you went onward
on this ended action,
I looked upon her with a soldier's eye,
that liked,
but had a rougher task in hand than to drive
liking to the name of love.
But now. . .
I am returned and that war thoughts
have left their places vacant,
in their rooms come thronging soft. . .
and delicate desires,
all prompting me
how fair young Hero is.
Saying. . .
I liked her ere l went to wars.
Thou wilt be like a lover presently and
tire the hearer with a book of words.
If thou dost love fair Hero,
cherish it,
and I will break with her and with
her father and thou shalt have her.
I know we shall have revelling tonight.
I will assume thy part in some disguise
and tell fair Hero l am Claudio,
and in her bosom
l 'll unclasp my heart. . .
and take her hearing prisoner with the
force and strong encounter of my amorous tale;
then after to her father
will l break;
and the conclusion is,
she shall be thine !
In practise let us put it presently.
What the good year, my lord ?
Why are you thus out of measure sad ?
There is no measure
in the occasion that breeds;
therefore the sadness is without limit.
You should hear reason.
And when I have heard it,
what blessing brings it ?
I cannot hide what l am.
I must be sad when l have cause
and smile at no man's jests;
eat when l have stomach
and wait for no man's leisure;
sleep when l am drowsy
and tend on no man's business;
Iaugh when l am merry. . .
and claw no man in his humor.
Yea, but you must not
make the full show of this. . .
till you may do so
without controlment.
You have of late stood out
against your brother,
and he hath ta'en you newly
into his grace,
where it is impossible
you should take true root. . .
but by the fair weather
that you make yourself.
I had rather be a canker
in a hedge. . .
than a rose in his grace.
In this, though l cannot be said
to be a flattering honest man,
it must not be denied
but l am a plain-dealing villain !
If l had my mouth,
I would bite;
if l had my liberty,
l would do my liking.
In the meantime
let me be that l am . . .
and seek not to alter me.
Borachio, what news ?
I can give you intelligence
of an intended marriage.
Will it serve for any model
to build mischief on ?
Marry, it is
your brother's right hand.
The most exquisite Claudio ?
- Even he.
- How came you to this ?
I heard it agreed upon. . .
that the prince
should woo Hero for himself,
and having obtained her,
give her to Count Claudio.
Come, come, let us thither.
This may prove food to my displeasure.
That young start-up
hath all the glory of my overthrow.
If l can cross him any way,
I bless myself every way.
You are both sure,
and will assist me ?
To the death, my lord.
Shall we go prove
what's to be done ?
We'll wait upon your lordship.
- Was not Count John here at supper ?
- I saw him not.
How tartly that gentleman looks ! I never can see
him but l am heart-burned an hour after.
He is of a very melancholy disposition.
He were an excellent man. . .
that were made just in the midway
between him and Benedick.
The one is too like an image
and says nothing,
and the other too like my lady's
eldest son, evermore tattling.
Then half Signior Benedick's tongue. . .
in Count John's mouth,
and half Count John's melancholy
in Signior Benedick's face.
With a good leg. . .
and a good foot, Uncle,
and money enough in his purse,
such a man would win any woman in the
world if he could get her goodwill.
By my troth, niece,
thou wilt never get thee a husband,
if thou be so shrewd of thy tongue.
Lord, l could not endure a husband with
a beard on his face. I had rather lie in the woollen.
You may light on a husband
that hath no beard.
What should l do with him ?
Dress him in my apparel
and make him my waiting-gentlewoman ?
He that hath a beard
is more than a youth,
and he that hath no beard
is less than a man.
And he that is more than a youth
is not for me,
and he that is less than a man,
I am not for him.
In faith, she's too curst.
Well, then, go you into hell ?
No, but to the gate;
and there will the devil meet me
like an old cuckold . . .
with horns on his head,
and saying. . .
''Get you to heaven, Beatrice, get you to heaven;
here's no place for you maids.''
So, away to Saint Peter for the heavens;
he shows me where the bachelors sit,
and there live we
as merry as the day is long.
Well, niece. l hope you will
be ruled by your father.
Yes, faith; it is my cousin's duty
to make curtsy and say,
''Father, as it please you,''
but yet for all that, cousin,
Iet him be a handsome fellow.
Or else make another curtsy and say,
''Father, as it please me.''
Daughter, remember what l told you:
if the prince do solicit you
in that kind,
you know your answer.
Well, niece. l hope to see you
one day fitted with a husband.
Not till God make men. . .
of some other metal than earth.
Cousin, you apprehend passing shrewdly.
I have a good eye, Uncle;
I can see a church by daylight.
The revellers are entering !
Lady, will you walk about
with your friend ?
I know you well enough;
you are Signior Antonio.
At a word, l am not.
I know you by the waggling
of your head.
- At a word, l am not !
- Come, come,
do you think l do not know you
by your excellent wit ?
Can virtue hide itself ?
Go to, mum, you are he:
graces will appear,
and there's an end.
...Well, l would you did like me.
So would not l,
for l have many ill qualities.
- Which is one ?
- I say my prayers aloud.
Will you not tell me who told you so ?
No, you shall pardon me.
- Nor will you not tell me who you are ?
- Not now.
That l was disdainful,
and that l had my good wit
out of the ''Hundred Merry Tales''
well, this was Signior Benedick that said so.
What's he ?
I 'm sure you know him well enough.
Not l, believe me.
- Did he never make you laugh ?
- I pray you. . .
what is he ?
Why, he is the prince's jester.
A very dull fool.
His only gift is in devising
impossible slanders.
None but libertines delight in him;
for he both pleases men and angers them,
and then they laugh at him
and beat him.
I am sure he is in the fleet.
I would he had boarded me.
When l know the gentleman,
l 'll tell him what you say.
Do,
Do.
- We must follow the leaders.
- In every good thing.
Are not you Signior Benedick ?
You know me well, I am he.
Signior, you are very near my brother
in his love:
he is enamored on Hero.
I pray you dissuade him from her:
she is no equal for his birth.
How know you he loves her ?
I heard him swear his affection.
So did l too; and he swore
he would marry her tonight.
Come, let us to the banquet.
Thus answer l in the name of Benedick,
but hear these ill news
with the ears of Claudio.
'Tis certain so:
the prince woos for himself !
Friendship is constant
in all other things. . .
save in the office and affairs
of love.
This is an accident of hourly proof,
which l mistrusted not.
Farewell, therefore, Hero !
Count Claudio ?
- Yea, the same.
- Come, will you go with me ?
- Whither ?
- About your own business.
The prince hath got your Hero !
I wish him joy of her !
Did you think that the prince
would have served you thus ?
I pray you, leave me !
Alas, poor hurt fowl.
But that my Lady Beatrice
should know me, and not know me !
The prince's fool ! Ha ?
I am not so reputed.
It is the base, though bitter, disposition
of Beatrice. . .
that puts the world into her person,
and so gives me out.
Well, l 'll be revenged as l may.
- Now, signior, where's the count ?
- Troth, my lord, l found him here. . .
as melancholy as a lodge in a warren.
I told him,
and l think l told him true,
that Your Grace had got the good will
of this young lady.
The Lady Beatrice
hath a quarrel to you.
The gentleman that danced with her
told her she is much wronged by you.
O, she misused me
past the endurance of a block !
She told me,
not thinking l had been myself,
that l was the prince's jester,
that l was duller than a great thaw,
huddling jest upon jest with such
impossible conveyance upon me. . .
that l stood like a man at a mark,
with a whole army shooting at me.
She speaks poniards,
and every word stabs.
If her breath were as terrible as her
terminations, there were no living near her;
she would infect to the North Star !
So, indeed, all disquiet,
horror, and perturbation follows her.
Look, here she comes.
Will Your Grace command me
any service to the world 's end ?
I will go on the slightest errand . . .
now to the Antipodes. . .
that you can devise to send me on.
I will fetch you a hair
off the Great Cham's beard,
do you any embassage to the Pigmies,
rather than hold three words' conference
with this harpy.
You have no employment for me ?
None, but to desire your good company !
O, God, sir,
here's a dish l love not.
I cannot endure my Lady Tongue !
Come, lady, come; you have lost the heart
of Signior Benedick.
Indeed, my lord,
he lent it me a while,
and l gave him use for it,
a double heart for his single one.
Marry, once before he won it of me,
with false dice,
therefore Your Grace may well say
l have lost it.
You have put him down, lady, you have put him down.
So l would not he should do me,
my lord,
Iest l should prove the mother of fools.
I have brought Count Claudio,
whom you sent me to seek.
Why, how now, Count,
wherefore are you sad ?
- Not sad, my lord.
- How then ? Sick ?
- Neither, my lord.
- The count is neither sad, nor sick,
nor merry, nor well,
but civil count,
civil as an orange,
and something of that jealous complexion.
In faith, lady, l think your blazon
to be true,
though l 'll be sworn, if he be so,
his conceit is false.
Here, Claudio,
I have wooed in thy name,
and fair Hero is won.
I have broke with her father
and his goodwill obtained.
Name the day of marriage,
and God give thee joy.
Count, take of me my daughter,
and with her my fortunes.
His Grace hath made the match,
and all grace say Amen to it.
Speak, Count, 'tis your cue.
Silence is the perfectest herald of joy.
I were but little happy
if l could say how much.
Lady,
as you are mine,
I am yours.
Speak, cousin !
Or, if you cannot,
stop his mouth with a kiss,
and let not him speak, neither.
In faith, lady,
you have a merry heart.
Yea, my lord, I thank it.
Poor fool, it keeps
on the windy side of care.
My cousin tells him in his ear
that he is in her heart.
And so she doth, cousin.
Good lord, for alliance !
Thus goes everyone to the world
but l,
and l am sunburnt.
I may sit in a corner
and cry "Heigh-ho for a husband."
Lady Beatrice,
l will get you one.
I would rather have one
of your father's getting.
Hath Your Grace ne'er a brother
like you ?
Your father got excellent husbands,
if a maid could come by them.
Will you have me, lady ?
No, my lord,
unless l might have another
for working days.
Your Grace is too costly
to wear every day.
But I beseech Your Grace, pardon me. I was born
to speak all mirth and no matter.
Your silence most offends me,
and to be merry best becomes you;
for out o' question,
you were born in a merry hour.
No, sure, my lord,
my mother cried.
But then there was a star danced,
and under that was l born.
Cousins,
God give you joy !
By my troth, a pleasant-spirited lady.
There's little of the melancholy element
in her, my lord.
She is never sad but when she sleeps,
and not ever then;
for l have heard my daughter say
she hath often dreamt of unhappiness. . .
and waked herself with laughing.
She cannot endure to hear tell
of a husband.
Oh, by no means.
She were an excellent wife
for Benedick.
If they were but a week married,
they would talk themselves mad.
County Claudio,
when mean you to go to church ?
- Tomorrow, my lord.
- Not till Monday, my dear son,
which is hence a just seven-night,
and a time too brief, too,
to have all things answer my mind.
I warrant thee, Claudio,
the time shall not go dully by us.
I will in the interim
undertake one of Hercules' labors,
which is to bring Signior Benedick
and the Lady Beatrice. . .
into a mountain of affection
the one with the other.
I would fain have it a match,
and l doubt not but to fashion it,
if you will but minister such assistance
as l shall give you direction.
My lord, l am for you, though it cost me
ten nights' watchings.
- And l, my lord.
- And you too, gentle Hero ?
I will do any modest office, my lord,
to help my cousin to a good husband.
If we can do this,
Cupid is no longer an archer;
his glory shall be ours,
for we are the only love-gods.
Go with me,
and I will tell you my drift.
I do much wonder that one man,
seeing how much another man
is a fool . . .
when he dedicates his behaviors
to love,
will, after he hath laughed
at such shallow follies in others,
become the argument of his own scorn
by falling in love.
And such a man is Claudio.
I have known when there was no music
with him but the drum and the fife,
and now had he rather hear
the tabor and the pipe.
I have known when he would have walked
ten mile afoot to see a good armor,
and now will he lie ten nights awake
carving the fashion of a new doublet.
He was wont to speak plain and to
the purpose, like an honest man and a soldier,
and now is he turned orthography.
His words are
a very fantastical banquet,
just so many strange dishes.
Well, may l be so converted,
and see with these eyes ?
I cannot tell.
I think not.
I will not be sworn but love
may transform me to an oyster,
but l 'll take my oath on it,
till he have made an oyster of me,
he shall never make me such a fool.
One woman is fair, yet l am well.
Another is wise, yet l am well.
Another virtuous, yet l am well.
But till all graces be in one woman,
one woman shall not come in my grace.
Rich she shall be,
that's certain. Hmm.
Wise, or l 'll none.
Virtuous,
or l 'll never cheapen her.
Fair, or l 'll never look on her.
Mild, or come not near me.
Of good discourse,
an excellent musician.
And her hair shall be. . .
of what colour it please God.
Ha ! The prince and Monsieur Love.
I will hide me.
See you where Benedick hath hid himself ?
Very well, my lord.
Come, Balthasar,
we will hear that song again.
Hmm, now divine air !
Now is his soul ravished !
Is it not strange
that sheep's guts. . .
should hail souls out of men's bodies ?
Sigh no more, ladies,
Sigh no more
Men were deceivers ever,
One foot in sea,
And one on shore,
To one thing,
Constant never.
Then sigh not so,
But let them go,
And be you blithe
And bonny,
Converting all
Your sounds of woe
Into Hey
Nonny, nonny.
Sing no more ditties,
Sing no more,
Of dumps so dull and heavy;
The fraud of men
Was ever so,
Since summer
First was leafy,
Then sigh not so,
But let them go,
And be you blithe
And bonny,
Converting all
Your sounds of woe
Into Hey
Nonny, nonny.
By my troth, a good song.
And an ill singer, my lord.
No, no, faith; thou singest well enough.
And he had been a dog that should have
howled thus, they would have hanged him !
Come hither, Leonato.
What was it you told me of today,
that your niece Beatrice
was in love with Signior Benedick ?
I did never think that lady
would have loved any man.
No, nor l neither.
But most wonderful that she
should so dote on Signior Benedick,
whom she hath in all outward
behaviors seemed ever to abhor.
Is it possible ?
Maybe she doth but counterfeit ?
Faith, like enough.
O God ! Counterfeit ?
There was never
counterfeit of passion. . .
came so near the life of passion. . .
as she discovers it.
Why,
what effects of passion shows she ?
Bait the hook well.
This fish will bite.
What effects, my lord ?
- You heard my daughter tell you how.
- She did, indeed.
How, l pray you ?
You amaze me.
I should think this a trick,
but that the gray-bearded fellow
speaks it.
Hath she made her
affection known to Benedick ?
No, and swears she never will.
That's her torment.
She'll be up twenty times a night,
and there will she sit in her smock
till she have writ a sheet of paper.
Then down upon her knees she falls,
weeps, sobs, beats her heart,
tears her hair, curses,
''Oh, sweet Benedick,
God give me patience.''
She doth indeed,
my daughter says so.
My daughter is sometime afeared . . .
she will do
a desperate outrage to herself.
It is very true.
It were good that Benedick knew of it.
To what end ? He would make but a sport of it
and torment the poor lady worse.
I am sorry for her.
I pray you tell Benedick of it,
and hear what he will say.
- Were it good, think you ?
- Hero thinks surely she will die,
for she says she will die
if he love her not,
and she will die
ere she make her love known,
and she will die if he woo her.
If she should
make tender of her love,
'tis very possible he'll scorn it,
for the man, as you know all,
hath a contemptible spirit.
I love Benedick well,
and l could wish he would . . .
modestly examine himself, to see
how much he is unworthy. . .
so good a lady.
My lord, will you walk ?
Dinner is ready.
If he do not dote on her upon this,
l will never trust my expectation.
Let there be the same net spread for her, and that
must your daughter and her gentlewoman carry.
Let us send Beatrice
to call him in to dinner.
This can be no trick.
The conference was sadly borne.
They have the truth
of this from Hero.
Love me ?
Why ? It must be requited.
I hear how l am censured.
They say l will bear myself proudly
if l perceive the love come from her.
They say too
that she will rather die. . .
than give any sign of affection.
I did never think. . .
to marry.
I must not seem proud.
Happy are they that hear their
detractions and can put them to mending.
They say the lady is fair.
'Tis a truth, I can bear them witness.
And virtuous, 'tis so,
I cannot reprove it.
And wise,
but for loving me.
By my troth, it is
no addition to her wit,
nor no great argument
of her folly,
for l will be. . .
horribly in love with her.
I may chance have some odd quirks. . .
and remnants of wit broken on me. . .
because l have railed so long
against marriage;
but doth not the appetite alter ?
A man loves the meat in his youth
that he cannot endure in his age.
Shall these quips and sentences
and paper bullets of the brain. . .
awe a man from the career
of his humor ?
No.
The world must be peopled.
When l said l would die a bachelor,
I did not think l should live. . .
till l were married.
Here comes Beatrice !
By this day, she's a fair lady !
I do spy some. . .
marks of love in her.
Against my will l am sent
to bid you come in to dinner.
Fair Beatrice,
I thank you for your pains.
I took no more pains for those thanks
than you take pains to thank me.
If it had been painful
l would not have come.
You take pleasure, then,
in the message ?
Yea, just so much as you may take
upon a knife's point.
You have no stomach, signior ?
Fare you well.
''Against my will l am sent. . .
to bid you come in to dinner.''
There's a double meaning in that.
But are you sure that Benedick
loves Beatrice so entirely ?
So says the prince
and my new trothed lord.
And did they bid you
tell her of it, madam ?
They did entreat me
to acquaint her of it,
but l persuaded them,
if they loved Benedick,
to wish him wrestle with affection
and never to let Beatrice know of it.
Why did you so ?
Doth not the gentleman. . .
deserve as full as fortunate a bed
as ever Beatrice shall couch upon ?
O God of love !
I know he doth deserve. . .
as much as may be yielded to a man.
But Nature never framed a woman's heart
of prouder stuff than that of Beatrice.
Disdain and scorn ride sparkling in her eyes,
misprising what they look on,
and her wit values itself so highly. . .
that to her all matter else
seems weak.
- She cannot love.
- Sure, l think so.
Yet tell her of it, hear what she will say.
No.
Rather l will go to Benedick and counsel
him to fight against his passion.
Do not do your cousin such a wrong.
She cannot be so much
without true judgement,
having so swift and excellent a wit
as she is prized to have,
as to refuse so rare a gentleman
as Signior Benedick.
He is the only man of ltaly,
always excepted my dear Claudio.
When are you married, madam ?
Why, every day. . .
tomorrow !
She's limed, l warrant you.
We have caught her, madam.
If it prove so,
then loving goes by haps.
Some Cupid kills with arrows,
some with traps.
What fire is in mine ears ?
Can this be true ?
Stand l condemned
for pride and scorn so much ?
Contempt, farewell;
and maiden pride, adieu.
No glory lives
behind the back of such.
And, Benedick,
Iove on.
I will requite thee,
taming my wild heart
to thy loving hand.
If thou dost love,
my kindness shall incite thee. . .
to bind our loves up
in a holy band.
For others say thou dost deserve,
and l believe it. . .
better than reportingly.
Are you good men and true ?
Fight, fight, yea !
Being chosen for the prince's Watch.
This is your charge:
You are to bid any man stand,
in the prince's name.
How if he will not stand ?
Then, take no note of him
but let him go.
If he will not stand when he is bidden,
he is none of the prince's subjects.
True ! And they are to meddle
with none but the prince's subjects.
You shall also make no noise
in the streets.
We will rather sleep than talk.
You speak like an ancient. . .
and a most quiet watchman,
for l cannot see
how sleeping should offend.
If you meet a thief. . .
you may suspect him,
by virtue of your office,
to be no true man;
and for such kind of men,
the less you meddle or make with them, why the more is. . .
for your honesty.
You have been always called
a merciful man, partner.
Truly, l would not
hang a dog by my will,
much more a man
who hath any honesty in him.
'Tis very true.
Well, masters,
good night.
And if there be any matter
of weight chances,
call up me.
Come, neighbour.
We hear our charge. Let us go sit here
upon the bench till two,
and then all to bed.
One word more, honest neighbours.
I pray you, watch about
Signior Leonato's door,
for the wedding being there tomorrow,
there is a great coil tonight.
Adieu.
Be vigitant, l beseech you.
It is so:
the Count Claudio shall marry
the daughter of Leonato.
Yea, my lord,
but l can cross it.
Any bar, any cross,
any impediment. . .
will be medicinable to me.
I am sick in displeasure to him,
and whatsoever comes athwart
his affection ranges evenly with mine.
How canst thou cross this marriage ?
Not honestly, my lord,
but so covertly that no dishonesty
shall appear in me.
- Show me briefly how !
- I think l told your lordship a year since. . .
how much l am in the favour of Margaret,
the waiting gentlewoman to Hero.
- I remember.
- I can, at any unseasonable instant of the night. . .
appoint her to look out
at her lady's chamber window.
What life is in that
to be the death of this marriage ?
The poison of that
lies in you to temper.
Gallants. . .
I am not as l have been.