Unit Christmas rations
must be picked up by 0900 hours.
Armor group tree decoration team,
report to the Engineering Depot.
My son, will you turn off
that wretched puppet?
Brush your teeth.
Don't call him a puppet.
I beg your pardon.
Look, he's not a puppet.
Howdy Doody's real.
Well...
He's real.
Mr. Deedee Doodoo will
have to say good night.
Oh, no.
And remember,
you have to be asleep
when he comes
down the chimney.
It's not even a chimney, Pop.
He has his ways.
Then I want to wait up.
Watch him do it.
Nonsense.
Okay.
I want a story then.
Oh, no, no, no.
No stories tonight.
Just one.
And then I'll go to bed.
Right away.
Then I'll brush my teeth,
I promise.
"It is said that
at the dawn of time,
"man, beast and all magical beings lived
together under Aiglin the Father Tree.
"But man had been created
with a hole in his heart,
"a hole that no possession,
power or knowledge could fill.
"And in his infinite greed,
"man dreamt of expanding his
dominion over the entire Earth.
" The blood of many an elf,
ogre and goblin
was spilled in
their war with man.
"And King Balor, the
one-armed king of Elfland,
" watched the slaughter
in dread and despair.
" But one day, the master
of the goblin blacksmiths
" offered to build the king
a golden mechanical army,
"seventy times 70 soldiers
" that would never know hunger
and could not be stopped.
" Prince Nuada begged
his father to agree.
" 'Build me this army, '
the king said.
" So a magical crown
was forged
" that would allow
those of royal blood
" to command the Golden Army
if unchallenged.
" 'I am King Balor,
leader of the Golden Army.
" 'ls there anyone
who disputes my right? '
"And in his throne room
no one challenged his word."
But, wait, what if someone
could challenge him?
Would they have a fight?
Well, most likely.
A challenge must
be answered.
But do you want to hear
the end of this story or not?
Yes, please.
Right.
"So the world was changed, and
the next time the humans marched,
" they felt the earth
tremble beneath their feet
" and saw the sky darken
with monstrous shapes.
" The Golden Army had no
remorse, felt no loyalty or pain.
"And King Balor's heart
grew heavy with regret.
" So he called a truce and
divided the crown in three pieces,
" one for the humans,
and two for himself.
" In exchange, man
would keep to the cities
" and the magical beings
would own the forests.
" This truce would be honored by
their sons and the sons of their sons
" until the end of time.
" But Prince Nuada did not
believe in the promises of man.
"And it is said that
he went into exile,
" vowing to return the day
his people needed him most.
" So the Golden
Army lay dormant,
" locked inside the Earth,
waiting.
"And there it is to this day,
"awaiting the day the crown
is made whole again.
"Silent,
still and indestructible."
Wow. What does it
mean "industrable"?
Indestructible.
Indestruct...
It means no one
can destroy them.
Wow.
Go to sleep, my son.
But it's just
a story, right, Pops?
Is it now?
Yeah, come on.
Those guys,
they can't be real.
Well, my son,
I'm sure you'll find out.
How long have you
been there, my friend?
They're over there.
I bought them today.
I haven't fed them at all.
I will go up first.
You will follow.
And remember, Mr. Wink,
don't be shy.
Next lot. Number 776.
This is an important
votive figure,
a fertility goddess dating
approximately 15,000 to 10,000 B.C.
This was found
in a loess deposit
in a terrace about 30 meters
from the Shannon River.
And we'll open the
bidding at $300,000.
Three hundred thousand.
Three hundred and
twenty-five, thank you.
Three hundred and fifty,
thank you.
Three seventy-five.
Three hundred
and seventy-five.
Going once.
Going twice. Sold.
And now we move on to
our next item, lot 777,
a piece of the Royal
Crown of Bethmoora.
The origin of this
piece harkens back
to the saga of
the Sons of the Earth
and the creation of
the fabled Golden Army.
And here it is,
our next item.
Lot 777.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please keep your seats.
The auction will
restart shortly.
I'm sure this is just
a temporary loss of power.
Now, for the first
time at auction,
a piece of the Royal
Crown of Bethmoora,
coming to us from
a long lost culture.
Lost?
Not at all.
Forgotten by you,
perhaps,
but very, very much alive.
Who are you, sir?
Sir, please identify yourself.
You can't just...
I am Prince Nuada Silverlance,
son of King Balor.
And I am here, sir, to reclaim
what is rightfully mine.
Security. Call security!
What do you think
you're doing?
This is outrageous.
Take what you want.
Please leave.
Anything, take anything.
Be quiet.
Sit down!
Proud, empty, hollow
things that you are.
Let this remind you why
you once feared the dark.
Fishstick. We have to talk.
Undercover.
Can't he get the
meaning of the word?
Look, we are still
government-funded.
We are still a secret, although
a dirty secret, if you ask me.
Officially we do
not exist, you see.
So that's the problem
when we get these.
Subway. Highway. Park.
And he posed for this one
and gave an autograph.
I suppress each photo.
Cell phone videos.
They cost me a fortune and
they show up on YouTube.
God, I hate YouTube.
Well, he just wants the world
outside to know what we do,
what he does.
He loathes me.
I don't think so.
No?
Target practice.
Oh, dear.
And then he
posts them around.
Do you know how
that makes me feel?
What's going on?
Oh, it's Friday.
I tell you, Fishstick,
he hates me.
He's out to destroy me.
My street cred is low.
Street cred?
My mojo.
Washington, they're wondering
if I've got the stuff.
You think I have
an easy job?
Do you think
I enjoy being a pain in the neck?
I am medicated.
I mean,
this is not candy.
This is...
It's an antacid.
Yes, it's an
over-the-counter medicine,
but this is medicine.
You see, I worry
because, you know,
I mean, I am,
we are, after all,
we're just humble
public servants.
It's not about you.
He's acting out.
Things are a little
tense with Liz.
Tense? How tense?
Tense how?
Well, you know, the usual.
A new couple
making adjustments.
They argue.
They argue, huh?
Sometimes.
How bad?
Like everybody else.
They have good days
and bad days.
I'm not done with you.
Hey, Abe.
Red, come back here!
Manning.
Pick up your clothes!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Put away your things!
Watch it,
boys, she's on fire.
Then again, there are
the really bad days.
I'm not afraid
of you, you know.
You should be.
Look at this mess. Look around.
I have one rule.
Don't touch my stuff.
Oh, I get it.
That's your rule. Okay.
The one and only.
I'm easy.
How's that even possible?
Everything is your stuff.
The same CD, LP.
It's Al Green.
You can't listen
to Al Green on CD.
But it's good to keep.
And an eight-track.
An eight-track, Red?
Yeah, well, one day, the world's
gonna realize its mistake.
Eight-track was
the way to go, baby.
Come on, kids,
you can come out now.
That's right, it's all over.
That's right.
And what about me, Red?
I need some space.
At least enough to
find my toothbrush.
Toothbrush? Wait a minute.
It's right there.
Red! I can't
live like this.
Security breach
central Manhattan.
Oh, damn.
Gotta go.
We all gotta go.
It's an emergency, right?
Security breach.
Let's go.
Red. Red!
All personnel
to garage area.
Hold on a sec.
Oh, jeez, it's Manning.
Watch yourself, Liz.
Red. Red!
Listen.
Manning.
Hi.
We're going to
downtown Manhattan.
Yeah, it'll be fun.
Downtown.
Very dangerous.
Dangerous for you.
And for me.
Now, I know you dream
of the outside world,
but, trust me,
it's not that great.
It's savage, as a
matter of fact. Bad.
Come on, fellas,
let's get this out of here.
These, on the
other hand, are good.
Mmm.
Cuban.
Good.
Being seen?
Bad.
Exactly. I confiscated a box of these,
and I'll get you some more.
But you've gotta do me
a little favor tonight, out there.
You have to be...
You have to be very, very...
Discreet.
What? Thank you. Yes.
You're welcome.
Discreet.
Invisible. In and out.
Really?
Hey.
Hey, I can be
discreet if I wanna be.
I followed you
and Myers, didn't I?
And then you had him
transferred to Antarctica.
That's very discreet.
He said he liked the cold.
Like a shadow.
Red team, Red team.
Like a shadow
in the night.
US Customs discovered
a few illegally imported items.
It's a minor infraction.
And a gas pocket.
They detected
a gas pocket up there.
Now FBI agents,
under my command,
are going up there right now
with special gas equipment.
Jeez, it stinks in here.
This is worse
than my room.
Waiting for a report on that.
Say "cheese."
Let's go.
Whatever they
called us for is over.
We had over 70
guests reported.
We have no survivors,
no bodies.
Same story here, babe.
Don't call me "babe."
"Abe," I said.
"Abe." Wrong channel.
Abe, I think Liz is
still mad at me.
Still the same channel.
Oh!
Can I ask
you a question?
No.
Now, listen.
When we get home later,
I'm gonna clean up
my whole mess.
That's not the problem.
What is it?
Not now.
Abe, what have you got?
Oh, this is interesting.
Both boxes have
the Royal Seal.
Only delivered
at a time of war.
Red? We have company.
Come on, Blue,
give me something to work with here.
Burrowing creatures.
How many of them?
- Many.
There are no corpses because
there are no leftovers.
Have you noticed the floor?
Oh, crap.
Precisely.
All these things
do is eat and eat.
Then poop,
and then eat again.
Remind you of anyone?
Damn it, Abe.
What are these things?
English, English.
Oh, they're Tooth Fairies.
Ha!
No, no. Third century,
Black Forest.
Feed mostly on calcium,
bones, skin, organs.
But they do go
for the teeth first.
Hence the name
Tooth Fairies.
I bet you they don't
leave money, either.
Oh, my God.
Liz, you're pregnant.
No, I'm not.
Yes, you are.
What have you got, Marble?
Think I may have found one.
But he's kind of cute.
Don't go near it!
It's biting me!
Marble.
It hurts! It hurts!
Red, we need you here!
Marble.
Nasty little...
Keep firing, Abe.
Keep firing!
Damn.
Sorry, lady.
You should be running.
There's a safe upstairs.
How do we get there?
We need a clearing.
Run!
Up to the safe, now!
Abe. Up the stairs.
Come on, Liz, burn them all.
Go. Go!
Yes, we're going!
Get in the safe, Abe.
Get in the safe!
Oh, no, no.
No, no, no!
Steel!
Damned beasts.
Fire is mine.
Fire is in me.
Red, stay away
from the window!
Fire is me.
Stop biting me!
World, here I come.
What have you done?
Guess we're out.
Hey, Hellboy,
over here.
Your Royal Highness.
Before entering
the council chamber,
you must surrender
your weapon.
I will not.
It is protocol, sire,
for peasant and prince alike.
For you, Sister,
anything.
According to multiple eye witnesses,
lives were, in fact, endangered.
There you have it, Hellboy.
But is he really
on our side?
Do you have superpowers?
Well, yeah.
But, really, all I wanna be
is just an ordinary person,
just like you and
you and everybody.
Hey, guys.
You're missing this.
We're on TV.
Liz. Liz,
are you all right?
Yeah, I'll be out
in a minute.
You don't need to do that.
You can trust me.
My readings are
quite accurate.
Shut up, Abe.
Get your damn hand
away from the door.
You have nothing to fear.
In spite of appearances,
I believe Red would be an
excellent father figure.
And what about this guy?
Walking around with a
toilet seat on his head.
A toilet seat!
It's quite obvious it's
a breathing apparatus.
Hey, I think we gotta
lose the garbage truck.
Sends out the wrong signal.
You think that's
our problem?
Transportation?
And this girl, we definitely have
to find out what's wrong with her.
She's cute, though.
We should get her on the show.
I hate it when
people stare at me.
Makes me feel
like a freak.
You had no right, Red.
It's Manning. Could you...
How many times do
I have to tell you?
It's a gas pocket.
And a gaseous
phenomenon that occurred...
Gas pocket.
What an idiot.
You've murdered me.
You have murdered me.
You have ridiculed me.
And you have brought
this unto yourself.
What?
Washington is sending
down a new BPRD agent.
A new guy?
Why?
To look after you.
Sire, please.
To set us free.
All of us, Father.
A truce based on shame.
The humans have
forgotten the gods,
destroyed the Earth.
And for what?
Parking lots.
Shopping malls.
Greed has burned a hole in their
heart that will never be filled.
They will never
have enough.
Honor?
Look at this place.
Where is the honor in it?
Father, you were
once a proud warrior.
When did you
become their pet?
I have returned
from exile to wage war
and reclaim our land,
our birthright.
And for that, I will call upon
the help of all of my people.
And they will answer,
the good, the bad
and the worst.
Perhaps I am.
Perhaps they made me so.
We will not fade.
It is.
I am sorry, Father.
And you, Sister, are you at
peace with your king's verdict?
I am, my brother. I am.
Then very well.
Death it is.
Now, for the final piece,
my sister.
Where is she, Wink?
Where is she?
Go find her.
Now! Find her!
Elevator
arriving now to section 42.
Elevator arriving
now to section 42.
Pardon me, boys.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Is he here?
Not yet.
I'm telling you,
we don't need this guy.
Well, I think we do.
Evidently, this guy's quite
the big shot in Washington.
What's his name?
His name is Johann Krauss.
Johann Krauss?
Sounds German.
He's the top man in...
Ectoplasmic.
Yes, thank you.
Ectoplasmic research.
Comes highly recommended
by our European liaison.
Johann Krauss.
"Liaison."
I love that word,
don't you?
It's so hoity toity.
I don't like Germans.
No fingerprints.
Here he comes.
Germans make me nervous.
No photo. Dossier says, and I translate,
"He has a nice open face."
Oh, my God.
Damen und Herren,
Johann Krauss at your service.
I like him.
Look at that.
Poor little thing.
Bought and sold on
the black market.
Crammed into
cargo containers.
Smuggled, abused.
He has very
expressive hands.
The seal on the box
worries me also.
A warring emblem.
Yes, from the Bethmoora clan.
The Sons of the Earth.
Your file says you're the
brains of the operation,
and I must admit,
I'm impressed.
In my file, you'll see,
Mr. Krauss,
that I worked very closely
with Abe in his training.
Ja, okay.
Let's see what our little
friend here can remember.
Memory gets a little sketchy
right after you've burned to death.
But maybe Saint
Malachy can help.
Oh, no, no.
No amulets, Mein Herr.
Teleplasty.
Plastic. Very modern.
Teleplasty by which
an ectoplasmic medium,
such as Dr. Krauss,
can control inanimate things,
organic, mechanical,
dead or alive.
Take it, take it all in,
mein Junge.
There we are. Get up.
Get up. Get up.
Now I have full control
of its limbic system.
Let us see how long
I can hold it.
What?
Hey, you chewed off
the tip of my tail.
Yeah, you, you little...
It says you're rude, brutish
und not very bright.
Wow!
It seems our
little friend here
remembers market
sounds and voices.
And a peculiar
troll language spoken
in the last place
his cage was opened.
The troll market.
The troll market?
Come on.
No one's ever found it.
That's because
it doesn't exist.
Mr. Krauss? Dr. Krauss, sir.
Our little informant there
doesn't look so good.
Back inside, you.
There we are.
So, now we know
where to begin.
Trolls dwell under bridges.
Wow. You're a genius.
By the way, there's over
2,000 bridges in New York City.
But Vladimir Vanya, 19th
century occult historian,
places the troll
market directly under
the east end of
the Brooklyn Bridge.
We've already looked there.
Yes, you have,
but not with me, Agent.
Not with me.
We're moving in.
Keep it coming, keep it coming.
Hold it.
"Not with me, Agent."
What an ego.
I like him.
Well, you can keep him.
I mean, am I the only one that
thinks this guy is full of...
No, no, no, no,
don't lean.
Lot 336, the Schufftein
glasses. Could it be?
The three surviving
pairs,
and we will use them to
locate the troll market.
Dr. Krauss, what a coup.
The Schufftein glasses.
You're my hero.
Hey. You Hellboy?
Yeah.
You're ugly, man.
Two more on
the wall in front of me
and then three on
the alleys facing that way.
What do you think of
Mr. Know-It-All?
Don't know,
too early to tell.
Hey, you're Hellboy.
I know, I'm ugly.
Forget it.
We'll talk about it later.
He's sure of himself, and I
think maybe you're intimidated.
Intimidated. Huh?
Keep us up to date on thecameras, Agent Sherman.
Over and out.
What's this?
Normally, we can't see
fairy folk and trolls.
They generate a cloaking
aura called "glamour."
But in 1878,
Emil Schufftein designed and built these.
Four crystal diopters
that penetrate that effect
and reveal the true
nature of things.
Oh, Dr. Krauss, they're more
beautiful than I'd imagined.
You must try them on then.
Oh, yes.
Try them on, Agent.
They'll look good.
I love these tight
little leather straps.
Intimidated?
Mr. Kraut? Sir?
Krauss, Agent.
With a double "S."
S-S. Right, right.
Listen, those gizmos?
How do you know they work?
I have a suspect.
Give me a vector,
Agent Sherman. A vector.
B-12, the alley, northbound.
Well, track the target.
We're coming down.
Keep an eye on her.
I'll be right back.
This little old lady?
Come on.
It's a Fragglewump,
an ugly Scottish troll.
They're afraid of canaries.
Oh, my God. Canaries, huh?
What about the kittens?
She feeds on them.
Come on, then.
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
That thing is a "she"?
Down, you fools.
What do you think
you are doing?
She's gonna eat the cat.
You'll make her
aware of our presence.
We should use
the canary now.
She's gonna eat it!
We should use
the bird, Dr. Krauss.
The bird.
She's going to eat the cat.
You will stay put
and follow my orders.
I can't sit by here...
You are directly under my command,
and you have to obey.
Stay put!
Oh, screw this!
Hey! Lucy.
Come back here.
I'm home.
Oh, yes, dearie.
Can I help you?
Give it up, nasty.
We can see you.
You see me?
How? How do you see me?
We're looking
for the entrance
to the troll market.
Any clues?
Come any closer and
I'll rip your heart.
We're gonna have to get
a little old-school, Abe.
Give me the bird.
Not a canary.
What, you're afraid
of this little guy?
Who'd know?
No more, no more.
I'll take you there.
Come on, let's go,
you dirty old troll.
Let's go.
Agent Sherman, we are
going into the troll market.
Keep communication
to a minimum.
Over und out.
I like him.
You see, this is
a man who takes charge.
You think?
Yeah. He's efficient.
He's precise.
You add "resistant" to that,
you got yourself a new watch.
Dr. Krauss is aware of the
chain of command, and he...
Oh, brother!
He seems to like me.
Here we are.
Wow, that's some door!
It's a complex
combination lock.
What do you think,
Agent Sapien?
Not good.
With the number of symbols on the
combination, we'll be here for days.
Well, not necessarily.
Let me try my technique.
Open it, Lucy.
I will not.
Pretty please.
Do as you may, demon.
Release the yellow beast.
Tear my eyes out.
Rip my insides and
my legs and my tongue,
but I will never
open that door.
Is that your
investigative technique?
It said "never."
It's unconscionable.
That means
he didn't like it.
What?
So, what, you're gonna
show us how it's done,
Mr. By-The-Book?
Is that it?
Yes, I think I will.
There we are.
Let me see. Yes.
Gentlemen, welcome
to the troll market.
Red, there's something really
important that I need to tell you.
Oh, Liz, you should
be here. You'd love it.
Nobody's looking at us.
We blend right in.
Agent, I said keep
communication to a minimum.
You'll blow our cover.
You know?
I think he's right.
I'm bringing you
here for sure, babe.
The fishbowl wants
radio silence. So...
Over and out.
The Royal Seal.
Brother Red.
Red, do you read me?
Yeah, I read you, Blue,
but I'm watching Sherlock at work.
I'll get back to you.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir, excuse... Pardon me.
Sir, may I ask a...
I gotta tell
the boys that one.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Have you seen anyone purchasing
this type of Tooth Fairy?
No one sells them
down here, pal.
Over in Jersey, maybe.
Well, what about this, then?
Do you recognize this seal?
Make him go away.
No. We don't.
Please, dear sir.
You'd better go. Now!
We'll make it
worth your while.
Don't waste your time.
We will not talk!
What are you doing?
You're absolutely
sure about that, huh?
Absolutely.
You won't talk, eh?
Never.
Never, huh?
Never ever, ever.
Feeling a little
chattier now?
We'll never talk.
Yes, yes.
We will, only don't
hit me anymore.
Chicken.
Who bought
the Tooth Fairies?
Prince Nuada.
They say Prince Nuada
broke the truce,
and now there is
talk of war,
a war with
the human world.
Sorry, kid.
That's all right.
Nice baby.
I'm not a baby.
I'm a tumor.
Yes, Red. I am following
a lead right now.
It may turn out...
It may turn out
to be nothing,
but I will let you
know soon enough.
What do you want?
Tell me your name.
Follow me.
Your father
left you this map.
In it, he said,
lies the secret
to the location
of the Golden Army.
Move away!
Quickly, Your Highness.
Can I help you
with something?
No, thank you.
I'm just looking.
You can't go in there!
Sir, why
are you following me?
I...
I was just hoping to find
an old map chart of Algiers.
Why are you following me?
I was not.
Did my brother send you
to steal the crown piece?
Your brother?
Oh, you're sorely
mistaken, I assure you.
Then answer me truthfully.
Why were you following me?
My name is Abraham Sapien.
There is no such name.
Oh, I don't like
it either, but I...
Enough.
Give me your hand.
Your hand.
You are an agent
for the Bureau of Paranormal
Research and Defense.
And your name is...
Oh...
Horrible, I know.
I'm Nuala,
Princess Nuala.
Yes, I know.
Forgive me,
Your Highness,
but as you were
learning about me,
I couldn't help but learn
a bit about you myself.
I know that you
need our help.
I'm afraid it's
the other way around.
The window. Out now.
I will take care of this.
Oh, dear.
Go! Now go!
Get out of here, Blue.
Yes. Come with me,
Your Highness.
You.
Let me put this to you
as delicately as I can.
My cigar, it was Cuban.
Now you pissed me off.
Oh, crap.
Whoa!
Now stay down!
Damn.
A tooth. Happy?
Give it up, pal.
It's over.
I wouldn't do that
if I were you.
Wow. Told you.
Oh, mein Gott,
what have you done, Agent Hellboy?
Look at this!
Now we have to leave.
Red. This is Princess Nuala.
Lady.
We should leave.
Now. Now!
Let's go.
To wage his war,
my brother needs this,
the final piece of
the Crown of Bethmoora
and this map to the location
of the Golden Army chamber.
The Golden Army.
The harbingers of death.
The unstoppable tide.
Howdy Doody.
Your Highness, if you hand
the crown piece over to us...
No. Where it goes, I go.
My father died to uphold
the truce with your world.
You must honor
his noble intention.
The lady's
in dire danger.
I take it you're vouching for her,
Agent Sapien?
Most emphatically.
Yes, I am.
Even so.
I am sorry, but we
simply cannot assume
such responsibility
on our own.
The lady just
lost her father.
What more do you want?
You may not care, but
there are procedures, rules
and little handbooks...
She's coming with us.
You got that, Gas Bag?
What did you call me?
You.
You will pay for what happened
to my friend down there.
Yeah, right.
You take checks?
Demon.
Born from a womb of shadows.
Sent to destroy their world,
and you still believe you belong.
Are we gonna
talk all night?
'Cause I'm really sleepy.
No, Brother, no!
Kill him.
It's just a jumping bean.
It's going for water. Hurry.
Oh, dear.
No. No, no, no, no. No.
What the hell is that?
- Excuse me!
Stay back.
- Hey, what's going on?
We've got
target in sight.
It's an Elemental,
a giver of life
and a destroyer.
What?
A Forest God.
A Forest God, eh?
I'm gonna get me Big Baby.
Somebody help! My baby's...
Help! Help!
How can I help you, ma'am?
My baby's inside!
Come with us,
dear lady, please.
There's nothing
to worry about.
We've got everything
under control.
Please. My baby's
still in there! Please!
Hey, little guy.
Homing in on target.
Hang on, kid.
Agent Hellboy.
Reach higher ground
and shoot the weapon.
Shoot the weapon!
First praise the tail, kid.
You must shoot it in
the energy ganglion.
The what?
The energy ganglion.
Scheisse. The head!
Shoot it in the head!
Whoa!
Oh, crap.
You gotta trust me,
little buddy. Okay?
You woke up the baby.
Agent Hellboy,
take the shot!
Right now! Take it!
That's an order!
Take the shot.
That's an order,
Agent Hellboy.
Shoot it!
Shoot the gun! Shoot the gun!
Demon.
What are you waiting for?
This is what you
wanted, isn't it?
Look at it.
It's the last of its kind.
Like you and I.
You destroy it,
the world will never
see its like again.
Shoot it!
You have more in common
with us than with them.
It's breaking free.
You could be a king.
You will not
disobey a direct order!
Shoot it!
It's getting loose!
If you cannot command...
It will
destroy everything!
That's an order,
Agent Hellboy!
...then you must obey.
Shoot it now!
Damn.
Shoot it!
Move back.
Step back, step back.
It's beautiful.
and this huge monster
just came out of nowhere!
Yo, give the
baby back, man!
Oh, what have you
done to my baby?
The baby's fine.
You freak!
Hellboy,
what'd you do to that baby?
The baby's fine.
Don't move.
Hands in the air! Up!
He's got a weapon
in his hand.
That is his hand.
Miss, stay away from him
for your own safety.
He was trying to help.
Don't you see?
He was just trying to help.
That's all we do.
That's all we've
done all these years.
She's touching
his hand!
We've just tried to
help you. You.
You're a goddamn freak.
We don't need
you around!
What a freak.
Liz.
Let's go home.
... investigation of the BPRD and its
promotion of intra-species marriage
seen by many as a threat
to traditional families,
fuelled by federal funds.
I didn't touch you yet.
You did a good job
out there.
Then tell me, why
don't I feel so good?
I mean, I killed that thing.
And for what?
They don't even like me.
I mean, they're afraid of me.
What do we do with that?
Red, I don't want
you to freak out.
I'm gonna leave
for a little bit.
I need time to think.
About what?
Can't you do your
thinking right here?
Look, I'll be really,
really quiet.
I'll get rid of the cats.
Red, why are you with me?
Do you need
everyone to like you?
Everybody?
Or am I enough?
Think about it.
You stay.
We belong dead.
It's blank.
No coordinates.
"Be near me
when my light is low
"When the blood creeps and
the nerves prick and tingle
"And the heart is sick and
all the wheels of being slow
"Be near me when the sensuous frame is
wracked with pangs that conquer trust
"And time, a maniac..."
Tennyson, "In Memoriam."
A beautiful poem.
Forgive me, I didn't
mean to startle you.
Oh, no. No, no.
I borrowed this book.
I hope you don't mind.
Oh, no, no. Please,
this is your home now.
You are safe here.
My brother will find me.
He always does.
How could he?
Our location is a highly
classified secret.
Yes, but I know of it now,
which means that he does, too.
We're twins.
Even as children, a link has
bound us one to the other.
Something I cannot explain.
No need.
You look different.
Oh, do I?
Perhaps my hair?
No.
It's your eyes.
I can see your eyes.
Yes. Just trying
a new look.
Is that a map?
Yes, it was in the cylinder.
There are no coordinates.
Perhaps there's
a watermark.
You were very brave
vouching for me.
How do you know I'm not
the enemy, bringing me here?
It's as you were
saying just now.
From intuition maybe,
a link.
Normally I'm able to
read others quite quickly,
but I've never met
anyone like you.
Nor I, like you.
Good night, Abraham.
Good night, Princess.
Your Highness.
Your Majesty.
Your... Ma'am.
Ma'am?
Gute Nacht,
Agent Hellboy.
Look, Agent,
I know you don't like me,
but I could take
away your badge.
Never had one.
Kept asking, though.
You will learn to
obey me, follow protocol
and stay fockused
at all times.
Oh, that word "fockused."
Yeah, with your accent,
I wouldn't use it that much.
I knew Professor Broom,
young man.
You didn't know
Professor Broom.
Yes, I did.
After my accident...
Shut up. Shut up.
...he designed
this containment suit.
A wonderful man.
And even then he was worried
about your future. He...
Hey, Gas Bag, stop it!
Right now.
Or what?
Are you threatening me?
Because I think
I can take you.
Excuse me?
You heard me.
I couldn't hear you
from all the way over there.
I can take you because
you have one fatal flaw.
Oh, I wanna hear it.
No, you don't.
You can't take criticism.
Try me.
Can't take it.
What's my flaw?
Your temper.
It gets the best of you.
Makes you weak.
Makes you vulnerable.
Oh, crap.
Johann.
Johann? Johann?
Hey, Johann?
Come on, pal.
Hang in there, will you?
Johann? Johann?
Damn.
Ow!
There we are.
Your temper,
it makes you sloppy.
Try to control it,
Agent Hellboy.
Before it controls you.
Glasshole.
Mmm.
Huh?
Hello, Red.
Well, you're up late.
What are you listening to?
Vivaldi.
Il cimento dell'armonia.
I particularly
like the last...
Hey, hey. What's that?
Just a remote.
This? Yes.
"Popular Love Songs."
Oh, Abe.
You fell for the Princess.
She's... She's like me.
A creature from
another world.
You need to get out more.
She's alone in the world.
I wanna help her.
I need to care for her.
You're in love.
Have a beer.
Oh, my body's a temple.
Well, now it's an
amusement park.
No, no, no.
The glandular balance of...
Just shut up and
drink it, would you?
What track?
Eight.
Can't Smile Without You.
I know.
Yep, I'm gonna need
a beer, too.
Well, see, I love this song.
And I can't smile or cry.
I think I have
no tear ducts.
I wish Father were here.
He'd know what to tell
you. Us.
I can't smile without you
I can't laugh
and I can't sing
I'm finding it hard
to do anything
You see,
I feel sad when you're sad
I feel glad when you're glad
If you only knew
what I'm going through
I just can't
smile without you
You came along
Just like a song
And brightened my day
Who'd have believed that
you were part of a dream?
Now it all seems
light years away
And now you know I can't
smile without you
I can't smile without you
Nuala.
Good dog.
Security detail
for the front gate, immediately.
It's the last one.
Look at her.
She's it, Abe.
She's it.
She's my whole wide...
You know?
Yeah. Yeah.
I would give
my life for her.
But she also wants me
to do the dishes.
I would die
and do the dishes.
Why is she mad at me?
It's not because
the room is dirty.
Something else.
Well, ask her, then.
No.
Listen, Abe.
Yeah.
When a woman's
mad about something,
but she's really mad
about something else,
you can't ask because then they
get angry because you had to ask.
Do you know what I mean?
Never mind,
don't answer that question.
You gotta just...
Yeah.
...find out.
Very quick of you.
The parchment.
It was of no importance.
The cylinder is
very interesting.
We will find
the Golden Army here.
As for the crown piece,
I know it's here.
I can feel that
much from you.
Father always tried so hard
to shield your heart from mine.
But it's in one of the books,
and I will find it.
Blue.
You always look
so beautiful in blue.
Blue.
Poetry. "Love.
"Found then lost."
Only words.
I will find it.
Listen, listen, Red.
I know what's
going on with Liz.
Red.
Abe.
I'm sorry.
He has to know.
Abe!
Know what?
Why?
Stay back.
I'll go first.
Abraham. No, don't...
He'll kill you.
Princess?
Abraham?
No!
I will kill you, Abraham.
And anyone else
if that is necessary.
Well?
Then why don't you just start
with me, Your Royal Assness?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Who put those there?
And your weapon of choice?
Five-fingered Mary.
You move and I'll kill
your Abraham first.
Red, you mustn't
harm the Prince.
What?
If you hurt him,
you hurt the Princess.
You've gotta be kidding me.
Will you give me
the crown piece?
No.
The piece.
Abe?
Red, I'm so sorry,
but they're linked.
What's going on?
Red.
Liz.
Red, behind you.
You may have mused in the past,
"Am I mortal?"
You are now.
Abraham, many people
have died for this crown.
He will, too.
If you want to save him
and see her again,
you will find the missing
piece and bring it to me.
Jesus, Abe, pull the
damn thing out!
I cannot.
Every time I touch it, every
time I come close to it,
it moves closer
to his heart.
I don't know
what else to do.
The wound will not heal
until the spear is removed.
We're running out of time.
Then we go after the Prince.
And we make him
take it out.
Hey, Liz.
You were asking me.
Don't talk.
No, no, let me tell you.
I know what's important.
It's you.
Red.
I could turn my back
on the world, all of it,
as long as you stay with me.
I'll stay with you.
You're the best man
I've ever met.
"Man."
"Be near me
when my light is low
" When the blood creeps
"And the heart is sick and
all the wheels of being slow"
The cylinder
yielded coordinates
to County Antrim,
Northern Ireland.
The Giant's Causeway.
Right about here.
Great. So we know
where he is.
What are we waiting for?
We should get going.
The Prince will demand the
crown piece, Agent Sherman.
So we give it to him.
Dr. Manning?
I'm afraid it's not
as simple as that.
Hold on here,
what are you saying?
The Golden Army
must not awaken.
So, what?
You're just gonna let
him die, is that it?
I'm sorry.
We called Washington.
We have our orders.
And what about you?
He saved your life.
I know.
I know this is
difficult for you, but...
Well, I won't
let him die.
Agent Sherman,
may I remind you
that I am the leader
of this team.
Oh, there's no doubt
about that, sir.
That is what you
are, Dr. Krauss.
And if ever you were human,
that time is long gone.
What's wrong
with her?
You want me to
call her back, sir?
Let her go.
I understand.
What about you?
You find anything?
No. Nothing yet.
Well, keep looking.
Absolutely, sir.
All of you.
But don't worry, sir, we know
it's here, and we're gonna find it.
When Tom Manning gets on
the case, things get done.
They get done.
They get done!
100%. I guarantee that.
Even without the piece, we
have to get him out of here.
We'll go to Antrim, and
we will find the Prince.
Keep looking.
I ask you, everybody,
keep looking.
Abe.
Just the two of us.
Yes. Yes.
Let's go.
We need to leave now, before
they run our clearance upstairs.
Guten Abend,
meine Freunde.
Do you have authorization
to take that plane?
You're not gonna
stop us, Johann.
On the contrary,
I've been giving it some thought,
and we should be able
to save Agent Hellboy.
You say I'm not human anymore,
but you are wrong.
I understand your
pain all too well.
A long time ago,
I lost the woman I loved.
And that was, in fact, the
source of my present misfortune.
I will tell you
about it one day.
But for now, the tactical
advantage is ours.
Consider this, the Prince
lacks the crown piece
and without it, his
army poses no threat.
So we have clearance, then?
Agent Sherman, Liz,
screw the clearance.
We will take that plane!
It should be here someplace.
The entrance should be here.
I don't understand.
Perhaps there's
a mistake on the map.
Hello there!
I bid you welcome, strangers.
How can I be of assistance?
We seek safe
passage to Bethmoora.
And what does a nice little girl
like you want in the nightlands?
We are looking
for Prince Nuada.
Him, I know.
Trade me something,
and I'll take you to him.
Here. I have a shiny belt.
But I have no pants.
Look, a wonderful
set of magic eyes.
I already have binoculars.
But I see something special,
something shiny underneath the bandages.
I want that.
No, you can't take it out.
Not without killing him.
Maybe I know someone
who can.
Will you trade me then?
All right.
Very well.
Keep going. Keep going.
Oh, my God.
You should have seen
this city when it was alive.
What happened to it?
Curse.
As soon as the Golden
Army was stored here,
a plague of silence
and death befell us.
And the world left us behind.
For a long time,
I alone dwelled in the dust.
All right, little girl,
the two of you come inside.
The rest of you,
wait out here.
Hello, old friend.
I have brought you visitors.
And I have
a favor to ask you.
I owe no favor to
you, goblin. Leave.
But I have done
so much for you.
I have brought
you many souvenirs.
And he has something shiny.
Red.
Something mine.
Red!
Anung un Rama.
You know that name?
And yours.
Elizabeth Sherman.
At last.
I have been waiting for
you both many a winter moon.
I am his death,
and I will meet him
at each crossroads.
Good. But when can I have
that which is mine?
Can you save him?
It is for you to decide that.
It is all the same to me.
My heart is filled
with dust and sand,
but you should know
it is his destiny
to bring about the
destruction of the Earth.
Not now, not tomorrow,
but soon enough.
Knowing that, you still
want him to live?
So, child, make the choice.
The world or him?
Him.
The time will come
and you, my dear,
will suffer more than anyone.
I'll deal with it.
Now save him.
It is done.
I have done what I can.
Now, give him
a reason to live.
Hey, friend, what
about that which is mine?
Don't forget about me.
What about me?
Friend?
Shiny.
Listen to me, you big ape.
You have to get up.
'Cause you're
gonna be a father.
I become
father?
Well, all this is
very touching,
but if you still want to meet
Nuada, we have to leave now.
Ready.
Here we are.
And there they are.
Seventy times 70 soldiers.
Sometimes I wish
I'd never created them.
Bim-bam went the hammers!
Whoosh went the furnaces!
And one of those fires
took my legs off, now.
This is as far as I can go.
I'm not very
good with steps.
But if you're here to stop him,
the Prince, I wish you luck then.
The Golden Army
must not awaken.
Undo what we did.
We will.
You're here.
So I assume you brought
the remaining piece.
No. We didn't,
but we should discuss...
I'm not addressing you,
Tin Man.
Abraham.
Abraham?
My sister is well
as I promised, so...
Abe?
What the hell are you doing?
You would do
the exact same for Liz.
Agent Sapien, no!
I am Prince Nuada,
Silverlance,
leader of the Golden Army.
Is there anyone here
who would dispute my right?
Kill them.
But...
He lied to us.
Abe, old buddy, if we ever
get out of this, we gotta talk.
Open wide!
Industrable, my ass.
Hey! Throw me a bone here!
Oh, crap.
Well,
I'm out of ideas.
I got one.
I challenge Prince Nuada
for the right to
command this army.
You challenge me?
Who are you
to challenge me?
You are nobody.
You are not royalty.
Yes. Yes! He is Anung un Rama,
son of the Fallen One.
He has the right.
A challenge must
be answered.
Very well then.
Red, please.
Red. Think about it.
Guys. Guys!
He will kill you.
Don't do this, Red.
Don't worry, babe.
I'm not gonna kill him, Abe.
But I am gonna
kick his ass.
Whoa!
Red.
Hey!
Nice ride, huh?
You jumpy, slippery bastard.
I got you now.
Kill me. You must,
for I will not stop.
I cannot.
Sorry, pal.
I win.
You live.
Nuala.
The humans,
they will tire of you.
They have already
turned against you.
Leave them.
Is it them or us?
Which holocaust
should be chosen?
I never had a chance
to tell you how I felt.
Give me your hand.
It's beautiful.
We die
and the world will
be poorer for it.
Nuala, my sister.
All that power.
Don't even think about it.
No. No, it's nothing.
I told you,
it's a dead end.
What are you doing?
Go away.
Check the belt locator.
Check the belt locators,
over there.
Over there.
You, you took that plane without
an authorization, young man.
Hey. Manning.
Here to help as always.
What's going on?
I quit.
What? Are you serious?
Looks that way,
doesn't it?
What's wrong with you?
You can't all just quit.
Watch us.
On second thought,
I think I'll keep this.
Come on. Come on!
Johann, they can't do this.
Stop them.
Dr. Manning, suck my
ectoplasmic schwanzstucker.
So what you said before,
about us living anywhere.
Guys. Guys!
Anywhere. You and me.
- Come on back.
Let's find a place
in the country.
I said come on back.
Clean air.
Green hills.
A yard with lots
of room to grow in.
It'll be great for the baby.
Babies.
Subtitles by LeapinLar