Felix (from other room):
Oh, yes. Yes. Oh, yes.
Oh, yes. Yeah, that's it, that's it.
Almost there.
Oh, God, yes!
Yes...
that's the spot.
I thought I heard sex noises,
but this is equally disturbing.
I'm shooting an ad campaign
for a restaurant chain.
Wouldn't you like to try
this delicious sundae?
- I'd love to.
- You can't.
It's not edible... it's a little bit
of food-styling trickery. You see,
the ice cream is actually just lard,
and the chocolate sauce is motor oil.
Later, I have to dispose
of the sundae at Pep Boys.
This is so exciting. I love learning
all the little
behind-the-scenes tricks.
If you really find it
interesting, I could use some help.
I have some money in the
budget. Do you think Oscar
could spare his assistant for the day?
This is actually my day off.
I'm just here for the free WI-FI.
Great! You can help me
with the hamburger photo.
Oh.
Step one: select the perfect bun.
Now, our featured bun must
be perfectly symmetrical
with a golden crust.
Okay.
It doesn't shy away from
attention, but it knows
it's not the center of the sandwich.
Got it. Oh!
It's the kind of bun that's
comfortable at a bar, or a Bar Mitzvah.
I'm done.
Yeah, you can talk all you
want... you're paying me.
That I am.
- Good luck.
- Oh!
- Hey, Felix.
- Oh, gentlemen. Welcome home.
- How was Atlantic City?
- It was all kind of a blur.
Lots of drinking and gambling
and bouncers shouting,
"No touching."
When I drink bourbon, I like
to touch people's... teeth.
At least you got to drink.
This juice cleanse is killing me.
It's killing all of us...
you smell like a hamster cage.
All right, Oscar, it's time
for me to be your agent again.
You had your fun, but
now it's time to...
Drink beer in my underwear?
Sit your ass down and
start writing that book.
Wow, I wasn't even close.
Oscar, you're writing another
book? That's wonderful.
Oh, it's no big deal...
I'm just ghostwriting
this autobiography for a
retired baseball player.
I just crank 'em out
and make some fast cash.
Oh, yeah, he does work fast.
He goes through those books
like seaweed through a human colon.
I miss solid food so much.
Yeah, I could use a nap.
Do you mind if I crash here?
My wife thinks I'm still
in Atlantic City, and...
I'd like to keep it that way.
I'm gonna be kind of busy, Roy.
Yeah, okay. You know, I can...
I can just sleep in the park.
Yeah. At the park,
no one nags you, or says they've lost
all sexual desire
because your body feels,
quote, "like a bag of
wet sand dipped in hair."
Take a nap here, Roy.
All right.
Your friend drops an
emotional bomb like that
and you just let him walk away?
- That's the polite thing to do.
- Absolutely.
Can't you see, he's got some
deep-seated feelings
that need to be dug into.
No, no, no, no. Don't
dig. You always do that.
- What are you talking about?
- You treat every conversation
like it's therapy.
You root around people's heads
and get them all mixed up.
(chuckles): 18 therapists in 15 years...
I think I know a little
bit about psychology.
Not everybody wants to share the
painful details of their lives.
Oh, really?
Heard of Facebook?
I found the perfect buns.
I thought it was your day off?
I'm helping Felix with a project.
Ah, yes, Dani, very
nice. I like this one.
Now we just have to modulate
the clumping of these sesame seeds.
Why have they all congregated over here?
What do these seeds know
that these seeds don't know?
I will get you tweezers.
And I will get you pliers
to remove the stick from his ass.
Subtitle sync and corrections
by awaqeded for www.addic7ed.com.
There he is. Hey, Murph.
I see you brought some writing juice.
Yeah. Sorry I'm late.
This girl recognized
me at the liquor store.
Guess she's a big baseball fan.
So I had to stop and do the
whole polite meet a fan thing.
You slept with her.
Yeah.
Marcus Murphy does not kiss and tell.
Well, she does. It's
trending on Twitter.
"Made it to home base
with Marcus Murphy.
#bestsexever #majorleaguepenis"
Hey, it was a team effort.
We're all just out there trying
to have the best sex we can.
Or any sex we can.
So, how's our book coming?
Great. I haven't started it yet,
but I know everything there
is to know about your career.
Seven all-star teams,
three Gold Gloves,
two sex tapes; both went platinum.
Yeah.
I can't take all the credit.
Those girls showed a lot of hustle.
Just passing through. Hello.
Pretend I'm not here.
Murph, this is Felix.
He's not here.
What are you, some kind of photographer?
Hmm, technically, I am
many kinds of photographer.
Currently, I am doing
some commercial work.
Although, my first love is portraiture,
or as I call it, illuminating the soul.
He's gonna keep talking as long
as you keep making eye contact.
Yes, any portrait can tell
you what a person looks like,
but by manipulating color
and light and shadow,
I can tell you who a person is.
Whoa. Whoa, hey, Oscar,
don't we need a picture
of me for the book flap?
I'm thinking casual
setting, natural light.
Felix, I have a deadline.
I can't keep wasting time.
(phone chimes) I've got work to do.
Oh, there's my lunch.
All right, you guys have ten minutes.
Oh, no, I've got to call my bookie.
You guys have 20 minutes!
Just see what I'm working with here.
Oh, yes, yes.
Structure's good. Okay.
Photoshop will take care of
that little scar on the earlobe.
How can you see that? It's so tiny.
Oh, as a professional,
I'm trained to notice
the most minute detail.
In fact, tell whoever
gave you that hickey
she's got a loose crown.
Pickup for Madison.
Oh, hey, neighbor.
- I thought this might be for you.
- Yep.
I'm sure you're wondering
why I got a job here.
Not really.
Well, my jewelry business
hasn't really taken off yet.
You know, it started as just a-a hobby,
something I did for "mad money".
But now I need to make "rent money,"
so... (chuckles) look at me!
I'm a working girl.
Scrappy working girl in the city.
Plus, it's free
advertising for my designs.
So it's all good.
No, it's all great.
I'm sorry, what did you ask?
I didn't.
Oh.
Oh, I forgot your utensils.
I will be right back.
Oh!
Living the dream.
(shutter clicking) Yeah,
that's it, that's it.
Back straight, chin out,
like a proud meerkat.
Yes, yes.
Who's that coming?
Oh, it's my friend the gazelle.
Yeah?
Huh, that is an interesting expression.
Uh, sorry, I just don't know
what a gazelle looks like,
so I'm picturing a skinny moose.
No, it's not that.
It just, it looks like
you're pondering something.
I guess I'm thinking about the book.
What about it?
I don't know. It just seems so weird
to have your whole life
boiled down to stats and game scores.
Yes.
Interesting. Anyone ever tell you
that you have unexpected depth?
My English teacher, Ms. Russell,
said something like that in high school.
At first, I thought she was
just trying to get into my pants,
but it turns out, she
also liked my poetry.
Poet, I knew it.
The camera does not lie.
Ah, I messed around a little bit.
I really enjoyed it, but
my dad said it was stupid,
and that I had to focus on baseball.
Yeah, so you spent hours
training, sacrificing.
All to make your father
happy, but no one ever asked
what made you happy.
This is spooky.
It's like you're right inside here.
Quick, what animal am I thinking of?
I'm not a psychic.
A meerkat.
We just talked about them.
Look, the point is,
baseball is only a small
part of who you are.
Yeah, exactly. I wrote a bunch of poems
about breaking up with
my first girlfriend,
Ms. Nicholson.
My math teacher.
We had very different
high school experiences.
But I would love to hear those poems.
Nah, nah.
It's embarrassing.
Oh, please, Murph,
this is a safe place.
I am zipping us into a tent
of unconditional emotional support.
Go ahead, I'm listening.
Careful.
Oh, here you go.
- Sorry for the delay.
- Oh, no need to explain.
My manager insisted I
remake your sandwiches.
- You're explaining.
- And, apparently,
it comes out of my
paycheck, but that's okay.
Only three more hours till
I break even for today.
So don't feel the need to
over tip because we're friends.
Okay.
Or because I gave you free onion rings.
No comps; that's coming
out of your paycheck.
Learning through failure!
My dad said poetry was for losers.
He even threw my notebook in the trash.
Interesting.
But I wasn't allowed to cry,
so I just kept hitting baseballs
harder and harder and sleeping my way
through the female faculty.
Tragic. The young artist has
his dreams trampled. (gasps)
This is the book.
A scathing indictment of
our sports-obsessed society.
MURPHY: Hey,
maybe I could put my poems in it.
Brilliant idea.
Meet me in the kitchen!
What the hell is going on?
We've had a breakthrough.
Turns out Murph has many layers.
Oh, no, no, you dug.
I didn't dig.
You do like to dig.
Hey, I-I came up with a
great name for the book.
Verses Loaded.
Yeah, it's like bases loaded.
Just give it a second.
Murph, the reason the publishers
keep asking me to write
books like this is because I
know exactly what they want.
They want a book about an athlete,
not about some poem guy.
Or poet.
So you think my poetry's stupid?
It's your father all over again.
You know what, Oscar?
I'm really excited about this.
It's my chance to show
the world who I really am,
but if you don't want to do it, fine.
I-I already have plenty of money.
Well, I don't, so we
need to write the book
or you need to give
me some of your money.
Now, now, I'm sure that
we can find a compromise.
Murph just wants to
honor the yearning soul
- beneath the jersey.
- Wait a second.
Felix, you got to write this with us.
Ooh, that's trouble.
- What's happening?
- Oh, no, no, Murph,
I couldn't; Oscar's the writer.
- Thank you.
- But I could sit and look
over his shoulder and edit as we go.
Great! It's settled.
What is happening?
Oh, wow.
First two writers, now three.
This book is gonna be twice as good.
Oh, that math teacher screwed
him in more ways than one.
Oscar, I can tell by your
nostrils that you're angry.
You need to check out
that vein in his neck.
I only have 36 hours
to turn in this book.
And I won't get in the way.
I will just be a supportive,
unobtrusive presence.
Oh, Dani, look at that. Very good.
You know what?
Now I'm thinking poppy seeds.
They're elusive little
devils, so I will get you
the small tweezers.
You know, people fall off terraces.
Happens every day.
- All right, here we go.
- Before we begin,
I'd like to ask everyone to take a knee.
Lord, as we begin this project,
give us clear heads and fast fingers
to help us write goodly.
- Amen.
God help me.
Huh. Look at us.
The dream team.
Yes, very exciting.
Now let's get started.
Chapter one.
"My name is Marcus Murphy."
That's true. That's right.
I like it.
I like it, too.
I wish I loved it.
What would make you love it?
Oh, I don't know. Let's just try it out
for a minute, bat a few ideas around.
"My name is Marcus Murphy."
"Marcus Murphy is my name."
"They call me Marcus Murphy."
"I'm Murphy. Marcus Murphy."
You know what?
Sometimes the muse just
teases. What we have is good.
"For as long as I can remember,
my family was into sports".
Same here.
You're being me. I got it.
"When I first picked up a baseball,
I knew I was home."
Felix, I can feel your ear.
I need to be able to see the pad.
What have we got so far?
(high-pitched whirring)
(whirring)
Oscar! Oscar!
Oscar!
Oscar, you could have killed someone.
Yes, but I chose to do this instead.
"It was down to the final stretch.
"Time to rally for one last push.
"And my mother pushed
with all her might,
and I came into this world".
Oh. Awesome! We did it!
Yes, you were born.
Now we just have to wait 20 years
till the part people care about.
Ooh, I am beat.
I'm gonna head home, take a nap,
maybe enjoy the company of a young lady.
Which young lady?
Oh, it's ten blocks.
There'll be someone along the way.
And then, I'm gonna bring
back some of my poems.
Great. We can figure
out where to insert them.
Are you open to suggestions?
Well, it's a collaborative...
Oh, I just got that.
(clears his throat)
All right, I'll see you guys tomorrow.
Felix, you keep this guy on track.
Oh, you bet. I will crack the whip.
- (imitates cracking whip)
- (laughing)
(Oscar laughs)
(laughing)
Ha, ha, ha. I'm gonna kill you.
Oscar, he wanted me.
I didn't ask for this.
That's exactly what you did.
You dug, and you broke Murph,
and you ruined what was supposed to be
a perfectly nice book about baseball.
Why are you so afraid to write
about anything with real depth?
Why must you only skim the surface?
Because I like the
surface. It's pleasant.
It's pleasant, or is it safe?
What's so scary down there?
Oh, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no.
Because it's keeping you from
fulfilling your potential.
No, no, no. You stay out of me!
When we were in college,
you wanted to be a
great sports journalist.
You wanted to win a Pulitzer.
I remember because I
was the one who told you
it's not pronounced Poo-litzer.
I was a kid. I had lots of dreams.
I wanted to touch a Lakers Girl's boob.
It is never too late to
dust off those dreams.
You know what you need?
A visit to the emotional
support tent.
Oscar, what are you doing?
I'm locking you in.
Oscar, let me out!
You know that I'm bound
by the laws of mime!
You got to finish this book, Oscar.
Oh, what's the point?
I'm a failure. I'm a hack.
Even so...
But it's due tomorrow, and
you barely even started.
Yeah, and I realized, that's
my way of protecting myself.
I get to say I didn't have
time to write a great book,
rather than finding out I can't.
Even so...
(phone chimes)
Ah, that's my snack alert.
My one solid food a day.
(laughs)
Come here, baby.
(laughing)
Mmm. It needs something.
Like being wrapped in
bacon, sitting on a donut.
Mmm. Mmm.
Emily, can I get a drink here?
Oh, sure.
I'm not a bartender, but what the heck.
I'm learning all sorts
of new things today.
Like day-old bread
makes great croutons,
and rats don't die right
away in those traps.
- Oscar.
- Go away.
Stay out of my moneymaker's brain.
Sorry, Teddy. It must be tough for you,
knowing that your livelihood depends
on another person's fragile creativity.
I wouldn't be surprised
if under all that anger
- was a little bit of fear.
- (Teddy laughs)
Oh, good luck getting in here.
My wife has been trying for years,
and she's not even in the lobby.
I'm gonna call the publisher and
see if I can buy us some time.
How'd you get out of the tent?
I'm sorry, Oscar. This is all my fault.
You know, I always thought
that I'd write a book
that would make people
see sports differently,
like Moneyball or Seabiscuit.
But instead, I'm cranking out a book
about a guy who has two talents...
catching baseballs and
not catching chlamydia.
I wasn't trying to upset you.
I honestly thought I was being helpful.
It's funny, you live
in denial for so long,
you can't see the sad
truth about yourself
until someone shoves it in your face.
DANI: I did it, Felix.
At first I thought you were
crazy for being so picky,
but now I see how all those
details make a difference.
What?
Oh, for God's sake, what is wrong now?
Are the seeds too close together?
Is the lettuce too
emotionally available?
No, it's a hamburger, all right.
I'm going to take a picture of it,
because that's what I do.
I take pictures of hamburgers.
You know, when I was in college,
I dreamed of being Annie
Leibovitz or Richard Avedon,
photographing the essence of humanity.
And now, I make fast food look good
so Americans can get fatter.
I am not an artist.
I am a merchant of death!
I'll leave my time sheet on your desk.
Felix, can I get you anything?
I'll have what he's having.
An existential crisis.
Is that one of those fancy drinks?
It's only my first day.
No, Emily, it's when the
reality of your life crashes
into the dreams of your youth.
Hey, I have an idea.
Why don't you both...
(loudly): shut up?!
I beg your pardon?
"Waa, waa, waa.
I'm not as famous as
some famous person."
"Waa, waa, Seabiscuit."
Do you guys realize how lucky you are?
You get paid to do what you love.
Look at me.
Instead of designing jewelry,
I've spent the day scrubbing toilets
and putting out a grease fire.
Which I started, but
that is not the point!
Wow. Emily, thank you
for your bracing honesty.
We really lost perspective
there, right, Oscar?
Well, that's not the way I
said "Seabiscuit," but, yeah.
And, Emily, we believe in you.
All of this... this is
just part of your journey.
Yeah, all this struggle is going
to make you a better artist.
Huh.
I never thought of it that way.
Thank you.
Well, onward and upward.
- (laughs)
- Go get 'em.
- God, her life is a train wreck.
- Ooh.
(sighs)
Hey, well, I had to beg,
but I bought us a couple of days.
All right, I'm gonna go
upstairs and write that book.
All right, so you're done playing
Midlife Crisis: White People Edition?
Wow. Look who turns into
Chris Rock when he's hungry.
See, I can make race jokes, too.
- No, you can't.
- No, I can't.
Yeah.
While you are writing, Oscar,
I will gratefully rededicate myself
- to the art of
food-tography. - TEDDY: Mmm.
- Teddy, no!
- Screw this diet. I'm starving.
That's not food. It's cardboard
and hairspray and paint.
I don't care.
Oh, there you are. I
just finished setting up.
Hey!
Don't feel obligated to buy anything.
Felix thought Emily's business
could use a little boost,
and he said it right in front
of me, so I had to agree.
Hey!
- Hi.
- I think I will take this tie clasp.
My ties have had a mind
of their own lately.
Yeah, I wasn't gonna say anything.
Thank you, Felix. That'll be $45.
So what about you, Oscar?
- Does anything catch your eye?
- Yeah.
I think I'll take these cuff
links for my friend Murph.
Oh.
Oh. Those are $600.
Guys don't buy guys jewelry.
Oh, nothing like a good nap.
How long was I sleep?
About 30 hours.
Have you been back there the whole time?
Yeah, I curled up in the bathtub.
I like to sleep someplace cocoon-like
to simulate the support I never
got from my mother, or my wife.
Want to dig into that one?
No, I'm good.
Hey, Marcus Murphy, I
got both your sex tapes!
- Oh, all right. Okay.
- He was great.