.
What are you waiting in line for?
Michael Jackson is coming.
Why are you standing here?
That question makes no sense.
Obviously, to guard the American star.
At 17:53, the personal jet of the American
star landed at Otopeni Airport in Romania.
Michael Jackson stepped out
of the airplane at 18:07,
and the 10,000 admirers
were in for a great disappointment.
The star received flowers
from 9 year-old twin girls,
waved and then left.
All that in 53 seconds.
Michael Jackson shot at
a stadium in Bucharest
a few memorable scenes
that will be included
in his future video,
"Police Walk".
Romanian policemen are extatic.
Michael Jackson is about to wear
a Romanian police uniform.
General Nitu is ordering,
"Do not overtake him ".
But who can, in fact,
overtake Michael Jackson?
Around 13:15 Michael Jackson was received
by president lon lliescu.
Living... Iiving...
Good afternoon. Di rector,
the boys is ready. Whenever.
OK, OK.
OF SNAlLS AND MEN
You'll be careful, OK?
OK, OK.
This vehicle has been our
livelihood for years.
It was a great achievement of our times.
We were the pride of this country.
We won the Paris-Dakar Rally with it.
Aro's prestige
is due to all of you,
who worked hard every day
so that the best cars would come out
of our production lines.
In this democratic transition process
that Romania is undergoing,
we can see that our sales went down.
Actually, this has happened
to the entire Romanian economy.
- Where the hell were you?
- I had something to do.
The hell you did.
We, the factory management,
and the ministry officials
decided to take the most drastic measures
in order to revive production.
Wait... hold on!
Our great Emil Cioran said...
For those who don't know, this means,
"To live eternity is to live day by day."
That's what we are going to do, damn it.
- You don't care about us!
- Look where you brought us!
Do you have a better idea?
You, with your union.
Tell us, here, in front of everyone.
I have been informed that a French group
have made a very interesting proposal.
They are coming today to
inspect our equipment.
Let us welcome them properly.
Hey! Shut up!
And stop by the cashier
for your last paychecks.
As of today,
the factory is being temporarily shut down.
Gica... Are we going to let them
make fools of us?
I would set his car on fire,
just like that, for eternity.
Cut it out, I'm talking now.
Eternite au jour le jour, what the hell?!
- It doesn't have any words.
- No, but it's a well-known piece.
It's Ravel's Bolero.
They're sure to recognize it.
I assure you, the guests will be impressed.
Yes, they will see we share their culture.
If the French don't recognize it,
we'll make fools of ourselves.
I'm sure they will recognize it.
There's no way they won't recognize it.
They know it not only in France,
but all over the world. It is a classic.
Whatever you want. It's all the same.
As long as we don't make
fools of ourselves.
Oh well, whatever you want.
Goodbye, Director!
10, 20, 25, 26, 27,500. Here you are.
Boy, I'd really like to know
what that one's like in bed.
That one makes squeaky noises.
Like a mouse.
- And what about that one?
- That one...
She keeps her eyes closed all the time
and breathes hard, like she's sighing.
Get out of here.
You've been with her too?
That chick? She's bad, man.
She screams loud enough
to wake the neighborhood.
What would she scream?
Good afternoon!
Thank you!
- How about this one?
- This one, I don't know.
- These stay here.
- Did you like it?
French.
Manuela, you know it's important to make
a good impression on these French people.
They came all this way.
Please, come on.
Manuela, you've been making me hot
for such a long time.
What's the big deal?
It could be good for both of us.
Yes.
They left the hotel.
Yes, bring Mrs. Carmen as well.
OK, OK.
The Official Day of the Car Makers.
You're right.
Thank you.
Sorry!
My friends!
Welcome!
Mr. Director!
- Good afternoon, sir.
- My son, Olivier. He's working with me.
That's his son. His name is Olivier,
meaning, "olive tree".
Olive, as in the tree.
Pleased to meet you.
We also have names
like Violet, Cherry...
- Just girl names.
- That's not true.
I have a brother-in-law
whose name is Pine.
Crazy people.
Coffee?
We' re very happy to be here
in this beautiful region.
He's glad to be here in
our beautiful country.
We have a beautiful country.
It rains a bit much here.
But it is beautiful,
and we also have beautiful girls.
We have a beautiful country.
It rains a bit much here.
But it is beautiful,
and we also have beautiful girls.
Of course!
- I brought you a small present.
- He brought you a small present.
This is from our factory in Pontarlier,
in Haut-Doubs.
That's also a beautiful region...
It rains often, just like here.
It's from their factory,
I don't know where.
I've never heard of the place.
But it's not Paris.
But he says it rains beautifully there,
just like here.
So this is our future. Yes, we produce,
we produce, we will adapt.
Here you can find as many of these
as you want after every rain.
The manager thanks you,
and there are a lot of snails here too.
With the rain, you know, snails...
- Even better!
- You can see on the back there's a recipe.
And the secret is a lot of butter and also
a lot of parsley and a lot of garlic.
Because the snail itself
doesn't have a lot of flavor.
After 10 minutes in a very hot oven,
it's impecable.
The secret is to add a lot of butter
and garlic, and parsley.
Yes, otherwise the snail
doesn't have much flavor.
And he's saying it's good. I heard that
too, there they pay good money for that.
It's a delicacy.
Delicacies... international.
I'll give them to my wife,
see what she can do with them.
My wife... my wife cooks.
The director's wife is a very good cook.
She will cook the snails very, very well.
- She does sarmale very, very well.
- Sarmale. Yes.
I am very glad you came to our small town.
We hope to make good business
with our French friends,
with our Latin brothers.
Good business for us,
good business for you.
- The director said...
- No, no, I understand.
He understands, he understands, of course.
My French is back.
Thank you, Mr. Director.
We also hope to do good business with our
Romanian friends, our Latin brothers.
So, I won't keep you any longer,
I know you are busy at school.
Sir, it is my pleasure.
You know I took half a
day off to translate.
I know, but I can manage in
the language of Voltaire, can't l?
I can still remember it from school.
I may not have a great accent,
but the words...
Don't worry, you speak very well.
What did he say?
This must be a quote from
a national writer...
Ionesco, Popesco...
I don't remember.
Ah, the poet. Yes.
Yes, yes, yes. I'll leave you now.
Goodbye, gentlemen.
I hope you will visit our school soon.
We have prepared for you a little surprise.
Thank you, madam, thank you.
Make sure I am not disturbed.
Guys, I think we have to buy this factory.
If not, they'll be firing all of us.
What the hell, can't we just raise
150,000 dollars?
- Come on, Gica, are you nuts?
- Why?
- How the hell would we get all that money?
- We'll do something.
We don't even have a hundred dollars now.
Are you nuts?
We'll fiind a solution.
Guys, I found something in the paper.
Look... the richest man in the world
is the sultan of Brunei.
- Say what?
- The Sultan of Brunei.
Let's do something.
Let's write to him, maybe he'll help.
Yeah, right. We wrote to the people at the
Ministry and they didn't even write back,
and this guy will write to you...
what did you say his name was?
- The Sultan of Brunei.
- You can grab my ass.
Hey, hey, hey, wait.
Why shouldn't we write to him?
What's the problem?
What the hell is your problem?
This guy's right. We' re in serious
trouble and you're making fun.
Write it down, there.
What's 150,000 to him?
Dinner in a restaurant, right?
The tip.
He might want to help us,
to do a good deed.
Half?
Yes, the rest afterwards.
As discussed.
150.000 dollars.
Yes, as discussed, but with one condition.
We are in agreement.
The factory will be closed.
That's not a problem, I'll take care
of everything. Next week, bankrupture.
- Bank... rupture??
- Yes, the factory... done.
It will go bankrupt.
What will happen to the workers?
Yes, what will happen to the workers?
It's not a problem. I'll take care
of everything. Don't worry.
Robert, I'm a fox old.
Ah... old fox.
I've been here since Ceausescu's regime.
When I say produce, everyone produces.
When I say bankrupture, it's bankrupture.
Robert, do you think that I'm a...
papagal (parrot)?
Yes, those birds.
Ah, parrot.
Hey, Petrescu! Petrescu!
Yes?
Come here!
Good evening, sir.
What did you guys talk about,
there at the union meeting?
What do you think? We met and we tried
to think of some solutions.
Very good, boys. Come up with solutions.
I've had enough of claims.
And no more trouble, OK?
The French want to buy the plant
and reorganize things here...
- Good evening, Director!
- Good evening!
They will make a snail cannery here
and only keeping about 300 workers.
- It would be good to be one of them.
- What would I do with snails, Director?
- What?
- Do you think I'd go that low?
You have a wife and a kid and
there are hard times coming.
Listen to me. I went to school longer.
- Good evening, director.
- Hi, boys!
What the hell is wrong with it?
Easy, easy, Be gentle or else it'll choke.
We'll give you a push.
Release the gear.
Hey guys, come here!
Come here a minute! Let's help,
push here for the Director.
Come on, come on!
Get it out of gear.
Come on, harder!
Thank you for today's accomplishments!
We're waiting for you tomorrow
with strength and initiative!
- How are you, baby?
- Daddy!
- How are you?
- Look what I learned today.
- What is that?
- Bolero by Ravel.
Good work!
- You smell like perfume.
- It's from the French guys.
Was it a salary bonus, or what?
Those people came because
they want to buy us.
We'll see how many of us they get rid of
and how many will remain.
In the end, me and the boys thought
the only solution is to write
to the Sultan of Brunei.
- To help us buy the plant.
- Who?
The Sultan of Brunei.
He's the richest man in the world.
Can I write to the Sultan of Brunei?
What for?
To send me a bicycle.
Let him first answer us about the plant
Come on, dinner's ready.
And you go wash. You smell like a whore.
- French perfume. What do you want?
- Really...
- I told you the French came to the plant.
- Shut up.
You can smell them all the way home.
You're such a lousy liar.
A letter came for you.
To hell with them,
with their visas and everything.
Come on, forget it.
You can be happy here too.
They're just idiots.
Damn stupid!
Come on, Mama!
Come on, Mama! And please,
don't tell me about happiness again.
You know, it's not just a dog.
It's a noble breed.
I don't want a dog in my house.
Darling, it's a labrador.
Just like Dr. Teianu's dog.
Pufi, come on. Pufi, be nice with daddy.
Which Teianu? Who's Teianu?
The lady anaesthesist at the hospital,
whose son is in Paris.
- Come on, Pufii...
- No!
- Come on, say hello to Daddy.
- I don't want a dog! Get it out of here!
Come on Pufi, get out! Come on!
Pufi, stay here.
Take him away!
How much did it cost?
Drop it. It's not a problem.
It's a noble breed.
His parents were
carefully selected.
- They're not stray dogs.
- How much did it cost?
- Almost nothing.
- How much?
15,000. That's not even 50 dollars.
- So tell me, isn't it worth it?
- 50 dollars? Have you gone crazy?
What? Didn't you say
that we can afford it now?
I did, but we can't afford it yet.
Wait at least a week, damn it!
Do you think I care about
the dog right now?
Come on, dear, don't argue with him.
You're waking up all the neighbors.
Mama, why are you not asleep at this hour?
Go on, go to sleep.
Do you want something to eat?
Snails.
What's that?
You add butter, garlic
and a little parsley.
Then put them in the oven for 10 minutes.
It says here that the
oven must be very hot.
You' re not going to eat that, are you?
What are you saying? You have no idea.
This is refiined food.
I don't want dog in my house.
Out! Go on!
- Come on, Pufi!
- Shoo! Get him away from me.
Let's go, Pufi! Don't be upset.
Come with mommy!
In the last 3 years, since the wind
of freedom started to blow...
in our beloved country,
our entire lives have changed.
But now we have new
problems, new difficulties.
Problems we didn't face before.
As for the factory, our French partners
have an interesting program.
They will employ around 300 workers
for their future business...
You know, sitting here watching TV, that's
sure gonna take care of all our problems.
Perfect...
- Is Viorel asleep?
- Yes.
How are we going to raise our kid
if you're unemployed?
We can't live only on my
salary from the shop.
I'll fiind a solution.
You will find... Have you been looking?
No... I don't know... We'll manage.
The hell we will.
Don't you see how bad it...?
Leave it for now.
We won't find a solution at night.
Leave it, leave it, leave it.
That's all you ever say.
Are you a man full of energy?
Are you healthy and under 40?
Give a family the gift of hope
and get 50 dollars for yourself.
Call 230 5644 or write to us at the Pro
Family Foundation, PO Box 31, Bucharest.
How much is 50 ti mes 1 000 ti mes... 6?
Do you think I'm in the mood
for math lessons now?
Come on, l' m serious now.
If you' re serious,
how come you smelled like perfume
when you came home from the plant today?
Did you hear me? I'm talking to you.
Keep it down, you're waking up the kid.
How stupid do you think I am?
Were you with that bitch?
Tell me!
Cut it out! Cut it...
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
You're lying to me!
Easy!
I want you to tell me the truth.
We can't live like this.
We have a child to raise.
I want you to tell me the truth.
I' m telling you the truth...
Are you telling me the truth?
I' m telling you the truth.
Did you cheat on me?
No.
I understand. No physical
flaws, diseases...
What did you say?
Cronic diseases... Or obesity.
I wrote that down.
So, you pay 50 dollars for every donation.
Yes. Good. Thank you!
Bye.
Hey, guys!
All of us, together, we can save the plant.
I' m telling you...
The plant, all the debts and a license
for the engine are worth 300,000 dollars.
If a thousand of us sell our sperm
for a week...
we collect 300,000 dollars in no time.
- What's that we're selling, again?
- Sperm.
An American clinic is buying sperm
for 50 dollars each.
I talked to them and they told me that in
one donation they collect 5 grams of sperm.
This means that 1 gram
costs about 10 dollars.
The same as a gram of gold.
Don't tell me that you aren't able
to donate a gram of sperm.
If I put my mind to it,
I can donate 100 grams a night.
Get out of here, you're lying.
If my wife knew that I carry
such golden bars...
If you don't know, shut your mouth!
No way, Gica. Who's gonna buy that from us?
There's an American clinic in Bucharest.
I saw it last night on television.
I even called them.
50 dollars, times 1000 men times
6 days is 300,000... dollars.
We can even donate a few times a day.
We can even offer them a discount
and we finish sooner.
That's not possible. It's not true.
It's true. It says so in the paper. Look!
So why should we do it for the plant?
We might as well each do it for ourselves.
And what are you going
to do with 50 dollars?
You eat for a week in a
restaurant, or drink
it in one night and
it's gone, right?
Look, if we all pitch in,
we can all buy the plant
and they can't kick us out of there.
Gica, you're crazy.
Is this what we do in the union?
Stop with the crap, Gica.
Stop right there.
I suggest we vote. Who's in favor?
Come on, guys.
We don't have another solution!
What do you mean
we don't have another solution?
I don't do such things,
I want to stay here in the factory.
The French promised us 300 places.
- 300?
- Yes.
Yes? And what about the others?
Come on, guys, let's vote!
What are we voting for? We're voting
to jerk ourselves off? Cut the crap.
OK, who is opposed?
OK. Who's abstaining?
Come on, guys, it's
not like the old times.
George, are you nuts?
Don't you understand
that we want to stay on at the plant!
It's you who are nuts, guys.
They won't be able to keep all of you on.
Most will have to go.
Yeah, smartass, but maybe
we'll be among those who stay!
Yeah, lots of luck and good bye!
You have 10 percent chances, go...
Guys, let's try again.
Who's in favor?
Mirel, come on!
I can't. If my wife fiinds out
she'll break my legs.
And I don't even think
what you're saying is possible.
It is possible. I'll
show you that it works.
I'll go first.
How about Gheorghiu?
He's bad off, with 5 kids at home,
his wife works part-time...
I say keep him.
You thought right, he'll
be licking our boots.
Orghidan.
- Gheorghidan?
- No. Orghidan.
Who's that? Do you know him?
- I have no idea.
- The other column, then.
What?
They're going to what?
What? Are they nuts?
They made some calculations
and the math is right.
It's about 300,000 dollars.
How much is the plant worth?
The French are paying 150,000... but how
are they going to get all that money?
You know, I myself saw the advertisement
in the paper.
- Show it to me!
- Yes.
Wait! You'll show me when I get back.
I have to go to school.
The French are waiting for me.
And what do you want to do about the list?
You handle it
and show it to me when I get back.
Class, good afternoon!
- Good afternoon!
- Welcome. Here is the third grade.
They have prepared for
you a little surprise.
Children, are you ready? Viorel, please!
This evening, Club Paradise.
Please!
Come on, come on, Viorel!
1, 2, 3, and...
Come on, Viorel!
Viorel!
Oh, it's not so bad.
It's a song that I like very much.
And now, what will I do?
What will my life be like?
What about these days I don 't care about?
Now that you 're gone.
You see, it does have words.
What the hell...
What is my heart beating for?
Beating too fast, too fast.
Bingo.
Hello.
- Hello!
- You here?
May l?
Go ahead.
Thanks.
Hello. How many?
Th ree for me, please.
Here you go. 1 500.
- Same for me.
- Three?
40 cards for 500 lei.
The prize for a line is 800 lei.
The prize for bingo is 8000 lei.
The game is open.
The first number 1...
8...
72...
53...
31.
31!
I got it.
Thanks. I don't know how to play,
but...
Thanks!
- Line!
We have a line on card number 1695...
Did we win?
Line.
Thanks!
The line prize was awarded,
we now go on to the bingo prize.
Man, do they wanna know a lot...
- They also want a photo.
- No way!
I've got some photos at home, but
they' re with my wife, on vacation.
And with my kid on his birthday.
Don't worry, Gica. We'll take some.
Some good ones.
- When?
- Right now. Mirel has his camera.
- Really?
- Come on, hand it over!
Tuck your belly in, man!
Put more cheese in that smile.
Way to go.
I don't know. Think about people in movies.
James Bond, correct?
Take that bloody photo already!
Hey!
Enough! Let's see what it says further on.
It is forbidden to
undertake any sexual
activity in the days
preceding the collection.
What does that mean?
Well, yeah. Or else you're going
to get there without ammunition.
Why, you mean nothing?
Nothing? Not even, you know...
Yeah, like you get much anal anyway.
It doesn't say. You saw, though,
these people are serious, professionals.
Professionals, my ass.
Look! This one is easier.
What is your favorite kind of music?
I'll write down Dan Spataru.
- Which one from Dan Spataru?
- The one with the paths.
Our paths will cross some day...
- Gica!
- What? What?
Write down something else! Show off!
What would that be? Beethoven or what?
Beethoven is OK.
How do you spell it? With 2 e's?
Good afternoon!
Good afternoon.
You g rew so tall. And so handsome.
He looks just like his dad.
Do you like cotton candy?
Yes!
There you go, go buy yourself one
at the kiosk. Go on!
What do you say?
- Thank you!
- You're welcome.
Tell that husband of yours
to get his act together.
I'm not telling him anything.
You just mind your own business.
He's embarrassing you.
The whole town is talking.
It's a shame for this kid.
I'm not ashamed. He's doing his best
to keep us off the streets.
I'm not saying he's a bad guy,
but he went a little overboard.
Maybe if you tell him, he'll turn around.
We have to get along, damn it!
Like people do.
Come on, Viorel!
I have to go.
Take care. You never know
how these things end up.
- How are you?
- Fine. I'm going home.
What are you doing here?
I thought you were taking
classes in French.
Were you being funny?
That was hilarious.
You knocked me over with that joke.
I don't think it's funny.
What's in that head of yours?
You think you've got it made?
Planning to go away with that guy, or what?
What is your problem, really?
I thought we had a deal.
Now you're playing the detective with me?
I was just saying, it's a small town.
You can't keep a secret.
Was I wrong?
Since when are you lecturing me?
Let's get this straight.
You don't get to do that with me, OK?
You slept with him.
George, I do what I want, when I want to.
And you don't get to dictate a thing.
Yes? Understood?
Go home,
your wife and kid are waiting for you.
Hello!
Hello.
For you.
Thank you!
Please, come in.
- Is this you? In the picture?
- Yes.
That's funny.
Please, please!
No, no. Go in like that.
Mama, this is Mr. Olivier.
Good afternoon, madam.
Olivier, nice to meet you.
Hello.
What's wrong, dear?
Don't stand like that.
Please, come in!
It's nice.
- Please, take a seat. Here.
- Thank you.
- Music?
- Yes.
Come! Sit!
Line.
That's my father.
He used to work at the plant, too.
- The plant.
- At the plant?
My father.
- Your father!
- Yes.
That's you next to him.
My father and my mother... this song...
Thank you!
Enjoy.
Cuckoo.
I have one in my home.
It's good.
Do you like Julio lglesias?
Yes.
Really?
Yes, I like him a lot.
- Do you speak Spanish?
- Yes. Of course.
Yes. I learned it because I wanted
to understand Julio's lyrics.
That's nice.
- What about you?
- No, no.
I studied at the Salvador Allende college
in Pontarlier.
The best kids in school
were learning German.
But I learned Spanish.
Until now, it didn't help me.
- So... you were not a good student?
- No.
Would you like some more jam?
No, Mama, no.
Good marmelade, madam.
Thank you.
What is he saying about marmelade?
Tell him, dear, that this is jam.
You use the whole fruit
and it's harder to make.
He says it's very good, Mama.
Leave us alone, OK?
I would like to go out with you.
Do you want to?
- I can't.
- Why?
Because this is a small town. People talk.
It doesn't matter if they talk.
What would you like to do?
I don't know. You can't
do much around here.
What do you like most?
We can do whatever you want...
We can go
for a walk or eat something.
- I like to sing.
- Sing?
Yes, to sing.
There is a karaoke night
this week at Club Paradise.
- Karaoke?
- Yes. Karaoke.
If I get a proposition, of course.
But things are complicated.
There are others.
I came to get the list with the guys that
will be kept for the snail can factory.
I want the list with the
300 that will stay on.
Did you hear me?
Do you want me to get the boys
and have a rally?
Do you really want a scandal?
What rally?
With whom? For whom?
Gica, there's no one working here anymore.
You'd better stick to your business.
Make decent money,
have a decent family business.
Listen, give me that list or I'm calling
the newspapers, the TV stations and all.
Call them.
You still don't get it?
This plant will be bought by the French.
And you have nothing to do with that?
They decide who are hiring.
Whoever behaves nicely.
Don't do anything stupid.
You have a wife and a child to raise.
Get some sense into that head of yours
and I'll put you on that list.
I see hard times ahead, I told you.
It's going to get worse.
You're screwing us up.
Remember what you did
during the Revolution?
What?
You gathered here in front of the plant.
"Freedom! Freedom!"
Well, you got it.
You have freedom now.
Handle it!
Never call me out here again.
I know what you want and I'm busy.
Wait a second, I have something
important to tell you.
I've heard that one before.
George, I had enough.
No, it's not that. I need you.
I want you to help me with something.
Come on, sit down here for a minute.
- What? You know I like you.
- Come on, cut the crap.
Stop it! What do you want?
Listen, were you there
when they signed the deal?
Yes.
Can you get me a copy
of the contract they signed?
Why would I get involved in this?
Well, it's important. I bet
they're hiding something.
And if we find any proof, or something,
we can call the press and have a scandal.
Why would I do something like that?
You realize that if they catch me,
they will fire me.
They're going to fire you anyway
if they privatise the plant, aren't they?
Maybe they won't.
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah!
So you did what you had to do to stay here.
- Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
- Wait, what's wrong?
What do you think? If I slept with you
because I liked it,
now you think
I'd do it with anyone, or what?
Manuela, no.
No, wait.
You know what? Go home and mind
your own business. I'm finished with you.
Manuela, I didn't want to offend you.
What the hell?
Sure, you didn't want to offend me.
Listen, tell me, have you ever loved me
just a little bit?
Or was I just someone
to screw around with?
- Come on...
- Say it!
Come on, Manuela, what's wrong with you?
To hell with all of you!
Stupid bastards!
Easy, easy, so it stops swelling.
And stop fiighting with them.
Let them say whatever they want.
It doesn't matter. It's not your fault.
It matters. Good for you, Viorel!
I'll go to school and
talk to the principal.
What's with these punks?
They're fiighting in school now?
Leave the kid alone.
Go!
Good night, baby.
Good night.
Good night. Go to sleep!
All this is only your fault. You
just had to play hero to save the plant.
I'm ashamed to even
walk down the street.
And now look.
The child is suffering because of you!
- How is it because of me?
- Because of who, then?
You had to go convincing everybody
to act stupid. My God!
- Ana!
- I think you're losing it!
Do you realize if we manage to
buy the plant, no one will fire us?
You'll be proud of me.
We'll have money to go on holiday.
Come on, calm down. Really. I'm just trying
to do my best to make it better for us.
How could it be better for us?
How could it be better
when you're off doing this kind of stuff?
Tomorrow you're selling your sperm
to the Americans.
Did you think how that might be
like cheating on me?
Did you think about that?
If you don't get yourself together, I'm
taking Viorel and I'm going to my mother's.
- Oh, come now, leave it!
- Leave it? I'm not leaving it any more!
I kept leaving it for years,
and where are we?
- I'm the butt of everyone's jokes.
- There you go again.
Actually, you don't care about a thing.
How will we raise this child?
Will we raise him
with what you're giving
to the sperm clinic?
Is that what you want?
- I just want to...
- To what? To save the world?
Don't you care about your family at all?
Don't you want to save us?
Never mind. I'll just save myself.
Don't you touch me, or I'll scream
and wake the whole building.
- You don't smoke, you don't drink.
- No, I never liked it.
- So you have a child.
- Yes, a 9 year-old son, Viorel.
Healthy?
Yes, except for measles and such,
and the flu now and then.
What studies do you have?
I'm a high school graduate.
With a 9, you know.
What music do you like?
Excuse me?
A singer, a composer you prefer.
Bolero, by Ravel.
I like it very much.
Very good. I'll put it down in your record.
It will make a g reat i mpression.
Otherwise your fiile is...
Stand on your feet, please.
- What is your height?
- 1.80 meters.
- Good afternoon.
- Dr. Filip.
Good afternoon.
Please, take a seat!
I'm a little bit late but I let Otilia
hel p you to complete the forms.
How are we? All OK?
We went through everything.
I think it's alright.
I gave you all the information
that you requested.
Well done.
Let's see!
It's alright.
There's one more thing.
From a single donation
there are many children, usually 10.
Sometimes, when they become adults,
some of them want to know
who their biological parents are.
You understand what I mean.
If they wanted, would it be OK for them
to contact you?
How"s that?
I mean, later on, when they're of age,
they might want to know
who their biological father is.
Will you allow them to contact you?
What do you mean by contact me?
Sometimes they want to know
where they come from.
But it's very rare, I must say.
OK, then.
So you give them the address
and they can knock on my door anytime?
No, we'll call you first.
Your gesture does you proud, sir.
You will be giving back hope to a family
that is suffering.
On their behalf, I thank you!
The nurse will give you
everything you need.
And... the money?
In 2 or 3 days, once we've done our tests.
Don't worry, the nurse will guide you.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome!
Bye.
- Petrescu!
- Yes!
Come with me.
Is everything alright?
Excuse me, do you have a magazine
or something?
My name is Manuela.
I'm 30 years old.
I like you a lot.
You like me... a lot?
No, no.
French lessons.
OK, OK.
Do you want to come to France with me?
Come to France with me.
No, I work at the factory.
What are you going to do
when they close down the factory?
I work at the factory.
No. You can't.
Yes, yes. I work at the factory.
300 workers.
- You can't.
- Why?
Because there will be no factory.
It will close for good.
We will sell all the
equipment and that's it.
No one needs your factory.
They don't care.
This place is dead.
But you said that 300 workers...
It's a lie.
No one cares about you people.
We won't make snail cans there.
We'll sell everything and that's it.
But I care about what happens to you.
Manuela...
Come to France with me.
Here you have no future.
You came all this way,
you lied to us and now
you're telling me to go with you to France?
Yes, because I tell you the truth.
Yes, yes, the truth.
- Mama...
- Yes.
Do you think daddy is OK?
Yes, I think so.
Do you think he wrote to
the Sultan of Brunei?
I don't know. Why are you asking?
For the bicycle.
I don't know...
Mama, are you also afraid at night?
Come on, enough, go to sleep.
Good night!
Good night.
They want more.
The Prime Minister's signature,
the Economic Advisor's signature,
the Minister of Finance's signature.
It's not that easy.
You sell the equipment for a high price...
I'm selling it for a high price,
but we're partners, we split the profit.
Fifty-fifty.
Yes, I understand.
I have many risks... The workers.
Press everywhere.
200... 200.
The visit to the foster home
was divided in 2 parts.
One private, in which Michael found out
that our kids know how to sing,
he received a gift from them
and generously offered autographs.
Then the star went to the kids' playground,
built by the Heal the World Foundation.
Michael's love for the children...
Hello!
Ana, is that you?
Ana...
I'm sorry!
I tried to do something
to make things better for us.
But..
I don't know...
I didn't think
you would leave over this.
Now I don't know what to do.
Is Viorel OK?
Ana... come back home!
I love you!
George, it's me.
Listen... be careful.
These guys are out to trick you.
- What?
- They won 't take anybody back.
This story with 300 people is a lie.
They're closing the factory and that's it.
But how do you know?
Somebody told me.
Who?
Listen, tell everyone.
Everybody should know.
- Did you sleep well?
- Great.
I opened the window...
Fresh Romanian air.
I' m really hung ry.
Shall we have breakfast?
I already ate.
Enjoy your meal!
Stop pushing.
We' re registering all of you.
Not you, Vasile.
Under 45 years, I told you.
Ion, put out that cigarette. I told you.
You know you' re not allowed.
Fill in this form here. Starting today,
no more drinking, no more smoking,
and no touching your wife, understand?
- And what if she wants to...?
- Say you have a headache.
Come on, play the Bond.
Better drop the gun.
- Hey, Gica, how do we do it?
- How do we do what?
Tomorrow we meet at the station
and leave for Bucharest.
- No, man, how do we do that?
- What's that?
That... thing... how do they collect it?
They don't collect it themselves,
we give it to them.
Just like that? No helping hand?
Come on. I'll explain later.
See how many people are waiting in line?
No shoving!
Have some patience, OK?
How are you?
Hi!
My brother-in-law saw a clinic
like that in China, on TV.
And they had some nurses
helping the men.
What, did they show
the nurses helping them?
No, but I thought that's
why they were there.
- Do they have nurses at this clinic?
- They do.
Then let's...
You should come, too!
But when you were there,
did they help you a bit?
Come on, I don't need that.
OK, whatever.
- What do you think about this situation?
- The situation is like this.
We realized that this way we can get
enough money to buy the plant.
Pay off the debts, buy
a license for the new engine...
and start production again.
Until now we have a list with 250,
but we hope to have more volunteers.
What are your arguments for this initiative
and what are your strong points?
Well, here in our factory, we have
vigorous, strong, smart people.
What woman wouldn't want
a father like that for her child?
We are determined to do this,
and please let everybody know.
Maybe a convenient solution can be found.
Or we'll go to Bucharest...
or maybe the clinic will open
a department here, in Campulung.
Don't you think this might cause
trouble back home?
Each of us should decide it
within their family.
Or maybe individually.
But I believe we shouldn't
get to this point.
To go to such desperate measures.
There is no problem.
Everything is under control.
The French part is settled.
But these guys have gone mad.
Petrescu from the union, he's getting
them to think they can buy the plant.
I'll take care of it! I'll take care of it.
Yes. It's OK.
Like... Iike we said.
Bye.
Miss, I have my husband
and my son working
here in this factory. I
don't agree with that.
Go home.
This is not normal.
Catalin, why do you...?
Go home, you're embarassing us.
You think, just because we're poor,
we should sell just anything?
The French are here!
I think it's enough for me.
I'm out of here.
Wait a second, what's going on?
What's wrong with you?
We're almost done.
It's good. Everything was solved.
We' re a team, aren't we?
I don't like this game, Dad.
It's not fun.
I came to help you...
That's it. I don't want to live like that.
Olivier, this is not the moment.
You know you can't save the world.
We know that we're in a
diffiicult situation.
We will make all efforts to fiind...
It's a business that has to go well.
If not, I'm fiinished.
It might be the last one.
They will fiind a way, you'll see.
They' re used to it.
They've always been knee-deep in shit.
I haven't.
- OK. I understand.
- What?
If you want to keep her, you have
to keep doing business like that.
That's easy to see.
OK, I'll let you do your business
with the parrot. I'm going.
Nelu, let go of that cigarette.
You'll get sick.
Good night!
Good night.
Are you tired?
No, but you know tomorrow I'm going
to Bucharest with the guys.
I know, I know...
OK, good night.
No... stop it!
Wait, wait!
You know I can't. Wait!
Come on, you know that.
It was spelled out on the goddamn form!
Yes, I know, but just a little.
They won't notice it.
I can't, don't you understand?
Woman, we have to save the plant.
What the hell?
You don't love me anymore!
I do love you. But I can't do it tonight.
I' m working for export.
Good night.
I will forget everything I've had
The burden I've carried so long,
The moment we said goodbye.
I won't ask for the impossible
I won't ask for your love
No need to look away
Our paths might cross someday
Our paths and love,
Our thoughts and happiness...
Stop eating, man.
Stop smoking. I told you.
Who's sneaking in the front of the line?
What's the hurry?
- What's for sale here?
- Concert tickets.
For Michael Jackson, free.
- Who?
- Michael Jackson.
Do you think you've got enough
cups for everybody?
It's not possible to...
We can come tomorrow as well.
In smaller groups.
Still, we need to hurry
because the factory
is going to be sold at
the end of the month.
- Sir, that's not possible.
- Why not?
Come on, Gica!
I understand, you know. We're talking large
quantities here. Can I make a proposition?
Sir...
We can give you a discount.
Let's say 20 percent.
That's enough, sir!
This way you only pay 40 dollars
per collection.
Enough, sir!
We deal with serious things here.
What we do here
determines the lives of children
and the happiness
of families that are now suffering.
I don't fiind your mockery
amusing in the least.
Our plant is bankrupt, madam. They're
privatizing it at the end of the month.
And they want to lay us all off.
Most of the guys you see out there
have children.
Children who want to eat, get dressed,
go to school, play...
How can they do that, madam,
if their fathers are unemployed? How?
- Stop yelling at me. I can't help you.
- Why, doctor, why?
The sperm that we buy here, we sell abroad.
We sell it to families that can't
have children the natural way.
We sell it to gay women
who want to have a child
without a man in their lives.
These people have a lot of money.
Enough money to buy the sperm
and also the treatment that's needed.
They want to give their children
as many chances as possible.
Yes, of course.
That's why they want to donor to be
a tall, handsome, young man...
with a high lQ, well-educated
and cultured.
Let me give you an example.
The best seller on the market now is
the sperm of Danish students.
They're tall, handsome, blond.
Our clients do not want to buy
the sperm of a Romanian worker.
Especially not in those quantities.
How's that our fault, doctor?
We're people, too.
I don't know, but I can't help you.
We won't go, we won't go,
Until we save Aro.
They say that it...
that it's good for the skin.
To keep it fresh.
Can't you use the collections
for cosmetic products?
I don't know if it's good for the skin,
but they don't make skincare products
from such things.
Go home and mind your business.
You didn't give me the
money for last time.
What money?
50 dollars for last time.
I already donated.
- Yes, yes. What's your name?
- Petrescu.
- Petrescu?
- George Petrescu.
George... hold on.
Petrescu George.
Yes.
You donated on the 17th,
but we don't owe you anything.
But I donated.
Yes, that's true, you donated,
but we can't use it.
You're sterile.
You can't have children.
It's a genetic disease, from birth.
It's called the Kleinfelter syndrome.
Come on, madam.
How is that possible?
No, it's nothing serious.
You won't die from this,
you don't need any treatment.
Only... that you can't have children, ever.
That's it.
Doctor, maybe there was a mix-up
with the cups.
We're a very serious clinic.
Goodbye!
What will I do now?
I don't know. It's not my problem.
Please get your colleagues and go home.
Gica!
So, Gica, how was it?
Are you fiinished, huh?
Come on, don't keep us waiting.
Did you donate?
How was it? It didn't hurt, did it?
Guys, they don't want to collect.
What do you mean, they
don't want to collect?
Why did we come all this way?
What, they don't have enough jars?
They don't wanna collect
because we' re workers.
Come on, you scared us.
Now tell us!
Come on, we're in a hurry.
We can go in 2 or 3 at a time.
Hey! Didn't you hear?
They're not collecting, damn it!
Wait, wait!
- Why is that, Gica? Why?
- Because we're workers.
- They' re saying their clients...
- Quiet!
Wait, let's hear what the man has to say.
They say... their clients don't want
to buy from workers.
Who do they want to buy from?
From educated people, students, doctors.
Shut up, man! Quiet!
- What the hell's wrong with ours?
- They say it's not the same.
Why don't you wanna collect from us?
What's wrong with us?
Cut it out!
Have we got the plague or something?
Go away, move it!
I made a fool of myself,
got the wife all pissed at me...
Police! Call the police!
The sperm of Danish students, you say?
Yes, that's what the doctor said.
Well if I'd known,
I should have dyed my hair blond.
We should have gone to Michael's concert.
What will I tell my wife now?
Sunburned, beaten by the police...
And no fucking money to show for it.
We'll be their laughing stock back home.
He'll laugh in our face.
"You made fools of
yourselves in Bucharest."
"I'm going to fire all of you."
- What's wrong with you?
- Nothing.
Yeah, nothing. Tell me what's wrong?
What am I going to tell Viorel now?
He really wants a bicycle.
I wanted to get him one with the money
from my last donation.
And they didn't give you anything?
Take it!
- No.
- Take it!
Ion...
Come on, or we'll miss our train.
Our paths might cross someday.
Our paths and love,
Our thoughts and happiness.
- Cheers!
Manuela...
I have a surprise for you.
Like night, like dreams
Are the black eyes of my love
Manuela
Like ear of wheat in spring
Like full moon is my love
Manuela
Her loving words,
The restless look of my love
Manuela
You have my senses imprisoned,
And all my dreams are
for Manuela
Since it came into my life
Since that afternoon
when I met Manuela.
I'm happy like no one is,
Because every day is witing for me
The sweetness of her kisses,
And that immense love that
Manuela gives to me.
We'll manage somehow.
Are you working for export tonight,
or do you have some for
the internal market?
What's up, George?
Did you get a package?
Still saving the plant?
Daddy! It's daddy!
How are you?
Come on, run!
Run, run, it's raining!
- What's that? The bicycle?
- Yes.
- Is it from the Sultan of Brunei?
- No, it's from me.
Tonight, I'm the Sultan of Brunei.
I told you, Mommy! I told you
daddy would bring me a bicycle.
- Yes.
- Look!
- Look, it has a horn too.
- Go, go!
There you go. Well done!
I found this bicycle in Bucharest.
- How was it?
- It was OK.
Listen...
you know what they told me
at the clinic?
They told me I can't have children.
They told me I have a syndrome...
I can't remember...
Something with a German name.
You know what I did?
I broke their windows.
How could they say that?
Viorel's got my eyes,
doesn't he?
Yes, he has your eyes.
Get him out of the rain,
so he won't catch a cold.
Look, Cucu, there's one
To your right.
Look over there.
Get him, he's running away!
- Careful. That one's going for export.
- Look how fat this one is!
Ion, do you think Manuela's French guy
is really taking the snails to France?
Yes, he says so. He's paying
one dollar per kilogram.
So you're going to Paris?
Lucky bastard...
To live on a footing with eternity
is to live from day to day.
Emil Cioran
- Romanian philosopher
At 16:02, the inevitable did happen.
Michael Jackson's personal jet
took off for lstanbul,
his next stop on the Dangerous tour.
To his list on conquests, Michael Jackson
can now add his Romanian fans.