How sensible. You brought two umbrellas?
I am tired from working late, but
I still want to beat you up.
How nice for us to each have an umbrella. I'm not getting
hit by a single drop of rain. My shoulders are dry.
Aigoo. Thank you so much.
♪ Softly, I'm melting now ♪
♪ And softly ♪
♪ I melt you, too ♪
What would you have done if
that grandpa wasn't there?
Would we have walked all the way,
each holding our own umbrellas?
If so, I would have beat
you with the umbrella.
- That's enough.
- You bring two umbrellas because there are two people?
Of course. I should have known when you called a
proxy driver all the way out to the Western Sea.
Be quiet so that I can say something, too.
Okay. Go ahead.
Speak.
You don't even have anything to say.
I love you.
Whooo. I'm on cloud nine!
You say that only now? You
sure are saying it early.
Aren't you going to reply? The
recipient usually says something.
Can I reply here?
I also, Park Do Kyung...
Stop. It's okay.
Why? I also want to reply.
- I also, to Park Do Kyung—
- Enough. It's okay. Stop.
Oh, why?
It's fine.
♪ Wanting to remain by
your side no matter what ♪
♪ If those were my feelings,
could you try to understand? ♪
Ah, I'm so pitiful.
Just from that one "I love you," I'm
dying from happiness, like an idiot.
You have emotionally starved
me, as you can see.
I still haven't replied yet.
Can I do it here?
It's okay. Don't do it.
♪ All the scars that
you've kept hidden away ♪
♪ Give them all to me ♪
I also love Park Do Kyung so much!
Park Do Kyung is mine!!!
♪ Keep me close to you ♪
♪ As much as I waited for you ♪
♪ I can wait even more ♪
♪ But somehow, this moment
for us feels like our last ♪
- Episode 17 - So Happy I Could Die Today ♪ But
somehow, this moment for us feels like our last ♪
Okay. Lift it up.
What?
♪ When the lazy sunshine comes in ♪
♪ I stare out the window in a daze ♪
♪ I think about you, who've
been buried in my thoughts ♪
I don't want to go in yet.
Should we just go to your house?
Hurry up and go.
♪ I try to not care, but I
can't help but be found out ♪
♪ My heart, why is my heart doing this? ♪
♪ What about love? ♪
♪ Why is my heart doing this? ♪
♪ Every day, it makes me shed tears
and snot and makes my heart hurt ♪
♪ What about love? ♪
♪ My heart is racing, racing! ♪
♪ I want to lay my heart
onto your sweet lips ♪
♪ Dream a dream of you, a
dream I'm kissing you ♪
She's 32.
Is a 32-year-old not a girl?
That simpleton idiot.
I mean, if we think about the
time when you liked me...
That's why she's an idiot.
Thank you.
I became prettier.
Because I am loved, I got prettier.
Hold on, Ahjussi! Ahjussi!
I accept the fact I'm late. I
can just go and get scolded.
Is being late important? No.
Love is what is important.
Wake up.
Wake up!
Oh, Do Kyung. I thought I was back
in your house, I was so shocked.
Aish.
You didn't go home?
You know about my house.
Some girl is ringing my
doorbell at all hours.
Ah, my head.
Get up. Let's go to the sauna.
I paid attention today. I stripped from
the top, and dressed from the bottom.
To not be cursed out by you, I
carefully dressed that way.
It seemed like you didn't notice.
Hey.
Please... Compliment me.
I need a compliment.
I don't have any energy. And even if I
play all night I don't have any fun.
I feel like I have "bad guy" written
on my forehead as I walk around.
And even in my heart, "bad
guy" is stamped in there.
- If you're going to be like this, why did you leave?
- I got kicked out.
I didn't walk out with my own feet.
She told me to not look back,
and even called out my steps.
Left foot, left foot.
I was going to marry Noona.
I'm not that much of a bastard.
At that time, Noona said,
"You don't have to force
yourself to deal with this."
She caught me smoking a cigarette.
I smoked just once before, when I failed
the bar exam and got my draft notice.
This was my second time ever smoking.
So she found out my true
feelings pretty easily.
I'm so humiliated.
I feel so bad.
I feel so humiliated.
Do Kyung, hug me please.
Sheesh.
I'm so humiliated. I'm so sorry.
How is Noona?
Don't be lonely.
Even if you don't have a father,
you have a mom who's like a dad,
and an uncle who's like a dad.
But if you still need a father,
even if Mom had to go out into the world
and drag out every guy in existence,
I'll find you the very best father!
This is the analysis for the food
trends for the next half-year.
It's not analysis if I can't
understand the first line.
Again!
- I will do it again!
- Go make me some coffee.
Yes.
Show me the one we downloaded earlier.
Oh, please don't worry. You know us.
Even if the sky falls, we will finish mixing the sound.
When we finish the accident scene, I will call you.
Yes, yes. Take care.
Joo Il and Ki Tae are looking
around for new offices.
We'll find someplace cheap, so know that.
We will not go work anywhere else.
Don't worry, CEO, you will continue to
get jobs. So we will recover very soon.
You're amazing. Can you work?
Let's go to Chairman Jang and apologize.
- It's not going to end just because we do that.
- And send that woman back to him.
Then, it's the end!
Forget it.
Are you punishing me right now thinking that
you were totally ruined because of Mom,
that Mom did wrong, so she should feel
it down to her bones? Is that it?
This all happened because I did wrong.
You didn't do anything wrong, Mom.
What?
Do Kyung, he...
Is...
Is he sick?
He's acting strange. I
think something's wrong.
He's not getting mad at me!
What's going on with him?
Hurry up and find out.
I'm so proud of you,
you're not even wilting.
You're enduring so well so
Unni won't feel sad, right?
Don't cry at night because you feel lonely.
Unni will come early
tomorrow morning, okay?
What do the flowers say?
You shouldn't talk to flowers. It makes you look
weirder than if you wear flowers on your head.
- Let's go. Sang Soo is treating.
- I will have sweet potatoes pork cutlets.
Oh, I'm leaving now. Why?
Let's eat dinner with my sister tonight.
With the director?
Tell him never mind.
I told you I would bring you home.
- What's the use going back and forth? We can take a taxi.
- But you are not alone... (I.e., pregnant)
I mean, you are with her, so I
should have gone to pick you up.
- Let's go inside.
- Yes.
Go inside.
- It's her boyfriend who made our company like that, right?
- Her boyfriend is me.
- So you've gone crazy.
- Don't say anything to her. I'll kill you.
Wow, you are like a married couple.
It's nice to see.
Our company is...
Well, they say that love triumphs all.
Why eat together? You two
could eat alone upstairs.
We can eat together. If you don't
eat, you can't do other things.
Why do you glare at me whenever I say anything? What
fun is a couple in love if we can't make fun of them?
I won't get all jealous,
I still have my pride.
Come here and sit.
- Yes.
- Sit down. Let's eat.
Please eat a lot. Oppa
said you like melons.
I also like meat. And sushi.
I like a lot of things.
If he ever asks what you
like, never answer him.
He will buy you only
that thing for 365 days.
It was 30 years ago, I was 14 years old.
I tasted melon for the first time,
and said that it was very delicious.
After hearing that one comment, for
30 years, he only buys me melons.
"Merong!" (Nyah-nyah)
Let me just say one thing.
Please love our Do Kyung a lot.
He's a pitiful child.
Can I take him home and raise him?
- I'm just joking.
- But it sounded real.
You can take him home and love him
until he suffocates with your love.
As long as I don't die from a
fluttering heart first, that is.
Wow. You have to have the
last word, don't you?
- So you love him that much?
- So much that I could bungee jump without a rope.
Of course, not alone. With him.
You... sound a bit crazy.
Take it easy. Even if
he's my little brother,
- there are limits to how much I can cheer on someone else's love.
- Yes, ma'am.
But, the lawyer friend seems to be late.
If we call him, he'll come out.
He's hiding somewhere.
Lee Jin Sang! Come out and eat!
- Lee Jin Sang!
- He's gone. He's not coming anymore.
This human...
So he ran way.
He went to meet Miss Monday.
It seems like that guy caused
some big trouble. What did he do?
- Something.
- So what did he do?
I'll tell you later.
Oh, I'm so curious. Can't you tell me? It's
making me sad that everyone knows but me.
What do you want to listen to?
Rather than listen, that song you sang
when you were a child, "Daydream,"
let's record that as you sing it.
I think it will be good
to hear when you get old.
Your voice at six years old, then at 36.
- I think it will be fascinating.
- No.
Why? Let's record that.
Please sing it for me.
The man who I loved most,
his voice at the moment
when he loved me the most.
I want to record that.
I want to hear it. Sing it for me.
♪ You pretend to be okay, smiling ♪
What is this?
Are those handcuffs?
Is this what you're into?
Oh, it's making me flustered.
♪ Because I know your scars
better than anyone else ♪
It's not something I had from before.
I bought it for you.
Am I dying?
Why are you treating me so well?
You're being too good
to me, it's scaring me.
♪ What should I do? ♪
I was passing by, and I thought
it was pretty, so I bought it.
It's making me uneasy.
I am so happy, but I'm so uneasy.
Am I uneasy because I'm so happy?
Don't think too deeply about it.
It's not the right timing to be
this happy, but I am, that's why.
You can just be happy.
Then I will just be happy.
And I will brush my teeth now.
Can I take a shower, too?
Let's take you home.
Everybody, look!
Hey! Everybody, come!
Jump! Jump! Yeah! Yeah!
Hey!
Are you playing to make up for lost time?
You are playing so hard.
Right. Why didn't you come all this time?
Oppa was just... Busy.
But from now on, I will
be comfortable and free.
Every day, every night, party-party,
crazy party! Here, drink!
Brother-in-law!
You shouldn't live this way. Think about
your child. Does my sister deserve this?
He must be crazy.
It's nothing. Nothing at all.
It's a friend's little brother.
He is just playing.
What a crazy guy. His jokes
are a little much, huh?
Let's have a drink. Yeah.
Let's go home, Brother-in-law! Even if you
hate my sister, you shouldn't do this!
Look, really.
Bastard!
Hey, Park Hoon, stop right there!
If I catch you, you're dead!
A loveless marriage isn't a sin, you know?
That guy, he's really gone crazy.
Get lost, you jerk.
Noona still loves you! How can
you not know a woman's heart?
I don't know! I don't know.
You son of a bitch.
Why? Why can't you admit
that it is your child?
Why can't you say that you
have a baby on the way?
You are a FATHER!
Oh, what is going on with our family?
Hyung is ruined, and Brother-in-law
left home. What is this?!?
You came?
Oh, that bastard. Crazy bastard.
He's just someone I know.
He chases me everywhere I go and does that.
He thinks it's funny.
Let's go dance.
Let's go quickly.
Go in.
Go back safely.
Ouch. That hurts.
If I look back on this moment as I die,
I won't regret this.
Why do all the people that come to my
house always have so many requests?
You never requested anything from me...
You never requested anything from
me, and that is why I liked you.
But in the end, you disappoint me.
This all began because of me.
If Oppa collapses, I can't end things
with him. I request you, please.
I want to help him, even by doing this.
Please help me.
Oh, get these grass bits away from me.
Are you trying to starve
this old man to death?
And you, go.
Isn't it a bit childish?
Joining hands with your enemy?
How about becoming more honest? Aren't you the
one who wants those two to break up the most?
Yes, that could be true.
But I haven't looked into
my heart that deeply.
I don't want to,
because I might see that that is how I truly feel, deep
in my heart. So before that, I'm changing my behavior
by telling myself that I really want
them to be happy together, truly.
What a difficult way to live.
I do understand you. I felt that
way until just a few days ago.
Even as I was doing bad things,
I felt terrible about it.
So I thought about it, and decided
to only be a halfway bad guy.
'I am not a completely bad
guy, I will only go halfway.'
'So you should get knocked
down flat, right about here.'
But you know who the most despicable
people in this world are?
People who are good, but quit.
Or people who are bad, but quit.
People who just quit.
Don't be vague about your feelings when you
don't really feel that way. Just be honest.
It's cooler if you just embrace your
desire to want them to break apart.
After talking to you, I see my answer.
They say you really know someone only after you break
up with them. After leaving him, Park Do Kyung
turned out to be a really great
guy, so I regretted it a lot.
But I don't think Hae Young regrets
breaking up with you, like I do.
You... You cannot even be
compared to Park Do Kyung.
Come in.
Director Park, the R&D department developed
something new. Let's go see it together.
Let's do that.
It seems this product's
profit potential is low.
Hey, Madam Park Soo Kyung.
Let's go.
That woman is ignoring me?
We should really consider profitability
a priority when developing products...
Why aren't you answering my calls?
Go. I am at work.
You're wearing heels, are you nuts? You're
pregnant at age 44, do high heels make sense?
I am pregnant at age 44, and
have you contributed anything?
I did contribute something, obviously.
You crazy punk.
I think I must have called you a
thousand times since last night.
You are so stubborn. How can you not
answer your phone, after so many times?
Are you trying to see who wins over whom?
There is no reason I should
answer your phone call.
When you kicked me out of your house, didn't that mean that we
were at least preserving our brother-and-sister relationship?
Don't make me laugh.
Could that be possible?
Wow, I didn't know you
were this uncool, Noona.
Cool, my ass. You can
feed that to the dogs!
What crazy people would sleep
together, make a baby,
do all kinds of things together, and
still remain brother and sister?
Didn't you say that your college major
was French? What are those two saying?
I cannot understand a single word.
Get lost!
Fine, then. So you're breaking up our
brother-sister relationship, too.
Let's just never speak to each other again.
That's not difficult at all.
Let's completely abandon all
our affection for each other.
But there is no going back now. It's over.
I spit on you! Spit!
What? What? What is it?
What's going on? What is it?
Who are you?
Let's do it, just once more.
Kiss.
I do know this word. Let's
just get off, right now.
But I have to ride this. I
have to go to a meeting.
Why are you getting off?
What is it? What did he say?
He asked to kiss her.
Kiss?
But he looked so normal.
And he looked a lot younger, too.
Director! Whoa!
You guys look so cool.
Wow, they kiss so well.
Whoa, really. Director.
Director, fighting!
Oh, they're really going for it.
Director, good job.
- Thank you.
- No, I was going to see him anyway.
Thank you for requesting that of me.
Don't worry too much.
Everything will turn out okay.
I am grateful.
What's wrong?
He keeps seeing it. I think he's
really up against something.
Let's try hypnosis. We
can't just sit and watch.
In the night sky, white flower
petals are flying around.
What kind of flowers?
I think they are cherry
blossoms, but I'm not sure.
Someone died. A singer. Lee Byung Joon.
[Breaking News: Death of Singer Lee Byung Joon]
♪ Why are you so cold to me? ♪
♪ Was love something that
changes so easily? ♪
[June 2016, Big Sale]
♪ Did I do something wrong? ♪
♪ If so, I am sorry. ♪
So you're sure that it's 2016?
It's June 2016, for sure?
But then, cherry blossoms don't
make sense for that time.
Just go abroad right now. Run away.
Would he chase you all the way abroad just to
kill you? Let's go to the airport right now.
Go home and get your passport. I'll give
you a ride to the airport. Come on.
♪ If those were my feelings,
could you try to understand? ♪
Hey. Do Kyung.
Do Kyung!
♪ All the scars that you've kept
hidden away give them all to me ♪
I have to tell her. I have to
tell her before it's too late.
Come out.
I'll bring you back home
before the sun rises.
Let's go.
♪ I've never expected anything ♪
♪ When you show me your
sunlight-filled beautiful smile ♪
In my life, a man calling me to come
out in the middle of the night,
after my sunbae during Freshman year
in college, this is the first time.
That sunbae wasn't really my type,
but I think that he liked me a lot.
He saw me at orientation, and remembered every
time that he saw me, up to the seventh time.
The second time was in the library. The third time was at
the main gate. And the fourth time was somewhere else.
Do you remember where we first met?
Why wouldn't I know that? We first
met at the coffee shop with Hee Ran.
You gave me a nosebleed
in both my nostrils.
That wasn't it.
Before then, we had already
seen each other, while walking.
You looked back at me, too.
Don't you remember that?
Which street?
Yeoiudo. In front of the post office.
Oh, that's right. I did go there.
So you saw me in the street, and
you fell for me at first sight.
And you remembered that?
No.
- Even before that, I knew you.
- How?
You kept appearing in my mind. Your face.
Even though I have never seen you before.
Then I saw you for real in the street.
Then I saw you in the coffee shop.
How can I appear in your mind
before you've ever seen me?
Just...
like a memory.
I kept seeing you.
Before you moved into that
room, I saw it in advance.
I couldn't see other things.
I only saw you.
At first, I thought that
I was seeing the future.
I thought that I had developed
psychic powers or something.
But I came to know it, suddenly.
What I was seeing. Why I was seeing you.
Why did you see me?
In the future, when I was dying,
what I was thinking about
in my final moment.
Like when your life flashes
before your eyes, as they say.
I saw something like that.
In the future?
Yes, before I die.
Before I die,
I thought of only you.
I...
I'm sorry.
My feeling of missing you was so strong,
that feeling pierced through
time and came back to the past.
My doctor said that that can happen.
In my memory at the moment of death,
we broke up and were not together. You
moved out of here, and we were finished.
As I died, I regretted that the most.
Why was I so stingy about my heart?
Why did I live always so stressed out
about things that didn't matter?
And I said so many things
to you that I didn't mean.
I will give you as much money as you ask for. Why force
someone when she says she doesn't want to live here?
Sorry for acknowledging your existence.
Don't be sick.
What were the words I really wanted to say?
Never mind my pride or anything else.
What did my heart really want most?
What were the words I really wanted to say?
Just...
please return. I'd like
it if you came back.
I'm sorry, but these are my true feelings.
I got sick from holding back my desire
to hold you and have all of you.
And that is how we got back together.
As I lived, I have never comfortably
expressed my heart, not even once.
I was flustered that you came
towards me so fearlessly.
I even wondered if it was okay
for a woman to be this way.
But... I liked it.
It moved me. If I died never
having loved like this.
It would felt really unfair.
Now, when I die,
♪ I still want you ♪
I won't have any regrets.
Thank you.
♪ My heart, without end... ♪
If I could believe this, it
is a really awesome story.
But I guess you didn't marry anyone?
If you miss me the most when you die.
Perhaps.
Perhaps you didn't marry because
you couldn't forget me?
Do I have to believe this story?
Since you called me out in the
middle of the night to tell me,
it makes it seem true.
Is it really true?
Yes.
I will believe you.
♪ If these crazy days became your days? ♪
♪ If you, like me became broken,
then maybe you would know? ♪
Do you know that I write
in my diary these days?
Because I am moved everyday.
That the guy who I love like crazy
is filling me up like crazy,
this is the first time.
So I write in my diary every day. I
feel like I have to memorialize it.
Every day, I feel so happy
that I could die that day.
♪ I know that you already
gave me your answer ♪
Thank you.
Me too.
♪ I know what that means. But I pretend
to not know, and circle around you ♪
♪ Do you know how I've been lately? ♪
♪ I can't sleep comfortably ♪
♪ I can't swallow anything ♪
♪ While looking at you, I become
more ruined. Do you know that? ♪
♪ Even if I feel like I will die, even if you
say that there is no way you will come to me ♪
♪ Even if I know that you are
only looking elsewhere ♪
♪ I still don't think
that I can let you go ♪
Tell him to come in and
eat before he leaves.
I don't know what fate is between us.
When are you coming back?
I have to see after I get there. I have to
talk to our Chinese associates face-to-face.
We can exchange documents for 100 days,
but it will just cause more aggravation.
You're getting on a plane, so why look
up the weather for the Yellow Sea?
Seize everything.
[Blue Box says: Prosecutors Office]
What is going on?
Lee Chan Soo, he took
everything and ran away.
You got screwed, too. While you were
abroad looking into foreign markets
he got loans all over the place,
and sought investments everywhere.
And Chairman Jang found out and
pulled out his investment.
So he got rid of you (by putting you in prison),
because he was afraid you would find out!
The Chairman says that he is tired,
so you should come back another time.
Chan Soo
He cannot answer his phone. You
will be connected to voice mail...
This bastard.
Just wait until I catch him.
Chan Soo, where are you going?
Oh.
You're not getting on a plane?
Chan Soo!
I really thought our
business was going well.
I thought our product was
selling like crazy, Chan Soo.
Is that product something
that would really be a hit?
Who wants to do real business with you?
I was always going to
swallow the money and run.
- I see you're not in your right mind.
- I'm sorry, but...
Not "I'm sorry, but...," you
should just say, "I'm sorry!"
Oh really? I'm sorry.
Did you manipulate the investors
into filing charges against me?
Are you the one who sent me to prison?
You should have just quietly resigned
from the CEO position, then!
Why did you fight for it so hard,
when you were about to get married?
I fought for it so hard because
I was about to get married!
And the company's name is "Tae Jin." Does it
make sense that Han Tae Jin is the not the CEO?
Oh, CEO my ass.
Is that such a coveted thing, anyway?
You are so clueless.
- That is why you are being dragged all over the place, wiping that Chairman Jang's ass.
- What did you say, you bastard?
Park Do Kyung and you both. You're both like
baduk stones that Chairman Jang is playing with.
One guy is the white stone. The
other guy is the black stone.
But at least that guy got to
experience love. You've got nothing.
You bastard!
Bastard.
Heo Films Institute
Let's go on a trip.
Today?
I can't leave today.
Can't we go on Friday night?
No, let's go.
Alright.
See you later.
What should we do with this?
I'm asking, just in case.
Yes.
Do you perhaps know where I live?
What are you? Why do I keep seeing you?
Why do you keep appearing in my head?
Do you have some kind of
audio surveillance on me?
Even if you did, you shouldn't
know whose voice that is.
What is it?
I thought about it. If I was dying...
I told that guy.
If after dying and coming back alive, he would still marry
you, then come to Seo Hee's wedding. If not, then don't come.
That jerk didn't come!
At the moment I die, if I
look back on this moment,
"This is nothing. No need to hold back."
"Go as far as my heart wants.
Don't hold back and just go."
I'm sorry I couldn't go to the wedding.
There was a situation.
Until I die, I won't leave you.
I won't ask you to forgive me. I am sorry.
No.
This can't be true.
It can't be.
Hae Young, it can't be.
I liked him first. I begged him to like me.
Don't hit him. That is my request.
At least that guy got to experience love.
You have nothing.
You... you cannot even be
compared to Park Do Kyung.
I recorded the song.
I love you.
We've never even taken one photo together.
♪ On an early spring day, you came to me ♪
♪ I knew that I would love forever ♪
♪ On a summer beach,
that happy sand castle ♪
♪ was swept away by the waves ♪
♪ It's okay if you leave me.
It's okay if you forget me. ♪
♪ my heart will always feel the same ♪
♪ Was I the only one who felt this bliss? ♪
Son of a bitch.
♪ Your gaze towards me is heavy ♪
♪ My footsteps that circle
round and round; As always, ♪
♪ I miss you. I need your mind. ♪
♪ I remember that cold day ♪
♪ I was afraid that my trembling
heart would cry alone ♪
♪ Like a dream that fades when
I open my eyes, let me go ♪
♪ If that's not true, then stay with me. ♪
♪ Showing me your shoulders
that have become heavy ♪
♪ You couldn't even let me hate you ♪
♪ In the dazzling bright dawn, ♪
♪ I want to see you. I need your mind. ♪
♪ I remember that cold day ♪
Try living some more.
Live, like this,
and continue to be... so lonely?
♪ Like a dream that fades when
I open my eyes, let me go. ♪
♪ If that's not true, then stay with me. ♪
♪ There is nothing good about crying ♪
♪ But the deeply engraved
marks make me sad ♪
♪ Who knows? Maybe you will return. ♪
[Lee Byung Joon, Sudden
Cancellation of Concert]
♪ That I could not love
you, more, more, more ♪
♪ I regret those past days ♪
♪ I love you, still ♪
♪ I will love you forever ♪
♪ Why are you so cold to me? ♪
♪ Was love something that
changes so easily? ♪
♪ Did I do something wrong? ♪
♪ If so, I am sorry. ♪