Park Do Kyung is a cure-all.
I'm better.
My fever's gone.
You had a tough time.
You did it tough.
Both of us.
We had it tough.
If you hadn't persisted,
we'd be over.
Thank you.
You didn't apologise glibly.
I thought, what if I die?
If I looked back at this time...
I concluded it's nothing.
No need to hold back.
Go as far as my heart takes me.
Don't hold back, just go.
I like that.
"Go as far as my heart takes me.
Don't hold back, just go."
The men I knew held back.
Men who tested the waters.
Calclulating men.
An embarrassed bankrupt
who dumped his woman.
None of them moved me
with their perseverance.
I wanted to be moved.
I'm insanely happy now.
If you hold back again,
- I'll kill you.
- Go ahead.
If you waver again,
I won't forgive you.
- I won't to and fro.
- I will to and fro.
Do it. You can.
E14:  SILENCE ALL SOUNDS EXCEPT THOSE OF LOVE
No...
Where were you? Where were you?
In case you died, we checked
the hospital roof!
Where were you?
I got better and left.
You should've told us
you were leaving!
I didn't see you, so I left.
You healed damn fast.
In the vision you saw,
you two broke up.
But in reality you dated...
Then things changed?
It changed! Hey, Do Kyung! Do Kyung!
Congratulations!
Hey, Park Do Kyung! You won, you rascal!
You changed your fate!
But what's that face?
You're too calm.
Shouldn't you be happier?
I should love her as much
as I can before I leave
to make her happy, right?
Leave? Who's leaving?
Why will you die?
It changed! Why die?!
Hey, that time...you lost her.
So you had dying regret.
But you're with her
so things changed.
Can't your ending change?!
Predestination has flaws
and famed fortune tellers
can be wrong.
They can't predict what
the heart will do or love will do.
Love!
What? Are you worried?
That you might leave your woman?
Now there's only one thing to do.
To the utmost,
love.
I'm so jealous!
What are you up to?
I'm off to work.
I just left home. You?
- I'm off to work. - Scared me!
You surprised me!
Sheesh.
Morning's so nice with you.
Come on. I'll drive you.
I feel I can do anything,
even kill someone.
Keep it together.
Pick someone to kill for you.
Oh, alright, Mom. Don't worry.
Of course I won't.
Okay. I love you.
Rooftop party. Rooftop party...
You're a 3 year-old.
No man dances on waking.
- Ask me why I'm like this.
- Just tell me.
I hit the jackpot!
I had an amazing dream.
Mom said to tell no-one...
Keep this quiet, okay?
Mom said it's truly great.
Awesome!
I don't dream much.
This is my first vivid dream.
What did you dream?
The stars in the sky shone like gold dust.
But they moved into a fish shape.
It wiggled, as if it was alive.
Then it fell from the sky.
- I caught it. - You didn't drop it?
For sure! I caught it in my hands.
Don't doubt me.
Anyway, as I woke from my dream...
how can I explain this?
My heart fluttered so much,
but was sinking too.
I felt I heard God's voice.
"This is your time."
- Sell it to me for $5.
- Crazy bastard.
Don't sell that dream,
not even for a million.
Of course I won't!
I might be Attorney-General.
No table manners!
Let's meet for a good dinner.
I know a great steakhouse.
What would you do without me
taking care of you.
So tell your family
before you start showing.
Oh, did you tell that guy? Mr. Brazil?
What is it?
You don't have his contact info?
Not even his e-mail?
Oh, that jerk, really.
Tell me his name.
I'll find out for you.
- He's not the baby's father.
- What?
- What do you mean?
- He's not the father.
What other man do you have?
What? By chance...
- A one-night stand?
- It's not your business.
Oh my god. A one-night stand,
really?
Mind your own business.
I'll raise the kid by myself.
Only I'll know who the dad is.
It's not that Brazil guy
so don't disturb his family.
Don't uselessly wonder
who the dad is.
And also...
- I'll emigrate. - What? Why?
In Korea,
I'll get tired of being
asked about the dad.
It's tough on the kid.
I'll raise it overseas.
That's too sad to raise it
alone overseas.
Stay here.
You have Do Kyung and me.
We can all help you.
I won't forget you
once I hit it big.
Stay! Where would you go?
- Shut up. Forget it.
- You forget it.
I'm late. Let's go.
We're here.
Noona. See you tonight!
Okay? Stay strong! Fighting!
If I say it's your baby,
you'll pass out.
And we'll feel awkward.
I'll keep quiet.
It's right to go it alone.
Let's keep being
big sis and little bro.
Thanks for your Tae-Mong.
(conception dream)
I'll remember it.
The stars. The fish.
How funny.
You needn't explain.
A man and woman making up
and breaking up
are like sunrise or rain.
We won't break up, though.
Don't break up. Ever.
Congratulations.
[Report Card: Oh Hae Young
1st in class - 2nd in year ]
Oh my goodness...
Oh my! Oh my! Oh my god!
Oh my! She went crazy! Honey!
Hae Young went crazy!
What is it?
She got first in class,
second in her grade.
Second out of 500 kids.
Sure! She'll go to Seoul Uni.
Yes...Sure. Goodbye.
- Who are you calling?
- Sister-in-law.
- That's enough. - Why?
I listened to her brag
how smart Seo Hee is.
It's her turn to listen.
She'd never guess this.
You did this.
It's me. Have you had dinner?
Did Seo Hee get her report card?
No, Hae Young just missed
first place in her grade.
I'll get the door.
Seems our reports got switched.
Tomorrow, I'll give you yours
at school.
Could I get it signed
before giving it to you?
Then I'll get yours signed.
[ Oh Hae Young -
29 out of 38, 218 out of 500 ]
Miss, come in.
I usually place first or second.
But I didn't study this time.
Mom is getting divorced again.
I want to leave this house.
Oh my!
Of course! It made no sense.
Number 27, Oh Hae Young.
B, C, C, B, D, D, D, C, D...
My heart sank, thinking
Hae Young was really second.
- Why'd your heart sink? - Huh?
I know, right?
Why'd my heart sink?
It's okay! Eat!
Why'd they put two
Oh Hae Young's in one class?
You need commonsense.
She usually ranks low.
How'd you believe she came second?
Of course her report was switched.
Hae Young, it was a good laugh.
[ Oh Hae Young ]
- You're that Oh Hae Young?
- Yes.
Your eyes are too big.
It's fine! Study isn't everything!
That's when I got this feeling
that I'd always lose to you.
The feeling I'd never win
over kids raised with love.
It's 'buy one, get one free'.
Take another.
[ Passionate Bottle Opener ]
You thought I was hitting on you?
Thank you. Bye!
Why are you so down?
I know why I can't succeed.
Why?
I can't be a success
because I love you.
Who tried to seduce you?
She must be powerful.
You're quick. How nice for you.
My body has special senses.
It's one big sensor.
I'm proud of you.
It's hard to resist,
even when she offers success?
Good boy.
Here. Eat sausage.
Welcome.
If I could love you
and be successful...
What to do? They're mowing
the barley field tomorrow.
We're rushing there
to finish filming.
- When will they cut it?
- The morning.
Oh, you can't manage a schedule.
I'm sorry.
What will you do?
We'd be glad if you come
but I can't demand it.
You can record the sounds
elsewhere.
Yes. Okay.
Why not just go?
Or else we must go to Go Chang.
That will be cut next week.
They should just leave it.
It's pretty.
- They need to harvest it.
- Wasn't it scenic?
Can we get there and back today?
When will you be back?
Tomorrow?
You're kidding!
I can't see you till tomorrow?
It can't be helped.
Work comes first.
Alright. See you tomorrow.
If I'm alive tomorrow,
I'll see you.
If I die from missing you,
I won't see you.
See if I'm alive tomorrow.
Hanging up.
- Yes. What?
- I need a favour.
What is it?
Send Manager Oh off-site.
- Then let her leave work.
- Don't fool around.
- You can't do it?
- No.
- This once. - Forget it.
I'll be nice to you from now on.
You dog. Heel!
Fooling around...
She said no?
Hello.
Open like this..aah!
Who bought these?
It's on me today.
By the way...
If you want to hang out with me,
I'm only free today.
From tomorrow, I'm busy forever.
How nice you'll be so busy.
Hello, everyone.
Ms. Oh Hae Young?
This is her.
- Ms. Oh Hae Young?
- Yes, that's me.
We're from Western District
Police Station.
- Your phone number is 072-11...
- 1131.
Yes, thanks.
- 1131. Correct?
- Yes, it is.
Due to a telecommunications crime,
you must come with us.
- Officer Go, take her in.
- Huh?
- They're taking her?
- Manager Oh.
You have the wrong person.
I did nothing bad.
We know.
Do you know there are
two Oh Hae Young's here?
- Yes. We know that too.
- I see...
Ms. Oh! Ms. Oh!
- Want to eat this?
- Stop it!
What's with you, punk?
She must've done wrong.
[ Team Leader Kim ]
- Hello?
- Ms. Oh, what happened?
I think someone bad used my name.
- If I get my hands on them...
- Turn off your phone.
Using your phone
ties you to the crime.
Every time you talk on it,
you lose money.
I'll call you later.
[ Power off ]
I lose money just answering?
Yes. Every time it rings.
Jeez. How long's it done this?
How much is my phone bill?
I'll be excused, right?
I won't have to pay it, right?
If there's a crime,
I'm not liable, right?
Hold on! Hold on.
Hey, she talks too much.
This woman is noisy.
Close your mouth.
- How dare she. - Officer Go.
Oh, there's the criminal.
There they are. It's them.
The guy in the cap is mean.
Hello.
Why are you guys so late?
We'll have to hurry.
- How'd you spring her?
- We have our ways.
Good work.
- You scared me!
- Everyone sleep but the driver.
What'd you say? Don't dare sleep!
Even the wind is blowing.
We're fortunate.
Our movie has little dialogue.
The sound must tell the story.
I trust you.
I'm odd. See you at the next site.
Next is the beach scene.
We have no time. Hurry.
We'll go by ourselves. Relax.
We'll get you when we finish.
- Work hard. - Have a nice time!
But is here okay for you?
How about the city
where you can lie down?
Isn't that better?
- You punk! - Your mouth!
Your mouth is trouble! Jeez.
We're going now.
Let's go.
No-one is around. Let's hug.
Here.
It's daytime.
- Let's go.
- So what if it's daytime?
What? What did I do? What?
[ C.E.O. Lee Chan Soo ]
[ C.E.O: Han Tae Jin ]
You waited a while?
Call me first.
I had to go to Customs.
The office expanded.
Things seem better.
Good follows bad.
Soon after your incident,
sales rose in Europe.
After that, all the banks
that wouldn't budge
began throwing money at us.
They wouldn't look at us before
when we begged for loans.
What work should I do?
What can I do?
Take it easy. You just got out.
Did you fix things with Hae Young?
Is it going well?
What's there to work out?
I'll give you back your position.
We went through a lot.
Look after Hae Young first.
Get married.
Don't put work first
and make her sad.
That's the proper order.
Let's go out and eat.
Leave a message after the beep...
Is this Western District Police?
Uh, yes, Oh Hae Young.
Oh Hae Young, yes.
But they said they're
from your station.
They took her with them.
- Those guys aren't ours.
- Th-they're not?
Oh dear...
They weren't detectives.
No. They weren't.
- Can you zoom in on that car?
- Yes.
- They're pros. - Pros?
They hid their licence plate.
W-what do we do?
We're the police.
This is Oh Hae Young's house,
right?
Oh Hae Young was kidnapped
by unidentified men.
So we're in pursuit.
There are two Oh Hae Youngs.
There's another Oh Hae Young
besides my daughter.
- Ma'am. - Ma'am.
- Wake up. - Are you okay?
Ma'am.
A dog barking at dusk
in the country...
I like that sound at this hour.
On a cold winter morning,
people shoveling snow
while I'm under my blanket.
Scrape, tuk tuk.
Around four p.m,
a little boy running on a hill road.
Tak tak tak tak tak.
And...
the sound of a music box.
It sounds pretty.
And there's one sound I want to hear.
Your saying my name.
You've never called me Hae Young.
Hae Young is still her, not me, huh?
Oh, sorry. That's petty of me.
You called her that for ages.
I didn't call you that
because of misgivings.
You might think I'm not
referring to you.
You might believe I'm thinking
of the other Hae Young.
That's true.
But my name is Hae Young.
Just call me by name.
I won't think of the other
Hae Young when I look at you.
So be comfortable.
Call me by my name.
I want a favour too.
No matter what Han Tae Jin
does to me, don't butt in.
Whatever he does,
it's right to take it all.
I was in the wrong.
I even took you from him.
So whatever I go through,
don't get involved.
Don't think of Oh Hae Young
when you look at me.
And let Han Tae Jin punish me.
Let's do that, okay?
And also...
Stop calling me 'that person'.
What's up with that?
What should I call you?
You know, that word...
- What is it? - That.
What is it?
Oppa.
Hae Young.
A little peck?
- Open your eyes. - Huh?
Look up at the stars.
Shall we just die today?
I want to die when I'm happiest.
Park Do Kyung!
Why don't you answer?
I know you're there!
You're surrounded right now!
What kind of love business is this?
In someone's barley field,
you slacked off all day!
Wrap it up quickly.
Come out now.
Come out now!
Oh my, you do look like detectives.
You sure do.
Impersonating a cop
and obstruction of justice.
You're in big trouble.
- Oh... - Please be kind.
- We were helping Park Do Kyung...
Oh, we're in trouble.
Freaking bastards!
Taking my girl and
putting us through hell!
You hussy! I'll break your legs
and lock you in the house.
I can't live because of you!
You add this crazy stunt
to all the others?
When you come home,
I'll kill you!
You bitch!
I'm sorry.
You can have her.
You keep her.
Just give her to him.
Uh, well...
- How is it? Good?
- It's edible.
That makes me sad.
This is pricey. Jeez.
Are you crazy?
Don't eat pineapple in pregnancy.
You don't know much as a mom.
It's all rumours.
Rumour or not, have awareness.
I want to go home, but I'm
not going because they say
not to come and go
in a pregnant woman's home.
Do an Internet search
on the do's and don'ts.
You have time now you can't drink.
Why's she here?
Just a sec.
Oh boy...
Why'd they walk in together?
Why are they here?
What are these women doing?
Don't mind me.
I just came here to eat.
She knows what he is, huh?
I do know. Carry on.
I saw your phone.
I wondered how you 'saved' me-
as "darling" or just my name?
I was MON. Why MON?
But I saw TUE, WED..
THU, FRI, SAT.
Ah, no SUN. Your day off?
How is it seeing Monday
to Saturday together?
It's no fun ending it alone.
Six of us can beat you up.
Wait, seriously?
We can talk about this.
Why do this? This isn't the way!
Cuckoo. Cuckoo.
Don't touch him. Just go.
Why dirty your hands?
You chased him for his status.
- Why butt in, Ajumma?
- I'm Mademoiselle. Miss.
Mon, Tue, Wed, Thurs, Fri, Sat.
I'm Dimanche! (FR = Sunday)
Sunday is mine.
We live together.
- You're married?
- No, no. I'm not...
Here's my advice.
Don't focus on appearance,
job, or money.
Date a man for his character.
Ooh-la-la.
Forget it.
You must have character
to judge character.
Fine. Keep looking at that,
meeting guys like that.
Fighting!
You, seriously!
Oh my goodness...
Unni, you're scaring me.
You fight so girly!
This girl! Hey!
Thank you. You mopped up in one go.
Women need taming by women. Right?
How am I gonna set up my week
all over again?
I'm sorry.
Jin Sang.
When you were in high school,
you were utterly adorable.
You came home crying
when your principal died.
You pushed the cart
around the neighbourhood
for the old trash picker.
That was so adorable.
When you studied with Do Kyung,
you two met me at the bus stop
if it was late.
When I got off the bus,
I'd think, "such lovable boys".
It was really nice.
When I think how you were then,
I liked everything about you.
I don't know why you changed.
Only you know.
Something happened, huh?
Know what, Jin Sang...
You're a very good guy.
Why are you saying this?
You make me want to cry.
So quit all this now.
Marry someone nice.
And also...
Become Attorney-General for real.
I won't tell the kid
you're the dad
but I want my kid's dad
to be a good guy,
a respectable, cool dad.
Two men joined the company
at the same time.
Let's see how one
failed at his job.
- Too much. - I'm full.
A lunchtime workout is good.
Excuse me, Na Sang Gyu.
Na Sang Gyu!
How can you sleep?
Manager, a post-lunch sleep
is great.
You young fellow.
Always sleeping after lunch
got you a belly!
Exercise like I do.
Crazy bitch.
What are they thinking?
Just let them be.
Forcing them apart won't work.
- Your chicken's ready.
- Thank you.
- You don't deliver?
- No, sorry.
Well, good food is worth
any distance. Bye.
Thanks. Bye.
I never dreamed
I'd bail out Do Kyung.
How'd that dame captivate him?
- She's noisy, so loud.
- He dislikes noisy women.
So she must be amazing somehow.
What's her appeal?
Ask him.
Oh my, as if he'd tell me.
Dog Jin Sang, don't drink out of it!
My mouth's as dirty as yours.
Dog Jin Sang, get a cup!
- Get a cup! Get a cup...!
- Nah!
Say it again.
Dog Jin Sang?
You're way younger
yet kicked him?
You dare call him "dog"?
What got into you?
I've said it for years.
His name *Jin Sang makes him
seem a *mess. (pun)
But you add 'Dog',
making it a bigger mess?
Jin Sang is 36.
Will you call him Dog Jin Sang
at 40?
When he's married with a kid,
you'll call him Dog Jin Sang?
You said it heaps.
Give Jin Sang respect.
And you!
Why do you let a younger guy
act rudely to you?
If he steps from close to rude,
warn him with a look or word.
Respect is earned
so earn it!
What's with you?
You mistreat him.
It upsets me. Stop.
You abused him!
- What?! - I said stop!
Oh no, I'm getting a feeling!
It's a bad feeling!
What's wrong now?
It's not true.
It's not! Say it's not!
What's with you two?
Gosh, we never did that!
I didn't do that with you!
Oh no! It makes no sense!
That dream.
That dream!
You're right.
It was a Tae-Mong.
(conception dream)
- No! - Crazy bastard!
- Crazy bastard! - Wasn't me!
No way. Wait! It wasn't me.
It wasn't me.
Hey, who's pitiable?
Who's pitiable?!
For the crime of womanising,
you're sentenced to life with
Soo Kyung. Bang-bang-bang!
Damnit! Sheesh!
Here, grab him!
Hey!
- Come here! Grab him!
- No! Hold on. No!
Dog Jin Sang has no right
to silence!
- No! - Sheesh.
Will it be tough on you?
Will it work?
Hae Young.
Oppa.
-Oppa. - Hae Young.
Mm, Oppa.
Hae Young.
Oppa.
Mm, Oppa.
Hae Young.
I'm sorry.
I know I'm at my craziest.
I won't ask you to forgive him...
nor to forgive me.
I'll take all the blame.
Seriously...
You made a fool of me.
I'm sorry.
Oppa.
- Going somewhere?
- A blind date.
How thoughtless after
I told you I loved you.
But I accepted this blind date
before that.
Sorry.
I'm glad you're going
on blind dates.
- I'm late for the date.
- Sure. Go.
See you next time.
Let's get a drink with
Hae Young some time.
Sure.
The deep love you'd die for...
can be the pain to make
another want to die.
But it can't be helped.
My love is precious.
Okay.
Seriously?
- It's done. - It is?
This is fascinating.
~ Please know I want to be close to you ~
~ If you do, please answer me ~
I want to call him...
to say we're dating.
~ All your hidden, painful scars ~
~ Give them all to me ~
~ So you won't be sad and weary ~
~ Let me be closer to you ~
Hi.
Yes. My father owned this house.
I heard you wanted to buy it.
Do you still want to buy it?
My father passed away.
Let's beg him.
...we ended back
with the right people.
The woman who lived here...
- Meet twice to be polite.
- Which Oh Hae Young...
Too hot!
I burned my hand.
Luckily it's my left hand.
I was braising beef
and spilled it.
I always mess up at new things.
You haven't eaten, have you?
Ta-da!
Get hurt, die.
So things won't change?
What's it all about?