My job takes me to a lot
of places. lt's got its downsides.
I sleep alone. l eat alone.
l'm used to it, though.
I'd like to meet someone...
...but it's tough
when you live out of a suitcase.
l go where I'm told, do what l'm told.
I shouldn't complain.
The work is steady.
The money's good.
But it's not for everyone.
My name's Joe.
This is what l do.
You're late.
Sorry, Mr. London.
They closed Svatopluk Bridge.
You are leaving?
I need the phone.
I can help with the bags.
No, I can handle it.
If you ever come back,
I can use the money.
Goodbye.
I was taught four rules.
One: Don't ask questions.
There is no such thing
as right and wrong.
Two: Don't take an interest in people
outside of work.
There is no such thing as trust.
Three: Erase every trace.
Come anonymous
and leave nothing behind.
Four: Know when to get out.
Just thinking about it means it's time.
Before you lose your edge,
before you become a target.
So you look for the right opportunity.
Nothing too risky.
Get the money and disappear foever.
This is it.
Four hits, one location.
The last job.
Purpose of your visit
to Bangkok, Mr. Vincent?
Holiday.
Bangkok. lt's corrupt, dirty and dense.
All my clients have one thing
in common:
They feed off the people.
There's big money in misery.
Where there's money,
there's competition.
And the guy paying me usually wins.
lt always starts the same way,
just like l was taught.
Secure a safe location...
...somewhere off the beaten path,
where you have privacy.
But you stay invisible too long...
...the human race
starts to look like another species.
So you ventue out. You observe.
And then you return
to your invisible world...
...like a ghost.
Hey, Larry?
-Yeah?
Jesus.
Hi.
-Look at these girls.
-Yeah, what's up?
Hello, gentlemen. How are you?
-First time in Bangkok?
-Yep.
Rolex? Good Rolex, you want?
Yeah, yeah. Look, look, good Rolex.
Watch out, Larry. How much
you wanna bet it's counterfeit?
-Two thousand. Look good.
-No, thanks. No, thanks.
No, no Rolex. Never mind,
never mind. You want girls?
-l can get you girl.
MAN 1 : No.
No girl? How about boys?
-You like boys?
-Oh, no.
You don't like boys, huh?
Hey, how about you, huh, cowboy?
One thousand buy new-car smell...
...satisfaction, money-back,
super-wrapper-pussy guarantee, huh?
Whatever happens in Bangkok
stays in Bangkok.
Wanna find garbage?
Go to a garbage dump.
I look for three qualifications:
They have to speak a little English,
they have to wanna make money...
...and above all,
they have to be disposable.
Do you wanna make some money?
I have work in town. I need some help.
What work?
Pick things up, drop things off.
Maybe some translation.
About a month's work, 2000 a day.
-Dollar?
-Baht.
Bullshit. Eh.
Five thousand, huh?
Forty-five hundred.
Four thousand.
Two thousand nine hundred
and fifty-two fifty, huh?
What do you say? Come on.
We'll round up. Three thousand.
You get paid at the end of the week.
No deal.
Okay, okay. How about half? Half now,
half at the end of the week, huh?
-What's your name?
-Kong.
Kong?
You can keep that
in the wallet you stole.
Be at 21 Samahan Road tomorrow,
7 p. m.
You come alone or you don't get paid.
Yes, boss.
Take off the shades.
Eh?
Glasses. Off.
Keep that with you at all times.
-l have good phone.
-Now you have two.
You answer whenever it rings.
If l call and you don't answer,
you don't get paid.
Time is very important.
If l tell you to be somewhere
and you are a minute late...
...you don't get paid.
You understand?
-ln English.
-I understand.
-You know the Caribbean Club?
-High-class ass.
Ask for a dancer named Aom.
You give her this.
Make sure the X is facing up like this.
She's gonna give you a package.
Don't open it.
-What's in it?
-lt doesn't concern you.
Then you go pick it up.
-l'll find someone else.
-Okay, okay, okay. l do it, l do it, I do it.
Come straight back here.
-You don't stop for anything.
-What if l have to piss?
Huh?
If you ask me one more question--
Then I won't get paid. l know that.
-Okay, I go now, huh?
-Hey.
Take the cell phone.
-You're late, huh?
-Give me the case.
You don't get paid for today.
-Why not?
-Ran from the police.
You told me not to stop.
I do what you say.
"Don't stop. No stop for nothing,
not even for piss."
From now on,
I don't want any more police.
You understand?
The human face can mislead
in a thousand different ways.
But the eyes never change.
l was taught to start with the eyes.
I'm Kong.
Wait, wait, wait.
The elephant.
No, the nose.
You see, pointing down?
Bad luck. No good.
Bad luck for you.
Good night.
I'm checking on a wire transfer.
Account code: 6514346.
Thank you.
Hello.
I have a cut,
and l need some medicine.
Disinfectant.
Do you speak English?
How many?
Um, one.
In the morning? ln the morning.
One.
Before bed.
Two hundred and fifty baht, sir.
-Thank you.
-Oh.
Oh, l have it.
-You're late.
- Sorry, boss.
Don't be sorry, be on time.
What happened to your face?
Some asshole tried to mug me.
Like 20 of them.
But I kicked their asses.
I'm so sorry, boss.
So sorry.
They take--
It's been opened.
Not me. It's them. They broke it.
But I won't let them have it.
I got it back for you.
I don't let them have it.
There's a beer in the refrigerator.
It'll take down the swelling.
Yes, boss.
He's a bad man.
Who?
The man in the case.
You're going to kill him?
- Can you teach me?
-Teach you what?
Everything.
I can help you.
Please?
Show me.
Again.
Good.
That was your first lesson.
Why didn't l kill him?
Maybe it's because...
...and this is strange...
...somehow,
when I looked into his eyes...
...I saw myself.
So l became his teacher.
Best way to defend yourself is to know
when something's about to happen.
So you have to learn
to read your surroundings.
See that man in the red jacket?
What man?
You're living in a city of mirrors.
Store windows, glass office buildings,
polished steel.
Eyes in the back of your head.
Ah.
Eyes at the back of my head,
huh, boss? l got you now, boss.
I'm not your boss. I'm your teacher.
So l call you aajaan, then.
-Like this?
-Yeah.
How is he bad?
This man?
He hurts many country girls.
From the north.
He buy them from their parents
and sell them.
Young girls, man.
Same like devil, huh, this guy?
How many people have you killed?
I don't think about that.
Do the police know who you are?
No one knows who l am.
No one knows where I am.
I know.
-How many jobs in Bangkok?
- Four.
Four.
Two left, huh?
Uh....
Um, I....
Um....
Can you help me?
Could you tell her
that I wanna take her to dinner?
Oh, right.
It's, uh, hot.
That's just....
Just eat it?
It's cooling it down.
It's hot again. lt's really hot.
Oh, the whole thing.
Yeah, that's better.
Oh.
No, you don't pull the trigger.
Squeeze it.
-lt's yours.
-What?
Congratulations.
Hey, ah.
Ah.
What--? Where--?
Okay.
Boss.
-Yeah?
I just left the club.
I think somebody's following me.
Be at the Chao Phraya ferry station
in 20 minutes.
-Okay, boss.
-Wait for my call.
Done, boss.
Okay, listen carefully.
Open the case. Sixty-five, 32, 1 5.
Put the cell phone in the case
and leave it.
The case has returned.
-Yes.
Put your boss on.
-We had an arrangement.
If I see your people again,
I'll kill your wife.
We'll try again.
You, what is your work?
Oh, uh....
Banking.
Ba-- Banker.
-Banker. Yes.
Banker. Banker.
Rain.
Rain...
...is you? Your name means "rain"?
This is your name.
-Bad man?
-Bad for somebody.
Floating market?
Where's Damnoen Saduak?
Ratchaburi province.
Hour and a half by car.
Get some sleep.
We leave early.
Dock the boat up on the right.
Hey, mister, you buy something?
Buy something?
Get us out of here. Get us out.
Dock the boat on the left.
Come on, faster. Hurry up.
Get me over there.
Fuck!
No. No.
Take it to the club.
He same like you, you know.
-Who?
-This guy on TV.
He fight bad guys and helps the poor.
Thai people love him.
He's a very good man.
Same like you, aajaan.
Four: Know when it's time to get out.
Three: Erase every trace.
Boss.
Two: Don't take an interest in people
outside of work.
One: Don't ask questions.
He's a very good man.
Same like you.
Political assassination
wasn't in the contract...
...so there are two ways to go:
Refuse the job and walk away now...
...or do the job and walk away rich.
The truth is almost anyone
can take out a politician.
That's not the hard part.
The hard part is getting away with it.
Kong.
Be here tomorrow at 6 p. m.
Last job?
-Yeah.
-Bad man?
Bad for somebody.
See you tomorrow, boss.
Talk.
Aom?
Kong!
Aom!
He fight bad guys and helps the poor.
Thai people love him.
When the nightmare
becomes real, you don't hesitate...
...you don't think, you just run.
Anyone in the way goes down.
lt's pretty simple:
You're the target now.
Leave the country
or you're going to die.
Why the fuck you care?
He's my student.
--exactly which direction
anybody's running...
...but they seem to be running away
from any possible danger.
Kong.
I had to tell them.
Take her to the street.
I cleared a way.
I got one more job.
Surat?
He's very bad.