This won't work.
It won't?
We have to exceed 80km/h
for the boob touch sensation.
No way!
That's impossible.
No, it can be done...
Sure we're OK?
Yeah.
Are you ready?
Now!
Boob touch sensation!
It's great!
Oh-oh...
DANGER
I love boobs!
Oppai Volleyball
...drawing nourishment from its roots,
striving upward to the light...
60km/h is an 'A' cup.
80km/h is a 'B' cup.
And...
100km/h is a 'C' cup!
100km/h?
Next we'll try it on
Mt Takato's "Hell Hill."
You'll die!
...the new teacher at
our Junior High School.
Miss Mikako Terashima,
a few words, please.
Good morning.
As the Vice Principal said, I'm the
literature teacher, Mikako Terashima.
Nice to meet you.
I dropped by the library
as soon as I arrived here.
I was glad to see it's so nice,
with a lot of books.
I noticed a certain book,
and automatically picked it up.
It's by Kotaro Takamura,
and one of my favorite books,
"DOTEI (The Journey)."
"DOTEI (Virgin Boys)"?!
He write, "In front of me no road
Behind me a road is made."
The teacher I respected most in
junior high told me about this book.
Since then, I've always
loved "DOTEI (The Journey)."
She loves "DOTEI (Virgin Boys)"!
A junior high teacher
loves "Virgin Boys"!
Please enjoy "The Journey,"
it will make you tremble.
She trembles from "Virgin Boys"?!
Try it!
I always keep "The Journey"
at my bedside...
Hey! You guys keep it down!
Control yourselves! Hey!
And finally, I want to say...
Sorry that I caused...
It's all their fault.
But don't stimulate them
so much next time.
I'm very sorry.
Oh yeah, Miss Terashima...
Yes?
The Boys Volleyball Club needs
an advisor, can you do it?
Club advisor?
Sure, I'll do my best.
Thank you.
See that adult program?
No, my parents jumped up
and turned it off.
Last night's title was 'Boob Festival.'
I only saw the title listed.
'Boob Festival'?
Wish I'd seen it.
Who's first?
Rock, scissors, paper.
Big news!
- You scared us!
- Bad timing!
Miss "Virgin Boys"
will be our advisor!
Really?!
Rie, you grew up with Hirata?
Don't mention that,
he's the worst thing in my life.
We weren't actually friends,
our parents were friends.
He said you took a bath together.
In kindergarten!
I wish he'd just die!
Do you have volleyball experience?
Yes, as a student in gym class.
It's OK, I'll just advise, not play.
But I'll persevere
at their practice.
Well, I've never seen them
actually practice.
And 'persevere' means
nothing to them.
A teacher shouldn't say that!
We should teach perseverance.
Sorry...
Why do you follow me?
I'm not, it's my way home.
How about having dinner?
I know a good place.
By the way...
Want to ask me something?
No, I just...
It's just that we both teach
at the same school...
You have a boyfriend?
I have to go.
Liar.
Boys Volleyball Club
Welcome, Miss Terashima!
Thanks.
What are you doing?
We're having a
welcome party for you.
This is your seat!
I'm grateful for the party,
but what about practice?
Practice?!
We have to?
Of course!
Now get changed!
Hurry, get changed!
1, 2, 3, 4,
5, 6, 7, 8.
You guys go ahead.
No way!
You stay up front.
Is everyone warmed up?
Shall we piggyback you?
- I'm not ready.
- Ethnic dance?
The 'Oklahoma Mixer.'
Alright!
Today you'll play the girls.
Go easy on them.
We can't play them!
Why not?
There are only five of us.
See, it's impossible.
Crap! We wanted a match!
Too bad!
If only we had one more!
I'm Yoshiki Jo, two grades below.
I want to join.
I can't join?
I've played since primary school.
You're experienced?!
Good, now you can have a match!
A match? Can I join in?
Great!
Let's play!
Rie, I'll go easy.
No first names!
Caught peeping in tennis again?
Bunch of losers!
It can't be...
Way to go!
- Lunch to go!
- Curry to go!
You're the volleyball club?!
Sort of...
Can't do 'A quick' shots?
What's that?
You mean 'A cup'?
Good one!
'A quick'!
I'm quitting!
Jo, wait!
Back to practice!
Spread out, receive!
OK, let's begin!
How dare 'Follyball Club' play us!
Definitely!
'Follyball... '?
Miss, you're late.
Let's party!
Well, well, please come in!
You won't go after Jo?
First of all, Miss,
let's play...
Twister.
What about volleyball?
We've never played.
We haven't been able to play
since we joined.
There was a scary school
senior called Nakai.
He tormented us until
he graduated.
To 'relieve tension' at matches,
we had to dance in our underwear.
[And to 'improve teamwork,']
We had to draw boob pictures.
So we're called 'Follyball Club.'
We can't use the gym,
the girls have the front court.
We forgot about volleyball
and just have fun.
You don't mind being made fun of?
Not really.
You don't want to win matches?
We can't win a match.
You make no effort, but say that?!
You were at assembly.
"In front of me no road
Behind me a road is made."
"Virgin Boys."
If you try hard,
I'll do anything for you.
Anything?
In that case...
Good idea.
Perfect!
Smart move.
Alright.
If we try hard,
you'll do anything for us?
Yes. What'll I do?
If we win a match
at the next tournament...
If you win?
You will show us your boobs.
Please!
No, I could never do
something like that.
Of course...
Teachers are like that.
What do you mean?
You said you'll do anything,
but you don't mean it.
You're a liar.
I'm not a liar!
I don't tell lies!
You'll show your boobs...
We did it!
You have to!
You promised!
Show your boobs?!
Keep it down!
Why'd you promise them that?
I don't know,
it just happened somehow.
You don't mind?
Of course I mind,
I hate it!
What a stupid thing to ask!
What are you looking at?!
Sorry.
It doesn't matter anyway,
they'll never win.
OK if they lose?
Of course not,
I'm their club advisor!
Sorry.
So what'll you do?
I don't know.
Don't know?
But isn't that a worry?
If rumors of that promise spread
around school, it'll be a big deal.
A teacher shouldn't have said that.
Don't talk like that,
I know it was a mistake!
I'm sorry.
Why am I sorry?!
Of course they should
try hard with no promise.
Right, those guys had no right
to ask for that.
Tomorrow I'll tell them
the promise is off.
Volleyball can be played like that?!
We'll never win playing like that.
We'll never win playing any way.
After Mikako promised
she'd show us her boobs...
How about drugging their lunches?
- That's a crime!
- True.
Maybe a love letter?
How?
Send our opponents a "meet me"
letter on match day,
so they'll skip the game
to meet that girl.
That's it!
Idiots!
Don't miss it!
Sorry!
Are you playing to the death?!
All of you run until you drop!
Show some spirit!
They're not like us.
To begin,
let's ruin their practice.
So many balls!
We've only got three.
Somebody's coming...
Hide!
What are they doing?
Rhythmic gymnastics?
I haven't seen leotards before...
Who are you?!
From which school?
Sorry, I've done nothing.
Miss Terashima...
Yes?
Phone call.
Hello, this is Terashima.
I'm sorry... alright.
How shameful!
What were you doing?
We wanted to see the top team,
Ryuo Junior High.
Then why were you peeping?!
Well, when you see girls
wearing leotards...
Sorry.
You tried to puncture their balls,
isn't that shameful?!
Otherwise we can't win.
That makes it OK to cheat?
You don't try,
you don't work out,
you don't desperately
try to see my boobs?!
Isn't that insulting to me?
You won't get to see easily!
Wait...
That's not what I mean...
What I want to say is...
First, about that promise...
Miss...
We're sorry.
What you're saying is true.
It's not fair.
You agreed to the promise,
we're sorry.
We're sorry!
I didn't agree...
Just like you said now,
we'll work really hard,
and win a match in the tournament
to see your boobs.
Right?
Let's do it! See her boobs!
Miss Terashima,
can't you stop them?
Let's get one more.
Move over!
The tournament's soon.
- For us, too.
- You'll lose anyway.
- We'll win.
- There's only five of you!
We want to have the court
like we used to.
I don't know what you told them,
but it's impossible for them to win.
It's not impossible.
They've started to train hard.
VOLLEYBALL
Make a Winning Team
First, get to know the ball.
Return from your forehead.
Chest slide,
back arched like a shrimp.
Fight, fight, fight...
26.
27.
Keep trying.
28!
Good, that's it.
Come on!
Fight, fight.
Fight, fight...
Sorry, I can't go on.
Boobs!
Boobs! Boobs!
I wonder if Jo will rejoin?
Something may persuade him.
We can't tell him
about the boobs, right?
Wow. Did Jo win all of these?
No, they're mine.
I played in junior and senior high,
and in my company.
But I had to quit
three years ago due to an injury.
My son owes you a lot.
Does he practice hard?
He didn't return from practice yet.
He trains hard.
We just dropped by to
talk to you about volleyball.
You do a great job as coach.
You think so?!
When leaping for the ball,
they land from the chest
to avoid knee injury.
Heading is effective.
Overhand shots made
correctly from the forehead.
Like top team practice.
Teams with that base
are the strongest.
Thank you!
Want my practice drills?
Of course!
Is Jo enjoying the club?
He simply followed me
around when he was little,
and had fun with the game.
I had to quit because of
my injury,
but he kept on playing
because he knew I'd be pleased.
That's how it seems.
So now Mikako is looking for Jo.
I see...
Jo's not like us,
he really loves volleyball.
Some kids will play
even without boobs!
Unbelievable.
Right?
But he had to quit
because we're lousy.
But we've really changed
with the goal of her boobs.
If Jo sees us,
he may change his mind.
Of course!
That's right!
Let's persuade Jo!
Split up and find Jo!
Ebu, did you see him?
I didn't.
- I'll go that way.
- Alright.
Have you seen Jo from
Tobata Junior High?
Jo?
Jo!
Follyball guy.
Let's go.
Jo! Come back to the club!
A Follyball invitation!
I don't care.
That's not true.
Jo, we need you in the club.
I'm not interested in volleyball.
Your Follyball Club
even lost to the girl's team!
Idiots!
- It's a Hawk!
- A 'Bab'!
That's normal?
It's modified.
Way to go!
Stay where you are!
Oh, no!
Who did that?
Come on!
Nakai... now what?
If he's not interested,
that's it.
We have to give up on Jo?
What's up, Ebu?
It's Jo, he...
Lousy jerk!
I'm sorry! Let me off!
Forgive me, I'm sorry!
Nobody trashes my bike!
What'll we do?
Nakai, of all people!
Look at me, loser!
Alright!
What's going on?!
Hirata?
What's with you guys?!
Jo is a junior in the club.
If you want to hit him,
hit us instead.
Are you sure?
What nerve!
You OK, Jo?
My seniors...
Jo, together...
Together?
Do it together.
Yes!
Let's look together.
Look?
At her boobs.
Boobs?
How'd you get hurt?
It's nothing.
Don't say it's nothing...
Miss,
Jo is back in the club.
Really?
Yes! Glad to be back.
Let's go.
Jo, teach me how to serve.
Left front attacker, Jo.
Right back is Kusunoki.
Practice these positions.
Let's play!
Fight!
Fight! Fight!
Boobs! Boobs!
Enough of that shout.
Miss, aren't you hot?
Not at all!
Ebu, keep trying!
Good time, 31 minutes!
Let's see how you do.
Way to go.
[815]
[GIRLS BO YS]
Closer together.
Iwasaki!
Underwear's showing.
Ready, 'cheese.'
Weren't the boys great!
Don't you think so?
I agree!
They may have their first win.
What do you mean 'may'?!
They've really developed.
They will win!
Right.
I hope they do win.
I hope they don't!
I'll be in trouble.
That's true.
So losing is better.
Losing is no good.
Which is best?!
I don't know anymore.
But...
But... they're trying so hard.
I can't go back on
my promise now.
So you'll keep it?
No way!
I give up.
If those boys keep trying...
Maybe I can tell...
About what?
Nothing, forget it.
[Regional Junior High]
[Volleyball Tournament]
The other team's late.
Sorry, only two players showed up.
- I understand.
- Sorry.
As the opposing team is absent,
the match goes to Tobata.
We did it!
A win!
Miss, we're waiting.
What?!
Miss, you promised us.
You haven't won yet.
- A default win is great.
- Right.
The rules say it's an official win.
But isn't this unfair?
What's wrong with it?!
You say that to avoid
showing your boobs.
That's not true!
You said it's not fair.
That's not it.
It's because
you didn't really win.
What's wrong with that?
Wait a minute!
She's right.
Is it really winning if we don't play?
Winning is winning.
Don't you want to see?
I want to feel right about seeing.
Seeing feels right!
I want to see her boobs by
winning with you guys!
That's true.
She won't feel right
showing her boobs with no win.
Right, Miss?
That's right.
Alright, let's win the next one,
and see her boobs properly!
Use this spirit to win Round 2!
Let's win together
and see her boobs!
Ryuo JH Nogata JH
Amazing.
We play them in Round 2...
You may be able to win.
They are stronger
on a one to one basis,
and their level of play is higher.
But that can't be helped,
they've played more.
So it is impossible?
But all of you are growing now,
with amazing strength.
I think you can win
with that strength.
Round 2 is after two weeks.
I think that now you
are able to beat them.
But...
- Hello.
- Seven popsicles.
But against Ryuo!
We can't beat them.
Impossible.
Everybody cheer up, here.
Thank you.
Let's go.
Listen.
I'll say this just one time.
Do your best...
to see my boobs.
Yes!
Ready...
Boobs! Boobs! Boobs! Boobs!
Please come this way.
I'm sorry to be late.
What's up?
I was nearby on business,
and thought of you.
I see...
Champagne?
Please.
You were looking for this.
It was in my stuff.
You found it!
But I quit smoking.
Thank you.
You finally quit...
Yeah. It seems that
you're still teaching?
I'm glad you kept at it.
You all like
Sheena & The Rokkets?
- Yeah.
- Great!
- I love them.
- They'll play live soon.
I want to see them!
Let's go see them together.
Great!
Going to a rock concert
just before exams...
wasn't your suggestion,
was it, Miss Terashima?
It couldn't have been.
Well...
It wasn't my idea.
Good morning.
Liar.
You must have been surprised
that I didn't want to go to school.
No, I'm just sorry that
I didn't listen more thoughtfully.
It's OK.
Are you working hard?
More or less.
I have to, for the new staff.
We stopped dating,
but still like each other, right?
Actually,
I wondered if we could try again.
I came to ask that.
Right, you bought all that
ice cream the day before!
It was melting from the power failure,
we tried to eat it all!
I ate three of them!
Oh yeah, I found a photo.
Which photo?
A really funny one.
Which one?!
Well, maybe I shouldn't...
Which one? Show me!
Not this one!
Throw it away.
No, it's mine!
- Give it to me!
- No way.
Boobs! Boobs! Boobs!
Stop!
They're not...
These boobs are not just mine!
They're everyone's dream!
Sorry.
I'll go now.
I'm sorry.
What am I doing?!
You're hot, hot lady!
You're hot, Mikako!
Nakai!
You guys are having fun.
That's why you fought me?
Yes.
Don't worry, I won't tell.
Boobs?
Good teacher.
Right!
You guys!
If you lose now, you're wimps!
Right!
Thank you!
Just as I suspected...
We're going to win!
Good afternoon!
Please change here.
Really use this
intensive training camp.
Yes!
Start with stretching.
Right, we'll do our best!
Get started.
Let's go and stretch!
Thanks so much for helping.
It's a pleasure to do it.
1, 2, 3, 4,
5, 6, 7, 8.
Other leg.
You're really working hard.
Of course!
Well? Don't you want to win
even without that boobs promise?
Not a bit.
Of course not.
It's for your boobs.
I see...
Good pass, way to go,
nice receive.
Good, rotate.
Next!
Good, next!
Sleeping.
They must be worn out.
Thank you.
Is that the training schedule?
It's just... you know...
It brings back memories of
overnight school stays.
Really? I didn't join any clubs
in junior high, so don't know.
Staff Room
Everything OK?
No problem.
What?! You shoplifted?
I was a too-average kid.
I wasn't particularly good at
studying or sports.
A school friend asked me to do it.
I didn't want to, but if I said no
I'd seem too straight.
I only did it once, but...
got expelled.
But it just meant
self-study at school for a week.
The teacher in charge of me
was Mr. Harada.
This seems to have been
forgotten by a student.
But any book will do,
so read it and write a book report.
Mr. Harada didn't scold me,
lecture me, or comfort me.
[He just handed me a]
[Forgotten book for a report.]
That's all.
It seemed boring,
so I just drew doodles instead.
But that's the only way a kid like me
could show defiance.
Here, it's your final day.
Then I happened to see a poem
called "The Journey."
[In front of me no road]
[Behind me a road is made.]
Terashima,
I entered your report "The Journey"
into a writing contest.
Literary Writing Contest
It was the first time I was
given an award,
so I was so happy.
[First Prize]
[Mikako Terashima]
People always hold their heads high
when walking forwards,
[First Prize]
[Mikako Terashima]
Unlike my nervous glances in the
store while shoplifting.
They never hang their heads.
I also want to look forwards.
I want to find my own road.
[I'm sure that I can leave]
[My own road behind me.]
[I think the judges chose]
[Me due to my frankness.]
I was so happy that...
I visited City Hall daily
while it was displayed.
Maybe you should be a teacher?
Of Japanese literature,
you've got it in you.
I'd never thought about
what I would do,
but I felt as if that road
had opened before me.
And so...
if I truly become a teacher,
I want to go and tell Mr. Harada.
I see...
Then why not go now?
I can't go.
I haven't truly become...
I think you are
an excellent teacher.
I believe that.
Thank you.
My first time to watch it.
You're still such a kid.
Nosebleed...
Already?
"Adult Secrets"!
"Special Edition"!
"Fishing Special"?!
[The popular fishing]
[Special you've waited for!]
[Filefish, yellow jack,]
[Amberjack, mackerel,]
All fighting for your cast
in the best places!
Those boys have
tried hard lately.
I guess so...
They're looking good...
Not at all!
You know why they try so hard?
It's disgusting!
Why?
Boobs?!
Our secret hiding place.
Previous seniors all
hid things here.
Carry on this volleyball tradition!
Yes!
Game time's getting closer.
I'm glad we joined volleyball.
It'll leave us good memories.
This spirit will also help for exams.
Definitely.
I'll take over our shop
after graduating.
No high school?
No.
Actually, I'II...
work at our ironworks.
Is that so?
It may be the last time
to do something together.
Maybe thanks to Mikako?
A great memory to end it.
Yeah.
Let's win!
Let's see Mikako's boobs!
We owe it to her to look
at her boobs.
You'll be the only one
left next year.
Beat Ryuo,
and members will join.
That's true.
VICTORY!
Excuse us.
What's wrong?
Don't know...
An odd rumor is spreading,
Miss Terashima.
If the boys volleyball team
wins the regional meet,
you have...
you promised to show them
your breasts, so they try hard.
Is that actually true?
Miss Terashima?
Please answer.
Miss Terashima.
Actually...
It is true, but not true.
What does that mean?
Us boys in the club
just made that up.
She would never agree to that.
That was just a joke, wasn't it?
Right!
Is that true?
I just said it was a joke!
Shut up!
I asked Miss Terashima.
Miss Terashima.
In fact I...
did make that promise.
I knew it!
Miss?!
I'm sorry,
but I never want to lie again.
It's inexcusable.
So that's what happened?
I was so impressed by
their perseverance.
But we were deceived.
Their perseverance is real!
They practice every day.
No more excuses.
It's so disappointing.
This is a terrible problem.
VICTORY!
[A FOLLYball Club]
[Is a FOLLYball Club!]
I told a friend about it.
And then it spread like this.
Oh? Don't worry about it.
But...
you shouldn't have promised that.
Wait! Miss Terashima!
Were you fired?
Yeah.
I have to stay away from the club.
It can't be...
Thanks for everything.
We won't be talking again.
Why not?
You shouldn't meet me.
Thank you so much.
Volleyball Tournament
Show some spirit!
This is from Miss Terashima.
Match 3,
team advisors please meet.
Right.
Do a good warm up.
Mr. Harada,
as I expected,
I couldn't do it.
I made another mistake.
I'm sorry to have to tell you this.
I'm sorry.
And who are you?
His former student?
That's right.
But not in his class.
I'm Terashima.
Terashima?
I shoplifted in third year,
and Mr. Harada...
I keep planning to organize it,
but just leave it as is.
What did you tell my husband?
Mr. Harada inspired me
to become a teacher,
but I keep making mistakes.
You became a teacher?!
Yes.
Because of my husband?
If he knew,
he would be so pleased.
During the time you had to do
self-study for shoplifting,
he'd stand in front of
that bookshelf every morning,
and fret over which book
he would take to you that day.
"The Journey"
You mean...
it wasn't a book
someone had forgotten?!
He wondered what book
would give you strength.
Maybe this one, or maybe not,
perhaps it's not the one.
He did that every day.
Sir...
He always wanted
students to realize that...
the road they should follow
is right in front of them.
It would be great if
you could...
teach your students that
their own road is in front of them.
My...
students.
Don't worry.
Shout and play!
Almost! Nice try.
Huddle!
Gather here.
Remember what we practiced,
and use all of it.
Let's do it!
As in practice!
We can take this set!
Get the first point.
Get this point. Come on!
Hey, you guys!
Time!
Who said I'd break my promise?!
I didn't say that!
Even if fired from Tobata,
I'm still your teacher!
Right!
Teacher...
Tell us once more!
Listening?
Do your best to see my boobs!
Yes!
Boobs! Do it!
Alright! Go for it!
Shout out!
Boo...
Oobs!
Did it!
Boobs!
They're great!
Good! That's the way!
Nice one, Ebu!
Jo!
Nice boobs!
See that?! See that?!
Keep it going,
take the third set!
Idiots!
Total member change.
1st string.
That was the 2nd string?!
It doesn't matter.
Mikako's boobs are on our side.
Yeah, we will win!
Boobs! Boobs! Boobs!
I'm very sorry.
Why apologize?
You know... that promise.
It's no big deal.
I knew about it all along.
The reason doesn't matter.
They learned how
great it is to persevere.
Isn't that enough?
Go and be with them now.
They're waiting.
Everyone...
We lost.
Damn!
Crap!
Everyone stand, come on.
Stand up.
You too, Jo.
Chests out.
All of you tried really hard.
You looked great.
That was excellent.
Thank you.
Miss!
Miss Terashima...
Yes?
What will you do now?
I'll continue to teach.
I got fired, but realized that
this is all I can do.
I resolved to improve.
Is that so?
Tell me your new
phone number when you get it.
Why?
You ask me why?
Just joking, I'll tell you.
Thank you.
Those guys...
Miss!
Thank you, Miss Boobs
Miss! Miss...
Thank you!
Miss, thank you!
Boobs are too big!
Take care!
Become fine men!
Thank you.
Miss, thank you.
Miss Terashima,
we don't know how you feel,
[but we don't regret]
[Losing that game at all.]
[Because we lost,]
[We could gather at your breasts.]
We had practiced that
on Ebu in case we lost,
and found good places.
Thanks for the wonderful sensation.
From the Boys Volleyball Club.
AYASE Haruka
as TERASHIMA Mikako
AOKI Munetaka
as HORIUCHI Kenji
KIMURA Haruki
as HIRATA Ikuo
TAKAHASHI Kento
as KUSUNOKI Yasuo
TACHIBANA Yoshihiro
as JO Yoshiki
HONJO Masaki
as SUGIURA Kengo
MEGUMI Ryuichiro
as EGUCHI Taku
YOSHIHARA Takuya
as IWASAKI Kouhei
NAKAMURA Toru
as JO Kazuki
Based on: Oppai Volleyball (Linda Publishers)
By MIZUNO Munenori
Screenplay by: OKADA Yoshikazu
Music: SATO Naoki
Executive Producers:
OKUDA Seiji / HORI Kenichiro
Co-Executive Producer: SUGANUMA Naoki
Production: HORIBE Toru
Producers: FUJIMURA Naoto / AKASHI Naomi
Co-Producer: KOKUTA Masahito
Cinematography: NISHIMURA Hiromitsu (J.S. C)
Lighting: MIYOSHI Akiyo
Sound Recording: YANAGIYA Fumihiko
Production Designer: KITAYA Takeyuki
Theme Song: "Kojin Jugyo"
by Caocao (avex trax)
Production: ROBOT
Production Companies:
NTV / avex entertainment / ROBOT
Warner Bros. Pictures Japan
TOEI / HORIPRO / YTV / VAP
STV- MMT - SDT - CTV - HTV - FBS
Directed by HASUMI Eiichiro
2009 "Oppai Volleyball" Film Partners