We had great fun in Paris.
30 years I've waited for it.
And now - moving to the country!
- Come on! For 24 hours only!
But I can't drive you to Odeon
every day!
- Especially not with your arthritis!
- Where is my suitcase!
Downstairs, in the car
- As usual, dad?
- As usual, my boy!
- Ready!
- Yahooo! Youpie!
- Youpie!
- Careful! Attention! And hop!
Uff
And hop!
You promised to bring me back,
'cause in 24 hours they'll drive me nuts!
- I have had it with these Buteaux.
- Oh! But not with the little Buteaux.
- They are sweet, the little Buteaux.
- I have had it with them too.
Oh boy, did you become grumpy!
- Hold still, don't move
- Like you had to ask!
And.. voila!
Damn seat! Always gets out of order!
Ready to go!
You have eaten well, huh?
Careful with the little legs.
Jean-Philippe Duroc of Advocacy of Paris.
I'm here to see my client Martial Gaulard.
- Right, here you are.
- Thank you.
- He's not in the same cell anymore?
- No, he's in the section for condamned to death.
Here it's the same as in Lyon...
You hear this?
- Our world in falling apart right before us.
- As for yours, we could get by without it.
- Here.
- How's Gaulard doing?
- He's fine.
- Is he nervous?
Would you be nervous in his place?
- Does he mention me sometimes?
- No.
Well, sometimes he says
stuff in his sleep.
Ah. And what exactly?
- Huh?
- What exactly does he say?
- "Bastard, imbecile lawyer!".
- Oh, my...!
- And sometimes he rattles his cell.
Here. Shall I open it for you?
- No, I, I, I'd like to talk to him...
through the window.
- All right.
Martial Gaulard, I have some
bad news for you.
Your appeal for reconsideration
was rejected. But, but!
Ha! But we've still got petition
for pardon!
Petition to president!
Where did I put it...
And do you know whom I'm meeting
tomorrow about your case?
General de Gaulle!
Oh! Sir! Sir!
You gangster, bastard!
- This will cost you a lot!
- How much more can it cost me, huh?
I am sentenced to death,
they won't cut my head off twice!
Hello! Yes, right away.
Come, come quickly! Get up!
Hurry up! Let's go!
Hey! Don't leave me here! Open up!
Thanks, Loulou.
Where are the keys?
- Inside, Dupuy's got them.
Get other keys and grenades
and gas masks!
Help! This man is hurt!
Not assisting...
in helping is prosecuted!
Don't shoot! You only make
your case worse!
- What are you waiting for?
Are you ever going to open this door?
- Excuse me...
- Good-bye!
Don't leave! I'll protect you!
They don't have a right to shoot!
But it's my car, isn't it?
Stop! Stop right now, Gaulard.
You are making your case really bad!
Gaulard, I'm begging you!
Oh goddammit!
You are innocent, Gaulard! I know it!
Don't behave now like you are guilty!
I am your lawyer! I will protect you
even against your will! Come back to prison!
I will explain everything on your behalf,
second turn to the left! Don't miss it!
Oh, oh no!
I said stop! I said stop!
Holy mother of God! Careful!
Beat it right now! Get off!
I was sentenced 'cause of you!
I have had it up to here with you!
Turn the volume up!
- ...security guard hurt by Jean-Philippe Duroc.
It is confirmed that Mr. Duroc
who is known for his leftist ideas...
Ah, you are a leftist on the top of it!
...instigated the mutiny...
that started in the prison this evening.
- But they are crazy! It's not true!
...says Rudy le Rouge. Duroc, after having
seriously injured guard Dupuy,
succeeded in making his client escape...
- Stop, I have to explain them everything!
Because you believe they will believe you?
Holy Christ, look!
Excuse me, Miss, for appearing in this outfit.
- How much is it?
- 100 francs.
- 100 francs, it's way too much!
- What's your problem now?
- What's my problem? it's my money!
Zip it and get in the car. It's been a year
since my last time! Start the car!
- Let's go to a hotel, it's more comfortable.
- I am sorry, haven't got much time!
Get on the rear seat!
It's my car, just so you know!
It's not a Lonely Hearts club!
- No, not in my car!
- Go, start it, drive!
It's them, go quickly!
Here Rocheteau. Suspects located.
Following them. Roger.
- The cops! Speed up, for God's sake!
- I can't! I'm at full throttle!
- That's it! They will catch us now!
- Oh no, they won't
Say, aren't those boobs lovely?
- Idiot, imbecile, dumbass!
- You want a piece of me now?
But it's can't be.
But it can't be.
Excuse me, Miss.
What on earth is this?
There was a little accident close to Lyon.
I've lost them!
It happens, huh? I will need barricades
in 50 km periphery!
I don't care about the protesters!
We can not let the whole country fall to pieces
simply because the students have gone crazy!
- What do we do with this?
- Get her out of here, for crying out loud!
Enough with this, basta, go, go!
- Go!
- Trying, but...
Go!
- Fine, I'm outta here!
- I am not going to leave my car!
Hold on, wait for me!
I am not going to leave my car!
- Should have thrown you out!
- Come on, do it now.
- You won't make it far on the stolen truck.
- I'm going straight to Paris!
- And stop bugging me about your old man.
- My father is sick, he is 76 years old.
I can see him right now, tiny person,
with twisted gray hair!
Yeah, yeah, real son of a bitch,
like all the bourgeois!
My father worked hard all his life to make
me what I am today!
Here we are, the guy started with nothing much
only to achieve nothing special!
Small wonder you are a leftist!
Shut it, Gaulard, you don't know the first thing
about my life! But I know all about your!
I studied all your records of petty excuses
and false pretenses!
Tearjerking drama! Born in Indochina, then..
Algeria, Haschish, H.L.M.,
it's so annoying... soldier... sweat.
First of all, take off your clothes!
They bring back bad memories.
No, I'm cold. Stop the car, I need to
go and call my father!
I was getting frozen all night in that hangar.
Give me back my pants!
Get them off, I'm telling you!
It's no good parading like this.
You are disgusting, Gaulard,
Like... like all the co.. cons.
Why stutter now? You are not in the court!
- Where are you going?
- To phone.
- Ah, right, your Chinese girl.
- She's half-Vietnamese.
- Ok, what is the number of your dad?
- 28-30 in Auxerre.
Could you bring me a cup of coffee too?
- Hello, everybody.
- Hello.
- Can I call from you?
- To Mecon?
- No, to Paris and then to Auxerre.
- Patron, fill me up!
And two coffees to go.
Hello, I'd like to speak to Medicis 41-17
in Paris, please.
Telephone.
Hello?
- Do not hang up. Bach-Yen!
- Yes, mother.
- Phone for you.
- Who is it?
- I don't know.
- Hello?
- Is it you, Blanche-Hirondelle?
- Martial, but where are you?
I escaped!
Incredible, huh!
What the hell is taking him so long?
Dammit!
- Officer!
- Yes? What is it?
- Same truck as was stolen from Caluire.
- The number is dirty,
can't see anything
Let's go and take a look.
- I love you and I want you.
- Me too, I want you.
I want to see you.
Martial! Pst!
- What time will you come?
- If all goes well, I'll be there by evening.
Let's try this.
This is it, the same number!
Hey! Jean-Philippe, wait for me,
I'm over here!
What the hell are you doing?
Hey, open it!
Stop.
Stop!
Martial! Martial! It cannot be...
Martial, Martial...
Help! Help! Over here!
Martial, help...
Ah! What is it...
- Don't ever try this again.
- But what on earth did I do?
- I don't give a shit bout you, but truck...
- Hey, a helicopter!
Shit, a helicopter,
ah, a helicopter, come!
- A what?
- There, there!
Hop on and close the door!
Climb, climb!
After, after them, for God's sake,
we will loose them!
- They are falling behind.
- Come, let's hide there.
- Don't adjust behind me.
- Oh!
- Shh! The chain.
- Huh?
The chain, get on, get on!
- Here, catch!
- Careful, it's your pardon!
Shit, my pardon could swim away from me.
Come on, in the name of God!
You've got the pardon?
Pass it over.
Didn't get too wet.
- This is it, the pardon of president?
- Yes.
If he signs here, you - oh!!
But if he signs here...
Show it to me!
"Decree: The President of the Republic,
in accordance with the constitution...
as of October 4th, 1958 declared:
the death penalty is commuted to
life imprisonment.
The President of the Republic,
bla, bla, bla, bla... decided...
to let justice take its course.
To kill or not to kill.
- Strike the unnecessary!
- Anyway, I am against the death penalty!
- Yeah, and I am for it.
- But you're crazy!
- Have you already seen such an execution?
- No.
But it's monstrous!
By early-morning light they wake the poor
guy up to shave his neck...
a glass of rum, cigarettes...
- Right, cut it. You are too descriptive.
Oh! I'm sorry, Gaulard. Excuse me.
I'll tell you one thing!
The guy who shot the accountant...
- It really wasn't you?
- I swear! But this son of a bitch
who let an innocent person to be sentenced
in his place, if I ever get him,
I'll skin him alive, take my word for it!
- Of course, law of your environment...
eye for an eye, the vendetta!
- The only way to calm people down.
Look at those little cons on
their barricades today
I would simply send the tanks,
and you'd see that in no time...
You know who you are, Gaulard?
A poor fascist who missed his calling.
- Oh, and what is it, my calling?
- To be a cop!
The helicopter! Jump! Quickly! Hide!
But where's the helicopter?
The helicopter?
What helicopter? Oh, I thought I saw one.
Remember this - all the cops are full of shit!
Better help me, instead of your
stupid jokes!
Gotta find you some clothes.
You can't parade like this anymore.
You look like a drag queen
in mourning! And you're not even embarrassed.
Surely you don't think that I will ever put
this on? It's disgusting,
we don't even know who wore it before.
- Come on, come on, big mouth!
Voilà! Quite different already.
It's funny, you remind me of someone,
but I can't remember who.
Are you hungry? We could buy something
from the farm over there...
Why do you always want to buy things,
when all you have to do is snatch?
Come, follow me.
Snatch and snatch all the time!
Hey, Jeannot, you're crazy! Stop it!
I've been watching you for 10 minutes,
I can't hold it anymore!
Stop it, Gustave will be back
any minute now!
No. No!
Yes.
- What are you doing?
- Non of your business...
Anybody there? Hey!
- Come on, undress...
- But we aren't going to steal!
You're not stealing, I am.  I'm
returning your suit and taking this one.
Give me my purse, I will leave some money
on the table.
Hide, quick!
Là, là, là!
...helped to escape his client,
Martial Gaulard,
a dangerous criminal who was
sentenced to capital punishment.
Marguerite, say, I can't find my moto!
- Where did you leave it?
- Over there. Someone stole it!
It's Gustave.
Go quickly! Hide!
- Cuckold!
- Me?
No, I am a cuckold. You are cheating on me!
Everyone in the village says
that you are sleeping with Jeannot!
- Who says it? Your mother,
your sisters, your girlfriends? Let me go!
- What are you doing in this bathrobe?
I was cooking you dinner, after having
milked your cows and cleaned your house...
He's there, I'm sure of it!
I can feel it, I know it!
- Who?
- Jeannot!
- If I catch him, I'll strangle him!
- Of course! He's in the wardrobe!
I hid him when I heard you were coming.
Come on, open it!
- No, it's ok.
- What are you waiting for? open!
Hello, Madame.
Bastard! Bitch!
- Can't you see it's not Jeannot!
- Who is this idiot?
I don't know hime, I swear!
Do you believe I could cheat on you with...
a guy like this?
- Pst! Pst! It's true.
I swear! I am Master Duroc,
lawyer of the Advocacy of Paris,
- here's my dress!
- My gun!
I'll convince you, you are talking to a
lawyer! Reconsideration of the facts...
I'm telling you, you're talking to a lawyer!
Let's recap the facts...
You shouldn't get so upset! Just don't
come home without warning next time!
- Bitch!
- I don't know him!
No!
- Jeannot...
- No, Gustave! I love you!
I don't know any of those men!
Nor Jeannot! I don't know him either!
Catch!
Bastard! Scum!
Stop it, you're completely crazy!
Get out of here!
No, stop it!
- Hey you, wake up!
- What's going on?
- Look here, we're out of gas!
- We should find a gas station!
They are all closed, we've already passed
many. And we don't have money!
- How so? And where is my purse?
- You left in your pants on the farm.
If only we could find a working station,
I could always shake the owner a bit.
- Listen to me, Gaulard!
- Yes, Maitre.
You're a bad thief, a very clumsy one!
Shake the owner...
- You don't even know what you're doing.
- Enough crying over your purse!
- You wanted to pay the cuckold anyway!
- I want to get out
- I can't stand this anymore!
- You will get out, hold on a bit!
- But what are we going to do?
- This.
...
- Perfect!
- I swear to God he is crazy..
Come here
I think I have a plan
You have, you really have an idea?
Hold it.
Voilà! There!
Hey, are you taking me for a clown?
- No.
Hold you shirt.
- Now the panties.
- Oh, no, no, not my pants!
- Good, are you good at acting?
- I am a lawyer!
Ah, right, I've heard something bout it.
chose. Mind if I clean my hands?
Move over, you're so dirty!
Voilà. You will lie down there.
- May I ask why?
- Lie down... do as I say!
There, head like this. Mouth open,
it's more spectacular.
Make a grimace.
- Can you be more tragic?
- Hold on... Ah!
Good, that will do. I'll explain now!
Somebody will stop when they see you.
He will get out of his car.
He will come up to you. You don't move.
- You fake being dead.
- Maybe I should hold my breath too?
Right. He will lower himself to you
to check if your heart still beats.
And here I come from behind and...
- You tap him on the shoulder...
asking to give us a ride.
- Voilà! You got it!
- Swear you won't do him any harm!
- Me? I couldn't harm a living thing!
- That's what frightens me!
- Quit talking now.
- Ok, you don't move, you got it?
- Yes...
I'll be over there!
There's a car!
Not helping a person in danger!
Article 63 of the Criminal Code
Bastards, egoists! No, there're
no more good people in this country!
They'll let you die like a dog on
the side of the road!
- Did you get his number, Gaulard?
- Here's another one! Quick, lay down!
Lay down, the grimace, the head, voilà!
- Hey, and what's that?
- Not your business.
- Tell me, Gaulard, what if I lie down
right across the road?
You're insane. They will run you over!
Hey, this one will stop for sure!
Stretcher, quickly!
Go, go!
It's serious, be careful with him!
He's got a terrible look.
Yes, go gently. Good.
Go, go, be on the way!
I am scared to death! Let's return to Paris,
Jacques, I have a bad feeling.
Calm down, Gisèle, Sansonnet passed
yesterday without a problem.
- They called me from Geneva this morning.
- They weren't risking too much:
2 fake Rembrandts and one green Picasso.
Caviar, you didn't take the caviar?
I took the lobster and foie gras.
- I hate foie gras.
And the crustaceans give me urticaria.
Always the same selfishness!
Come on, war is war, it's revolution
out there, do not forget!
Fauchon is still open!
Oh!
- Ah! If this happens at the Swiss border,
we're as good as dead!
- It's French border that is dangerous.
French don't want their gold to leak
to Switzerland!
- Plug the toaster into the outlet.
- That'll teach me to let you fix something...
50 golden bars! You couldn't be trusted
even with the metal!
- This too will have to do somehow. Jacques!
- What now?
- It feels like something is there.
- 200 bricks! Obviously, it's hard!
- They won't feel anything.
- Jacques, my jewelry, where is it?
- They were there on the front seat!
- Calm down, I put them down.
Stop saying "calm down",
it's becoming annoying!
Who is harassing me for 3 weeks now
with his revolution, who closed his factory..
out of fear it would be taken,
who's afraid of the workers, unions,
of the leftists, rightists, centrists?
- I'm not scared of anyone, Madame.
- And you know why? I bought everyone!
- Not the customs.
No, not the customs!
Here is RTL Information,
edition of the mid-day
presented by Jean-Pierre Farkas.
- During this last weekend ...
of May 68 with no lottery, gas
and cigarettes,
the French will follow on the radio
the negotiations ...
which started at the hotel
du Chatelet, Rue de Grenelle
between unions, employers ...
and Georges Pompidou.
A Memorandum of Understanding was presented
but more likely it will be rejected...
by the vast majority of the strikers.
They discussion is still on-going,
but the first movement of workers
was more like, "No, that's not it..."
Did you hear this?
We give them this, and they want that!
They will surrender everything!
They will give them all!
Our France is over,
Our France is over.
Eat your pâtée, Lulu, and you too
Gisele, and stop it.
With your mania for bronzing,
you'll get wrinkles before your age!
- Leave me alone! We didn't go to Cannes!
Ah! Get the thief!
What is it, Gisèle, the thief!
Ah! Jacques! Stop him, get the thief!
Murderer!
Hold the thief!
Help!
Ah! Ah! We should inform the police!
- But we can not!
They will find the gold and money
that I didn't declare for the taxes!
And do you know how much
will be the fine?
10 times what I have stolen!
I mean, what was stolen from us!
- Thank God, I kept my jewelry!
- Hold on! Come Gisèle,
Try to contact Dijon, the hospital.
We've got severe damage here!
Ok. Hello, hello,
give me Dijon, please.
- Chauvin, here is the pharmacy.
- Maybe we should make him a transfusion.
He keeps bleeding!
Power to the people!
Look what they've done to him!
Murderers! Assholes!
C.R.S: SS, C.R.S: SS! C.R.S: SS!
Shit!
The fascists in Poteau!
- Martial!
- Jump!
- I will dirty the seats!
- To hell with the seats, get on!
- Here! Dirty the seats he will!
- Well, you know...!
Find me something posh to go with Bigogne.
One second. A-ha!
Ties from Hermès,
pull-over from Christian Dior, nice, huh!
Shoes from Weston.
Nothing but "must-have"!
That means something posh,
something that everyone wants to have!
For example: in cars
Rolls is a "must-have"
St. Tropez is also a "must", Meûgève...
I got it: Prison is not a "must-have"
- No, it's not a "must-have"
- Sometimes, health is a "must-have"
- Look at that, shoes in crocodile leather!
Oh no, monsieur!
We don't wear crocodiles in 1968!
- Oh yeah! It's not "must-have", is it?
- Exactly, it's more like 30-s
You've got a taste of a nouveau-riche!
I've got a taste like all the poor people.
Hey, look at you, you look posh
with all this, you've got some class.
- You think?
- Yep. Are you married?
- No.
- You've got a babe, then?
- A what?
- A doll, a chick.
Ah, you mean fiancée, a babe.
- No, you know, I live with my father.
- At your age,
you still live with your parents?
- He's a widower, so I live with him.
Before I lived with a girl,
a girl like this,
an orphan.
- Okay, and then?
Well, I thought it would be perfect,
she doesn't have a father, I got one.
And then...
She didn't want yours?
- No.
- Too bad!
I'll tell you a thing about the orphans,
if they aren't two, screw them!
Huh?
Clothes only were worth millions!
3 manteaux from Dior,
6 suits from Chanel,
my evening gowns from Givenchy!
All my Hermes scarves!
My Morabito shoes!
And my other Cartier watch!
Stop speaking English, it is ridiculous!
- Does he bite?
- Yes, he bites everyone except us.
Gisèle, look!
The Rolls! Ah!
- Help! Help!
- Why, what's wrong?
- You! Mind your own business!
What should we do?
- No! Only not that!
- Why not?
The cops!
- What?
- But do something!
- Write down the car number!
- But I know it already, it's MY car!
- We'll get my dad and be on our way.
- No, oh! I'll wait for you, hurry up...
No, come, I'll present you under a
false name.
- No, we are in a hurry. It's late!
- And if I go alone,
they would want me to stay for dinner.
Come on, Martial, do it me.
All right!
You'll see, they are very nice people.
I'll tell them that you are a colleague
from the office. Office behind the bars!
Is it you, Jean-Philippe?
- Yes, dad! This is my dad!
- Turn the light on!
Yes, go!
My Jean-Philippe!
- What are you doing here?
- They threw me out of the door.
- Who, the Buteaux?
- Who else do you think?
- But for how long are you sitting here?
- Since the afternoon news block on TV.
The one who was sentenced to death and
escaped - is it him? Hello, young man!
Hold on, I don't understand anything!
What happened?
- I will not let anyone insult my son!
- It's stuck.
- They were washing you with shit!
- It's stuck again.
Two bastards with bastard children,
bastard past and future!
- I like your old man a lot.
- Maybe you weren't polite with them?
When they were talking about you on the TV,
they insulted you. So, I told them:
"You shouldn't insult someone who
has an appointment with General de Gaulle!"
But you were always against the General!
They took my chair and brought me here
without giving me a piece of shit to eat!
- You don't eat that.
- I don't care anymore!
- Your cousins are really nice!
- What are you doing?
- The door|
- It's the old man, he's hungry, I bet.
- He wouldn't reach for the door bell.
- I put him far away from it.
- Maybe he'd like to apologize.
- Oh, you don't know this old devil!
I will give him some soup anyway.
- But...
- Gaston, it's the escaped guy!
- Papa, the fishy!
- Gangster!
- Shut your hole, you son of a bitch!
- Stop it, Martial, let him go!
It's my family!
If someone has to destroy everything
here, it's got to be me!
There!
Here, Jean-Philippe! The ammo!
Got it!
- What's going on there?
- Nothing, it's a western on TV.
- Sounds cool, what channel?
- The 2nd, but I think it'll be over soon!
The violence has to stop...
Under the table, can't you see we're
serious? Under the table, all of you!
Martial, the gas, look!
- Hey! Hey! Hey! Downstairs, quick!
Oh! Junior!
- Go.
Will you be back to play with us?
- Ready, steady, go!
Bastards!
Allez!
- There's a little left!.
- Not enough! And the stations are closed.
- We don't have money anyway!
- Not a problem, I can always..
Yeah, I know! Shake the owner!
Don't you think it's enough already?
- You're still preaching, I'm surprised.
- Shut up!
Don't fight, kids! I've got some pocket
money over here!
It's not much, but hey...!
Because of the strike of the
personnel of la S.N.C.F.
We are sorry to announce that the train 1017...
destinated for Paris will stay in Auxerre...
until the strike is over.
- Gisèle!
- What! What else now?
- Bastards! They are on strike!
- All the passengers are asked...
to get off the train.
- Didn't I tell you this country is over?
This country is ruined!
I don't have any money left!
Quick, we need to get money for the tickets!
- Oh, my! He is heavy!
- Give him to me!
Tomorrow we are going to the bank,
we are entitled to 500 francs each.
- And in the afternoon we're back in Paris.
- 500 francs! I'm getting sick when I think...
about 200 million in that car!
- Pardon, go ahead, Madame.
- Thank you, sir.
- After you, sir.
- Only after you.
- No, no, you go first.
- Over here!
- Don't shout like that...
Hey, anybody there?
- Hey, you, lazy asses!
- What's going on?
- Didn't you hear? There's a strike!
- Yes, but we need our money back!
- We just bought our tickets.
- Send in a letter, they will pay you back.
Hold him. You will give us our money back,
my friend!
- We don't give a shit about your idiotic strike.
- Hey, stop it.
- Strikes are legal.
- Go to hell.
- I don't give a damn about your legal stuff!
- So, what are we going to do?
I see only one solution:
we spend the night in the Rolls and tomorrow..
- Tomorrow what?
- Tomorrow, kids, will be a new day!
- Give me your hand!
- Huh?
Don't rush, the bank has just opened.
I didn't get a minute of sleep this night.
- Go in the queue like everybody else!
- We are so not everybody else!
Hands up! If you move, I shoot!
- Could I borrow your gun for a bit?
- What for?
- To rob a bank!
- Fine, you can take it.
- Here, bring it back when you're done!
- Can I have yours too?
- Yes, sir.
- They look so real!
If you say so.
80, 90, and 100 which makes 1000.
- Thank you, sir.
- Let's go.
- Hands up, nobody moves!
It's a hold-up!
You, over there, get out of your aquarium.
You put it here.
Quick, do it, good.
Everybody down on the stomach!
You too, bloodsuckers!
What do you have there, Mommy?
I said on the stomach!
Hey! Your shepherdess!
Yes, sir.
Good.
You hear this? Where is Martial?
What's going on?
Martial! Martial!
Go, go, quick! Quick!
Just so you know, what you've just done,
my little friend, is illegal.
- You're my partner in crime now!
- Hide you, big mouth!
We'll be out of gas soon, have you seen?
Go straight ahead, we'll see then!
He took all my jewels!
- The Rolls.
- The Rolls. Oh!
Stop! Stop!
- Our car!
- Was it your car, this Rolls?
No, it wasn't our car. It was just a car.
Just a beautiful car!
Come on, wake up, Gisèle. Let her go!
Wake up, Gisèle. Calm down!
Enough crying, look! Come, come, I have
an idea, you'll see!
- Hold on, I will need you as witnesses!
- We'll be right back!
- How are you doing?
- Very well.
Very very well, indeed!
Tell you something!
I don't think it could be any better!
- Quick! I need 302.20.20 in P.C.V.!
- Quick? There are 3 people before you!
But it's a car! It will leave the zone
where we can reach it!
- Fine, cabin number 1.
- Thank you, Miss, thank you!
- First, cash.
- 100 francs for 50 liters? I could..
stick my hand down your throat for that!
Well, if you're that unhappy, you can...
Take your stinking money! Here!
Don't choke on it!
I count the drops.
- Hello?
- You are being called from P.C.V. of Auxerre.
- Auxerre! Who can it be?
- If it's the Buteau, tell them to piss off!
I'm listening. Hello?
Is this the thief of my car that I'm
having the honour to speak to?
- No, it's his lawyer on the phone.
- Did you hear that? His lawyer!
We only borrowed your car for a while
because of the C.R.S. and tomatoes!
But once I meet General de Gaulle,
I have an appointment at 11:00...
- But he's mad!
- I will go to police and return it.
- No need to go to police!
- Why not?
You know better than me that a good
arrangement is better than a bad trial!
This Rolls is a collection item,
we are emotionally attached to it.
It's symbolic for us.
- That's it, we can go now!
- Right.
- Whom are you talking to?
- The owner of our car.
Give it to me!
Go, start the car! Hello?
So, I have an offer for you:
I'd like to buy out my car from you!
How much?
- 10 million, in fact, 100.000 in new francs.
- I could not disagree more!
- Shut up right now!
- What did you say?
Hello, yes, I see. Sorry, but they've already
offered me this much for the car details.
If you want your pile of metal back in one
piece, you'll have to cash up for 20 million.
in the bills of 500.. .
- But I don't have this money!
What do you mean we don't have it!
Give it to me! We will get it!
Good, then call me back in the afternoon.
And no tricks, or...
your collection item will be compressed
and sold to an amateur art lover.
Don't you think it's strange? The guy
wants to buy out his own car?
- Well, 20 mln. is exactly what I need!
- No, no, no and no! Impossible!
What, now I can't sell my car, Maitre?
- I'll leave you here and head for Elysees.
- No way. I'm waiting for an important call!
And until I get this call, I'm not
stepping out of this car!
That's it! I'm about to petition for your pardon!
"My General! The prisoner awaits outside...
in the Rolls. If you say "yes", he'll return
to prison. If "no", he'll escape.
- It was him!
- And next to him - Tante Yvonne!
I'm late! He didn't wait for me!
- Hide yourself! He shouldn't see you!
- Oh no, but I want to see him!
What a coincidence! Maybe he'll offer
us a cup of coffee! Turn!
Are you crazy! Let me go.
Stay here.
Oh, my General.
My General.
I was searching for you,
Jean-Philippe Duroc, lawyer at the court,
you have granted me an appointment at 11 h.
It's about Martial Gaulard.
He is General, my innocent!
I mean, he is innocent, my General!
Thank you, my Général. Have a safe trip!
Hello! Yes, it's me!
I've got the money. 200.000 francs. 20 mln.
in the old money in the bills of 500.
- As you said...
- Go down to the road in front of your house.
- What address?
- 44, Avenue Foch.
- Are you blond, dark haired? Fat, thin?
- I will go!
- It will be my wife!
- Is she pretty or an old bat?
- She's not an old bat...
- I will be wearing a sable jacket!
- She'll be wearing a sable jacket!
- And the car? Ask him!
He hang up!
Hey, you are not going to leave
just when Jean-Philippe...
No, Marcel. Here are we
go separate ways!
I was happy to get to know you!
Kiss your boy for me!
I got it! I got it! Your pardon!
He signed! Look!
- But where is he?
- Gone!
- Gone where?
- Avenue Foch, to pick up the cash.
Oh! Bastard!
Oh no, no.. it can't be..
I have to stop him!
Oh, goddammit.. no, no!
Gisèle, I'll be watching you!
- Oh no!
Hey, shall we go for a walk?
You coming?
- How much?
- 20 million.
20 million! Are you mad?
Have you seen yourself?
You bastard!
Giséle!
- Was it him?
- No!
Help! Catch the thief!
Catch the thief!
- Gisèle, what happened?
- He ripped it out of my hands.
I had it right here!
And our car? Thief! Cheater!
There! Jacques!
It's the Rolls!
- The car, the car!
- Hurry up!
Hurry up, it will be gone again!
- Wait for me Jacques, wait for me!
- Stop, stop!
Thief! Stop!
Let's go, quick!
Look, it's him!
Forget it, we missed him,
Jean-Philippe, we'll never find him!
Yes, we will find him!
- Where is Bach-Yen?
- At the manifestation with her friends
on the barricades.
- What are they doing there?
- No idea. They are all crazy!
Go now, last thing I need is a broken window!
C.R.S: SS! C.R.S: SS! C.R.S: SS...
Blanche Hirondelle, Bach-Yen!
- Reinforce the barricades!
- Give it to me! Blanche Hirondelle!
It rains, here... Shh!
Not a way to calm down!
Disappearance of the head of the state
considerably heated the atmosphere.
I'm in the Latin Quarters. Quartier Latin,
agitation rises with every hour!
Stop it, no, let me through!
Listen, let me pass!
I'm not...
Stop it! Enough already....
L'Etoile de Jade, is over there,
on the other corner of Boulevard St.-Germain.
I am going to try to pass.
You got the petition?
I put it in here.
They are nice, the kids, right?
Stop screwing around, kids!
This cars costs a lot!
- It's a collection item.
- You are a collection item, bloodsucker!
- Damned capitalist! Piece of shit!
- Are you for real? I am simple worker!
I live off my pension!
- All the old bastards should retire!
- Hello? Ah, no, no.
It's not the thief,
it's the father of his lawyer.
Speak up, I can't hear a thing!
- Shut your holes!
- Old bastards should retire!
What? Your car?
Your car is right here.
You can come and pick it up,
crossroads of Mabillon.
Before the road of Four. Hurry up,
'cause it's getting hot in here!
Power to the people! Jobs to the young!
Ah! For God's sake!
Excuse me, can I go through,
I am a lawyer and I've got..
a client who is over there.
- A client? Bad timing, don't you think?
But it's just to tell him he was
granted a pardon!
Excuse me! Please! Hey!
Go, hurry up!
Pardon, pardon, pardon, pardon!
Here is Christian Brincourt directly from
the crossroads of Mabillon at the corner...
of the street of Four. Demonstrators
act according to a developed strategy:
Once the forces of government approach,
what is actually happening right now,
the students step back and regroup behind
the barricades.
Christian, isn't it the leftist lawyer?
This is an unexpected turn of events!
We've just found...
Maitre Duroc, for whom the police was
looking all over the country
But I just want to pass behind the barricade
to see my client!
Look at the screen.
Wasn't it him who escaped together
with Gaulard?
Yes, that's him!
I'll contact Rocheteau.
He's out on patrol.
I'm calling TO.657.
Hello, it's TO.657.
Duroc is showing off at the barricades.
- Where is it?
Crossroads of Mabillon, corner of the Four street.
- Go, go, quickly!
- Where did you leave your motorcycle?
- I hid it over there.
Excuse me, young man, would you kindly
direct me to the crossroads of Mabillon?
- Over there! But it's a mess!
- Thank you, come Gisèle!
- Get out of the car!
- I can't, I've got arthritis!
Then you need a wheelchair, not a Rolls!
Jump, quickly!
Hold this, I'll be right back!
Marcel! Come here, big boy, come on!
The Rolls is packed with money!
200.000 at least!
Hey you, Popeye!
Hold this for me!
- Martial! Where's dad?
- Don't worry, he's here
What the hell are you doing?
-But, but..
- Jean-Philippe!
The Rolls, there!
It's burning! No, no....
- Oh, mon Dieu!
- Hold on, it's not the right time!
It's a disaster! Look at it! It's terrible!
Oh Jacques, we lost everything!
- Gisèle, calm down!
- Stop whining!
- I don't want to see it! It hurts!
Thank you.
- Do you think it's fair?
- What? All those burning cars?
No, that my boy, an honest man,
will go to prison?
While you will remain free?
- Did they arrest you?
- Are you kidding? I'm turning myself in!
I cam to turn myself in, Judge.
Can I?
I'm warning you, from this moment on,
everything you say....
could be used against you.
- It was me who attacked the security guard.
- Note it down, please.
- Do not lie! I got your petition!
- You will be free in 30 years!
- Please, Duroc, calm down.
Mr. Bâtonnier you will be a witness...
What am I saying...
Your honour, having worked in the
Advocacy of Paris for 10 years,
I never let the slightest...
- Wait! I robbed the bank,
hi-jacked the Rolls, the truck with tomatoes,
the car of Mr. Duroc, whom I...
forced to go with me by threatening him.
- See, my colleague Duroc is innocent.
He was my hostage all this time!
Gaulard, why are you doing this?
- So, Mr. Writer?
Can sign your novel already?
Yep, looks fine to me.
Can I borrow your pen, your honour?
Pardon, thanks. I sign:
Martial Gaulard,
being sound of mind and memory.
Because I'm not crazy, your honour,
and I will prove it to you.
Move back, Gaulard!
Move over! Martial, you are putting
yourself in a difficult situation!
Let me go! Let me go!
Help! Help me!
- Hold the bike.
- Help!!
- Better?
- Yeah.
And thanks for the petition anyway!
Martial!
- Yeah?
- See you!
- See ya!