Bill?
Are you in there?
I feel I have a great deal of promise.
- Promise?
- Yes, unlimited potential.
- I graduated near the top of my class.
- Uh-huh.
I see you've been out of school
for a year already.
Well, okay, yes. But I think
that's a little misleading.
I look at this past year
as a period of real growth for me...
in terms of preparation
for the future.
- What are your goals?
- Goals? You mean
in terms of architecture?
Where do you see yourself,
let's say, five years from now?
Oh. Well, um...
It would be great to get this job
so I can get out of my mom's house.
No. Five years from now.
I'd have to say...
Well on my way, sir.
That's where I see myself.
I see a lot of room
for me to grow here,
and I don't want you to concern
yourself with this past year.
I'm the first to admit
I had a little difficulty...
just as far as
forward momentum,
but I've had a lot
of job interviews recently,
and I don't want to say anything,
but I feel like I'm on the verge
of a real breakthrough, I really do.
And I think big things
are gonna happen.
Well, I'm certainly
on your side, Tim.
- Tom.
Tom Thompson.
Hello?
Tom!
- Phone call.
- Who is it?
It's a girl.
- Hey, what's this friggin' lock?
- Not now.
Hey!
- Hello?
- Is this Tom?
Tom Thompson?
- Who is this?
- It's Ruth Abernathy, Bill's mom.
Bill's... dead.
- I have to talk to you.
I'm, like, shaking.
- Did you get the job?
- Do you remember a guy
named Bill Abernathy?
- No. So you didn't get the job.
This has nothing to do with the job.
Come on, think. From high school?
- Look, I don't remember him.
Are you okay?
- No?
- Is that your Brooks Brothers?
- I had to do some research at the firm.
- You can't bowl in your Brooks Brothers.
- Where's Brad?
He's on the phone.
He won't get off.
Glass. Brad Glass.
Right, from Brooklyn.
No, no, no,
United States.
Sorry to wake you.
What time there?
He's been trying
to reach that guy in Japan
about that stupid dog breeding thing.
- We have to talk to you. Hang up.
- Miss Tsumaki. Miss Tsumaki!
Six dollars a minute,
this woman keeps putting me on hold.
- Did you get the job?
- Get off. I have to talk to you.
- Is that your Brooks Brothers?
- Do you remember
a guy named Bill Abernathy?
- Miss Tsumaki?
- What happened at the interview?
- They claim they're gonna call me.
- Hello? Hello? Listen.
Very important. I need feedback
from husband about business proposal.
- Can he call back?
I have him call you back.
- Chihuahua.
- Okay. I call back.
- Yeah, call back.
- I call back.
- Call back.
- Okay. Bye-bye. Bye!
- Good-bye. 'Bye.
Listen, I'm trying to run
a business here. That's a business call.
I'm sorry to interrupt your business
call, but Bill Abernathy is dead.
Who's Bill Abernathy?
Before I get the chance to tell
this very mysterious-sounding woman...
that I basically have
no recollection of her son,
- she just starts crying.
- She cried?
- Jesus, who is this woman?
- I don't know.
But there were these long stretches,
nothing but crying, for like minutes.
I feel really bad for the lady.
She sounds like
a nice, warm person.
- So I guess I'm gonna need a suit.
- For what?
Hello? What have we been talking
about? I'm gonna be a pallbearer.
- What?
- You didn't get out of it?
Are you done laughing? This is
my whole point. I'm in big trouble.
- How could you tell her "yes"?
- I told you, there was crying.
How am I supposed to
respond to that?
Call her up.
Tell her you got back trouble.
It's no good.
I am in, I am committed.
I am just gonna have to
do this one little thing for her.
It starts off as
one little thing, all of a sudden
you're enmeshed in a situation.
- This could be part
of a whole scam operation.
- What?
One minute you're
carrying this guy's coffin,
the next you're lying in a ditch naked.
- Is that suit black?
- No, it's a charcoal gray weave
with a chalk stripe. Why?
- What are you, 40 regular?
Scott, please.
- No, no.
I wear this suit to work.
This is my main work suit.
I have a problem here.
I have to look presentable.
This is a $600 suit.
- Now I'm starting to see you
for who you really are.
- Come on.
No, I'm serious. What if it were Brad
lying in the coffin?
Whoa! What are you
talkin' about, "Brad"?
Hey, all the shit you eat,
your heart's a time bomb.
That's nice. That's a nice thing.
I've had enough. I gotta go.
- What do you mean? We're not done here.
- Hey, it's 10:30.
So? It's Tuesday night.
Can you believe him?
It's 10:30 already?
Come on, let's go.
If you don't lend me the suit,
Scott, I can't do it, I can't go.
- I'll have to call her back.
- That's good.
You don't need this right now.
- And don't forget the wedding shower.
- Oh, yeah. I'm not going.
- You're going. You're the best man.
- No.
How can he marry her?
She's like an albatross around his neck.
You don't understand.
It's called a relationship.
Oh, what?
Cynthia's an albatross.
Bring some wine, okay?
You better come.
- Cynthia. Hi.
- Oh, hi!
Oh, my God, you'll
never believe who's coming.
- How could you invite Jared Schneidman?
- Just relax and you'll be fine.
- Why?
- Is that what you're wearing?
Of course, it's what I'm wearing.
We're here.
- Wait. Who's coming?
- Now, don't panic.
- I'm not.
- Good. I ran into her
at D'Agostino's this morning.
- Cynthia!
- Who?
- Hi!
- I'll be right back.
- I'm sorry.
- Oh, Cynthia, come o...
- There's a lot
of single women here tonight.
- Who's coming, Scott?
- What are you talking about?
Cynthia said someone is coming.
It's not that Loretta person, is it?
Because that did not work out.
- Sweetheart...
- Shut up!
What the f...
That is not good dip!
Oh, gee. There she goes again.
Do you see how she,
like, spits?
...before you listen to me, Brad.
- Sweetheart...
- Shut up with the "sweetheart"!
- I don't understand.
You haven't the vaguest...
Isn't that Julie DeMarco?
- I have to borrow a shirt.
- How many times do I have to tell you...
- What are you doing?
- That's Julie DeMarco out there.
Don't you have any regular shirts?
Like, just a shirt?
What are you talking about?
Like that. That's a good shirt.
Don't you have any shirts like that?
- Yeah, I'm wearing it.
- Take it off.
- What?
- I have to borrow the shirt, Scott.
- What is this obsessión
with my clothes?
- I was in love with her, okay?
- So?
- "So"? So I haven't
seen her since high school.
Imagine that she sees me
and I'm wearing the same fuckin' shirt!
Look, I just got this shirt.
- Guys.
- He wants to borrow my shirt now.
Whatever. We gotta
do something about the dip.
Lauren's having a frigging
conniption out there.
Did you leave your answering machine
on? I gave Tsumaki the phone number.
I got a line on a couple
of prize-winning dogs.
- What's wrong with the dip?
- Lauren's sisters are
all lactose-intolerant.
"Lactose"?
Don't marry her, Brad.
- Lauren...
- He doesn't care. Julie, Julie.
Is it too much to ask that I could have
one dip for me and my sisters to enjoy?
- What about salsa?
- Salsa! I love... I love salsa.
T... Tom! You remember Julie DeMarco.
She's back in Brooklyn.
Oh! Hi, sure, yes.
Didn't you move away senior year?
- Yeah, Long Island.
- Her father made
a killing in real estate.
Julie's right.
Salsa, guacamole. It is so obvious.
You know what? I think I have
some avocado in the kitchen.
- Let's take a look.
- I just want to tell you one thing.
- Did you ever think salsa or guacamole?
- Okay.
So, you... Wow.
You look, uh, really...
Oh, God.
Well, that's really...
Hey, Mary Lou!
God! Jared Schneidman?
I-I know.
D-Do you know he's engaged?
He is not! Oh, my God!
- Everybody's getting married.
- I know! It's like
a virus or something.
I know. I mean, I was,
you know, supposed to, but...
- Oh.
- You know, it didn't work out.
But, yeah...
But I thought for sure you would
have been snatched up by now.
Oh...
So you remember me?
Tom! What,
are you kidding?
So you think I would
have been snatched up, huh?
Well, you know, a lot of giris
were, uh, after you.
- No.
- Yes.
- Yes!
- What about that girl?
- Who?
Oh, you know, uh, Shelly.
Shelly What's-Her-Name. She loved you.
- I have no idea
who you're talking about.
- Yes, you do.
Remember, you guys did that play,
that musical together?
- Musical? No, I don't...
- Yeah, you were great.
You had a great voice.
I don't... sing.
What do you mean?
I'm Tom Thompson.
We were in band together.
Oh.
- You okay?
- Please, I'm fine.
This is good. It's time you let go
of Julie DeMarco, just move past her.
So I've decided. You should
ask Julie DeMarco out for coffee.
She's one of the sweetest people
I have ever, ever known.
Yeah, Tom, did you see those legs?
Forget about it.
- You were staring at her legs?
- No, not for me, for Tom.
- I can't believe you.
- What?
You should be staring at my legs.
I've been staring
at your legs for nine years.
What are you saying?
You're tired of my legs?
No, Cynthia,
I'm agreeing with you.
I'm saying that Tom should ask
Julie DeMarco out for coffee.
- Don't you think he should?
- Yes!
Are you okay?
Please, I'm fine.
How was the party?
It was okay.
Gonna see your father on Sunday?
I don't know, Ma.
Anything new?
Good night, Ma.
See ya tomorrow.
Ohh.
Tom.
I got in touch
with Jimmy Gold.
He's coming down
from Boston.
And then the cousins
from Jersey.
Maybe, you know,
a friend from the gym.
We might be one or two short
on the pallbearers.
Mrs. Abernathy,
I am really sorry.
I wish there was something
I could do to help you out.
I know how you feel.
You do?
- I'm giving the eulogy.
- What?
- Ruth Abernathy came to my house.
- Jesus, you didn't get out of it?
- You're getting enmeshed.
- Are you having a thing?
Tom, don't get upset.
Brad and Lauren just stopped by.
- It's not like a thing thing.
- Is that lasagna?
- I can't believe you people.
It's just like a conspiracy.
- No, it's not!
- If you must know, this was my idea.
- Oh, your idea.
- We're two couples having dinner.
- I need to be a couple now.
- Not everything's about you, Tom.
- That's right. It's all about you...
and your sisters and all
your dietary restrictions.
All right, that's it!
I've had your shit...
- Let's go. I'm ready for you now.
- Relax.
- Get you a drink, Tom?
- Yes, you can, Cynthia.
- And some lasagna. Thank you.
- Take it easy.
I don't know.
What about the chess club? Can't
we do anything with the chess club?
It should be personal.
I mean, you loved the guy.
- I did not love the guy.
- Maybe you traveled together.
Yeah, excellent!
Scott, read that back.
Okay. "Chess. You loved him.
Traveled together."
- Okay. We are on our way.
- You traveled together playing chess.
- Yes! Yes!
- Through China.
You played chess in China
and then you fell in love.
See, that doesn't help.
You don't know this Ruth Abernathy
person. She means business.
- So, Scott, you're
coming with me, right?
- What, to the funeral? No.
- Scott!
How about giving
a little moral support?
- Yeah, Scott, I need some moral support.
- Don't worry.
- I'll support you, Tom.
- Just Scott.
- Hi. How are you?
- It's Julie DeMarco.
What, she just
comes over now?
Hi. I'm sorry I missed
the lasagna, but I got... Anyway.
Here are the magazines
we were talking about.
- So. What's going on?
- We're writing a eulogy.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Don't worry. We didn't know the guy.
You guys are going to someone's funeral
who you don't know?
- Actually, they're not going. I'm going.
- Scott and I are going.
- Why don't you come too?
- You're inviting me to a funeral?
- Yes!
It's not like it's a real funeral.
- It is! It's a funeral.
- If she's going, I'm allowed to go.
- She is not going.
- Typical bullshit.
- Tom!
- It's okay.
Obviously, Tom does not want me to go
to this funeral thing and that's fine.
- I have nothing against you
going personally...
- All right, we're all going.
No, no, no.
Only if it's okay with Tom.
- Tom, is it okay?
- Is it okay, Tom? Come on.
- That's the dead guy's mother?
- Uh-huh.
Jesus.
Thank you.
Excuse me. My condolences.
Who will perform the eulogy?
The tall young man with
the dark suit and hair. Tom Thompson.
Thank you so much.
Ring any bells?
No.
Mr. Thompson,
if you would please, sir.
Good luck.
Who is Bill Abernathy?
This is not
an easy question to answer.
I could spend countless hours
recounting my personal experiences...
with Bill.
The chess club.
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
Instead I ask,
who is the real Bill Abernathy?
What is the single...
elusive, intangible,
inner quality...
that makes... made...
Bill...
Shh.
Bill.
Well, folks, I don't...
I don't have that answer.
Who really does?
Shh.
Pull ahead.
- I got it.
- All right.
Here we go.
- So, you guys, I don't think
this is funny, all right?
- We don't think it's funny.
- We weren't laughing.
- Yes, you were.
I can't, you know...
- That was a sneeze.
- I don't think it's funny.
I just don't understand.
We weren't laughing.
I'll see you all later.
I don't feel like staying.
I'm very... I'm gonna go.
Julie! Julie!
- Ohh!
- Come right this way, please.
- Julie! Where are you goin'?
- Come on, I'm losing him!
What are you doing?
- Julie!
- Come on! Hey, hey, wait!
Where... Where are you going?
- What are you doing?
- Where are you going?
- I'm leaving. This isn't funny.
- I know. I felt terrible.
So, you remember him?
- What?
- I saw you in the chapel.
You were crying.
Hey, buddy,
are you kidding with this?
Do you mind?
We're about to bury this guy.
This is a person.
This is a person's life.
I don't remember him.
- Oh.
- Hey, what's goin' on over there?
It was just so, so sad.
I don't know what the hell he's doing.
- Do you wanna get some coffee?
- Unbelievable.
- He's pickin' up chicks.
- Coffee?
Yeah. If you wouldn't mind.
- Yeah, all right.
Why don't you call me?
- C-Call you?
- Get him off.
- All right, let's go.
- Whoa!
- All right, all right.
Come on, back it up.
I never should've asked you
to be a pallbearer.
It was too much for you.
- There's a will.
- What?
You're in the will.
All the way in.
Hello?
- Julie, hi.
- Hi.
- Hi, it's Tom Thompson.
- Oh. Tom.
- Hi. How are you?
- I'm fine.
So listen, um, I was calling
because we've talked about din... um...
- Uh...
- What did we talk about?
- Did we, at the funeral,
talk about doing this, uh...
- Right, right.
- The coffee thing.
- Yes!
- Um, listen, I was thinking...
- Yeah?
What if Scott and Cynthia come along?
- Scott and Cynthia?
- Yeah.
- Oh, you mean like a, uh...
- Yeah, you know, like the four of us.
- Tom!
- 'Cause I'm seeing Cynthia
on Tuesday anyway.
- Tu... On Tuesday?
- Tom!
- Who was that?
- Huh? Oh, it's, uh... it's ju...
- This crazy woman...
Jesus, this neighborhood is...
Hey, lady, you wanna keep it down?
I am on the phone here!
Are you on the phone?
- Hello.
- Hello?
Who is this? Hello?
Jesus.
Tom?
Oh, my God. Tom?
Uh, hel...
...Ulie?
- H-Hello?
- Julie? Julie?
- Hi! Hi!
Wh... Well, that was weir...
What was that?
lt... Did...
D- Did you... That was really creepy.
- She just kept saying "hello."
Did you hear her?
- No. Didn't you hear me?
- Y... No.
- No? I w... Well, I was calling you.
Were you trying to contact me?
Uh, y-y-yeah.
I ke... I kept saying "Julie."
Didn't... It must've been
a weird party line thing.
- That has never happened before.
- Huh.
So listen,
Tuesday is bowling night.
- Oh.
- Uh, how about Thursday?
Great.
Oh, no,
I- I can't take his car.
Look at this mess.
Mrs. Abernathy.
- Take it. He wanted you to have it.
- No, really, I can't.
I gotta get it out of here.
Please.
Twenty-five-year-old kid
makes out a will.
I should've known right then.
I brought you some, uh...
nut clusters.
They're my favorite.
Oh, Tom.
I'm sorry about the funeral.
So...
how are you doing?
I'm fine, I'm...
I'm gonna be.
Thank you.
Maybe I should just
have them take it all away.
- Oh, here, here.
Let me help you with that.
- Thanks.
I gotta get it all out of here
if I'm gonna sell this place.
Oh, you're gonna
sell the house?
Yeah. You know, maybe
it's too big for one person.
Too quiet.
I mean, it's like I have
the TV on all the time now.
Thank you. It's very nice to have
someone to help out around here.
Oh, sure.
Who knows? You know,
I was thinking, maybe, of going
to one of those computer schools.
Oh, yeah, computers.
That's good.
You think so?
I'm gonna have to go through
Bill's stuff in his room.
- I wish I could help you out.
- Oh, no, no.
I mean, it's just that
I'm... I'm very busy.
- I mean, I got a job interview.
- Oh, a job interview.
Yeah. Actually it's a second interview.
I bet you get it.
Thank you.
I hope so.
I'm a little worried.
Do you mind if
I make a suggestion?
- Sure.
- Why don't you try pushing
your hair back over your forehead.
You know, like the other afternoon.
Like... Yeah, like that.
Just...
You don't let 'em see your face.
You're a good-looking man.
Well, maybe I'll let you
know how the interview goes.
I mean, if you're interested.
- Sure. If you have enough time,
you can drop by.
- Yeah, if I have the time.
- Whoa! My God, look at you.
- He's turned a corner.
Oh, very important. I sort of mentioned
that I live on my own, okay?
- So just don't blow it.
- You lied to her?
- No, she seemed to have
a thing about it.
- So what are we supposed to say?
- Oh, this is it!
- What are we supposed to do at the end?
- Cynthia and I are going for cocktails?
- A late movie.
- You guys say you have plans
to see a late movie, then just go.
- How are we getting home?
Deal with it.
I need the car.
He's gotta drive her home.
That's the whole point.
Could you give me an opening for
the story about Brad and the oranges?
- Tom, just be yourself.
- Yeah, you're right.
- Scott, you set me up
with the orange story.
- You got it.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wh... What was it?
- Uh, "Mean To Me," maybe?
- No, no!
- Louis Armstrong did
a great versión of it too.
- Oh! Oh, oh, oh. Uh...
It goes:
# Dah dah-dah dah-dah #
# Dah dah-dah dah-dah
Dah dah-dah dah-dah #
- # Dah dah-dah dah-dah... #
- # If I only had a brain #
Tom, you've heard of
Django Reinhardt, right?
- No, Scott.
- Oh, my God. He is so amazing.
- He only had three fingers.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Mmm. That's too bad.
So, anyway...
Julie, did you know Tom's
got a second interview tomorrow?
Oh! That's great.
- Yeah, well...
- "I Surrender, Dear."
- You what, honey?
- # Dah-dah, dah-dah #
# Dah-dah, dah-dah #
# I surrender, dear ##
I love that song.
Oh, you know what? I think that's
on Decca. I've seen it in the bins.
- What, you have that record?
- Yeah.
I need that record desperately!
- Yeah, so they seemed
to really like my portfolio.
- What?
Oh, 'cause... Oh!
That's so exciting, Tom.
- Yeah, you should really see
Tom's stuff. It's so great.
- Oh, go on.
Well, it's a really good firm
and they seem to have room to grow.
And you can maybe finally
move out of your mom's house.
Didn't you have... What was that,
that story about Brad and oranges?
Didn't you have a story
about Brad and oranges?
No, Scott.
Whoa, Cynthia and I
have to, uh...
we have to go get
some cocktails.
Mmm.
I- I-I cannot believe you.
I'm sorry. That thing about
your mother just slipped out.
No, the whole evening.
What were those topics?
- You were supposed to feed me openings
so I could jump in with the zingers.
- I was.
- You weren't zinging.
- Oh, bullshit!
- How am I supposed to zing
on, what, "jingle-jangle"?
- Django Reinhardt!
Look, I'm sorry. She told me
she was working in this record store.
- You told me to keep things flowing.
- Oh, flowing. Yes, flo...
You know,
you're making me sick, Scott.
- You still have the drive home.
- The drive home?
The drive home is useless, you know.
- Yeah.
- Hi.
You know, we really didn't get
much of a chance to talk tonight.
I wanted to tell you something.
I remember you.
We shared a music stand,
didn't we?
Yeah.
I used to talk to you
about that guy I went out with... Kenny.
That's right.
Anyway...
What I remember is...
you were a really nice guy.
Julie.
- Oww! Oh, shit.
- Ooh!
I am so... Ohh. Okay.
- Oh, my God.
- I should've warned you I was going in.
- Oh, God.
- Are... Are you...
No, you know, it's my fault.
I just... I do this, you know.
L... I give out
the wrong signals.
Oh.
L...
I'm re... I'm really sorry, Tom.
I'm going away.
You're going away?
- It's sort of a... sort of a long story.
- But you just moved back.
Well, I'm not really here.
It's, like, a temporary arrangement
until I'm ready to go.
I needed a place to stay and my dad,
you know, owns the building and I just...
I mean, if I wasn't going away...
Well, I'm very sorry.
I mean, your work is very strong.
I fought for you.
But the partners felt,
and I had to agree with them,
you just don't fulfill
our needs at this time.
I want to thank you
for coming in.
I didn't get the job.
I'll get the boxes.
He loved the Mets.
Thank you for doing this.
I got something you might want.
Come here.
There might be
one or two of you in there.
You can take one.
It's hard to believe.
- You're a beautiful boy.
- Oh, no, no.
- Yes, you are.
- Well, thank you, Ruth. Thank you.
Bill Senior, on the other hand,
he had to get by on his wits.
No chin.
I met him one night at this party
at Aunt Lucille's.
I was 16.
I fell for him like that.
Next day he left for Vietnam.
Two years.
So... what, you just
waited for him?
Oh, sure.
- I mean, there were
plenty of other suitors.
- I'm sure.
But Bill Senior, you know,
he just... tickled my fancy.
Whew, and those letters he wrote.
Holy cow.
I would've waited a few lifetimes.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
It's that easy.
I had the dial set a little thin.
- Press the button.
And now you'll feed
everything down to the last piece.
It's a perfect result!
- That's pretty good!
- Every time.
- It's beautiful.
- It's perfection in slicing.
- Please, Tom.
- Ruth, I'd really rather not.
I need you to do this.
He never talked to me
about things like this.
It's... It's important to me.
Please.
What do you want to know?
Giris.
Well, I think
there was one girl Bill liked.
Really?
What was her name?
- Julie.
- Was she pretty?
- Oh, yeah.
He did everything he could, but he just
couldn't stop thinking about her.
Even when he tried
really hard not to.
She haunted him.
So what happened?
Well, she told him
she was planning on going away,
but I don't know.
He couldn't let her go.
I mean, he'd been in love
with her for so long.
And I guess no one tickled
his fancy the way she did.
So, this Julie...
Do you think
that's the reason he...
No, Ruth. I knew we shouldn't
have gotten into this.
- Could be the reason, you know.
- Ruth, no.
- Did she go to Yale?
- What?
There were all these
toll receipts in the car.
New Haven. Did she go to Yale?
She didn't go to Y...
No, Ru... It...
I don't think it had anything
to do with her. I know it didn't.
Hello?
Tom? It's Julie.
Hi, Julie...
- Julie?
- Can I come over?
I have to talk to you.
- Come over here?
- Yeah. I'm in the neighborhood.
I'm coming, okay?
- What are you doing?
- Someone's coming over. A girl.
Don't make a big deal...
Is that what you're wearing?
It's my friggin' house!
Okay, try not to say "friggin',"
don't call me "Tom-Tom"...
and no stories about me doing magic.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- What's going on?
- Nothing.
- So, could I come in, or...
- Oh, sure.
- Julie, this is my mom.
- Oh, hi.
I'm Tom's mom.
How are you?
Tom-Tom comes out
in his funny little hat and cape...
and he has a little magic wand.
I'm telling you,
he was the cutest thing you ever saw!
- I got a picture.
- Mom, no pictures.
- Oh, wait, no! I got one in...
- Mom!
I'm goin' in the kitchen now.
Oy.
It was really nice meeting you.
Oh, it was nice meeting you too.
- I'm sorry.
- No, I'm sorry.
It's just, this thing happened
and I didn't know who else to turn to.
Well, what's...
what's up?
Scott came to see me
last night.
He did?
What, at work?
- Yeah.
- How is Scott?
He made a pass at me.
Oh, my... Wh...
I can't believe he did this!
What in... What...
I can't believe it!
How could he kiss you like that
when he's supposed to be married?
- How do you know he kissed me?
- How do l... How's that?
I said "pass,"
I didn't say "kiss."
- Oh, my God! Did he tell you this?
- No. I'm sorry.
- I hear "pass," I move right to "kiss."
- Well, he did kiss me.
Bastard!
What is he thinking?
I don't know what to do.
Do I tell Cynthia? Do I not tell her?
Oh, you... you... you tell her.
This is a moral issue.
Unfortunately, Scott is an adulterer and
that is something Cynthia should know.
Okay, okay, but what if
it's not all Scott's fault, all right?
- What if it's partly my fault?
- What do you mean?
I'm just saying, he shows up
out of nowhere looking for a record?
I should've seen it coming. I just...
I let things get out of control.
- The same thing happened with Jed.
- Jed?
One minute we're having
this casual conversation...
"Maybe we should live together."
The next thing I know,
I'm getting married.
- This is the guy you were gonna marry.
- Yeah.
I mean, I cared about him, you know,
and he really wanted to get married.
But I guess I wasn't sure,
and I should've told him
that at the very beginning.
I mean, before that whole
marriage thing got started.
Have you ever not told someone something
that you should've told them,
but you were afraid to,
so you didn't,
and then it turned into
a whole complicated thing...
that you never should've
gotten into in the first place?
You kids want some Bosco?
Mom! No!
Oh. I love Bosco.
This is why you
never got first chair.
- What?
- In band.
Mr. Busto wanted you to challenge
Cliff Young for first chair,
but you wouldn't do it.
Oh, my God.
- I forgot about Cliff Young.
- You didn't want to hurt his feelings.
- Well, he loved his solos.
- Yeah, but you were better than he was.
- No.
- You were.
I'll, I'll give
Cliff Young his trills,
but you had it all over him
in the upper register.
How do you remember
all this?
I have a really good memory.
Well,
I guess I was always screwed up.
No, you were just worried
about other people's feelings.
Yeah, but the thing is,
you spend your life worrying
about how other people feel,
you sort of lose track,
you know, of how you feel.
Does this have anything
to do with you going away?
Sort of.
My plan...
is to save up, buy a car,
pack all the things
I really care about...
and just drive off on my own
for, like, a year.
Because I never really
been on my own. You know?
Y- You've got a thing.
On my mouth?
Listen, um,
there's this thing tonight
at St. John the Divine.
I got the tickets for me
and, you know, Jed.
- It's this guy Gorczcki.
- Hockey?
A composer.
I know.
So, uh,
do you, you know...
do you want to go with me?
Yes.
- How could you do this to me?
- What?
It's 2:30.
Where the hell have you been?
- I really need to talk to you.
Can we please just go inside?
- They're waiting for us.
- Who?
- Weren't you even listening
to me the other night?
Of course I was listening to you.
What did you say?
Aunt Lucille's.
The pool party.
Did you even remember
to bring your trunks?
Oh, Jesus. Let's go.
I packed some of Bill's.
Come on!
# Papa loves mambo #
# Mama loves mambo #
# Look at him sway with it
Gettin' so gay with it #
- # Shoutin' "ole" with it now #
- Hey!
# Papa loves mambo #
Ohh!
Do you remember me?
- Uh...
- Of course you don't.
You were this high.
Boys, you remember Tom
from the funeral?
Ruth told me everything
you've been doing.
She did?
I can't tell you
how wonderful you are,
helping my sister-in-law
through this time.
Oh, there she is.
Ohh! Oh, you look great!
You're making me cry.
- Oh, well...
- You are so strong.
I owe it all to Tom.
I mean, he was there for me, you know.
- When I needed someone, he was there.
- Tom.
# Feelin' that zing again, wow #
- # Papa loves mambo #
# Mama loves mambo ##
Julie, hi.
It's, it's me, Tom.
No, everything's fine.
Listen, what time did you
say the concert was?
No, I can make it, um...
It's just, I had this horrible
family thing I couldn't get out of.
Okay, great.
No, I'm still here.
Okay.
Bye.
# Come a little bit closer #
- # Hear what I have to say #
- So, did you like it?
It was great.
- It was nothing like anything
we ever played in band though.
Weren't all these recalled?
No. That was the, uh, Pinto.
- I don't think we're gonna make it.
- Are you kidding me?
This... This thing's
running like a top.
- # Oooh #
- # But there's a full moon risin' #
I'm sure
it just needs a minor adjustment.
Tom?
- Hmm?
- Who's Ruth?
Ruth?
You know, Ruth.
Under the seat, I found "Ruth."
Oh, that's Ruth Abernathy's.
Bill's mom.
I've been sort of
spending some time with her.
You know, she's been going
through a, a difficult period.
Are you kidding me?
What do you mean?
That is so nice of you.
Oh. No, i-it really isn't.
Yes, it is.
You don't even remember that guy.
That is so nice of you.
No, it... it really isn't.
# Because I'm still
in love with you #
# I wanna see you
dance again #
# Because I'm still
in love with you #
# On this harvest moon ##
- That's your room?
- What?
Yeah. I tried to
get that off.
It's, like, welded
to the door.
Can I see?
Um, my mom doesn't really
like me to drive her car.
We really shouldn't dally.
W- We're getting into
a dangerous zone here.
You wait here, okay?
Oh, shit.
- Oh, Julie. Julie...
- Oh, my God.
- I know. I should probably
get rid of the bunk bed, huh?
- Oh! I'm sorry.
- Shh!
Ohh.
- Do you still play?
- Not really? Do you?
No. I lost mine.
Oh.
- I remember these.
- Yeah.
Shh!
Oh! Sorry.
These were great.
What happened to these?
They, they killed
a lot of people.
Um, I was cleaning out my closet...
that's why that's out.
- Oh, my God.
- What?
My hair.
I look so bizarre.
No. No, you didn't.
Look at that dress.
What was I thinking?
You look beautiful.
For the last seven years
I've been wishing I'd danced with you.
What?
Oh, uh, it was the...
homecoming dance.
- You and me, we went to a dance?
- Oh, not together.
But it was during one of those weeks
that you and Kenny were broken up.
We were talking
on the bleachers...
and "Rock Lobster"
started playing...
and you said
"I love this song,"
which I kinda took as a signal...
that you wanted to dance.
But...
I didn't ask you.
- Why not?
- 'Cause I can't dance.
- Tom.
- What?
- I'm goin' in.
- You're...
Hi.
- Oww.
- Oh. Oh.
Oh!
Hello?
So, how was the concert?
- Hey. Hey, Ruth.
- Is there something you
want to tell me, Tom?
- Hello?
- Mom, I'm on the phone here.
- Who's calling so late?
- Mom, please.
Well, is somebody
in there with you?
I heard somebody come in with you.
Is there a girl in there?
- Mom, I am on the phone!
- Jesus.
Are you still there?
I'm here.
I- I found your bracelet.
Is she there?
She's there, isn't she?
Are you gonna screw me, Tom?
Are you gonna screw me over?
You are, aren't you?
You're gonna screw me over.
You did what?
Don't make a big deal out of this.
You had sex with the dead guy's mother?
That lady from the funeral?
- The lady from the funeral.
All right, Brad?
- Did you tell Scott?
- I'm not talking to Scott.
- What do you mean?
- Scott's an asshole.
- What are you talkin' about?
- Brad!
- What's going on here?
Who are you these days?
- The point is, what am I gonna
do about Ruth Abernathy?
- What are you gonna do?
- You're gonna get out of there.
What are you, nuts?
- This is no good.
- Brad!
- Okay. Okay. We have to wrap this up.
Wrap it up?
We're nowhere, okay?
I'm in a dilemma, Brad. Look.
- What's that?
- That's her charm bracelet.
- The dead guy's mother?
- Ruth Abernathy.
- Her name is Ruth.
- Okay. Okay.
Take that friggin' bracelet and
drop it in the mail. You understand?
Write her a little love poem
and get rid of it, 'cause you're lost.
What are you saying? Just drop it
in the mail? That's your big solution?
- Get in here, Brad!
- Okay!
- I gotta go. That's three calls.
I gotta go.
- Brad...
Listen, that's all I got,
all right?
Mail it. Clean break.
Tom.
Look, it's good about you and Julie.
Don't worry about it.
Thanks, Brad.
It's my birthday.
I'm having brunch with
my parents on Sunday to celebrate.
That'll be nice.
Mmm.
It'll be the first time
I've seen them since I left Jed.
Mmm.
Would you go with me?
To meet your parents?
Yeah.
You want me
to meet your parents?
Yeah.
Is $15 enough?
Ma, the name of this place is
Chanterelle. That's $50 right there.
I'll get you another $5.
Tom?
Is that for you, Tom?
- Hello.
- Is Tom here?
Can you tell me
what this is regarding?
You know where he went?
Say something.
- Honey, could we just eat
first before we...
- Tom.
- Hi.
Hello.
Hi.
Tom, this is
my father Philip.
- It's really great to meet you, sir.
- I don't understand.
- And, uh,
- Excuse me, sir.
This is my mom Suzanne.
- Oh. Good morning.
- Hello. Are you eating here too?
Yes, Tom... Tom, uh,
is going to be joining us.
- I thought we were here to talk.
- Please, honey, don't get upset.
- I am upset.
- Oh. Um...
Uh, look, look.
This is my birthday, okay?
Tom is my guest.
All right? Okay?
I'm sorry. This is rude.
I just don't understand.
Could you tell me what he's doing here?
My daughter walks out
just before her wedding.
I've barely heard from her in two
months. I want to know what's going on.
- Well, that's understandable.
- Why is he talking?
- Are you sleeping with her?
Is that what this is?
- Dad!
- Philip.
- All right, I'll get to the point.
This trip...
we've all talked about it,
your mother and I and Grandma, and
we all agree... we don't understand it.
Sweetheart, listen,
a little vacation is a great idea.
Why would you want to waste
a year of your life?
Look, I don't want
a vacation, all right?
I'm...
I'm lost, okay?
I'm completely... lost.
I don't know what I'm doing with
my life, and I need to take this trip.
It's important, okay?
I mean, Tom understands, you know.
I feel like he's the only person
who understands what I'm doing.
That's sort of the reason
I wanted him here.
Tom, maybe
you could explain it to us.
Well, Mrs. DeMarco, Mr. DeMarco,
um, I can understand...
how you might not want Julie
to go away right now.
Uh, the truth is, it probably
has nothing to do with this trip.
It's probably because
you just don't want her to leave.
But... But I just think
that Julie feels...
Don't go, Julie.
- What?
- I don't want you to go.
I mean, a year?
- I thought we were doing something here.
- Tom, what are you saying?
- I told you this was
a temporary thing. I said that.
- I know.
I've never felt like this
in my whole life, Julie.
I feel like we... I mean,
I feel like... I really know you.
Don't you?
I mean, is it just me?
- Excuse me, ma'am.
- There you are!
- Who is this?
- Oh, my God!
- Mrs. Abernathy?
- I wanna talk to you.
- Ruth, this is not a good time.
- We're having a brunch here.
- We're going outside.
- This is the way you say good-bye?
- It was just for the sex, wasn't it?
- Jesus, Ruth.
- He's sleeping with everybody.
Have you been tested?
- What is she talking about?
And what's this lousy poem? Is this
supposed to mean something to me?
- You wrote her a poem?
- No. Let's go.
- Sex, sex, sex.
You're a horrible young man.
- Julie...
- Julie?
- Oh, is this her?
- Yes.
- This is Julie, and we're going.
- Tell her, Tom.
- Tell her what you did to
your best friend's mother!
- Oh, my God. Tom!
He wasn't my best friend.
- Julie.
- What are you talking about?
- Tom!
Look, Ruth,
I don't even remember Bill.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
# She's a super freak
Super freak #
# She's super freaky
Yeow #
# Everybody sing #
# Super freak
Super freak #
# She's a very special girl #
- # From her head down to her tail #
- Hey! Hey!
- How's about a little response?
Tommy, how ya doin'?
- Brad...
- Hey, nurse! Over here!
We got another patient!
- No, no! Don't, Brad! Don't!
- This is...
This is my good friend Tommy. We need
to give him a little mouth-to-mouth.
- Stop kidding, all right?
- Hey, what's the matter, man?
It's my last Tuesday!
- I'm gettin' married!
I'm happy. I'm happy.
- I know! I am too!
I'm just not in the mood, all right?
I forgot.
You don't like bachelor parties.
You only get turned on at funerals.
- All right, very funny.
- Nurse, please! You talk to him.
- No. I'm outta here. I'm leaving.
- Where are you going?
- Brad, get off!
- # That girl's a super freak #
- # I really like to taste her #
- # Every time we meet #
- Lauren is right about you.
- # She's all right, she's all right #
- I defended you.
- # The girl's all right #
- # With me #
- I said you'd come through
in the end, but she's right.
She told me not
to have you from the start.
She said Scott should be my best man.
- Scott? That's what she said? Scott?
- # She's a super freak #
- Yeah. 'Cause he's a better best man.
- # She's super freaky #
Don't marry her, Brad.
- # Temptations, sing #
- Hey.
Lauren's an albatross
around your neck, Brad. Don't marry her.
- Tommy...
- And by the way, Scott thinks so too.
# Whoa-ohh-ohh
Ohh-ohh-ohh-ohh #
# She's a very kinky girl #
# The kind you won't
take home to Mother #
Bastard!
Hey! Hey!
Let him go.
Are you okay? Tom...
- Get off me!
- Hey, asshole!
- Get out of my party! Get out of here!
- I saw you with her, Scott.
No one wants you here! Get out!
Get off of me, Joey!
I don't want him here!
You're not allowed!
- What happened?
- Scott!
- Tom?
- Yeah, Mom?
Scott's here.
So, what are you doing in here?
New carburetor.
Just checking the idle.
So, Brad's a little upset.
Tried talking to him, but...
Doesn't look like
you're gonna be the best man.
Well, you'd make a better best man
anyway, wouldn't you, Scott?
Cynthia kicked me out.
We had this little fight and it...
I don't even know what it was about.
Look, Tom, I'm really sorry.
I messed up.
Tasha Cortina.
- Oh. Tasha Cortina.
- Yeah.
But she had that lip thing.
- What lip thing?
- You know, that little scar.
- No, I liked that scar. It was sexy.
- For me, it ruined everything.
- Oh, you're too critical.
- Yeah.
- Boys?
- Ma! We're talk...
I can't believe
you just walk in here.
I'm 25 years old.
This is why I need the lock.
- I just wanted to know
if you want some ice cream.
- A little.
Seventh grade. Nancy Weinberg.
Oh, she liked me.
- She did not like you.
- She did.
She had this very serious thing,
like an obsessión.
No, don't you remember
Angela Mineri?
Angela Mineri told you Nancy Weinberg
had this big crush on you.
- You went up to Nancy
in front of everybody...
- Oh, no. Shit.
- And she laughed in your face.
- Yeah, that's right.
- It was the other Tom.
She had a crush on him.
- What other Tom?
The other Tom.
Wait, what are you saying?
- Oh, Jesus.
- Mr. Jellison's class.
- In eighth grade.
- He got a 58 in unit one algebra...
and then he started crying.
Whatever happened to that guy?
- He went to a different
high school... Madison.
- How do you know?
'Cause Nancy Weinberg kept on going out
with him all through high school.
Whatever happened to that guy?
I don't know. I heard that Nancy
Weinberg is in grad school at Yale.
Yale. Yale.
- Tom, what are you doing?
You're going now?
- I gotta go!
I've been driving all night.
I have to tell you something.
Can I come in?
Ruth, please.
You lied to me.
You used my son...
the memory of my son.
That was all I had left.
How could you do that?
I remember when my third-grade teacher
cut her finger on a paper cutter...
and had to go home.
I remember when Bruce Feinbaum
tripped Matthew Ellison...
during the fire drill...
An-and everyone laughed.
L... I have a really
good memory, Ruth,
but...
no matter how hard
I wracked my brain,
I couldn't remember your son.
The fact that I could...
forget him like that,
that his life could...
leave so little impressión on me,
that really scared me.
I mean, it...
It terrified me.
Because I wouldn't
want to be forgotten.
I- I'm sorry. Sh-Should
I just keep waiting in the car?
No, it's okay.
R- Ruth.
Um...
This is Tom Thompson.
Hi, Mrs. Abernathy.
He, uh, wanted you
to have his car.
Oh, no. No. No.
L... It'd be too sad.
Look, I have a car.
Well, l... I did put
some money into it.
You keep it.
Yeah?
So, uh,
you guys were close?
Not really.
We just knew each other.
It's so hard to let him go.
I don't know.
I mean,
I needed someone.
I needed someone too.
# Let the river #
# Rock you like a cradle #
# Climb to the treetops #
# Child, if you're able #
# Let your hands tie a knot #
- # Across the table #
- May He lift His countenance upon you...
- and grant you His most precious gift...
- # Come #
- # And touch the things
you cannot feel #
- and His blessings of peace.
- Amen.
# And close your fingertips #
# And fly where I can't hold you #
Mazel tov!
# Let the sun rain fall #
# And let the blue clouds
enfold you #
# And maybe you can sing to me #
# The words I just told you #
# With all the things
your feelings were facing #
# Then don't mind me #
# 'Cause I ain't nothin' #
# But a dream #
# The mockingbird
sings each different song #
# Each song has wings #
# They won't stay long #
# Do those who hear #
# Think he's doing wrong #
# While the church bell #
# Tolls its one-note song #
# And the school bell #
# Is tinkling to the throng #
# Come here #
# Where your ears cannot hear #
# And close your ears #
# Child, and listen
to what I'll tell you #
# Follow in the darkest night #
# The sounds that may impel you #
# And the song that I am singing #
# May disturb or serve to quell you #
# If all the sound
you're hearing is what they sing #
# Then don't mind me #
# 'Cause I ain't nothin' #
# But a dream #
# Mm-mmm-mmm-mmm, mmm ##
Julie.
Tom, leave me alone.
I just wanted
to give you this.
Julie, pl...
- Julie, wait!
- Tom, don't do this.
- Please, just take this.
- Tom.
I don't want this.
I'm going away.
It's a birthday present.
Belated. Please.
Please.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
The band is gonna take a short break
now, but we'll be back a little later.
I don't understand.
It has a new carburetor,
if that's what you're worried about.
Tom.
Uh, I can't take your car.
The tires are good
for another 10,000 miles,
so, you know,
that should take you...
wherever you wanna go.
It's a really good car.
Please take it.
I'll be your deejay
this evening spinning tunes.
We're gonna slow things down
with this one.
# Come to me now #
- # Lay yourself over me #
- I love this song.
- # Even if it's wrong #
- Is that a signal?
# We'll be all right #
# And I shall believe #
# Broken in two #
# And I know you're onto me #
# That I only come home #
# When I'm so all alone #
# And I do believe #
# That not everything is gonna be
the way you think it oughta be #
# It seems that every time I try to make
it right it all comes down on me #
# Please say honestly #
# You won't give up on me #
# And I shall believe #
# Open the door #
# And show me your face tonight #
# I know it's true #
# No one heals me like you #
# And you hold the key #
# Then not everything is gonna be
the way you think it oughta be #
# It seems like every time I try to make
it right it all comes down on me #
# Please say honestly #
# You won't give up on me #
# And I shall believe ##
- Hello?
- What's going on?
We have a problem here.
- Did you knock?
- I'm knocking. Hello!
Hello!
What's going on?
She won't come out.
Wh... Oh, Jesus.
Ma.
Ma, come on. I'm only
gonna be ten minutes away, Ma.
- No.
- We'll see each other all the time.
- I don't want you to go.
- Ma...
- Ma!
- Not now!
I just got over
that back injury from roller-blading.
I'm just saying,
this is getting heavier and heavier.
What happens when Julie comes back?
You'll have to move again?
- No, she gave it to me.
They're letting me rent it.
You wanna be careful
with my bunk bed?
You wanna complain, you pay.
So, is that, uh,
the last of it?
That's everything. Don't worry.
This is gonna be good, Tom.
- What if this job doesn't work out?
- Didn't you get the job already?
- Yeah, but what if it doesn't work out.
- It's gonna work out.
Come on, let's go.
- # Come a little bit closer #
- Tom, let's go.
- # Hear what I have to say #
- Come on, Tom.
It's getting late.
- Hey, Tom, come on!
- Tom, you ready?
All right, all right.
I'm ready.
- # Just like children sleepin' #
- Let's move.
# You'll dream this night away #
# But there's a full moon risin' #
# Let's go dancin' in the light #
# We know where the music's playin' #
# Let's go out and feel the night #
# Because I'm still in love with you #
# I wanna see you dance again #
# On this harvest moon ##
This is what I believe.
# Been so long since I met you #
# And all the changes we been through #
# And all this time I can't forget you #
# Everywhere I turn I think of you #
# I #
# Wanna trust ya, lady #
# And you #
# You're all I need #
# Soul to soul, fire to fire #
# Nothin' to light this man's desire #
# Love is a beautiful thing #
# One to one, you and me #
# Oh, I know it's our destiny #
- # 'Cause love is a beautiful thing #
- # Beautiful, so beautiful #
# To stay together
through thick and thin #
# Now I know I got a friend #
# 'Cause love is a beautiful thing #
# We've faced the fears
all through the years #
- # Now I know there are no more tears #
- # Love is a beautiful thing #
# Ahh, ohh-ooh #
# Soul to soul, fire to fire #
# Nothin' to light
this man's desire #
# Because love is a beautiful thing #
- # Ohh ohh-ohh #
- # Ohh-whoa-whoa #
# You and me
Oh, I know it's our destiny #
# Love is a beautiful thing #
- # Yeah-eah-eah #
- # It's a beautiful thing #
# It's a beautiful thing #
# Love is a beautiful thing #
# Ohh-ohh, ohh-ohh #
# Ohh, love is a beautiful thing #
# It's so beautiful, so beautiful #
- # It's so beautiful #
- # Whoa-ohh, ohh-ohh #
# Ahh-ahh #
# Beautiful, beautiful #
# It's beautiful, beautiful #
# Hey, I wanna embrace it in my heart #
# Beautiful, a beautiful thing #
# Oh, Lord, it's so beautiful #
# So beautiful, let's stay together #
# Let's stay together #
# 'Cause I'm still in love with you #
- # Hold me #
- # For the good times #
# I'm tired of bein' alone #
# Here I am #
- # Here #
- # Beautiful #
# It's a beautiful thing #
# Don't let nobody change your mind #
# It's a beautiful #
# Beautiful, ooh-hoo #
# Ohh ##