Mama, it isn't even finished.
it is as far as you're
concerned, young lady.
This is hardly the way to
spend a sunday morning
listening to a minstrel song.
It's papa's favorite.
It's not mine.
I'm going to put it up here
out of your reach.
No, mama I can pull the chair here
step up here,
and I've got it.
Well...
I'm going to put it up here
on top of the book shelf.
I see.
How about there?
I haven't figured that out... yet.
Well, at least
you're an honest child.
Mother?
Yes, augusta?
When I get ready
may I go on ahead?
I have to meet
stanley henderson.
You can't go like that, you're naked.
We're going to wait for your father
and then we're all going
to church together
just as if we belong
to the one family.
Oh, mother, his train might
not even get here on time.
If it doesn't, walter will call
from the station.
Walter?
Yes, ma'am?
Isn't it time that you were
leaving for the station?
I was just going, mrs. griffith.
Good.
Oh, mama I'm all ready.
Can I go with walter
to pick up papa?
Please, mama, please?
Can I, can I?
May i.
Please?
All right.
Weee! I'm going to pick up papa
I'm going to pick up papa!
I'm going to
pick up papa!
She does get a little hysterical
at the mention of papa,
doesn't she?
Now, stand up, there.
You see you keep
your dress clean.
Yes, mama.
My little consolation prize
come on now.
We're going to pick up papa, we're going...
slow down, child, or you'll us
yourself up before we get there.
Walter, does papa own the whole rail road?
No, he's just a superintendent.
Oh.
Being a superintendent is much
better than being the fellow
who owns the rail road.
- It is?
- Sure.
He gives out all the orders
and don't have to pay out
any salaries.
Walter, what's a consolation prize?
A consolation prize?
Oh, that's just a trifling
no-account nothing
that someone gets
when they loses.
Do you think I'm a trifling
no-account nothing?
Not you, child,
not you.
I bet neither does papa.
Won't you come home,
bill bailey?
Won't you come home?
She sings the whole night through?
I'll do the cooking, honey,
I'll pay the rent?
I know I've done you wrong?
Remember that rainy
evening, I threw you out?
With nothing but a fine-tooth comb?
I know that I'm to blame
and ain't it a shame?
Bill bailey won't you
please come home?
Won't you come home,
bill bailey?
Won't you come home?
She sings the whole night long?
I'll do the cooking, honey,
I'll pay the rent?
I know I've done you wrong?
Remember that rainy
evening I threw you out?
With nothing but a fine-toothed comb?
I know that I'm to blame
well ain't it a shame?
Bill bailey won't you
please come home?
Come home?
Bill bailey won't you
please?
Come home?
How sweet it is.
Have a little booze, pal.
Ah, no more for me,
I'm driving.
Oh, well how about you?
Oh, no thanks.
Then, in the case
of that thought
I'll just drink a little toast
to the best emergency crew
on the moonstar railroad.
Still got a little left. I'll
make it one for the road.
Well...
looks like we're gonna be
in grainseville on time.
I promised the family I'd
go to church with them
this morning.
Well, I could slow her up
or head off into the next siding.
Or drive into a creek
or something?
No, no, no.
It's about time I started
going to church again.
I'm a big boy now.
Got my library card
and everything.
I used to go all the time, you know.
I didn't mind it at all.
But then after...
hey, there's corrie!
Well, fellas,
thanks for the whistle.
Hiya, sweetheart!
Gosh, did I miss you!
Did you, papa?
Did you really?
You know you're just
like all the other females,
in desperate need of reassurance.
I promise,
while I was away
I didn't even think of any
other girl of six but you.
Oh, papa,
you're wonderful.
When I'm around you, I think I am.
How are you, walt?
How are you, mr. griffith?
Say you do look lovely in
that little white ensemble...
morning, mr. griffith,
back for a while?
Well, until the next
emergency, bert.
Good, good.
Before we go any further,
it's time for our history lesson.
Now, what is today,
july 8th, famous for?
You're going to church.
Besides that.
I don't know, papa.
There you go.
You forgot to look
at the calendar
before coming out of the house.
Now on july 8th 1779 the british
burned fairfield, connecticut.
You know, augusta came into the living room
almost naked.
I'm afraid my history lessons
are lost on you, corrie.
I think you're a trifle
more basic.
Now you wait here while papa
goes in and sends his report.
Morning, mr. griffith,
everything go well?
Well, I'd say fair
what?
Send this to the main office at fort worth.
Wreck at sidden's landing.
Two freight cars and one flat car derailed.
Track clear,
traffic proceeding normally.
Hey, mr. griffith, look
at the apple of your eye.
Corrie, get down from there!
You get down from there
right away!
That was right away,
wasn't it, papa?
Now what is your poor mother going to say
when she sees that dress.
Maybe if
I don't turn around.
You know who's gonna get
blame for this, don't you?
I'll tell her the truth
mother knows
I'm an honest child.
Never mind, I'll take the
rap, I'm bigger than you.
Now, I'll cover you
from the back
when you get into the house
you run up to your room
and take your dress off.
Thank you, papa.
Oh, it's really nothing
you only get one to five
as an accessory.
Good morning.
Now let's get right back
into the car,
we're late for church.
Nice to see you, dear.
Thank you.
Hello, papa.
Miss corrie, what happened to your dress?
Turn around.
Well young lady?
A funny thing happened to
us down at the station,
I was holding corrie
in my arms...
mother, I slid down
the coal chute.
With no help from your father?
No, I did it all by myself.
You really look a mess, corrie,
when are you gonna grow up?
Never! I've seen what it's done to you.
Now that's enough of that.
You go right into the house and
have ellie give you a bath.
Can't I stay home with her? after all,
that's a large bath tub,
she's liable to drown.
She's a very strong swimmer.
We are going to church
and corrie is going to say
her prayers at home.
I'll only pray for papa.
I think that's a very good idea.
Now you go.
Can't we wait for corrie to take a bath?
We'll only be a few minutes late.
Oh, father, we have
to be there on time.
I have a young man waiting
for me at the church steps.
Only one? hm!
Hardly seems worthwhile to make the trip.
Besides, mother has to
play the organ
at the services.
Your father seems to have
forgotten about that.
You two are up to it again.
Up to what?
Cutting corrie out,
excluding her from the family.
Jack, you talk such nonsense!
I get it's just a feeling
whenever I see the two of
you gang up on her.
I admit I could be wrong.
After all I voted for
william jennings bryan.
Three times.
It's no use trying to
discuss anything with you.
You just turn everything into a joke.
That's how I find things.
Well, I haven't got the
same escape that you have.
You've been in this condition
more and more often.
I am not in that condition.
If I were I would have slid down
the coal chute with corrie.
And you'd be taking a bath too.
And you wouldn't need to go to church.
It's a wonder
you didn't do it.
I didn't think of that.
Walter, I have told you again
and again not to come this way.
Just looking at that house
makes me physically ill.
Imagine anybody having the bad taste
to paint their house
that awful color.
I admit it's a little nauseous
at this time of the morning,
but at sunset it does have
a pretty effect.
It's original anyway.
I'd be eternally grateful
to anyone who would do something
about that terrible house
up to and including
burning it to the ground.
Father, if we're so late to church
that stanley henderson
III doesn't wait for me,
I'll... i'll not forgive
you till my dying day.
Step on it, walter,
we have two heathens
who are in desperate need of salvation.
Good morning, ma'am, good morning, augusta.
I'm sorry I'm late, stanley.
Oh, that's all right.
At least I won't have to
wait till my dying day.
I'll sit with augusta.
Suit yourself.
Good morning.
Good morning, amberlyn.
Good morning, stanley.
You can take your hands out
of your pocket, stanley,
the collection plate won't be
around for another half hour.
How would you even know they have one?
Good morning, amberlyn.
How do you do, dr. elkins?
I found this lost sheep
wandering around
the neighborhood.
Congratulations.
Now you'd better get to the organ.
Well, it's been a long time, jack.
Yes, it has, it has.
I haven't missed any of your sermons,
amberlyn repeats them
at home word for word,
especially the fire and brimstone type.
I think she's a little
worried about my soul.
Aren't you?
Well I have other problems like
keeping the trains on time.
Where's little corrie? she
following in your footsteps?
No, she's at home, praying for my soul too.
I've got so many people
praying for my soul,
anything I do personally
would be an anti-climax.
Mr. griffith, would you buy a raffle
for the church for 50 cents?
Now what would I do
with a church if I won one?
Jack, this is for the benefit
of the church fund.
Are you coming?
No, no, i...
i just thought of an emergency.
I'll see you next sunday.
Fortunately for you
I'm not a betting man.
You'll be missing a good sermon.
Ha ha, don't worry about
that, I'll hear it tonight.
Well, mr. loubie, how are you
this fine sunday morning?
Busy, mr. griffith,
very busy.
Mr. loubie, I'd like you
to have the pleasure
of purchasing the last ticket
on a very unusual raffle.
Raffle?
Not interested.
Oh, but this raffle was organized
by the railroad brotherhood,
for little tots left
homeless by train accidents.
Now you couldn't turn
down a cause like that?
Watch me.
But the tickets
are only 50 cents.
Oh, I know it's a real bargain,
but I think I'll have to turn it down.
Uh, in view of the fact that
this is the last ticket,
I have been given the authority
to reduce the price to 25 cents
and my daughter, corrie,
will draw the winning ticket
right here.
I have no change.
Don't worry about that, mr. loubie,
I personally will lend you a quarter.
There's the quarter
and here is your ticket.
Would you please draw?
I never win in a raffle
anyhow, number seven.
Number seven.
See what did I tell you?
Number seven?
That's me, I won.
You really couldn't lose mr.
Loubie, because...
here's the quarter you loaned me.
- Thank you.
- Now, what's the first prize?
Oh-ho-ho-ho,
now for the big moment.
Incidentally, the contents of this envelope
were sealed and unseen by any human eyes
since slipped within by a blindfolded
justice of the supreme court.
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh.
What is it, mr. griffith,
what is it?
Oh, mr. loubie,
you're gonna be thrilled
by this first prize.
What is it?
It's a complete paint job on
your house, free and clear
a paint job?
Everybody in town's been
trying to win this.
Well, I guess it's worth a quarter.
Now what color
would you suggest?
Oh, same color we got now,
just touch it up a bit.
Oh, uh, I'm afraid that we
couldn't possibly match that.
Well how about aquamarine?
Orange?
Yellow?
What colors do you have?
Ah, the raffle committee s
ays a beautiful ivory white,
this is used exclusively
by the country club set.
White...
well, just go ahead
and have it painted.
I'm sorry I got mixed up
in the whole thing.
I just don't know what's
happened to walter.
He always picks us
up after church.
It's a lovely day for a walk.
And mr. griffith will have
some explaining to do too.
Papa?
My father's right
about your father,
he tipples.
As far as I am concerned, stanley,
your father can go climb a tree.
Seems like that would be one
of your father's specialties.
I'm sorry you caught m e
spending my time like this
on the sabbath but mr.
Loubie just won a raffle.
And first prize
was painting his house?
I figured that was better than
burning it down to the ground.
I love you, jack griffith.
I think mr. loubie and I
are two very lucky people.
Mr. loubie wasn't so lucky,
every ticket had number seven
on it, he couldn't lose.
Well that's what happens
when you hire cheap labor,
they talk too much.
You look as though you're read
for another bath, young lady.
I haven't taken the first one yet, mother.
Well, all right.
You're not angry at me?
No more than george's mother
when he told her about the cherry tree.
See you later, darling.
All right, sweet heart.
Back to work.
Come in, father,
come in.
Folks, I'd like you all to
meet my father, anthony ghio,
mayor of texarkana.
How do you do, everybody?
Now I'm sure we'd all
appreciate a few words?
Of course, of course.
Last time your grandfather
restricted himself
to a few words, he was six months old
and his mother stuck a bottle in his mouth.
Dear friends of grangeville,
it's a constant pleasure to
come to your beautiful city
and spend a few days
with my daughter
and my two lovely grandchildren.
Notice how he left me out?
And it is also interesting
to see my son-in-law,
jack griffith, every once in a while.
I liked it better when he left me out.
But this party is not for
family reminiscences, no,
nor should I squander my, uh,
charming politic al personality
on citizens who are not
eligible to vote for me.
That reminds me of a story...
- father, father...
- there was... um...oh, yes.
Sit here, mr. ghio.
No, no, I'll just sit
back her out of the way,
thank you so much. thank you.
Everybody, miss freda summers
will now sing, "rose of tralee".
Papa, will you sing bill bailey later?
My agent couldn't book me in.
The pale moon was rising
up on the green mountain?
The sun was declining?
Beneath the blue sea?
When I strayed with my love
to the pure crystal fountain?
That stands
in the beautiful?
Vale of tralee
the cool shades of evening
their mantle were spreading
and mary was smiling, was listening to me
the moon through the
valley her pale rays...
I think I'd better go for the ice cream.
When I won the heart
of a rose of tralee
I bet he'll bring some
strawberry ice cream,
my favorite.
Well, I know he won't bring vanilla
because that's my favorite.
- Hi, norman.
- Hello, mr. griffith.
Gallon of ice cream, strawberry.
Yes, sir, right away.
You want me to mix it up
with a little vanilla?
- No, just strawberry.
- Yes, sir.
What is the matter with you?
Well, mr. griffith,
today is the day
joan ought to be having
that baby any minute now.
Oh, oh. well, what are you doing here?
Oh, it's all right,
I'll get a report.
We don't have a telephone
but old doc wright,
he's gonna wave
a handkerchief,
two waves if it's a girl
and one if it's a boy
and the wilson's
will call me here.
A boy or a girl? huh?
No, he's not in the store.
Yes, I'll tell him, goodbye.
Yes, honest, I'll tell
him, please, goodbye!
Norman, you should be home.
Why didn't cosgrove
give you some time off?
Oh, he had to go home for lunch.
Look, you go ahead
and I'll fill in for you
till he gets back.
Oh, mr. cosgrove
would kill me.
A husband should be with his wife
at a time like this.
Are you sure you have time, mr. griffith?
Oh, don't worry about that,
there's still three tenors
and a coloratura
on the program.
You can have a large
family before they finish.
Well thank you, mr. griffith, thank you.
Go ahead.
Won't you come home
bill bailey
won't you come home
she sings the whole night through
anyone here?
Well...
what can I do for you, sir?
A penny's worth
of jelly beans.
A penny's worth of jelly beans.
A penny's worth
of jelly beans.
There doesn't seem to be any jelly beans.
You see the trouble is
they've been shifting...
are you new or something?
As a matter of fact, I am.
Say...
would you do me a favor?
What?
You see I gotta make
some banana splits,
and I'm a little
out of practice,
now if I made one,
would you eat it?
I don't have enough money.
Oh, don't worry about that,
sit right down, son.
You see today we have a
special on banana splits,
one penny.
Can I go get my brothers and sisters?
Well, when you taste it
you might not like it.
Try that on for size.
You forgot the cherry.
Well I told you I was out of practice.
Hi, cosgrove.
There's one for your sister.
That's better, here's your penny.
Penny?
Keep your shirt on, cosgrove,
I'll make up the difference.
Where's norman?
I sent him home to his wife.
Well he can stay there
as far as I'm concerned
- he just lost his job.
- Wait a minute,
you can't fire norman
with a new baby
and another mouth to feed.
Any law in the land says
I have to feed it?
How can you be so mean? because I enjoy it,
a man can't really do anything
well unless he enjoys it.
Let's go in the back for
a little cough medicine.
Not on me, you don't have a drink!
I'll buy the bottle, diamond jim.
Nothing like security.
Oh, pardon me.
And 49 cents for the triple banana split.
Here's 50 cents, I gave
him an extra cherry.
...
you, uh.
You didn't pour me even, jack.
There you are, doctor.
Good luck.
...
say.
Did you ever think of selling this store?
Well, I might.
You can't get any decent
help around this town.
Now I have to look around for
somebody to take norman's place.
That'll be a kick in the head for him.
You're a tough man to get mellow.
You, uh, you thinking of buying?
Well, I got a little
syndicate lurking around
for a small investment.
You've got it if I get the right price.
What do you consider the right price?
How about that?
No, but I'll come down a little.
Tell you what, cosgrove,
- suppose we split the difference?
- Ok, I'll be losing money
but I don't want to use
any more of that pad.
Of course if we make a deal
I'd expect you to hang around for a month
you know, so the new owner
gets things ship-shape.
I'd put that in the agreement.
Well, cosgrove,
I think we could say we got a deal.
Here's the ice tea.
Oh, how nice.
And the sandwiches are in the icebox.
Thank you sweetheart.
Now then, dear,
I'll be back,
in two to three hours.
Don't rush, darling,
take your time.
Bye, bye daddy.
Bye, sweetheart.
Now as to the notes
of our last meeting...
feed the kitty
don't you ever bring a full bottle?
Clear the court.
Gentlemen do you realize
on july 19th, 1848,
the first women's rights convention
was held at seneca falls
in the state of new york.
The north is just the only place
they can get away with it.
Ever since that day we men
have been in trouble.
Women are running everything.
It's on account of women
that the drug stores
don't open on a sunday morning.
No speeches, just shoot.
How sweet it is.
I let it ride.
Now, if we get a cold or a cough
and want a shot of medicine,
we have to wait till sunday afternoon.
But for the measly sum of $500 each,
we can own that drug store
lock, stock and barrel
and it's the barrel we're interested in.
Are you going to shoot?
Oh!
Ha ha,
there it is again.
I should have let him keep talking.
Well don't let it be lonely,
fill it up, fill it up.
Also for the measly sum of $500,
we'll each receive a
nice profit every month
besides, each having a private key,
in case we get thirsty on a sunday morning.
A key, sounds good to me.
- Count me in.
- Not me, not a chance.
I have more practical
things to do with my money.
You're covered.
You know my station
agent' s been telling me
about those little train trips
you've been making to waco.
I told him that they were undoubtedly
for business purposes
and that girl you meet
every week up there
must be a close relative
like a cousin or something.
Come to think of it,
I've always wanted
to own a drug store.
Count me in.
I thought you'd feel that way.
How about you, frank?
Sorry, not me.
Now, I never wanted to bring this up but...
remember you were filling
out that bill of lading
for the insurance company
to get your settlement?
Now I wonder if they knew... count me in.
Me too before you start
digging in to my past, ho-ho!
How about you, leopold?
I've never done anything wrong in my life.
Except that once at the creek...
ok, shoot, blackmailer
I will pass out the keys
to my friends next week.
On with the game.
How sweet it is.
My partner, mr. keith,
will give you some passes for the circus
in return for your graciousness.
There you are, young
man, two passes for you.
- Thank you.
- And two passes for you, sir,
thank you very, very much.
Now just a minute,
since you won't be working here next week,
you won't be needing these.
- Hello, norman.
- Hiya, cosgrove.
Here's the paper,
here's the check.
Sign the paper and the check is yours.
Norman, you are now in
full charge of the store.
- Me?
- Oh yes...
my syndicate requires that they
receive 50% of the profits
for their investment.
The other 50% is yours.
Agreeable?
I can't believe it.
Now you can have all the
babies you wanna have.
50%, my goodness.
Oh yes, ah, there is another
little clause in the contract.
Mr. cosgrove will stay on for one month
and work under your supervision.
Well I guess you can't really
find good help in this town.
Well, I guess that's true.
But do the best you can.
You poor soul.
Oh, uh, cosgrove. what do you want?
Those passes for the circus,
I don't think you'll have time to go.
Oh and clean up the prescription counter.
It's a mess.
I want to talk to you, jack.
Well, shall I drop everything?
Later will do, smarty boots,
let's get corrie to bed.
What do you want to talk to papa about?
She's my manager.
Young lady,
I'm going to be as honest
with you as you are with me,
it's none of your business.
Now you get down and say your prayers
- and then you get into bed.
- Just a moment,
we will now have our history lesson.
What is tomorrow famous for?
Washington went to connecticut
to become general.
Not even close
- wyoming made it to the union.
- No chance.
I don't know, papa.
The circus is coming to town.
Oh, papa, can we go, can we go?
Sure we can go.
Yes, well, now that's the end
of her sleep for tonight,
she'll be dreaming of giraffes
now you say your prayers.
God bless mama, god bless
papa, god bless augusta,
god bless walter and ellie, good night.
How about grandpa?
- But he's back in texarkana.
- God looks over that city too.
God bless grandpa.
Goodnight, baby.
Good night, sweetheart.
And please, god, if you
make mama happy with papa,
I'll mind my own business, thank you.
Jack, remember me?
Oh, yes, you wanted to talk to me.
So that's what you did with my cigars.
How much did you pay for the drug store?
- What drug store?
- How much?
Well, I didn't buy it alone.
I happen to represent a syndicate.
How much?
You see fred thought it
would be a good idea
if we all chipped in, I was against it.
I didn't want to be the
only one to hold out.
How much?
$500 a piece, but we'll get it back.
Sure, in cough medicine alone.
This happened to be a very
smart business maneuver.
Every time you have one too many,
you make a smart business maneuver.
Are you through with me? yes.
Then I beg to be excused.
Sure, why don't you run
down to the drug store
and start liquidating your investment?
Well, now, I just might do that.
Papa, pick me up.
Tell me what you see.
Wild animals,
ladies on horseback,
cowboy and indians,
two elephants,
and oh, papa! what is it?
Oh my, the most beautiful
pony and cart I ever saw!
You must really like it from
the sound of your voice,
It went up two octaves.
Oh, papa, if someone
ever bought that for me,
I'd never want another
present in my whole life.
Would you mind putting that
in writing, young lady?
Oh, papa, don't make a joke I love tossy.
Who?
Tossy, that's the pony's name.
You've named her already?
Sure, when you love someone very much,
you've got to call it by a name.
That's the quickest love affair on record.
And when you're away on a trip,
I'd have someone to talk to.
What about mama and augusta?
Oh, they're always too busy,
besides I could do errands for you
and tossy could take me to school.
You can't beat that for a practical gift.
Then you mean you'll get it for me?
It might warp your whole life if I didn't.
Besides, 20 years from now
I wouldn't want you to blame
everything on your poor father
just because he refused to buy you a pony
you could talk to.
Oh, pop, I love you, love you, love you.
Where's the pony and cart?
Now, corrie, there are other
wonders in this world
just look around, look at all this.
I can't see tossy.
Thank you.
Ok, up you go.
What about tossy?
When do I see her?
Well, don't you wanna see
the bareback riders,
they're terrific and the trapeze artists
- are coming on soon.
- I wanna see tossy.
You're a railroad man's daughter all right.
You've got a one-track mind.
Well, I'll look for the circus owners.
Your father is about to
drive a hard bargain.
Please, papa, not too hard bargain.
You're right, I wouldn't want
Tossy to think she came cheap.
She might get a little sulky.
All right, hop up.
Now you sit right here
and I'll be right back.
Who do you think that is?
Oh-oh, could be the sheriff.
Nah, he doesn't come around
till about the second day.
Besides he's too fancy.
Hey, you don't think it could
anyone with good news, do you?
Not a chance. but we
might as well find out.
Such terrible trouble now,
nothing else could happen.
All right, what do you want?
Are you a kicker?
Or a rube with a paper up his sleeve.
Well, your language is very fascinating
but I'm afraid I don't understand you
all right, pal, now are you or
are you not a process server?
Oh, no, my name's jack griffith.
I'm a railroad man.
I came here to make an arrangement
with the circus owners for
their financial benefit.
Are you harvey and keih? we ain't saying.
I'm harvey and this is keith.
Why don't you step inside and have a drink?
Thank you.
What are you doing...
financial benefit, you idiot.
Well, looks like somebody's
having a good time.
Oh, papa, he ate fire and cooked a chicken.
Wonderful!
Say, uh, didn't you want a pony?
- Yes.
- And didn't you want a cart?
Uh-huh.
Well, you have a pony and a cart.
Oh, thank you, papa!
Thank you!
I'll never want another
present in my whole life.
I hope not.
You know the owners wouldn't sell the pony
and the cart by itself, I had
to buy the whole circus.
I just want tossy and the cart.
You can keep the rest of it.
Thank you.
I sure hope that pony can talk.
Let's go get her.
Well, I promised mr. harvey and mr. keith
that I'd keep mum about the whole deal
for at least 24 hours.
Yeah, we wanna break the news
to our kinkers in our own way.
Kinkers?
Kinkers are what they call the people
who work in a circus.
How do we know we can trust
the kid to keep quiet?
I wouldn't worry about that if I were you.
Can I see my pony now? sure, sure.
Follow me.
Oh, tossy! you're all mine.
We'll have such fun together.
Well, I guess it was a bargain at that.
We can take her home now, can't we, papa?
The pony goes with the
works when it's paid for.
You see the money to make
the purchase is in the bank
and the bank doesn't open until tomorrow
and they have another show
and another parade tomorrow
and they need tossy to advertise it.
Well tomorrow
it'll be my pony,
and I want to ride her
in the parade.
It'll be perfectly all right.
I mean, as soon as the deal goes through.
I suppose, I'll own these too?
You know I always wondered
what it would be like
to own an elephant. now I own two of them.
They don't take any care at all.
Nope, all you gotta do is feed 'em.
I never thought of that. they
never lay down to sleep.
They rock and eat, eat and rock,
take on better than a hundred pounds a day.
Each?
- Sure.
- Will you shut up.
100 pounds a day.
I never figured on that.
- Just hay, hay is cheap .
- just hay?
Well, you don't have to buy
grass when you can find it.
Don't forget people feed 'em all the time,
apples, peanuts, sugar
candy, they'll eat anything.
But 100 pounds a day,
people would have
to feed them people.
They aren't any more are there?
No, just these two.
Oh, they never touch meat.
The way things are going
I'm not likely to touch it
for quite some time either.
Well, see you at the bank in
the morning bright and early.
A hundred pounds a day. each.
That's 36,500 pounds a year.
And all on account of a pony.
Oh, you'll get to love tossy
as much as I love her.
Oh I'm madly in love with her now.
Let's hurry home, papa, I'm hungry.
You'd better get used to that, corrie.
Beginning tomorrow we have
two of the largest mouths
in show business to feed.
Now we don't wanna get
caught so eat quietly.
Mama told me to chew my food well.
Then we've reached an impasse.chomp away.
Who's in there?
Nobody but us chickens
and one of the chickens
is starving to death.
She's had a long day at the circus.
I've been worried.
The circus has been over for hours.
Well, I had no way to
get in touch with you.
Didn't you give her anything?
She's eating like a...
like a young elephant.
No mama, an elephant eats 100 pounds a day.
Mostly grass.
Don't talk while you're eating
even when you're not eating.
I think she has a fever. just
look how flushed she is.
And look how flushed you are.
It's my natural coloring,
I spent a lot of time outdoors.
I know that flush. that
flush comes from indoors.
Now come along, young
lady, you've had enough.
I'm gonna put you to bed.
I'll get an apple,
for tossy.
And who is tossy?
Oh, it's a new little friend of corrie's.
She's going to walk her
to school every day.
Very cute too.
Has big grey eyes,
long pony tail.
Goodnight, papa.
I'll say a special prayer for you tonight,
because you're the smartest one of all.
Out of the mouth of babes
comes sheer nonsense.
Come along.
Better make up your mind soon
the carpet's beginning to go.
Are you sure you know
what you're doing, jack?
I certainly do,
so take your hands
out of your pockets
and start counting.
Well I thought that drug store transaction
was pretty simple minded,
but this takes the cake.
Why are you buying a circus?
I happen to be madly in love
with the coochie dancers.
It is a wonder amberlyn
doesn't have you committed.
That's because she is
madly in love with me.
Now will you please give them the money?
It'll be all right,
henry.
Ah, thank you mr. griffith,
and, ah, see you at the circus.
Oh, we think the elephant's pregnant.
Gee!
Well you're over 21, but my son isn't.
Well know what is that supposed
to mean, your son isn't?
It means that a father can
still influence his offspring
in the choice of family
he might marry into.
You listen to me laughing gas,
there's two sides to that coin
and when the profits from
that circus start to roll in
I might put them in another bank.
I hope you'll be happy
with your coochie dancer,
- mr. griffith.
- Thank you, stanley
don't forget,
he thinks the elephant is pregnant.
If it's a boy I'll name him after you.
Well, I guess there's nobody in there.
Oh, uh, pardon me, sir, uh, ma'am,
could you tell me where
I might find mr. harvey?
Why?
Well I'm supposed to meet him
here at the head of the parade.
Went to town this morning with keith.
I know that I met him there
and did a little business with him.
But he was supposed to be back here.
Hold on.
Sparrow!
Talk to this guy, will ya?
I'm in charge here what's the trouble?
Well, there's no trouble,
I'm looking for mr. harvey.
Well that usually spells
trouble he's not around
you better go back to town and hunt him.
Oh, look for some beautiful
dames. You'll find him.
Let's get the parade moving!
No, the parade can't start without us,
it mustn't start!
Well, I'm afraid it'll have to, young lady.
- Papa, do something!
- Just a minute.
This parade doesn't start
until I say so.
What were you saying about
this parade not moving?
Wait a minute, you people
are getting the wrong idea.
I happen to be the new
owner of this circus.
What?
- Well didn't mr. harvey tell you?
- No
well here are the papers.
Oh, it looks legal all right.
Oh, don't worry about that, it's legal,
and my daughter, corrie, has her heart set
on riding that pony and
cart during the parade.
Well, let's not hold up the
parade it's getting late.
What are you standing around?!
Go with your daddy.
Ok, leo, out, and get in the back wagon.
Get in, honey.
We'll talk this over I
ater in the cook tent
- while we're having some
grub.
- that's ok with me.
Well, here we go.
Well hold her down, lou, hold her down!
Step up front, mister, step up front.
Now do you think tossy
will be strong enough
- to pull the both of us?
- She better be
after all the trouble you've
been through for her.
You could have fooled me,
I thought I went through
all this trouble for you.
Let's move it out, mister. move it out.
I'd like to speak to mrs. griffith, please.
Why mr. henderson, how nice.
Amberlyn, I didn't want to intrude
while you were having
your friends for tea...
well, come on in and have some with us.
Oh, no, thanks, no, thanks,
I just thought, uh...
there is something you ought to know.
You'll know it in a minute.
I suppose he's in that
delicat condition again?
Oh, mother, in front of stanley's father
and all your friends.
Do you know about that drug store madness?
Well, this folly he took on all by himself,
he owns the circus.
Augusta, what am I going to do?
Faint, mother, faint.
Get some water, somebody.
Help me get her inside
that's pete,
he's always playing up to
the owner of the circus
I guess he got the word on you
I wonder what he's bucking for
you suppose he wants my job?
Maybe he wants to become a partner?
Nah, he's to smart for that.
Did you see harvey anywhere in town
while the parade was going through?
No, isn't he here?
He promised to run the circus for me,
that's a fine way to run a circus.
Oh, will you get lost, pete,
don't you see this fella's in trouble?
- Trouble?
- Oh, quiet, sparrow
- mind your own business.
- Let him talk,
I feel sorry for the poor
guy, he's really been took.
You know, I'm just starting to get it.
No, you got it. did you give him a check?
No, they insisted on cash.
They didn't dream about girls
when they went to bed,
they dreamed about someone just like you.
All right, petey, that's good.
I guess they didn't bother to tell you
the show carried over 20,000 in mortgages?
And they're way overdue and
just about to be called in
let's stop worrying about mortgages
and start doing a little
talking about back salaries.
- Back salary?
- All right, pete.
And you're the new owner,
and what are you going to do about it?
Well, I could climb up on a
high wire and end it all,
but for some reason rather I feel sorrier
for harvey and keith than I do for myself.
I don't understand you, mr. griffith,
aren't you gonna get the
law on those two grifters?
No, I don't think so.
Whatever they're looking for I
don't think they'll find it.
Besides, they haven't even got pete now.
Go, pete!
Hey, birthday time.
Happy birthday!
Happy birthday, dear.
This is very nice, but it isn't my birthday
you mean your father bought you a circus
and it isn't your birthday?
- No.
- Now wait a minute!
Any time a father buys his girl a circus
that's her birthday!
Ladies and gentlemen,
since I am the new owner of this circus
I feel that I should take
care of my obligations.
I'm going to make out a check
for the rest of the balance
I have in the bank,
I don't know whether it will take care
of all of the back salaries,
but it's the best I can do.
For he's a jolly good fellow
for he's a jolly...?
Wait a minute, wait a
minute, wait a minute.
I don't wanna give you
the wrong impression,
I am not a jolly good fellow.
It just so happens,
that the fellow who owns and runs the bank
is a mean, nasty old man.
And I'd rather not leave
my money in that bank.
There's the check.
Corrie, let's go home.
Come on, up to now it's been a
very long, unbelievable day.
Shouldn't we take some cake?
I don't think so.
Let's not get used to the good life.
- So long everybody.
- So long.
Ho-ho, well, thank you, pete.
What are we gonna do now, papa?
Well, I guess it's time to
go home and face the music.
There might not be much music.
Well...
first I wanna make a stop.
At the drug store?
You know, there's a lot
of your mother in you.
Augusta?
Why are you crying? what happened?
Oh, like you care!
Of course I care, what is it?
My life's over that's all.
Stanley's father won't
let him see me any more.
Well, that's the best
news I've heard today.
Of course, it hasn't been such a good day.
Don't you understand that
this is the best thing
that could have happened to you?
Now if he really loves you,
nothing his father will say
will keep him from coming around.
You know, your mother's father
didn't want me around either.
She mentioned that several times today,
after mr. henderson
told her about
how you bought that circus. aha!
I promise you father, if I
can't see stanley any more...
I know you won't forgive
me until your dying day.
Corrie, you better go home with her
she's liable to try something desperate
like tearing my pictures
out of the family album.
I think mother's done that already.
Walter.
What's going on here?
Walter, will you please tell mr. griffith
that we are go ing to my father's
and that ellie will see to his needs here.
Mrs. griffith says she's...
i heard, I heard.
Amberlyn, will you please let me explain.
I don't wanna go.
I don't wanna leave papa and tossy.
Father, you have ruined my life.
Will you come to your senses?
Walter, what are you waiting for?
Can I go and kiss ellie goodbye?
Nobody's kissing anybody,
goodbye, just drive, please.
How about a belt?
Don't look at me like that
so I bought the kid a pony and a cart.
What's so excruciating about that?
You know, she's your baby too.
All right...
so I'm impulsive, expulsive,
repulsive, pulsive.
Oh, you beautiful doll,
you miserable soul.
Call me irresponsible
call me unreliable
throw in undependable too
do my foolish alibis
bore you
well I'm not too clever I just adore you
call me unpredictable
tell me I'm impractical
rainbows I'm inclined to pursue
call me irresponsible
yes, I'm unreliable
but it's undeniably true
i'm irresponsibly mad
for you
what's happened to us
we used to have fun together
whenever I did anything cr
azy you'd start laughing.
Remember the time at the picnic
when I put the sack over mrs.
Bonetti's head?
You fell down laughing
that was the 4th of july
picnic, remember that?
Later on we went down to the river
and we watched the fireworks.
Just you and I
what happened to us?
It's like you never left.
You still won't talk to me.
What's goin' on down there?
Oh, hello, mr. griffith.
We just ran out of grass
up at the fairground.
Is this all right?
Maybe grass ain't the answer
a pregnant elephant might want
some ice cream and pickles.
100 pounds a day.
I'm gonna end up with a fat elephant.
First time I ever ended
up with two empties.
Thank you, walter,
and now will you go and help the girls
with their things please? yes, ma'am.
I must say, father,
you don't seem to make us very welcome.
Well, what do you expect?
Descending on a man like a gypsy caravan,
flowers and candy? of
course you're welcome.
I never understood how you
tolerated that buffoon
for the last 15 years.
18 years.
And we could go and stay with
aunt harriet in houston.
Oh, stop talking like either
one of your children.
It's just that you arrived a couple of days
before an election, that's all.
My campaign manager tells
me I'm going to lose.
Oh, father, you never lose an election.
That's what I told him.
But he says I've got to stoop
to modern methods now,
I've gotta start kissing babies
and giving away free beer and hot dogs,
and shaking hands with people.
I'd just like to see that.
I have been mayor of
texarkana for eight years
on a simple platform, texas for texans.
And if they don't like it
they can go across the str eet to arkansas.
None of this nonsense about all
men are created free and equal.
If they were so free and equal
let 'em shake hands with each other.
That's the spirit, father!
You'll give us back to england again yet.
Now, don't you get sarcastic
with me, young lady,
just because you can't
hold on to your husband.
Now what did I say?
What did I say to...
oh, nobody understands me.
It's a good thing women can't vote,
we'd be worse off than we are now. i...
nice to have you back, honey.
Please, ellie, you'd better talk to mr.
Griffith,
otherwise we'll never get home.
Oh, what's wrong now?
Nobody's talking to nobody down here,
the children are crying,
mrs. griffith locks herself in her room,
and if mr. ghio don't win this election,
things are gonna get worse.
You've got to talk to mr. griffith,
he might know what to do.
But, walter, mr. griffith
is in that condition again.
Honey, that's where he gets his best ideas.
Oh, I gotta hang up now.
And there's never been a man
in the history of texas,
and texas has had a long
and illustrious history,
who has done more for the town
than our incumbent mayor,
anthony ghio.
I feel that all of you good
people are in my family,
and if there's anyone with
in the sound of my voice,
that hasn't met my katie or my children,
I want y'all to come up to the house
and have a sunday dinner with us.
And now, for the third time,
our honorable mayor is appealing
to the decent citizens of
texarkana for their votes.
Without succumbing to the
low tactics of his opponent
who is procuring his votes
by giving things away.
Giving things away!
What did you ever get from ghio?
Nothing!
But I promise you if I am elected mayor,
I promise you from the
bottom of a big texas heart
that I'll listen to my neighbor's opinions,
both big and small.
I think grandpa better
start giving things away.
You be quiet, young lady.
And now good friends, folks,
good friends of texarkana,
it is now my extreme privilege and pleasure
to introduce our candidate,
the julius caesar of texas,
anthony ghio.
You just got here in time
for the decline and fall
of the roman empire. no chance?
The ides of march are upon us,
caesar should have stood in bed.
My friends of texarkana,
if you want to get your babies kissed,
if you don't care what happe
nsto this beautiful city,
if you don't...
vote for ghio!
A vote for ghio is a vote for progress!
Come on and join the ghio bandwagon!
Vote for ghio!
Everybody welcome!
You're all invited, come one come all,
enjoy the circus and it's for nothing.
You're all guests of the voter's friend,
mayor ghio!
Vote for ghio!
- Papa
- corrie, come on, get in.
I knew you would come, I knew you'd come.
If I had as much confidence
in me as you have,
I'd run for mayor myself. I'd vote for you.
Yeah?
I wonder if your mother would.
Let's go there.
What a trick!
How did you happen to think of it?
My son in law bought the
circus just for tonight.
Pretty smart, huh?
- Speech!
- No, no, wait.
This is no time for long-winded speeches.
So what do you say we all go to the park
and get free ice cream and free hot dogs?
I think I'll go with grandpa, mother.
Where's corrie?
In the pony cart with papa,
on the arkansas side.
So that's his plan . he's kidnapping her,
he's taking her across the state line.
I want corrie.
Not as much as I do.
Remember, you're in arkans as now amberlyn,
you try to get her back
without extradition.
You've been drinking?
Yeah, but I'll be sober
in the morning. get up!
You come right back here!
Amberlyn, amberlyn,
what happened?
My hand!
Help me, sparrow.
You can go in now, mr. griffith.
How is she?
There's some muscle
damage on the right hand,
oh, it'll be fine for all normal purposes.
As far as playing the
piano, I don't think so.
You could be mistaken.
Well let's say that...
i have been.
Don't stay too long,
I've given her a sedative.
Amberlyn..
I'm sorry.
Don't be too sorry.
It was partly my fault.
Chasing that stupid pony cart.
I'll make it up to you,
I promise.
I thought that if we left
you for a little while...
it might bring you to your senses.
Had the opposite effect.
Amberlyn, you've gotta believe me.
I've had enough.
There's nothing I can say?
I've heard all the words
and don't tell my father about my hand,
I don't want to spoil this day for him.
Can I go in and talk to mama?
I don't think so, sweetheart,
the doctor gave her some medicine.
Like the medic ine you take, papa?
No, not exactly.
I don't feel like going
back to the circus, do you?
No, I don't either.
My bonnie lie
s over the ocean
he's making friend
s.
and votes.
Thanks, frank, here, have
a cigar, have a cigar.
Well, jerry, have a cigar.
What happens to the circus now?
Oh, your son in law will lose it.
Easy come, easy go
but at least he made two children happy.
What do you mean by that?
Well, corrie got her pony,
and you're a cinch to get yourself elected.
Y... huh?
Thank you...
have a cigar.
That's the fourth time
he's shaken hands with me.
What do you think he wants?
Would lieutenant governor be too much?
Have a cigar.
Have you got a letter for me too?
I ran out of ink.
Have you been spying?
I sure have.
You remind me of george washington
saying farewel I to his troops.
More like sherman retreating to the sea.
Too bad you're going,
I was just getting to the point
where I could tolerate you.
If I could believe that, I'd stay.
So long.
Mother!
Where's papa?
I looked everywhere. he's not around.
He went away, darling.
Where'd he go?
Did he leave you a letter?
I got one too.
"Dear augusta, take good
care of your mother,
"try to be as much like her as you can."
"she's the sweetest
person I've ever known."
well then why did he go awayr?
Perhaps we...
we were both at fault.
I don't want any old letter,
I wanna be with papa!
Now where is he?
I don't know, baby,
but when he's ready, he'll let us know.
All we can do now is pray.
I'm not gonna pray again
until papa comes back.
She's just a child, she
really doesn't understand.
She may understand.
Better than either of us.
Grandpa, please.
Please what?
Please find my papa.
Oh, what are those?
Tears?
Ooh, my, my, my.
Young lady, I think you and I
had better have a heart to heart talk, mm?
Do you see that picture
over the mantelpiece there?
Yes, sir.
Well that is the ghio family crest.
Yes, grandpa.
And do you see the armored helmet,
with the three feathers of
royalty on top of the shield?
Yes, sir.
Well that means that the ghios
were members of the knights
of the royal army of tuscany
and no knight worthy of
his name ever cried.
No, sir.
No one of the house of ghio ever cries.
Yes, sir.
Now wouldn't you like to carry on
the tradition of this
great and noble family?
Wouldn't you like to be the most beautiful,
- the most aristocratic and...
- I want my papa
all right, we'll find your papa.
Thank you, grandpa
somewhere in these united states,
he has a job with the railroad, find him.
But, mayor, there must be
thousands of railroad lines
In continental america
well, that gives you
lots of places to look.
Goodbye.
Oh
Mother, you're playing!
Corrie, what are you doing
home from school so early?
I spilt some ink on my dre ss,
but your hand is all better.
You can play. yes, corrie.
Papa will be so happy
when grandpa finds him
papa isn't going to know,
and I didn't mean for you to find this out.
But why not?
Does augusta know?
She's older. she can keep a secret.
A secret?
Corrie, you're six going on seven.
I don't think that that's
quite old enough to be trusted.
I'm an honest child, you said so.
A little too honest sometimes.
Now, this is a secret and
if papa comes back to us,
it has to remain a secret.
He must never, never know
that my hand is well enoug to play again.
He must not be told, you understand?
No,
he loves your music,
he'll be so glad your hand's not broken.
I see that I'll have to
explain this more clearly.
When your father has had
too much to drink...
medicine.
Well, we'll call it that
for the time being.
When he has too much medicine,
he does foolish things
and that keeps us apart.
Oh!
Well, now, if he doesn't
know that my hand is better,
there's just a chance
that he won't drink the medicine any more
and then we can all be together again.
Now do you understand?
I think so.
I'll keep it a secret,
but I think it's foolish.
Well you just indulge
your foolish old mother.
Now then,
I think it's about time we all
went back home to grangeville.
And wait for papa there? perhaps.
Oh, mother, I love you.
I don't care if I am a consolation prize.
Now then, you just run upstair
s and get into a clean dress.
I can't understand why you'r
all rushing off so quickly.
Well, we felt that we'd
overstayed our welcome,
practically as soon as we got here.
I'll miss you, grandpa.
I'll miss you too, dear.
Your daughter seems all smiles
and cheerful for a change.
Yes, well, she received
a letter this morning.
From stanley henderson III,
he says he's gonna stand up to his father.
- Stanley henderson II.
- the second.
And see me whether he likes it or not.
Aha, well, nothing's changed.
I remember when a daughter of
mine went with a young fellow
that I didn't approve of
and she stood up to me
whether I liked it or not, 15 years ago.
- 18 years ago.
- All right, 18.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, father.
- Goodbye, children.
- Thank you.
All right, walter, have a good trip.
Goodbye.
Grandpa, don't just stand
there start looking for papa.
I've started, honey, I've started.
Well, mr. ghio,
did your train get on the wrong track?
No, the right one.
It's been a long dusty ride
though, I'll tell you that.
I'm a little parched.
Oh.
You're looking well.
Uhh, no thanks.
My cough has been cured for good.
Oh!
I've... i've been talking to
the president of the railroad,
he tells me you're doing a great job.
Is that so?
I could put you in touch wit h
my parole officer if you want.
You like ah, working here
in louisiana, do you?
Ha ha, it's better than
wrestling alligators.
I suppose I could be standing here all day
before you'd break down and ask me,
but your family is fine,
they went back home.
They're waiting for you, jack.
Which of the family is waiting for me?
You're worse than I in my prime.
All right I'll give it to you straight,
that little heathen corrie,
practically made me take an oath in blood
that I'd find you and get you back to her.
It's a notion.
I could take a little train
trip on the weekend.
I get to ride free, you know?
I wouldn't want to miss
an opportunity like that.
Especially when you've got
some place to ride to.
Yes, yes.
Well, in a case of that sort
I guess I ought to get a lot of work done.
Good, good.
Uh, thank you very much for dropping in.
All right.
- Oh er, pop
- yes?
Don't alert the enemy that I'm coming.
You don't think I want them
back on my hands, do you?
Son.
...
oh, pop.
Clear as a bell.
Corrie, will you come away from that window
and sit down please?
Are you sure he's coming?
According to your grandfather,
who wasn't supposed to alert the enemy,
he should be here by now.
Maybe he stopped off at the drug store,
- I'll go get him.
- Now, corrie, you sit down,
and don't get yourself so worked up.
She didn't even touch her
breakfast this morning.
- Neither did mommy.
- I wasn't hungry.
There he is!
There's papa!
Oh, please mommy, can I go
outside and bring him in?
No, he's old enough to
come in here by himself,
without any encouragement from any of us.
Mommy, he's writing another letter.
That means he's going away.
Oh, mommy I love you, he's coming in.
He's coming in!
But then he'll know your
hand is all better,
what about the secret?
I think it's a foolish secret.
Besides,
I learned about honesty from you.
Looks like bill bailey
finally made it home.
Oh, let's hope he stays.
Remember that rainy
evening I drove you out?
With nothing but a fine tooth comb?
I know I'm to blame and ain't it a shame?
Bill bailey won't you please come home?
Come home?
Papa, when I grow up,
I'm gonna marry a man just like you.
You do, and I won't let him in the house.
Bill bailey won't you please stay home?