Ok, welcome back.
This is Artie Decker,
De Voice of the Fresno Grizzlies...
and we've got a good one, my friends.
Top of the 9th here at Chukchansi
Park, and a beautiful night.
We can actually feel
that fall is finally on its way.
It's a rather crisp 107 degrees, but dry.
We've got 15,000 sweaty and bloated
people all pumped up on Churros...
rooting on our Fresno Grizzlies.
And Brad, this is why I love
announcing Minor League Baseball...
because I get to say
names like "River Cats..."
or the "Rancho Cucamonga Quakes."
I don't have to ever say boring names
like "Tigers," or "Red Sox," or "Cubs."
Ok, we got a little break in the action...
as they're having a little
meeting on the mound.
Artie, do you know what time it is?
I sure do, Brad.
It's time for Artie's Kiss Cam!
Thank you, Gwen.
Let's see what kind of young lovers
we got at the ballpark tonight.
Alright, there's a kiss.
Well, you know one
thing when you see
a kiss like that, they're married.
Wait, wait, we've got a proposal.
"Will you marry me, Clara? Love, Nate."
There's our young Romeo now.
And whoa! He has scored!
Brad, that is what you young
people would call a "hottie."
He's got Britney Spears and
he's about to give her the ring...
and he goes the other way!
I can't believe what I am seeing...
and I'm sure she's got a
great "personality," but, oh my.
I thought Jerry Garcia was dead.
What's he doing in the
stands marrying him?
Here at Chukchansi Park,
love is blind, and apparently so is Nate.
Alright, let's get back to the action
as the meeting breaks up on the mound.
Here's the situation.
1st and 3rd, 2 outs.
And here's the pitch.
Swing and a miss.
Diaz fires down to 3rd.
They've picked him off 3rd!
You're out!
Ballgame over!
I'll tell you,
Myers is getting an earful...
and as my mom used to say,
"There's no cure for dumb."
Gwen! We won.
And that closes out the
last game of the season.
The Grizzlies take the
Sacramento River Cats...
by a score of 3 to 1.
We'll be right back with a happy recap.
That is a bad way to end a game.
Artie. Mr. Decker.
I want to say thank you for what
has been an awesome semester.
I mean, you taught me a lot,
and... I got you this.
What did you do, Brad?
It's got all the famous
calls you told me about.
Harwell, "Red" Barber,
Scully, Russ Hodges.
You know, that's really great, Brad.
Thank you so much.
Well, as the great
Yogi Berra once said,
"It ain't over till it's over."
Well, this Fresno
Grizzlies season is over.
I'm Artie Decker,
De Voice of the Fresno Grizzlies.
So, on behalf of Brad Zolick and
the late Gwen Foster on the organ...
good night everybody,
thanks for listening and lights out, Alice.
I love this job.
I'm fired?
I'm sorry, Artie.
I'm changing everything.
New logos, new uniforms, new music.
All the deadwood is
floating to the sawmill.
I'm deadwood?
You're old school.
You reminisce and you tell stories.
All our sponsors are for hearing aids,
beds that go up and down,
and scooters.
Not the cool kind, the sad kind.
We need someone who's wired in.
To what?
Facebook.
How many friends do you have?
I don't have any friends.
Have you made any posts?
No.
What was your last update?
My what?
Have you poked anybody?
I haven't poked anybody!
Has anybody poked you?
No.
The thing is Artie,
even if you were connected...
I don't know that I'd
want to be poked by you.
How many apps do you have?
I don't have any apps.
You don't have any apps?
No.
Everyone has apps.
I don't have an app.
Do you play Angry Birds?
Angry Birds?
Who's your favorite Angry Bird?
I don't have a favorite Angry Bird!
Everyone has a favorite Angry Bird.
Hashtag.
When was the last
time you hashtagged?
Are you out of your mind?
What the heck are you talking about?
We need announcers that tweet.
I'll tweet.
I'll make whatever noise you want.
Sorry, Artie, my mind's made up.
Feel the burn, everyone.
And 1, 2, 3, 4.
Ok, ok.
How are we doing, Diane?
Oh, my sciatica.
My other sciatica.
10 minutes to cheesecake, ladies.
There we go. Good job.
Hi, Artie.
Hi, ladies.
Caught the end of the game.
"No cure for dumb." Funny.
Yeah.
Funny.
Don't fall, hon.
I got it.
Alright, everybody, pull your core in.
I don't have a core.
Work those abs.
You know, Artie,
this could turn out to be a good thing.
It could give us more "us" time.
You mean me wearing a captain's
hat following you around Costco?
You don't want to retire? Fine.
You were offered a job teaching
broadcasting at Fresno State.
You could teach young people.
I could, but why should
they know what I know?
Ever the nurturer.
I don't want to teach,
I want to do. I still have a dream.
The Giants?
Yeah, the Giants.
I've been chasing this job for 35 years.
You give up your dream,
you give up.
I'm not quitting.
I feel 10 years younger than I am,
and I look 10 years
younger than that.
So basically, you're asking
a 38-year-old to retire.
You're 38? Paint the house.
Artie, to me, you're the best
announcer in the whole world.
You should be
broadcasting for the Giants.
But after all these years, honey...
something tells me they
don't have you on speed dial.
Mmm.
It'll be ok.
I'm sorry.
R-life awake.
Garage activated.
Vehicle charging.
Solar panels activated.
Good morning, Harper,
Turner and Barker.
Waffles ready.
Coffee ready.
Time for breakfast.
But-but, Mom.
Honey, hold on one second.
Uh-huh.
Well, I can have that up
for you in about 3 hours.
Yeah, 1 hour, that's what I meant.
Sure, I can hold on.
Stupid!
What's the matter, honey?
I missed a note.
Come and have breakfast.
You're going to get it.
You know that you always do.
Yeah, I'm right here.
Right. And when would that be?
That's so soon.
You got to be kidding me.
Dad! Dad.
I'm the soysages,
Turner gets the Wheatie-O's.
Ok. Hey, babe,
can you take over here?
I'm on a call.
Thank you.
But-but M-Mom! Th-The other
k-kids are gonna w-watch them.
Honey, I don't think you'd
really enjoy the Saw movies.
Remember when we
went to see Avatar...
and you spent the last 2 hours
with your head inside my purse?
I... I... I was...
I looking for the gum.
I'm right here.
I can't believe it.
My computer just crashed.
I'll have to call you right back.
Barker, can we discuss some
of the many other possibilities
for today's wardrobe,
including some involving pants?
Honey, can I talk to
you outside for a second?
Sure. I have nothing but time.
D... Dad?
C... Can I watch the Saw movies?
Sure.
Yeah!
Wait. That's way inappropriate.
Aw!
What's up?
Oh.
That was nice. Like a little mini date.
Crazy year, right?
I mean, the whole thing.
Moving to Atlanta for my job.
Yeah, it's had its challenges.
Well, guess what.
That was my boss on the phone...
and the R-life
has been nominated
for "Best New Product of the Year."
Oh!
That's fantastic!
I know!
They're flying us both next week.
5 days of lectures and
networking and love.
Oh. Saturday is Harper's audition.
Yeah, but it's at night.
We'll fly back early. We'll make it.
Also, Turner has speech therapy.
I have to buy Harper
a dress for the audition.
We're supposed to take
the kids to the symphony...
Honey, we haven't had a
vacation since Barker was born.
That's 5 years.
Mmm-hmm.
This conversation is the longest
we've been alone in months.
So, great.
I'll call my parents, they'll fly down.
They'll be happy to watch
the kids while we're gone.
A cruise. What cruise?
The one that we bought them
for their 40th anniversary.
I said just get them
matching tracksuits.
Look, we'll figure something out,
we'll figure something out, ok?
Well, we could always call your parents.
Oh, you're serious.
Yeah. They haven't seen
the kids in what, a year?
10 months is not quite a year.
Call them.
They're not coming.
Don't you need to talk to 'em first?
You know that they're just going
to say that they can't make it.
What? What?
What?
The itch.
You're kidding. You're getting
your "Artie and Diane Rash"?
Have you forgotten how they
disapprove of the way that we parent?
My father doesn't listen.
My mother, she's a tornado with lipstick.
Alice, we need this vacation.
And as you know...
who's going to be with
you in the Hilton Head?
Nigel?
That's right.
In fact, 'ave you 'eard me new song?
I'm gonna love you
till the police come
Anything for you, Nigel.
Carl flushed my pillow down the toilet.
Toilet overflowing.
Bathroom flooded.
Ok, I'll call my parents.
Artie, pick up the phone!
What are you doing?
I can't hear ya, the phone's ringin'.
Hello?
Hi, Dad.
Alice, hey, how are ya?
Is Mom around?
Yeah, hold on, I'll get her.
Your daughter.
Put her on speakerphone.
Don't tell her I was fired.
Oh, my.
I got it.
Put her on hold.
I know.
I'm trying.
Put her on hold.
I can't.
You're making me tense.
Now, put her on hold.
It's right there.
I'm gonna start a fire, here.
Hi, Alice, what's goin' on?
Well, now that you ask...
Phil has to go away next week
and I'd really like to go with him.
And we need someone
to watch the kids,
so I was wondering,
would you want to?
No. No.
We'd love to!
Listen, I'm cooking dinner.
I'll call you back in a
little bit for the details.
She said yes.
You said yes.
Artie, we practically never
see our grandchildren.
We've never seen their new house.
They've never been to Fresno.
I just got fired.
I'm licking my wounds.
I'll lick 'em. Come on!
They need someone
to take care of the kids.
Can't the house do it?
We have one child.
These 3 kids are the only
grandchildren we're ever gonna have.
I'm awkward around those kids.
I don't think they like me.
Honey, they don't see you enough.
They have to know you better
before they don't like you.
No, but it's a real thing, Di.
And it all comes from Alice.
Like the last time,
the little one left the house...
wearin' flippers and a bathrobe.
So I made a little joke. I said,
"Ohh, this one, any hope for normal?"
And I got this withering gaze.
Like you're giving me now.
Well, first of all...
it might be a good thing if you
learned "the little one's" name.
It's Barker.
Di.
Listen to me, I'm fragile right now.
I need a job.
I don't need Alice's disapproval.
I'm not going.
You're goin'.
That's what I meant.
Her whole way of
raising her kids is a giant...
in our face.
It's her generation. It's just their way.
HO! What are ya lookin' for, sailor?
If ya haven't found it yet,
it's not there. I'll help ya out.
Come on!
He's not done groping.
And could she have found
anyone less like me to marry?
What's your problem with Phil?
He's such a sweet guy.
He is sweet.
I think he breastfed the kids.
Perfect, it's raining.
Scattered showers, honey.
It'll be over in 20 minutes.
It's an omen.
What's it an omen of?
Impending doom.
I have a great idea.
What's that?
Shut up!
I'll think about it.
You know what grandparenting is?
What?
A 2nd chance.
That's pretty good.
And you know what Alice told me?
What?
The kids are over-the-moon
excited about our coming.
Why them?
Because they're your
grandparents and they love you.
D-Do we have to wear these?
Well, Grandma made them.
And she thinks you like them.
Why would she think that?
Because I told her that you did.
Look, it's going to be ok.
I promise you.
You know, they're very funny.
Grandpa tells lots of jokes...
that you won't get.
So just laugh.
Just laugh and I promise you
we'll get through this week.
Remember,
Mama loves you very much.
They're here!
Oh, no.
Hi!
This is a McStadium.
Hey, thanks for coming.
Hello, Phil.
Oh, my goodness!
They're wearing their shirts.
I told you, they love those shirts!
Give me a kiss.
I'm so excited.
This one's gonna be
prettier than her grandma.
Harper.
I know.
How's the fiddle coming? Still fiddling?
Mmm-hmm.
Hello, boys, still single?
Mom, you brought groceries?
You know Dad.
He just wanted to make sure
you had food here for him.
Ok, and toilet paper?
Well, I know what I like. Aloe.
Are those for us?
Those are definitely for you!
Yep. One for each of you.
Here you go. And for you.
S-Super Squirters! Awesome!
You bought them guns.
Yeah.
Dad. We don't do guns.
Hey, if you think that's something,
wait until you see this.
This is classic Artie.
Artie Decker bobbleheads.
Here you go. Look at this, huh?
What do you say?
That's creepy. Make it stop!
Thank you, Grandpa.
Th-Thank you, G-Grandpa.
Hey, you know what?
Since we're all gonna be pals now...
instead of calling me "Grandpa,"
why don't you call me "Artie"?
So it's "Grandma and Artie" now?
What are you, my boyfriend?
No, listen. We went through
all those names last time.
I don't want to be "Mup-Mup,"
or "Bup-Bup," or "Boop-Boop."
Those are puppet names.
My name is Artie.
Always been Artie. Call me Artie.
Can I call you "Farty"?
That's not a name, dope.
Hey, that was a put-down.
You owe me 3 put-ups.
I like your shoes.
I like your shirt. I like your hair.
Let's go inside.
You guys all have
to change because
we're going out for dinner.
Come on.
Get the bags, Farty.
Alice, this is a beautiful house.
Thank you.
It's a prototype.
Prototype?
Welcome, Alice and Phil and
Harper and Turner and Barker and...
2 unidentified guests.
But that's not strange.
It's the R-life.
It's Phil's invention.
It's what he's worked on all this time.
Wow.
This is the brain center
to this fully automated...
voice-activated,
prototype smart house.
And I'm just going to enter you
2 into the system right now.
Alright.
Beam me up.
You all get these portables...
and if there are any problems,
Turner understands the whole system.
Turner does?
Well, if Turner can do it,
I certainly can't.
Alice, this is so beautiful.
How's work, Dad?
How's your season?
Very good.
Yeah, we had a good season.
Yeah, a lot of good kids.
You know, your dad still signs off
every broadcast, "Lights out, Alice."
Really?
Yeah.
See, when Alice was a little girl,
I wasn't home a lot to put her to bed...
so on the radio I would say...
"Lights out, Alice,"
and it sort of stuck, you know?
Wow, that's really nice.
Yeah.
I thought so.
What's this?
It's some photos.
Pipi and Papi look great.
Yeah.
Here you are.
Oh, yeah.
I took that picture!
That was a great day, yeah.
Farty wet his pants!
Barker, indoor voice.
Guns.
Ow! Ow! Ow!
That's so hot!
What are you doing? It's too hot!
Here, do it yourself.
What's the matter?
Do you realize what we are?
What?
We're the "other" grandparents.
We can't be all 4.
I'm serious.
They have their real grandparents
that they love and
put up on the mantle...
and then there's us.
And who's putting those
pictures on the mantle?
Our daughter.
She is not sticking up for us.
I don't think the kids even
know what I do. Or did.
Look, Artie, I know you're upset
about getting kicked in your career...
but we need to focus, buddy.
Our grandchildren are gonna love me.
What about me?
That's your problem.
Welcome!
New people.
Hello.
These are my parents. They're
going to watch the kids this week.
Welcome to Healthy Tiger.
All healthy Pan Asian food.
What's that?
No MSG, no gluten, no sodium.
Just healthy food.
I'm droolin' already.
Pan Asian, just like me!
My mother's Japanese,
my father's Chinese,
my kids are Korean and
they go to Hebrew day school.
Oy vey!
Come on. Yeah!
How do you ruin Chinese food?
Ok.
We seem to have an empty chair.
No, no, that chair is for Carl.
Who's Carl?
Barker's friend.
How nice. When's he coming?
He's already here.
Hi, Carl. You look great.
Did you get a haircut?
Tell him.
Carl is Barker's imaginary friend.
He's a kangaroo.
Maybe we should have
eaten at the Outback.
Kids, go wash your hands.
Come on, Carl.
Bye, Farty.
He's in a real "testing
the boundaries" phase.
Plus, he's also a little constipated.
Now, you're talking my language.
I have some stuff
that will blow his mind.
They used it to blast out the Chunnel.
Thank you, Lord Arthur.
Now, do you have any
special instructions for us?
Like, what the kids like to do,
what they like to eat.
Yes, Mom, great. Thank you.
First of all, they don't eat any sugar.
No Carvel?
That's the saddest thing
I've ever heard in my life.
We have tried to introduce
just a little bit of sugar
and it was like going off
the rails of the crazy train.
Oh, my gosh!
And there's another
subject I'd like to discuss.
Sure, anything.
Your language.
Oh, he won't curse.
I'll break his freakin' arm.
That's great,
but that's not what I meant.
You see, there's a way
that we talk to our kids.
For instance, where
you would say "No"...
we would say,
"Consider the consequences."
Or where you would say, "Don't"...
we would say,
"Maybe you should try this."
Or where you would say...
"Quit your whining,
you're giving me a headache"...
we would say, "Use your words."
You see, that way, the child feels
that he has value, he has worth.
He is heard.
It's a way.
Let's order.
Great.
That's very good, but if you stay
inside the lines, it looks better.
Here, look at mine, see?
Dad, we don't really worry about lines.
Honey, draw whatever
your imagination tells you.
But what's the point of having
lines if you're just gonna...?
Artie.
That's beautiful.
That's absolutely beautiful.
It's very avant-garde.
Picasso.
Exactly.
You didn't finish your dinner. Ya
know the great thing about Chinese...
I mean, Pan Asian food,
is that if you mush it all up it's...
What happened?
What did you do?
I don't know.
He doesn't like his food to touch.
I didn't know! Look, I'm un-smushing.
There's so much
un-smushed Pan Asian.
What?
Use your words, Barker.
Use your words.
Farty ruined my food! Evil Farty.
Evil Farty, what have you done?
Mama! Dada!
Don't go!
I have to go.
Would you...? I'm trying to let go!
Don't go!
D-Don't go!
Just let go.
He's just so strong.
Let go, baby. Let go, baby.
Just get in the car.
I am trying.
Barker, honey, just...
Get in the car.
I love you.
I'm trying to get in the car!
Get in the car.
Bye.
No!
Drive.
Bye, honeybun.
Goodbye, goodbye.
Honey, stop!
Bye.
Go.
Yay!
I'll be home really soon.
No!
Barker's hyperventilating.
Stop the car, please.
Go, go, go!
Yay!
Give me your worst,
worst case scenario.
Everybody dies.
Then anything short of
that will be a happy surprise.
Onward.
Really go now.
No!
Oh good heavens.
Time for breakfast.
Come on, we got to get to school.
Ok. Let's get this party started!
It's going to be great!
It's going to be awesome!
We are going to have so much fun.
This is going to be the
best week of your life!
Right, Artie?
Sure thing, Regis.
Ok. Here we go.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Oh, my gosh.
This is it, right?
Yeah.
I'll see ya on the other side.
These are done.
Hot skillet! Sorry.
Alright. Here are your sausages.
Soysages.
Soysages?
What are you, from the Bronx?
Did Mom leave my
eggless egg salad for lunch?
Eggless egg salad?
How would I recognize it?
The toast is ready.
Di, we have to make lunch!
I know. I know. It's on the counter.
Make the sandwiches.
Alright. My waffles, my waffles!
I got it.
5 second rule. Got it.
N-Not too much almond milk in
the c-cereal. It g-gets too wet.
Is this the right amount?
Uh-uh.
Well, eat fast.
Ok. Here you go.
You have to cut up the berries
and put one piece in each
hole in the multigrain waffle.
This food can touch?
Eggless egg salad coming up.
Ok, put the lettuce,
hit it with the lettuce.
It's fine, they will never know.
No crust, no crust.
Now there's no sandwich.
Look what you made.
I like them, Carl likes them.
Right, Carl?
And your opinion has value.
And, what's the other one?
Worth.
But I know from experience
that wearing heels can be tricky.
Especially during recess.
Wouldn't you and Carl both be
more comfortable in sneakers?
No.
Hey, what's going on?
We are going to be late.
It's Project Runway.
I tried handling it like Alice said,
but it's not working.
Alright, get the other 2
in the car, I'll handle this.
Artie.
It's ok. Let me try.
Take off those shoes
and I'll give you a dollar.
5.
2.50.
Deal.
Just punch in "go to school."
Why is this easier than you
just telling me how to get there?
I heard that.
Whoa! Whoa!
Is he in there?
It's Dad, and it's a recording.
It's just a little family joke.
Yeah, it's interesting because,
usually, jokes are funny.
But hey, why kill time laughing, huh?
Ok, here you go.
Thank you. What?
"Go garage." Go garage.
Say it with force.
Go garage. Go garage.
Welcome back, Alice.
Mommy!
Alice, what happened? Where's Phil?
He's on his way to the airport.
I'm going to meet him in a few hours.
There's an 8:00 flight tonight.
But...
One of my clients called. They need
me to update their website immediately.
Can't it wait until you get back?
No, it's ESPN.
There's a crisis with the X Games.
You work for ESPN?
Yeah, I'm one of their web designers.
Honey, get in the backseat.
Really? I didn't know that.
It's interesting. ESPN. Really?
Nice school. How long have
you been workin' for ESPN?
Ohh, about 5 years.
Really?
Mmm-hmm.
Turner...
Artie is going to pick
you up after school...
and take you to speech therapy today.
Wh-Wh-Where are you-you going to be?
Grandma and I are going
to buy Harper a dress.
Great.
Have a good day, you 2.
See you later.
I can't believe I'm going to get a tardy.
6 tardies are an absent.
How many does this make?
1.
Does she seem a little tightly wound?
Mmm-hmm, she has H.A.S.
High Achievement Syndrome.
Did you make that up?
Yes.
Hurry up, I can't get a tardy.
I know she's a little tightly wound.
But we're working on it.
Work on it soon before she explodes.
W-W-Watch where you're going,
Tu-Tu-Tu-Turner.
S-S-Sorry.
Hey, did you see that?
Dad, no. No.
Turner's therapist says that he has
to work out peer conflicts on his own.
He has a therapist?
He had one,
and now he has a new one, Dr. Jimmy.
Also a kid?
No.
ESPN again.
I need to get to a Wi-Fi.
Maybe I can use the one here.
Go ahead, I'll get Barker to school.
Are you sure?
Sure. What's the problem?
Ok.
Got the R-life.
But then pick me up here.
Don't leave me stranded.
Have I ever left you stranded?
4 times when I was a kid.
I love how you remember everything.
Ok, Barker, hop out.
I can't. I'm still buckled in.
Carl, unbuckle him.
Hello?
He's at a doctor's appointment.
Stupid me. Ok.
Boy, this is harder than
one of your grandma's bras.
I'm going to be late.
I'm tr...
It works, ok? Your horn works.
I won't need this by
the time you're done.
Here you go. Here.
Careful, he's a runner.
Bye, Farty.
1 second.
Hey, Ash.
Hey, Cody.
Did you get my Evite?
Yep, I'm coming.
Cool.
This is my friend, Harper.
This is Cody.
Hey.
Hi.
I'm having this birthday
thing Friday night.
There's going to be a DJ,
and my parents
promised not to be ridiculously lame.
Right. Parents.
So, if you want to swing by,
that would be pretty cool.
Oh. Um...
I can't.
I got this thing the next day.
She has a thing.
I got a thing.
Ok. That's cool.
Yeah. No, it's super cool.
Well, if you change your mind,
just, you know...
Yeah. Totally, I'll...
Cool.
Bye.
Stop it.
Microwave on.
Garbage disposal on.
Vacuum cleaner on.
Oh, please, just let me do the dishes.
Welcome back, Artie Decker.
What a morning.
It's 9 AM, I need a martini.
Tell me something.
Did you believe that story?
Absolutely not. What story?
Alice's work emergency.
You think she was lying?
Why couldn't that work have
been done at Hilton Head?
It's like she doesn't
trust us with her kids.
Like she thinks we're idiots.
By the way, where is she?
Where have you been?
I know.
You know, Harper,
when I was your age
this was my favorite time of the day,
right after school.
Why, what did you do?
Well we used to go to
my friend Heidi's house,
put on her mother's clothes,
blast music and smoke.
Mom!
Don't smoke. Don't smoke.
Oh, Lulu, that was so great.
Honey, you're really
starting to take control...
and literally holding the reins.
Ok, Turner...
would you like to share?
Good work, Turner.
Awesome.
Super job, Lulu.
See you next week?
Thank you.
That was really awesome.
I take it you're Turner's grandfather.
Hi.
I'm Artie Decker.
Cassandra.
You seem to be having some trouble
embracing our program, am I right?
Well, let me say first,
that I have professional
experience in this area.
Oh, wonderful.
Where did you receive your degree?
Oh, no degree. No.
I speak for a living.
I'm a baseball announcer.
Little different than a PhD in
speech therapy from Yale. Right?
Right. Yeah.
That's a point well taken.
But on the other hand,
I sat here for almost an hour
and I saw these kids
do everything but speak.
So, are you training
them to be mimes?
Because a lot of those jobs
are being shipped overseas.
"I'm walking, but there's wind,
"but there's no wind." You know?
Ok.
I am employing the Houghton method.
Now these kids, they're under
too much pressure to speak...
so we make it very clear that in here,
they need not say a word.
They're currently in a movement phase.
Yeah, I saw that.
They're moving everything but their lips.
And he wears these
ear buds all the time.
What's that about?
He is listening to the words
that he has trouble with...
and then when he's comfortable,
he can repeat them.
And it's helping him a lot.
How can you tell?
Listen, I haven't seen
the kid in a year...
and frankly,
I don't see any improvement at all.
What I see is my
grandson is now Flight 38
from Salt Lake.
Hey, Turner!
Cassandra's just telling
me how great you're doing.
She sees so much improvement.
It's great.
Sometimes I shouldn't move my lips.
I'm sorry.
That's not bad.
"Not bad"?
She looks like a 12-year-old widow.
I do?
You do.
But that's perfect for a
classical music program.
Well, what about this?
This is perfect for someone
with a cute little hiney.
I love it.
Mom, it's for a concert,
not to meet the fleet.
Hey, it's an audition,
and all auditions are alike.
"Get their attention!"
You sell the sizzle, not the steak.
That's how I got all
those weather girl jobs.
So, are you a trained meteorologist?
Trained?
Oh, honey,
I had a tight dress and a pointer.
I used to sing my forecasts.
As a matter of fact,
sometimes your mom
used to sing them with me on TV.
Mom, you never even told me that!
I mentioned it.
Remember our winter song?
That was our best one.
No, I don't remember that one.
Sure you do.
We sang it 1,000 times.
I love you. Come on, please.
No one's watching.
Only for you.
Ready?
Button up your overcoat
in the wintry breeze
Take good care of yourself
'cause it's 9 degrees!
Good job, Mom.
Do the spin.
Ok.
I'll never shop at Bloomingdale's again.
Aw! You still got it, kiddo.
That was great. Ah!
Alright, now...
you've got to try this on.
I'm dyin' to see this on you.
Ok.
Mom. She cannot wear a
cocktail dress to the audition.
I'd like to feel that
you're listening to me.
Oh, I'm sorry, honey.
Did you say something?
No, no.
Look at this.
This is a hot little number.
Oh, not for her. For me.
Cue the band.
Hey. What are you doing?
Guarding the door.
Can I go in?
Not today, sir.
Is he crying?
He doesn't cry, he makes the face.
I didn't mean to upset him.
You should've used your exit shoes.
My what?
Exit shoes, to walk away
and not use a red voice.
And a red voice is...?
Super-mad sounding.
You shouldn't use it. Never.
Uh-huh.
That's why you have a cool toolbox.
It's where you keep
your cool blue voice,
your exit shoes and
your repair squares.
Where did you learn all this?
Preschool.
You mean,
there are more kids like you?
I'm doomed.
Alright, I'm goin' in there.
What's in it for me?
Thank you.
The little capitalist.
Hi, there.
Alright, so I am taking a repair
square out of my cool toolbox
to say in my blue voice,
that I am sorry.
So, are we good now?
No.
Would you like $5?
An unopened package of
men's size 34 underwear?
No.
Is there anything I can
do to make this right?
W-Well, th-there is 1 thing.
Aaargh!
They made 6 of these?
Oy.
Now, this is Artie's idea of fun.
Ooh! Look at that.
Who knew ice cream could be a cake?
Yeah.
Alright, now here's the deal.
Just little pieces...
and you don't tell
Mommy about the movie...
and I don't tell her about the cake.
Ok? Alright? Deal? Friends again?
High 5! Alright.
Incoming message.
Urgent e-mail from "E-spen."
ESPN...
Pam Rosen.
You guys ok?
I will be right back.
Ms. Pam Rosen, please.
My name is Cal R. Life.
Yeah. L-Y-P-H-E-T. The "T" is silent.
What a great day.
It's like a birthday that came early.
It was a great day.
And my forecast for
the rest of the week...
Sunny, sunny, sunny.
Back to you, Herb.
Oh, it's your dad, I'll be right in.
Hi!
Today is your lucky day, Ms. Rosen.
The catfish just jumped
right into your frying pan.
Yeah, Artie Decker,
"De Voice" is in town.
He heard about your X Games
and he would love to audition.
I'm just walking in.
Video chat me in 2 minutes, ok?
Hi, Artie, we're back!
Did you have fun with the boys?
Look at this place!
We're going to have to call FEMA!
Cake. Where's Artie?
He left!
He left?
If your mother sees this...
What's going on?
Hi.
What did you do?
I just got here!
You gave them cake?
I gave them slivers.
Why? Why, Artie?
Because he upset
Turner at Speech Class.
What?
It was nothing.
I just asked a question.
"Why is nobody speaking?"
That's all.
Hello, love!
I can't wait for you to
get here, me little rabbit.
Shh! Not now! Oh, my.
Did he have a tattoo?
Hmm?
Harper?
Mom! You lied to me!
Yogurt is not like ice cream!
No, honey.
Baby?
My favorite!
Harper!
Ooh!
This perfectly sums up your
entire approach to parenting.
We had an approach?
I don't know.
Would Artie and Turner like
to continue watching Saw?
You must be mistaken.
Saw, Rated R for
strong graphic violence,
nudity and language.
No.
Why did he give them cake?
Because he does what he
wants and she defends him!
Where are the kids now?
Oh, I put them on the
treadmill until they calm down.
I told you my parents
couldn't handle this.
Maybe it's just a case
of first-day, worst-day.
Oh.
Hey. You better hurry up.
You're going to miss your flight.
Honey, I don't think
that I should go today.
Maybe I should go tomorrow morning.
Ok. Yeah.
We'll still have 4 days together.
Ok.
You look good in cake.
What in the world is wrong with you?
What did I say?
What did I say to you?
Just talk to me. Don't yell.
I said, "Artie,
this is a 2nd chance for us."
I said, "Artie, please behave."
I said, "Artie, I really
want those kids to love us!"
Or can't you remember all
the way back to yesterday?
Ok, that's what I did.
When the cake went in
their mouths they loved me!
Yeah, and now Alice doesn't
want to leave us alone with them.
She doesn't trust us!
She said that?
On the phone to Phil.
I accidentally overheard her
when I was listening at the door.
She thinks we're a
pair of knuckleheads.
Especially you!
It's the bottom of the 9th, Artie.
We're going to lose the game.
Shape up.
Oh!
Wonderful. Oh!
Bravo.
Oh, wow!
Harper, that was wonderful!
I stunk.
You most certainly did not!
Wasn't she wonderful?
No.
This will not be good
enough for your audition!
You must practice more!
When my daughter underperforms,
I shun her.
This girl should be shunned!
Practice, practice, practice!
Gee whiz.
Wasn't she the villain in
the last James Bond movie?
Oh! Sweetie, don't listen to her.
You know back in Amarillo,
when Artie was announcing there...
I got this audition to
be the local weather girl.
Well, I was so uptight.
Artie took me out the night
before and we both got bombed!
And the next day I got the job.
So, you're saying I should drink?
No, no, no. I'm not saying that.
I am saying that
perhaps you could relax.
You could go out with your friends.
You could have some fun Friday night.
You know?
Friday, I was invited to a...
Oh.
No.
No, no, no!
I have 3 more days!
I have to practice! I have to...
I have to practice every second!
Doctor Schveer?
Yes?
Perhaps we got off on the wrong foot.
But I would like to let you know that
if you ever speak to my
granddaughter like that again
there will be nothing left of you,
but some red hair and an accent!
Is that clear, comrade?
Ooh! Thank you. Here ya go.
Mmm!
Carcinogens.
Oh, the first one just laid a base.
This is the real thing.
I'm at the ballpark.
He likes baseball, huh?
Yeah, he likes lots of things.
He likes sports.
He likes science, he likes movies.
He likes cake.
Touché.
He's just hidden behind that... stutter.
Well, you know, kids have a
way of working these things out.
No, they don't, Dad.
That's why there's prison.
Alright, guys, bring it in! Bring it in!
Get all those hands in there.
Come on.
Everybody on 3. 1, 2, 3...
Let's have fun!
I am so excited about this.
Let's play!
He's pitching!
Yeah.
He has a good arm.
Like Mom, like son. Yeah, right.
No, you had a hose.
But then you hit puberty
and you got all girlie on me.
Well, gee, Dad,
I'm so sorry that I hit puberty.
I was so proud of you back then.
You were usually the only girl out there.
You used to stand up
to those stinky boys.
Do you remember that summer
when you worked for me in the booth
keeping score and doing stats?
You were so cute, sitting there
scrunched over your little pencil.
You never saw that ball comin', did ya?
You could have yelled "Incoming."
I was on the air.
I didn't want to start a panic.
You do love that job.
Yeah.
Yeah, I do.
Batter up!
Ah! This is that bully kid.
Yeah, Ivan.
I would so like to see
Turner strike him out.
Strike!
Strike 1! Hey, he is really good.
He's really good.
Way to go, Turner!
Turner Simmons on the mound...
a young Cuban prospect
who escaped on a raft.
He's facing Ivan, a miserable child
who is loathed and
despised by everyone.
Dad!
Swing and a miss! Strike 2! Hoo-hoo!
1 more strike and it's back
to the dugout for
this 8-year-old bullfrog.
Dad...
The yearbook said Ivan
is "Most likely to do time."
Simmons looks at him.
He shakes it off.
Here's the pitch.
Strike 3! You're out of there!
Woo, hoo, hoo, hoo.
Lights out, Alice!
Way to go, Turner! Way to look!
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Blue, Blue! That's 3 strikes!
1, 2, 3! Outta there!
Time!
It's ok!
This is my dad and he's new here!
Oh, ok.
There are no outs in this game.
No outs? How is that possible?
They hit until they get on base.
Seriously?
Seriously.
Dad, why don't we just sit down?
Oh...
Alright.
But you know that's kind of stupid!
Because if you just
think of the song...
'Cause it's 1, 2, 3 strikes,
you're out...
at the old ball game
Not... until you get a hit
He's right!
I hate these games! What's the point?
The point is for the kids to enjoy
the game without competition.
Yeah, but competition is the game.
Ya know, it's like life.
Let me ask you somethin'.
I mean, how do you
even know who's winnin'?
In this league, we don't keep score.
Every game ends in a tie.
Oh, no.
No agony of defeat?
Just the thrill of a tie?
It's good they don't keep score!
Yeah, 'cause your kid stinks.
Oh, I will bust you up!
The old guy's right. It's boring.
See?
It is not boring!
They're children and
they're having fun!
And there's plenty of time
in their lives to keep score!
And you're out!
No, I'm not.
Oh, yeah.
Turner, you struck him out.
No, I didn't.
Yes, you did.
You're out. No, I'm not!
You're out! No, I'm not!
3 strikes, you're out!
No, I'm not!
Barker, what's going on?
Farty is going crazy.
Again?
You're out!
No, you're out!
Ivan, no hitting!
Use your words!
Yes, Mom.
I'm angry that you said I was out.
Well, it's not boring anymore.
How is this Artie's fault?
All I saw was that little
monster grab a baseball bat
and hit your father in his...
in his special place.
Well, you didn't see what led up to it.
Oh!
It was my fault.
Oh, honey.
You threatened her violin teacher?
She says "threatened."
I say "defended my granddaughter."
Phil?
Hey.
Hey, we won. I won!
I won! Can you believe it?
Oh, my gosh!
That's fantastic! That's fantastic!
Daddy won!
Congrats, Dad!
Hey, so, ahh, they're giving
me the award tomorrow night.
When are you gettin' here?
Phil, you don't know what's
going on here. It's madness.
We can't leave our
children with my parents.
So, what are you saying?
That you're not coming?
Phil, please listen to me.
Try to understand. I'm sorry.
Ahh, yeah. I understand perfectly.
Alright. Um...
See ya when I get back.
Ok. We're going home.
No.
No?
Artie and the kids are going home.
I am taking you to the airport.
What?
Alice, your dad and I have
bent over backwards to
try to do things your way.
You haven't bent over at all.
Oh, I'm bent.
Believe me, I'm bent.
Now, look. You asked us to come here
and take care of our grandchildren
and you haven't given
us the chance to do it.
You have been on our backs,
especially your dad's...
ever since we got here!
Ok, take his side,
because you always do anyway.
And for a good reason.
Because after your kids grow up,
your husband is the one who stays.
Alice, I know you're trying
to be a perfect parent
but, honey, there's no such thing.
And frankly, you need to show Phil
he's not just their father,
he's also your husband.
Alice, I'm your mom.
Take it from me, I really get it.
"Love the man, love the dream."
Well, your husband's
dream is coming true
and part of that dream is
you being there with him!
How can you not go?
Oh, honey, you have to go.
You're going!
What about my clothes?
I don't think he wants you in clothes.
Besides, your luggage is already there.
Hey, kids, Mommy's finally going.
What about my audition?
I'll take care of it! It'll be fantastic!
See ya at the ranch.
Oh, no. Bye!
This is a happy day.
Oh, happy day
Could you drive? I don't feel good.
Gonna stand there gawking?
Gonna let me in?
No score here in the
bottom of the 7th and 2 outs.
The Giants and the Atlanta
Braves locked into a pitching duel.
Lincecum and Hudson,
both have been fantastic.
As Buster Posey steps in,
takes a strike in the inside corner.
I got to tell you friends,
this is one of those nights...
72 degrees, 45,000 fans,
smell of the popcorn, the hot dogs,
all of those clichés,
but I'll tell you somethin'...
there's no other place I'd rather be.
Posey hits a line drive
to 3rd and that'll do it.
That's it, no score through 7.
We'll be back. This is Artie Decker,
De Voice of the Giants.
Reminder: No school today.
You have tickets to the symphony.
What's wrong with your face?
Oh, and you're such a
pleasure in the morning?
You're not going to like this.
Barker!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Is it coming off?
Well, not exactly.
Sorry, Farty.
Mmm-hmm.
Let's go!
I gotta go number 2!
No, we're already late!
Artie, just take him.
Alright. Ok, batter up! Let's go.
No, no, he can hold it, guys.
He's fine, he can hold it!
The symphony starts at 2!
Quarter?
Not today, thank you.
Ok.
Hey, buddy.
Sorry!
So sorry.
That's not human.
Hurry up!
Yeah.
Ok. Here we go.
Ok, there you go.
I can't sit on that.
I'll give you 10 bucks.
Daddy always sings to me.
Hmm.
Come out, come out, Mr. Doodie
and swim in the swimming pool
I know it's dark where you're hiding...
but out here it's really cool
Come on, come on, Mr. Doodie...
'cause we've got something to do
And if you hurry...
you'll meet Carl the kangaroo
Yes!
Hey, buddy, can you keep singing?
Come out, come out, Mr...
Come on.
He's still out there!
We're ok! We're ok!
Nothing's the matter.
Thank you very much.
This way. Come on, honey.
Oh, we made it.
Big crowd. Must be helmet night.
It wasn't that funny.
Carl and I want to leave.
Don't leave your seat.
You said "don't."
Consider the consequences, mister.
Shh!
It's not me, it's him.
I'm sorry. Kids.
Barker? Barker?
Hey, come back here!
Don't go "no". Yes! Get.
Ow!
Who brings a child to Tchaikovsky?
Me. Voodoo-man. Ha!
Carl, come on!
Gr-Grandma?
Yes, dear?
Artie's ch-chasing Barker.
Oh, that's nice, dear.
What?
Ow!
Excuse me. Excuse me!
Excuse me. Barker! Get back here!
Stop it!
Barker!
Oh, my...!
Where is he?
Over there!
Barker!
Carl!
Get over here!
Let's see.
Artie?
I'm sorry!
I can't take this anymore!
This whole "teachable moments"
and protecting their self-esteem
and nobody gets punished!
And every game ends in a tie!
All I hear is "Use your words.
Use your words".
But the word they never
use with these kids is "no"!
Come on, Mr. Decker.
The other patients are waiting
for you in Arts and Crafts.
1 second.
I am very sorry for
what happened here.
Just split it with her.
Thank you.
Savages.
Well, he'll be there.
Yeah, Artie Decker.
You're going to love him. He's a pro's pro.
Tomorrow, 11 AM, Piedmont Park.
I'll see... He'll see you then.
Alright, bye now.
Piedmont Park, map.
Dinner!
Who was that?
Market research. Always at
dinner time. How do they know?
Hey, kids, would ya sit down?
I have something I want to clear up.
Something's bothering me.
I just want to say...
I was never, ever going
to actually spank Barker.
But you threatened to spank him.
But I never was going to do it.
But he didn't know that.
That's why it worked.
Oh.
There we go!
It looks great!
Thank you, honey.
Th-This isn't what-what we asked for.
Yes, I know.
I got your e-mails. But...
This is how a family eats.
We all sit at one table and
we all eat the same thing.
It's not how we eat.
But you know somethin', Barker...
Grandma worked very hard
to make your mom's recipe
just the way that
your mom makes it
so I think that we owe her the
courtesy of eating it and enjoying it.
Oh, honey, thank you.
That is so sweet.
I'm going to order a pizza.
Who's in?
Hey, you've been sittin' here for hours.
Are you playin' a game?
That looks like fun.
Do you just press it here?
No, no, no!
Game over.
Ah...
Sorry.
Turner, let me ask you a question.
You ever watch the X Games?
Stuff like that?
S-S-Sometimes.
Yeah.
Do you think you know the lingo?
You mean like "h-heinous,"
or "gn-gnarled out," or "n-nose bone"?
Yeah, that kinda stuff.
Listen, how about later I tuck ya
in and we talk more about this?
S-Sure. Except for the t-tucking in.
I'm 8.
Ok, I get it.
And, listen, I'm sorry if I
embarrassed you the other day.
Wh-Which day was th-that?
Touché.
One other thing.
This Ivan kid, he's a punk.
Stand up to him.
Anything he starts, you can finish.
Believe in yourself.
And Turner, once you believe in yourself,
you can do anything.
You can look trouble right
in the eye and just wink at it.
And everything will be ok.
It's all attitude.
Now, how do you turn this on?
Th-That's just a t-table.
Ok, let's go.
Goodbye, Harper, Turner,
Barker, Diane and Farty Decker.
She did that on purpose.
Remember, you're taking
Barker for a play date.
Ok.
Alice says this is very,
very important.
They're still new here...
and Barker hasn't had a
chance to make new friends, ok?
I got it.
Bye, Barker.
Bye.
Let me ask you something.
This play date kid, he's imaginary, too?
No.
How will I know how to get there?
Use the R-life.
Turner already punched in the address.
Ok. Di, can you pick up
Barker after the play date?
Pick him up? You're supposed
to stay with him the whole time.
What? When did his play
date become my play date?
Arti, I can't help you!
I got to go, hon.
No, I...
Ok.
Bye.
Bye. Have fun!
Ok.
Alright. Have a good time!
We're going to have a
great time at the play date!
How would you like
to ditch this play date?
I hate play dates.
No one talks to Carl.
Well, how rude are those people?
Would you like to do
something fun with me?
Great. Alright, let's go.
R-life, find me a mall.
Do you guys want to
go to the skatepark later?
I-I-Ivan!
What do you want, T-T-Turner?
Listen, p-punk!
Anything you start I-I can f-finish!
We were at our
locker and he ran up...
and it was such an awkward silence.
I had no idea what to say.
So, are you coming to my party?
Oh, hi. Oh, I don't think that I can.
I got to go. See you tonight, I hope.
Oh, please don't go.
He so likes you.
So, Tony, are you going
to bust a 900 today, dude?
Or are you going show us something
that's going to blow our minds.
Something we've never seen before?
I don't know. Maybe I'll try a 900
and then give you a tattoo
right in the middle of it.
Come on! We're late!
But I have to go pee-pee!
I don't have a song for that.
Sorry.
Talk a little bit about that particular
night and you hitting the 900.
It wasn't something I planned to do.
It had just I had hit my best...
I got to go pee!
How does it feel to be back in Atlanta?
Hey, I'm here.
Sorry I'm late. Motorcycle trouble.
I'm Artie "Mad Dog" Decker!
What's up, homeslice?
You're Artie Decker?
Reporting for duty.
We up for the same job?
I hope not.
Wait a second.
You don't know who this is?
Of course I do.
Dude, this is Tony Hawk, man!
Yeah, Tony Hawkman.
How you doing?
Alright. Who's the kid?
This is my agent.
Too many facelifts. If he gets one more,
he's going back in time.
I'm going to go take my runs.
So, how do we roll?
How do we roll?
Well, we roll this way.
The riders are practicing, so you just
ad lib like it's the actual event.
Just call it like I see it?
That's it.
Ok, dope.
Hey, can't have a kid up here, man.
No, no, no. Kid's with me. He's fine.
We're just going to go right over there.
I promise you,
everything's going to be good.
You sit right here. Ok?
Carl and I have to go pee-pee.
Just give me 1 minute and I promise
you can do all the peeing that you want.
But we really... Shh!
Farty has spoken.
Ready?
Yeah, yeah, coming.
Ok.
Go! Go, go.
Hello there, everybody!
It's a beautiful day and
thanks for coming out!
Here's one...
Cut!
What?
He's finished. The run's over.
Oh. Alright. Uh...
Give me 1 more chance.
I'm just warming up.
Hey, even Sinatra cleared his throat.
Alright, pops, come on.
Try to keep up.
Ready? 3, 2...
It is on and it is epic.
We're expecting to see
a front side heel flip 540...
990 body varial with a Cab 7 Melon Grab.
Melon Grab, my cousin got arrested
on the subway for melon-grabbing.
Tony started when he was very young.
He actually skated out of his mother.
Can I ask you something?
I wonder about this.
Absolutely.
How do you practice these tricks
before you get really good at them?
Do you say, "I'm just going to do this.
Somebody get a mop"?
Wait. Is that a kid on the half-pipe?
Barker!
Barker, what are you doing?
I told you I had to pee.
Is all that coming out of you?
I saved it up.
When? Since birth?
What you did back there
was pretty dangerous.
Do you know that?
Carl told me to do it.
I don't think Carl is being
a very good friend to you.
For a kangaroo,
he's something of a thrill-seeker.
And I think it's time that you
start telling Carl what to do.
One other thing. I was supposed
to watch after you today,
and I didn't do a good job.
I'm sorry.
So, Farty would appreciate it
if when we get home,
you don't tell anyone
what happened. Ok?
20 bucks.
Deal.
Let's go home. Come on.
Carl, come on.
How could you? What?
You think I don't know?
I want my 20 bucks back.
He's just a little boy!
He's fine.
Fine? Take a look at him.
Not him. Turner.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about Turner and
that brilliant advice you gave him.
Hey.
I have to ask, did you hit him back?
No.
Why not?
B-Because I hit him f-first.
Oh. Then he...
He started screaming and
s-someone helped him fight me.
2 against 1?
How big was this other...
It was his little sister.
She did this.
Turner, this is all my fault.
When I said stand up for yourself,
I didn't mean hitting.
Alright, listen. Oh, boy.
The older I get, the lower the floor gets.
Turner, can I share something with you?
Just between me and you.
No one else knows this.
This is just 2 guys talkin'.
When I was your age,
I was very shy because I was short.
I didn't talk to anybody.
And my self-esteem...
You know, the way I feel
about myself, was really bad.
Do you ever feel that way?
Yeah? Well, you know what?
You shouldn't.
Because you're a great kid.
Alright, I want to play you something.
Hey, house, I want to play something.
Ok.
Oh. Ok.
Now, the first time I heard this...
I knew right away that
I had found my voice.
I knew that I had to
become a baseball announcer.
And once I knew that...
it didn't matter what anybody
else thought or said about me.
Sh-sh-shot heard round the w-world?
Right.
The shot heard round the world.
Let me tell you about it.
It's 1951. Long time ago.
2 teams: Brooklyn Dodgers,
New York Giants.
And they hated each other.
L-Like Luke S-Skywalker
and D-Darth Vader.
Worse. Well, the baseball
season ends and they're tied.
Now, this 1 game would decide
who would go to the World Series
against the great New York Yankees.
Biggest game in the
history of New York.
Bottom of the 9th inning, 2 outs,
the Giants are losing 4 to 2
and a batter named Bobby
Thomson comes up to bat.
Bobby Thomson up there swinging.
He's had 2 out of 3, a single and a double,
and Billy Cox is...
Close your eyes.
Close your eyes, come on.
Close your eyes and you can see it.
Bobby hitting at .292. Lockman
without too big of a lead at 2nd
but he'll be running like the
wind if Thomson hits one.
Branca throws.
There's a long drive!
It's gonna be, I believe...
The Giants win the pennant!
Bobby Thomson hits into the
lower deck of the left field stands!
The Giants win the pennant
and they're going crazy,
they're going crazy!
And home!
I don't believe it!
I do not believe it!
The Giants won it
by a score of 5 to 4
and they're picking
Bobby Thomson up
and carrying him off the field!
That's what gave me my dream.
Now the big dream, of course,
was to announce for the Giants.
D-Did you?
No. But...
Y-You still might?
You never know.
C-C-Can I h-hear it again?
Sure.
Bobby Thomson up there swinging.
He's had 2 out of 3,
a single and a double,
and Billy Cox is playing...
Honey, we're going to play a game.
You want to join us?
Grandma, I can't.
Why?
Because if I don't do well tomorrow
then I won't get into the
Atlanta Youth Symphony
which is a feeder for Juilliard
which offers a graduate
class with Sarah Chang
whose students are
virtually guaranteed
to get into the Berlin Philharmonic
which is the orchestra
I most want to play in.
Sweetheart. Yes.
Berlin's not going anywhere.
Well, neither am I if I don't practice.
Ok, I'll tell the boys.
But you're sure now?
Yes.
Ok.
Gentlemen, the game
is called Kick the Can.
Are you going to recycle that?
I-It's d-dirty out here.
And windy!
I know. It's called "outside."
Is she coming?
Oh, too bad.
Alright, guys, the object of the game,
kick the can without getting tagged!
Ok, here we go!
Come on!
Kick... Come on.
S-Sounds b-boring.
Boring?
Oh, yeah?
Who wants a chance
to clobber old Artie?
Right.
And then see him eat dirt!
And then kick the can so hard...
it goes in one ear and out the other!
I do! I do!
I do!
In my ear?
Out of my way, Farty.
Over here!
Good kick!
Turner, it's mine!
I got it, I got it!
Look out for me, I'm Super Artie!
Watch it, watch it!
Pass me the can!
Over here.
Farty!
Well!
Ok. Let the games begin!
Come on!
Ah!
Ooh!
Are you ok?
I'm fine.
You should see the other guy!
I got more ice.
Oh, thank you, honey.
It should be stopping soon.
I should start dinner.
Grandma?
Yes, dear?
I know my audition is tomorrow,
but I practiced all day.
And you said I should
relax the night before
and there's this party tonight.
It's the 1st party I've been
invited to since we moved.
What if I just went
for a half an hour
came right back home,
got a really good night's sleep?
What kind of a party?
Just this party for some boy.
He kind of likes me.
I'll do your make-up!
Oh!
I wish we could stay.
Yeah, we should do this, like...
Yeah, like...
Every week?
Yes.
The child that was
involved was not injured.
Take a look and a listen to this.
It was scary.
I was about to nail this 900
and there's this kid up
there just whizzing away.
I hit his stream and I fish-tailed,
and now it's on YouTube.
It's got more hits
than Charlie the Unicorn.
And when I asked what he was
doing, you know what he said?
"I was chasing Carl, my kangaroo."
That's one twisted little dude.
This is from Tony Hawk's practice
run this morning at the X Games.
And you know,
it kind of begs the question...
what kind of parent would let their child
wander out onto the half-pipe?
Hey!
How is this for bonding?
I taught 'em how to shave.
Yeah. Show her your legs, boys.
That's great!
And guess what? I ordered Chinese...
I mean, I mean, Pan Asian, for dinner.
Noodles!
Alright, go upstairs and change.
When ya come down,
we're gonna arm-wrestle Grandma.
How come we just had 1?
It's not too late.
Oh!
It's really late. Come here,
I want to show you something.
What?
Look at this.
That's Alice's song.
Yeah.
She was, like, 3 or 4 years
old, how did she remember?
I don't know,
but it's at the top of her playlist.
Wow.
Aw!
We must have sang that song a
thousand times to her in the car!
You know you want to.
I don't want to sing it.
Oh, I wonder, wonder,
whom-ba-doo-hoo-whom
Who wrote the book of love?
Tell me, tell me, tell me
Oh, who wrote the book of love?
I got to know the answer
was it someone from above?
Oh, I wonder, wonder,
whom ba-doo-hoo-whom.
Who wrote the book of love?
What is that?
Chapter one says you love her,
you love her with all your heart
Chapter 2, you tell her...
you're never never never
never ever gonna part
And chapter 3, remember...
the meaning of romance
And chapter 4, you break up
But you give her just
one more chance
Oh, I wonder, wonder,
whom-ba-doo-hoo-whom
Who wrote the book of love?
I wonder who
Yeah.
Who wrote the book of love?
Thank you.
Grandma?
We're down here.
Oh!
Oh, boy.
Oh, Harper. Oh, this is great.
Wait, my camera.
Ok.
Oh.
Oh, honey, you look so great!
Thank you.
You look so beautiful.
Artie, what do you think of
your granddaughter now?
Wow. Ooh.
Oh!
Whoa!
Doesn't she look like her mom, huh?
Just like her mom.
Hey, it stopped raining.
Carl says we should go
outside and play again!
Oh, no, Barker, it's too muddy.
But he wants to.
Barker, remember
what we talked about?
You're the boss of Carl.
You tell him what to do.
We can't go out now, Carl.
Carl, no!
Stop!
What's wrong?
He ran away.
He said he's never coming back.
Oh, he'll come back.
He has to pick up his mail.
Yeah, mail.
Makes sense.
Barker!
Carl!
Artie, get him.
Barker has left
without adult supervision.
Carl, don't go!
Barker!
Goodbye, Artie Decker.
How many heart
attacks can you give me?
Oh, no, no, no!
Barker, are you ok?
He's fine.
What, are you hurt?
Look, can't you see?
He's dead, the car killed him!
Carl is dead!
What? No! I killed Carl?
Oh, honey, he's fine.
He's just dazed.
Yeah, yeah.
Carl, you're ok, aren't ya?
Yeah, I'm alright, mate. I'm alright!
That wasn't Carl, that was you!
Shut up!
No, he's not alright!
He's dead!
He's mushed all over the road.
His head is here and
his body's over there!
It's your fault! You made
me get into a fight with him!
We are so past weird.
I love Carl!
I even pack extra
fortune cookies for him!
Excuse me, what's
Chinese for mental case?
Hello?
We were cruising and heard the alarm.
Is everyone ok?
Yes.
No, he's dead! The car killed him!
He came out of nowhere!
Officer, you're wasting your time.
What happened?
Why are the police here?
Why is the alarm on?
Oh, hi!
Mommy!
Was there a break-in?
It's nothing.
It's absolutely nothing.
What are ya doin' home?
I killed Carl!
What?
You killed Carl? How?
Who is Carl?
Is he a family member?
Yes!
No!
He's a kangaroo!
He's a what?
Turner, your eye!
How did that happen?
Artie did it?
Oh, no, no, no.
Ivan's sister did it. I did that.
You hit Mom?
It was an accident!
Ma'am, would you
like to file a complaint?
No!
We were playing a game.
That's the dress.
Does she have make-up on?
Don't growl at us.
This is unbelievable.
We leave and she's 12,
we come home and she's 16.
Boys, go in the house.
Turner, turn off the alarm, please.
You know, you're not supposed
to be back until tomorrow.
Well, we were just so curious
as to why Barker was nearly
killed this morning at the X Games!
Uh-oh! Get your taser ready.
That's not right.
Barker was at a play date
this morning with Artie.
Oh, yeah?
I was in a little bind
and I had to take him
with me on some business.
What business did you
have at the X Games?
Yeah, Artie, what business?
Um...
Aren't we forgetting the
most serious issue here?
What issue?
The death of an imaginary kangaroo.
He's imaginary?
Yes!
You can go.
Would someone please
explain what happened to Carl?
We were playing Kick the Can
and it started to rain,
so we all came indoors
and I was helping Harper
get dressed for her party.
A party? You're throwing a party?
No, Dad, I'm going to a party.
For a boy who likes her.
A boy? What boy?
The night before your audition?
Are you kidding?
I told her she could go.
It's ridiculous.
It is out of the question.
Maybe it's ridiculous for me to spend
all my time practicing the violin...
never doing anything else and
auditioning for a school tomorrow
where I'm never going
to do anything else
the whole rest of my life.
Huh?
Well, she's using her words.
Harper. Harper!
I cannot allow you to take a talent...
a gift to which you have dedicated
so much time and effort
and throw it away on a whim.
I hate you and I wish
anyone else was my mother!
Maybe not those words.
Thanks, Mom and Dad.
I couldn't have gotten
through the week without you.
I say we head for
the airport right now.
Don't even take our clothes,
we just skedaddle.
I followed you for 35 years, Artie.
Wherever you needed to be,
that's where I was.
No complaints.
Well, some.
But this week...
This week was supposed to be
about us and our grandchildren.
Not you.
Did you have to go to that audition?
It's not one of my better moments.
For 1 wonderful hour...
we weren't...
the "other" grandparents.
Oh.
There you are.
You ok?
I've had better Mommy days.
You know, it may not have been
horrible to let her go to that party.
I know.
I just walked into that
scene and I freaked.
I can't believe my parents killed Carl.
Well, I was thinking about that.
You know, they didn't kill Carl,
only Barker could do that.
And it somehow took us not
being here for him to do it.
So, what's your point?
Maybe we coddle him too much.
Maybe he needed a little tough love
to let go of his imaginary friend.
But, Phil, that would
make my father right.
Yeah. We can't have any of that.
Harper?
I could come back.
No, no, no, it's ok.
I'm going to check on Barker.
Thanks, Phil.
I'm sorry.
For what?
Narrow it down for me, Dad.
For this week.
For almost getting Barker hurt today.
I just feel terrible about that.
What were you even doing there?
I was on an audition.
Because the Grizzlies fired me.
What?
Why didn't you tell us?
Because it's humiliating.
Why would they do that?
You're so good at that job.
Maybe not good enough.
Alice...
your mom was really hoping
that this trip would help bring
her closer to her grandchildren.
And she and Harper have developed
a relationship that's kind of great
and I don't want to see that
end just because I screwed up.
What about you?
Hmm?
Don't you want a relationship
with your grandchildren?
Of course I do.
I mean...
like an hour before you came
home, it was really good.
It's just that sometimes...
I don't feel...
What?
welcome, here.
What happened to us, Dad?
How old were you
when Harper was born?
26.
Mmm-hmm.
Did you know what you were doing?
No.
I was 23 when you came along.
And I was terrified, because you
didn't come with any instructions.
And I thought I was doin' ok.
Because unlike my father,
I wasn't constantly telling you
what an annoying little
waste of time you were
and believe me, I'm cleaning that up.
And I thought that we
were actually having fun.
Me and the weather girl
and the cutest little girl you ever saw,
traveling around the country.
But then years go by, and your
daughter goes off to college
and she doesn't come home
for Thanksgiving or Christmas.
Or summers.
Or ever.
And you get these clues, this inkling
that perhaps all those years she
wasn't having such a good time
and that maybe she thought
you didn't do such a good job.
And that really hurts. Doesn't it?
Yes.
So, little girl,
I have to give you 3 put-ups.
No, Dad.
Please.
It's ok.
Harper, Turner, Barker.
They're great kids and
you're a really good mother.
Yeah.
I'm basking in the glow
of my children's affection.
Harper? She didn't mean anything.
I mean, she's 12.
Get ready,
it's going to get a lot worse.
Only, don't let her
turn her back on you.
Because that will break your heart.
Harper?
No. Um...
Barker has a special request
for tomorrow, before the audition.
And it involves all of us.
Carl, your 2 favorite things
were milk and tofu dogs.
Now, you can have both forever.
Grandma, thanks
for decorating the box.
Oh, honey, it was my pleasure.
Um, Carl...
Can Artie say something nice for Carl?
Me?
How do ya...
I'm sorry, Carl.
He died so young.
Mmm.
How do ya say goodbye to somebody
you could never say hello to?
It's hard.
I didn't get to see Carl very often,
but then again, nobody else did.
Except for Barker
which is what made him so special.
Carl wasn't just Barker's friend,
he was a part of him.
And that made him a part of all of us.
Carl, you will forever be in our hearts.
Keep on hoppin', buddy.
Ok.
Alice, you take Harper backstage.
We'll grab some seats. Ok?
Barker, Turner, you're with us.
Good luck.
Knock them dead.
Thanks.
Break a leg.
Bye, Dad.
Don't applaud. That's that woman!
Good evening.
Welcome family, friends
and distinguished judges
to the Atlanta Performing Arts Center.
I am Doctor Schveer.
We have 14 amazingly
talented musicians
all vying for 1 position at
this prestigious conservatory.
So, without further ado I give you
Chet Halloran on the saxophone.
Yeah! Go Chet!
Hang on a second, honey.
You know,
when you were just 5 years old
we took you to that little
music school for the first time.
And all the other kids they
were just banging on things.
One kid tried to play another kid.
But from that very first day,
you played.
And not just played...
you had this look of such
fulfillment on your face.
And I said to your dad,
"Whatever it takes...
whatever we have to do, I always
want to see that look on her face."
Lately, I'm not seeing it.
So, honey, do you really not
want to switch schools again?
Ok.
What do you say we ditch this audition?
Really?
Yeah. It's ok.
Mommy, I didn't mean what I said.
Oh, baby.
I wouldn't want anyone
else to be my mom.
And I love you.
That's good because
you're my only daughter.
And you know,
I don't really understand the boys.
I know. How weird are they?
Yeah, yeah!
Hi, baby.
We regret to inform you of a
slight change in our program.
Harper Simmons has
forfeited her slot...
and her future.
Since the next
performer is warming up...
we're going to have to
take a 10 minute break.
Hey, what's going on?
She's not goin' to audition.
You're not disappointed in me, are you?
Oh, no, no, no.
That's not even a possibility.
Is this is all my fault? It is, isn't it?
I came 3,000 miles to ruin
my granddaughter's life.
It's not your fault.
Really?
It was our choice.
Oh honey, I love you.
Here, take my picture, Phil.
Get in there.
Uh, where's Turner?
You! Kid!
Turner!
Bobby Thomson, up there swingin'.
He's had 2 out of 3,
a single and a double
and Billy Cox is playing him
right on the 3rd base line.
1 out, last of the 9th.
Branca pitches.
Bobby Thomson takes a
strike called on the inside corner.
Bobby hitting at .292.
He's had a single and a double
and he drove in the Giants
1st run with a long fly to center.
Lockman without
too big of a lead at 2nd...
but he'll be running like the
wind if Thomson hits one.
Branca throws.
There's a long drive!
It's gonna be, I believe...
The Giants win the pennant!
The Giants win the pennant...
and they're goin' crazy.
They're goin' crazy!
And home!
I don't believe it!
I do not believe it!
Bobby Thomson hit a line drive...
into the lower deck
of the left field stands...
and the place is going crazy!
The Giants won it
by a score of 5 to 4...
and they're picking
Bobby Thomson up
and carrying him off the field!
Yeah! Yeah!
Wow.
I saw it. I saw it, Artie.
Call me Grandpa.
My big boy. How on earth...?
Grandpa taught me.
Oh...
Your father was wrong.
So was yours.
Oh, AI.
How much would it embarrass
you if I kissed you right now?
I think a lot.
As soon as we get home.
Ok, look forward to it.
Dr. Schveer, I shun you.
You are shunned.
My friends, it's taken me over
35 years to say these words...
it's opening day for the Giants
and we've got a capacity crowd.
Giants are out in the field.
There's Charlie "The Naz" Naznic...
batting .290,
takes his stance at the plate.
Yes, Art. Let's see if Naz
can get his team out of a jam.
Ok, Turner, here's the action.
Naz swings!
He gets some wood on that one!
Hard drive to Barker Simmons.
Ooh! It's through his legs.
Walters has it. No, Walters loses it.
Sherman's got a glove down.
No, he stopped to pick his nose.
Now, Douglas is sitting down
and taking off his shoes
because his mom said
to me before the game...
"Sometimes he's in another world."
Sherman still working
on that thing in his nose.
Man, that must be
really packed in there!
You betcha!
Naz rounds 2nd, heads for 3rd.
Sherman has the booger!
I don't believe it! I do not believe it!
The other players are
coming over to examine it.
I can see it from here!
Wow, you could take an
aerial photograph of that thing!
I'm sure there's gonna be
orange slices in the locker room
and a couple of tissues.
Meanwhile, Naz scores.
And that is another home run!
The Giants are still leading, 34 to 27.
What a 1st inning!
You're tellin' me.
I hope the 2nd inning is shorter
cuz, ahh, grandpa
needs a bathroom break.
Whoo!
Go Barker!
Our next batter is
comin' up to the plate.
He's number 3, Barker Simmons.
Yeah, Barker!
Young man with incredible power.
3-foot-4 and 45 pounds.
He hits it to shortstop.
Oh, it's through!
Barker heading towards 1st base.
No, he makes a right turn!
He makes a right turn.
Barker, go back!
He's going the wrong way.
Well, what are you doing here?
I just wanted to say hi.
He just wanted to say hi.
Well, I don't think I've ever heard...
Turn around, everybody.
Take our picture.
Ok, picture.
I got to tell you friends,
this is one of those days.
78 degrees,
the sold out crowd of 56 fans,
the smell of the popcorn, the hot dogs,
the loud pushy parents,
and the cryin' kids.
But I'll tell you somethin',
there's no other place I'd rather be.
And as my grandson Barker
said to me this morning...
"Man, your feet smell like cheese."
This is Artie Decker,
De Voice of the Peewee Giants...
saying see you next game!
And... lights out, Alice.
Settle down, it'll all be clear
Don't pay no mind to the demons
They fill you with fear
The trouble, it might drag you down
If you get lost,
you can always be found
Just know you're not alone
'Cause I'm going to
make this place your home
Um...
Andy? Andy, there's no paper.
Anyone have 5 singles for a 5?