Miss Ginger D'Amour.
Miss Cindy Consuelo.
Miss Joy Hampton.
And another of Chicago's favorites.
Miss Vicki Gaye.
Put her on the list.
What about this one? Will she go?
Expensive merchandise, Louis.
The boss ain't buying them.
He's just inviting them to a party.
Rico's party.
Rico Angelo is throwing a party.
You get a hundred bucks for showing up.
Rico Angelo. King of the rackets.
Royalty.
Are you going?
─ Uhuh.
I've been out with the mob before.
Most of the time all
they want to do is ..
Wave their cash around.
By the end of the evening, they're
usually too drunk for anything else.
It's a hundred dollars.
I want to stay home tonight.
Eddie might call.
Yeah.
Like he did last night?
I heard you walking the floor
until 5 o'clock this morning.
How long since you've heard from him?
Three weeks.
Almost a month.
Vicki, what am I going to do?
Call him.
Or find someone without a wife.
But the divorce was
all set. He told me it was.
Thanks, Joy.
Keep your hands out of my things or
I'll pull your hair out by the roots!
Listen, chubby.
Put on more pounds and you won't be
round long enough to tear anyone's hair.
Let her alone, won't you.
Look Joy .. go on home.
I'll try not to be late.
And remember.
It's only a man.
Only a man.
How do you do it, Vicki?
I made up my mind a long time ago.
Never get crowded into a corner.
Never let them get too close.
After a while .. they go away.
You've never been in that
corner, with your looks?
Just once.
In a dark and dirty little bar
back home in Oklahoma.
I was fifteen.
Very romantic.
Go on in, baby.
Rico Angelo. Make yourself at home.
Come on Rico, what do you say?
It's a party.
Forget her. She means
nothing to you anyway.
The most beautiful doll
in the world. That's all.
Hey boss, we're doing okay, huh?
Girls, come on over here.
Meet Mr Rico Angelo.
Hello Mr Angelo.
This is lucky Louis.
─ Louis Canetto.
Hiya, Puss.
The coat goes in the bedroom.
Wowee.
─ Salary.
What was that act for?
You know, with the photograph.
It's a picture of Jean Harlow.
The movie star, Jean Harlow?
She got married today out in Hollywood.
Mr Angelo is giving
a party to forget her.
Forget her?
Did he ever meet her?
No. But he's seen every
one of her movies.
He'd been carrying a torch for her.
The way he figures it,
she double-crossed him.
Well, that makes sense.
It's going to be an evening. I can tell.
Hey, come on kids.
Hurry it up, let's mingle a little.
There's nice guys out there.
They want to say hello.
Move along now. Come on,
kids. What do you say?
I wish I could find a
safe place for this.
Come on, just one time.
Come on! Let's go!
Stay close to me, Puss.
You're bringing me luck.
Shoot the five hundred.
Come on. Five open. Spread it out.
A pleasure to meet you, Counselor.
Particularly outside my courtroom.
You usually cause a little
difficulty for me there.
My job is to convince
the jury, Your Honor.
Not to make life
comfortable for the judge.
Come on baby, try it again.
Eight and one. Come on, dice.
Six.
Try again.
Thirty three, let's go. Six it is.
That's four hundred you got already.
Any part of it. Any part of it.
Don't get too far away, Puss.
We got some talking to do later.
[ Gunshot! ]
Nice shooting, Rico.
Where'd you get her?
Between the eyes?
I'll see you some other time.
Well, I took care of her.
She had it coming, Tommy.
She had it coming.
You're drunk, Rico.
Sodden, stupid drunk.
Ah, don't ride me.
I .. what are you all looking at?
Huh? Come on, it’s a party. Get going.
It's a party!
I got her out of my system.
Oh, I feel better already.
Congratulations.
Do you think Rico is drunk? Huh?
You catch me later.
Come on, what I'm talking
about now is a party. It's a party!
Come on, dice.
Pass the dice.
Hello.
Would you like to take me home?
Not particularly. Why?
Would you dance with me?
It's only a dance.
It would get me near the door.
It wouldn't kill you.
Why don't you give Louis his money back?
That would get you off the hook
You don't miss very much, do you?
Just a minute. I'm going
anyway. I'll take you.
Can I help you, Mr Farrell?
Let him alone. Let him alone!
Nobody helps when Rico's around.
You okay, boy?
I'm taking this girl home, Louis.
Sure.
Sure, Mr Farrell.
Would you like to come in for a minute?
There is not much in the icebox but
I could make you some .. cocoa.
Cocoa?
Haven't had any cocoa
since I was nine years old.
Maybe you got a new recipe.
I should have told you.
I have a roommate.
Joy .. man on the premises.
Joy?
Sit down.
That was quite a picnic tonight.
It had its moments.
For me particularly.
Mr Canetto was getting to be a problem.
It wouldn't have been if
you'd known all the facts.
Mr Canetto can't get out
of line. He's out on bail.
Mr Canetto goes on trial for
murder this coming Thursday.
A murderer?
He seemed a little scared of you.
He has to be. I'm defending him.
I haven't told you my name.
Vicki Gaye.
I heard someone mention it.
Been in Chicago long?
─ A few months.
Three years.
What did you do before you were
glamorized by The Golden Rooster?
Dance a little.
No talent?
I think so.
No takers.
So you gave it up?
It was that or give up eating.
And then?
Modeling.
Modeling for what?
Calendar art? Girlie magazines?
Tell me when I'm warm.
It seems I don't have to.
Bad?
It's nothing.
Excuse me.
Joy.
Do you know any reason
she would slit her wrists?
Did you know she was
three months pregnant?
Who was the guy? Come
on honey, who was it?
Come on, come on.
You don't live a year with a kid without
knowing who's taking care of her.
That's enough. No more questions.
Are you running this, mister?
Anything else you want to know,
she'll answer tomorrow in my office.
Thomas Farrell. Is that you?
She'll need a sedative
before she leaves.
Get her some water.
Sure, Mr Farrell.
You can't go back to your
place yet. Do you want a hotel?
Anything.
Over there.
I'll go and see about that cocoa.
It will probably taste more like
brandy and coffee, but it might help.
If I'd been there.
If I'd gone home tonight.
She'd be alive now.
Probably.
But what about tomorrow night?
The night after that?
Self-destruction among showgirls
seems to be a kind of ..
Occupational hazard.
Probably the cheery
atmosphere of nightclub life.
By the way, our genial host
of the evening, Mr Rico Angelo.
Owns a sizable piece
of The Golden Rooster.
He might be able to
do something for you.
Seeing you're a dancer.
For which I'll take your word.
You might prefer that to
parading around half-naked.
This is a copy of your medical
report, Rico. I'll leave it with you.
When Louis goes on trial, in case
you get summoned as a witness.
You'll be too sick to show up.
That will prove it.
What have I got?
Incipient general paralysis.
That sounds high class.
High class and probably very true.
Hey, where you going?
Come here. Sit down. Eat something.
I handle your business for you, Rico.
I'll even protect your hoods for you.
But I refuse to eat with you.
Why?
You're a slob.
A slob. How do you like that?
Did you hear what he said?
Shut up.
And there is one more thing.
Outside, Louis.
There's a girl, Vicki Gaye,
works at The Golden Rooster.
I'd like her to have a better job.
Okay. Make a note.
That leg of yours. It don't stop
you from nothing, does it.
Don't get sore at Rico.
Fix a job for her.
Don't mention my name.
"Expect Canetto to face chair."
"Guilty verdict for Canetto likely."
"Farrell's final summation today."
Forget that. Anything more?
No, the Express isn't out yet.
That jury has been pretty cold. It's
going to be tough breaking them down.
Forget the jury.
I'll take care of the jury.
Make sure I have those
headlines in court today.
[ Buzzer ]
Yes?
"A Miss Vicki Gaye is here."
─ Send her in.
Lou.
Hello.
Sit down.
Police been bothering you?
─ No.
I wanted to see you.
─ Professionally?
Personally .. I want to
thank you for what you did.
You already thanked me on the phone.
At the club this morning, they said
I was to have a number of my own.
They said that someone ..
I don't know what they told you at the
club. I'm not particularly interested.
I'm due back in court in a few
minutes. Was there anything else?
Here is the money that Louis
Canetto gave me at the party.
Will you see that he gets it.
That's a very sentimental gesture.
But Canetto doesn't need money. What he
needs is a good lawyer and lots of luck.
I would still rather give it back.
Why?
Maybe I want you to have
a better opinion of me.
A girl is entitled to what she can get.
When you sell your pride,
it's tough to put a price on it.
Four hundred dollars isn't very high.
[ Door knocks ]
They are calling you from the court.
Department 181 of the
Criminal Court, State of Illinois.
For Cook County is now in session.
Judge Bookwell presiding.
Take your seats.
Order in the court. No talking.
Order in the court.
Is the defense ready for summation?
Ready, Your Honor.
Watch that walk.
Gentlemen.
I would like you to look upon the face.
Of a dead man.
At this moment, I wouldn't give you
two cents for the life of Louis Canetto.
You are also looking
at a defeated attorney.
Defeated not by facts.
Not by the testimony of the ..
District Attorney's witnesses.
But by circumstances
over which, unfortunately ..
You and this court have no jurisdiction.
Take care of this thing
for me, will you?
Thanks.
You gentlemen have been
summoned here as intelligent ..
Honest citizens of the state
of Illinois to decide ..
Whether Louis Canetto shall live or die.
But you're not making that decision.
That decision has been made for you,
"Expect Canetto to face chair."
"Guilty verdict for Canetto likely."
That's where this case is
being tried. In the daily press.
By crime reporters and sob sisters
grubbing and rooting among the ..
The moral garbage of our city.
They have decided
Louis Canetto is guilty.
They have taken over your rights.
Abrogated your sacred
privilege to judge for yourself.
In no uncertain terms, they
have told you what to do.
I'm with you, gentlemen.
I wouldn't be flattered.
Mr Farrell.
The daily newspapers
are not on trial here.
I'm sorry, Your Honor.
I said a moment ago I'd
been defeated by the press.
I now find I must also submit
to the disapproval of the court.
Very well, gentlemen.
You will bear with me for a moment.
I notice that some of you
are looking at my watch.
Not very impressive, is it?
But it has a certain.
Sentimental value.
My father gave me this
watch, when I was a kid.
In City Hospital.
It keeps good time.
Of which, I shall try to use as little as
possible while we examine the facts.
In all my years on the bench.
I have never seen a jury so flagrantly
defy the court's instructions.
Your names will be struck
from the jury list of Cook County.
Where can I find Mr Farrell, please?
Try Mick's Speakeasy, round the corner.
The second one down.
I'm looking for Mr Farrell. Is he here?
He just came in.
You know why?
The best lawyer in the state
of Illinois. Rico knows it.
Rico knows. I talk to them plenty. They
don't even talk the same language.
Order up, Tommy.
Have a drink, Mr Farrell.
He don't drink, you crumb.
Get him some coffee.
I'll take it down there, Nick.
And what’s the matter with here?
The chick. Chicks come first.
This .. this isn't an accident?
I was in court this afternoon.
Yes, I saw you.
Very interesting.
Criminal cases usually are.
Let me ask you a question.
When I took money from Louis Canetto
you said I was selling my pride.
What makes you so much better than me?
Louis Canetto is a murderer.
He's guilty and you know it.
And still you got him off.
Why?
If a man's dying of cancer he's entitled
to the best medical care he can afford.
If he's facing the electric chair
he's entitled to the best lawyer.
I'm .. one of the best.
And like a competent surgeon,
I get a good fee.
You mean your pride
sells higher than mine?
That's right. It's my business.
A mouthpiece for the mob.
A guardian angel for punks and gunmen.
You like being that.
It wasn't forced upon me. I could have
chosen another branch of the law but ..
This was the quickest way.
I'm a great believer
in the quickest way.
You may have noticed that I
limp more in front of a jury.
Did you notice?
Yes.
I do that to get their
sympathy and their pity.
And I take their pity and I use it.
Is that what you want .. pity?
If it is, you have mine.
For a lot of things.
Get out of here.
Blinkey, open up will you.
─ Okay.
Hiya, Puss.
Thank you.
Hey, fellahs.
Hey, Mr Farrell.
That was a pretty good show today. That
business with the watch was very funny.
I'm glad I amused you, Louis.
Next time, maybe I'll let you fry.
Here.
Keep it as a memento.
Thanks.
A pretty good day for tips.
Hey Nick. Set them up. Another round.
He's out there again.
Third time this week.
He's boozing it up tonight,
though. That's a switch.
Doesn't he ever ask you
for a date or anything?
And now.
Miss Vicki Gaye!
I was brought up in this district.
We used to swim down there.
It was a little slimy but it was cool.
When the bridge opened, we used to
hang on to the girders underneath.
The trick was to see who had the
nerve enough to hang on the longest.
One day, one of us was a real winner.
But something went wrong. He
slipped and got mixed up in the gears.
Like being caught in a meat grinder.
The bones of his hip weren't set
too well. He dragged his left leg.
He didn't mind too much.
He was twelve years old.
In a kind of a way, it made him
a hero with the rest of the gang.
A few years later, when the ..
When other kids were walking their girls
through Hammond park on summer nights.
He began to think that somewhere
along the line he'd been cheated.
One night I made myself a promise.
That someday, in spite of a crooked
body, I'd be a whole man again.
Respected. Admired.
Even envied.
That was my goal.
The law was the road to it.
Criminal law because
it was the quickest way.
I have respect now.
There are judges in this
town who are afraid of me.
Politicians who ..
Hate my guts.
But they all respect me.
I got off the road once.
I married.
She was a showgirl.
Pampered, spoiled. Very beautiful.
Being beautiful, she felt entitled
to anything the world had to offer.
Penthouse apartment. Furs, jewels.
I was in love with her.
I enjoyed giving it to her.
And then one night I went to her
room and she told me from her ..
Sweet-smelling bed.
She couldn't bear the
sight of my crookedness.
There wasn't any divorce.
That wasn't part of her plan.
I left that night.
I haven't seen her since.
Where is she now?
In the apartment.
With the furs and the jewels and
a check on the 1st of every month.
I wanted to tell you.
I wanted you to know.
I'll take you home now.
Yes?
Hi.
─ Hi.
I realize you're an artiste now,
and probably won't be interested.
But there are a couple of
live ones in from St Louis.
No thanks.
I already told one of them
I was behind on my rent.
Which I managed to raise
to two hundred dollars.
I've got a date.
Well .. twelve roses.
A whole dozen.
He must be loaded.
What do you think?
How's it look, pretty good?
Fine Mr Tom, sir.
You don't mind working so late?
─ No sir, no sir.
May I say it's a real pleasure
to see you like this.
I tell you Jessie, it's a real
pleasure to feel like this.
But .. music, will you.
─ Oh, yes sir.
We can't do without music.
Uhuh.
Chopin. Nocturnes.
What do you think?
Very appropriate.
You ever heard it?
─ No sir, I have not.
Neither have I. Let's try it.
[ Buzzer ]
Yes, sir.
Hello, Jessie.
─ Evening, Miss Vicki.
Happy anniversary.
Well, how do you like it?
I did it all myself.
Of course, Jessie ..
Arranged the table, bought the flowers.
Cooked the food. Incidentals like that.
But I did it all myself.
Beautiful.
Oh, here.
This is something I really did myself.
What is it, Tommy?
─ Open.
It looks very expensive.
─ It is.
I thought we had an agreement.
All I thought was, how beautiful
it would look on you.
I've never given you anything.
You never let me.
You had your job, your own apartment.
There was nothing I could do for you.
Make an exception. Just this once.
Well?
[ Telephone ]
Hello.
Yes, Lou. What is it?
Where?
Is Rico there now?
Yeah. I'll come as soon as I can.
Meet me outside.
I have to leave.
There is ..
A meeting. A dinner.
A dinner .. at 2 o'clock in the morning?
That's normal for Rico Angelo.
Is anything wrong?
There might be if I don't get there.
I'll get you a taxi.
I'll wait here.          ─ No.
─ I want to.
Say, it's a great honor.
For me to stand here.
To honor Frankie Gasto.
A hard boy and a vicious boy.
And what's more.
A boy you can trust.
For anything that calls
for a boy like that.
The last couple of years,
Frankie's done a great job.
Organizing the poor-room collections.
A lot better than all
you mugs put together.
Ha ha.
So I'd like to present.
This little token.
See .. a little pool cue.
Engraved with solid silver.
From Rico .. to Frankie.
Competition.
I'm honored.
To present this to Frankie Gasto.
Who's a great guy!
You know, he did make a
couple of .. small mistakes.
Trying to set up another
organization to take over ..
What I built up.
Well.
That's ambition.
Huh?
And a guy that's got ambition
has got something coming.
I could have asked anybody else
to give this to Frankie for me.
I like to do things personally.
From .. Rico to Frankie.
Rico .. Rico!
You damned fool.
He crossed me.
He had it coming. He crossed me.
Get him to a hospital.
No ambulance. Can't wait.
He crossed me. I had to teach him.
If he dies, I'll try
telling that to a jury.
Tommy?
Getting worried about you.
It's blood, Tommy.
It isn't mine. That's
all you need to know.
[ Telephone ]
Hello?
─ Tom?
Gasto pulled through.
He's going to live.
Tell Rico to go to Miami.
Wait there until he hears from me.
"Right."
Don't ever answer either of these
phones. The less you know, the better.
Tommy .. get out of it.
Before something happens.
Get out now.
─ And do what?
Hang out a shingle in some
farm town and wait for clients?
Why not? You could make a living.
Sure. They're waiting in line.
All over the country they're waiting in
line for a crippled attorney with a ..
Crippled reputation to
draw up their wills.
The difficulty is centered
in this are here.
However, there seems to be
some small degree of hope.
A set of corrective procedures by Doctor
Karl Linden, Royal Hospital, Stockholm.
Consisting of multiple osteotomies.
Osteotomy is medical jargon
for the breaking of bones.
Then, internal fixations
with wires and screws.
Later, bone grafts.
To be done at monthly intervals.
A long, tedious procedure.
Acute discomfort. Considerable pain.
I don't imagine that frightens you.
You're probably used it by now.
The one thing I should I add.
There is no guarantee of success.
I'll let you know.
I never knew there was pain.
You never told me.
You'll go, won't you?
No matter how long it takes.
A year away from you?
Whenever you need me.
Just turn around and I'll be there.
Tommy.
Hello Jessie. Is Mr Farrell home yet?
I've been shopping. The most
wonderful kind of shopping.
Ask for any place in the whole world and
they give it to you in your two hands.
The doctor said he would have to
relax before the first operation.
What do you think of the French Riviera?
The golden hours in Antibes.
It is "Antibes" you know. Not Antibes.
I learned that today.
Mr Farrell has gone, Miss Vicki.
He went to New York last night.
His boat sailed this afternoon.
He asked me to give this to you.
[ Tommy's voice ]
"So I didn't want to say goodbye."
"Please try to understand."
"I would like to be alone now."
"We have waited so long for each other."
"This year will not make
too much difference."
"Take care of yourself, darling."
"Write me."
"I love you."
Hello.
I wanted to meet you close up.
I'm Genevieve Farrell. Tommy's wife.
I should have recognized you.
We are sort-of the same type, aren't we.
They say that happens. A man
always marries the same girl twice.
Of course, he can't marry you,
but that's the general idea.
I know about the Stockholm trip
naturally. How is he coming along?
Alright.
─ You hear from him regularly?
Yes.
It's been a long time, hasn't it.
I mean, since he left.
Over a year.
I hope it's successful.
He's an attractive man, Tommy.
Or would be ..
─ What do you want?
I told you. I was curious.
I wondered what you were like.
I know what you're like.
You are not in love with Tommy.
What are you hanging on for?
I gave up a lot for Tommy
when I married him.
Besides, this operation
might change everything.
I think it's only fair you should know.
I've written to Tommy.
I told him if things work out,
if he wants me, I'll be waiting.
You had no right.
No right? Honey, I'm his wife.
Honey?
You are just married to him.
Thank you.
─ Thank you, Miss.
Vicki .. Vicki!
Stay there.
[ Italian language ]
Chicago! It is very important, señor.
Chicago, USA .. Chicago.
Telephone .. America, America.
Hello?
Ah yes, Rico.
Well soon. I don't know exactly when.
I'm anxious to see you, too.
Yeah, I'll call you.
When I get there.
It's Rico's way of saying welcome home.
Eighteen hundred bucks.
Good enough?
Rico, we'd better have a little talk.
Oh yeah, we've got a lot of
catching up to do. Later, huh?
Oh hi, Farrell.
─ Louis.
Say, why didn't you bring the chick?
A lot of nice people here tonight.
The most important guys in town.
Get on up here, I said
and say hello to my boy.
Welcome back, Tommy.
─ Thank you, Your Honor.
How do you like my boy, huh?
He looks fine.
─ It works pretty good, huh?
That cane, in a few months,
he won't even need it.
Right, Tommy?
I want you to meet somebody.
Cookie La Motte - shake
hands with Tommy Farrell.
So this is your genius?
Maybe you've heard of Cookie?
Oh, everyone's heard of Cookie.
The youngest punk in Illinois
ever to beat a murder rap.
Sixteen, weren't you Cookie?
Fifteen and a half.
Excuse me.
Well, Cookie ain't a punk anymore.
Him and me, we've kind of merged.
He takes care of the southern
part of the state. I operate here.
But.
Right now, the reason I
want you to meet him ..
Cookie is in kind of a jam.
What mischief has Cookie been up to?
Did you ever hear of a smart-aleck
punk named Jeffrey Stewart?
I know a lawyer, Jeffrey Stewart.
Just been appointed Special Investigator
to inquire into the rackets.
That's him. He got the political bug.
Wants to be senator or something. Well.
What does he do?
He turns the heat on Cookie.
He calls him before the Grand Jury
in Springfield and if they get a ..
A, what do you call it, an indictment ..
It means Cookie must stand trial, right?
That means I go next.
Well.
In a way, while you're talking up for
Cookie, you'll be talking for me, too.
Right?
What do you say? What's his chances?
You want it quick?
Get out of town, Cookie.
If possible, get out of the state.
You haven't got a prayer.
No?
Why?
Too many witnesses against you.
Witnesses?
For instance?
Well to name a few:
Manny Nicholls, for instance.
Saul Horseman, for instance.
Frank Deleary, Lippy Burke. There
is quite a list. I can't remember all.
Witnesses?
Those guys are dead.
That's what I mean, Cookie.
Any investigator in his right
mind knows who buried them.
You know something, Rico.
I don't like your genius.
He has a sense of humor.
But I don't like him.
Cookie, you go on.
Let me talk to Tommy alone.
You weren't very polite to Cookie.
You hurt his feelings.
I didn't realize he was so sensitive.
A nice partner you're hooked up with.
He's a smart kid.
Brilliant. He's also a psychopath.
You know, that's what I like about
you, Tommy. You've got class.
Big talk .. fancy words.
But what's it mean?
He's insane, Rico. Crazy.
Gone in the head.
Why?
Because he got rid of a few rats who got
in his way? Maybe I'd do the same thing.
Am I crazy, too?
─ You're predictable, Rico. He isn't.
He doesn't kill for business.
He kills because he enjoys it.
He's like .. a dog with rabies.
Except he doesn't froth at the mouth.
Someday he'll get around to that, too.
Look, maybe he froths, maybe he don't
froth. All I know is, he's in trouble.
And so am I .. so get to work, will you.
Sorry, Rico.
That's what I want to talk about.
I'm going to the coast
in a couple of days.
Get a license out there and set
up a new practice. Legitimate.
It will be tough for a while
but I figure I can make it.
I don't think I like this, Tommy.
All of a sudden you walk on two feet,
and you kick your friends in the face.
I don't see it that way.
You know everything about me,
Tommy. My whole operation.
Where the payoff is, and who to. All my
friends, all my enemies, alive and dead.
I always told you everything,
Tommy .. like a Priest, you know.
The only difference is,
a Priest can't talk.
You know me better than that.
Alright. Yeah.
I'm talking like a louse.
Well.
Let's put it this way. I need you Tommy.
You are my boy, like a son.
You walk out on me now,
what happens to poor Rico?
Poor Rico gets himself another
lawyer. There are plenty in town.
But only one Tommy Farrell.
Not available, Rico.
You know there is one thing I could
never stand, it was a reformed drunk.
A reformed crook I would
put in the same class.
A lawyer doesn't become a crook
just because he represents one.
I can plead any crooks case, even yours.
Or Cookie La Motte.
I'm out, Rico .. for good.
Nobody ever quit me.
I got rid of a few guys
but nobody ever quit.
Except me.
Get used to it, Rico.
I hate to do this.
You're making me sound like a lousy guy.
Tommy, you know what you told
me about this new hip of yours?
How it's strung together
with pins and wires.
Plates and screws.
Suppose somebody took
a crowbar to that hip.
Huh?
One fast swing ..
It would look like the inside
of a busted radio set.
You wouldn't walk so good.
Maybe never. It hurts
me to think about it.
Try it, Rico.
Me? Nah ..
You're my boy.
I couldn't do a thing like that.
But I know a guy who would.
Have him try it.
And take that chick of yours.
That's what I call a real, pretty chick.
I only saw her once, but ..
The face of an angel.
You know what a bottle of acid
could do to a face like that?
There is a guy for that job, too.
If you touch her.
If anyone touches her.
I'll kill you, Rico.
You don't have to kill me, Tommy.
Because nobody is going
to lay a finger on her.
Because you are going to
take this Springfield job.
Now.
Let's go and be polite to Cookie.
Bring him in here.
I don't chase around after punks.
Temperamental.
I like it.
Look.
It's the last job I'll do for Rico.
He understands that.
When this thing is over,
the day it's over ..
Tommy .. don't try to explain it to me.
You've taken this case.
For some reason you want me with you.
Well .. I'm here.
[ Buzzer ]
Yeah?
Hello.
I was just passing. And I thought I'd
stop in and say hello to my counselor.
How is it going?
I wondered, when we get there tomorrow.
I thought perhaps you might
want to rehearse me a little bit.
Tell me what to say.
What you need to rehearse
Cookie is keeping your mouth shut.
And get yourself a
decent suit of clothes.
Just trying to be of some help.
─ Sure.
Can you read?
Run over this stuff and see
how they can fail to indict you.
They'll indict, and that
means a jury trial.
Now, you're a genius in front of a jury.
─ So is Jeffrey Stewart.
I'm not worried.
Rico says I'm in good hands.
The best.
Right?
It had better be.
Mr Field.
─ Yes, sir.
As a prospective juror.
Do you have any moral aversion
towards capital punishment?
No sir.
Could you send the defendant,
Cookie La Motte, to the electric chair?
If he deserved it, yeah.
The state finds this juryman acceptable.
Thank you.
─ You're welcome.
All yours, Mr Farrell.
─ Thank you.
Mr Field.
─ Yes, sir.
Have you formed any kind
of notions about this case?
Whether the defendant
might be guilty or innocent?
No sir.
Do you know anything
about Cookie La Motte?
No .. no.
Do you read the newspapers?
Yes, sporting pages.
That's all you read?
─ And the comics.
Something fishy about this one.
I can't put my finger on it.
Accept.
I don't like him.
He's okay.
Rico says he's okay.
Accept.
May we have a decision, Mr Farrell?
Is this juryman acceptable or not?
Acceptable, Your Honor.
─ Next.
Rico is waiting for you.
Juror bribed. La Motte vanishes.
Juror bribed.
Put them in there. In this cab.
Cookie has gone over the state line.
Whiting Indiana. Heard on the grapevine.
Says they'll get rid of Jeffrey Stewart.
Get rid of him, how?
Take a guess. You know
what this can mean to me?
It could be a lot of trouble, boy.
Go see him. Talk some sense into him.
I warned you about that punk.
Some day he'd froth at the mouth.
Didn't take long, did it?
Don't ask me to wipe his face.
He's your baby now, Rico.
Clean up the mess yourself.
Get me to a phone.
Take the bags to the apartment.
Wait for me there.
How many ..
─ Vicki, do as I say.
Whitey, the Harbor Grill.
Get rid of Stewart how, Cookie?
We vote him out.
My friends and I vote him out.
I've some very accommodating friends.
Listen gay boy, you don't run around
knocking off State's Attorneys.
It isn't being done this year.
If Stewart gets a scratch, they'll
run you down like a sewer rat.
Why me? Stewart's in Chicago.
I'm not in the state.
Your accommodating
friends are. Good enough.
Whose lawyer are you?
Theirs or mine? You talk like theirs.
If you're such a genius, what am I
doing sitting in this trap right now?
Look, I can do something about lawyers.
What are you going to do about it?
Talk! Do something whatever,
or shut up and let me do it myself.
I ought to warn you.
Rico knows what you've got
in mind. He doesn't like it.
Well, that's lovely. You can
tell Rico from me he can go ..
[ Radio broadcast ]
"Tonight, the checkered career of
Cookie La Motte came to a grisly end."
"La Motte and four companions shot
to death in a Whiting Indiana saloon."
"The four slain men have
still not been identified."
"In gangland circles .."
It is whispered the mass killing was
decreed by hoodlum Czar, Rico Angelo."
"The opening salvo in a campaign to wipe
out all henchmen of the dead La Motte."
"If this is true, no man who ever worked
with La Motte or even knew him."
"Can feel secure tonight."
The fact that mobsters are conducting
a private war to kill each other off.
Doesn't mean Illinois State has turned
the administration of law over to them,
Tomorrow, we will appear before a
Blue-Riband panel of the Grand Jury.
To secure an indictment against
every person in high position or low ..
"In any way connected with
Rico Angelo and his racket empire."
Tommy.
─ Alright.
I couldn't call and couldn't drive back
on the main road. Crawling with Cops.
All night long I kept thinking:
what if he's dead?
What if he's dead!
Tommy.
Oh Rico doesn't want me. If he did
he'd have taken care of it tonight.
Now listen .. I've got to talk to you.
We don't have much time.
There is some cash here.
It isn't much, but it will have to do.
Take it.
Get on the first train you can make.
Go to the coast. Any place.
─ Why?
Let me know where you are.
─ Why? What have I done?
Nothing, nothing.
─ What am I running from?
Listen .. this whole town has exploded.
They're planning a Grand Jury right now.
They'll name me. I'll be indicted.
If you're in trouble, I belong with you.
Not hiding someplace.
Vicki, will you do what I ask?
─ No.
Not unless you go too.
[ Telephone ]
Hello?
Yes, Rico. How are you
this pleasant evening?
I got it all figured out,
this Grand Jury business.
Without your testimony,
the state don't have a case, right?
I mean, if you don't talk they
don't even make out a warrant.
Well, so .. keep out of sight, Tommy.
Keep on the move for a while.
Well now, that's a
masterpiece of legal strategy.
"Whose brain are you using? Lou Forbes?"
Listen boy, you do like I say
and there won't be any beefs.
Tommy, don't make me get tough. Remember
what I said about you and that chick?
It still goes. More than ever.
Now start moving.
Go on home and pack. I'll pick
you up there in a few minutes.
Tom!
Police Officers.
Hi there, Mr Farrell.
Mind telling us where
you were, earlier tonight?
Alright, it doesn't matter.
Pretty Boy lived just enough to
tell us that you were in Whiting.
Let's go, Mr Farrell .. you too, Miss.
What are the charges?
─ You?
A material witness.
Her?
You take your choice.
Let's go.
When does he come up for bail?
Sometime this morning.
Then I'll get a bondsman
and bail him out.
You .. sure you want to?
Farrell was in Whiting
last night. They know that.
If you pay his bond now, you might as
well tell the Police you sent him there.
Very smart.
What do we do now?
Nothing. Just sit tight.
As long as Farrell doesn't talk, we ..
─ He won't talk.
Let him rot for a while.
Okay, but the girl I want out.
Louis, see that she gets her job back
at the club and keep an eye on her.
What for?
─ Legal brain.
So long as she's where I can reach
her, that's why he won't talk.
The defendant Gaye is being held
on an open charge. Is that correct?
That is correct, Your Honor.
Your Honor, since there
is no definite charge.
I request that Miss Gaye be released
without bail on her own recognizance.
Request denied.
The court will accept recommendations
from the Prosecutor's office.
No recommendation for
the defendant Gaye.
However, in the case of Thomas Farrell.
In addition to the specific
charge of suborning a jury.
We would like to remind the court.
That he will be a key witness in the
people's case against Rico Angelo.
We recommend sufficient bail
to assure his presence at trial.
Bail for the defendant Gaye is
set at five thousand dollars.
For the defendant Farrell.
Two hundred thousand dollars.
You come out this way, honey.
Somebody is paying your bail.
Tom.
Well, what's your pleasure today?
Do we talk things out for a change?
Or are you thinking of making
this your permanent address?
The food is inexpensive
and the bed's not bad.
I might just do that.
Besides, I have to come to trial
sometime. You can't hold me for ever.
It's going to seem like forever, Tom.
I'd like to help you.
─ And yourself.
Incidentally, when do they
start pushing you for senator?
The day you start talking.
Once again, who killed Cookie La Motte?
Person or persons unknown.
Once again, who bribed that
juror down at Springfield?
Not me. You know that.
Sure, I know that. You're too smart.
But will a jury think so?
I doubt it.
When I was a practicing attorney.
A couple of weeks ago.
My great stock in trade
was defending the guilty.
Evidently, yours is
convicting the innocent.
Tom.
You are my whole case
against Rico Angelo.
I need you.
So you're threatening me.
─ You bet I am.
I warned you. I can be
just as conniving as you.
Maybe more so.
But there is one difference between us.
I happen to be on the right side.
And I have no rights at all.
Except one.
The right to be left alone. Do you mind?
I'd like to read my newspaper.
What you need Tom, is a smart lawyer.
Maybe so. Want the job?
I wouldn't be bad at it.
I might even dream up something
as good as that .. watch gag of yours.
I always admired that piece of business.
Tell me Tom, where'd you get the watch?
Not from your father?
I buy them by the gross.
You plead my case for
me I'll give you one.
If I were pleading your
case, I wouldn't need it.
All I'd want from you is a statement to
go states evidence against Rico Angelo.
Ten minutes after you signed it,
you'd be walking out that door.
I'll think over your advice.
Mail me your bill.
Excuse me, Mr Stewart.
He's got a visitor.
After two weeks. I thought
you might like a little company.
Go ahead.
Thanks.
She's a nice girl, Farrell.
I tried to come before.
They wouldn't let me.
Are you alright?
How about you?
─ Fine.
I have a job.
At the Golden Rooster.
More money than before.
Pretty funny, isn't it.
Did they tell you who paid your bail?
Just the club. That's all.
Why?
No reason. I just asked.
Tommy.
Why hasn't someone
done something for you?
They could get you out .. Angelo could.
Right now, Angelo would like to
pretend I don't exist. I'm a criminal.
He can't afford to get mixed
up with the criminal types.
Maybe if I went.
If I told ..
─ No! Stay away from him.
Don't ever go anywhere near Rico Angelo.
I was going to write to you.
Now it doesn't seem very important.
My wife is divorcing me.
A little late, isn't it.
Not for me.
Alright, Mr Farrell. Let's go.
Oh, Miss Gaye.
I .. just wanted you to know.
You can have a pass now,
any time you want it.
Thank you.
We're sorry to have to
hold him here like this.
Actually, it's not Farrell we
want at all. It's Rico Angelo.
If you could just get Farrell to talk.
To supply us with certain information.
We'd do everything we could to help him.
You mean, he'd go free?
That's right.
Have you told him that?
─ Every day.
What was his answer?
Nothing.
Then why tell me about it?
Because we think he'd listen to you.
He could go to prison for twenty years.
You know that.
Yes.
[ Door knocks ]
Just a minute.
What are you doing here?
I just wanted to wish
you a happy new year.
Happy new year. Get out.
I said get out!
I got a message for you.
From Rico Angelo.
He says tell Tommy he's doing a good job.
Playing smart. He wants him to know that.
You're a liar.
Rico Angelo didn't say anything.
That's right.
I'm just making conversation.
All the same, Tommy is
doing okay, not talking.
I mean.
You know.
His friends appreciate it.
I hope he does talk.
I hope he digs a black hole for all his
very good friends and shoves them in it.
You included.
You ought to be nicer to me, Puss.
You might need me sometime.
I could be a big help.
Why would I ever need you?
You know.
In case they put the screws
on Tommy and he sings a little.
Be a good time to have me around.
I ain't afraid of Rico Angelo.
A lot of guys are, but not me.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe I do need someone.
You ain't got far to look.
I always had a kind of thing for you.
You know what I mean?
─ Louis.
Tell me something.
How bad a spot am I in?
Don't worry about it.
─ Yes, but ..
Like you said, if Tommy did talk ..
What would Rico do to me?
I don't know.
Maybe nothing.
He'd try to kill me, wouldn't he.
Well, not if I'm here.
Not if I'm here.
─ Thank you, Louis.
Hey come on. What are you,
crazy or something?
What's the matter with you?
Hello?
─ "Mr Stewart?"
Yes.
I want to see Tommy.
You've got to let me see him.
You had a visitor's pass
whenever you wanted it.
I don't mean there.
I can't talk to him there.
I want to see him alone by ourselves.
Do you think you can get him to talk?
I don't know.
I'll do what I can.
But I've got to be alone with him.
Just for a little while.
Please.
Help me.
See you later, Farrell.
The phone will ring in a few minutes.
Three times.
It means I have to leave.
They won't let me come back again.
For the last time, will you
talk to Jeffrey Stewart?
You're afraid, aren't you.
Not for yourself. For me.
Afraid of what they'll do to me.
Who told you that?
I'm not afraid .. why should you be?
When we're not together,
we have nothing.
We're alive. That's something.
As long as I keep my mouth
shut, you'll be alright.
Do you think so?
Do you really think so?
Let me tell you something.
I had a visitor last night
in my dressing-room.
Your good friend, Louis Canetto.
He came in while I was changing.
He didn't ask.
He just walked in.
He's the one who told me.
And then he came close to me.
As close as I am to you.
And then he put his hands on me.
Tell me it's alright, Tommy!
I'm sorry for what I've done to you.
[ Telephone ]
It's no use. He's protecting me.
See that she gets home.
─ Right.
Bring Farrell to my office.
You know we had to pay a month's
rent in advance for that place today.
Looks as though we wasted
the taxpayer’s dough.
You could have been a
big help to us, Farrell.
We really could have used you.
But since obviously you're
not going to play along.
There's nothing much
we can do, is there.
I think this is everything
you came in with.
You'll have to sign for
it downstairs of course.
Would you like to explain this?
There's nothing to explain.
We're letting you go. That's all.
You're out.
─ What did you tell the newspapers?
That I talked? That I
turned state's evidence?
I don't tell them a thing.
I let them draw their own conclusions.
They will, too. Everyone will.
Including Rico Angelo.
He'll think I made a deal with you.
You know what you're doing, of course.
The second I set a foot out the building
you can put a call in for the coroner.
That's your problem.
What about the girl?
That's your problem, too.
You've made it for
yourselves, both of you.
I want protection.
Not myself. For her.
Good enough.
We'll send her to the coast.
Hold her there as long as you want.
Alright.
Get a stenographer.
There will be someone
meeting you in Los Angeles.
You won't have to look
for him. He'll know you.
And .. don't leave the compartment
until he picks you up.
Swear out a warrant for Rico Angelo and
anyone else named in the transcript.
Is that all?
You can go now.
If you want.
Or, we can hold you here a while longer.
It might be safer.
Now there is not a safe place anywhere
above ground. I think we both know that.
Wait a minute.
You want this?
Thanks.
I don't have a permit.
Incidentally, if you should have
any trouble locating Mr Angelo.
He won't be far behind me.
Do what you can for him.
Mr Farrell.
Hi Nick.
Let me have a beer, will you.
Good to see you, Mr Farrell.
Anybody been in today?
No, it's a little early yet, Mr Farrell.
If anyone comes in,
tell them I was here.
I'll be back later.
It's like he's looking to get
knocked off, Mr Stewart.
He's done everything but advertize.
Yeah.
I can't figure whether Angelo is looking
for him or he's looking for Angelo.
I'll finish that beer now, Nick.
─ Sure, Mr Farrell.
Alright, Nick.
─ Good to see you.
[ Telephone ]
Hello?
Yeah, he just come in.
For you, Mr Farrell.
Hello?
─ "Farrell - Rico wants to see you."
Yeah, I thought he might.
Where is he?
Don't ask questions and
don't make any moves.
Is Rico there now?
Put him on.
"Never mind, is here now."
Just walk out the back door.
"Farrell."
"Do you hear what I said?"
"Walk out the back door."
Everybody out.
Louis.
Stay here.
You too.
Rico, I'm telling you, you can't ..
─ Keep your mouth shut.
You weren't hard to find, boy.
I didn't want to put you to any tröuble.
I figured you'd catch up with
me sooner or later anyway.
A couple of times today we could
have cooled you real good.
I wasn't worried.
I know you too well, Rico.
Some things you like
to handle personally.
You and Stewart had
quite a conversation.
How far did you go, boy?
All the way. Everything.
Why?
I'm asking you.
Why do you do a thing like this to Rico?
I'm a peculiar guy.
I don't like jails for anyone.
Especially me.
We'd have got you out.
We were working on getting you out.
─ How?
In a basket?
Here's what I want you to do.
I want you to go back to
that Stewart character.
And tell him you made a slight mistake.
You were anxious to
spring yourself, huh?
So all that talk you
gave him was .. just that.
Talk.
Rico, you're living in a dream world.
It's too late.
Maybe not.
Ask your lawyer. Tell him, Lou.
Whatever Rico says.
I think you'll do it.
Yeah .. I think you will.
From Rico to Tommy, huh?
Oh no.
Not for you.
As for you, boy.
Bring her here.
Take it off.
Sick, eh?
Sick in the belly.
It could have been, you know.
It can still be.
Like I say.
The face of an angel.
You can't do this, Rico.
─ Make me try.
Lou Forbes thinks maybe I can.
He doesn't know you like I do.
Listen, Rico.
Think back a long time, right in this
neighborhood, a few blocks from here.
You didn't know me then, but I knew you.
Everyone did.
"Rico Angelo". King of the kids.
We used to look up to your, Rico. You
were a big guy. And how did you make it?
By beating up on the
weak and the helpless?
Not Rico.
Rico went looking for the biggest
and toughest he could find.
And he cut them down to size with his
own two hands. That was Rico's way.
And it's still your way, Rico.
A man can't change that much.
That's why you won't do this.
I remember once, one of the kids.
One of the weak ones.
His old man gave him
a watch for graduation.
His old man was a drunk and a bum,
but he gave the kid a watch.
He was proud. He went showing it to the
gang: "Look my old man gave me a watch."
Next thing you know, some mug
took it away from him. A big guy.
Took it away. Kicked the kid.
Knocked him down.
Then Rico came along.
He worked that big guy over and good.
And when he was finished he handed
the kid his watch and he said:
"Go on home."
"On this block, no kid gets hurt."
You don't remember that, do you Rico.
Well, I do.
I was the kid.
Stop.
You've come a long way
from those days, Rico.
You got yourself out the gutter, out of
the filth and muck and stood at the top.
It wasn't luck. It wasn't an accident.
It took a big man.
This.
This is not the act of a big man.
This I'd expect from some of the lice
who feed from you, but not from Rico.
It's beneath the Rico I once knew.
Rico Angelo. King of the kids.
And you know something, Rico?
In your own peculiar
way you're still the King.
You going to listen to this?
Shut up you two-bit, greasy punk.
Don't ever open your filthy mouth
when I'm speaking. You understand that?
Listen, Rico. He's ..
Why, don't ever raise your hands
to me or I'll blow your head off!
Lay off. Let him talk!
Go on.
He's the kind of a punk you listen to.
That's why you're in a jam now.
Not on account of me.
I may be in a jam, but I'll get out.
Rico, I'll make a deal with you.
Put her back on that train
and I'll make a deal.
What kind of a deal?
You going to see Stewart?
And land back in the can? I can't help
you from there. I've got to be out.
I'll defend you, Rico.
How?
He can't. They won't let him in court.
Not in court, you poor slob.
I'll prepare your case.
I'll tell that monkey every
word to say and how to say it.
I'll take my own testimony
and rip it to shreds.
I can do it, Rico. You know I can do it.
Can he do it?
Tell me.
Rico.
[ Gunshots! ]
Big talk, huh?
Fancy words.
You got class, Tommy.
That's why I like you ..
Ahh!
One of our boys found it upstairs.
It had your initials on the back.
Did it really work again?
Keep it .. as a souvenir.
T-G