What do you think?
I don't like that
parts of it are purple.
They were grape popsicles.
It's tacky.
Who cares about that?
It's cool.
Color matters, Joe!
What do you think?
I think it's awesome.
I mean, I really like
where we put the game room.
Game room?
That's not a game room, Joe.
That's a spa.
Okay, for you and your wife,
it can be a spa.
But for me and my wife,
it's gonna be a game room.
Who's your wife?
Alyssa Milano.
Bette Midler.
Is that the lady
that lives on the corner?
Oh, my God.
You know nothing.
What do you think?
I think it's great.
It reminds me of that house where we
used to play Nintendo when we were kids.
Remember? Remember?
It was that... what was that kid's name?
It was like Tim something,
right? Tim something Irish.
Close.
Phillip Schlemenson.
That's it. That's this house.
I hated that house.
It was great.
I made out with Phillip's sister
in that house.
I made out with Phillip
Oh,
you never forget your first.
You just called him
"Tim something Irish."
Wasn't my first.
[ Imagine dragons'
"on top of the world" plays ]
♪ 'cause I'm on top
of the world, hey! ♪
♪ I'm on top of the world,
hey! ♪
♪ waiting on this
for a while now ♪
♪ been dreaming of this
since a child ♪
♪ I'm on top of the world
Sync & corrections by Rafael UPD
www.addic7ed.com/
♪
to think about our work
for a little while longer...
No. No, no, no, no.
No, no. That's your problem.
You think too much. Sometimes
you just got to go with your gut.
No. No. That's your problem.
You only go with your gut.
That's why you have a tattoo
of Clay aiken on your ass.
I'm telling you, my gut instinct
has served us very well.
We have a new business
because of it.
I found our secretary on
a subway platform because of it.
And it is the reason
why my boyfriend
is a gorgeous jewish doctor.
He's a nurse, Louis.
Wyatt is mennonite
and a nurse.
They're gonna promote him
to jewish doctor any day now.
I'm pretty sure
it doesn't work that way.
[ Chuckles ]
Agree to disagree.
Hey, Joe,
you got a phone call.
May I just say, rosanna,
that the way you're presenting
your bosom this morning
is sure to make Bernardo
the envy of every shark
at the rumble.
And may I just say,
joke, joke, joke, gay, gay, gay,
I will cut you.
It's your girlfriend
on line two.
All right, just tell her
I'll call her back.
Call her back?
What? We have...
We have work to do.
In the year that you and Ali
have been dating,
I have never seen you
not take her phone call.
Ah, it's nothing.
Meaning,
"ah, it's something."
Eh, it's no big deal.
Meaning,
"eh, it's a huge deal."
Oh, okay.
Okay, okay. Fine.
Fine. Uh...
I, uh, I think I have to
break up with her.
What? Oh, my God.
Why didn't you
bring this up sooner?
Because I didn't want my drama
to get in the way of our work.
Oh, my God. It's so funny. I always feel
like our work gets in the way of my drama.
Well, tell me...
What happened?
So, last night,
I picked her up after work.
She's been really stressed out lately
because the store is in trouble,
and she has a lot riding on some buyer
that's coming by to see her today.
If this story isn't about you
or me in the next 30 seconds,
I'm going to eat my fist.
[ Chuckles ]
No, no, don't.
Don't. Don't.
It's too easy.
Yeah.
Anyway, so, she had
a couple glasses of wine.
You mean four.
It was three.
It was four.
Girlfriend likes her liquor.
Then out of nowhere, she tells
me she wants to get married.
And she wants kids...
Like, now.
So there's this "play me
or trade me" ultimatum
on the table,
and I'm just...
I'm not ready for that.
Oh! I can't believe
what I'm hearing.
This is crazy.
You know how much I love Ali.
I mean, for God's sake,
I introduced the two of you.
No, you didn't.
Well, I had a lot to do
with you two getting together.
You had nothing to do with it. You
were out of the country when we met.
Well, I've told enough people
that I set you two up,
so when legend becomes fact,
print the legend.
It's just, you know,
it's just...
Hey, okay, okay, okay, okay.
What is your gut telling you?
My gut is telling me
that there's lots of reasons
that I should break...
Stop. That's what your head
is telling you.
What is your gut
telling you?
Ugh.
My gut is telling me
that she is the sexiest,
most beautiful woman...
Stop. That's what your Schmeckle
is telling you.
Aim for the middle now.
What is your gut telling you?
It's... it's telling me
that, you know... it's...
It's telling me that...
That's your answer,
Joe.
It's not saying,
"I-I-I-I-I-I have to marry her""
and if that's the case,
then you... you...
Oh, God, I can't believe
I'm saying this.
[ Sighs ]
You got to let her go.
It's not fair to her.
Mm. Oh, my God, Louis,
I think you're right.
My Schmeckle's gonna hate me
for this.
Hey.
I was literally
just calling you!
What are you doing here?
Uh, we need to talk.
Wait, wait.
I have the most amazing news.
Do you remember
that night we went out
and Louis had, like,
four vodkas on the rocks?
Oh, he had one.
Four.
Maybe two.
It was four.
Girlfriend likes
her liquor.
Anyway, I took an ice cube
out of his drink
and said, "this would make
a really cute ring," remember?
I just remember him yelling,
"it's flu season.
Stop fingering my mojito."
[ Laughs ]
Yeah. He did.
But I designed one,
and now
it's gonna be featured
in the largest jewelry catalogue
in New York.
Wow. Ali.
That is fantastic.
Raise the, uh, uh,
raise the roof.
[ Squeals ]
Louis, why did you tell juanita
at the dry cleaner's
that I'm a doctor?
Oh, yeah, that. Right.
Well, I mean, I-I, you know,
I just...
She needed a doctor's note
to get out of jury duty.
You don't... you don't
see anything wrong with that?
A woman who wears cosmic
radiance by Britney Spears
should not
serve on a jury.
That's not what
I'm talking about, Louis.
I mean, I'm not a doctor.
I'm a nurse.
Yeah, right. That.
Well, you know, I mean,
I just... I said "doctor"
because, you know, it's...
It's... it's easier to say.
Easier to say?
How is that easier to say?
Doctor. Doctor.
Nice, hard consonants.
Clicks right out.
As opposed to "urrrr."
You know,
that's a slow-motion word.
Elphaba, stare blankly
if you agree with me.
See?
Louis, are you embarrassed
that I'm a nurse?
[ Scoffs ]
Wyatt, my love, come on.
I find it upsetting that
you would even ask such a thing.
Of course I am!
How could you not
know that?
I just thought it was
part of your schtick.
Sweetheart,
I am my schtick.
I just feel like everything
is falling into place.
Well, look, I just wanted to
talk to you about last night.
Oh, I'm sorry about that.
It's just I was stressed out
about losing the store,
and then I started stressing out
about losing you, and...
Just forget
it ever happened.
Okay,
but you did say that...
No, no, no. No. No.
My life is so good
right now.
It's perfect.
I love you, Joe, and the last
thing that I would ever want
is for you to do anything
because you feel pressured
into it, so...
What did you want to say?
Oh, my God.
What are you doing?!
I'm going with my gut.
Ali landau,
will you marry me?
Really?
Yeah.
Yes!
Yes, I will marry you!
Oh, my God.
Mm.
Gosh, why would he do it?
What's better than Ali?
Well,
she wants to get married,
and she gave him a "play me
or trade me" ultimatum.
Wow.
A "play me or trade m""
ultimatum.
Yeah.
What is a "play me or trade me"
ultimatum?
I have no idea.
I was just going along because
I didn't want to seem gay.
Wyatt, my love,
you're a male nurse
who DVRs everything on bravo.
That ship has sailed.
Oh, God, I just realized
she's gonna be in my yoga class
tomorrow.
That'll be so awkward
for me.
Okay, let's come out of
child's pose into warrior I.
Did you talk to Joe
last night?
No.
Oh, well,
we were kind of busy.
I assume you know
what happened.
[ Sighs ] I do.
How you doing? You okay?
You seem okay.
Okay? I'm thrilled.
Oh, come on, baby girl.
It's me.
What?
You don't think I am?
Of course I'm thrilled.
And to tell you the truth,
a little relieved.
I got you.
We're doing survive and thrive.
Good for you,
you brave little toaster.
Down dog into plank
into upward dog.
Okay, what are you
talking about?
I just want to say for
the record it was not my idea.
I would hope not. I think
he was a fool to do what he did.
What? I could have told you
he wasn't ready to get married.
I tell everyone in my life,
"run everything past me first."
Even yoga-wear decisions...
Hint, hint.
What do you mean
he wasn't ready to get married?
He proposed.
What? What happened
to "play me or trade me"?
What is that
supposed to mean?
[ Elevator bell dings ]
Is he in?
Does he seem upset?
Oh, he's in a good mood.
He came in early, and he
just started working. Why?
What'd you do?
It's bad.
Do you need the girls?
Yes, please.
Thank you.
[ Clears throat ]
Hey. What you doing here?
I thought yoga goes till 9:00.
I wasn't feeling it.
Okay, well, I got news.
I got newer news.
No, just listen to me.
Go ahead.
So, I did what you said.
I went with my gut.
I mean, I was ready
to break up with her.
But then she looked at me,
and she told me she loved me,
and she just...
She took the pressure off.
And in that instant,
I knew...
Rosanna:
Joe, Ali's on line one.
We're working.
He'll call back.
No, I'm taking it.
What are you doing?
Well, we're working.
He'll call back.
No, I'll take it.
Don't be weird.
Hi, honey.
Yeah, he's right here.
Why?
He did what, now?
Well, well, yes, yes,
but... but I...
[ Stammers ]
Right.
No, I know that. I know that.
It was gonna be
a longer conver...
I think we should meet up.
Should we meet?
Or maybe...
I have no interest...
Okay, well,
I don't want any trouble.
You know what I mean?
Okay, bye.
[ Receiver clicks ]
What'd she say?
I'm going to kick
your aiken.
What were you thinking?
I was...
You know, it's funny.
No, you don't... don't
even answer that question!
That is a ridiculous question,
because you don't think!
You just vomit
whatever's in your head!
You're a mental bulimic!
Do you understand what you
just did today? Do you?
The engagement's off.
She doesn't trust me.
Oh, I can't believe I did this.
I-I'm a terrible person.
I hate myself!
You're not really gonna make
this about you, are you?
What have I done?
I just destroyed
my best friend's life!
You poor thing.
How can I help?
Maybe some tea.
That'd be nice.
Yeah? You want some lemon,
sugar?
Yeah, lemon's good.
Stevia if you got it.
I'm not getting you
a cup of tea, you schmuck!
Oh, God!
I can't do this
with you anymore, Louis.
Oh, come on.
Joe, we'll get through this.
No, this isn't cute.
This isn't like when you bought
me that parrot just for giggles.
I thought it would give you
an air of whimsy.
No. No, that... that's not
what it gave me.
You know what it gave me?
It gave me
a bathroom floor
that looks like
a Jackson pollock painting.
I'm sorry!
Oh, yeah, yeah.
That's what you said
when you totaled my dad's car...
With my mom's car!
Gays can't drive stick.
Ironic, right?
I wasn't thinking!
Yeah.
No, t-that's the problem.
You don't think.
You never think, and I
always end up getting hurt.
Oh, come on.
All of those things were silly.
Yeah, but this isn't silly.
This time you crossed a line.
And I'm done.
What are you saying?
I'm saying that...
The cost of being friends
with you
has now officially
outweighed the benefits.
I'm saying that
this partnership is...
This friendship is...
Is over.
No. No, no, no, no. Wait.
Joe, Joe, Joe, wait, wait, wait.
Think about this!
No, I'm going with my gut
on this one, too.
There you go.
Thank you.
You're Louis' boyfriend,
aren't you?
Yes, I am.
He talks about you
all the time.
My mother would be so happy
if I was dating a doctor.
[ Chuckles ]
Yes. So would Louis.
Oh, hey, Joe.
Oh, hey, Wyatt.
Why aren't you at work?
Uh, let's just say
I had to get out of the office.
Oh, hey, I heard
you broke up with Ali.
Gosh, that's terrible.
Actually, I proposed to Ali,
and she accepted.
Well, gosh,
that's wonderful.
Yeah. And then Louis
went and told her
that I was gonna break up
with her.
And now
the engagement's off.
Well, gosh,
that's terrible.
Are there gonna be
any more?
No.
No, that's where it ends.
All right, I guess
I'll see you around.
Huh?
Hey, Wyatt?
Yeah?
How do you do it?
Two hours in the gym
every morning.
The rest
is just good genes.
Oh, I can't believe
he sent you here.
He didn't. Oh, please.
Of course he did.
You two do everything
for each other.
You're a perfect couple.
In fact, why did I even think
about marrying Joe
in the first place?
What's the point?
He's already married to you.
Not anymore.
What are you talking about?
I really blew it this time,
Ali.
[ Sighs ]
Our friendship's over.
Give me a break.
This is the guy who called you,
giggling, from my bathroom
after we had sex
for the first time.
You were totally
out of our league.
We were so excited.
How do you deal with Louis?
I mean,
doesn't he drive you crazy?
Well, that's easy.
No one in the world
loves like Louis.
I mean, I question
a lot of his decisions,
but one thing I never question
is his heart.
And if you keep that
in mind,
you can forgive
all the other stuff.
Oh, speaking of hearts,
I got to get back to work.
I'm in the cardiac wing today.
That's why I got a heart on.
Wow.
[ Chuckles ]
I can give you one
if you want.
No,
I don't think you can.
Ali, listen.
We were 12 when Joe's parents
got divorced, okay?
And... and he was so sad
that he stopped going to school
for like a month.
And every day,
I would go over to his house,
and we would
do his homework,
and I would tell him
which girls were getting boobs.
And I'd make him a panini.
Because I had to make sure
that my best friend wasn't
gonna get held back a grade.
It's a very nice story,
but I'm not sure what it has to
do with... Ali, listen to me.
You've got to marry him
because I need to know
if I'm not gonna be around
to take care of him,
at least you will.
He was this close
to breaking up with me.
He's not ready to...
He's ready.
But he's not certain that...
He's certain.
Louis, I just think that if he doesn't...
Ali, you're the most wonderful person
that's ever
come into Joe's life.
You're hotter than he is.
You're smart.
You're a bad cook,
but with a little effort,
you could learn
to be a mediocre cook.
And what's more important than
all of that... you love Joe.
And he loves you
more than...
More than almost anything else
in the world.
What are you doing?
Ali landau...
Will you do me the honor
of marrying my best friend?
This is so inappropriate.
Just... just... just...
Just answer the question.
I'll think about it.
Thank you.
[ Sighs ]
Louis, what kind of
freaky 12-year-old
knows how to make
a panini?
[ Door opens ]
Oh, you're still here.
Thought you'd be gone.
Just came in to, uh...
Pack up a couple of boxes.
Sure.
[ Sighs ]
I'm really sorry
that I...
I'm just sorry.
Yeah, me too.
[ Cellphone rings ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Ringing continues ]
Oh, hey.
Yeah, he's right here.
Why?
He did what, now?
Well, that's all kinds
of inappropriate.
Oh, he did?
Oh.
You will?
You have no idea how happy
you're making me right now.
Well, I mean,
I don't know, you know.
He's such a pain in the ass,
you know?
All right, well, listen,
you're my fiancée now,
so, uh... if you want me
to forgive him, I, uh, I will.
I-I will forgive him.
I love you, too.
Yes. More than him.
Bye.
[ Chuckles ]
Who was that?
Wrong number.
So now that we're engaged,
whose apartment
are we going to move into,
and whose apartment
are we going to get rid of?
P.S.... It's yours, Ali.
Okay.
We are not engaged.
We are engaged.
Do we understand that?
We do not.
We have been waiting
to plan Joe's wedding
for our entire life,
and we are not going to
let you ruin it
with a barefoot-on-the-beach
theme.
I wasn't.
Weren't you?
I was.
Yes.
Guys, I'd like
to acknowledge something.
Two people who really love
each other came together today.
And it almost didn't happen,
but this relationship
is truly meant to be.
And I have no doubt
that it will last forever.
Aw. Thank you.
You drive-a me crazy.
Hey, come here!
You do!
I'm worth it!
I'm worth it.
With that hat
I hate.
Do we need to worry
about this?
I think we just
need to accept the fact
that there are four people
at this table but three couples.
Huh. I think
that's kind of nice.
Oh,
I still have my heart on.
It's not that nice.
[ Laughter ]
♪ I'm on top of the world
Sync & corrections by Rafael UPD
www.addic7ed.com/