(CHATTERING)
MAN: Ten-hut!
(SILENCE)
(BUGLE PLAYS)
Be seated.
(SHUFFLING)
Now, I want you to remember. . .
. . .that no bastard ever won a war. . .
. . .by dying for his country.
He won it. . .
. . .by making the other poor dumb
bastard die for his country.
Men. . .
. . .all this stuff you've heard
about America not wanting to fight. . .
. . .wanting to stay out of the war. . .
. . .is a lot of horse dung.
Americans. . .
. . .traditionally love to fight.
All real Americans love
the sting of battle.
When you were kids. . .
. . .you all admired
the champion marble shooter. . .
. . .the fastest runner, big-league
ball players, the toughest boxers.
Americans love a winner. . .
. . .and will not tolerate a loser.
Americans play to win all the time.
I wouldn't give a hoot in hell
for a man who lost and laughed.
That's why Americans have never lost
and will never lose a war. . .
. . .because the very thought
of losing. . .
. . .is hateful to Americans.
Now. . .
. . .an army is a team.
It lives, eats, sleeps,
fights as a team.
This individuality stuff
is a bunch of crap.
The bilious bastards who wrote
that stuff about individuality. . .
. . .for the Saturday Evening Post...
. . .don't know anything more about real
battle than they do about fornicating.
Now we have the finest food
and equipment. . .
. . .the best spirit. . .
. . .and the best men in the world.
You know. . .
. . .by God, I actually pity those poor
bastards we're going up against.
By God, I do.
We're not just going to shoot
the bastards. . .
. . .we're going to cut out
their living guts. . .
. . .and use them to grease
the treads of our tanks.
We're going to murder those lousy
Hun bastards by the bushel.
Now. . .
. . .some of you boys. . .
. . .I know are wondering. . .
. . .whether or not you'll chicken out
under fire. Don't worry about it.
I can assure you. . .
. . .that you will all do your duty.
The Nazis. . .
. . .are the enemy.
Wade into them!
Spill their blood!
Shoot them in the belly!
When you put your hand. . .
. . .into a bunch of goo. . .
. . .that a moment before was
your best friend's face. . .
. . .you'll know what to do.
There's another thing
I want you to remember.
I don't want to get any messages
saying we are "holding our position. "
We're not "holding" anything.
Let the Hun do that.
We're advancing constantly. We're not
interested in holding on to anything. . .
. . .except the enemy.
We're going to hold on to him
by the nose and kick him in the ass.
We're going to kick the hell
out of him all the time. . .
. . .and we're going to go through him
like crap through a goose!
Now. . .
. . .there's one thing. . .
. . .that you men will be able to say
when you get back home.
And you may thank God for it.
Thirty years from now when you're
sitting around your fireside. . .
. . .with your grandson on your knee. . .
. . .and he asks you:
"What did you do in the great
World War ll?"
You won't have to say:
"Well. . .
. . .I shovelled shit in Louisiana. "
All right, now, you sons of bitches. . .
. . .you know how I feel.
I will be proud. . .
. . .to lead you wonderful guys
into battle anytime. . .
. . .anywhere.
That's all.
(JEEPS RUMBLING)
(DOG BARKS)
The Arabs need food and clothing.
They strip our dead before
we can even bury them.
Looks like the reports were
pretty accurate.
Sixty-one armored vehicles,
45 tons of ammunition. . .
. . .twenty-five 40mm guns,
three self-propelled 105s.
Not counting mortars, machine guns,
rifles. . .
. . .pistols, telescopes, belt buckles,
Gl socks.
One thousand, eight hundred men.
(CHEERING)
(SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Our people salute you, general. . .
. . .for your brilliant amphibious
landing on the continent of Africa. . .
. . .and for your enlightened
administration of our country.
I've enjoyed being here, Excellency.
Naturally, I'd prefer to be in Tunisia
fighting the Germans.
(BAND PLAYS)
"The lions in their dens
tremble at his approach. "
I appreciate that, Excellency.
(BAND PLAYS)
Magnificent!
I wish our troops looked that good.
Tell me, general,
what do you think of Morocco?
I love it, Excellency.
It's a combination
of the Bible and Hollywood.
BRADLEY: These men fight at Kasserine?
CARVER: Yes, sir.
For the American Army to take
a licking like that. . .
. . .the first time at bat
against the Germans. . . .
Up against Rommel, what we need
is the best tank man we've got.
Somebody tough enough
to pull this outfit together.
-Patton?
-Possibly.
God help us.
(SIREN WAILS)
(SPEAKING IN ARABIC)
Lieutenant. . .
. . .where is the duty officer?
Sir. . . .
-He said he's caught at shaving.
-Why isn't he here on duty?
Guess he needed a shave.
We got a new commanding general
due today.
(CRASHING)
MAN: Who the hell is kicking me
in the butt?
Oh, sorry, sir.
-What were you doing down there?
-Trying to get some sleep, sir.
Well. . . .
Get back down there, son.
You're the only son of a bitch here
who knows what he's trying to do.
Yes, sir.
PATTON: Brad, how the hell are you?
-Fine, George. Good to see you.
We were all under the impression
you wouldn't be here until 0900.
Yes, I gathered that.
-You know my boy, Dick Jenson.
-Yes.
Brad, tell me.
-What are you doing here?
-Ike wanted a report on Kasserine.
Meanwhile, I have to stay here
as an observer. . .
. . .but I report directly to Ike.
You're spying.
Get me General Eisenhower's
headquarters.
Tell me, Brad. . .
. . .what happened at Kasserine?
I heard it was a shambles.
Apparently, everything went wrong.
We'd send over a 75mm shell,
the krauts would return an 88.
Their tanks are diesels.
Even when we managed to hit one
they kept on running. Our tanks. . . .
The men call them
"Purple Heart boxes. "
One hot piece of shrapnel
and the gasoline explodes.
I warned them about the tank.
I taIked to one of the
soldiers about the half-tracks.
I asked them if the machine-gun
bullets pierced the armor.
And he said, "No, sir.
They just come through one side
and rattle around a bit. "
I understand they had a little trouble
coordinating the air cover.
The trouble was no air cover.
-General Smith on the line, sir.
-Excuse me, Brad.
Bedell?
Listen, I'm calling about Bradley
and his job here.
I need a good number-two man, I want
to make Brad my deputy commander.
You clear it with Ike?
All right, thanks, Bedell.
Now you're not spying for Eisenhower
anymore, you're working for me.
-Okay?
-Fine, okay.
Dick. You got those stars?
-Yes, sir.
-Let's get them on.
What's the matter, Brad?
I've been nominated by the president.
I know, but it doesn't become official
until it's approved by the Senate.
Well. . .
. . .they have their schedule
and I have mine.
George. . .
. . .if you were named admiral
of the Turkish Navy. . .
. . .I believe your aides could dip
into their haversacks. . .
. . .and come up with the appropriate
badge of rank.
Anyway, congratulations.
Premature congratulations.
You know. . . .
I think those stars look better
on a green shirt.
Did I ever tell you about the time I
designed a uniform for tank crewmen?
It was green leather,
it had red stripes. . .
. . .and sort of a row of brass buttons
down across here.
And topped off
by a gold football helmet.
The Army rejected it, of course.
Goddamn, it was beautiful.
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
Lloyd Fredendall is just leaving.
George, there's one other thing I put
in my Kasserine report.
Some of our boys
were just plain scared.
That's understandable.
Even the best foxhound is gun-shy
the first time out.
I can remember. . .
. . .when nothing frightened me
as much as the idea of. . .
. . .a bullet coming
straight for my nose.
I don't know why, but the image of a
bullet coming right for my nose. . .
. . .was more horrible
than any other possibility.
Well, I can understand that,
with such a handsome nose.
You want to know why this outfit
got the hell kicked out of it?
Blind man could see it in a minute.
They don't look like soldiers.
They don't act like soldiers.
Why should they fight like soldiers?
You're absolutely right.
The discipline's pretty poor.
ln about 15 minutes we're going
to start turning these boys. . .
. . .into fanatics, razors.
They'll lose their fear
of the Germans.
I hope to God they never lose
their fear of me.
Up bright and early, general?
Breakfast?
Have all my officers
finished breakfast?
We're open from 6 till 8.
Most of the officers are
just coming in, sir.
Please inform these officers
the mess hall is closed.
But, sir! It's only a quarter to 8.
From now on, you will open at 6
and no one will be admitted after 6:15.
Where are your leggings?
Leggings? Well, hell, general, sir,
I'm a cook.
You're a soldier.
$20 fine.
Gentlemen. . .
. . .from this moment any man. . .
. . .without leggings, without a helmet,
without a tie. . . .
Any man with unshined shoes
or soiled uniform. . .
. . .is going to be skinned.
This is a barracks.
It's not a bordello.
(CHATTERING)
-Good morning.
-Good morning, sir.
Doctor.
Sir.
I understand you have two cases
of self-inflicted wounds.
Yes, sir, we do.
Get them out of here.
One has developed a serious infection.
I don't care if he dies,
just get him out of here.
Doesn't belong in the same room
with men wounded in battle.
-I'll see that they're moved.
-One more thing.
There'll be no "battle fatigue. "
That's an order.
Battle fatigue is a free ride
to the hospital.
I'm not going to subsidize cowardice.
Yes, sir.
Doctor. . . .
Where's your helmet?
I don't wear a helmet
in the hospital.
Start.
I can't use my stethoscope
when I'm wearing my helmet.
Well. . .
. . .then cut two holes in your helmet
so that you can.
And get those yellow-bellies
out of here, today.
Hold it.
Turn right, here.
The battlefield is ahead.
Don't argue.
I can smell a battlefield.
He was out here yesterday.
It's over there. Turn right, damn it.
It was here.
The battlefield was here.
The Carthaginians
defending the city. . .
. . .were attacked by three
Roman legions.
They were brave, but they
couldn't hold. They were massacred.
Arab women. . .
. . .stripped them of their tunics
and their swords and lances.
The soldiers lay naked in the sun. . .
. . .2000 years ago.
I was here.
You don't believe me.
You know what the poet said:
"Through the travail of ages
It's the pomp and toils of war
Have I fought and strove and perished
Countless times upon the star
As if through a glass and darkly
The age-old strife I see
Where I fought in many guises
Many names
But always me. "
You know who the poet was?
Me.
There's an opportunity
for us to mount an offensive.
We've concentrated on the flank. . .
. . .draw strength from the British.
It appears now that we could. . .
. . .split the African corridor.
Drive through Rommel to the sea.
I'm sorry, but that territory
has been reserved. . .
. . .for General Bernard Law Montgomery.
We're supposed to let him win this one
no matter what.
They're entitled to have their hero.
Montgomery did push Rommel
clear across North Africa.
What about the Americans?
Don't they need a hero too?
You have anybody in mind?
Air Vice-Marshal Coningham
is here with General Buford.
Excuse me, gentlemen. . .
. . .while I ask our British friends
what's happened to our air cover.
BRADLEY:
Harry.
How are you?
George. Good to see you.
-You know Arthur Coningham.
-Sir Arthur.
Delighted to see you.
I've heard so much about you.
Gentlemen, it appears there's been a
slight misunderstanding here. . .
. . .and Ike thought we should fix it.
No, no. No misunderstanding.
We're supposed to have Allied
air cover and we don't.
German planes are strafing my troops.
lf I may say so, general, I'm afraid
your operation reports are inaccurate.
Report? Three days ago, the crowds
took off after my command car. . .
. . .ran my ass into a ditch.
My staff has assured me,
we have complete air supremacy. . .
. . .everywhere in the Mediterranean.
PATTON:
When I complained about air cover. . .
. . .you said our troops
were not battleworthy.
You spoke of the discredited practice
of using air force as an alibi. . .
. . .for lack of success on the ground.
I have to wet-nurse Montgomery,
I don't have to stand for that.
I sincerely apologize for that remark,
whoever made it.
And I promise you one thing, general:
You will see no more German planes.
(CHICKEN SQUAWKS)
We were discussing air supremacy,
Sir Arthur.
(HORN HONKS)
(GUNFIRE)
Damn door won't open!
By God, that's enough!
Get that thing out of here!
Come on, you bastards,
take a shot at me on the nose!
Get back in here, George! We need
a corps commander, not a casualty.
CONINGHAM:
How'd you manage to stage that?
I don't know. . .
. . .but if I could find
the Nazis flying those things. . .
. . .I'd give them each a medal.
PATTON: Can't get over how cold
it gets in the desert.
Awfully cold, sir.
PATTON: Rommel's out there somewhere,
waiting for me.
JENSON:
Yes, sir.
PATTON:
You know. . .
. . .if I had my way, I'd send
that genius son of a bitch. . .
. . .an engraved invitation
in iambic pentameter:
A challenge in two stanzas
to meet me alone in the desert.
I'll deliver it.
Rommel in his tank and me in mine.
We'd stop about 20 paces.
We'd get out, we'd shake hands. . .
. . .then we'd button up and do battle,
just the two of us.
That battle would decide
the outcome of the war.
It's too bad jousting's
gone out of style.
It's like your poetry, general.
It isn't part of the 20th century.
You're right, Dick.
The world grew up.
Hell of a shame.
Dick, I want a 24-hour guard
put around this area.
lf we don't, the Arabs will dig
them up for their clothes.
Yes, sir.
Our graves aren't gonna disappear
like everybody else's who fought here.
The Greeks, Romans, Carthaginians.
God, how I hate the 20th century.
General.
General?
We intercepted a German radio message.
Rommel's 10th Panzer is going
to hit us near El Guettar.
Rommel, huh?
(BRAYS)
All my life. . .
. . .I've wanted to lead a lot of men
in a desperate battle.
Now I'm going to do it.
Look.
Battalion strength at least.
They haven't spotted our positions yet.
They'll get an education
in about 10 seconds.
Wait till they get a dose of
that artillery fire.
Commence firing.
Fire at will.
Commence firing. Fire at will.
What a hell of a waste
of fine infantry.
-Get General Bradley on the radio.
-Yes, sir.
Sir, I can't raise him.
Go tell him to hit them hard. Here's
where we hold them by the nose. . .
. . .and kick them in the ass.
Go on.
Put him in my car.
(PLANE WHINES)
Rommel. . .
. . .you magnificent bastard.
I read your book!
PATTON: Captain Richard N. Jenson
was a fine boy.
Loyal, unselfish and efficient.
I am terribly sorry.
There are no coffins here
since there is no wood.
We will have a trumpeter
and an honor guard...
...but we will not fire the volleys as
people would think an air raid was on.
I enclosed a lock of Dick's hair
in a letter to his mother.
He was a fine man...
...and a fine officer.
And he had no vices.
I shall miss him a lot.
I can 't see the reason
such fine young men get killed.
There are so many battles
yet to fight.
NARRATOR: Battle-weary, but
victorious, American Gls and Tommies...
...of the British 8th Army meet in
an Allied victory celebration...
...at Wadi Akarit in North Africa.
For the first time in this war,
Broadway and Piccadillyjoin hands.
Meanwhile, General Montgomery,
hero of El Alamein...
...continues to lead his
victorious British 8th Army...
...in a relentless drive against
Rommel's vaunted Africa corps.
(SPEAKS IN GERMAN)
General Bradley's done
a tremendous job with 2nd Corps.
He's moved into Bizerte
and taken over 41,000 prisoners.
Good. Very good.
You're not surprised, are you?
After all, you trained that outfit.
-Excuse me, general.
-Hm?
This is interesting. We've discovered
Rommel wasn't present at El Guettar.
-Who says so?
-G2, sir.
When we took 10th Panzer,
Rommel was in Berlin with an earache?
Severe nasal diphtheria, sir.
Also, Hitler probably
retained Rommel in Berlin. . .
. . .because things were going badly
for the Africa Corps.
He didn't want his favorite general
to lose face.
I'm my favorite general,
and I don't like to be told. . .
. . .that some second-stringer
is up against me. Then I lose face.
Who the hell are you, anyway?
CARVER: General, this is Lieutenant
Colonel Codman. Your new aide.
Codman. I pulled your name off
the list because I know your family.
I'm glad you did, sir.
Rommel is the best the krauts have,
and I kicked the hell out of him.
Now my own G2 section is telling
me he wasn't even there.
But, general, he undoubtedly
planned the German battle.
lf you defeat Rommel's plan, you've
defeated Rommel. lsn't that true?
Codman. . . .
-Have a drink with me tonight.
-Yes, sir.
I have a plan
for the invasion of Sicily.
I want to make sure I get it approved.
You can help me.
I want to give a dinner
for General Alexander.
Get to him before Montgomery does.
This will be strictly a formal affair,
Codman, but purely social.
By that I mean. . .
-. . .purely political.
-Yes, sir.
I want the finest food, the best wine
available. Everything, comme il faut.
(SPEAKS lN FRENCH)
(SPEAKING IN FRENCH)
(SPEAKS IN FRENCH)
Thank you.
George, this is really splendid wine.
Thank you, Arthur.
Thank you.
Sir Harold, I think it was Alcibiades
in the Peloponnesian War. . .
. . .415 B.C.
He said, "lf Syracuse falls, all
Sicily falls, and then ltaly. "
He knew that Syracuse was the
jugular of the island.
Old Alcibiades always went
for the throat.
I propose to take Sicily
in the same way.
-How's it going?
-The old man has them in his pocket.
PATTON:
Now, according to my plan. . .
. . .General Montgomery will land here.
I'll hit the beaches here,
take Palermo.
Monty will drive north on the coast,
I'll come due east. . .
. . .take Messina and cut off
the German escape route.
Yes. . . .
It looks like an interesting plan.
Well, gentlemen,
to the conquest of Sicily.
ALEXANDER:
To the conquest of Sicily.
OFFICERS:
To Sicily!
George, you'd have made a great
marshal for Napoleon. . .
. . .if you'd lived in the 18th century.
But I did, sir. I did.
Morning. Is General Smith in?
MAN: I believe he's in the lavatory.
-Thank you.
-Ah, there you are, Bedell.
-Monty.
Bedell, I've been giving a good bit of
thought to the Sicily operation.
Yes?
I assume we're alone.
Georgie Patton has already
discussed his plan with Alexander.
I realize that. . .
. . .but I have an idea that his plan
may lead to an absolute disaster.
Oh?
Bedell, look.
This is Sicily.
Now then, according to Patton's plan. . .
. . .I will attack Syracuse here.
And he would attack Palermo up here.
Now, obviously our forces would be
divided.
And obviously, they
could be chopped up piecemeal.
Now then, what I propose, and what
I shall insist on, by the way. . .
. . .is this.
(MONTGOMERY EXHALES)
I will land at Syracuse as planned.
But the Americans--
The Americans will land here, at Gela.
I will advance north to Messina,
the Americans protecting my flank.
After all, Messina is the key.
It's the reason for invading Sicily.
I'll discuss your plan with Ike.
I'm sure he'll give it
serious consideration.
-Amusing, isn't it?
-What?
That the plans for the
invasion of Sicily. . .
. . .should have been put forward
in an Algerian lavatory.
George, I have bad news for you
about your Sicily plan.
Ike has turned it down.
Since the Italians will be defending
their native soil for the first time. . .
. . .and the German resistance is
stiffening, we shouldn't be divided.
-Well, where do my people land then?
-In the Gulf of Gela.
There's nothing there
but a beach.
Yes, but it puts you in a good
position to support Montgomery.
Where does Montgomery land?
He'll land in Syracuse and drive north
to Catania. Possibly even Messina.
And you'll be alongside,
protecting his left.
I see.
ln other words, we get the burden again
while good old Monty gets the glory.
Ike had to consider all points of view.
He made his decision not as an
American, but as an Ally.
Had it been the other way around,
I assure you, Monty would protest.
No. . .
. . .I've been in the Army 30 years.
When I get an order, I say, "Yes, sir. "
And I do my best to carry it out.
This is what happens when your
commander stops being an American. . .
. . .and starts being an Ally.
I don't think I've made
myself clear, sir.
It's true, Montgomery met the
toughest resistance there at Catania.
However, if we're--
Perfectly clear.
Old Monty is as stuck
as a bug on flypaper.
But this order from
General Alexander. . .
. . .directing you to turn over the
Vizzini-Caltagirone road to Montgomery.
Well, then, old Bradley will have to
slug-- slug, mind you. . .
. . .his way up center of the island over
those tough mountain roads, won't he?
Yes, sir.
Messina, Bell.
Messina. . .
. . .is the heart of it. lf they'd
followed my plan, I'd be there by now.
I'd cut off the retreat of every
German on this island!
Now, you know what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna go to Palermo.
I'm gonna beat that limey at Messina
if it's the last thing I ever do!
Hey, what's all this talk about taking
the Vizzini road away from 2nd Corps?
General Alexander's orders.
Road goes to Montgomery.
Now, that road was assigned to me.
How can I get north without it?
You know the terrain there.
I'm sorry, Brad. But Monty's run
into tough opposition. Very tough.
You wouldn't be taking advantage of
this situation, would you?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Without that road, your army,
except for my 2nd Corps. . .
. . .would be out of a job.
Free for you to go into Palermo.
Who said anything about Palermo?
I can read a map.
Does Alexander know
you've pushed out this far?
That's a reconnaissance in force.
George. . .
. . .are you saying I've got to slug
it out in those mountains. . .
. . .with heavy resistance?
Just so you can make
a bigger splash than Monty?
General. . .
. . .I just follow my orders.
Like the simple old soldier I am.
General Bradley.
Sir, General Alexander has heard
we're moving west.
He says here, "Stop immediately.
Go no farther than Agrigento.
Repeat. Stop, immediately. "
That's what you think it says.
I think it was garbled
in transmission.
Ask them to re-transmit the message.
That'll take half a day at least.
Yes, sir.
Now, Brad.
Where were we?
We were talking about a simple. . .
. . .old soldier.
Look at that, gentlemen.
Compared to war. . .
. . .all other forms of human endeavor
shrink to insignificance.
Let's go, sergeant.
Move out!
Give me that helmet.
Come on, let's get out of here!
What silly son of a bitch
is in charge of this operation?
I don't know, but they
ought to hang him.
PATTON:
Afternoon, Padre.
PADRE: These men are here from the
States, looking over our program. . .
. . .for the spiritual welfare
of the men.
We'll take you right into Palermo.
Col. David toured us around
your quarters. . .
. . .and I saw a Bible by your bed.
Do you actually find time to read it?
I sure do.
Every goddamn day.
Sir, Patton's taken Palermo!
Damn!
(CHEERING)
(BAND PLAYS)
Palermo's the most conquered city
in history.
First the Phoenicians. . .
. . .the Romans,
Carthaginians, Byzantines.
Then came the Arabs. . .
. . .Spaniards, Neapolitans.
Now comes. . .
. . .the American Army.
This is from General Alexander, sir. . .
. . .reminding you that you are
not to take Palermo.
Send him a message, Cod.
Ask him if he
wants me to give it back.
PATTON: Let me ask you a question
for a change.
You've just come from Washington.
How do they feel about our boys
taking Palermo?
The general impression is, your army
barreled through token resistance. . .
. . .while Montgomery faced the brunt
of the fighting.
Don't they know we took on
the Hermann Göring division?
Toughest outfit in the German Army.
The people at home
are interested in you.
They're curious about your
pearl-handle revolvers.
They're ivory. Only a pimp
from a New Orleans whorehouse. . .
. . .would carry a pearl handle.
What about your language?
When I want it to stick,
I give it to them loud and dirty.
What do your troops feel about that?
I don't want these men to love me.
I want them to fight for me.
Ernie Pyle says you have a secret
weapon here: General Bradley.
Ernie calls him "The GI General. "
Omar Bradley is no secret.
He's a damn fine commander.
MAN:
What's your feeling about Montgomery?
PATTON:
He's the best general the English have.
He seems more concerned with not
losing than he does about winning.
He's not aggressive enough,
is that correct?
Look, I've been getting into
a lot of trouble lately.
Yesterday, the office told me
that my Italian prisoners. . .
. . .didn't have enough latrine.
They didn't know what a
latrine was till I showed them.
lf I've said anything too critical
of my British colleague. . .
. . .let's forget about it.
I will tell you one thing, though.
Off the record.
I'm gonna beat that. . .
. . .gentleman to Messina.
Ah, Freddie. Do you realize what
this madman Patton is saying?
He's going to save our skins
by taking Messina.
This report might interest you.
Here I am in these bloody marshes,
fighting malaria and Germans. . .
. . .while he's taking Palermo
and getting all the glory.
Well!
Now he's up against three good
German divisions and he's stuck.
He's not going to get Messina.
That's reserved for the
British 8th Army and me.
(BOMBS EXPLODING)
It's time for a move, Lucian. Terry
Allen's 1st Division is bogged down.
You're bogged down too.
What we need is another end run
just to break things loose.
-Lucian. How's my fighter?
-Fine, George.
Come in, come in. We need another
one of your amphibious specialties.
Lucian, I want you to send a
reinforced battalion by sea. . .
. . .to make a landing up here at Brolo
behind the kraut lines.
You want me to do a land-based attack.
Right. I want a coordinated
attack the morning of the 11th.
I don't think we can make it
by the 11th.
-Hell, it's only 15, 20 miles.
-My boys have been dying for yards.
Hm.
Maybe you better kick a few butts
if you have to.
I recommended you for your DSM
in your last promotion.
I know what you can do when
you put your mind to it.
Excuse me, sir.
I'm sorry, but I can't
do the impossible.
You're too old an athlete to think
you can postpone a scheduled match.
You're an old athlete yourself.
You know matches are postponed.
lf we can't back Lucian up by land,
our end run could be a disaster.
Those men might get caught
on the beach and cut to pieces.
-What's the matter?
BRADLEY: All we're saying is. . .
. . .not to rush in until we're ready.
Give him an extra day.
Just one more day.
The landing is on.
We're going to Messina.
We're going to get there before
Montgomery does.
-What's so important about that?
-General Truscott. . .
. . .if your conscience won't permit
you to conduct this operation. . .
. . .I'll find somebody who can.
General, it's your privilege to
relieve me anytime you want to.
This match will not be postponed.
Any questions?
No, sir.
You're a very good man, Lucian.
You want to guard against
being too conservative.
Remember what
Frederick the Great said:
''L 'audace, I'audace!
Toujours I'audace!''
Go on, have a drink.
Excuse me, sir, I won't be drinking
for the next couple of days.
lf anything happens to those men,
I'd like to be there with them.
You're not going, so forget about it.
You believe Truscott's right?
No.
But you're gambling
with those boys' lives. . .
. . .just to beat Montgomery
into Messina.
lf you pull it off, you're a hero,
but if you don't. . . .
What happens to them?
The ordinary combat soldier.
He doesn't share in your dreams
of glory, he's stuck here.
He's living out every day, day-to-day,
with death tugging at his elbow.
There's one big difference
between you and me, George.
I do this job because I've been
trained to do it.
You do it because. . .
. . .you love it.
The men on the beach are
catching hell, general.
The men are doing their best.
We have no replacements.
I can't break through to the coast.
I'm going down there myself.
PATTON:
Colonel!
How did he get over there?
PATTON:
What the hell are you waiting for?
Looking for a place to ford, general.
I sent a patrol to reconnoiter.
PATTON: I've done that. Down there
this sewer's no more than 3 feet deep.
Get that outfit cranked up
or you'll be out of a job!
-And put that helmet on.
-Yes, sir.
Move it! Let's go!
-What's holding up this column?
-I don't know, sir.
Planes!
Come on, move it!
Pull up over there.
-Come on.
-What's going on here?
Sir, these mules--
Jackasses!
You let a column get stalled and
strafed on account of two jackasses?!
(GUNSHOT)
No. No.
Now, dump them over the side
and clear this bridge!
We're pinned down because
we can't get air support!
Nobody's getting any air support!
Put fire into this battalion,
or I'll get somebody who can.
Major!
-You the executive officer here?
-Yes, sir.
-Your name?
-WaIker.
You're now commanding officer.
You've got 4 hours to break through
that beachhead.
lf you don't make it, I'll fire you.
50,000 men on this island would
like to shoot that son of a bitch.
Please take me home.
Take me home.
-There he goes, "Old Blood and Guts. "
-Yeah, our blood. His guts.
Hi, how are you, son?
Where are you from, Gomez?
California, sir.
Me too.
-Where were you hit?
-In the chest, sir.
Well. . .
. . .this might be interesting to you.
The last German I saw had no chest.
Didn't have any head either.
You get well quickly, son.
What's the matter with you?
I guess I just can't take it, sir.
What did you say?
It's my nerves, sir.
I just can't stand
the shelling anymore.
Your nerves?
Hell, you're just a goddamn coward.
Shut up!
I won't have
a yellow bastard crying. . .
. . .in front of these
brave, wounded men.
Shut up!
Don't admit this yellow bastard.
Nothing wrong with him.
I won't have sons of bitches afraid to
fight stink up this place of honor.
You're going back to the front,
my friend.
You may get shot, you may get killed,
but you're going up to the fighting.
Either that or I'll stand you up
in front of a firing squad.
I should shoot you myself,
you bastard! Get him out of here!
Send him up to the front!
You hear me? You goddamn coward!
I won't have cowards in my army.
I had to kick a few butts. . .
. . .but Truscott finally broke through
to those people on the beach.
Have you seen the casualty lists?
Yes, I've seen them.
What's the word from the coast road?
The 3rd Division's east of Brolo,
heading toward Messina.
Let's get over there.
I want to go in with the troops.
You go ahead, George.
I'm not very good at that.
General Bradley. . .
. . .it's time to consider how many
casualties we'd have. . .
. . .if we were still crawling on
that goddamn road.
Forward, march!
Don't smirk, Patton.
I shan't kiss you.
Pity. I shaved close this morning
to prepare for getting smacked by you.
Forward, march!
You wanted to see me, George?
Got a letter here from Ike.
I was rereading Caesar's
Commentaries last night.
In battle, Caesar wore a red robe to
distinguish him from his men.
I was struck by that fact because--
"Despicable. " First time anybody's
ever applied that word to me.
Well, at least it's a personal
reprimand, it's not official.
The man was yellow. He should've
been tried for cowardice and shot.
People have taken a lot worse
than a little kick in the pants.
I ruffled his pride a bit.
What's that compared to war?
Two weeks ago at Palermo they said
I was the greatest general. . .
-. . .since Stonewall Jackson.
-Now they draw cartoons about you.
Dirty bastard!
They got me holding a little Gl
and kicking him with an iron boot.
You see that, what's on my boot?
A swastika.
On my boot.
An iron boot with a swastika!
"You will apologize to the soldier
you slapped. . .
. . .to all doctors and nurses present
in the tent at the time. . .
. . .to every patient in the tent
who can be reached. . .
. . .and last but not least
to the 7th Army as a whole. . .
. . .through individual units,
one at a time. "
God, I. . .
. . .feel low.
PATTON:
Oh, God...
... Thou art my God.
Early will I seek Thee.
My soul thirsteth for Thee.
My flesh longeth for Thee
in a dry and thirsty land.
So as I have seen Thee
in the sanctuary.
My soul followeth hard after Thee.
But those that seek my soul
to destroy it...
...shall go into the lower parts
of the earth.
They shall fall by the sword.
They shall be apportioned for foxes.
But the king shall rejoice in God.
Everyone that sweareth by him
shall glory.
But the mouth of them
that speak lies...
...shall be stopped.
Ten-hut!
PATTON:
At ease.
I thought I'd stand up here
and let you people see. . .
. . .if I am as big a son of a bitch
as some of you think I am.
I assure you I had no intention. . .
. . .of being either harsh or cruel
in my treatment of the. . .
. . .soldier in question.
My sole purpose was to try
to restore in him. . .
. . .some appreciation of his
obligations as a man. . .
. . .and as a soldier.
lf one can shame a coward. . .
. . .I felt one might help him
to regain his self-respect.
This was on my mind.
Now, I freely admit. . .
. . .that my method was wrong. . .
. . .but I hope you understand
my motive. . .
. . .and will accept this. . .
. . .explanation. . .
. . .and this. . .
. . .apology.
-Dismissed.
-Ten-hut!
Good evening, general. I want to
report on a private poll I'm taking.
What poll?
The fan mail.
Eleven percent con,
89 percent pro.
And that 11% of protest, in most
cases, is both obscene and anonymous.
But the pro letters are mostly from
relatives and servicemen.
"I want you to know we're proud
our son is serving in your army.
From the newspaper, we're not clear
exactly what you did and why. . .
. . .but we want you to know
we're for you.
Keep going, and God bless you. "
Keep going, huh?
Where?
I thought you might like a sip
of wine, general. It's New Year's.
You didn't celebrate at all
last night.
I'm sick of sitting around this. . .
. . .royal doghouse.
We've taken Sicily.
I'm ready for a new assignment.
Maybe you've got it.
Here's a radio message, just came in.
Cod.
I've been relieved.
They've relieved me from command
of the 7th Army.
I don't believe it.
Happy New Year.
Just a minute, sir.
Since they're sure to give you
another command. . .
. . .isn't it logical they'd
relieve you here first?
You mean command of all American
troops going into Europe?
It's possible. I know it's been
discussed from time to time.
The logic of it is so obvious,
it couldn't mean anything else.
Sir, I'm going to open
this bottle of wine.
No, Sir Cod. . .
. . .but if you find a bottle of cognac,
I'll help you drink it.
-How you feeling tonight, general?
-Not bad, not bad at all.
-Get me some writing paper, will you?
-Yes, sir.
Your wife ever give you the devil
for not writing?
All the time, sir.
Only I don't write as often as you
do. Don't seem to get around to it.
Lucky for us we got them.
Who wants to marry a couple of
broken-down old horse captains?
That's what my wife says to me
every time I come home, sir.
Why are you up so late, George?
Thought you'd like a nice hot bath
or something.
I got this sleeping pill from the doc,
just in case you need it.
Sleeping pill!
-What's going on here?
-I heard the news, sir.
-They announced it on the radio.
-What news?
About General Bradley, sir. How they
gave him the top American command.
Oh.
Oh, yeah.
I just thought you might be
feeling kind of low, sir.
Your writing things, sir.
Here on the desk, sir.
Yeah. Thank you, George.
One little dog face.
One measly little slap.
That's what done it.
Ah, George.
I wish I'd kissed the son of a bitch.
(CLAPPING)
(PATTON SPEAKS IN FRENCH)
He's paying tribute to the Free French
Forces under DeGaulle and Leclerc.
(SPEAKS IN FRENCH)
And to the people of the Resistance. . .
. . .who risk their lives
to help destroy the Germans.
"France will be free again.
I give you my word. "
"Just as Free French troops liberated
Corsica, Napoleon's place of birth. . .
. . .I will someday land in France to
liberate the birthplace of Lafayette. "
General, the reporters would like
a word with you.
-Good afternoon.
-General.
Can you tell us the purpose
of this visit to Corsica?
General Eisenhower ordered me here.
You wrote the mother of the boy you
slapped, "The rat should've been shot. "
-Is that true, general?
-No comment.
Sir, I understand
Gen. Alexander suggested. . .
. . .you take over Gen. Clark's
Italian campaign. . .
. . .but it was killed
due to the incident.
-No comment.
-Can you say where you're going, sir?
Off the record,
Eisenhower's ordered me to Malta.
Interview concluded.
You plan on slapping
any soldiers there, general?
PATTON: In 1528, these forts
were defended by. . .
. . .400 Knights of Malta
and 800 mercenaries. . .
. . .against a force of 40,000 Turks.
Codman.
-Still no word from Gen. Eisenhower?
-No, sir.
Not even a response about
the two turkeys I sent for Christmas?
No, sir.
Go ahead, gentlemen.
Take a closer look for yourselves.
Looks like you boys have hitched
your wagon to a falling star.
Pass the word.
If anyone wants out, I'll understand.
Sir, I can speak for the entire staff.
We want to stay with you, no matter
what duty you're assigned to.
Up in London, they're planning
the invasion of Europe.
I've trained my mind,
body and spirit for that.
What, in God's name, am I doing here?
All right.
Let's get on to Cairo.
See if the pyramids
are still standing.
-This place is for me?
-Yes, sir. This way, sir.
Whoever found it has a genius
for cloak and dagger.
Who picked this cathouse?
I think it was Gen. Smith, sir.
To spite me, that son of a bitch.
-Welcome to London, Georgie.
-Bedell. How are you?
-Is Ike here?
-He asked me to brief you.
Would you excuse us, please?
Let me put you straight about Ike.
We hear a lot about you
criticizing his decisions.
Not really. You know me.
I'm just an old fool.
At times, I do wonder whether
he isn't a limey at heart.
George, this is the toughest coalition
ever attempted in history.
Ike's trying to hold it together
and lick the Germans at the same time.
-It's a hell of a job.
-I understand.
You have an important assignment
connected to the Normandy invasion.
Good. I've studied the Overlord Plan
and there's a number of flaws in it.
You can't depend on Monty taking
Cannes by D-day. He'll never make it.
I've drawn up an alternate plan
to land at Calais. . .
-. . .following an air bombardment--
-Will you just listen for a change?
Ike stood by you when everyone,
I mean everyone. . .
. . .wanted Patton
with a rope around his neck.
We're gonna let it leak out
that you are here undercover.
That you're preparing to invade
at the Pas de Calais.
We hope to pin down
the German 15th Army there. . .
. . .so that they can't be used
against us at Normandy.
Is that all I'm good for?
We're going to build an army
of 12 divisions around you.
All fictitious, of course.
Dummy troop concentrations,
dummy landing craft. . .
. . .simulated radio traffic.
The Germans are convinced that you
will lead the main invasion effort.
Their agents will spot you soon. . .
. . .then we can move you to Knutsford.
-What do I do there?
-Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
Frankly, George, you're on probation.
Take my advice and behave yourself.
Remember. . .
. . .your worst enemy
is your own big mouth.
(BAND PLAYS)
Look at this nasty-faced
son of a bitch. Ready for combat.
I'll call him William
as in "the Conqueror. "
-Sir, should we leave him in the car?
-No. Good afternoon, ladies.
Good afternoon.
(WlLLlE BARKS)
Watch this, Cod.
-Sir, he'll kill that dog.
-I'll hold him.
I'm terribly sorry, general.
Did Abigail frighten your dog?
That's quite all right, madam.
This way, sir.
Your name isn't William.
It's Willie.
WOMAN:
My dear friends.
General George S. Patton, Jr.,
has accepted our invitation. . .
. . .to say a few words to you. . .
. . .on the occasion
of this inaugural ceremony.
General Patton is not here
in an official capacity. . .
. . .and I have assured him
most earnestly. . .
. . .that nothing he says
will be quoted.
May I present General Patton.
-Remember, sir, watch your language.
-Yeah.
My dear ladies.
Until today. . .
. . .my only experience
at welcoming has been. . .
. . .to welcome Germans and Italians
to the infernal region.
At this I have been
quite successful. . .
. . .since the troops, which I have had
the honor to command. . .
. . .have, to date, killed or captured. . .
. . .some 170,000 of our enemies.
I feel that such clubs as these
are of very real value. . .
. . .because I believe
with Mr. Bernard Shaw. . .
. . .that the British and the Americans
are two peoples. . .
. . .separated by a common language.
Since it is the destiny of the British
and Americans to rule the world. . .
. . .the better we know each other. . .
. . .the better we will do it.
The Russians,
don't forget the Russians.
I think that a club like this. . .
. . .is an ideal place
for promoting mutual understanding.
Because as soon as our soldiers meet
and get to know the English ladies. . .
. . .and write home and tell our women
just how lovely you truly are. . .
. . .then the sooner the American ladies
will get jealous. . .
. . .and force this war
to a quick termination.
And then I'll get the chance to go
to the Pacific and kill Japanese.
NARRATOR:
All over the nation...
...mass meetings are held to protest
General Patton 's statement...
... that Britain and America
will rule the post war world.
That Russia will have no say.
Congressional leaders like Senator
Clayburn Foss are quick to react.
This man has insulted
our Russian allies...
...implying Anglo-American world rule.
In my opinion, he should be
severely disciplined.
This time I didn't do a damn thing.
They promised there
wouldn't be any reporters.
I made a few remarks off the record.
Ike told you to keep your mouth shut.
You know how suspicious the Russians
are of the British and us.
I was only trying to be polite
to the old ladies.
lf I'd seen the Russians there, I'd
have mentioned the sons of bitches.
Bedell, I don't know
anything about politics.
I have no political ambitions.
All I want to do is
to command an army in combat.
Well, it's out of our hands now.
Ike sent a message last night
to the chief of staff.
Now it's up to General Marshall
whether you stay here as a decoy. . .
. . .or he sends you home.
He's a good man.
At least he's a fair man.
I'll let it sit with him.
PATTON:
George. . .
. . .our war is over.
Over, sir?
It's just a question of waiting
for the orders now.
I feel I'm. . . .
I'm destined to achieve some
great thing. What, I don't know.
But this last incident is. . .
. . .so trivial in its nature
and so terrible in its effect--
It can't be an accident.
It has to be the work of God.
Yes, sir.
The last great opportunity
of a lifetime. . .
. . .an entire world at war
and I'm left out of it?
No, sir.
God will not permit this to happen!
I am going to be allowed
to fulfil my destiny!
His will be done.
NARRATOR: In the greatest amphibious
operation ever attempted...
...a predawn naval bombardment
prepares the way...
...for allied soldiers to assault
the Normandy beaches...
...and claw out a desperate foothold
on the continent of Europe.
I knew Montgomery couldn't take Caen
on D-day or D-plus-10. And I said so.
And here they are all hung up
in the hedgerow country.
They should pivot the way von
Schlieffen planned it in World War I.
Then we might get a chance to do
some real broken field running.
But they don't listen to me.
What a way to enter
the continent of Europe.
Along with all the rest
of the spare parts.
Sir, everything on this plane
is high priority.
Gen. Bradley wouldn't send for you
unless he had something in mind.
I'll tell you, Cod.
I've learned my lesson.
lf I ever do get another chance,
I'm gonna keep my mouth shut.
I'm gonna play the game.
lf I forget, you remind me.
-I'll give a gentle nudge in the ribs.
-Give me a swift kick in the ass.
Yes, sir.
Welcome to France, sir.
Hope the war's still on.
Where's the boss?
Right this way, sir.
Patton, haven't seen you
since Messina.
How are you?
You're doing a splendid job
decoying the Jerries.
You'll forgive me,
I'm off to the front.
Best of everything, old boy.
By the way. . .
. . .intelligence confirms
that I'm against Rommel again.
Rommel.
Hi, how are you, George?
-Pretty fair, Brad. How are you?
-Fine.
Well. My, my.
Isn't this plush?
Looks like you're
bucking for archbishop.
Chet Hansen had this rig built for me.
George, sit down.
Ike wanted me to talk to you
since we can level with each other.
That's right.
We're making 3rd Army operational
when I take over 12th Army group.
Do I get it?
I'll be honest with you.
I've had reservations.
You've been my senior ever since
I left the academy.
You were the boss in North Africa
and Sicily and I just thought. . .
. . .well, it might be a problem for us.
It wouldn't bother me.
There's one other thing.
We're different kinds of people.
Goddamn it, Brad, you're always right.
With your brains and my screwy ideas,
we make a great team, like in Sicily.
Truthfully, if I had been your senior
in Sicily, I would have relieved you.
Brad. . .
. . .I'm not crawling on my belly
to get a command.
For God's sake, get me in this fight.
The only way out of the doghouse
is to do something great.
I gotta get back in the war!
Hitler's own people tried
to kill him a few days ago.
First thing you know,
it'll be over and. . . .
I'll. . .
. . .keep my mouth shut.
I'll behave myself.
I give you my word.
George. . .
. . .I've been working
on a plan called Cobra.
I'd like your opinion.
We've been slugging through
hedgerow country. . .
. . .half an acre a day
and we've got to find a way out.
I want to use this road.
The Saint Lô-Periers road.
Monty will pin down
the enemy forces at Caen.
We'll pulverize an area
3 1/2 miles wide with bombing.
Then seven divisions will follow.
The 3rd Army will swing around here, a
sweeping end run right across France.
What do you think?
I think you'll need a screwball old
cavalryman to command the 3rd Army.
George. . .
. . .Ike came to that conclusion
in London three months ago.
He what?
Why, that dirty--!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I promise to keep my mouth shut.
(SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
George could have the courtesy
to tell us where he's going.
Good God, look at that.
Where you going, general?
Berlin.
I'm going to personally shoot
that paper-hanging son of a bitch.
(CHEERING)
Hold it. Hold it!
This place isn't on the map.
You know why?
We've run clear off the map.
Give George a headline,
and he's good for another 30 miles.
(HONKING)
SOLDIER:
Atten-hut!
Hold it!
Pay attention. We're gonna clean
this mess up right now.
Let's move this vehicle out this way.
This one out this way.
Back that thing up there,
and we'll take this one here.
All right, get up off your ass.
Let's go now!
That's it.
That's the way to move.
Good boy. All right, come on.
Come on, now. Here we go. Come on.
That's it!
That's it! Gun it!
Gun that thing!
Okay, come on.
Watch it!
Go, go, go! Come on.
Hold it up.
Come on, baby. Yeah, yeah.
Come on.
That's it.
Come on, now.
-Chet.
-Yeah, will do.
Come on, keep coming. Keep coming.
Hold it up there.
Now come on! Hold it!
Hey, dummy, hold the fricking tank!
That's it. Come on.
Good boy.
-Hold it up there.
-General!
General Bradley wants to have
a word with you.
Okay. Come on!
Okay. Hold it up. Take over.
George, you'd make a good traffic cop.
George this drive has been
magnificent. . .
. . .but I'm sorry to say
I have to slow you down.
-What the hell for?
-We'll have to cut off your supplies.
Gasoline, ammunition, everything.
We're up against new priorities.
-I think I smell Montgomery.
-Take it easy, George.
There are serious issues involved.
Political issues.
By God, it is Montgomery.
The launching sites for the B-2 bombs
are all in his area.
Churchill wants those bases destroyed.
Hitler kills more civilians
in London than soldiers.
Expect Montgomery to do anything?
You give me gasoline and I'll gain
ground with it, kill Germans too.
Give me 400,000 gallons.
I'll go to Berlin.
George, I can't do it.
The Siegfried line
is an empty shell.
They stripped the equipment
and sent it east.
It's crawling with cows.
I can punch through in two days.
There's no use in arguing with me.
It wasn't my idea.
Why did you pick me to command?
I didn't pick you.
Ike picked you.
George, you have performed
brilliantly.
You are loyal, dedicated.
You're one of the best I've got,
but you don't know when to shut up.
George, you're a pain in the neck.
I have a lot of faults, Brad.
But ingratitude isn't one of them.
I owe you a lot.
Hell, I know I'm a prima donna.
I admit it.
What I can't stand about Monty is,
he won't admit it.
(TANK SPUTTERS)
Captain, the Bailey's run out of gas.
The point tank has run out too.
And there's a kraut column up ahead.
Yeah, I know.
PATTON:
Were you in command here, captain?
I was in command.
My tank platoon was supporting
an infantry company.
Tanks ran out of gas,
so we had to fight it out.
We started 11:00 last night.
Finished a couple hours ago.
This morning the fighting
was hand-to-hand.
I had a dream last night.
In my dream it came to me. . .
. . .that right now the whole Nazi Reich
is mine for the taking.
Think about that, Cod.
I was nearly sent home in disgrace.
Now I have precisely
the right instrument. . .
. . .at precisely the right moment of
history and exactly the right place.
The Saar?
This will change too, very quickly.
Like a planet spinning off
into the universe.
A moment like this won't come again
for 1000 years.
All I need is a few
miserable gallons of gasoline.
Right now, the weak spot is here.
In 10 days, we could be in Berlin.
What about the fortifications
that were done in Metz?
Fixed fortifications, huh?
Monuments to the stupidity of man.
When mountain ranges and oceans
could be overcome. . .
. . .anything built by man
can be overcome.
You know how I'm sure
they're finished out there?
The carts.
They're using carts to move
their wounded and the supplies.
The carts came to me in my dream.
I couldn't figure it out.
Then I remembered. . .
. . .that nightmare in the snow.
The agonizing retreat from Moscow.
How cold it was.
They threw the wounded and what was
left of the supplies in the carts.
Napoleon was finished.
Not any color left.
Not even the red of blood.
Only the snow.
Look at this, Cod.
I love it.
God help me, I do love it so.
I love it more than my life.
NARRATOR: Paris is liberated,
and French troops lead the way.
The Allies march into the city
after four years of Nazi occupation.
The hard-fighting French
2nd Armored Division...
...under Major General
Jacques Leclerc...
...gets an unforgettable welcome...
...as they enter their beloved Paris.
In a powerful drive to the north...
... General Montgomery cuts off and
bypasses the French coastal towns...
...of Boulogne, Calais and Dunkirk.
Pushing on to capture the vital
Belgian port of Antwerp.
Meanwhile, the main body
of Patton 's army...
...resupplied now and rolling like a
juggernaut, slashes toward the Saar.
Nazi resistance appears to crumble.
It seems that nothing can stop our
troops from driving on into Germany.
-Sir, General Bradley on your line.
-Good, good.
Brad, listen, I've got a bridgehead
across the Saar.
I'm on my way to Germany.
Wait a minute, George.
There's a lot of trouble up north.
I want you to transfer tank armor
to Middleton's 8th Corps right away.
Brad, you can't do that.
George, listen.
I don't have time to argue.
There's a lot of enemy activity
up around Ardennes.
No, I don't know how serious it is. . .
. . .but Ike wants us to meet
with Bedell Smith tomorrow at Verdun.
Be there at 11 00.
Yes, sir.
PATTON: There's absolutely no reason
for us to assume. . .
. . .that the Germans are mounting
a major offense.
The weather is awful
and their supplies are low.
The Germans haven't mounted a winter
attack since Frederick the Great.
Therefore I believe that's exactly
what they're going to do.
I want you to start making
contingency plans. . .
. . .for pulling out
of our eastward attack.
Changing directions 90 degrees,
moving up to Luxembourg.
Don't look so stunned, gentlemen.
I want you to plan
for three possible axes of attack.
From Diekirch, due north.
From Orléans to Bastogne.
From Neufchâteau against the German
left flank.
We've identified four German armies:
The 7th, the 5th Panzer,
6th SS Panzer and the 15th.
They've hit us with 26 divisions.
They've overran two regimens
of the 106th Division.
And 7500 of our men
were forced to surrender.
Our concern is that von Rundstedt. . .
. . .has the 101st Airborne trapped
here at Bastogne.
Bastogne, by the way, is the key
to this entire area.
lf we can hold it, we can break up
the entire German offensive.
lf they take it,
we're in serious trouble.
Ike wants to know if anybody can go. . .
. . .and relieve the 101st
before they're torn to pieces.
There's nothing Montgomery can do.
At any rate, not for some weeks.
What about you, George?
I can attack with three divisions
in 48 hours.
I'd give myself some leeway.
Ike wants a realistic estimate,
George.
You're in the middle of a fight now.
It's over a hundred miles to Bastogne.
My staff's already working
out the details.
Frankly, I don't see how
it's possible.
Not in this kind of weather.
I should have thought you'd want
to fall back and regroup.
Not me. I don't like to pay
for the same real estate twice.
TEDDER:
But what about your men?
You can't cart them off 100 miles,
expecting them to attack without rest.
I trained these men.
They'll do what I tell them to do.
We hadn't realized you were
so popular with your troops, general.
I'm not. They'll do it
because they're good soldiers.
And because they realize, as I do,
that we can still lose this war.
Then I think I can speak
for Field Marshal Montgomery.
He'd say you're asking
the impossible of your men.
Of course he would.
Cause he's never realized that's
what we're in business for.
(BOMB EXPLODES)
General McAuliffe refused
a German surrender demand.
You know what he said?
What?
He said, "Nuts. "
Keep them moving, colonel.
A man that eloquent has to be saved.
(SILENCE)
This is where it pays off.
The training and discipline.
No other outfit in the world.
Pulled out of a winter battle,
move a hundred miles.
Going to a major attack with no rest,
no sleep, no hot food.
God! God, I'm proud of these men!
Sir, von Rundstedt's thrown another
panzer division against Bastogne.
101 st Airborne's barely holding on.
We need damned air cover. lf we had
decent weather, we might make it.
CARVER:
General Mason, sir.
Hello, Mase?
Listen, we're short on foot soldiers.
Cannibalize your antiaircraft units
and turn them into riflemen.
Yes, every last one you can find.
Good evening, general.
I just got the weather report
for tomorrow. More snow.
There goes our air cover.
We may have to wait
for better weather.
Brave men dying up there. I won't
wait, not an hour, not a minute.
Going to keep moving.
ls that clear?
We're going to attack all night
and attack tomorrow morning!
lf we're not victorious. . .
. . .let no one come back alive.
You know something, general?
Sometimes, they can't tell when
you're acting and when you're not.
It isn't important for them to know.
It's only important for me to know.
-You want to see me, general?
-Oh, yeah, chaplain.
I'm tired of 3rd Army
having to fight Germans. . .
. . .with supreme command,
no gasoline. . .
. . .and now this ungodly weather.
I want a prayer, a weather prayer.
A weather prayer, sir?
Yes, let's see if you can't get God
working with us.
Gonna take a thick rug
for that kind of praying.
I don't care if it
takes a flying carpet.
I don't know how this
will be received, general.
Praying for good weather
so we can kill our fellow man.
I assure you, because of
my relations with the Almighty. . .
. . .if you write a good prayer,
we'll have good weather.
And I expect that prayer
within an hour.
Yes, sir.
"Almighty and most merciful Father. . .
. . .we humbly beseech Thee. . .
. . .of Thy great goodness. . .
. . .to restrain this
immoderate weather. . .
. . .with which we've had to contend.
Grant us fair weather for battle.
Graciously hearken to us...
...as soldiers who call upon Thee...
... that armed with Thy power...
... we may advance
from victory to victory...
...and crush the oppression...
...and wickedness of our enemies...
...and establish Thy justice...
...among men and nations.
Amen. ''
Weather's perfect.
Cod, get me that chaplain.
He's in good with the Lord
and I want to decorate him.
Hiya, general!
NARRATOR: Supported by medium bombers
and fighter bombers...
...flying sorties
against German positions...
...elements of the 3rd Army...
...spearheaded by the
4th Armored Division...
...drive into Bastogne...
... to relieve its 18,000 defenders...
...on the day after Christmas.
During this operation,
3rd Army moved farther and faster...
...and engaged more divisions
in less time...
... than any other army in the history
of the United States.
(MUSlC PLAYS)
Excuse me, sir.
General Katkov would like to know
if you'll join him. . .
. . .to drink to the surrender
of Germany.
My compliments to the general.
Please inform him that I do not care
to drink with him. . .
. . .or any other Russian
son of a bitch.
Sir. . .
. . .I cannot tell the general that.
You tell him that.
Tell him word for word.
(SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN)
The general says he thinks that. . .
. . .you are a son of a bitch too.
Okay. I'll drink to that.
One son of a bitch to another.
(SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN)
(CHEERING)
Is it true that Roosevelt,
before he died. . .
. . .promised you
a command in the Pacific?
Yes. But now that he's gone, I don't
think there's much chance of that.
Doug MacArthur
doesn't want me up there.
We're told of "wonder weapons"
the Germans were working on:
Long-range rockets,
push-button bombing. . .
. . .weapons that don't need soldiers.
"Wonder weapon"?
My God, I don't see
the wonder in them.
Killing without heroics. Nothing
is glorified, nothing is reaffirmed.
No heroes, no cowards, no troops.
No generals.
Only those that are left alive
and those that are left. . .
. . .dead.
I'm glad I won't live to see it.
REPORTER: It's said you're still
using former Nazis in key positions.
Despite the denazification policy.
Well, if I'm supplied
with trained personnel. . .
. . .I'll get rid of the Nazis.
Until then, I'll use them to keep
the railroads and telephones working.
After all, didn't most
ordinary Nazis join the Party. . .
. . .in about the same way Americans
become Republicans or Democrats?
Yes, that's about it.
You agree that national policy be made
by civilians, not by the military?
Of course. But the politicians
never let us finish.
They always stop short and leave us
with another war.
You thinking about our Russian allies?
Did you say if you found your army
between the Germans and the Russians. . .
. . .you'd attack in both directions?
No, I never said that.
I never said any such thing.
But I wish I had.
(LAUGHING)
Sir, there's a call on your line from
supreme headquarters, General Smith.
Bedell?
Ike is furious.
How could you compare Republicans
and Democrats to the Nazi Party?
And the statement
that you refuse to denazify. . .
. . .has the Russians, the British,
everybody, screaming.
Well, the hell
with the Mongoloid Russians.
We've given them Berlin, Prague,
God knows what else.
They gonna dictate policy too?
George, don't be a fool.
The war in Europe is over.
Washington dictates policy.
The war shouldn't be over. We should
stop pussyfooting about the Russians!
We'll have to fight them anyway. Why
not do it now, when the army's here?
lnstead of disarming Germans let's
get them to help fight the Bolsheviks.
You better shut up.
This line may be tapped.
I don't care. I'll tell you. . .
. . .we've been fighting
the wrong people.
You and I don't have to get involved,
you're so soft about it.
Leave it to me. In 1 0 days
I'll have us at war with them. . .
. . .and make it look like their fault!
George, you're mad.
You're absolutely out of your mind!
Well, I'm no diplomat.
I'm a combat soldier.
That's all they understand.
Get Ike to give me the word,
and I'll kick them back to Russia!
Shall I call the artist back, sir?
Oh, the hell with it.
Nobody wants to see a picture of me.
I'm mad!
Don't you know that?
Field Marshal Montgomery,
his majesty is prepared. . .
. . .to receive the next chief
of the imperial general staff.
Thank you.
Take care of yourself.
George.
Well, gentlemen. . .
. . .all good things
must come to an end.
And the best thing
that's happened to me. . .
. . .in my life. . .
. . .has been. . .
. . .uh. . .
. . .the honor. . .
. . .and privilege. . .
. . .of commanding the 3rd Army.
Goodbye. . .
. . .and God bless you.
Brad. . .
. . .they've taken the 3rd Army
away from me.
I know.
I thought we could have dinner
together tonight.
Thank you, Brad.
That's damn thoughtful.
I appreciate it.
Right now, I think I'll take
Willie for a walk.
George, look out!
After all I've been through. . .
. . .imagine getting killed
by an oxcart.
No, Brad, there's only one proper way
for a professional soldier to die.
That's from the last bullet
of the last battle of the last war.
At least the 3rd Army earned its pay.
In our drive across Europe,
we liberated. . .
. . . 1 2,000 cities and towns. . .
. . .and inflicted a million and a half
enemy casualties.
I sense from now on, just being
a good soldier won't mean a thing.
I'm afraid we're gonna have to be
diplomats, administrators, you name it.
God help us.
George, I want to say one thing.
You've done a magnificent job
here in Europe.
That's right, George.
That soldier you slapped did more to
win the war than any other private.
I'll see you for dinner.
Six-thirty?
PATTON:
For over a thousand years...
...Roman conquerors
returning from the wars...
...enjoyed the honor of a triumph,
a tumultuous parade.
In the procession came trumpeters
and musicians and strange animals...
...from the conquered territories...
... together with carts laden with
treasure and captured armaments.
The conqueror rode
in a triumphal chariot...
... the dazed prisoners
walking in chains before him.
Sometimes, his children,
robed in white...
...stood with him in the chariot,
or rode the trace horses.
A slave stood behind the conqueror...
...holding a golden crown...
...and whispering in his ear
a warning...
... that all glory...
...is fleeting.