- We're kicking today.
- Yeah.
Wanna go?
- It's freezing outside.
- We've been inside all day!
- Let's get high.
- We've been getting high all day!
- We'll get high. When?
- Now!
I hate people who
get stoned and yap,
who talk shit and then regret it!
You're like that!
- I didn't say a word all night!
- Crapoid.
You've got a lit cig in your mouth,
one in your hand
and one in the ashtray.
You're gonna wake Vincenzoni!
Pentothal!
Be right down.
The moment has come.
Now I'll go downstairs
and she'll say it.
I wonder how she put
up with me for so long.
No matter what she says,
I have to forget it before noon.
Don't think about it.
In three years I've learned this,
while waiting in line at
the cafeteria, you can read, talk
do whatever you want,
but don't think!
You're in worse shape than I
thought... But the end is near.
"The end is near..." Their
commitment takes them so concise.
I'm dumping you,
it sounds pretty stupid.
My reasons are your total
lack of information,
your laziness and lack of dignity.
This is just what I needed.
You live past glories, but which?
Actually, you live
sitting down on yourself, you...
What do you do?
Night watch, comrades!
Everything fine?
All is well, thanks.
What does "I'm dumping you" mean?
That we won't make love anymore?
That we won't see each other?
That we won't say hello anymore?
None of this or maybe all of this.
It's the concept that counts:
I am dumping you.
I don't care about the mechanics.
Fascists!
- Run home, I'll...
- You'll what?
Bastards!
Get that asshole!
Did you do it?
No, it was...
Where is...?
- What are you doing?
- Getting something to drink.
Can you get me a glass of water
and turn up the heat?
Gross!
There's never a fucking clean glass!
Galileo!
Little pest!
Because coldness, the
real kind, can sit here,
in the pit of this dude's heart.
I'm a wolf, don't call me Fido.
You're beautiful, Robby!
- How do you do it?
- The gym.
It's late mom,
I have to go to school.
It's the spark plug.
Sergio!
Your egg sandwich!
Why didn't you take it?
Drive slowly!
Go to hell!
- Poor thing...
- Insane!
Here she is.
- Hello Ma'am!
- Good morning Ma'am.
I'm speechless.
Forgive them, they're vandals.
1968 was a...
I was saying that 1968
was an amazing period,
I got a bad deal though,
I fell in love
with a girl from Trieste and...
Kids!
Please!
Petrilli!
Zanardi.
Tomorrow I'll give you
a history test,
on the Second War
of Independence, okay?
- Sure.
- You do want to finish high school?
- Yes or no?
- Sure.
I assume you want
to go to college too,
or get a job,
so you'll need this piece of paper.
- Sure.
- See you tomorrow.
I have your homework.
Besides for Infante's,
they all stink.
Infante gets a B, rather an A.
Is that okay?
All the others literally stink.
Infante, come here.
I'm going out with Mirella today.
Some monster tits!
I'll ask...
Infante.
Good morning professor.
Zanardi, Colasanti and Petrilli
to the principal's office.
Thanks, excuse me.
Excuse the intrusion,
Colasanti, Zanardi
and Petrilli are here.
Come in.
No, stand up!
This man has a few things
to say to you!
I'm from police headquarters,
she has filed a report against you.
The accusation?
Trespassing in her yard,
torturing and killing her cat.
Don't be so concise!
These pigs crucified
a poor helpless creature,
mine or not, doesn't matter!
Actually it does.
- I'd like to say a word.
- Say it, Zanardi.
Say this word,
but before you spew out
your usual hogwash,
look what I found in my yard.
Your phone book.
You're finished,
I'll hound you until
you're behind bars!
Impossible, it was
in my pocket this morning!
This is a dirty fucking trap!
You stole it from my coat?
No, it wasn't me.
Do what you want. If you're
done, we'll go back to class.
You make me sick Zanardi,
you're pompous and arrogant,
you're a sadist!
Get out of here, you infect!
You too, worms!
Yes Ma'am!
Comrades, colleagues, cohabitants,
is there any coffee?
You're always the last to wake up.
Noodle soup, who wants some?
Fuck this...
Space.
I'm dumping you,
it's the concept that counts.
I don't care about the mechanics.
I don't care about the mechanics...
Stop fucking slurping!
Ringo, didn't you notice
he's not doing well?
No.
Enrico!
The coffee is there.
- What's the weather like?
- I don't know.
Is there sugar in it?
Did you stir it?
Stir it yourself.
Anna?
Should I go take the exam?
I don't know, all I know
is that I'm late!
I don't know a damn thing!
Do you hear me?
See you tonight.
Wait, you didn't even give me
a kiss.
You wouldn't happen to have
five bills to lend me?
Yes, but don't get stoned
before the exam.
Are you crazy?
Not before or after, never!
Five?
Here.
I'll pay you back.
Five plus ten from last time...
I'll repay it all
at the end of the month.
Give me another kiss.
- Five plus ten...
- Yes, we'll add it up tonight.
- You're always rushing.
- I have to go to work!
I'm freaking out,
should I take the exam or not?
- What are your feelings?
- I feel I'm going to be late!
Get dressed, you'll get cold.
Five bills...
That's it,
I refuse to stay
in that shitty apartment!
Goodbye Bologna, I'll go to Naples!
Or Paris or Champagnol
or Morocco.
By now all departments
have been taken over...
I'm totally out of the loop.
Breakfast, morning breakfast...
Butter and jam in abundance!
"The index opposes
all other signs..."
Damn, I've only got
half a joint here!
"...as a differential class
in the same category
and not as a differential class."
Signs are deciphered,
appearances are not.
appearances must not be deciphered.
No way can appearances
be deciphered!
A tiny joint and the exam is done!
What's this smoke?
Smoking's bad, what the hell will I
tell your mom while I'm banging her?
Out!
- Jerking off makes you go blind.
- Go to class!
Get your ass to class.
- You wouldn't throw Materazzo out.
- No.
He's not the kind of guy
who let's himself get thrown out.
Out!
- See what the raw deal is?
- How many raw deals are there?
I left some stuff under the
lining of my phone book.
- Zanna, you're dead.
- We're dead.
Good, Colas... We've got
to get the phone book back.
Grab the cards,
let's see who has to do it.
Let's grab 'em...
- Queen.
- Seven of hearts.
Son of a bitch,
I'm supposed to meet Mirella!
Let things reach pure appearance,
let them deplete into
pure appearance,
let them sparkle.
Signs are deciphered,
appearances are not...
Signs aren't appearances
and appearances aren't signs.
You can decipher signs
as much as you fucking want,
but never appearances.
Got the student ID...
I've got everything.
But...
Fuck, the keys!
Well, Anna will be home
this afternoon anyway.
Let things reach pure appearance,
let them sparkle...
Fuck, the basin!
Well, it won't flood the house
too badly in half a day.
Signs are deciphered,
appearances are not.
No, not this!
Vincenzoni old and bony,
open up!
Vincenzoni Attilio, age 73.
Who are you?
Enrico Fiabeschi,
Anna's boyfriend. Move!
Where are you going?
This isn't the end, I'll tell Anna!
Careful, it's dangerous!
Alright!
I pester you?
Just tell me to go away
and you won't see me anymore!
- Go away.
- But you have to tell me.
I am telling you.
Yes, but now it doesn't count,
you were supposed to tell me
before!
She's telling you...
He's stuck.
Ternana - Ascoli game...
Luciano, I need to make a call.
Son, one shouldn't go outside
in pajamas!
Mariella, I don't have much
change, let me talk to mom.
Hello... Hi, Michele.
Can I talk to mom?
Hello, mom... Dad, it's you.
What?
Let me talk to mom,
I don't have much change!
Mariella, you again?
I don't know!
Let me talk to mom!
Mom, finally! I wanted...
Now I'm getting pissed off.
Signs are deciphered,
appearances are not...
Signs yes, appearances never.
We were different from you,
we protested to defend our ideas.
We wanted to get to know
each other...
Sex was carefree,
we'd go to someone's house...
Bullshit!
When you're young it's hard
to believe in a cruel destiny...
You know Mirella, right?
Class 2H.
...but then you realize
that destiny is assisted
by what we've assembled
and it is this that decides for us!
Go get her, and come to the club.
Colas will be there too.
Mirella alone with Zanna and Colas!
Don't want to think about it.
Uncertain weather, low visibility.
You're not coming?
None of my shit's clean,
I'm borrowing a shirt and stuff.
You know about today's meeting?
It seems the cops
found out about Luisa's deal.
But we won't let it happen.
Lucilla dumped me.
You can handle that...
I'm taking your boots too.
Are you always...
...so stagnant?
What's my fucking problem?
Why does my life suck?
My uncle's right,
hash rots your brains.
Luisa,
Matteo,
Gianna, the cops,
Lucilla...
This white sky!
Don't ask me anything,
don't make me talk.
I wouldn't dare.
I love you,
I have so many things to tell you.
Your nose is dirty.
- I'm burnt out.
- Why, honey?
Life burns me out.
I feel clumsy.
- I feel alone.
- Come to mama.
Honey, be careful.
Bone up... Bone up...
Bone up...
Bone up, fuck!
Bone up.
Please, bone up!
Bone up, up!
Well, at this time of the day.
It's too easy...
When you don't know what to do
it's too easy to take refuge
in copulation.
If someone would think
from reading this crap
that I've got nothing left to say,
I'd say that in each board
there's enough material
to construct a few stories
that I won't narrate because
I have nothing left to tell you.
He's the best!
Better than the best,
practically a rock star!
What happened?
Will you ask me a few questions?
Youngsters do nothing,
yet they expect things to happen!
We were both here... What happened?
We know the "whys"
let's discover the "hows"!
Our comrade
from the research group
will give us a detailed
explanation of the situation.
Comrades, the only way
to get ourselves out of this shit
is to step up the fighting!
It's not just the group's
problem, but all of ours!
The initiative has to be ours!
Sit-in!
11,000 uninhabited houses in Bologna
and thousands of homeless students.
Enough with these
scheming feminists.
Show your face!
Shut up for a second!
There was a problem
with the truth pamphlets.
Do we still have a propaganda group?
You think you're superior...
Coefficient bullshit at the max.
I said, bullshit at the max!
I can't work with all this ruckus.
This is my house too,
go somewhere else,
anywhere you want.
I don't oppose, but what the fuck!
You're an artist,
and you don't give a shit
but we give a shit about you.
You're an artist so you think
you're the shit.
You spend the night at school
and call it a sit-in,
you slap up two posters and
your conscience is at peace!
You read the "Espresso"
every other week
and "Linus" when you feel like it
and you think you're informed!
In practice buddy,
you either become productive
for the movement,
or go fuck yourself!
The Pentothal who doesn't
give a shit, you made him up!
It's a non existant myth!
It's not you who doesn't give a shit,
it's the others
who've emarginated you!
You think you're the shit
cuz you're an artist!
Of course I work...
at the consortium.
What do you mean, which?
You think you're the shit
cuz you're an artist!
At the drainage consortium.
In Latina.
What do I want?
I'm here for the exam.
Did I read anything? No.
I work, how can I?
As if I have time to read
Kripke and Chomsky...
Who'll take care of my kids, you?
Plus I don't know them...
What do you mean, what?
I don't know any of this shit.
Why do I want to take this exam?
All I need to graduate is "Modal
Philosophy" and "Model Theory",
and you think I'd just
give up like that?
This is "Semiotics"?
This is "DAMS"?
What's that?
Oh, this isn't Philosophy?
Now you tell me?
Next, Fiabeschi Enrico.
Hey there, that's me.
Good morning. Topic?
"Apocalypse Now".
Take off the sunglasses please.
Well I studied all night,
so my eyes are...
Take them off anyway.
Tell me about "Apocalypse Now".
"Apocalypse Now", is directed
by Francis Ford Coppola,
with music by the Doors.
The film starts off
with a burning forest,
choppers fly overhead
and underneath,
is music by the Doors.
A beautiful scene.
- How much did the film cost?
- A load of money!
They probably spent a million
dollars just on the helicopters,
then Storaro...
- Did you read about the film?
- Of course.
The main actor is Marlon Brando.
Marlon Brando is Kurtz,
the film's main character.
Kurtz is all like...
What's the name of the real
main actor?
The real main actor.
What's the name?
There are many actors in the film,
but Coppola...
...Marlon Brando
used as a pretext...
Marlon Brando is really...
...for Coppola it was a pretext...
...a pretext for...
Maybe I should ask you
something else.
The film depicts a battle,
what kind?
A battle between man and nature.
- And then?
- And then, what?
There's the battle against
the productive system,
against repression
of the imaginary,
Vietnam,
the process of Vietnamesization,
individual and collective.
Exactly, individual and collective,
battle between man and nature...
That's what I said before,
but if you want to be picky...
That was the answer.
- Let's talk about Conrad.
- Who?
"Heart of Darkness."
What does the river symbolize
for Conrad-Coppola?
Oh, "Cornad" Coppola...
The river symbolizes...
- The journey.
- Exactly that!
The journey of this river
which descends into the valley
and gets covered up by branches...
The journey of the snake!
"A mighty big river which resembled
an immense snake
with its head in the sea
and its body at rest
curving afar over a vast country
and its tail lost in the depths
of the land.
It fascinated me
as a snake would a bird."
Enough with this farce.
I wasn't able to study,
just let me pass, or else
I'll have to join the army.
- Why not?
- Because you didn't study.
You're punishing me
with a year of army life
cuz I don't know "Apocalypse Now",
I couldn't give a shit about it!
I mean, I wasn't able to...
I flunked six people today
who had actually tried
more than you.
But this isn't
a meritocratic society!
Everyone becomes someone
thanks to someone else,
I'm the only one
who has to follow the rules!
- Listen, the proletarian...
- You're a bitch!
This is a dumb-ass exam
and you're a fucking Fascist!
Thirsty for power like Hitler!
You didn't even ask me the difference
between sign and appearance!
You asked about the snake!
Know where you can stick it?
Up your dirty Fascist ass!
Out.
Go get your pussy proletarianized!
- And close the door when you leave!
- Fuck you!
Fuck you!
I think of my sister,
brother, mother,
father, grandfather
who is no longer around...
Moon,
you're so beautiful,
I look at you and get
knots in my stomach...
What a shitty day!
I think about how at my house
we'd laugh...
- It's them.
- Zanardi's wearing the scarf?
Yes, the other one's Colas.
Zanardi is just like I imagined him.
But now I'm sort of...
You should hear the stories
they tell about them.
Don't tell me, or I'll get scared.
- Relax, come on.
- Alright.
Hi, I'm Mirella.
I've heard wonders about you.
Just think, you'll see me naked soon.
The power's out.
Do you like music?
I'll turn the heater on.
Well?
The Mirella I met in the gym,
who I picked up.
I'll carry your bag.
Who I kept making dates with...
Who I told all about me...
Today I did 60 push ups
and 40 sit ups!
I do it for internal evolution,
for spiritual growth.
...I may be noble, but who cares.
Combining these two worlds,
nobility and gym, is difficult...
You find yourself at a reception
with a tie and salad fork...
What do you mean nobility?
My grandmother was a princess!
Do you take the 13?
We should hang out.
We can go out with friends
if you want.
It's cool, whenever you want.
The onl y thing left of her is the
memory of all the lies I told.
Not a kiss,
not a "Billo" caress...
- We're getting bored without you.
- Come on out!
Being shy?
Out! Out!
Awesome!
You're so beautiful Colas,
how do you do it?
The gym.
Here's the other.
Guy's dicks are all the same,
don't you think?
That's like saying
all pussies are the same.
Come here.
Mirella,
do they look alike?
No, actually.
- Colas' is longer.
- When it's limp.
Get the ruler.
What's the point of going on?
I think I can jet now.
Fuck!
Hear that shout?
I know only one set of tonsils
capable of that,
Gino Nardella's,
man of culture and beggar!
I've practiced waiting in line
for years,
now I let out a shout every
15 minutes, automatically,
I'm as precise as a stop watch.
Every day I spend three hours in line
and I still don't know anyone,
the head of the guy in front of me
and the breath of the one in back.
Deranged lunatics!
Fuck, it's 2:15!
Here, the Greek table,
the Calabrian kids...
Guys from Messina, Enna,
Sardinian feminists,
the gay posse from Pescara.
Alone. I'm alone.
This is not possible!
What?
This is the sickest soup
I have ever tasted, try it.
I believe you.
It made my mouth all shitty.
- I said I believe you.
- You have to taste it.
I believe you!
- Tell them!
I've never tasted anything
so gross!
- I understand.
- Taste!
- Fuck off!
Panic transversalism,
schizophrenic nomadism
dictatorship of meaning,
proletariat in precarization,
time freed from work,
subtractive proletarian transience,
generalized social misappropriation,
non violent demonstration
defended by small weapons,
hysteric creativity, Mao-Dadaism,
ironic sensual poetics,
deterritorialization,
reterritorialization,
hysteric subjectivism,
generalized femininization,
creative subversion,
repression of subject.
Happiness is subversive
when its collectivized.
Permanent marker, erasers,
exacto, stapler,
scissors,
butts, filters, paste, glue stick,
scraps, pencils, pastels,
color chart, brushes,
ink, rapidograph, chalk,
plates, glasses, ash tray, lighter,
masks, pencil shavings,
crumbs, glasses,
rulers, squares, compass...
...and Lucilla's purse.
Why did she leave it here?
I love you.
First kiss.
I don't care about the mechanics.
Now you say I'm weak, but
you didn't think so on Thursday.
I ask myself what I'm looking for.
What am I looking for?
I ask myself what do you want.
What do I want?
Why did Lucilla
leave her purse here?
I don't care
about the mechanics...
Do I care about the mechanics?
No, I don't care
about the mechanics.
Should I put it on automatic pilot?
No, so long as it goes.
Go!
We've got a flat, pass me the joint.
This really is a desert.
But I'm a multitude,
so be thankful I'm here.
It's like a morgue.
All flat...
We've been going around for 3 months
and haven't run into anyone.
There's nothing, not even basil...
After this last pleasant observation,
want to go?
Lucilla, I finally found you!
It is you, right?
Good, I'm happy.
You're beautiful,
you always were.
I love you.
Now that I found you again,
I won't leave you!
You'll never leave, right?
We'll always be together and I won't
have those horrible dreams anymore.
Open up!
Why did you lock yourselves in?
What the fuck are you doing?
You took forever!
No phone book.
Did you look really well?
I'm starving now!
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
- Mirella, wanna come to the cafe?
- Yes.
What a loser!
Here.
I didn't know you knew
Zanardi and Colasanti.
I knew of them, Elena let me get
better acquainted with them today.
That bitch!
- You went to the club?
- Yes, but they were waiting for you.
I bet you had fun.
Somewhat...
- What's that face about?
- I know why!
What did you do?
I could say mind your own
business, but I'll answer you.
We got naked and touched each other.
Zanardi... God, I hate you!
"Bea Guidicini, Blake's Hotel,
18 Hampton Road, W1 London."
Bea, think of me now...
Wherever you are, turn around.
Turn around now,
it's me, your Z anna.
That'll do, end of broadcast.
I haven't read your letter yet, so
I don't know that you've dumped me.
Hey, do you have a joint?
Do you have a joint?
Is anybody here?
Is there anyone here?
I am, I'm chewing
and meditating in the dark.
Do you have a joint?
Chew, chew...
I've been wandering for 3 hours,
do you have a joint?
No, but it's warm down here
and I'm soft and clean.
I'll smoke later.
FORBIDDEN TO FORBID
TOMORROW SOCIALISM BEGINS
BE PUNCTUAL
THE NEW '68 WILL BE CALIBER 38
As the sky changes hues...
Changes hues my foot!
- Sirio appears under the moon...
- The moon...
The whole city sets itself
for the long night.
Noise is captured
in the thick clouds of smog...
...a rug of bright embers...
Lovely, is it yours?
- No, it's my friend Pompeo's.
- You still hang out with him?
- What am I doing here?
- You already said that.
- Get with it.
- Leave me alone!
Get with it, people will get bored
and tired!
Love me!
The exam?
- It went badly?
- She's a bitch!
Honey, no one understands you.
Want to hang out tonight?
No, I'm going out with Diana.
Are you always with her?
She always stares.
- I feel lonely.
- But I'll be home early.
Wait for me at home.
Come on...
When will you be back?
She said early!
What the fuck do you want?
- Leave her alone.
- She's always eavesdropping!
Take the car keys,
go home and wait for me.
Sorry.
She's always there...
- Can you lend me five bills?
- Again?
- I need it.
- For what?
To buy you some flowers.
Some flowers...
Here.
Diana, why don't you do this
once in a while?
At least your hair will be...
Up yours!
You're higher than a kite...
Wanna get high?
Okay guys, no problem!
To the train station I went,
for eptadone to get spent,
took off in the van I was lent!
The housewives get in line
to hear me crank and rhyme
and they have a hell of a time!
Look at all the people!
Massimo's even there.
Wonder what he's up to?
I can stop to see a friend, right?
Massimo a.k.a. Mighty Max,
resident of Bologna,
do you have a joint?
I'm waiting for Mezzasega,
he's bringing some herb.
Seeing that it's not too late,
it's my duty to stay and wait.
- Go park.
- Where?
- Pull the brake and leave it here.
- It's Anna's car.
- Whose?
- Never mind. I'll park there.
Do you have the weed?
- It's him.
- Yes.
The one with the mustache
and long hair.
Cute!
I got it, but let's go smoke
somewhere else.
- Where?
- At one of their houses.
Chicks?
So long as it's a joint
with friends, it's cool,
but you never know what
to expect with chicks...
I'm out of here.
What, you're leaving?
We need your car
plus this is some killer weed.
Enrico, you don't know
what you're missing.
I live on the edge,
I'm touched by the slums,
I chat with wanted criminals,
I'm in full swing,
I earn and burn millions.
I take risks, I waste away,
I humiliate myself, then I give up...
I give up.
Then I get high and it's all
perfect, better than before.
The alternative is a pub, a job,
savings, the regular
crumbling of the body,
the nice guy, the annoying girl,
the natural dork,
two times two is four,
wake up at eight!
That's even more of
a pain in the ass!
Nothing like resurrection,
resurrection...
I'm glad you called me.
Really glad!
I'm glad you called,
so unexpectedly...
- Don't turn on the lights.
- Right, it's better.
Get naked.
Huh?
What's wrong with smoking up
with some chicks?
They exist, I can't hide from them.
It could happen
that we smoke up together.
"On the peak
of the ancient tower,
solitary thrush..."
Nice Infante, that's the way
I like you. It came out well.
I wonder if it'll get blurry
if we make a poster of it?
As your brain may have realized,
in exchange for this
you have to do us a favor.
Wanna come with me to Mexico?
Would you want to?
I wouldn't even go
around the corner with you.
You're the famous Fiabeschi...
- I've heard about you.
- It's me.
- What's your name?
- Marilisa.
Pretty name!
How would you feel about
going over there?
We can lie down, kiss a bit,
have sex, but just for fun.
Okay, but let's use my
parents' bed cuz it's bigger.
Of course, your parents' bed...
...cuz it's bigger.
If it's not in the office she
must have brought it home.
It's not hard to get in, enter
the bedroom from the back yard,
she won't be home.
Look in the drawers and search
through her purse if you see it,
but don't make a mess.
Remember, she's
going to her sister's
so take your time
and find the phone book.
You have plenty of time.
We're going to a club
so we can have a solid alibi.
Colas, you're the best.
Yes, the best...
Who were you with?
Menozzi. Says he
wants to marry me.
Now, let's get noticed.
What the fuck should I do?
He's tall, you're not,
not your fault.
His hair is like silk, yours isn't,
can't help it.
He has curls, you don't,
not a big deal.
He's thin and you're plump,
it happens.
He dances well and
you don't, at all.
He's rich and you're not,
he's cool and you're not,
he's...
He's fucking your girl on
the couch and you're not.
He's him and you're not.
So?
Go outside and torch his car.
Ma'am, it's me!
Let me explain.
It's me.
Don't call the police!
Please have pity!
Pity!
Let go of my hand!
My mother will die!
I'm the valedictorian
of the class.
The valedictorian!
Fuck, the keys!
Gross!
Wake up!
Wake up, the keys!
The car keys!
- Danny took them.
- Who?
Who the fuck is Danny?
- The girl I was talking to.
- Where'd she go?
Home, or her parents
would've killed her.
Where does she live?
No!
She's not even 18, no driver's
license... Son of a bitch!
You have to go, my parents
are on their way home.
Listen... What's your
fucking name?
Bitch, it's 2:00
and that fucking ugly-ass
friend of yours
took my car.
Now you tell me where she lives
and if she has
a fucking phone number!
Calm down,
at this rate you'll die before 40.
I know her.
- Where does she fucking live?
- Near my house, I'll bring you.
- How'll we get there?
- We'll walk.
- It's on the other side of town!
- We'll take a little stroll.
He really did it!
What a bitch!
She even left you the keys,
what more do you want?
And if it had been stolen?
I'm going.
Well, I'll go with you.
We'll smoke one more joint,
just for the hell of it.
You've got another joint?
A crappy one.
She's gonna kick me out this time,
I can feel it.
It's over.
Poor woman!
Was she strangled?
Probably by a manic.
No one is safe anymore,
not even here.
Not bad, Infante!
Dear Zanardi,
rules exist that forbid us
from believing in miracles.
It's crazy to believe that you
can suddenly become cultured
if you've never read a book,
or become respected if you've
always behaved unjustly.
These are miracles
that can't happen.
Just like the outcome of
yellow and blue is green,
not pink or brown.
Green is mathematical.
Remember it.
We should celebrate,
let's go get fucked up.
Wanna get high?
Where will we get the stuff?
You thought I was stupid enough
to leave it in the phone book?
Enough paranoia!
If she dumps me, it's the end,
no more car or house.
All I'll have is this jacket,
these pants
and I'll be a bum in the streets.
Fuck, be careful!
Why did I have to run into you?
Damn me and the moment
I ran into you!
Damn it!
Are you going to pass me
the fucking joint?
Yes or no?
I only took one hit.
Pass it to me!
Wait!
You gonna kill it or I will?
I will.
NEVER GO BACK NOT EVEN
TO GET A RUNNING START
It's four.
Ringo's sleeping,
Gianna's sleeping,
so is Matteo,
I'm not.
Totally stoned,
but alert as a killer.
I'm not relaxed at all.
Actually, all the opposite, I'm
like a hundred meter sprinter.
I have to relax.
I'll get up and make myself
a triple dose of chamomile.
I'll get up now.
I'll get up on three...
What if I smoke a joint instead?
Smoke a joint and jerk off,
that way I'll get up.
Okay, I won't get up anymore.
I need to stay lying down,
and live this deadlock.