Part 24
EUNPO BORDER
NAKRANG TERRlTORY
LAHEE / Princess of Nakrang
Send a message to the palace.
lnform the king
that Goguryeo has invaded us
and request an army.
Yes Your Highness.
EUNPO BORDER
GOGURYEO TERRlTORY
What's that?
CHA CHASUNG
They're sending
smoke signals to warn war.
JAMYUNG
But this is Nakrang territory.
Goguryeo is far away.
Their army will come.
TAECHU
lt'll be difficult to
capture Princess Nakrang alive.
She's shielded.
PRlNCE HODONG
l have to capture
Princess Nakrang alive
and take herto Guknae palace.
lt is the king's order
as well as the purpose
of this battle.
Your Majesty.
WANG JA-SlL
We'll discard the carriage.
l can't let myself be
a burden on Nakrang.
Look overthere
Your Highness!
BUDAL / Second general
Your Highness you leave the border.
Do you regard me as just a girl
or as your crown princess?
HA HOGAE / Soldier
The queen is waiting foryou!
Do any of you know
Sun Tzu's ''The Art of War''
and learned sword fighting
from the king himself?
Your Highness!
l'll not abandon Eunpo.
SUAK
6 miles from Eunpo Gate
Watch that area.
DO SUGl
Do not let down
your guard for a minute.
CHlSO
Only l prepare
the queen's food.
MO YANGHAE
Bring more rice.
At least two rice balls
for each soldier.
l'll wait forthe
crown princess here.
WANG HOL
l'll leave Do Sugi
and the troops behind.
l'll send a messenger if
danger is on the way.
lf that happens don't look back.
Return to the palace immediately.
Great General!
Go ahead without me.
Yes sir.
Find a chance to
get rid of Jamyung.
How can you say such a thing?
We're at war now.
She went running to
Hodong's side the minute
she heard the war
broke out.
She'll side with Goguryeo
if we let her live.
Hol!
Bring Puku.
Time is of the essence.
How can you.
Bring me Jamyung.
You.
knew?
Just because l've grown
attached to you
as my husband and
brother-in-law
doesn't mean l've forgotten
my vendetta against Jasil.
Sister-in-law.
You want to do your
filial duty to me?
lf you don't want to
see me dead
you must bring
Jamyung back alive.
NAKRANG WAGNGEOM LOOKOUT
RYU Jl Minister
DOCHAL Minister
The smoke signals came up
simultaneously from Mukbang
Minbong Algi and Eunpo.
CHOl Ll
Who's the enemy leader?
How many Goguryeo
troops were mobilized?
We'll learn the details
when a messenger arrives.
There was no news
from our spy that
SPY
the five tribes agreed
to the war.
And there was no news of
any movement of theirtroops.
Then why would Muhyul
invade us?
lt's probably revenge for
breaking the talk of marriage.
We must send an army to
bring the princess back.
The Crown Princess is
not a fragile flower.
lf she can't lead her army
on battlefields
she can't become
the Queen of Nakrang.
MOBYUNGHACHlK
King's order to mobilize troop
l'll summon the army.
Summon 700 troops each from Algi
Minbong Mukbang and Eunpo.
l'll obey your command
Your Majesty.
GOGURYEO GUKNAE PALACE
What's holding
the four battlefields?
EUL DUJl / Officer of Right
lt wouldn't be easy for General
Wu to defeat General Majo
who's defending Mukbang.
And since capturing
a hostage alive
is much harderthan killing one
the prince will be having
a hard time in Eunpo.
KlNG DAEMUSHlN
l know that.
We've been eating and
sleeping on horseback.
Ourtroops are different
from Choi Li's lazy bums.
Why can't they sneak up and
bring them down
in one fell sweep?
Your Majesty
we have a message from
our spy in Jinyang Palace.
Speak.
CHU BALSO / Envoy for southern district
Choi Li summoned the
armies from the four prefectures
and sent them
to the four borders.
Why that treacherous man.
Liu Xian / Former King of
Nakrang Commandery
He's become a cunning
strategist after
Liu Xian / Former King of
Nakrang Commandery
for a decade.
l didn't expect him to
retaliate so quickly.
We must send reinforcements
to the prince.
No.
Choi Li's army will get there
first even if we send them now.
Hodong will win somehow.
He'll be victorious in Eunpo
and bring Choi Li's daughter back.
EUNPO GATE
GOGURYEO TERRlTORY
We must buy time until the
reinforcements arrive.
There's only one strategy
Goguryeo will employ
when they're outnumbered.
An all-out attack.
How can we buy time when
they swarm over us like bees?
What happened?
BUDAL / Second General in command
BU TUNG / Lieutenant
The corpses of ourtroops
and those of Goguryeo have
piled up like a mountain.
Ourtroops can't
march forward
with the corpses in the way.
Food supply is a
bigger problem.
Our men need to be fed.
Captain take Butung and
go to the Goguryeo camp.
Yes Your Highness.
EUNPO GATE
GOGURYEO TERRlTORY
We have a message from the
Crown Princess of Nakrang.
Speak.
Son you read it.
Mountains of dead troops
of both Goguryeo and
Nakrang have
rendered us immobile.
l propose two-hour of truce.
l wish we both have
time to clear away the corpses
move the wounded
and feed the soldiers.
You just want to buy time
until your reinforcements arrive.
Walk overthe corpses if
that's what you want.
Your men trip over dead bodies
but you won't even help
the wounded and
pick up the dead?
You vulgar jerks.
Like father like son.
They sent a couple of
ignoramuses as messengers.
l'm old enough to be
yourfatheryou punk.
We'll accept the crown
princess's proposal.
No Your Highness.
We'll resume fighting
in two hours.
Feed the troops collect the dead
and bring back the wounded.
Why did you agree to it.
You know she's just
trying to buy time.
l also need time.
Here take these.
MlCHU
Make sure you eat some too.
SOSO
Eat up.
This way.
Can you do it?
Yes Your Highness.
We're trained
in acrobatics.
Casting a net is
a piece of cake.
l'm ready to give up my life
foryou for saving Puku's life.
Thank you.
Cha Chasung but you're not
from Goguryeo.
And Hangkai
you're from Nakrang.
l must give you
a great burden.
You'll be seated among my
counsel the day l become king.
You're most gracious
Your Highness.
Your Highness arrows from the
Yeonna tribe have arrived.
All right.
Select the best and the
strongest archers we have.
Yes Your Highness.
Prince.
Do as exactly as you are told.
Yes Your Highness.
You may leave.
No more tighter.
Do we have to go
to battle too?
Boss.
lLPUM
You can leave with Michu.
l'll pay him back
for saving Puku.
l'm not staying
here just for Puku.
We're in a horrific
blood-drenched battle
but l feel as if l've
finally become a man.
Cha Chasung.
l thought my life was about
doing circus acts and
selling laughter.
Michu l want to live
like a real man too.
Can't we just live a
quiet long life?
But that's how we've lived
until now quiet like a mouse.
l may not become
the great general
but l want to be called
''general'' at least once.
Please let me make something
of myself before l die.
Honey.
People are looking.
l may never be able
to go to Nakrang.
Yes.
Since you killed
a Nakrang warrior
you may never be
allowed on their land.
l'm sorry Puku.
Because of me.
You'll regret it for
the rest of your life.
Let me help you capture
Princess Nakrang alive.
No.
More Nakrang
troops are coming.
lf you don't capture
Princess Nakrang
you'll never leave this place.
What man would let his woman
hold a sword and smell blood?
What kind of woman
do you want me to be?
l haven't thought about it.
You want me sitting
pretty in a garden
wearing silk robes and draped
in jewelry waiting foryou?
That sounds good too.
lt would be nice to
see you in that.
You told me this in Simbeon.
lt's important to
know who you are
but it's also important to
know your purpose in life.
Yes.
Maybe meeting you.
sharing your pain
is my purpose in life.
l came back because my
present with you is more
important than
finding out who l am.
Puku.
l'm not a woman who
can benefit Goguryeo.
satisfies a man's lust.
l want to be someone.
who shares
everything with you
even death
The two hours are up.
Drink this.
The feathers
were cut in half.
lt'll add to theirflight
but the arrows
could lose balance
and miss yourtargets.
Wait for a north wind and
aim a few inches above target.
You must aim and kill the
crown princess's guards.
Yes Your Highness.
Your Highness.
Our prince challenges the
Crown Princess of Nakrang.
Has Prince Hodong
gone crazy?
Will the Crown Princess
of Nakrang
who'll succeed the throne
cower before a challenge?
Are you Princess Nakrang
only capable of adorning
yourself and playing a lute?
How do Nakrang army
serve such princess?
l'll cut off his head!
Stay calm!
He means to aggravate
you with insults.
Don't fall for it.
l know.
l won't fall for such
a childish trick.
With no future
for Nakrang
you should admit defeat
and save your own lives.
There will be ten rounds
but our prince will concede
three of them leaving seven.
lf you even so much as slash
his robe during the seven rounds
he'll apologize and
withdraw from the battle.
Challenge!
Your Highness
we the troops of Nakrang
wish to see your skills.
Shut up.
You dare doubt our
princess's skill?
We have nothing to lose
since Goguryeo will
concede three rounds.
Give my message
to your prince.
Prince Hodong had a match
with our Great General once
but it was a draw.
lf he can defeat
the Great General
l'll accept his challenge.
She fell for it.
We'll signal you when we succeed.
North wind.
Budal, Butung!
Wipe out their archers!
Yes Your Highness.
Protect the crown princess!
Those rats.
Your Highness.
l'm sorry
l couldn't protect you
Just what are you?
l'm the bodyguard of Goguryeo
who was abandoned by Nakrang.
What? You're from Nakrang?
How can a girl
become a bodyguard?
Maybe Prince Hodong
has feelings for her.
Are you Hodong's woman?
Ask the prince yourself.
Awoman of Nakrang will
abandon her country for a man
and kill her own countrymen?
l'll neverforgive you.
The prince's army has
retreated safely.
Really?
Then we'll go to
Bukyang as promised.
JlNYANG PALACE NAKRANG
Please kill us forfailing
to protect the crown princess
and our border!
Your Majesty
please kill us.
l, Wang Hol, seek punishment.
Please cut off my head
and set it as an example
so that Nakrang will never suffer
such an insult again!
Your Majesty
please give us death!
Please give us death!
MO HASO
What have you done?
l didn't know
this would happen.
Who gave you permission to
break the talk of marriage
without the king's permission?
Do you not know that
only l have the right
to decide the crown
princess's future?
Then you should've
gone to Goguryeo.
What?
Neitherthe King nor
the Queen of Goguryeo
were in their right minds.
l put a stop to this
marriage because
l was afraid Lahee would
end up dead or crazy
if she enters such marriage.
Jasil.
lt doesn't matter if
you hold the title.
lt doesn't change the fact that
you're not her birthmother.
700 Nakrang troops were
killed in this war
and more than 400 were
seriously wounded.
What about our casualties?
A little more than 300
troops were killed and.
Less than 200 were injured.
We have captured 2500
of Nakrang people
building the fortress.
1300 were taken by the Hwanna and
Gwanna tribes as spoils of war.
Your Majesty.
What is it?
General Wu is returning to the
palace with 1200 prisoners.
l have to hand it to Wu Naru.
l heard he was injured
fighting Majo.
l assume he's fine.
Your Majesty ljust
received a message that
the prince will arrive
at Bukyang shortly
with the Princess
of Nakrang in captive.
l told you
Hodong could do it!
He's not only the best
swordsman in Goguryeo
he's now the best
strategist as well.
How shall we receive
Choi Li's daughter?
She's a hostage but
she'll marry our prince.
We should receive
her accordingly.
l agree.
She'll be Hodong's wife
and my daughter-in-law.
Give Choi Li's daughter
a grand welcome.
BUKYANG OUTSKlRTS
OF GUKNAE PALACE
Congratulations Prince.
You have done well.
Now you're a step closer
to becoming crown prince.
Aunt why did you
trouble yourself?
YEORANG
l had to greet your wife.
There she is.
Prin...
What's the meaning of.
Hodong doesn't know
anything about women.
l apologize Princess.
l'm grateful
l wasn't dragged by a horse
with a chain around my neck.
How can you say such.
You're not a prisoner.
You're here as our guest.
As Hodong's princess.
Please appease your anger.
Your Highness.
Come in.
A man from your
house brought these.
He got here quickly.
Put them on the table.
Yes.
Please wearthese until we
can make you new clothes.
They're mine.
And wearthese for now.
My brother will spare no jewelry
for his eldest daughter-in-law.
lt's all right.
lt is all right.
l had promised Hodong jewelry
and makeup as wedding gifts.
My people were
brought here as prisoners.
l'm not so clueless
that l'd adorn myself with
Goguryeo clothes and jewelry
in such situation.
Well if you'd rather stay in
your bloodstained clothes.
lf you'll bring me
some water
l'll wash my bloodstains
off my hands.
All right.
Bring her some water.
Yes Your Highness.
When he was young Hodong
came back from his trip to
Nakrang as an envoy and
told me you had a foul temper.
He was right.
Your Highness.
Who are you to sit at
the prince's table and
share his precious tea?
l'm Puku.
the prince's bodyguard.
You're that Puku?
The girl Hodong brought back
to the palace from Simbeon?
The prince took care of
me when l was ill.
l heard that
Queen Maeseolsu gave you
to the Great General
of Nakrang as a gift.
That's correct.
And how are you
so well informed?
There are no secrets
in the palace.
Then you must know.
Puku is my friend and
my woman.
What do you see in
this skinny girl?
Leave us.
Yes Your Highness.
You're to take the Princess
of Nakrang as your bride soon.
You can have many girls
like her after
you become crown prince.
l'll marry Princess Nakrang
forthe sake of Goguryeo
but it's none of your concern
what l do with Puku.
Hodong.
l'm exhausted.
At least once a day
l want to smile like the others.
At least once a day.
l want to feel how happy
to be alive and breathing.
And only she can
do that foryou?
Yes.
Where is Puku from?
She grew up in Dongmohyun
but she's originally from Nakrang.
Nakrang?
Haven't you learned
your lesson?
You've suffered
more than enough
because your birthmother
was from Buyeo.
l'm happy enough that she's
not from the Biryuna tribe.
They say that a hero is
rendered powerless by beauty.
l'm afraid
a girl will ruin you.
GUKNAE PALACE GOGURYEO
Please don't frown.
Smile forthem.
They're your people.
Why are they my people?
Just as the people of
Nakrang are my people
the people of Goguryeo
are your people.
Treat them with kindness.
ls that why you killed
troops of Nakrang and
brought me here?
Your mother was the
one who started this.
Nonsense.
lf l hadn't gone through
trouble to bring you here
your mother would have
taken you away from me and
given you to Wang Hol.
Prince Hodong.
Let's not argue.
Our people are watching.
Why aren't you
with the prince?
Palace life seems
so complicated.
l think l'll only be a
burden to the prince.
They must be
Nakrang people.
They are with
General Wu Naru.
They must be prisoners
captured at Mukbang.
Nakrang has done
nothing for us.
We can't even call
it our motherland.
We've come this far.
Let's forget
we're from Nakrang.
Puku.
Your Majesty!
Please punish us with death!
Save your heads
hands and feet
and use them to conquer
Goguryeo someday!
Your Majesty!
Come to my chamber.
Send an envoy to Muhyul and
find out what his terms are
forthe release
of the crown princess.
Also forthe release
of our people.
They took the crown princess
to Guknae Palace.
lt seems they'll force her
to marry Prince Hodong.
That can't happen!
Our people will not
acknowledge her as queen
if she is forced to
marry the enemy prince.
lt's their ploy to snatch up
Nakrang with princess
on their back.
l'll meet with
Muhyul myself.
Your Majesty.
l'll meet him at the
border of Eunpo.
Do whatever is necessary
to bring Muhyul to Eunpo.
YOUNGANJUN
JlNYANG PALACE NAKRANG
l'll send Donggobi along
YOUNGANJUN
JlNYANG PALACE NAKRANG
with the messenger.
We need to send her some
clothes and a maid.
She can't lose her dignity
in the Goguryeo palace.
All right.
What will you do
if the King of Goguryeo won't
release the princess?
l'm afraid our people
will turn away from her
if she's forced to marry.
Jamyung.
Only if Jamyung is alive.
What are you saying?
Will you forsake Lahee?
l'll save her.
l'll bring her back to you.
l'll stop Muhyul from
marrying her off to Hodong.
But why are you
bringing up Jamyung?
A king must prepare
forthe worst.
l have to have an
alternate plan.
Your Majesty.
The best thing is to bring
Lahee back but if we can't.
lf Jamyung is alive
l'll find her and
make her crown princess.
And if Jamyung
is not alive
the Great General
will succeed me.
QUEEN JASlL'S CHAMBER
What?
He'll do what if
Jamyung is alive?
He'll make her
crown princess?
CHlSO
Things have gotten out of hand
since you broke
the talk of marriage.
lt's a bridge we must
cross sooner or later.
But l had no idea Lahee
would be captured.
lf she's forced to marry
Princess Jamyung will
become crown princess.
Never.
Jamyung is Hodong's woman.
And she killed General Ha Hogae
and Captain Takchi in Eunpo.
l've heard as well.
Who is Ha Hogae?
He's the king's most loyal retainer
and a meritorious subject.
How can the princess
who turned against her country
become crown princess
and queen?
You're right.
How can anyone
accept her?
Lahee may be captured
but Heaven is on my side.
Jamyung put a noose
around her own neck.
l Do Chal write this
letter to Queen Jasil for
DOCHAL / Minister
the sake of the future of
the crown princess
and Nakrang.
Lady Mo is already aware
that Princess Jamyung
Queen Mo Haso's
daughter is alive.
What brings you here?
Lady Mo is looking foryou.
But why were you so startled?
lt's nothing.
Let's go.
BUDAL / Second general
Are you having an affair?
Are you writing a love
letterto some wench?
Give that to me.
Princess Jamyung
Lady Mo
Queen Jasil.
l may not know
how to read well
but l have an idea
what this letter says.
Sugi!
Ready the horses!
Yes!
Father!
Father.
l'm all right.
l'll alert the great general.
Master will help you.
Father
what has he done wrong?
A slave who betrays
his master must die!
Let's go.
Bring him in!
l didn't miss your heart
because l'm too old to shoot.
l know that My Lady.
lt is so that l could ask
you if you betrayed me
the late general
and Younghojangwon
for a taste of power.
Speak.
Princess Jamyung killed
General Ha Hogae and Takchi.
How can we make such a
person crown princess?
That is none of
your concern!
A king's life can't be
compared to a thousand of
his subjects' lives
or even tens of thousands.
Killing them is
no matter.
Nakrang must unite
against Goguryeo.
Nakrang will collapse if
the two princesses fight
overthe throne.
You arrogant.
My Lady.
Where is Sister-in-law?
She's inside but she
said to let no one in.
Sister-in-law!
lt is Hol!
Open the door!
Since you seem to have a
reason foryour betrayal
l won't stain my hands
with your blood.
Kill yourself!
Sister-in-law
l'll knock this door down
if you don't open it!
What's keeping you?
Are you trying to beg your
masterforyour life?
My Lady l'm off to see the general.
Please live a long life.
Do Chal!
Father!
Master.
Please protect our lady
and Nakrang.
Father.
l deserve to die.
Don't be sad.
Serve our lady and
Master.
Father!
Yourfather was a great
retainer of Younghojangwon.
Give him a funeral befitting
his status as a minister.
Yes My Lady.
Sister-in-law!
lt doesn't matter
who becomes king.
Forthe sake of Nakrang?
Don't give me that nonsense.
You haven't changed a bit
since you shot that
fire arrow at Sister.
Whether it's Jamyung
Lahee oryou that becomes king
do you think people
will care?
lt would have
been the same
if our general had become
king instead of Choi Li.
Sister-in-law!
ls anyone born
to become king?
No you brat.
The powerful man
becomes king
and the weak one
gets trampled.
Unless he were crazy
any king would want to
provide for his people.
A king can't exist when
his kingdom is in distress!
He'll die with his people!
Why don't you know that?
Hol.
Since you're the great general
you live forthe
Kingdom of Nakrang.
l'll live for our
general's revenge.
GUEST CHAMBER
GUKNAE PALACE GOGURYEO
The queen has invited you to tea.
The prince wants to
have lunch with you.
LAHEE / Princess of Nakrang
Who'd have known
the Princess of
Nakrang would
be so popular in the
Goguryeo palace?
Princess of Nakrang l
come from the king's chamber.
May l come in?
Sir.
What is it?
The king wishes to see you.
All right.
What's wrong with her now?
Puku.
She still has poison
left in her body.
ls it because she overexerted
herself at Eunpo?
ls she worried about
Princess Nakrang?
l don't think so.
We saw Nakrang prisoners
on our way back.
And?
She's been upset ever since.
Puku.
What?
You saw that woman who stabbed
you with the coral hairpin again?
No.
lt is l Puku.
Come in.
l was about to go see you.
Prince do you
believe in dreams?
Like seeing your
future in dreams.
You saw the future?
l think so.
lt was no ordinary dream.
l could sense that the
images in my dream
were things l'll
face in the future.
l don't know
but coming from you
l'll believe it.
You've opened your
energy channels.
Don't tease me.
Were you happy with
me in your dream?
Were our children playing?
Don't tease me.
What was it?
On a vast field l was standing
alone with a sword.
l saw hundreds of troops running
toward me from a distance.
What was l trying
to protect?
lt's so frustrating.
Why are you frustrated?
lt's easy.
The enemies were
my enemies
maybe the Biryuna tribe,
Liaodong or Xuantu.
And just as you protected
me in Simbeon and Eunpo
will you protect me for
the rest of your life?
So you'll depend on me for
Why?
Do you not like it?
You don't like a weak man?
Well if that's my fate.
lt'd be nice
if my fate were to protect
you and Goguryeo but.
l have to go see Father.
QUEEN MAESEOLSU'S CHAMBER
The king summoned the
Princess of Nakrang.
l know.
SONG MAESEOULSU
l'm on my way as well.
YANGDEOK
Your Majesty
did you know that Puku
the girl you had given to
the Great General of Nakrang
came back?
Did she?
l saw her with my own eyes
at the prince's chamber.
She is Hodong's woman.
lt seems that way.
The Queen of Nakrang
wanted her as well.
She seems to be very useful.
Keep an eye on
her at all times.
The Crown Princess
of Nakrang is here.
Greetings Your Majesties.
Welcome.
Welcome Princess.
General Wu Naru couldn't
stop praising your beauty.
And he was right.
Your attire.
l've sent you some
clothes a few times.
l was taken from
the battlefield.
lt is only natural that a
prisoner is still in her armor.
Did you call for me?
Be seated both of you.
Let me offeryou my
congratulations before l sit down.
l had once asked the
prince to relay my message
to the queen wishing her
safe birth of a healthy prince.
Did you give
herthe message?
l couldn't.
l knew you'd be delivering
the message in person.
You must be happy to have
given birth to Prince Haeaewu.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
We should set
the wedding date.
The soonerthe better.
As you wish.
Be it tomorrow orthe day
aftertomorrow
the date is of
no significance.
The King of Nakrang
cherishes his people.
He wouldn't forsake his
people for his child.
So?
lf l'm forced to marry
he'll take the title of
crown princess away from me.
Do you really think so?
When he has no
other child but you?
Although he's not his child
he has General Wang Hol.
Princess our wedding was
already under discussion.
He has no reason to take your
title of crown princess away
even if you marry me.
CHOl Ll'S OFFlCE
JlNYANG PALACE NAKRANG
l'm done packing for
the princess in Goguryeo.
Very well.
lf l weren't crown princess
l'd have no reason to live.
Pack this among herthings.
What is the
meaning of this?
The princess our Lahee
wouldn't go on living
if she weren't crown princess.
No. That can't happen.
l decide herfuture.
Muhyul will demand
things l cannot accept.
l can't have Lahee insulted
and living in Goguryeo
or have her become
a burden to Nakrang.
Lahee will understand
the meaning of this dagger.
Your Majesty even if l were
to marry Prince Hodong
l'd have nothing
to offer Goguryeo.
lf you can't bring anything
l'll take what l need from
Choi Li, yourfather!
lt is of no concern to you.