Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
In this period of economic growth...
...the construction of a European
highway network...
...is very relevant.
Mr Roubier, the well-known
French representative...
...has joined us to elaborate
on his views regarding this matter.
Mr Roubier, please tell us...
...whether you will also negotiate with
the Italians about this contract.
No, sir. A French company
is already on it.
And I'm not in the habit of
thwarting my competitors.
Will you limit yourself to France?
Yes, and I'm proud of it, sir.
For this project,
people will have to be evicted.
Or is that a rumour?
-I know what you're trying to say.
A couple of bungalows
won't stop progress.
I think general interest is more
important than private interest.
In the meantime, in San Remo,
in contrast with what he said...
...Henri Roubier, the opportunistic
business man...
...stole from his competitor,
Lejeune & Co., the order...
...for the construction of a
European highway network.
In his usual discrete and
energetic manner...
...he secretly obtained...
...the approval of initiator
Enrico Mazzini.
This news just came in...
Highways: customs personnel
continue their protests.
We'll discuss this in our studio with...
...Mr Lejeune and his partners.
They will inform us about their project
to build a European highway network.
When will you negotiate with
Mr Mazzini?
Right away.
Since Roubier, our competitor...
...was good enough to retire
from this project.
At the first opportunity we'll get...
...we'll show him how grateful we are.
PERCHED ON A TREE
Bastard.
What's that?
What's happening?
What's going on?
Wait a minute.
What's happening?
-The truck drivers are on strike.
Why are you on strike?
We're protesting against the customs
officers, because they're on strike.
So what?
-They're on strike because we are.
What are you doing?
Come on, get out.
-Wait, I need to have a rest.
You tried to run me over.
-What?
You almost did.
-Come on, out!
Attempted murder, premeditated.
The police will take this
very seriously.
What?
-Where are you going?
Out.
-No need to tell me.
I love surprises.
Oh sir, that's great.
Your friend told me everything.
I don't know how to thank you.
So you're going to Cassis as well?
I'm not going to Cassis at all.
-Yes, you are. Remember? Cassis?
I'm not going to Cassis.
-Yes, you are, You are.
Not at all. Oh no...
You'll say it's bad but
it's stronger than me.
When I want to gamble, I have to do it.
My husband forbids me to go
to any of the casinos in France.
So I'm using this opportunity to go
on a business trip to San Remo.
Serves him right.
Forbids! Forbidding
should be forbidden.
Cut it out.
-My husband's very old-fashioned.
He's wrong. Life's one big game.
It's a matter of being
lucky or not.
What do you say, Mr Roubier?
-Are you Roubier? How terrible.
An industrialist like you.
A politician.
You presented your own book on TV:
"I Did It On My Own".
It was ridiculous and
pompous.
Nobody does it on their own.
In life, you're lucky or unlucky.
Life's about making an effort.
Will power...
...work.
There's no such thing as bad luck.
Hello, sir.
-Who are you?
I don't know. And you?
I don't know.
But what are you doing in my bed?
-I don't know.
And what's she doing here?
She's also in my bed.
Is she your wife?
-No, she's your wife.
No, my wife is like this...
But what are you two doing in my bed?
That's mine.
I say.
But where are we?
Where are we?
We were driving on the road.
-How do you know?
The bend.
Yes, I remember.
The bend. I went like this...
What a fright. What a fright.
You're right.
Do you think... I'm crazy
to ask you...
...but we're not dead, do you think?
I don't think so.
Then I don't understand.
Where are we? Where?
Where on earth are we?
I'll have a look.
Don't move. Don't move.
This is dangerous.
Is it me or are we swaying?
We're balancing.
We're swaying a lot.
Where on earth are we?
What shall we do?
No, we were doing fine.
Don't move. Don't move.
Never mind. We're alright like this.
We shouldn't ask for too much.
Now what do we do?
It's best to wait until
daylight.
And most of all, let's not move.
Don't move an inch.
Don't move.
-No, no. It's cold.
There's a draft.
What are you doing?
Very carefully. Don't move.
Like that. No, no.
Don't move.
We landed on a tree.
It's better to land on a tree
than to hit it.
See that luck exists?
You're right.
As long as the mistral doesn't start.
God bless.
Thank you.
-I didn't say that for you.
When she wakes up, we'll
have to be very careful.
What shall we tell her?
That we wanted to enjoy
the view.
Do you hear that?
They're looking for us.
Stupid animal.
Here, here. No, not there.
Are we there yet?
Did we arrive?
Yes, we're just getting out.
Quidou?
But Quidou.
-I'll go there.
What are you doing there?
My poor Quidou.
I want to get out!
I want to go!
I want to get out.
Who are you?
-It's me. Don't you recognise me?
No.
-Look, look. See?
No, it's him.
Still the same.
It's him. There.
Quidou?
Where is he?
-Quidou?
It was so quiet here.
Let her be.
She'll calm down.
-What do you mean, calm?
Yes, she'll calm down.
-Of course she will.
Have you got something to drink?
-Yes, water.
Now he's going nuts.
Calm down. Calm down.
Calm down, please.
You're not leaving, are you?
The water.
Calming, relaxing.
The ideal remedy for
the overwrought business man.
Yes, I'm going.
What happened to me?
Nothing, you just fainted.
Nothing serious.
Drink this. It'll do you good.
You'll see.
Where are we?
We're here.
Everyone's here.
Feeling better?
Oh, yes.
Really?
-Oh, yes.
You're taking a nap.
So we have some peace and quiet.
Right, since the car's
quite stable...
...let's think about what
our options are.
Every problem has a solution,
every solution...
So we could just stay here
and starve to death.
No, somebody important like you.
It would be noticed.
They're looking for you right now.
That's impossible, because I was
travelling incognito.
I was working on a billion
dollar deal.
And now you're on a tree.
I'm meeting the minister
at 11 am.
What time is it now?
Oh, there's plenty of time.
I'm getting out. I'm going.
-This belongs to you.
What's that?
-It belongs to you.
Oh, yes, it does.
It's mine.
Help! Help!
Help!
Hot record!
-Where?
Is the car getting hot?
Do you want to dance?
-She's gone insane.
What's hot? Stop, stop.
It's breaking.
Look, look. This is a disaster.
This is a disaster.
How do you want to get out?
What a disaster.
We're doomed.
The truth is we're already dead.
No, come here.
Reality's here. There.
Oh, how beautiful!
This is magnificent.
Come, let's fly.
I'll fly.
What are you doing?
I'll smack you.
Sit down. I'll smack you.
-Why?
We're not going to fly.
-But you're all...
That's it for today.
You stay here. Like it or not.
With us.
You're not very nice.
You won't let me do anything.
-I'll smack you.
I can't dance,
I can't fly.
I woke up for nothing.
Listen, now that we're a bit
stable again...
Hey, do you have to do that?
Be patient. Not right away.
No, or else I leave.
Choose. She or me.
Listen, now that we're
a bit stable again...
...we need to think about
what we're going to do.
Each problem has its solution,
each solution...
I already know. We can
only wait and starve to death.
For me, for me.
-No.
Enough.
-Thanks.
For me, for me.
Sir, I'm sorry about earlier.
You couldn't know, but I'm
a very sensitive woman.
Suddenly finding yourself on top
of a parasol is a shock.
It's alright.
-I'm calm again.
I even feel fine.
I think this adventure
is quite poetic.
Anyway, I don't regret
a thing.
Me neither.
Really, not at all.
-Quidou, Quidou, he ate everything.
He ate everything. Good.
-That's not so bad, is it?
There he is. Smack him.
-Yes, right.
Good.
I hope your husband's
not worried.
He thinks I'm cheating anyway.
He won't believe I spent the
night in a tree.
Is he jealous?
Oh là là. No, he's
an admirable man.
But I don't like him.
He's a bit like you.
Well, I say.
-Yes.
He's very ambitious, but he has
no sense of humour. Just like you.
I beg your pardon.
I only saw my husband laugh once.
Yes, I saw him laugh on TV.
It was about your election campaign.
Have you gone mad?
-It was about your election campaign.
I'm leaving.
We were cracking up and forgot all
about the movie they showed afterwards.
I'm leaving.
He was great.
Did you see it too?
Don't get angry.
What happened to
Henri Roubier?
That's a mystery at the moment.
Was he so overworked that
he lost his memory?
Has he gone insane?
Did he commit suicide?
Did he work for a foreign power?
What an idiot.
-Has he been kidnapped?
We interviewed Mrs Rombier
at her home.
Mrs Rombier?
I just know my husband hasn't
strayed from the right path.
His name is not on any list
of traffic victims...
...so I came to the conclusion
that he has been kidnapped.
Whoever you are...
...I forgive you.
But I beg you to
spare my husband's life.
Give him back to us alive.
I'm still alive.
No matter what the ransom is...
...we'll pay it.
Oh, no. Don't pay!
Henri Roubier. Yes, a man
who did everything on his own.
In a time when many authors
produce hollow words...
...Henri Roubier's message
spoke of actions.
I Did It On My Own,
a real manual for success...
...was awarded because of its
effectiveness.
I Did It On My Own is about
a man who started with nothing.
The author says: Yes, I
started with nothing.
I started as a cyclist. This sport
teaches you to be energetic.
A lesson in loyalty and fair play.
Sport stimulates the
noble side of people.
It teaches you to act
without cheating.
My life as a business man...
...was always a reflection of
my sports career.
What a report.
Henri Roubier married rich banker's
daughter Marval de Beaufort.
This beautiful love story
incited a lot of jealousy.
Roubier says that
money isn't everything...
...but that it should also not be an
obstacle for a lover and business man.
He quickly made fame as the
self-made man of asphalt.
My first highway was
my first victory, wrote Roubier.
Of course, Henri Roubier
went into politics.
I'm not in politics to do
business, but...
...to defend freedom.
I speak to you in the name of freedom,
neither from the right, nor from the left.
I belong to no party.
For me, there is only one party...
...France. And France, that's you.
Everyone who's listening.
But there is no freedom
without highways...
...I mean without authority.
Did you see that?
The latest news.
The escaped maniac, nicknamed
the Camping Vampire...
...has not yet been arrested.
Entertainment. We end this
news broadcast...
...with a scene from Vlasko
Briski's latest movie...
'Waltz of the Vampire'.
It's currently being shown in
cinemas in Paris.
This film is not suited
for young viewers.
I might have picked him up
on the highway.
Just my luck.
Good to see you again.
They're still there.
We're quite comfortable here.
Quite comfortable.
A boat.
-Where?
There!
A boat.
I've got it. Don't move anymore.
This can't have done that.
My God.
"Much later..."
We're doomed.
We're all doomed.
Don't you have anything more to drink?
Anything to eat?
Such a full backpack.
We're dying. We're dying.
Not at all. Not at all.
In India, there are yogis
who don't eat...
...for forty days.
Nothing.
Yes, but they're trained for it.
Maybe.
He's nice and chubby.
This monster wants
to eat my dog.
Good...
...at least I can do some
sunbathing.
I'll die with a nice tan.
Am I giving you any ideas?
Yes, I have an idea.
We're saved.
We're saved. We're saved.
Look. See that tree?
-Which tree?
The tree right underneath us.
If we can get there, we're safe.
Because then we can go
down via those trees.
Did my sunbathing give
you that idea?
Yes, we'll make a rope by
tying our clothes together.
That way, we can get
to the first tree.
And after the first tree?
-What after?
Then we can climb from tree to tree.
And then we'll be free.
Come on.
We're saved. We're saved.
Climb back up.
Good to see you again.
You saved my life.
It was a reflex.
Anyway, that proves
you're not him.
That he's someone else.
Good to see you again.
My skirt.
If they find us half naked
in your car...
...what would my husband think?
He's able to kill all three
of us.
Oh no, I'm sure your husband's very nice.
Very gentle.
He must be a poet. Very nice.
I'd like to meet him
if I'll still be alive.
Ex colonel Müller, husband of
the woman who disappeared...
...is apparently being charged.
Ex colonel Müller is charged with placing
a bomb near the TV station...
...that linked the disappearance
of his wife...
...to industrial Henri Roubier.
Well, I'll be!
See? I wasn't exaggerating.
If you want, I can testify.
-What, testify?
Get the bazooka.
-Cut it out.
If your husband saw us...
We're again talking about the
highways of Gascony.
Mr Lejeune of Lejeune & Co...
...is shocked by the disappearance of
Henri Roubier.
And he assures us that he'll
do all he can...
...to solve this mystery.
A psychic told me I'll die
at the age of 80.
That leaves two possibilities.
Either you're older than you look...
...or the psychic wasn't good at math.
Waiter.
A big glass of water...
...with ice cubes.
Thirsty?
-Perrier
St. Peter, good St. Peter.
Thank you, St. Peter.
Quickly. We have to get
rid of the water.
A bottle in the ocean.
-Where?
No, this bottle. Look.
I'll throw it in with an SOS.
It'll break on the rocks.
Alright, that makes three bottles.
-No, two.
Sorry, but I can count to three.
We only had two.
-And that one?
Listen...
-What, listen?
It's empty, so it was full.
-That doesn't prove anything.
That proves the bottle was
emptied, drunk.
And if it was drunk,
it has to be paid.
Officer, come here please.
I have a small problem with this
gentleman and this lady.
How many bottles do
you see on the table?
Three.
The third one landed with a parachute.
-With a parachute?
With a parachute.
And you'll land at the police station.
It's my car. It went off the road.
In a bend.
Landed on a parasol.
At one kilometre of Cassis.
Good heavens.
I'm warning you.
If this is a hoax...
...you won't have a sunstroke
at the end of your holiday.
There! Up there!
Look, they're all naked.
Come on. Come.
I'll have to inform the chief.
There. There.
When I received your message,
I was on duty of course.
I found the message and then...
You should know how happy we were.
I came closer and I saw
them and I said...
...we have to warn everybody.
Henri Roubier and the wife
of ex colonel Müller...
...had their love nest on the Côte d'Azur.
Excuse me.
We're going live to our
colleagues in Marseille.
I'm at the location of the event.
What a tragedy.
It's terrible. A car on a tree.
You should see it.
You should see it. You should see it.
Hello Marseille. What's happening?
I get no more video.
Alright. It's coming back.
I have video again.
Important business man Henri Roubier
was found half naked...
...with the wife of ex colonel Müller...
...in a car, hanging on a tree.
In the company of a
mysterious man.
Which strange event were they returning
from, so scantily dressed?
Henri Roubier is an excellent driver.
If he lost control at this point...
...he was probably not sober.
Operation Parasol has just started.
I'm told that Operation
Parasol is commencing.
Stay with us and listen.
Hello, hello. Operation
Parasol has started.
Keep your spirits up.
We're coming.
Thanks.
Dear viewers, I'll pass
the microphone.
I've just been told that special experts...
...have arrived in the studio...
...to provide commentary
for Operation Parasol.
Back to Marseille.
-Are they really as good as dead?
I'm afraid so.
The rocks are steep there and
the tree roots have come out in part.
Can't they lower the swing and
get them up one by one?
No, that's no way to
save them.
Why not? Idiot.
-You're about to be rescued.
We're having the Super Puma crane
brought over from Martigues.
But it only does 12 kilometres
per hour.
It will be here in 24 hours.
Everything's fine. Don't worry.
We'll get you out.
And that tree? Can it hold
the weight?
Probably not.
Do you think they're lost?
-It looks bad.
I'm not surprised. The engineer
says there's little they can do.
We can believe him.
What a disaster.
-A huge crash.
My God. My God.
Please give us a miracle.
Hello, hello. Mr Henri Roubier.
Your wife wants to speak to you.
It's touching to see how the family
unites over this tragedy.
They show that their emotions
can be bigger than fate.
Even in bad times.
Mrs Roubier reminds us, with
her restrained grieving...
...that real emotion is silent.
Out of respect for her,
we'll now be silent.
Film this.
She's so beautiful.
Look, she's a real Mater Dolorosa,
painted by the young Goya.
Film this. Zoom in on her tears.
Madam, I'll be silent now.
Make sure you get it.
Madam, I'll be silent.
My darling...
Your device isn't working.
One, two, three.
Press this.
-Alright, thank you.
My darling...
...I've found a place
for my sadness.
I can't judge you.
Only God judges.
I'm innocent.
I'm only here...
...to pay respect to your soul.
You may die soon.
And you live in mortal sin.
At dawn...
...I'll send a priest.
No.
My darling.
Goodbye, my darling.
Lucienne.
Lucienne, where are you?
My darling, where are you?
Come down, Lucienne.
Father Jean-Marie Marval de Beaufort
is among those present.
He's accompanied by his sister,
Mrs Roubier.
Let me remind you that she's
also a Marval de Beaufort.
Father Jean-Marie is listening
to his sister attentively.
And he's leaving the central stage.
No matter which religion or political
conviction we have...
...we cannot but admire the courage
of this priest who's going down...
...to save a soul.
That's the only reason why
he's going down.
This is a fantastic example.
Isn't this the way martyrs
sacrifice themselves?
Why don't you use the swing...
...to get the others up?
Because the swing cannot get close
enough to the car.
The smallest pressure on the trunk...
...will make it snap.
With a crane, you can get to them.
The weight should go
straight onto the car.
Straight, yes.
-They all have to go at the same time.
So they can't go one by one?
No, if you pull one up,
the car would come up.
The tree would snap and you'd
get a huge roller coaster.
Alright, father.
Forgive me, father.
I know you have a pure soul, my son.
I don't.
-Yes, you do.
I was always faithful to my wife.
-That's important to the Lord.
I absolve you.
But I haven't finished.
-Excuse me. I'm going back up.
Don't you have an electric hoist?
-Yes, but it's broken.
He'd rather send others to heaven
than himself.
Anyway, your wife's no longer worried.
Young lady, I hope your husband
is as religious as my wife.
My husband. He's religious alright...
...but in a rather bloody way.
The father seems to think God works
in a mysterious way.
Dear viewers, the reality
of father Jean-Marie...
...who experiences
the beauty of his task...
...invites us to think about the
mystery of life, about love...
...money and the end of our lives.
Ah, the special rope
arrived from Grenoble.
Preparations are ongoing.
Everybody's helping as best they can.
There's an atmosphere of
feverish excitement and caution.
We're all ready.
Well, almost all.
On this highway...
...more than 3000 people died
in 10 years.
One Roubier more or less.
Gentlemen, do not insist.
I gave my word to Henri Roubier.
I do not negotiate with others
while he's still alive.
What if something tragic happens?
We'll discuss that when it happens.
It's just a big advertisement.
A famous person like Roubier
does this for an advertisement?
Some people don't know when to stop.
This isn't candid camera, is it?
But I recognise you,
Mr Jacques Gellogra.
The people in the car seem to have
resigned themselves to their fate.
It takes courage to stay so calm.
Will you vote for him?
If he survives and decides
to run, definitely.
You've seen the car by now.
You can't look any longer.
What if it falls?
This is the most dangerous part
of the rescue operation.
Instead of getting them up,
rescue workers will...
...let them descend towards sea level.
Where divers will be ready to help
in case of any danger.
You will witness the rescue
operation as if you were here.
Hello, can you hear me?
Tie yourselves together.
The main mountaineer will go down
to direct the rescue operation.
He'll hand you a double rope
that will lead you towards the ocean.
Using a double rope in
the classic manner.
Who can still maintain that mountain
climbing is a useless sport?
We've almost reached the moment
when they'll be rescued. The climax.
We'll get back a man strengthened
by today's ordeal.
And if Henri Roubier will decide about the
fate of the country tomorrow...
...at least he'll know that big people
need little people.
He fell down.
Now there are four people in the car.
The tree. The tree might break.
This is terrible.
I can't watch.
Do you remember the police man?
If somebody gets out...
...it'll come up. The lethal roller
coaster. It's terrible.
I can't watch anymore.
So now we have four people in a car.
On top of a tree.
What happened?
It must have been the rope
from Grenoble.
It snapped.
-Into the camera, please.
It must have been rolled up wrong.
Listen.
A helicopter. We'll be rescued.
Our last chance. Our only hope.
One gust of wind and the helicopter
will crush against the rocks.
But let's not get ahead of ourselves.
The helicopter flies like a huge...
...eagle to its nest.
The device that grabs the car has
arrived at the dangerous location.
Dear viewers, we need a miracle.
Yes. No. They can't have lasted
this long and fall to their deaths now?
They must be rescued. I feel... I know
they'll be rescued. I just know it.
The device that grabs the car
is no longer in position.
Two people are hanging above the abyss.
And they're turning
around and around.
A dizzying merry-go-round.
Oh, they're back. It worked.
Thank God.
They're back in the car.
They've been saved.
My heart. This is costing me
years of my life.
Just in time. They're
attaching the cables.
There's a fire. Fire, fire.
The fire brigade.
Fire.
-Attach the last cable.
It can't be true. Such bad luck. Fire.
Gendarme, call the fire brigade.
All resources are being used.
It's great.
The firemen connect the hoses
and assume their positions.
The tree would have been on fire if the
fire brigade hadn't been on the alert.
This family, dignified in their grief...
...deserves to be called 'great'.
They've been saved.
The tree gave in, but their
nerves didn't.
There they are. Saved from
hell, from the abyss.
The rescue operation ends like a
Tale of a Thousand and One Nights.
The flying car. Aladdin's car.
The helicopter flies a victory round.
Yes, it is a real victory round.
They get a big applause.
But what's happening?
The car flies away from the abyss.
The helicopter goes to open sea.
It can't be true.
Have they been kidnapped?
Is this air piracy?
Oh no. This is terrible. Horrible.
You will hear the latest developments
during our news broadcast.
Dear viewers, and you too, officer...
...I think we can say in all fairness:
"Operation Parasol, I was there.'
I did it on my own.