And whisky for me.
Make it a double.
Have you tried this Afghan?
It's great with whisky.
How's being a writer, fun?
It's cool if you're a pro.
But you have to pay to play.
Some guys claim
they can write in a cold-water flat,
with their folks around
and an empty fridge: Bullshit!
Only suckers buy that.
You need a nice environment.
A house in the mountains...
A nice bottle of whisky...
Some cool music...
Music is what you put down on paper.
But writing on music
turns you into a lyricist.
Without music,
I couldn't even sign my name.
You can't blame music for that.
What about other stuff?
You need music for it too?
Listen to the macho man!
Wow, it's the A list!
Shit! Here comes the Joker...
The party's over...
How did he find us?
Okay, you morons.
I had to make a zillion calls
to find out where the action was.
If I ever find the big mouth...
Too late. We were about to go.
No kidding.
Man, I'm in the mood tonight!
You with this grandpa?
Does it bother you?
No, I'm waiting my turn.
For what?
To take our friendship
to a higher plane.
Hi, man.
Don't go sulky.
I like people who can take a joke.
He'll have you
laughing your brains out.
Didn't you know? He's a scream!
But she doesn't appreciate that.
He hangs out with sorry guys.
Let me show you a trick.
How do millionaires smoke?
Like me!
No. Give me the pack.
And the lighter.
I'd like to know
how much you charge.
For what?
To get lost.
What bribe would make you
go to bed early?
About what time?
About now.
My price is one million.
Per night.
Here's two million.
I'm paying in advance
for the next time.
I love doing business
with responsible people.
That's a good one!
The old man's cool!
You have a good night now.
I get it, you're a smart dude...
Now say good bye to everybody,
and off you go, home to bed.
Take your money back.
Lady Di! I'm joking
and your friend's taking it too far.
What joke, you took the money?
Get going!
Mom's waiting for you.
Let him stay...
No!
We don't want to go to bed, do we?
Baby making a scene?
No, he's just leaving.
I'm not going anywhere!
You all suck!
Come on, let's have some fun.
I have to ask you to leave.
Why?
You're disturbing a customer.
Who is he to lay down the law?
If you don't know,
brush up on your reading.
Do I have to show you to your car?
You'll crawl on your knees
to have me back!
I piss on your crummy club!
You pick on me?
I'll have the taxman
on your ass!
I'll close you down!
You'll be on fucking welfare,
you shitheads!
Not here.
There are too many old ladies
spying on us.
Come with me.
You can't come up,
my folks are home.
Otherwise I could?
What do you think?
Would your brother Robert...
be upset if he knew
we were going out?
Why would he be?
He's a bit impulsive.
He might not understand.
Do I ask him about his dates?
That's enough. You have to go.
Don't forget me till next Saturday.
You see her only on Saturdays?
She can't go out during the week.
Models are obsessed
with beauty sleep.
It's for the best. I couldn't handle
seeing her more often.
Money wise or...
I'm a beggar on weekdays
and a prince at weekends.
Your bill, Sir.
Thank you.
Irresistible,
but much too expensive.
The bill?
No, I'm talking about Diana.
Imagine the cost
of a whole week with her.
Based on last Saturday's expenses...
And the bill?
What is this?
I hope it's a mistake!
Robert!
Come here a second.
If they score, I'll kill you!
What?
Just a minute...
I have to catch my breath.
How are things at home?
Fine.
Your sister, how is she?
She's okay.
Speaking of your sister...
I know a girl about her age
and I'd like to give her a present.
I thought I'd ask your advice.
A girl like Diana, for example,
what would she like?
I got it!
You want to get laid!
No, it's just...
If you have a chick you want to bang,
forget the presents!
Take her home,
give her some whisky and bang her.
Jesus,
do I have to teach you everything?
Dismissed.
If you break them,
you're paying them, okay?
Look.
Phone and power bills.
Show the young lady
what we have to pay
out of two lousy pensions.
One more thing...
I've read it. It's poor.
My place is out of the question.
Hotels are vulgar.
Her place, I get Robert.
Where can we go?
No friends?
I've got acquaintances.
They're all married.
And they all live
way below my standards.
Do you mind changing the subject?
Why?
You can't spend the evening
talking about yourself.
It's no fun for your wife,
whoever she may be,
to listen to you
blabbering about some disco queen.
Especially on an anniversary.
What anniversary?
10 years of marriage.
Are you nuts?
We do that every night.
Maybe tonight it's special.
What do you mean?
Maybe I want it to be special.
But...
Maybe it's our 10 day anniversary.
Of working together...
Of me being your wife.
At least
that's what these people think.
So spare me your cheap flings.
Don Pepe can kiss my ass!
Where are you going?
I've got to pee.
You know...
when you bring a girl to your place,
sometimes she asks
where the bathroom is.
So?
So it's good to know where it is.
To be able to find a clean towel,
turn the stereo on...
To have some personal things
here and there...
That's easy.
But I don't have a "here and there"
to take her to.
Talk to Pepe.
He's an understanding guy.
What?
Must I finance your sexcapades?
Open your eyes!
That's the city you live in.
The view is perfect,
beats the top of the Hilton.
See the nobodies passing by?
Millions of nobodies.
When I first saw
your nobody writer face, I thought:
Miruna, coffee!
I thought: This nobody
wants to be somebody.
This guy wants to learn the trade.
Where is that coffee?
There are 3 basic trades
in the world:
Wealth, poverty and sex.
Either of them pays the rent.
But on love and writing
you starve, fool!
You die for free.
The residence is vacant, isn't it?
How narrow minded!
I give him all these profits,
trying to open his eyes to the future.
While he is busy singing serenades!
It's been available since yesterday.
What?
The residence on Autumn Street.
So what?
So it's available.
Is this a conspiracy?
Are you ganging up on me?
When does he need it?
Saturday.
It's early yet.
First I want results.
Back to work!
Don't talk like that to a client!
Do I have to pay for them?
How much they owe?
I'll put down half.
Is it him?
It is!
Who?
That guy who can't pay the bill.
Weird, suddenly he's broke!
And married, too...
Thank you...
Here...
Smoke it like a millionaire.
Don't mock the needy.
It's not nice.
Aren't you ashamed?
Beat it!
Mind your own business!
You live here?
Sing a song for the World Bank,
All the orphans wait in rank
Sing a song for PHARE Fund...
Here.
Thank you, Sir.
Isn't that too much?
I feel sorry for them.
So...
How come it didn't work out?
I spent the day
exploring the house,
setting everything up,
rummaging everywhere.
I filled up the fridge.
One tiny detail slipped my mind.
Let's have some light...
One second
and we'll have some light...
You don't really want
to turn on the lights, do you?
Bad boy!
One second.
Want a drink?
You know what
I like most about you?
No.
You don't show off your money.
Most of the men I ve dated
like to... brag a bit.
They know that a girl
who has looks
can't shop in any cheap store.
I like it when a man is able
to give me a few luxuries,
but he should do it like you,
in style.
Don't you agree?
I do.
Want to go upstairs?
We have music up there, too.
Don't answer.
This is the Filantropica Residence.
Leave your message after the beep.
Ungureanu speaking.
I'd like to rent the house for
Thursday the 13th and Friday the 14th.
I hope the price is still the same.
Call me with confirmation
on 4235617.
It was a mistake!
Don't be silly! Somebody dialed
the wrong number.
Guess who called me yesterday?
The Joker.
He saw you haggling
over the bill in a restaurant.
Who, me?
And you were married, too.
God forbid!
Of course I didn't believe a word.
But now that you brought me
God knows where...
You believe that nutcase?
Whose house is this?
Mine!
It's my house! I live here!
Understand?
This is my writing desk,
my typewriter,
a page from my novel,
a sentence I left unfinished
to be on time for our date...
Domident toothpaste...
Fresh towels...
My built in closet, with my clothes...
The photo album...
What more do you want?
Your number.
Sorry?
Your phone number. I don't have it.
2236877.
Let's call your place
and see who picks up.
It's ringing!
You hear? It's ringing!
Hello? Ovidiu?
Yes!
He is not at home?
I'll call back another time.
Wrong number.
Let me drop you off!
Are you sure it's your car?
Where are you going alone,
at this hour?
Here.
After that, I gave you a call.
You're all the same.
You get dumped
and run back to your wives.
Come on.
Shocked? Since I started with Pepe,
I don't do it anymore.
I changed careers.
Coming, darling?
I bet you've never been
with an experienced woman before.
Otherwise you wouldn't run
after cheap Barbies.
Ready to wake up, Sir?
It's worth opening your eyes
on such a lovely day.
Besides, the publishers
from New York and Paris
are already here with the contracts.
What time is it?
It's 3 pm, sir.
And I'm serving your breakfast...
in bed.
Today it's Sunday, we're free.
You know what I was thinking?
No.
What about taking me to a restaurant?
Super!
That will really be a change.
Let's do it for real!
Drink, eat, the whole works.
Who's paying? I'm flat broke.
Nobody! We take up a collection.
What's our cut?
We don't get a cent!
But we can at least taste
all those delicacies
they put on our bills.
French champagne...
Seafood salad.
Chateaubriand flambé...
Manchurian caviar...
Tenderloin...
Trout in sauce...
Two coffees and dessert...
Exactly 2,700,000 lei.
Radu, Mircea and Alin
are next for the karaoke contest.
Sorry, we don't have that much.
I didn't hear you.
It's too much!
I can leave you my papers,
and come back tomorrow and pay.
Don't give me that crap.
I want to see cash.
And on with the karaoke!
Now we're going to hear
an all time classic.
He's going to kill my husband!
Please calm down!
Wait a minute, let's talk!
Don't worry,
we'll have a talk you and I.
Let's behave like civilized people...
Playing games, smart ass?
You want me to pay
out of my own pocket?
Out of my own pocket?
For you, motherfucker?
Have some more!
Some more?
SAVAGE BEATING
IN FANC Y RESTAU RANT
You could have smiled a little.
The eyes look more convincing
than the mouth.
Not a bad job, though.
Would his mother recognize him?
The "Popescus"?
The most widespread Romanian name.
Don t you recognize my style?
You didn't sign.
I don't sign everything.
How many suckers
were taken in by this story?
Only one, isn't it?
Only one sucker, Miruna?
My sweet, my darling,
my little moustache,
can you leave us alone for a minute?
Yes, your wife was in on it too.
Guess who else.
The waiter.
Of course. And who else?
The voice on the answering machine...
Saturday night...
Ungureanu.
Bingo! You ve just won a color TV!
No joke. Tomorrow evening
you'll be both on live TV.
Who?
Who do you think?
You two, the Popescus!
Face to face with the people,
on ProTV.
Don't count on me.
Unbelievable!
Is nothing moving in here?
Has all activity stopped?
General strike?
Hello! Anybody home?
Mr. Puiutz, our collaboration
has come to an end.
Zorro, stay calm! We have to prepare
tomorrow's broadcast.
We've done two weeks training for this.
There's a lot of money at stake.
But above all, we are going
to create a masterpiece.
Doesn't that word dazzle you,
Mr. Writer? Masterpiece!
You take me for someone else.
Let's set things straight.
My name is not Popescu.
The lady here is not my wife.
I'm not even a real writer,
unfortunately.
I'm just a school teacher
who has to teach his students
masterpieces
of Romanian literature.
Any remarks about my face
and I'll confiscate cell phones.
Be warned.
Take out a blank page.
Draw a margin.
Is Robert Dobrovicescu here?
He's been absent for days. Why?
Can we have a talk?
One second.
"Patriotic sentiment
in the poetry of 1848."
And we work in silence, okay?
I'm listening.
Do us a favor.
If the boy shows up
in the next few days,
give him a message from us.
From us? Meaning?
Doesn't matter. Say two gentlemen.
The important thing is the message.
Listen up.
The Baron is very upset.
He wants the money in three days.
If the boy doesn't show up
with the cash and some apologies...
Life is complex and full of surprises.
I don't get it.
He didn't get it.
Your turn.
The boy trashed a brand new car.
The owner is really upset.
Really upset, that's the message.
He wants money for the damage
and he sent us talk to the boy.
If he plays hide and seek,
we'll find him even in Vladivostok.
And it might be worse.
How much does he owe?
He knows.
He should be a smart kid
and realize that...
life is complex and full of surprises.
He's young and it'd be a shame
to have him crippled...
Or worse...
You never know.
How much money, did you say?
3,000 bucks...
It's the thought that counts,
not the money.
That's enough!
One move and I'll squeeze one off!
God dammit!
You fucking with school?
Write your essays!
Who did that to your face?
Nobody.
If you want revenge,
we'll do it for a minimum charge.
Don't let me see any copying.
3,000 dollars...
Bucescu! The cell phone!
Florin...
Calinescu...
brings you "Scandal of the Day",
talk show of the new millennium!
Tonight, we have three special guests!
Good evening to all of you.
I am Florin Calinescu
and I have to tell you I'm disgusted.
Fed up.
This morning, looking for
some new ideas for the show
I suddenly realized I'm fed up.
I'm sick of politicians,
sick of the Parliament's big talk,
sick of public and political scandals.
Where are the ordinary people
with their everyday problems?
Where are you, people who
watch my show every night?
Let us meet an ordinary couple
who's struggling hard, like you,
like myself,
to pay the huge cost of transition.
And the core of their story
is precisely a bill.
Ladies and gentlemen,
on my right,
Ovidiu and Miruna Popescu.
And on my left,
Mr. George Stanete,
waiter at the Karaoke Club.
He's going to tell us what happened.
Good evening.
Mr. Stanete, could you describe,
in your own words,
the incident that occurred
two days ago?
These two came to the restaurant,
they ate and drank all evening
and then refused to pay
on account
that they had no money.
I can't go to my boss
with an unpaid bill for 2 million lei.
He'd fire me.
So what did you do?
I worked him over a little.
Could we have
a camera on Mr. Popescu?
Is this what you call "a little"?
A little, at first...
Later...
we got heated.
Before hearing
Mr. Popescu's side of the story,
here's the telephone number to call
with your questions and comments.
Please write it down.
Hello, this is ProTV.
That night was
your 10th wedding anniversary.
Yes. My husband had saved
some money for the occasion.
And I insisted we go out.
Usually we can't afford to.
What is your monthly income?
We earn 3 million lei between us.
Where are my glasses?
In 65 years, I've never lost anything.
That's your fault!
Where did you put my glasses?
Remember our 40th anniversary?
I washed your socks
while you were watching Colombo.
Shut up! I'm waiting to go live.
It's a scam!
Come here,
you have to see this!
We ve never had great ambitions.
Maybe we hoped for a better life...
Remember her?
The couple who couldn't pay
at The Polenta.
It's a scam!
Tell us how you first met.
He wrote me a poem...
I was in a crowded tram.
He slipped a piece of paper
into my purse.
I found it when I took out money
to pay the fine: I had no ticket...
I always carry it with me.
"The smile she gave me in that tram
Was shining with a million lies,
"My life became a traffic jam
"And so did Mr. Ion Susai's."
Who was Mr. Ion Susai?
A friend of mine,
you don't know him.
Florin, we can take calls.
The control room
tells me we have a call.
Good evening
to you and your guests.
Good evening.
I'm Pavel Puiutz
from the Filantropica Foundation.
I've read this story
in the papers and
I am deeply shaken.
These two people
are not vagrants.
They both have jobs,
both earn salaries.
And yet our society denies them
a decent life,
and a minimum of respect!
I totally agree with you.
Do you have a question
for one of our guests?
An announcement.
This morning, my foundation
opened a bank account
in Mr. Popescu's name
at the Romanian Bank for Prosperity.
We've already made a deposit
and we'd like
the account number displayed,
so that other people
will be able to help this couple too.
Mr. Puiutz, say the number
and we will display it on the screen.
The number is...
It's my turn!
Can't see a thing!
We have a second call.
Mr. Gorea from Bucharest.
Do you hear me?
Perfectly.
Good evening to you and your guests.
Good evening.
I want to ask one question.
The government has promised
to increase pensions.
When?
We haven't seen anything yet!
Do you have any idea
of what we're talking about?
Of course!
But these youngsters you've invited,
they go to restaurants
and don't care about
old people with low pensions!
Thank you for your contribution.
It seems we have another call.
Mr. Fotica from Bucharest.
I have to tell you
these two are pulling your chain.
Please mind your language.
Just let me explain.
I've seen these crooks
last Thursday at The Polenta,
doing the same lousy routine!
Some customers paid for them,
myself included.
Believe me, they're pulling your leg!
This is a serious accusation.
Any reaction?
It's absurd! How can he imagine...
Lies!
I've never worked at The Polenta.
I'm sure it's a mistake.
I'm afraid not.
It seems this gentleman
has seen us someplace.
No point in trying to hide it.
Maybe you'd like to tell us more.
Maybe one night I kicked you out
of a club, with the help of security.
Right!
You made waves, at The Cool Club.
At The Cool Club?
Lmagine that,
the places I frequent.
Soon we'll hear
we were on the Riviera,
or in the Securitate,
during Ceausescu's time!
Just a nice practical joke at the phone,
a good laugh...
It's no joke, Mr. Florin!
You're with friends, aren't you?
I hear voices and music.
Is that a problem?
I have a question for you.
What form of transport did you use,
that evening,
to go to the restaurant
where you saw us?
My own car.
Your own car?
What do you do for a living?
I'm a student.
And what do you study?
I study in a private university.
Now I will show you something.
Please bring the camera
as close as possible
so everyone can see it.
I will bet Mr. Student here
has no idea how much this costs
or how to use it.
Will you take the bet?
Why not?
It could be interesting.
Mr. Fotica?
Yes!
If you're still there...
Tell us how much
is a tram ticket these days?
Personally, I've lost track.
Come on, Mr. Florin!
Don't you see he's playing the crowd?
Speaking of playing the crowd,
instead of wasting your time
with cheap science fiction,
I suggest you take the tram or the bus,
at least once a year,
just out of curiosity.
You'd see a bit of real life
and maybe you'll feel less
like playing jokes on TV.
Don't make fun of what
you don't understand, Mr. Student.
If life blessed you with rich parents,
try at least to be... more modest
if you can.
We'll be back after the break.
Want to make a deposit?
I want to withdraw
the equivalent of 3,000 U SD.
At the current rate of exchange,
that makes 90,540,000 lei.
Password, please.
Password?
Yes, your account is protected.
You can't withdraw
without the password.
Can't do it...
leave a poor man
without his last penny...
What did you think I do, charity?
He's a rookie.
He doesn't know the ropes.
The word copyright doesn't ring a bell?
Yesterday on TV
you talked different.
Maybe. You too had lower claims,
at the beginning.
Come on, boys!
We've been working nights,
we've been working days...
Don't be sulky. Have a drink!
What if I tell the police?
Slow down, boys!
What did you say?
He's really is a rookie.
How about singing a happy song?
Give me 3,000 dollars, as a loan.
3,000 dollars?
What manners,
after everything I taught you!
"Give me!"
I need it.
He needs it.
You've flunked out, teacher.
You'll have to revise a little.
Come back and impress me!
Move me! Bring me to tears!
Tell me about the poor Cinderella
you're trying to help.
What does she need? A fur coat?
A cozy apartment?
An out stretched hand
without a story to tell gets no charity!
Be a pro, for God's sake!
Popescu.
What happened?
No strings attached.
What is this?
It's for Robert.
He needs it.
But don't tell him it's from me.
That boy is a bum.
He doesn't deserve your help.
Let him fend for himself.
What can he do?
I'm telling you now,
so you won't regret it later.
I have to run along.
Remember where I live?
Drop by at 9 p.m.
6th floor, apartment 46.
I'll be waiting.
Mom!
Sleeping with your clothes on...
Why didn't you wake me up?
I didn't have the heart to.
You must call a certain Mr. Puiutz...
Looking for the young lady?
Miss Diana, yes.
She went out earlier.
At about 7 pm.
Rex! Down!
You're looking for the girl
who's on TV?
Do you know where she went?
Domident! Anywhere!
She had a suitcase
and she was in a hurry.
But who are you?
Cheers.
Let's hear another one.
"Romanian girls are
using more and more"
"Those beautiful,
expensive German cars"
"But they still love their country
like before"
"In spite of their big crush
on German cars"
Divine.
Say it once more, I want to learn it.
1213 years old,
are you interested?
Robert?
What are you doing here?
I'm hiding.
It's all right. You can go home.
What's all right?
The money. We got it.
No shit!
You had a stroke of luck.
Go home and talk to Diana.
Diana, your sister.
You're really stoned.
I haven't got a sister.
Sure!
Must've been my sister
who came to school...
That one...
She's not my sister.
She's a girl from the block.
I sent her to bullshit you.
You can't lend me 3,000 U SD,
can you?
Not really, man.
Don't laugh. I can't either.
You know, Robert...
There are plenty people in this world
who aren't worth
lifting one finger for.
You're top of the list.
Even the Baron's thugs
are more fun than you are.
So, why did I break my ass
trying to save your skin?
Let's go.
You have to sleep.
I'm taking you to a lady friend.
You'll be safe there.
I've located him.
He took a cab from the station.
Is this your stop? That'll be 50,000.
Beat it.
Run!
What do you want?
Here he is.
Where have you been?
Your wife was worried stiff.
You scared me to death!
What happened?
I can't believe it. You're drunk!
One doesn't earn that much everyday!
This calls for a drink.
He who never touches alcohol...
He looks fine!
How do you feel
about all this support?
What are your plans for the money?
Please, one at a time!
I'm happy for this couple.
Our foundation prefers to help
one person in difficulty
instead of spreading popcorn
to hundreds.
Sorry, it's too crowded over there.
Marriage certificate.
Let's have a picture
of you and your wife.
Enough for tonight.
Let them catch their breath.
Thank you all and good luck.
You are always welcome.
That's all. I'll go home myself.
Hope you have everything you need.
Mr. Popescu...
May I remind you that you owe me,
morally and materially.
3,000 dollars.
Don't bother, I know my way out.
We've been working days,
we've been working nights...
It's late. Shall we go to bed?
We'll clean up tomorrow.
What time do you get up?
Eight. I have to be at work at nine.
Wake me up too, I'll fix breakfast.
It's all right.
I'll make myself some eggs.
Darling, not tonight.
I'm very tired.
Do you mind?
No, I understand.
I'm going to write for a while.
If I fall asleep,
will you turn the TV off?
Honey...
Can you believe it? Ten years!
They passed
as though they were days.
"The night wormed
silently into the city"
"like the hand of a thief in my pocket."
No, don Pepe.
"...like me,
in bed with my sleeping wife."
Babe! Are you free tonight?
What do we have here?
Get in the car!
Why?
"Punk kid chased by thugs."
"He's better off begging,
than stealing."
You feel pity for this little scumbag,
this creep,
this suburban piece of shit?
Watch your...
Shut up!
You feel pity?
I've got your money!