THIS SUMMER
FOR THE FIRST TIME EVER
Welcome to the world's fastest sport!
THE WORLD OF CARS
Where only the best of the best compete.
TAKES FLIGHT
Ah, for flyin' out loud.
For the first time
we have a crop duster in the race.
Well, he's gonna die.
Rusty, you're going up against
the best racers in the world.
THERE'S JUST ONE PROBLEM
I'm afraid of heights!
That airplane needs some help,
y'all know that, right?
Yeah!
It ain't how fast you fly,
it's how you fly fast.
You can fly a whole lot
higher than you think.
Ballistic!
He's ready.
THE PLANES ARE ARRIVING
Hey, look who made it. It's Rusty.
Dusty. Dusty Crophopper.
Farm boy.
FROM ALL OVER THE WORLD
Wow, you're Bulldog, tallyho!
Most people call me Ishani.
I'm El Chupacabra.
We will have many adventures.
We will laugh, we will cry, we will dance!
Probably not with each other.
Don't let anything distract you.
She is like a sunrise after
a lifetime of darkness.
Or like fresh fertilizer on
a field of dying grass.
This is not your thing, my friend.
Danke for representing all us little planes.
But, you're a car.
Serious identity issues.
FROM DISNEY
You think you can beat me?
I swish my cape at you!
You have been shamed.
IF YOU LOOKING FOR A HERO
Kennedy approach, over.
Go back to Jersey, ya bum.
WATCH THE SKIES
This is Dusty Crophopper.
I'm caught in a storm! I'm going down!
I'm going down!
It's a really compelling underdog story.
Like Old Yeller.
- That's not an underdog story!
- There was a dog in it.
- Go!
- Yes!
What?
Oh, man. That's nasty.
PLANES
Mayday! Mayday! Big castle! Roll right!
I owe you my life.
- Are you crying?
- I don't cry, I'm British.
IN THEATRES
IN THEATRES AUGUST 9