Yes, I did!
Yuri Chursin
Vitaly Khaev
Okay, Lyuda, turn it on.
It's on.
Okay, we are beginning
our investigative experiment.
Crucian, where did you sit?
- At that table.
- What was next?
- She stood up.
- She who? She who, Crucian?
- Marinka.
- What Marinka? The victim!
Well, she stood up...
the victim...
She said
that she wanted to pee...
And she went to that one...
- Point with your hand.
- Here.
So did the victim go
to the toilet right after you came?
No.
What was before that?
We were sitting and talking.
What did you talk about?
Lyuda, focus!
Sure, sure.
We just talked...
- I was asking her...
- About what?
- Why she stayed at Igor's place.
- He's mumbling, I can't hear a word!
About what?
Say it again, louder!
Why she stayed at Igor's place.
Okay, what exactly
did you ask her about?
I've told you already!
It's an investigative experiment.
We are recording everything.
So once again, louder
and for the camera.
Or you didn't understand?
Marat Basharov
Andrey Fomin
So, Crucian, what did you ask
the victim about?
Why she stayed at Igor's place for
the night after the birthday.
Okay, Crucian, let's swim further.
What did she answer?
She said it had been late and dark
and she had been afraid to go home.
Go on.
I told her that I love her.
Anyway everyone knows
that I love her.
But why should she stay at somebody
else's place for the night?
What would they say about me?
She told me to shut up
and went to take a pee.
Then she came up to that one
and took the keys.
Point with your hand.
- Were you sitting at that table?
- No, over there.
Okay, let's sit down.
Valya, and you sit down too.
Igor Gasparyan
Maxim Konovalov
So, you were sitting here
and she went out?
Yes, to take a pee.
And you were standing here?
Yes, I gave her the key
and she paid me right away.
I asked her to pay right away
before she pisses.
Anna Mikhalkova
Alexander Ilyin
I feel disgusted to take money after
because I need to work with food.
Okay, Crucian, go on.
Then I stood up, followed her,
and knocked at the door.
Okay, stand up. Let's go.
Marina Golub, Fyodor Dobronravov,
Elena Morozova
Lyuda!
How many times did you knock?
- Two. Then two again.
- Okay, knock!
Seva, it's cold...
She asked, "Who is there?"
I said it's me.
She opened the door.
Okay, you open the door
for us, please.
Yes, of course, just a moment.
Seva, you didn't understand?
Also Starring
Liya Akhedzhakova
Okay, Crucian. What's next?
Nothing. Marinka opened the door
and that one started screaming,
demanding me to pay:
you can't shit together
for one price.
No, you know what I meant?
If you are together, even if you
are related, you must pay for two.
Correct?
I just reminded him
the regulations.
Okay, go on, Crucian.
I paid, came in,
and locked the door.
Okay, come in.
Just don't lock the door,
so we can see.
Seva! Take the kids away.
Where was she? Was she sitting?
Yes, on the lavatory pan.
Okay, Valya, sit down.
Okay, go on.
I took out the knife
and stabbed her in the neck.
Where from did you take the knife?
From the pocket of my trousers.
Okay, give him... this...
Seva, find something.
Seva, poke this into yourself.
Check if it goes in.
- In what?
- In the body.
They should not be dangerous.
Shit!
Lyuda, hold the camera.
Okay, show us
how you stabbed her.
Like this.
No, like this.
Okay, how did the victim react?
- How?
- What did she do?
Well, she farted.
Then she began to wheeze
and fell down...
I don't remember.
What did you begin to do next?
I decided to dismember her.
Music Composed by
Alexander Manotskov
- I began to cut her hand.
- Okay, show me how you cut.
Her hand...
Like this.
Then when I reached her bone,
I thought that she had bones
and I wouldn't be able
to sow them.
Okay, why at all
did you begin to sow her?
Where would you put the pieces?
- Did you have a bag?
- I had a little bag.
I could wash off everything
that was left.
What a simpleton!
Everything would get stuck there.
How would I know? I thought there's
a pit where all shit is washed off.
What pit? It's a bio- toilet.
Director of Photography
Sergey Mokritsky R.G.C.
- I told you to shut up.
- To throw pieces into my toilet!
Seva, get her out of here...
Why are you laughing?
It's working already.
Okay, go on.
Okay, Crucian. What were we at?
I really thought there was a pit.
I decided that I need to unscrew the
lavatory pan to throw her in there.
Produced by
Natalya Mokritskaya
Ulyana Savelyeva,
Leonid Zagalsky
I stood like this.
I took it and began to pull.
I pulled and pulled.
But it didn't give in.
I made myself dirty:
nobody cleans here...
I thought: come what may;
and I went home.
Written by
Brothers Presnyakovs
It seems done.
They charge so much and there
is no toilet paper here!
That's it, Lyuda. Turn it off.
Directed by
Kirill Serebrennikov
Valya, take the ears off...
Seva, later, later.
Renat, where are you?
Already?
Good.
No, I won't be soon.
We have a dismemberment.
May I go?
Listen, there is a big bag
in the fridge.
It's mother.
Mom came in the afternoon and
brought some meat. You chop it.
Where? On the balcony...
Just be careful
and don't fall through.
Listen, I'll come and think
of something. Maybe some soup.
And what do you want?
What?
PLAYING THE VICTIM
Valya...
Valya, what's the
matter with you?
What are you doing?
Dad...
You don't turn
the TV off again...
And it's winding
and winding electricity.
Turn it off or
we'll have to pay money.
Turn it off.
A meter, Valya.
Everything has a meter.
Electricity, us...
You didn't turn the TV off
and it winded the whole
mother's salary. Yes?
And she winded my meter so
that all my life went by in a glance
before I could look around.
There are such
situations in life
when you live and live
not suspecting anything.
And you've already
disturbed somebody,
even somebody very close to you,
you've disturbed
just because you live.
Dad, who did you disturb?
Valya?
Dad, who?
Who, dad?
Valya, you don't sleep?
You dreamt about your father again?
Why are you in a hat
all of a sudden?
Valya, I also dream about him.
Yes, I do.
I don't dream about him...
Come on, Valya. You dream
about him or not - it's okay.
Where are you going?
Calm down and have a rest.
Valya!
Go to bed.
- Do you have problems at work?
- I am fine.
- And why Olya doesn't visit us?
- She just doesn't.
You shouldn't lead
the girl by the nose.
You have to make up
your mind about her.
Why are you taking it out?
It's all in flake- camphor.
Already in flake- camphor?
Valya, it's been a long time
already. It's enough.
How long?
Long enough.
And not enough for me.
Valya, you can't return your dad.
And we have to live.
I won't be making up
my mind about her.
- Who are you talking about?
- About Olya.
- Why?
- So you don't have an excuse.
- What excuse?
- That I live.
I don't live and
you shouldn't either!
Valya, I need it, you see.
I don't want to go crazy.
And I want!
Hello, uncle Peter!
Why did you come out?
We are talking.
Come on, it's so stuffy.
Can't I? I won't...
Valya, stop it!
And they pierced his ribs...
Blood and water poured out.
Uncle, look at my press.
It's so strong.
So what?
Try to hit it.
Slow down.
Why to slow down?
Try to hit it!
Come on, it's really strong.
Valya, wait. Come on, stop it.
Sonny! What happened?
Did you hit him?
No.
He asked for it himself.
You hit him, you moron!
It's not nice to be famous,
It's not what raises you up high.
You don't need to create an archive,
To worry about your manuscripts.
Self- giving is goal of creative work
And not the fuss, not success.
It is a shame when meaning nothing
You're a story on everybody's lips.
Sysoyev, come on. He is she now,
washing window standing on the sill.
Come on, Valya.
You want to help her, right?
What are you saying?
"Let me help you?"
Come on, show us your actions.
- I tell her, "Let me help you."
- I can't hear it.
Speak louder.
- I tell her, "Let me help you..."
- And?
She remains silent.
What should I do?
I tell even louder,
"Let me help you."
- "Let me help you."
- And then?
"Let me help you!"
I go to the kitchen,
take a bucket,
and come to the door.
Come on, show it.
Come to the door.
She turned to me and said,
"You don't have to do anything.
Continue to rest."
Okay.
Go on, Sysoyev, go on.
I slammed the door
and went out to the porch.
Suddenly I hear a loud noise.
I return to the room.
Window is closed,
and she is no longer
on the windowsill.
So, according to your words,
it was the draft that...
Yes, exactly.
It means the window got shut by the
draft and threw her outside, right?
Threw her outside.
Slam the door!
That's why this is
an investigative experiment.
We have to check everything out.
Comrade Captain,
may I get down?
Okay, get down, Valya.
Well, Sysoyev. Slam the door.
Here it is. I told you.
You've seen it.
I told you.
- We have to check the strength.
- Whose strength?
The window's!
With what strength
the window closes?
How can we understand if it
could push a person out or not?
Yes, well done, Lyuda.
Okay, Valya. Get up on the
windowsill and open the window.
- Comrade Captain, if he is right?
- That's what we'll try to find out.
- Seva, take off your belt.
- I don't have a belt.
How come? Are you nuts already?
It's part of the uniform.
You can take my belt in the
sleeping- room, in my trousers.
There are no trousers here.
How come there are no trousers?
- There aren't any here.
- And who took them?
Okay, Sysoyev. Calm down,
that's enough.
I wasn't here; my wife fell
to her death. Who could take them?
I wanted to ask one thing.
Did you seal up windows
for the winter?
And why?
Renat, why didn't you
seal up windows?
Look for any pantyhose with
Lycra, they are more durable.
We need durable...
Look, what you got!
Don't you know what Lycra is?
These are worm, woolen ones.
The ones with Lycra are all
shining and transparent.
What did I want to say?
I forgot everything
because of you.
How do you imagine it?
In other words, I have to wait?
Valya, take it. One end tie to
yourself, another - to the radiator.
I hope you don't mind if
you don't have a belt in your house.
- I had a belt.
- I had several...
Okay, that's it!
Do you love me?
A fool.
I am working. That's all.
I kiss you.
Okay, Valya.
You make a sailor's knot.
Look, if suddenly it slams
and you fly out,
you just tuck right away,
so you don't hit the walls.
Get on there.
Seva, take it off.
Hold it.
Tighter. Wind it
round your hand.
Pull in right away.
Don't wait, Seva.
Okay, Valya...
Seva, don't wait.
Lyuda, pay attention.
Make sure to shoot all of this.
Okay. I'll do a panoramic view.
Sysoyev, let's go.
Sysoyev, you do it when I tell you.
Okay, on my count.
Valya, step closer to the edge.
Turn over there.
No, I can't.
You can't what?
I'm afraid of height. If anything,
I'll better fall with my back first.
What back?
How will you tuck then?
I don't know. Somehow sideways...
How will you do it
sideways, Valya?
Everything you do is sideways.
Your whole life is sideways!
Okay. You ready, Sysoyev?
Yes.
Slam it!
- I didn't get it.
- There is no draft.
Ah, Sysoyev!
A point not in your favor.
You saw it yourself:
it was closing.
Yeah. It was closing.
And now it wasn't.
Okay, Sysoyev. Try it
one more time and that's it...
Comrade Captain.
Get up.
And you slam.
An unpleasant moment,
Sysoyev, isn't it?
But it was closing.
All of you saw that it
was closing. Everyone saw it.
Okay, enough, Sysoyev. Enough...
No, it isn't enough.
Comrade Captain,
let's try one more time.
Get out of here.
Okay, it's done. We are leaving.
Keys... Keys...
So what? Is that all?
Let's seal the apartment up.
Do you want to get married?
Married?
Do you have your
passport with you?
What do you mean?
Let's register our
marriage right away.
Ah, you are playing the fool!
You know that you
badly hurt me now.
No, I am serous.
Do you hear me?
I am very serious.
Let's go to your place.
No!
First you talk to the boy!
Come on. Your boy
will turn 30 soon.
He is upset.
He is very upset.
Go on, feel sorry for him!
- He won't feel sorry for you.
- What are you talking about now?
You know what I am talking about.
What's the matter, Valya?
You are crazy.
- Hello, aunt Galya.
- Hi, Kostya.
Okay, I'm off now.
Alone...
Listen, could you
strangle me a little bit?
How? You mean with my hands?
No.
Keep touching me with your hands.
But I need at that moment
to have not enough air,
to really suffocate...
Oh, scarfing.
What scarfing?
It's called so.
I've read in Marie Claire.
Jerk- offs do it like this: beat of
and strangle themselves with scarf.
It intensifies the sensation.
No, on the contrary,
I need to put it down.
- Put down what?
- The sensation.
Cut off oxygen for me!
Slow down, relax.
I am fine.
If only you thought
about me just a little,
we'd be married long ago.
But who am I?
What am I talking about?
You don't need it!
You decided, what would
you say why we have to part?
Don't think too much.
We are kind of together anyway,
playing that you are my man
and I am your woman!
The only thing hurts my feelings:
at 33 I'll have to go out,
make somebody fall in love with me,
look for somebody anew.
I can't get acquainted
with anybody or talk.
I ran out of steam on you
about 5 years ago.
I am exhausted.
I don't have any interests left.
Who am I going to catch?
I'll have to play that
I'm interested in a person
to get him to marry me...
Valya!
Hello, Olya.
Get up. Totally grew lazy.
Got a scarf on!
He used to sleep with his hat on.
And now the scarf.
Valya, go and get some bread.
- Which should I get?
- Get Moskovsky long loaf.
- And if they don't have it?
- Get pita then.
Pita? Isn't it dangerous?
- Pita is bread too. Even tastier.
- Tastier...
But we are at war with them.
- With whom?
- With those who bake pita.
-But they live here.
- Who?
Who bake pita. They live here.
They are still part of them.
So what, not to buy pita now?
I don't know. You could
venture, of course.
But what if they get
a secret order to poison all pita.
Even you said,
pita is tastier than our bread.
- Even tastier than a long loaf, yes?
- Yes.
So, all this pita will be bought.
And then boom...
Since they got their orders.
But everyone would know who did it!
Of course, it just would be late.
We would have already
eaten their pita.
Hey, sister, come here.
You will go to Moscow.
- Brother, why should I go to Moscow?
- You'll find out soon.
Be careful!
The doors are closing...
What's your name?
17 years old! No!
We continue to fight
with our world terrorism.
I think we'll do
without bread today.
I'll cook noodles.
Noodles are like bread.
And tomorrow I'll get it myself.
Whatever you say.
I'll pick it myself and buy it.
Let's go, Olya. You'll help me.
It's okay, don't cry.
Don't take cheese away.
Here is a chicken.
Crab sticks for the salad.
Olya, in school Valya was made
to go to the swimming pool.
- To the swimming pool?
- Yes.
In third grade they
started to take him there.
- And he was afraid of water.
- Really?
His father wanted
to teach him to swim.
He took him in the boat
to the middle of the river.
And threw him out.
He thought Valya would swim.
And he almost drowned.
So, he even doesn't approach water.
- We'll put it here.
- And so?
And nothing.
You put bananas here.
Imagine, he specially didn't take
second swimming trunks with him.
And they don't let you in a pool
in the ones you have on...
And he pretended that he forgot,
because he was afraid.
If you try to persuade him,
he'll pretend and
you'll get nothing from him.
Tell me as a woman,
will you live with him?
Yes.
Yes? Do you know
what is to be done?
No.
Olya... You've got it?
Come on, no more tears.
Take the matches and
let's go to cook noodles.
No. I already said that
he needs second swimming trunks.
I said. That's it.
Fuck it, Valya!
I warned you that we'd be
in the swimming pool.
I didn't know
that second pair is needed!
What's the big deal?
I told you not to jump in!
My trunks are clean!
I put them on today!
- No!
- Please. I even didn't pee today.
- So what?
- There is no even a single stain.
- Look, how many germs are there.
- And no germs on the second ones?
No! They are clean!
You don't wear them outside!
But they are clean!
How they can be clean
if you've put them on!
All kinds of stuff are on them!
And we put chlorine in the pool!
We follow all regulations!
Girls, let's go!
Okay, that's it!
Then we'll be right here,
on the bank,
on the edge.
Okay, Lyuda.
Alright, girls, breathe deeply...
- Lyuda, did you turn it on?
- Yes, already.
Okay. We start an investigative
experiment in the case of Takhirov.
Zakirov.
Yes, Zakirov Takhir.
- Remember, no one gets in water!
- We got you!
I'll watch you and I'll see!
Zakirov, how did you get
in the swimming pool?
-By ticket.
- And the victim?
She had a season ticket.
So, you knew that when you come
with your ticket she would be here?
Yes, I did.
Okay. Where was the victim?
Here, in the second lane.
-Okay, did she see you?
- Nah, I not wanted she see me.
He didn't want her
to see him, yes?
Yes.
-Okay, what did you do next?
- I jumped into the pool.
Okay. Let's pretend
that you jumped right here.
But don't go into water!
Approximately like this.
Yeah. A circus with horses.
Seva, don't you know
what to do with your hands?
Oh, Valya. Fuck it!
I warned you that we
would be at the pool!
What am I going to do now?
And I have to close
the case by tomorrow.
Comrade Captain, I didn't know.
I put clean trunks on purpose.
I didn't know I have to bring them.
Okay, Zakhi...
Zakirov.
Okay, Zakirov. You're in water.
What's next?
I am in water... She's grinning.
Her friends were there.
She's crying to them...
I dove right away.
Okay, you dove, yes?
Come on, squat down.
Okay. And then?
Then I swam towards her.
Okay, how far did you swim?
Well, 10, 15...
Not more than 7 yards.
Okay, Valya.
Stand 10 yards away from him.
Okay, Zakirov.
Imagine that he is the victim.
Swim towards her,
I mean towards him,
and do what you did
with the victim.
Swim.
Fuck it, Valya! We even found
second swimming trunks for Takhir.
And you were coming
from home, not from jail.
Comrade Captain,
I really didn't know.
Is it a children playground here
for you? This is a crime site.
Is this clown tired?
Come on, show us!
I don't remember well...
I swam up to her.
She was floundering about
with her feet, splashing around.
Okay, try to remember...
I started looking for her feet.
Because there were
other feet there.
And she had green nail polish
on her foot, a green pedicure.
I found it...
Listen, why are you standing? Help
me, flounder about with your feet.
Come on, Valya.
What are you smiling at? Move your
feet. Do something today already.
Then I swam up to her.
I grabbed her feet and pulled
them to me, as if she dove.
Okay, grab him and pull,
as if you are under water.
Grab him.
She was floundering about
with her feet there.
Stop floundering!
I let her go
and swam to the other side.
I got out and left.
When she came to the surface,
they thought she was swimming.
And I left.
Hey, where are you going?
And how long he hanged under water?
At least six minutes.
Six?
You're thinking in the
right direction, Lyuda!
It means he at first
swam to her about 30 feet,
then he was holding her,
and then swam away.
Zakirov, did you show
everything right to us?
Yes. It happened like that.
More or less.
I loved her, Comrade Captain.
I loved her and she didn't.
She didn't love me.
She was just playing.
I did everything I could for her.
And she began to live
with my brother.
How could she?
I begged her. I stood on
my knees. I begged him.
I was telling him,
"You're my brother."
I gave her everything that I could.
You need pantyhose - please,
as many as you like.
I always told her
to come by and pick out.
One of each, two of each.
You need pantyhose - please.
Chocolate - only foreign.
English Karli- Varli.
The best chocolate.
I gave her three bars at a time,
treated her friends.
Okay, Zakirov.
Stop singing songs.
Let's keep silence now.
How long is it?
Zakirov, were you
without an aqualung?
Yes. I was without an aqualung,
just in swimming trunks.
We have to check it.
It doesn't add up.
Is he like a fish?
Or like a pearl diver?
Even they can't make it
so long without air.
Okay, Zakirov. I'll
note down the time now.
I'll tell you when to start,
and you hold your breath
as long as you can.
We have to check it.
- Got it?
- Yes.
Let's go.
Not to breath?
- Are you breathing?
- I wait when you tell me to start.
He is waiting...
- Hold your breath!
- I got you.
But how long?
What kind of day it is today!
- What's his name?
- Takhirov.
Takhirov! I'll wave my hand now
and you hold your breath.
Hold it as long as you can.
-Got it?
- No.
- What don't you get?
- My name is Zakirov, not Takhirov.
Listen.
Listen,
Zakirov.
If you don't get us quickly,
we'll tape your mouth and nostrils
and take tape off in half an hour.
We'll see what kind of a
fucking diver you are!
Explain me, what I should do.
I don't resist.
Close your mouth and don't breathe.
Let me know when you run out of air.
I got it.
Done! No more air.
Shit!
What a freak!
He didn't hold on
even a minute, bitch.
Maybe to slay him here,
in this swimming pool!
Hello, Renat. Where are you?
Watch it.
Look, there's a chance
to go to a pool.
On Saturday.
And what are you doing?
I see. Meeting of the classmates.
15 years since graduation.
Will the girls be there?
You were studying
with the girls, or what?
I know all this.
You'll meet, have a drink,
and everything will start anew.
You think I haven't been
to such parties?
I see. I'll go alone.
I won't go with you.
What I have to do there?
It isn't interesting for me.
And imagine, it's
interesting in the pool.
We have a totally different level of
integration into culture with you.
Look, and maybe it wasn't he?
And who?
How could he if he couldn't?
Maybe he did it some other way.
What a freak!
- Freak.
- What a freak.
- Damn with him.
- Yeah, damn with him.
- We've held our experiment. Right?
- Yeah, right.
No one saw him,
because he dove at once.
Right.
- That's it...
- That's it!
Something comes together
and it's okay.
Okay then.
A good pool, isn't it?
Zakirov, is a ticket here expensive?
Yes.
But by season ticket it's cheaper.
I bought for one visit.
I thought it would be
enough to drown her.
Lyuda, maybe we'll go here
together and swim?
You swim with your family.
I have a bath with my family.
Let's do it with you.
- Was it on?
- Compromising stuff.
- Come on.
Give it to me!
Erase the end.
Move it, Zakirov!
Stop mumbling at once!
Listen, Zakirov. How did you
hold your breath under water?
With my arse.
- Valya!
- What?
I am tired. I'll go to study.
- Where?
- In the university.
You studied there. Tell me,
what faculty is the best.
They are all the same.
Why do you need it?
It will be easier for me
with higher education.
You think I should catch
creeps my entire life?
Why are you playing?
You are looking for a
high paying, prestigious job?
- And what's wrong with it?
- Nothing.
Just why should you walk
the roundabout paths
to the target that is
half a yard away from you.
Here is your devoted
genie Takhirov,
who'll make all your wishes come
true if you set him free.
He is the prisoner of the lamp,
and you can become Aladdin.
What? How? No.
And why are you afraid?
We'd tell captain that he ran away.
The worst that will happen to you:
you'll get fired.
And you'll help the man.
He isn't guilty at all.
She's guilty.
It's just very simple.
This one will be gone
in seconds.
He'll get to his mountains,
and you'll get your reward.
Listen, I'll do whatever you want.
We have a car. White one.
I'll give you money.
As much as you want. Honest.
Let me go before they come back.
Listen to your buddy.
Whatever you say,
I'll do everything.
- Come on. How...
- What are you waiting for?
Look, one minute more and his hairy
arse will be a dot in the horizon.
And you will be in a white car
with a heap of cash.
Go ahead.
I was joking, Seva.
We'd serve life for this dude.
And even if he gets away...
Please, pass me
the key over there...
You think he'll be looking
for us to thank us?
He'll just sing against us.
Why were you saying
all that crap to me?
So, that you'd get
the essence of the moral.
What is it?
Moral, Seva, is in the ways
of satisfying the needs.
You study and work.
Live calmly, save your salary.
That's what human being is.
Normal member of the society.
Takhirov didn't know that,
and here is the result:
he's in handcuffs!
It's so easy to stumble, Seva. And
I don't want it to happen to you.
You like naked men?
- Do you have latest newspaper?
- Yes.
Go fuck yourself!
Brother, Seva, come on!
Come here!
Shut up, I said!
Come here, fast!
Dress him! That's it!
To the station!
Excuse us!
Excuse us, please!
How long should I wait for you?
Hush!
- What's up?
- He's expressing remorse...
He just asks to be sent
far away to Siberia.
He wants to purify
himself spiritually.
He went into such hysteric here.
He isn't the first one,
he isn't the last one.
And as far as Siberia goes,
it'll be up to the court to decide.
It's not for him to choose.
Not necessarily in Siberia.
We have a lot of places
like that in Russia.
Let's go to the balcony
and have a smoke.
Smoke here. Why should you
go outside?
Can we?
No. Go out to the balcony.
Let's go and have a smoke.
You go, I don't smoke anyway.
Let's go, you'll make me a company.
Let's go and have a drink...
Come on, go with your
uncle to the balcony.
And I'll clean up everything here.
Come in and let's talk.
Come on in.
Why do you stay at the doors?
Are you afraid or what?
What's the matter with you?
I'm just joking with you.
Fill it up!
Your mother asked me to talk to you.
Your mother and I will live together.
An ordinary dinner and he died...
Who?
My father. Your brother.
Oh, yeah. But you know,
he had problems.
He dined and died.
It usually happens.
Whom did he have problems with -
you or my mother?
With his health, Valya.
Why do you use these chopsticks?
To make life more complicated...
I understand if you ate
what they eat with them.
And what do they eat with them?
Raw fish, rice pellets.
Whatever these narrow- eyed eat.
And in Russia, Valya, you need
a spoon in order to live!
To grab more and eat.
And not to peck like them
with the sticks.
Look here.
We put a scoop on the stick,
because a stick alone
isn't enough for our table.
How will you pull the food
toward you?
And here, look.
It's comfortable.
You see? Comfortable.
Let them meditate at their Orient.
And peck with their sticks.
You know, uncle, after
Genghis Khan all boundaries
between East and West
have been erased.
Maybe they have been erased for you.
But not for me.
And not for your mother.
Were there Nazis in the village
where you were born?
Occupation?
That's why you take care
of European culture so much!
The German blood boils!
Appeals to you!
Listen, you scum!
Start your own family and move out!
And your mother and I
will live here!
Scum... With these chopsticks.
Beast.
- What's the matter with you?
- Nothing. You don't exist. Killed.
Scum.
- And what, you cook raw fish?
- Yes.
- And people order it?
- And they eat it?
- Yes.
Just great!
And how much is it?
It's different.
There are 15 types of
sushi alone on the menu.
From 2 euros.
Yeah? No. I am afraid of worms.
You get worms from raw fish.
And then they live inside a man.
Okay. We'll continue.
It isn't funny anymore.
Tomorrow morning
we'll go to see mother.
So what, that she's healthy
like a horse?
Shouldn't we visit the healthy ones?
She loves us, really.
Renat, she loves us.
Yes, and you too!
And you're in kimono...
Are you from Japan?
No, it was the manager's idea.
There are a lot of
Japanese restaurants now.
So they do their best
to cash on this exotic.
Till the first emergency,
so to say.
It's a dangerous business.
Over there... you have
to study for a long time
to be able to cook all this crap.
There is a fish there,
if you cut it wrong,
it emits poison...
Come on.
- How is it called?
- Fuga.
Fuga.
The most expensive fish.
Vasya, our chef, cooked it recently.
He drank a little for courage.
He cut this fish and served it.
Whole staff stood there and
watched to see what happens.
- And what?
- Vasya!
We ran out of sake
and served heated Russian vodka.
Maybe that's why we got along then.
But everybody got
real tense though...
I am fine.
We are in a restaurant.
I can't today.
We're investigating.
Yes, he's here too.
Because he is my boss.
And we have a murder here.
Yes, a murder.
Hello.
Hello!
No, I am at work.
Why you wear kimono, I asked.
I'm saying it.
Our manager told me,
when I retired from the theater.
Samurais are standing at every
corner in the restaurants now.
- Samurais?
- Yes.
He meant the restaurants like ours.
And you, he said,
would be an old
Japanese woman with a past.
Right now.
With a past.
So that it'd be different from
others. Get it? So it'd catch you!
Teahouse like a bonbonniere
Rolled in blooming roses.
From the deck of
English gunboat,
One sailor stepped down
at that moment.
He stepped down there
as it had to be
To meet all famous sailors.
He asked for wine
and a cup of tea
And couldn't say anything else.
And in the corner,
a beautiful Japanese girl
Sang something softly about love.
He remembered his native land,
Sea blood began to boil in him.
And in the morning
the gunboat again
Set its sails on the order.
Why did the Japanese girl cry so?
And why was the sailor so cheerful?
Ten years passed by like in a tale.
And the girl's son was growing up.
He childly opened his eyes wide
And asked, "And who is my father?"
And the beautiful Japanese woman,
Tenderly fingering her son's hand,
Answered her sweet little boy,
"Your father was
an English sailor!"
So pour me stronger wine.
How many roses are blooming
in my garden.
Wine makes it easier for me,
Because I'm still in love with him!
I beg you. We have to open
in 15 minutes...
If you don't sing...
I am the witness here!
Okay, we still need her.
All right.
When you finish with your
testimony, come to my office.
I will! I will.
- I am testifying, and this one...
- 15 minutes.
- Lyuda, turn it on.
- Already.
- Okay, Verkhushkin.
- Yes.
With what purpose did you
come to the restaurant?
Ten years. Anniversary
of graduation.
Be specific. What graduation?
From Astronaut's College or what?
Ten years since we
graduated from school.
- We gathered here...
- Who is "we"?
Our class, former class.
Was the victim from your
class as well?
Yes. Horse and I
sat together in class.
What horse?
This is his nickname, Horse.
We were friends.
Okay, you were friends.
Step aside from here.
Bring me the menu.
And come back at once.
Well done.
And where did you sit here?
Also together.
I sat here and Horse opposite,
at your place.
Okay, Valya. Sit down.
- What, again?
- I'm bringing the menu!
You'll be instead of
Horse today.
Okay, you were sitting.
What were you talking about?
And right away about why, where,
from what did you shoot at Horse?
At the victim...
- What's this?
- These are rolls.
When we had a drink,
he began to bait me
in front of everybody.
I own a car wash.
And he told me
to finish my food quickly,
because he wanted me
to wash his car.
And what's the difference between
the rolls and these sushi?
It's the same shit.
Rolls just have caviar
sprinkled on the top.
Okay, Lyuda!
Why exactly did you shoot him?
I told him to stop laughing,
and he kept laughing loudly.
I tell him to stop laughing,
Okay, go on!
I told him, let's go outside.
He says, let's go.
We got up.
Okay, get up.
- Did the victim get up too?
- Yes.
Valya, get up!
So, how did you go? Who was first?
He went first, and then me.
He went to the bar, to that doll.
Yeah, he just walked up to me,
and that one shot at him
right away!
I felt at once that
something would happen now!
And it did.
I feel it every day,
especially when they have their
graduation celebrations here.
Graduates!
Wait, wait!
He went. And where were you?
Let me adopt a pose.
Like this!
It's me - the last thing
he saw in his life!
Valya, go to her!
He came up to her
and said something.
I took out my gun
and popped off at his head twice.
- You popped off!
- Yes, I popped.
He popped.
They weren't BB's,
with real bullets.
Just like kids. Fucking bastards!
Shit, shit!
They buy everything for
themselves, fucking fagots!
And we have to go
and clean up after them!
Fuckhead!
Where did you get the gun?
Where did you get the gun!
Where do you get everything?
Where the fuck did you
fly in here from?
I never thought in my life that I'd
get in such fucking environment!
Where from all of you flew in?
You went to the same schools,
had the same teachers.
Your parents are almost
of my fucking age.
What did they make you from?
Out of what?
All of you!
Shit, this one forgets his swimming
trunks going to the pool.
This fagot pops off at the guy
he sat next to in school.
What the fuck do you need in life?
How do you want to live it?
And this one too, fuck!
What the fuck have
you done yesterday?
No, I don't fucking understand you.
I don't, though I'm not old yet.
And I don't understand them.
How is it possible
to sew up a police inspector?
- What's his name?
- Semakin.
To sew up Semakin, dress him
in a woman's clothes like a whore,
and throw him drunken
into the holding cell.
I don't get it!
And all of you
are not such milksops.
All of you are almost 30!
At your age I already had
a kid and a wife!
Where did you get all those
woman's clothes?
Those slutty pantyhose...
I went to get my mom's one.
Your mom's?
Your mom's...
Wasn't it bloody hard for you
to go for them?
No, at the most, on April Fools'
day, on day of humor,
I put mustard instead of
my wife's toothpaste.
This is a normal joke.
And what about you?
And the most important is
that you don't give a fuck!
And you don't give a fuck
that you don't give a fuck.
But it's you, your generation,
you drive trains, fly planes.
Lawyers by the way.
Work at nuclear plants!
And most importantly,
why the fuck do you go to work?
Don't give a fuck
and go to such responsible jobs.
And then everything goes
to shit in our society!
I'll call police now.
Stasik, calm down.
Come on... He popped off.
I am calm, I am calm...
Come on, bring that fish.
Your fish and sake.
If I don't try it now, I never will.
- You mean that one?
- That, poisoned one.
Vasya, bring fuga.
Shit!
- He popped off. Popped...
- Stasik...
Go to the arse,
somewhere to the nearby table,
where I can't see you...
How long has it been?
4, 8, 16...
Okay, I started to be fan at 14.
Our soccer team has been
fucking with me for 26 years!
No, there were successes before:
we made it to the finals.
But now, fuck, every
championship goes to shit.
You wait four years,
and then what?
Because the same stupid
asses like you play.
They don't give a fuck.
And most importantly,
they learned to pretend!
They used to protest before.
It was a public position: we don't
fucking need a thing and we protest.
And now it's all hush- hush,
no protests.
They pretend to be whoever is
needed, get any job they want.
And don't do a shit.
Just screw around!
You're screwing around with life.
And those, who take it seriously,
go crazy, suffer.
You have to fucking play in soccer.
And they take make- up artists
and stylists with them.
And in the end, they fucking loose!
You have to think there,
how to score a goal.
And this asshole is combing
his permed pubes,
so that they stand up
in the rain.
He doesn't listen to the coach
during the break but fixes his hair.
Fill it up, mother.
Shit, this isn't food.
It's some mindfuck!
And everything should be quiet,
"popped off", "caught up"...
They understood it
that in order to be left the fuck
alone they have to pretend.
It's a global fuck- up...
on all social levels...
And what do you want?
I took the number 26 tram yesterday.
I ask the driver
whether his tram goes
along Malyshev Street.
And he replies,
"How the fuck should I know?"
Just imagine, driver doesn't know
the streets on route of his tram!
- And what did he tell you?
- Who?
This Horse.
Spit on it...
Spit...
He said, spit on it.
Maybe he wanted to spit
on everything! But he had no time...
He was killed...
His schoolfellow relaxed!
- Are you done?
- Done!
Get lost!
Spit on it...
Slide apart.
Well done...
I'm happy, very happy...
Me too. I'm very happy. Well done!
You've really been
a man here, Valya!
But of course... It's bad
if a baby is born and
you aren't married. You see?
We thought and decided that we
wouldn't go for a honeymoon
and we wouldn't have a wedding.
No, how come?
We have to drink to this.
- Valya, we have to drink to this.
- We'll drink.
- It's just necessary.
- We'll surely drink.
Come on.
Like this?
You're right that you
won't have a wedding.
Why should you feed them?
You'll buy something
you need on this money.
- A washer.
- Yes.
And do you use
the chopsticks, do you?
And you?
The fish is really good.
- Where did you buy it?
- In a restaurant!
It should be expensive.
It's okay. Today is a special day.
Pour me just a little.
That's enough.
So what, Valya? Are we eating right?
Right!
You know, it's comfortable
for me with these fingers.
Is it right?
Right.
And why don't you eat yourself?
I'm listening to you.
In general, you're a fine fellow.
I respect you.
It'd be good for you
to find a normal job.
Or a baby will born... He'll ask,
"Daddy, where do you work?"
And what will you tell him?
Valya, really. You just go,
pose the corpses...
Who needs this? Why?
Oh, Valya, Valya.
I somehow feel myself not good.
I'll bring some water.
Okay, who went where?
Well, she got up.
She really wanted
to go to the kitchen...
But her legs gave way
and she fell down.
She fell right here!
Okay, lie down...
Okay, Valya, what was then?
Then... Uncle rushed to her...
Why are you staring?
Come on, rush, rush!
Then he stared at me,
wanted to say something, stood up,
and fell on the floor himself.
And what was she doing?
She? She got everything
at once and ran to the sink.
She began to drink water.
I tried to explain to her
that it wouldn't help,
that poison was already working,
and that it would be better
just to wait it through.
But she screamed
and kept drinking.
Then she limpened on the sink,
and that was all.
Come on, limpen!
Lie down!
Okay. What's next?
Next...
I didn't know for sure
whether they'd be poisoned or not.
But since it happened like that,
I was just watching.
I tried to remember
in order to play...
to reproduce everything later.
Because you would need
to find out, how it really was...
Alright.
Lyuda?
Turn it off.
Valya.
What's the matter?
Don't be afraid, sonny.
Don't be afraid.
Why are you scared, Valya?
Valya, come on!