Try in another way
Listen to me...
I will fall down being after you all the day
Falling down is not gentle
I like to beat people, but I don't want to do it now
See the gun? Found on your body
I haven't assay it yet
If it is used...
You must get at least 5 years
At least, do you know?
The judgers are cold-blooded
But I can assume not to see the gun
Throw it away
But it costs
Cost?
What cost?
You need to help me
We can keep the promise
What did Luo talk to you in Marseilles?
He wanted to find a dealer
He had no acquaintance to trust
You helped him
No
Luo gave me 30 thousand to bring goods to Holland
Half half profit
Too dangerous
Small trade meeting is ok
Then what did you say to him?
I said I can ask somebody to do
Can you?
Simon
Who is Simon? Simon
Simon...?
Simon Samani
They three brothers cooperate with each other
Simon Maxime and Jean
Dealer in Boliviere
They live in Boliviere, yes
But can't get a deal, they are too rich
They often go to Holland
Bring back one kilogram each time, it's enough for a long time
They are big dealer in Paris and Marseilles
Then?
I told Simon his background
Then you helped Simon trade for drug
No, I didn't
When is Luo's first deal?
I don't remember the date
He called me to ask for 50 grams
Then?
I sent it to him
How much did he pay you?
One thousand and five hundred
One thousand and five hundred for you?
No, I gave the money to Simon
How much did you earn?
Only 200
You 200, then Simon 1300
Great, it's a good deal
Then?
Luo added 200 grams more
This time Simon went with me to Marseilles
Why would Simon go with you?
Because trust is limited, he didn't believe me
I'm afraid I'm (logged)
Will you?
Donno, maybe yes
How much did Luo pay you?
How much do you earn?
Nothing
Luo had no money
Then the following one?
He asked for more goods
How many?
300 grams
I said 300 grams
How much is it?
He paid Samani 9000
Me 1500
I don't understand, why need you?
Simon and Luo has already known each other
Why do you still be the intermediator?
That's our convention
Simon had no such case,
he didn't want to get involved
You were in charge of carrying of goods
Yes
Then?
It was over, Simon was too crafty
Why?
Impure and expensive
Sure
Then no job?
Yes, no job
Then what about you later?
I help Luo to contact with other people
You know many people
Who was he this time?
Momo
Momo...?
Who is Momo?
Everyone knows who is Momo
I don't know where did you know him?
In Paris?
Bar
Which one?
Can't remembers
Ever saw Simon again?
Before and later
No, but I tried to keep away from him
His two brothers are mad
Why say so?
They always armed with guns...
They were afraid of my business
Their worries are right
Then?
Someday they came to see me
Beat me
Do you have the address of Simon?
No, I don't, you must have, give it to me
I just know he lives with a France girl Noria
I don't know the actual place
Who is Noria?
I don't know
Shall I go? Make a record first
Name?
Taylor Luyadi
Why called (Gauthier)?
Coz it has some taste of France...
Where are they now?
I don't see them ever leave
What dose she look like?
Light brown hair, down like this
Is she tall?
Something likes that
Pretty?
Oh, fine
I go to eat something
Bring me ham sandwich
Me, too
You stay here
Xi, must be her
I think she must go to drink coffee
Follow her
Xi, dude!
Monitor the exit of the building
We go to find her
Let's go
I go inside
Police, don't move
Let's leave quietly
I haven't pay for my coffee
I pay
Be quiet, which will be alright
He is upstairs?
Who?
Bring her along
Police, don't move
Come
It's not my home
Why do you come here?
I'm waiting for a friend
Come on, take on the clothes
We can go to bed when we truly love each other!
What do you think?
The dirty things are not drug
There is nothing inside
What on earth are we searching for?
I don't know
We will find
Check the plug on the wall
They must hide something
You must wear it for a long time
Whose?
Mine, the bankbook is mine
You have account in the bank?
Yes
What about you?
No, I don't have an account
I mean that's your...
Come, count!
They must leave already
Catch Stlouis?
Yes
He is cautious, too
Helpful to our case?
In order to inform your
How much?
A big amount
Is that illegal?
Damn, we would eat at 4
Whose is it?
Mine
The keys are yours?
I never saw that
It's not my home
The keys are not mine
They are put on the shelf
Whose keys?
Maybe former owners?
He left many things
What's his name?
I don't know him!
I forget the archive
Xi, it's on time
You maybe useful for sometime
Give the overclothes to me
Quickly!
Your watch
Take off all of them?
All
Lay down
Cough
Ok, take on the clothes
What shall I do?
Tell me one thing
You can change
I'm telling your truth now
Not before?
I don't think it's him
I'm poor
He has credit card
We should make it clear
Yes, but he is a lonely old man
With 4 children
One of which is disabled
I accuse him he is
I don't know he has credit card
You knew it before
Don't be woebegone
Do you know him?
Yes, it's him
Can I go to the toilet?
You should go to toilet earlier
Stupid, you have no right to do it
He is nervous!
I really can't bear...
Can't bear
You can bear!
They keep me waiting for several hours! Stupid!
Ok, come
It's a brand, with paster
How much?
Around 150
That will put you in jail for 10 years!
That thing?
Nothing found
We can put 100 grams drug here
We all know you are a dealer
You searched my house, nothing yet...
Ask me to do dealer?
Too ridiculous
It's you who are ridiculous
What's your name?
Samani
Everyone calls you Simon
Birth date and place?
August 16, 1955 Tunisia
How long do you live with Noria?
Around one year
Any record?
No
Souce of incoming?
No job for two months
Worked in the outskirts
400 monthly, a job of no future
Any bank account?
No
We find the evidence that you bought a car
Where is the money?
That's reserved a month ago
How much is your rent?
The house is Noria's
I ask you how much is your rent?
Donno...150?
She pays the rent
No bank account, but you have savings
I have no money to hide
Then how do you live through recently?
The remaining money of job
Which job?
I have no money,
The deposit of buying a car?
Except the 2250
Other money is not yours
All are mine, they are Noria's
Go to prove that I'm wrong
When did you come to France?
3 years ago
Reason?
Travel
Look at the new style clothes, buy good suit
Good looking
Have you family?
I have 5 brothers
All are in France?
In Tunisia
Do you know Luo Panzers?
Taylor Luyadi?
We are all from Tunisia
Did you meet in France?
No...Ah, ever saw Taylor
Saw him in France
Did you see Luo in Marseilles?
Did you go to Marseilles?
No, never
Ah, I went
I went there to visit him
Once
Why visit him?
There must be a reason
No, just dropped in
Panzers said he met you and Luyadi in Marseilles
He said you want him to trade drug for him
He is lying
Someone named Simon left his telephone number in Paris
3488996...Any impression?
Of course yes, that's my telephone number
Then you provide Luo Heroin
No, I didn't, no one will call me Simon
I gave the telephone number to Luo
We have tracked Panzers's telephone number
He phoned you
A lady asked Luo if he need the goods
What's the matter?
I don't know, ask Noria
Someone told Luo, Simon just left
No one will call me Simon
No one?
That's too ambiguous
Many people named Simon
After that, he asked for Maxime, your brother
Are you clear?
Many people named Maxime!
You admit your brother answered the call
He is not around, not at all in France
He was driven out
After that, he was back
He answered the call
Can you explain?
I have nothing to explain!
If you have any evidence, just accuse me
I understand my right
No, I can't hear anything
How do you know?
How?
Wearing grapevine?
I don't know
Is it serious?
They actioned
They all heard
You have no evidence to accuse him
Marseilles's police ask you to go for a drive?
Yes, his brother will be happy!
I'm alright
Can I see you later?
When? Later
Call me first?
Bye-bye, Lambert
I'm Gam...
Lawyer Lambert, how are you? See you later
No problem
Try to ask them to calm down
Margin is looking for me
Bicha usually hugs me
I prefer he give me money
How much does he owe me?
He will pay off
Does he work now?
But he has a specialty to earn money
You are so good, why do you have no job?
Am I on vacation?
Nobody will put cash at home
Find other things to do
If you are arrested, you will be in big trouble
If I introduce those big figures to you
They will ask who is the buffoon?
I'm joking just now
That's not funny
You won't laugh if bulletin shot in your ass
Those people are not humorous
We are already disappointed, especially now
All are killing each other
Simon is arrested
In Tunisia, complain for hiking up of the bread...
600 people died in the riot
Now, he will talk about the case of Simon
He is not my privy C
These are heard
Marseilles orders...
Can you speak again?
What order?
(A hue and cry from court)
Police in Marseilles has already inform relative departments in Paris
That's from judger
For this case, I think they won't let him go
Marseilles will arrest you, that's a bad news
Even harder in Paris
They won't let him go
I will try my best
I will help the girl out
We just care about brothers
Why not bail him out like in USA
Marseilles want to tack him to death
No true gangs in France
What are they afraid of?
In Holland, German, Spain
If bailed out, he can come out
Why don't you warn Simon?
You are our private lawyer, aren't you?
My mother warned him, what does that mean?
Someone blame him out, I just receive the news
We are hep
Thanks, great
But I eat too much
Ok, anyway
What's that? How does it come?
Mint wine
The lady over there invites you
Who? Which one?
She is Aicha, Shaby's wife
The one whom you helped out of the jail
Good health!
I have a talk with him
We can trust him
Ok, sign
Sign what? I won't sign
It's you said
I said nothing
I refuse to sign
It's the same whether you sign or not
I won't sign
If he won't say, we are in trouble then
I will catch them, send them to Marseilles
Try another way
He is really troublesome
Let's see then
Your coat
I want to find the policeman
Just a minute, you wait first
I want to see him!
Damn!
You have seen him
Late for 2 hours
What do you do with that woman? Idiot
Do you like her?
She excites you?
Xi, don't be nervous
Anyway, she is troublesome now
Her procurer is mad
He can't manage her, he is a madman
He is the damn criminal
Shut up, I can't talk with you seriously
You always ignore
No, tell you, it's she who pursue me, do you know?
Look at your suit
Like a procurer
Of course! He ask me to be a procurer again
Yes, really, friend
Don't you think so?
It's no problem dining with a cheater
But they always want more
You said I become a cheater? Aren't you?
Yes, yes
Ok, we make it clear
I don't like you doing that
Come on
Is Lydie downstairs?
Nobody here
I can't let you in
I see her car is still here
I said, you can't go inside
Is she here?
No, I've already told you
They are talent cheater
You are here!
I have friends here, Inspecteur Mangin
See one, and then see all!
I was caught by fly cop!
Me? Come on!
I can't work soon
D¨¦d¨¦ will be back soon
Tell him things have gone
He should understand
I told him, he can't believe me
I don't know, prosecute him
Grame him is ok
Ok, will your policeman friend help?
What are you doing?
Speak with inspecteur
He will take back the accusation
Don't follow her, she is drunk
Sorry, a friend has a birthday party
Come on
I'd better go back first
He is already mad
Now he is really unhappy
Good night, no, wait
Sorry
D¨¦d¨¦ should say sorry to me
Did you see? Ah?
You arrest him, he asks me to defend for him
Can you do that?
Maybe I put him into jail again
He never know it's me
At least I can let him in jail for another two years
He would be in prison and he will thank me
Sometimes, you are really funny
It's the best way dealing with police
No harm at all
If yes, they ask for it
Anyway they deserve
I have tired of defending for my privy C
I tell you
They are murder and thief
Things in their archives are truth
We just do what we need to do
I tell judger: (Judger...
He didn't do that, he is a kind man)
My privy C's are all guilty
I'm sure
It's incredible
Can I see inspecteur Lolun?
Ask the lady, go
How is it going?
Gauthier, are you ok?
Do you go to Pizi restaurant for dinner?
Are you happy yesterday night?
Inspecteur, how are you
How are you?
Let me talk to him
Do you know him?
Ren¨¦, go over there
How about the girl?
I go to see her, contact later
Mr. Aijiashu? Follow me
Oh, seat here
Averyone called Ren¨¦?
Yes, French name, I like it
You are criminated in 1980
Yes, bribery and ammo trade
Can you tell me...?
Do you have any impression of these names?
No, I don't think so
Do you have any impression of Luo Panzers?
Ever heard of Luo
But Panzers, no impression
I knew one or two Luo in bar
They usually came to the bar
Good, then it seems that...
Luo called you in bar in Marseilles
I can't remember whether any guest called me
or anybody called me
Who are responsible for the answering the phone
Me
Then Luo called you
Inspecteur, listen to me, when I had something to do...
I will ask guest or other people to answer the phone
Coz I can't answer myself, no time
Do you have any impression with the people in the photo?
I know this one, he is Simon
I saw the girl one or two times in bar
She was coming to find somebody
Whom?
If I'm not wrong, I met her on the phone
I can recognize her voice
She called to find Simon
How do you know Simon?
I knew him when I was young
We are neighbors, I know his family
I know his brothers, Jean and Maxime
Where do they live?
I can't tell you
I don't like those ask for the address of guests
Then you explain...
Why did Panzers call to the bar to find Simon?
Mr. Inspecteur, usually somebody called here
Sometimes I keep the message for the guest
Panzers usually called here
Yes, many times a day
But I'm not sure if it was from Panzers
What do you make a living?
They are not my friends
But Simon is a man not attend to his proper work
Jean and Maxime, I don't know
I'm not familiar with them, just ordinary guest
Ok
Shall I go?
Make a record first
Come here, open it
Ciga?
I'm hungry, anything to eat?
What do you want?
Sandwich? Anything
What sandwich?
Ham
What do you drink?
Water
Give me sandwich and water then
Ok, come here
Come here
Get a number, quick
Ok, your number
Manager, how are you
It's Marie Vedret
For the training of police
She will work with us
Mangin, take care of her
Sure
If any case, let her do
She is ready anytime
She is really extraordinary
Anything funny?
Take a photo first
Sit there
Wait, let me put the things down
Your number?
Take care!
Great
Again
If know then point him out
That's alright, look
Go, they won't hurt you
Ah, it's you, is your finger alright?
Ah, I'm in my shop
Three young men came in
They pointed to me with gun
Order me hand in the keys of the coffer
I refused
The one with gun dropped the gun
Picked out a knife
Cut my finger
Did they wear masks?
No, they didn't
We find one of them
Try if you can recognize him, look
Then, I can hardly beare the ache
I waved my arm
I hit the...
Alarm, they ran away
They are all gone
Now listen to me
Try to recognize the ugly face
Look at behind the curtain
Shall I look?
Don't be afraid, they can't see you
Come, look
Can you see?
Yes
How?
No
I can't recognize anyone here
Which one?
I can't recognize
Not the no. 5?
He isn't
Which number do you say?
5, no, he isn't
Ok, come here
Follow me
Lolun, come here
You said no. 5 isn't?
Look at the chart
Any familiar name?
Ah?
No one
Including Gauthier Luyadi?
Yes
Luo from Marseilles?
No
Did Simon ever say where to visit somebody?
I said, I never went there
He didn't say where
But he didn't go to Marseilles!
We know he usually bring heroin to...
Luo gave us names of you two
He lied!
I don't know him, he is lying
You knew him when he called you
Impossible, it's impossible to find my number
He called you to reserve the order
It's impossible to find my number
He can't called me
Your number is 3488996
Yes, how?
What?
What are you doing?
Again
Let's restart from the beginning
If you don't know Luo
He can't call you
We have track Luo's phone line
He called your number
I'm not interested
You will be interested
Educational
Is Simon here?
He has no goods any more?
Too bad, he doesn't know...
What should I do?
Ask him bring some goods tonight!
I have said, he has no goods!
Impossible! I have nothing left!
Even him
We should stop for a while, do you understand?
Why do you ignore without goods?
He had a little yesterday
Yesterday, I had no time
You need many?
He know how many I want
Don't know how to say
Today is weekend
Any impression?
That's not me
Great!
He called your number!
Maybe he phoned
I don't know him! Damn!
Say it when decided
Don't say any more (damn it!)
You said it's impossible to find your number...
Maybe Simon gave him my number
That's not the voice of Simon
Explain!
No, that's not me
Who is that?
How can I know?
Will woman answer the phone when you are out?
Then who is the woman answering the phone?
Maybe part-time workwoman of weekend
I doubt what on earth did you do in the weekend
Those girls won't answer the phone
They had their things to do
What did you do in the weekend?
Amah
Where?
Wherever has
Nonsense!
I don't believe
Would I say I please you with my voice?
Do you know three brothers Jean, Maxime or Simon?
Heard, but don't know
They are not live in France
Didn't they come to Paris?
Maybe for vacation...
It's your diary?
Yes
Names inside is your friends'?
Yes...
Who is Aicha?
Come...
Aicha?
I remember, Nov. 11, Aicha
The woman I know in gym
She gave me her phone number
To let us contact with you. Do you see her again?
Once...in the street
Didn't she call you?
I didn't gave her my phone number
Where did she live?
Can't remember
You do, where did she live?
Maybe 15th district
Strange, we checked her number
The one named Aicha
Lived in 20th district...
I don't understand
Gapha, replace me for a while
I will be right back
You look on us as fool?
Don't pretend to be innocent
Tell the truth!
Look, Panzers!
Do you know him?
An old woman know you
What's this?
I tell you...but I want to tell the truth!
An old woman saw you and recognized you
Which old woman?
The one you cut her finger
Are you silly?
She recognize you!
Who did?
I didn't hurt any old woman
You cut her finger down!
I never cut down the finger!
To get the password of the coffer
Coffer? Password?
Nonsense
Not nonsense, tell the truth
What truth?
The coffer, stupid!
I don't know what are you talking about!
(For our daughter)
She know you can cut somebody's finger
Bad guy can be kind, too
I agree that people like you
My T-shirt, shit
Look!
A big fuss
He is son of a gun!
Get down the murder!
To a big fuss! Son of a gun!
What happened?
Nothing, I have a backup T-shirt
If I pee shall I hold it?
You are still here?
Don't be so impolite!
Coz you are a trainer?
Be polite
I'm edgy!
Come in
Mangin!
What happened?
Nothing, he ram on the table
Write a report to me
Understand
I don't like that!
Can you recognize your own voice?!
Not mine!
Who answered? Aicha?
Where do you find the key?
Can you recognize?
Yours or Simon's?
I never saw that
Not yours?
Do you know what will happen to you?
I will send you to be on trial in Marseilles
Shut up...
Shameful
He is educating on us!
Listen yourself
What do you want to do?
Tell me what happened?
Yours or Simon's?
I will send you to Marseilles to be on a trial
Sure!
Follow me
Let's go
Are you sure we can succeed
Tell him why you attend the action
They take all my things away
For 6 hours, why so long time?
I'm not feeling good
Coz the wine!
Shut up!
Must be
Like an utterly worthless person!
I have a good appetite
An utterly worthless person!
Are you still in India?
Look at your blood pressure!
You didn't drink there!
What do you want to do?
Burst the vein!
Do you want to play?
Go away!
No, he is angry
Just outside...
I used all the night
Are you familiar with outside?
Everything is familiar!
I have a friend from other place
He is familiar...
Impersonation
I remember when I was young, in the bar
The guy always say to winebottle
The remaining is not too much...
They said to winebottle
He said looking at them...
Sirup... How are you!
See them...?
Mint...rice cake...
The guy is really serious
Me, too
I'm not sure
Almost done, but you mess it up
I want the woman...
3, 4, 5...
Ok, done
I like the girl
I will be in trouble...
You son of a gun!
He is done...
Over there...behind Gauthier!
Relax...Come...
I finish my archive
Have a drink we go to Ren¨¦
Who makes record of me...?
Are you mad?
We are talking about business
Wait... Mr. Mangin?
I'm busy
Looking for you
Mangin
Where?
It interests me, I come right now
How about commando?
You ask them go
I thought you went to bar
We are behind
A man with knife...
Chahuana Street..., we go
D¨¦d¨¦?
We find him later
The same route
All get on the car
Go!
They mess you up
They are bound to die!
Find a good dream
I'd better go back to Marseilles by air
Only one hour
No, that will mess it up
Ok, it's too bad for you
Just a business within two days!
Ambulance is coming...
You missed the corpse
Shall we check them?
Of course not
Don't do that in public
You needn't
You needn't ask to get the information
What happened?
Someone called that heard sound of gun
No witness
But find an arab killed
Is he dead or not?
Sent to first aid, it's a miracle he came back
It's the best they kill each other, I like most
I track them
How are you..., D¨¦d¨¦ beat you again?
Do you know why?
He loses up the money again
He loses money and she help to sodomize others
You two are really having a good taste
He hurt my face, how could I work?
If he beat me like a policeman
without wound...
I have regular customer
I'm not wandering in the street
I will be used to it
Money is evil!
D¨¦d¨¦?
I don't want to be cold all the night
He is upstairs..., where else to go?
Give the keys to me
He hide in my home
Oh, that's your home
I pay the rent, rent under my name
Let's go
With her? Any trouble?
Don't exaggerate...
We can handle him...
People like him always bring us trouble
What then?
Don't be slowly
D¨¦d¨¦ is yellow race
Only beat woman
That's the thing
You stay
You'd better follow me...
go there
Contact you later
Better he doesn't see you
Don't put me inside!
Go back to be procurer!
I hurt my foot when I broke the door!
We find 40 grams' drug
That's his, not mine!
Who ask the 40 grams'!
We can see you everyday
The accusal is small
Whatever the accusal is
My duty is to do like that
Do you want one?
I need, I have got
Search everywhere...
Take him away!
Search everywhere!
Let me go!
What are you doing here?
Police
Drive licence and car licence
Aren't you crazy?
Mangin, he lashed me with belt!
Didn't we arrest him?
No, we didn't...
Go inside...
No, we don't
It's a good place for a policeman
You are rich!
Just render one
How much does it costs
I pay by cash
You are so lucky, they just finish
I really like it
you are afraid of being ugly
Go and see!
Do you have children?
Yes, two
How old are they?
one is 15, the other is 10
Where do you and your wife sleep?
But bed seems to be inversed...
She didn't die in the bed
Now my elder daughter sleep there
She is living inside the room
I really like it
You are really gentle...
Extreme misery
Say when my feeling is ok!
Like a shy prostitute!
Can I bathe?
Look, the wine is good
I spend much money
Be careful, it is too hot
Where do you sleep?
Over there
There?
It will be better you are alone there
My mum is not in good mood, she said...
If I can start from the beginning
I would rather be a prostitute
I'm good looking, she said
Like many other women
She think prostitutes are pretty
or coquettish
How old are you?
19 doesn't believe love
I call you later
How are you
Ren¨¦, how are you
Why didn't you show up last time?
I have something to do
You are in trouble
Go to see Jean
He needs me, real
I can't...
Simon is looking for you, too
Ok
He wrote to me, he is disappointed...
I have saved the girl
He wants to know why is he still in
His phone call is tracked
His dealer looks me as a fool
One day he said towel
then spinner
Then selling blanket
fitment
Then he said
Simon planed to carry the goods
The guy is a fool
Listen to me, Luo must take back his affidavit
A cup of water please?
Luo will deny in the front of judger
I mean
I am sure he will deny
Will he admit the crime beforehand?
What shall we do then?
I'm sure he will deny
How are you, Maxime, are you ok?
What's the condition?
Are you ok?
Yes
How is the non-dead guy?
You look yourself
He is still in bandage after 3 months
That's my tendon
What happened?
Agnail
Which kind?
Can't remember
Dr. told me, but I forget
I didn't wear your shoes luckily
They ask me to operate again
I'm scared
That's not funny
They must breast him!
He can't shot right in short distance
The guns blocked
You mean your gun is blocked?
The one you shot on stays with 4 guys
How lucky you are
Things are bad for you now
Keep lowness
If he doesn't turn out, we shouldn't turn out either
I hope you get him down quickly
He should turn out after the examination
Police in Marseilles know, too...
If they want, maybe delay for one year
One year?
Yes, miss!
Any medicine for headache?
I go to find one
Follow me
I think we have no way
Here you come
Simon is in prison
Who knows what does Jean want to do
He is useless
Don't worry, he is not as stupid as me
Of course not
Don't do that after being out
I almost lose my life
You only care about yourself and money!
That's it
Yes, you are right
I'm supprised by the money problem!
I don't like money
Nor any trouble
Is that simple
Listen to me, if you are questioned
You know nothing, understand?
Never heard of Gauthier
I try to contact your brother
Why can't you stand in the bright side?
You are overexpose
If I were you, I will go back to Tunisia
Tunisia?
I would rather go to prison
Not long
After things go down, you can come back
Those policemen won't stop
Till you are dead
Do you notice?
Ok, enough
Shall we go?
Maxime, we're going
Thanks for your letter
I understand
Mangin, how are you
Thanks for visiting my privy C
Thanks Gapha, he is fromo Marseilles
Let me introduce, lawyer Sha
Marie, our training head!
Nice to meet you, I'm Lambert
You are out?
Bailed out
But I have been there for 3 months
You will be innocent
Judger don't like woman to be in prison
They think women are weak and innocent
I'm innocent
It's just my duty
I won't follow one guy to death all my life
Out is out
Isn't it better?
Why do you come here?
Just drop in
That's our duty
Then come to your duty
The date tonight is still ok?
I think so
Bye bye!
I hope you can dine with us tonight
If I am a cheater
I am eager to arrested by you
Shut up
You are pretty
How about Maxime's lawsuit?
Can't change anything!
He insisted, so I went to meet him
Mangin, stop!
Sorry, inside
Will you come tonight?
No, I will go back to Marseilles
Continue trying hard
It's a challenge for me
We try our best to arrest them
The judger just lets them go
You think that's funny!
The woman shouldn't be set free
Doctor, how are you
Gapha, from Marseilles vice squad
I'm making a record for Sha
It's order from court
How is his situation?
Physically, I'm ok
Then we start
Please
Ah?
More policemen
Maxime, are you ok?
I'm very fine
Nothing to tell us?
You falled down on the knife when you were on a walk?
Maybe
Simon is in prison while you are lying here
How pity is your brother!
Why?
Simon is in prison and you take over his business
Sit side by side with Gauthier, don't you?
No, I mean
Mean what?
Coz...
I don't know him
Listen to him
You accept...       What's wrong with you?
The tendon
Is your heel ok?
Aching?
Should be
I ask you promise to confess
Who are you?
Maxime, Simon's brother?
Maxime...
How this happened?
I don't know
You don't know
That bag is nice
Where did you buy it?
Gamin District
These are my brothers, Aicha...Jean...
My little brother Jevin...my lawyer
He introduces...
this person...
He gave us keys of the house
So she looks faithful, but
We don't know what does she do behind us
You let them to be these way?
Leave it
I bring the money home
You asked for the money
Simon doesn't let me to be a prostitute
You can only do that
You are hopeless, so...
intermeddle all the day
Simon really chose a winner!
Shut her up, or I will beat her!
I'm going out, bye
Judger will ask you what's (Gray goods)
What's (pink goods)
You say (blanket) is ok
Kidding?
I'll try my best
Ok
He is a fool
He doesn't understand at all
Wait here like a savior
Come back to Earth!
Don't you miss your man in prison?
Understand his situation?
A good woman
Always support him behind him
Thanks for your reminder, if sentence him 10 years
I won't wait for him for so long time
As long as I'm alive, he won't stay in prison for 10 years
If yes, you should ask him first
If I see you are with man
I will shot him dead
Ren¨¦, calm down
Simon won't know
Our habit is
Don't touch woman unknown
I'm not stupid
I will find in other places
If you do that, you are finished
If I know, are you sure!
Our family is keen on face-saving
We are all respected by others
I'm just kidding
Don't joke with such things
Will you go to Marseilles?
Yes, with his mother
Can you give me fare of train?
I'm poor
I need money
More
I want first class
What can she do with 50 dollars?
Then you give her?
What's wrong with you?
No, let me
No, I invite
Come here, give me the bill
Come on, you have no money
My money is more that yours
Your privy C never change money
You can say they usually lose their money
I bet with them
They always like that
If I bet 10, they will bet 1000
He don't know how to get back the money
He just can say: later
Find it after I help you out
But they never change money!
Oh, really?
You must change money to me
Listen to me, she means
She is too...
Thank you, miss
Shall we...one night?
Can't remember anything?
I remember you
No change
It's a thing 10 years later
Don't touch me
I swear...
Maybe the clothes...
There are many pretty and lovely women
Less pretty than you
No, I mean
I have been tired of this kind of life
I plan to sell
What do you want to do?
I will leave
There are 4000 lawyer buildings in Paris
Twenty of which accept big case, profitable
200 of which have a good business
Others...
Which one you can go to?
Nowhere
I have other things to do in the future
For example?
Court
Hope one day I can...
Be inspector or judger
Will judger wear diamond earing?
I can take off in the court
Sure?
Let's dance, ok?
No, I don't dance
I eat too much
I don't want to go to any place
If she wants to go...
Let's dance
(You are still so lovely...)
She don't believe I date you
She thought it's another woman
It's none of my business if it's another woman
You are really...
Really born...
It's yes for her and me
born to be a couple
You can say so
Full of mysterious
Yes, I don't know why
That's your business
Marie
I want you
Shall we stop?
Do you like me to say (continue)?
You are not grateful at all
You can go
Mangin, you are stupid
Should say have a bad taste?
Really? Why?
Two policemen!
Am I really not good?
Actually do you think of it?
Yes, I do
I don't
I never do with policeman
Come
I mean go to bed!
What an attitude you are
Do you want to cajole me?
We now need D¨¦d¨¦
Western Indian will let woman be prostitute quickly
Two weeks later, then abandon them
But they are rhythmic
What's the point?
I know why do you kick me under the table
You put D¨¦d¨¦ to jail, I date with his girlfriend
Son of a gun
Are you ok?
Ok
Not dancing?
I'm not coming to dance
But go
I wanted to invite you to drink
But here only woman can invite
I have no money!
Bad business?
No, wait...
Calm down
You go tonight by air!
Yes
Or I can't face my work
And I'm work for someone!
Why do you help D¨¦d¨¦
The necklace is beautiful
Anything else?
You can take mine
Do you want?
Too bad, yours is worthless
Worthy of feeling
Don't you like?
You dance well
We are forgeted!
Noria, are you happy?
We shall leave each other?
Yes, ok
Sometimes high, sometimes low
Sometimes alone or not
You will think why are you with bad guy...
Do you always ache like that?
My mother doesn't love me...
So I want to balance with woman
You love to find excuse
May say in that way
Get on the car
I drive you to your car?
Then we say good night?
I fetch the car, you needn't send me back home
Can I ask you a question?
Will you treat me like Lambert did just now?
You won't
Why I won't
Maybe you and she are not alike
You just imitate
Those people don't know how to accept you
I don't want to be accepted by others
Because your man is in the prison
You can't be with others
Lambert is not the style you like
You were factitious when you two are together
You are stupid
Is he good in the bed?
He loves me at his first sight of me
Sure
It's useful to have a good lawyer
Understand, business matter
Can give me more rights?
Partially, let me go
You are stupid!
Come, kiss me
Stop, are you crazy
That's too ridiculous
Let me go!
That's too ridiculous!
You think if you love a woman for a while
you can...
That's too ridiculous
Sorry
But I believe the moment
Real
I understand
Then what shall we do now?
Let's go for a drive
We go to buy Eiffel Night
I want to read newspaper
Please
I never love anybody
I do
You say, it's...
I love him very much
I think we can last for long
Stupid
If love is like that, it's finished
You will feel uncomfortable at the beginning
It's more sense of safety if believe in nothing
I feel bad
It seems that I have no future
I think I'm wasting my life
No, you will be ok
Now it's ok
We behave like two children
That's what I like
We talk all the night, forget the time
Do that from 15 or 16
Day is breaking
I'm going
Train will start an hour later
Hello, can I speak to Mr. Mangin
No, it's for me
That's alright, thanks
Can I ask for the second number?
I'm ok
No...
Yes...
Simon's little brother left a bag
I don't know, he tell me not to open it
Have a look!
There are two guns inside
What shall I do?
Do nothing, as if never see it
If someone ask you to send the bag
Never do that
When will you be back?
Tomorrow
One more thing: change a new lock
So that they have no keys to open
You try to contact me less frequently
Anything wrong?
Nothing
But I lose confidence
Don't lose confidence
They won't keep me for long
I know, I'm trying...
I've try my best
Even if we broke up
I think I love you for ever
I never forget you
Even if I'm with other man
I swear I never love others
Do you what happened when girls do that?
You mean you plan to leave me?
No, I swear I won't
I'm sure you are good
You are for my good, I know
Not like your other brothers
I don't want to destroy the feelings of your family
But that's true
They won't let you love any woman
Money is everything
I will go back to be a prostitute at last
They think so
Noria, listen to me
You won't end like that
No need at all...
To end with prostitute like others
If you need money, ask from Ren¨¦
Ok
How to deal with the robbery?
Our people won't steal each other
What do you mean?
What robbery?
All our money are stolen
Noria, they say you stole them
Look, you are so again!
I know it's not you, I believe you
I love you
If it's me I will ask you to forgive me
Won't beg them
None of their business
I want to trust you
I really want, but it's serious
That's about our family
Swear, none of your business
I assure you with my head
Are you nervous, ladies?
She is already ok
Ok, V...
The moment comes, tomorrow is an important date
You are required to accept the exam
Two days later, she can teach you
She will be police officer
Some people can be decided quickly
Some have to wait...
Wait? I can't be trained like that all my life
Normal training is 3 years!
No, thanks
Half pint
Does test give you great pressure?
Bachelor of Arts
No, Master's
Better!
I hate exam
Good, (hallucinogen)
Why call me (hallucinogen)?
Detective hating love!
Good!
I think I will miss you much
Let me see if I can find him
That's private !
Where are you?
Who are (they)?
I come right now
You don't know where I go, ok?
Happy tonight
They will let him say, you don't know them
I don't know them
Who do they think did it
My little brother and I
They think money is stolen by us
What money?
I've said, steal from them
Their mother said to me
How much?
I don't know, she didn't say
I think it's a big amount
How much on earth?
I don't know
Listen to me... If you want me to help you
You should tell me the details
Understand?
Did you steal the money?
No, I didn't
I mean
Help my brother out
Help me
They will harry him
What do you want me to do?
Go after them with gun?
I depend totally on you
Don't disappoint me
I'm scared
Wait
Come on
Calm down, ok?
Ok
What did you do?
Try to attack
That afternoon, Maxime called me
Said there is a bag for me
Within witch there are two guns, handed to my little brother
Then he said he asked my little brother...
to hand in the bag with guns
Let him testify them
I never see my little brother after that
Here is the name and sign
I never mention about the money
Things are complicated
I stay to monitor her little brother?
Nonsense!
I mean! You must stay
See you later
Is your eye better?
Unluckily
My cornea has been operated for 3 times
What are you doing at home?
Waiting for you
Jean has something to talk to you
Don't worry
Nobody is angry
Noria, it's Aicha
Everything is bad, your brother is coming, too
How do you say? Bitch!
Are you crazy?
No, he is just a bit excited
Come on
Let me talk with him
I want to listen to his voice
Ask him to listen
Come and help me
They will kill me
Please, Noria
Or they will kill me!
You'd better come
Don't bring anybody
I'll be here in one hour
Why do they all go to your place?
You give them keys or they break up the door?
Both
How can?
After I'm out
For the faith, I gave them keys
Then I add a new key
The key is bad, I think they did
You betrayed your brother?
Come on, one is enough!
I don't hurt Simon
Simon, go to hell!
I always care about the problem
He is in prison
We are close to each other
I live with him
He really loves me
He is a Muslim
What's the point?
You just know how to misunderstand him
I know what attitude they use to deal with woman
Not bad than us
Noria...
I sleep beside you
That's not my business!
Who are you?
Why beat me?
You are her brother, you must know!
I know nothing!
Shut up, stupid!
Don't talk to him, ok?
We have something to do!
Come on, it's kidnap!
It's time
If they are in the stairs?
Aicha, do you hear?
I won't come in if it's not my brother who opens the door
I want my brother open the door
Don't be silly
Come in, we can negotiate
Is that negotiation?
That's not my idea...
Don't move
Le me take care of your brother
Do you see what they do?
thanks for keep me here
Whose gun?
Not mine?
Do you want to trap me?
I swear the gun is not mine
What's that?
My savings
So many savings
I struggle for it, legally
Were you amah?
He doubts everyone, including me
Do they use wire?
Yes, 200 volts
How is your head?
Nothing
Send him to hospital
What did I do?
You will be more sate in my home
No 17, 3rd floors, Dedilace street
Key is here
You know my brother
I saw him in your home
Hello
I need to take back the bag?
Ah? What bag?
Don't tell me you don't know
You are Noria's lawyer
It's you who keeps Noria outside of prison
You know Noria! Know Mangin!
What happened?
Why come to my home at 3am?
What bag?
What's the difference between 3am and 10 am?
We are not scaring you
What does it mean?
You take a seat
Let's talk first, then you can make a phone call
What happened?
What's the matter?
You know Noria steal the bag with money and drug
I don't know Noria...
or bag!
What happened?
Is that gun?
I'm lawyer, I'm not bastard
I always tell all I know
Don't cry
We can cry louder than you
You are lawyer all the time
Now you are a cheater
amphisbaena!
I don't understand what do you mean
He is a fool
Listen to me, I'm from law society
You will lose your business doing that
He won't pay attention, he is a fool
I'm coming to make it clear
I don't want to have any problem with you and Mangin
I just come to want my things back
What?
The bag with drug and money
Any problem?
Aren't you alone?
You are asking or seeing me?
Mangin, I have trouble
What happened?
They act like mad dogs
Noria stole their things and went away
How do you know it was Noria?
They told me
They are abnormal
They think I collude with her
Incredible
They think or know?
No time joking
She is in danger
How much did she take away?
They said 200 thousand
I'm scared
They will kill her if found her
I must find her
He has detracted the money
They won't find him
I will talk to him, face to face
Even if I lose my life, I should know the reason
They won't hurt you
They just scare you
I've try to speak for you
But if they find I can do nothing
They won't be polite
If they appear, I can't stay and wait for the death
I have gun, I will deal with them with gun
Don't say that
I'm not warning you
I'm not good at shoot
The hurt won't be too much
That's gift
They give me the gun
Are you crazy!
Why accept such gift?
You shouldn't accept such gift
I haven't wear clothes yet
I think it's safe here
I want to talk to you
They dare to kill policeman
You know how to shot to pretect yourself
Of course I know
I never shoot
Why not find Ren¨¦?
Kidding?
That's put sheep to the mouth of tiger
They are angry with me
Coz I can't bail Simon out
Nothing can be achieved...
I'm finished
You'd better go
I have done something wrong
I shouldn't sleep with the woman
She is a bitch
I shouldn't sleep with her
She is a cheater
What are you doing?
Are you crazy
Let me tell you
Listen to me
You are mad
Shut up!
Shut up and close the door
Did Simon tell you where is the goods
No one knows
Not in Aicha, not in their mother's either
He knew you pocketed it
Don't speak to me like a policeman
Did you take it?
Is it important any more?
Whom I care about is you
You care about nothing
Did you take the money?
No...
They will kill you
They won't let you go
No, you won't! You are the worst
Ridiculous
I'm the enemy of them
What I care about it's true
Why do you usually cheat me?
Why?
Do you understand?
I always lie
I lie all my life
Cheat teacher in the school
Cheat my brother
My family, anybody
My family thought I'm studying lodging school
Noria is just the name Simon renamed for me
I cheated him
I think I love him
Simon, his brother, Ren¨¦...
They don't care if we tell the truth
Arab have their habit
their truth
But they seems cheating
I like that
Actually they want to kill you
You won't kill anybody tonight
But others will, they will
Money is in the storeroom in the central station
I know you are silly to do this, but it's late
Do you love Lambert?
No
Can you let me be a policeman's wife?
Then what do you do tonight?
Nothing for tonight
Nothing?
How else?
Do you dream of being in the beach with palm?
With many waiters serving you
To me, it's heaven
Let go the things of beach
But you can't go into the water
There are coral and shark
Then you hurry
It's too bad of that kind of life
Of course
Searching, Waiting, tracking, that's the job
You shouldn't do that, shouldn't like them
Money, money!
They only know how to rob and bet!
I'm not too nervous about money
Will you advice me turn the money back?
You are as silly as them
I broke them down and the drug
Coz I got the goods
I don't do with you
You have nothing
I have nothing
We should find another bastard
You think it is funny
Give me the bag
Where?
There, your feet
Wait for me here
Policeman keeping promise
Mangin,
That's the most important
Keep promise
Sorry
All are there
Think for a while!
Will, Mangin!
Thanks
If you need help, ask me
I will, bye
Good night, Mangin
Are you satisfied?
I'm satisfied with the money
But who knows he has any plan!
Mr. policeman!
Come here!
No wander, do you remember it?
Have a cup
What's this?
Distilled spirit...
No, whisky
What are you doing here?
They set you free?
I'm innocent
Can't stop you beating me!
But you can't?
Jpw about your wife and children?
Only 7 to 10 days
Again?
Yes
Where is another rattoo?
I will find the place
Which name you would change to?
Yuxun
That's my middle name
Louis.Yuxun.Mangin
She wants to call him Stephin
But that's fucking name, isn't it?
If girl?
Can't be girl
She checked
No, it's boy
Yes, if boy
yes
Will you go back to sleep tonight?
My woman knows I'm here
She trusts me very much now
I seldom go out
I've been much quiet
Goodbye
I'm leaving
I supposed you will say that sooner or later
But I think...
You will say it with anger
Now matter how, you won't understand
The end is just galling
My mother finds something wrong
But we need to sleep
I'm tired, too
It will be clear later
Do you think sleep can solve the problem?
Yes, because you are tired
I'm not tired
You are so tired
No tend to continue at all
Things have past
No, not past
I can't live with you
You must be disappointed
I can't fulfill man's need
You teach me not to cheat
I just think you can love me
Just so simple
I'm good at love
Maybe I'm too young
You are still strong like before
Immoral!
You won't care about anything
Like a sealed tower
Nothing can touch you
That's why I leave you
Do you think they will let you go?
They have taken back the money
That won't satisfy them
They are niggards
They only killed several people in ten years
They won't come to me
They always said
(Mountains never collide)
They won't hurt me
One month, one year...
You are not the same as them
How do you know?
Everyone said policeman and thief are the same
You don't afraid of me, I won't care
I just do things I like
Kiss me goodbye
Noria, let it go
Kiss
No
You want to suppress your love to me?
I'm very sure
The End