Wait, wait, wait.
No. Come on.
Let's go, you said you would.
Come on, I'm gonna make you like nature.
I don't think nature likes me very much.
All I'm saying is you don't get
fresh air like this in New York.
Okay. Sure, whatever.
All right, you wanna go back?
What?
To the house, not the city.
Is he going to...
What?
Tom!
Here, here. I'm gonna...
He's not breathing.
I'm gonna call someone.
All right, I'll go.
- I'll go.
- No, no, stay.
I got it, I got it.
Breathe.
I think this needs stitches.
Doesn't need stitches.
Just... just put that on.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Do they even teach shrinks that?
You'd be surprised
what they teach shrinks.
Just put that...
Just put...
- Ow!
- Oh, sorry, sorry.
No, I'm just kidding.
It didn't hurt.
Oh.
Do you wanna...?
You all right?
Yeah, yeah. I just...
Just that kid.
I know. It was touch-and-go.
You risked your life for
a complete stranger.
It's not like I had a choice.
Look...
If I wasn't such a fantastic swimmer,
then I wouldn't have gone in, but I am.
And, anyway, I'm all right, right?
Thanks.
Look, what you did was very brave.
I just got scared. That's all.
I know.
I'll take that to the cleaners.
It's his, actually.
Paramedics must have
grabbed the wrong one.
I was gonna stop by the hos...
Oh, hey, hey, hey.
It's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
Hey, Mary.
They were about to admit a
Dr. Thomas Seymour before I noticed.
Ian Wilkinson.
You get a read on him?
No. Temazepam in his veins,
maybe 10 of 'em.
Oh, Jesus.
Yeah, Mary and Joseph.
Hello.
I thought you might be looking for this.
I'm the, uh...
I'm the guy that pulled you out.
My wife was pretty shook up,
so she'll be happy to know...
Dr. Seymour?
It's, uh... it's me.
Danny?
Danny Miller?
Yeah.
Wow, I'm sorry. I... I didn't know
that you were, uh, out.
They kept it pretty quiet.
Right.
So I... Ian, um...
Oh, uh, Ian was the warden's first name,
Wilkinson was the chaplain's last,
so that's me now.
What has it been, 10, 12 years?
Really?
It feels like twice that for me.
Oh, of course, of course.
I'm sorry.
This is... it's...
Wild, right?
It makes you think, huh?
Yeah, it does.
Chaplain would say that, uh, coincidence
is the crack in human affairs
that lets God in.
A chaplain would.
Well, look, um, I gotta...
I gotta get to work,
so all things considered,
you... you look all right.
Yeah. Yeah.
All things considered.
You take care.
'Cause my mother's a bitch, 'cause
she didn't believe that he raped me.
The bitch said...
You know what she said?
Young lady!
She said I made it up.
Fuck her.
Her man gets two years,
two years probation,
and she blames me, takes it out on me.
Bitch killed my dog.
She killed my fucking dog, that's why.
I cut her, the bitch.
Showed her some fucking
justice across her face.
That is enough, Miss Demers.
Will counsel and the psychologist
please approach?
Dr. Seymour.
So, what do you think?
I'm... I'm so sick of that case.
"My dog. My dog. My dog."
You really think the mother's
boyfriend raped her?
I'm gonna violate him anyways,
before she kills him.
Kids usually need a reason
to kill somebody.
Not in that neighborhood.
Bought you a drink.
Why, thank you.
Ian Wilkinson.
He's one of yours?
Yeah, and you did a good thing.
Were you ever gonna tell me?
You know I couldn't.
Do the police know it's him?
I took care of that.
He was off his meds, he's depressed,
went for a swim.
A swim? Angie, Danny is...
He's Ian Wilkinson now, okay?
Yeah, when did we start doing that?
We do it every once in a while.
He's a very exceptional...
"Exceptional."
And damaged young man.
Mm-hmm.
Smart, bright.
He has a chance,
a future if we keep the police
and the press out of it.
He thinks you can help him.
Well, you know that's not gonna happen.
And you can't tell anyone
about this, not even your wife.
Have your drink, Tom.
You earned it.
That water was deep.
I gotta get back to court
and least look like I'm working.
Think about it.
So you're back Thursday, then?
No, no. I told you I'm filling in
for Bob this weekend.
You've been cutting down
on your hours, so...
- Yeah, I know. Sorry.
- ...we could use the cash.
You should come down.
- This weekend?
- Yeah.
Is there an opening or something?
No. No, it's just...
Because I just gotta
finish this chapter on parental abuse,
and I haven't listened
to the tapes yet, so...
No, it's just it's a good time.
I got it.
I hate talking about it this way.
- No, I get it.
- Really, I'm sick of it,
the calendars, the thermometers.
Hey, listen.
No, I... I want that.
I do. I want it.
Whatever it takes.
As many times as it takes.
- Okay.
- I'm your man.
I'm gonna try and finish up
here in the next few days
and get down there, okay?
You know what?
I'm gonna drive you down.
We'll stop at a B&B and
get right down to it.
Stop. It's fine.
Just finish whatever it is
you need to finish,
but try to come down, okay?
You're beautiful.
You know that?
It's too easy to assume
that Nicole simply lacks conscience.
Many children are obsessed with
issues of loyalty and betrayal,
but hers is a...
Primitive and exacting.
So the question then becomes
how to distinguish
between access to a personality disorder
and relatively healthy...
Danny. What are you...
What are you doing here?
Hey. I was just in the neighborhood,
and, uh, you left your letter,
uh, at the hospital the other day.
It has your address on it.
You didn't hear the doorbell?
- Mm-mmm.
- Anyway, it looked important,
like a bill or something.
Oh. Well, thank you.
You look a bit better.
How you feeling?
Well, I got out of the hospital,
and I slept like the dead.
Okay. Well, uh, thanks for this,
and, uh, I gotta get back to work, so...
What?
You're the only person
I can talk to about what happened.
Can I come in?
- Uh, sure.
- Yeah, thank you.
Yeah, of course.
I just...
Just h-have a seat.
I'll...
Look, Danny, I can give you
the name of someone else
who can help...
What are you doing?
What... please don't smoke in here.
Someone else, huh?
I'm the knife that's
been cast into the sea.
Excuse me?
Sigmund Freud, Doc.
No, I know who wrote it,
but I wouldn't categorize you that way.
Now please put the cigarette out.
I just want you to know that...
- No, Danny, stop.
- Can we just...
Please, we cannot do this.
I'm not your therapist.
Can we at least talk for a second?
No!
I'm sorry.
Jesus.
They convicted me for a crime
that I didn't commit, and you...
You basically sentenced me, so...
Can you at least help me
get my life back on track?
I rendered an opinion.
That's all.
You know that I'm innocent.
You gotta know that, right?
I actually don't know that,
and I need to ask you
to leave my house right now.
Do you understand me?
Now.
What the fuck?
What the hell?
Hey, Louis.
- Whah!
- Whoa.
Gotcha.
Really?
Good jab.
See you, Louis.
Hey, Mom.
I'm in here.
Louis tried to talk to you out there?
Ah, you could say that, yeah.
He keeps coming in here on his breaks,
talking and talking about the past.
It's very depressing.
I'm at a point I'm...
I'm ready to go downtown and
hire a Mexican or something.
Mom, what...
Where's my daughter-in-law?
She's in New York.
Oh, in the old days, it was the...
It was the men who went
on the business trips.
Mom, don't start with this.
Even if it's always
the women who do the work.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait a sec.
What did... what'd you do to your wrist?
I just... I slipped a-and fell.
Look, I'm really sorry
I can't stay for dinner,
but you sure I can't make you something?
Oh, for goodness sakes,
I can still take care of myself.
I know you... okay.
Thank you for getting my groceries.
I love you.
Okay. Okay, buddy.
Bye-bye.
My advice to you... a little
less thinking, a little more fucking.
I mean, look at me.
I got the four kids,
and let me tell you something.
That did not happen from thinking.
Mm. And three wives.
Defense rests.
What about you?
You're looking more distracted
and morose than usual.
What's that about?
You remember Danny Miller?
I just got a chill.
I ran into him.
He's out under another name.
And not a patient of yours, is he?
No.
Well, good.
Then stop working on what you're
working on and write that.
You could sell that in a second.
There is nothing creepier
than the truth, right?
Joke.
For God's sake, it was a joke.
Just don't talk to him
in any circumstances.
That was a long time ago.
Let that be a long time ago.
Yeah, he's implying it was
my testimony that convicted him.
Well, that's a little overstated,
don't you think?
I mean, come on.
I know he was no angel.
But still, it bothers me.
He was my last case
on that side of things.
When I think about it,
maybe we did go too fast.
Maybe we came at him a little too hard.
What... what are you talking about?
He didn't deny being there.
He admitted to putting the cushion
on her face, to touching her.
Yeah, but he didn't have any of
the old lady's skin under his fingers,
so there was nothing conclusive.
Nothing conclusive?
His goddamn fingerprints
were all over the bedroom, Teddy!
Easy, tough guy.
Holy cow.
You know, if we continue like this,
I'm gonna have to start
billing somebody, anybody.
Yeah, and the chickens...
I don't want to hear about the chickens.
For God's sake.
The fact of the matter is
you did the right thing.
You did, and there's
always gonna be questions.
I got one for you.
Do you think he honestly ran across you,
or do you think he found you?
He insists it was random.
Like anything's fucking random.
I tell you what.
If you need a weapon,
I'll get you a gun.
What is wrong with you?
Thank God they still make
reporters that look like that.
Wowee.
Hey.
Honey, is that you?
It's Angela.
Ange? What?
Ian.
Ian?
Ian Wilkinson turned up
at Morgan Hamilton Penitentiary tonight
trying to get himself re-incarcerated.
Tried to handcuff himself to a guard.
They want to commit him.
Well, maybe they should.
They want to commit him
unless his parole officer
or his therapist comes and gets him.
Okay. I'm not his therapist, so what...
That's not what he told them.
I can't get over there tonight.
Please help me out on this.
See, you... you gotta be kidding me.
Tom, like it or not,
you're part of this.
I gotta go.
Fuck.
Hey, pull over to the side of the road.
I gotta take a leak.
Yeah. Okay.
I'm sorry.
You all right?
Yeah.
I'm fine.
You know what?
Give me a drag of that.
Thought maybe you ran off.
Yeah, well, maybe.
Do you remember our last session?
The session before my trial?
I put my arms around your waist,
and you looked at me.
You looked at me, and you walked away,
and I never heard from you again,
I never saw you again.
I was 11 years old, Tom.
Okay. Well, um... you're out now.
You're here.
Do me a favor.
Crack the window, will you?
There's no smoking in my office, okay?
Ever.
I started, uh, burning
my fingertips in prison.
I don't know why I do it.
It's clean in here, very chic,
like a... a hotel.
Safe, nice...
No distractions.
Hmm, no distractions.
Now, is that why
you tried to get yourself
back into prison last night?
Yeah. Yeah, and I jumped
in the river to cool down.
You still taking the Temazepam?
Yep, 20 milligrams.
Where you living?
Some shithole.
You got a job?
The marina.
Anybody at home?
Nope.
What about your mom?
Dead.
I'm sorry.
They let me visit her in the
hospital with the cuffs on.
You know what killed my mother?
Those fucking handcuffs.
And my father wasn't even
fucking there when she went.
And, uh, he's in Norwich now,
in some narcissistic
coma he calls a bar.
He used to visit me at Windsor,
acted like I was at
some fancy prep school,
but when they take you to prison...
Well, you turn 18,
you know your life is over.
Look, I want you to know that I had
no idea that you went to prison then.
Don't lie, Dr. Seymour.
I'm not lying.
It's the truth.
That's bullshit!
Danny, it's not bullshit.
Listen...
Fucking sorry.
That's great.
That gets me my fucking
life back, doesn't it?
I didn't do it.
I didn't do it, and you know that.
Come on, do you really believe that?
The forensic evidence was overwhelming.
Time's up.
You know...
You could open your eyes
when we're doing it.
Oh, jeez, I'm sorry, honey.
The book is work.
This is supposed to be the fun part.
No, I... I know.
You're right. I just...
You should have come down.
I know. I know.
I know it's a good time for us to try...
No. No, because it was fun.
Because New York is fun.
New London is cloudy.
Hey, wait.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hang on there.
Wait a second.
Maybe I just get a little jealous
seeing you with all these
young artist types, huh?
Oh-ho.
Thomas Seymour jealous.
That, I like.
Oh.
You all right?
Um, my mind's just racing.
It's okay.
Go back to sleep.
Oh.
It's lopsided...
Well, yeah, now that
I'm talking about it.
Hey, honey, you moving out
on me one painting at a time?
She's got a show.
We ran into each other
at Pete's, by the river.
It's Ian, Tom.
You remember?
Yeah, o-of course, of course.
How are you, Ian?
How you doing?
Good.
We've been talking,
and he's thinking
of applying to schools.
I said that we could call around.
Sure. Sure, that... that sounds great.
What's this show that you...
Oh, no, it's nothing.
It's...
Bob called me at the last minute
and had to cancel, so I said
I'd put something up.
That's great, right?
Isn't that great?
Oh, no, yeah, it's definitely great.
It's not MOMA.
It's not nothing, though.
It's just a faculty show.
Yeah, no, I think...
I think it's great.
I'll definitely come down for it, hon.
Ian works the night shift at the marina,
so I said I'd give him a ride home.
You know what?
I... I'll take him.
Don't you have to go to court today?
I do, but I can drop him off.
It's right on the way.
Oh, okay. Great.
I... I have to get back
to the city, and...
It's crazy!
It is.
I prefer to drink out of a real cup.
So that's where I work,
and that's where I drink.
So, no kids, huh?
Nope.
Hmm.
'Cause sometimes I wonder
why my parents even bothered.
What were they looking for, you know?
Your dad really doesn't want
to see you at all, huh?
My dad wants to erase me.
He never wanted to see me, not really.
He had the garage.
He fixed it up like a workshop,
put a lock and key on it,
but he'd just sit there
and talk Fallujah, mostly.
He told me the story about he...
He blew a hole in this guy's chest,
and he slid down the wall
like a red glob of spit.
No, my dad, he just liked to hunt.
I hated it.
One time, maybe I was six...
He just pulled over
to the side of the road,
grabbed an automatic out of the back,
and shot six deer in seconds,
like we were in an ambush.
Bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop!
I was right beside him.
They were so beautiful up close.
He made me shoot one of them in the head
so it wouldn't keep on trying to get up.
I don't know if it was
the adrenaline or not,
but I... I couldn't stop crying.
With the blood s-splattering in my face.
My dad saw it.
Oh, he was pissed.
Just keep on going straight, man.
You know, I read somewhere
that we only use 10%
of our mental capacity.
You think about that?
Yes, as a matter of fact.
It's like buying a suit that's
too big for you, you know.
Like maybe one day, you're gonna fit it.
Hmm. Then what do you
think the other 90% is?
I don't know.
Maybe it's animal, you know?
Like, if we don't have
this tiny, little fraction,
we're just all animal-like,
like when we're sleeping
or when I was in the river.
No thinking, just animal.
Did you use CPR to revive me?
Yeah.
It wasn't your wife?
Why are you asking?
Nothing.
I'm just curious, you know?
I mean, your wife, she...
She's a very nice lady.
Mm-hmm.
Very sweet.
You're lucky.
She's hot.
- Hey, hey.
- Sorry.
Hey, uh, that's me right there,
that hunk of shit.
Hey, good-looking.
Ah.
Why don't you set your bags down,
and I'll help you take them up.
Oh, you're a prince, Ian.
Thanks.
You need to stop coming to my house.
Do you understand?
Listen, I want to help you,
but if you don't stop, we're done.
You're hurting me, Dr. Seymour.
Do you understand?
Ah, thank you, sweetheart.
You are in violation of
your supervised release.
You have the right to retain
counsel or to request counsel.
If you cannot obtain it
through ordinary means,
the court will appoint someone to you.
Do you understand?
He tried to rape his 13-year-old niece.
You were right about him.
Ugh.
Does Nikki know?
Probably.
Thank God she was in prison.
Can't believe how often
I'm saying that these days.
And Ian?
Yeah?
Have you been talking to him?
You sent me to go get him, remember?
Yes, and thank you.
After that?
What is it?
Did he say anything about me?
Because, uh, we were...
We have been speaking every night.
These talks are deep.
But lately, he's been a little quick,
distant almost.
I... I don't know if I said
anything to upset him.
Angela, he's your parolee.
No, I know that...
And how did he get out?
The headmaster at Windsor
really went to bat for him,
cashed in some favors, and so did I.
So, he hasn't mentioned me?
Angela, Angela, look at me.
What's going on?
What?
He's a job, a case.
He's your case.
I'm... I'm worried about him.
He's a good kid.
Yeah? How can you be so sure?
Tom, how many of these cases
do we see every day?
This kid is...
He's special.
I think he has a real shot.
You think I'm wrong?
I don't know.
I don't know what I think.
He would make me hold
a chicken in my hands,
you know, after... after he came back.
He was different, scary.
He would, you know, tie my hands to it
and then cut off its head.
I would hold it while it shook
and the bleeding came all out.
And you understand that's wrong?
That that's...
You're safe here, Danny.
You understand that?
Mrs. Green?
Yes. Dr. Seymour, please come in.
Thank you.
You're better-looking than
the picture on your book.
No, thank you.
I... I appreciate you
seeing me on such short notice.
Oh, it's my pleasure.
I'm not sure I can tell you anything.
Are you treating Danny?
Yes.
Yes, I am.
So, you used to teach him
here at Windsor.
Yes. He was one of the
brightest boys I ever taught.
Yeah, there's... there's nothing
like feeding a mind
that could take everything
you can give it
and then comes back asking for more.
And how old was he then?
13 and 14.
Is there anything else
from that time that...
Struck you about him that sticks out?
He was very good at getting people
to think they were helping him
until they ended up exhausted or worse.
Three of our staffers, to be exact.
You know, my husband
still blames himself.
What he did to that child.
Oh, yes.
Yes, that's...
That was terrible, terrible,
and I know very difficult to talk about.
I'm sorry.
I... I blame Mr. McDonald.
You see, I still want to forgive Danny,
because the other boy,
he was one of those boys,
always a problem, always.
But Danny did...
He stabbed that boy.
He walked across the room,
and he stabbed him.
Thank God the poor child survived.
Broke my husband's heart.
But I blame Angus.
Do you see?
Mm-hmm.
Because you feel like he let it happen?
Wanted.
He wanted it to happen.
Angus McDonald came
to us a teacher, a teacher,
but he had Danny writing
all these terrible things
over and over about what happened.
Angus was over-involved.
Go on.
I think I've said enough.
This is Tom.
You've reached my cell.
Leave me a message, and I'll
get back to you as soon as I can.
Tom, I'm really mad at you right now,
and I don't want to be mad at you,
but you should be here.
I shouldn't even be
leaving you this message.
But this is good.
This is really good.
I think the guy from The Times is here.
She's a liar.
Why would she lie?
Why don't you believe me?
She said you stabbed a kid, Danny.
You have no idea
what I had to do in there,
what they called me,
what they did to me.
And Angus?
He's a creep, a stalker, and a fag.
It doesn't matter.
Whatever.
Fuck, you hate me.
Why do you hate me?
I don't hate you.
Would you stop it?
Why do you hate me?
I don't hate you.
I'm just trying to figure out
what happened at Windsor, that's all.
You still think I killed her.
Well, I didn't.
It wasn't me.
It was someone else who did that stuff.
I don't know who it was.
Fuck it.
I have to go to work!
Danny, stop it.
Stop it!
You were supposed to help me, I thought.
You were. You were.
Will you calm down?
You were supposed to fucking help me!
Danny!
Fuck! Fuck!
Danny, calm down.
Danny, Danny, Danny.
Those used to belong to me.
I don't know who they
belong to anymore, okay?
Fucking take it.
Are you finished?
Now you want to tell me
what really happened at Windsor?
Why? So you can pretend
like you give a shit?
Hey, just wai... wait a second.
Danny!
God damn it.
♪ Seems like the truth ♪
♪ Turned to a lie ♪
♪ Well, this is why
I'll ask you why... ♪
Ange.
Listen...
No, no, no. Wait. Wait.
I want... I want to buy you a drink.
Tom.
No, come on, sit.
Sit down.
Sit, sit, sit.
Have a drink with me.
- One drink.
- Thank you.
So, have you heard
anything from our boy?
He's at my house...
On the couch.
I don't know what you said to him,
but he's trying to turn his life around,
and digging up the past
is not gonna help him.
Wait a second.
I thought you wanted me to...
Not like that.
To keep going over and over it, Tommy?
I mean, come on.
If you have doubts about your decision,
you need to leave that shit back there.
Come on, Angela. You know
that's not what's happening here.
So, what did he tell you?
Angela, what did he say?
Look, all I know is
if you're not helping,
you're hurting.
Thanks for the drink.
♪ Yes, I know ♪
♪ Trying to move... ♪
Ah, don't say it.
Don't... don't say that word.
What word?
"Work."
Look, I know, but I really...
What did I just say?
No, I got it.
It's fine.
So, what's with all the new bags?
Did you listen to my message?
Yeah.
All of it?
Colin Waters.
The Colin Waters Gallery.
No, no, I know.
Colin Waters. That's great.
Do you know who Colin Waters is?
Are you serious?
Yeah, of course I know
who Colin Waters is.
Come on.
There is no Colin Waters.
It's just a bunch of guys who
call themselves Colin Waters,
but they have a gallery in Bushwick,
and they want to give me a show.
That's great.
And they have a studio
above the gallery where I can work.
In Brooklyn?
Yeah.
Do you know how hard it is
for a figurative painter
to get a solo show these days?
No, I... I know.
That's great.
That's great news, honey.
Congrats, really.
Oh, Jesus.
They got here before me.
I need to bring some work
and other things down there.
You should have listened to the message.
Hey.
What's up, Lauren?
This is Tom, my husband Tom.
Ah. Hey, man.
What's happening?
The chair?
Well, I need a place to sit, right?
It's just...
I mean, it's just
a kitchenette right now.
It's an empty space.
It feels like you're moving out.
Well, only if you don't come with me.
Tom.
The city, a room,
kind of like when we first met.
We didn't leave your
apartment for a month.
The show's not until June.
We have over a month.
You're shaking your head.
Why are you shaking your head?
Am I shaking my head?
Yeah.
I think this book is getting to you,
all those stories about kids.
You know what?
You're right.
This is a really good
opportunity for you.
I'm so tired.
Put me to bed, will you?
Mm-hmm.
Oh! I need to stop at the bakery.
I want to get something
for the guys at the gallery,
you know, those muffins that we love.
Sure.
Who was that?
Ian. Isn't that crazy?
What did he want?
I don't know.
I couldn't tell you.
I was too distracted by his charm.
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
Whoa, what is going on with you?
What's going on with me?
What's going on with you?
You think you can hang out with
someone your own age for once?
Huh?
Fuck you.
No, seriously, fuck you.
Ladies and gentlemen, announcing
train number 1-7-9,
the 8:17 p.m. into...
Lauren, wait.
I'm sorry.
I just... I got a lot
on my mind right now,
and I think maybe
the book is getting to me.
You know, just writing about
these kids and these cases every day
has just taken its toll.
I'm sorry.
I just feel like I'm losing you...
Tom, it's time.
For what?
Everything.
Good things, everything
that we talked about.
Tom?
Tom.
Yes.
I know, I know.
You're right.
I'll see you in a day or two.
She's okay, even if she's an artist,
and you should go down there
and spend more time with her.
Ah, it's complicated, Mom.
Complicated?
Religion is complicated.
Politics is complicated.
And Dad?
Complicated.
But I wasn't.
I was easy.
You see who he's got working out there?
You remember.
That's Neil.
That's little Neil Bridges.
You boys used to torture him
something terrible.
What's he doing here?
Uh, he needed a job.
It's the least I could do.
Man, I can still hear him
crying, screaming.
I don't even remember
who went in after him.
I know it wasn't me.
Wasn't you.
My father.
He jumped in, remember?
You ever think about
what would have happened if...
No.
Not really.
Um, what kind of tea do you have?
Uh, we got black tea, green tea,
chai, peppermint, uh, Earl Grey.
Nothing with caffeine, though, right?
Hi.
Ian, hi.
Hey.
What are you, uh...
What are you doing in the city?
Uh, anything herbal's fine.
I got it, I got it.
What...
What are you doing in the city?
I, um... I was staying at my friend's,
had an interview for Hunter, so...
Oh, that's great.
That's great.
Yeah.
Thanks.
What a coincidence.
This is crazy.
Exactly, exactly.
I mean, like, obviously I want
people to see my work.
Otherwise, what's
the point of making it?
Right, but still...
I totally forgot how noisy
this neighborhood is.
Yeah.
Like... oh, sorry.
You have an eyelash
that's about to fall out.
Good. Do I have to blow on it?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Um...
I used to be really into
this thing called "encaustic,"
which I'm trying to bring back.
It's like you take beeswax and resin,
and you put that on the canvas.
It makes it three-dimensional,
and, like, you can iron it
and melt it.
It's amazing.
I mean, I have to tell you that, uh...
Yes?
Um, it doesn't matter.
What? Come on.
You can't do that.
What?
Um...
You're... you're incredibly inspiring.
This makes me feel like, um...
I don't know, like...
Like anything's possible.
I got it.
Dr. Seymour is a very lucky man.
Yes, he is.
♪ I had a good woman ♪
♪ So I ♪
♪ Everything she wanted, I bought ♪
♪ But I had to cut ♪
♪ That woman loose ♪
♪ Somebody else was riding my cruise ♪
♪ Now I'm doing fine, I got good news ♪
♪ When it comes to love ♪
♪ I'm no stranger to the blues ♪
♪ I'm no stranger... ♪
Rough night, huh?
Yeah, I ran into some old friends.
And Lauren?
She's down in New York.
So, what's up?
You called me?
Ian's father knows he's out.
He called the penitentiary
asking questions about his son.
Did he call you?
Call me?
Why would he call me?
I'm worried he's gonna try to find Ian.
I thought he was staying with you.
No, he went back to his apartment,
and he's not there,
and he's not at work.
He missed his appointment today.
That's never happened before.
Who's Angus McDonald?
He told you about that?
God damn it, Tom.
Stabbings like that happen
all the time in juvie, okay?
So let's not exaggerate it.
Wait. He didn't go find Angus, did he?
Angela, I don't know.
I don't know where he is.
'Cause I got my eye on Angus.
He's up on campus.
What a piece of work.
Those kids, students he's had
coming in and out of there.
He always seems to be two drinks away
from whatever perverted
shit he's thinking.
Angela, listen, your
investment in this kid...
Don't you analyze me.
You worry about your own investments.
I'm just not sure
he's who you want him to be.
Jesus, who is?
Who is?
And you need to worry
about who you need him to be.
Angela, I don't need him
to be anybody, okay?
Just do me a favor, okay?
If he reaches out,
you hold him, keep him,
and don't do anything until I get there.
Hi.
Hello.
- Dr. Seymour?
- Yes.
Professor McDonald's inside.
First time here?
Um...
I've spoken a few times on campus.
Jeremy.
Yeah?
Is there any coffee left?
Cold.
Good.
He likes cold coffee.
That's good.
Dr. Seymour.
Mr. McDonald.
Have a seat, please.
Don't worry about him.
He's been up all night.
So, Danny Miller, huh?
Yes.
Where is he?
Do you know?
I don't know, actually.
Where is Danny?
Everyone wants to know.
Or is it, "Who is Danny?"
Right?
Angus read your book,
your first book.
You have a very optimistic view
of your profession, Doctor,
except for when it comes to Danny.
So, what is it you want to know?
Well, one thing I'd like to know
is how a writing class
turned into a stabbing.
Hmm.
And if I tell you,
will you give him my address?
Do you want me to give him your address?
Now you sound like a therapist.
And as a therapist, you should know
that Danny is not the victim.
He could be a very seductive young man,
and, well,
I don't know what he told you,
but nothing happened between us,
nothing physical, at least.
Everything I did for him, and...
I'm the one accused.
You know what he's capable of.
I'm sure you do.
He wrote about you over and over.
You see, Danny is crazed with talent,
a strong writer,
but a black hole.
You get taken.
He takes you in.
Jeremy!
Now, this story that Danny
was writing in my class,
well, excuse the pun,
but he looked me in the eye.
He walked across the room
and showed me the point of it.
See?
But the thing is,
he seemed to enjoy it.
I mean, Danny seemed
to enjoy the act of it.
Fucker acted like he was my friend,
but he ain't shit.
See?
Don't be alone with him.
I'm not worried about that.
Lucky you.
Dr. Seymour.
Dr. Seymour. Hi.
Hi.
I'm sorry, but, uh...
I know this seems a little awkward,
but could you sign the book, your book?
Oh, sure, sure.
Come in.
Oh.
Whew.
It's cold out there.
Yeah.
Oh, wow. I haven't seen this in a while.
Yeah. I started reading, and I like it.
Yeah?
A lot, yeah.
Uh, but the stories
the children tell themselves,
I mean, they're more for
the adults than for them, right?
Maybe for both.
What's your name again?
Rowena.
You know, I, uh...
Saw you speak on campus.
You were great.
Hello. Ange?
We have a problem.
Why? What's wrong?
Any word from Danny?
Dan... no.
Why?
I got a call from Danny's
father on my phone,
my personal phone.
He said he knows where Danny is.
I don't know what he's up to.
Can you talk some sense into him
before he does something stupid?
He's not stable.
I traced the phone to Norwich.
You have an address?
I'll call you back.
Hey, you following me, asshole?
Don't you think I know when
somebody's following me?
Don't you think I know who
you are, Dr. Seymour?
I'm just here to talk about your won.
My son's no good.
He's no good, all right?
He's an embarrassment.
He needs to go back in the hole.
Captain, I know you've
been trying to contact him.
Not that it's any of your
business who's contacting who,
but obviously you've been in
contact with him, huh, Doctor?
You know, I thought you'd be
the one fucker to understand
that him going to prison
was a good thing.
Well, he's out now, and
we're just trying to help him...
And he needs to be stopped.
All right?
Don't you know how hard that is
for a father to say about his own son?
Huh? You know what?
Get the fuck out of here.
You're like all those other
fucking bleeding hearts.
You got no clue
what you're dealing with.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Hey, honey, I'm sorry.
I miss you.
Wait. Hold on a second.
I can't... I can't hear you.
Let me just turn this down.
Where are you?
I'm at home.
Your parents'?
No, at our home. I missed you, too.
Right. Well, I'm on my
way back right now, okay?
Good.
How much longer do you think you'll be,
'cause we're making dinner.
Oh, yeah?
Who's there?
Ian. We drove back
together from the city.
Lauren, I don't want him in our house.
Have you ever used a knife
before in your life?
I'm trying to keep it all together.
Those vegetables aren't
going to cut themselves.
No, Lauren, I'm not kidding.
Listen to me.
Are you listening in on my phone call,
my private phone call?
Lauren, step into
the other room right now.
Oh, this music.
Lauren.
Please put on a song that
doesn't give me a headache.
Thank you.
Lauren, listen to me.
Okay, well, we'll wait for you to eat.
No, no, Lauren, Lauren.
What's wrong?
Let's go!
Go!
Lauren?
Lauren.
Didn't you hear me calling me?
Well, hello to you, too.
What the hell do you think
you're doing, huh?
I... I'm sorry. We were
just having some dinner.
Just relax.
Don't tell me to relax.
Ian, you need to leave
my house right now.
Tom.
It's okay.
Now.
Okay.
Um, thank you for dinner.
It was lovely.
Why would you talk to him like that?
You don't know anything about him.
Danny, I thought we said you weren't
gonna come to my house anymore.
Have you seen the news?
No. Why?
An old man got murdered up in Danbury.
Two kids did it.
It's all gonna happen again,
isn't it, all of it?
Have you talked to your father?
Why would I do that?
Have you?
Shit. They're gonna put me away again.
They're gonna fuck me over again.
You have no idea
who this kid is, okay, none.
And you do?
He's not a page out of the DSM.
He's a child.
I want you to stay away from him.
Just trust me on this, okay?
Stay away.
Okay, fine.
I need to finish this.
Dr. Seymour, Tom.
I was wondering
if we could talk to you for a second.
We'd like to get a comment on
the piece that's running tonight
about the two juveniles in Danbury.
They're not my clients.
Do you mind if we turn on the camera?
Actually, I do.
I'm not involved in that case.
No, but you are aware
they released Daniel Miller,
the young man who murdered
Elizabeth Parks 12 years ago?
He was a client, a patient.
As a matter of policy, I don't comment
on my clients, past or present.
Sorry.
I'd go on down
the north fork for salmon,
and all of a sudden, it was
whitewater rafting in-boat.
What am I doing here, the north fork
of the Salmon River in Ida...
Put a pin in that.
We will continue.
I gotta go put out a fire.
I'll be right back.
Did you tell her?
Calm down.
Did you tell your reporter friend
he was out?
Calm down.
Did you?
She already knew.
I just confirmed it.
Father's out there talking
to anybody who will listen.
Fuck.
Tom.
Tommy.
Did you actually think this was
never gonna get back to us?
Just because we sent that kid away
doesn't mean he's going to stay away.
Come on.
I, uh... I'm going to
go back to my meeting.
If you, uh... if you
would like to grab a drink
and forget that we ever got involved
with this fucking thing to begin with,
please just give me a call,
but calm down.
She's going to run whatever she has
tonight, tomorrow, whatever,
and it'll be done.
And the number one thing
we can rely on are people
and people's complete lack of
follow-through and long-term memory.
So calm the fuck down.
Danny.
Listen, I think me, you, and Angela
need to get together, make a plan.
And if you want, we can try and
work on this together, okay?
But call me back.
I will make the time.
I went to Lizzie to feed the cats.
Kittens. We needed to feed the kittens.
My mother stayed at home,
and my father was back,
back from the war.
Are you tired, Danny?
No. I'm...
I like Lizzie.
She couldn't see so good.
She had, um, cats,
cats in her eyes.
When I went, she wasn't there,
so I went upstairs.
She had this powder,
lady powder,
smelled like flowers.
It was sticky.
And then what?
I heard her.
Um, I heard her come in and upstairs.
I run. I have to get past her,
but she was blocking me.
She wouldn't move, so I kicked her.
I kicked her down.
And she was twitching,
making this noise,
so I took the cushion off the chair...
She had these cushions from Boston...
And covered her face to get her to stop.
To get her to stop.
And she kept kicking and kicking.
And what did that feel like?
Like a chicken
with its head cut off.
Why did you go back?
You went back.
I don't know.
But if you knew it was wrong,
why did you go back?
I don't know.
'Cause your fingers were clean.
Under your nails...
I don't know.
I don't know who this kid is.
It's okay, all right?
It's okay.
Just... just tell me what else
happened back there?
It doesn't fucking matter what happened!
You're not gonna believe me, anyway.
Well, how can anybody help you
if you continue to take
no responsibility?
And what about your responsibility?
I'm sorry that I took that.
It was wrong.
She's very sweet.
And give those back to my father.
I don't want them anymore.
Wait. Danny, listen.
For your own safety,
you need to call Angela.
Danny.
Ange, it's me.
I found him.
Where?
In my office.
Still there?
No, he just left.
You didn't hold him?
No, I didn't.
Why?
Because he broke in.
Because he stole from my house.
Because he's not my case or my patient!
It is not known where Daniel Miller
was relocated after his release,
but Miller's father spoke with
us earlier this afternoon.
Why he's out is beyond me.
Last I heard, he was
somewhere in Connecticut,
New London, most likely.
The release of convicted juveniles
like Daniel Miller has
become a hot topic
in the wake of recent violent crimes...
I'm going to bed.
...by juveniles in the area.
Oh, hey.
I'll be in in a minute.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
You?
I don't know.
I don't know if I'm okay.
Why didn't you just tell me
that that was him?
Because it was over
a dozen years ago, Lauren.
Because I didn't want to put
that back on you, on us.
That kid needs your help.
Yeah, I don't know if I can help him.
Excuse me?
They put him away...
Because I thought he was bad.
And do you still think that?
I don't know.
I don't know what I think anymore.
That's the problem, Lauren.
I was trying to protect you, is all.
No. No, no, no.
No, I was.
You were trying to protect yourself.
You know what?
Things are good or bad.
But people,
sometimes people are just not easy.
I'm going back to the city for a while.
You know where to find me.
Are you sure?
Pretty sure.
Don't do anything before I get there.
How far away are you?
Not far.
All right, I'm going.
And I said...
Before he does something
to himself or who knows what.
Danny.
Her niece lived here
for a while, I heard.
Danny, that gun's
gonna get you put away.
It might.
It's crazy, though, right?
I mean, I can't even close my eyes
without seeing her face...
Upside down right there,
staring back at me,
even if they burnt
this whole place down.
Why don't you just
give me the gun, Danny?
No.
You know, I thought it was gonna be
my father who came here first.
Search and destroy.
Mr. Miller, that's what he was good at.
Now, little Danny Miller
kept on coming back here,
because every time he did, he thought...
I thought...
That Lizzie would be walking around,
feeding her cats.
"Up and about," that's what
my mother used to say.
Like none of this happened,
Lizzie or my mother.
Danny, I don't know if I ever
told you this before, but...
When I was a kid...
Me and some friends,
we pushed this boy in the water,
and we watched him almost drown.
You watched.
See, Tom, that's your problem.
That's your real problem,
is you like to watch.
You are a fucking tourist, Tom.
That's what the rich do.
They tour.
But he would have drowned
if my father didn't jump in.
You jumped in to save me.
Danny...
Or I guess we could have
gone down together,
but you saved me, Dr. Seymour.
Did I tell you that before,
about the drowning?
Did you know it was me at the river?
I don't think you did.
Danny...
You like to watch, Tom,
until you don't.
But people like me
don't have that choice.
Why didn't you help me?
Why?
I thought I was, Danny.
Don't lie!
Danny, put the gun down!
Danny.
Open it.
Pick it up.
Do it, or I'll kill you
and then kill myself.
Do it!
Now! Now!
Do it! Open it!
Okay, okay.
Pick it up.
Pick it up!
Good.
Hold it.
Danny, why are you doing this?
Danny, come...
Don't do this, Danny.
Danny, don't do this.
Close your eyes.
Don't do this.
Now, that is feeling.
That is not watching.
That is feeling.
Is that what you were afraid of?
That feeling?
That someone could like that feeling?
Why?
Because we're killers?
We are, all of us, killers, Tom.
But liking it...
That is a whole 'nother story.
Did you like how that felt?
No. No, I didn't.
Neither did I.
I kicked her...
And she fell,
and she started shaking, and...
I... I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Danny, it's okay.
I-It's okay.
It's my... it's my dad.
He... he knows where I am, Tom.
Um, okay, listen.
Everything's gonna be okay, all right?
I need you to go upstairs
and stay out of sight, now.
Get the hell away from the car!
Just... just back off
and leave him alone.
I swear I'm so sick
of you fucking idiots!
Just leave him alone!
Who do you think told me he was here?
Ah, bullshit.
Bullshit, huh?
Argh!
Bullshit?
Huh?
Ahh!
He can play you,
but he ain't gonna play me.
"It's the stories,
the stories children tell themselves,
after the event or the act."
"That's what we work with,
not to punish or accuse,
but to help them retell their stories
in a way that gives them hope,
possibility,
and a future..."
"Because if you don't believe
a child has a future,
then why believe in anything?"
No offense,
but don't you think you're exploiting
the kids you're trying to help?
Um, I think the only person
that he's exploiting here is himself.
I wouldn't worry about her.
She got busted for dealing drugs.
That's her main claim
to fame around here.
Fuck off.
My God.
Good friend of yours?
I thought so.
I saw the ad in the paper.
Hmm.
And this is riveting stuff, Tom, truly.
Thank you.
Truly, but, um,
you didn't mention me in your book.
No, I didn't, not in this one.
No, I don't think a chapter's
enough for you.
You need your own book.
So, Portland, huh?
Yeah, and in school,
like a million of us.
It's basically like prison,
except there's, you know, girls.
So you're good?
Past and present?
Yeah.
You know, getting by.
Forward motion and all that.
Danny.
There you are.
Hey, baby.
Rowena.
Yes.
Yes, of course.
You look good.
Oh, I transferred up here
when Danny did.
Sorry I missed your talk.
I had class.
Did you tell him about your story?
Well, I...
No, he didn't.
Oh. Well, he's quite talented.
I imagine he would be.
It's going to be in the quarterly.
I don't think he wants
to hear about all that.
No, it's good and strange.
It's about this boy who
buys these toy soldiers,
these made-in-China toy soldiers...
All right, all right, all right, enough.
Hey, Ro!
Hurry up!
I'll see you soon, all right?
Okay.
Good to see you again.
Toy soldiers were from Walmart.
Excuse me?
Well, in... in my story,
the toys, they're from Walmart.
It's basically... it's about this kid
who starts messing
with his psychiatrist,
his former psychiatrist,
the one that he had when he was a child.
It's just a story, Tom.
I'll send it to you.
Give it a read.
What's this story called?
The Tourist.
Ah.
Oh, but that's not you
anymore, though, is it?
No.
I mean, you, you pulled
the trigger, didn't you?
You almost killed him.
I thought you would.
What?
What the hell is so funny?
Nothing, man, just people like you.
I'm sorry.
Well, look, I gotta get to the airport.
Can I drop you off someplace?
Uh, yeah.
How's Lauren?
She didn't make the trip with you, huh?
No, she's working.
Everything good between you two?
Mm-hmm.
She must be due pretty soon,
though, right?
Yeah, she is.
Wow.
Tom, that's great.
I know that you guys
were trying for a while
and it was really hard on her, so...
Congratulations.
I'm very happy for the two of you.
How did you know my wife was pregnant?
I asked you how you knew.
Tom, we talked on the phone.
She called me, and we talked.
She didn't tell you that?
We didn't talk on the phone, Tom.
I read about it on Facebook.
You need to relax.
You're a very tense person.
It's a boy, though, right?
Isn't that what they
just told her, a son?
You're gonna be a father, Tom.
How incredible is that?
What are you gonna name him?
I guess you don't have to
answer that right now.
You still got some time.
I have to say I cannot wait to meet him.
♪ Galileo was bluffing ♪
♪ It's just a mess out here ♪
♪ There's no compass to guide us ♪
♪ Through the flashes
of violence and fear ♪
♪ Ohh ♪
♪ Pinball and a motor hum ♪
♪ Black kettle in a riptide ♪
♪ Sand bleeds through our fingers ♪
♪ If time said it stood still in line ♪
♪ Ohh ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa ♪
♪ You will get the best of me ♪
♪ Worlds collide into recipe
for disaster ♪
♪ Sweet disaster ♪
♪ Birthmark on a crow's foot ♪
♪ Kilimanjaro or bust ♪
♪ There are no mountains to move here ♪
♪ You just do what you say,
what you must ♪
♪ Ohh ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa ♪
♪ You will get the best of me ♪
♪ Worlds collide into recipe
for disaster ♪
♪ Sweet disaster ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa ♪
♪ You will get the best of me ♪
♪ Worlds collide into recipe
for disaster ♪
♪ Sweet disaster ♪
♪ Sweet ♪
♪ Light-years and a pocket watch ♪
♪ You can't get close enough ♪
♪ To the rhythm of solitude ♪
♪ Ashes to ashes to dust ♪
♪ Ohh. ♪