ROCCO: There's 2 kinds of people
in this world when you boil it all down.
You've got your talkers
and you've got your doers.
Most people are just talkers.
All they got is talk.
But when all is said and done,
it's the doers who change this world.
And when they do that,
they change us.
And that's why we never forget them.
So, which one are you?
Do you just talk about it...
...or do you stand up
and do something about it?
Because believe you me, all the rest
of it is just coffeehouse bullshit.
POPPA: Peace, they say,
is the enemy of memory.
So it had been for my boys.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
For some time now, the past
had felt like a dream to them,
faded and worn.
And then suddenly,
as if not a day had passed,
it was back.
I could see it in their eyes.
I could feel it,
heavy in their presence.
Something calling them back.
(RAIN PATTERING)
Something's happened.
No. Stop. Stop, stop.
Please, stop. Oh, God.
Please. Please.
God, no, stop...
...(GUN FIRES)
A priest?
Did they release his name?
No, but I made a few calls.
I still have friends in the diocese there.
McKinney.
Father Douglas McKinney.
You knew him?
Knew of him.
Everybody did.
He's a good man.
Youth hostels, soup kitchens.
He even made it to the papers sometimes.
Look, boys, I think it's best
if you just stay put...
...until we try to figure out
what the hell is going on.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Aren't you at least gonna try
and talk them out of this?
For all we know, it could be somebody
just trying to get away with murder here.
Aye.
Only there's a thousand
easier ways to do that.
Trust me.
Someone's trying to call them out.
You kill a priest, in a church,
and make it look like it was them.
Bring them back with a vengeance.
Someone thinks it's really clever.
Only one problem with this little plan.
What's that?
It worked.
(LINE OF BLOOD PLAYING)...
...* Well, it was said on the day of my birth...
...* A ghost of a dead
man walked the earth...
...* And my mama don't love me none...
...* She hates everything my daddy done...
...* You're so young,
my bastard son...
...* You're wanted by
the motherfucking law...
...* You're so young,
my bastard son...
...* You're wanted by
the motherfucking law...
...(STAMMERING) Exactly
what do you intend to do?
Every last motherfucker
that had anything to do with it.
There is no new information
on the victim found slain...
...this morning inside
the Church of the Holy Saints.
As you can see, the size of the crowd
here has increased substantially...
...as we have confirmed that the body
was ritualized with pennies in the eyes.
Many remember this
as the grisly calling card...
...of the prolific vigilante killers
known as the Saints,
who went on a murder spree
here in Boston.
A rampage that ended 8 years ago...
...when the Saints brazenly
walked into open court...
...and executed Mafia don
Poppa Joe Yakavetta...
...before a courtroom of
terrified witnesses...
...and then simply disappeared
without a trace.
As police have yet to confirm
the Saints' possible involvement,
the ominous question
hangs heavy in the air.
'Are they back?'
(PANTING)
We need to keep our heads here.
It's probably not even them.
Course it ain't them.
It doesn't really matter, does it?
All our skeletons just came
screaming out of the closet.
We're fucked.
We're not fucked.
We are totally fucked.
And not just fucked.
Like elephant-dick-pounded-in-the-ass,
no-reach-around,
jungle-fucked.
Now's not the time to panic, green beans.
I disagree.
Now is a perfect time to panic.
We are all accessories...
Don't fucking say it.
I'm gonna say it, all right.
You've got a mouth on you,
Greenly.
Both of you calm down.
Just calm down.
Shut the fuck up.
(OFFICER CLEARING THROAT)
Her ETA's 10 minutes.
Thanks, Seamus.
(OFFICER CHATTERING ON PA)
It's game time.
How we playing this?
Feds love to pull the
divide-and-conquer routine.
We hardline her.
Stick together on this.
Agreed?
Agreed.
We're a brick wall.
Let's rock this bitch.
* Comin' back, baby,
how about you?
* I'm the real thang
CHORUS: * Real thang...
...* This ain't no pony show...
...* Ain't a pony show...
...* I came to rock the mike...
...* He's going to rock the mike...
...* Come on back, baby,
let me know...
...* Let him know...
...* 'Cause I'm the real thang...
...* Ain't no question about it...
...* And I'm gonna stand up and shout it...
...* From every stage I sing
Eunice Bloom.
It's a pleasure.
Now, you have got to be Greenly.
Smecker always said
you were the funny one.
Well, funny as in 'ha-ha,' though,
not like funny as in 'gay,'
'cause I'm totally not.
What we're trying to figure out is,
with all due respect, Agent Bloom...
'Special.'
Excuse me?
You see, there's a 'special'
before my 'agent.'
If we're gonna address each other formally.
I'd appreciate if you popped it in there,
because it makes me feel special.
Of course, I was hoping we could
be a bit more personable.
In fact, I'd welcome you to call
me Eunice, and maybe I...
Okay, Eunice.
I don't see why the fuck
the Fed is even involved.
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
'Fuck'? This isn't a 'fuck' situation, is it?
I mean, I can understand a 'goddamn'
or 2, but why skip all the way...
What is the Fed's interest in this?
Their interest, Detective,
is capturing the men responsible...
...for the murders of 22 of Boston's
finest criminals.
They could have sent
anyone. They sent me.
Now, why do you think that is?
Well, since we've already broken the
'fuck' barrier, allow me to be blunt.
It is because I am so fucking smart...
...that I make smart people feel
that they are retarded.
(MEN CLAMORING)
Motherfuckers.
Which one do you want?
Me first, man,
me first.
(IN FRENCH) Bust his head.
(IN FRENCH) That son of a bitch over there.
All right.
House is closed, motherfuckers.
(IN SPANISH) Why are his hands chained?
(IN ENGLISH) Romeo is very fast, man.
(IN SPANISH) He says the Frenchman
can't lay a hand on him.
(IN SPANISH) But he can't hit him back.
(IN ENGLISH) That's the bet, ese.
(IN SPANISH) He's got to last 5 minutes.
BOTH: (IN ENGLISH) 50 on the Mexican.
Never fight a Mexican, Pierre.
Pound for pound, toughest
motherfuckers on Earth.
Attaboy.
You know why?
We like pain, Pierre.
Come on, come on.
Think about it, man.
Tabasco sauce?
What kind of fucked-up people
would even invent that shit?
Get the fuck out of the way.
(IN FRENCH) Whore.
Don't be scared, now.
Remember, I can't hit you.
I ain't gonna hit you.
Found a loophole, bitch.
I ought to be a lawyer.
Thank you.
(WHISTLING)
MAN: Shit, man.
(MEN WHOOPING)
Please, stop.
Oh, God. Please.
Please. Oh, God.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
It wasn't them, but I'm sure
you boys already knew that.
All their vics were criminals.
Clearly not the case here.
So, it wasn't them,
which makes this a local matter...
...and falls under our jurisdiction.
So, with all due respect, we'll see
you later, Special Agent Bloom.
(SIGHING)...
'With all due respect.'
Man, I hate it when people say that,
because it is inevitably followed by
a disrespectful remark.
Here, let me give you an example.
With all due respect, Detective,
this matter falls under whatever jurisdiction
I fucking say it does.
You fucking...
Let's just...
What can you tell us about the shooters?
'Shooter.' Singular.
And I can tell you...
How shall I put this delicately?
He's a short little fucker.
One guy.
Dwarf. Got it.
Let me show you what I'm talking about.
Detective Greenly,
you're the victim.
David.
You can call me David.
Very well, David.
The Saints' signature stance,
Copley Plaza Hotel 8 years ago.
2 men of identical height
put Yuri Petrova on his knees...
...and each dropped iron
to the back of his head.
Power hath descended
forth from Thy hand.
Eyes front, David.
The position of the victim and the
angles produced by the killers' stance...
...created a unique scenario.
The bullets crisscrossed in the skull
and exited the eyes.
Here, this did not occur. The rounds
moved on a straight trajectory...
...through the back of the
victim's head and out the front,
which happens when...
One guy's holding 2 guns to
the back of your head.
One guy.
(GUNS FIRE)
But you said he was wicked short.
The Saints were later determined
to be 5'11' tall.
The rounds exit Petrova's eyeballs.
Here, they came out the lower cheek,
3, 4 inches below the eyes.
That puts him at 5'7'-ish.
That's not uncommonly short.
The killer posed as a late-night confessor.
Once the victim entered the booth,
the killer had him isolated.
No escape.
Short stuff comes out of the confessional,
kicks in the door of the priest's chambers,
leaving a crescent-shaped indentation,
which tells us that this cowboy was
wearing a boot with a pronounced heel.
Gave him a couple inches.
We're looking about 5'5',
gentlemen.
That's wicked short.
Wicked.
Speculation on the Saints'
possible involvement...
...in the murder of Father
Douglas McKinney...
...continues to boil over.
In fact, it has split the public
right down the middle.
My cousin was there.
He saw the body.
His hands were crossed over his chest.
It was them.
It wasn't them.
You know, maybe the priest did something.
There were pennies in his eyes, they did it.
They didn't do it.
It wasn't them.
RADIO HOST: You're on the air, caller.
MAN: Well, finally,
man, yeah.
This guy was indicted last year
for ordering the murders of 22 people.
And it slid right off his back.
Piece of shit.
Indeed, Boston has been under the
terrible reign of this thug for years now.
Where's the DA's office?
Why can't they make anything
stick to Concezio Yakavetta?
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
I can't believe that none of us
were consulted on this.
The disrespect.
We never would have okayed
such a thing. A priest. It's infamità.
Are we not Catholics?
For Christ's fucking sakes.
And for what? Revenge?
There's no business in it, Concezio.
The cops.
They can be all over us.
Forget the cops.
What about these Saints fuckers?
These guys were long gone,
and now you're trying to bring
the devil right back to our doorstep?
8 years ago,
these vigilante fucks
put my father on his knees...
...(SPEAKING ITALIAN)...
...and executed him...
...in public.
Mi padrino, a blood relative
and benedictator to all of you.
You think that I don't know
that each one of you...
...has been waking up with the
night sweats over this for 8 years?
These sons of bitches prison-fucked us.
In the ass.
And then they wiped their dicks
on our grandma's drapes.
And we have been living
in silent fear ever since.
We don't talk about it.
Rape victims seldom do.
(MEN CHUCKLING)
Concezio is right.
Pretending you don't got a problem...
...don't solve nothing.
Let's take a moment...
...and look at the serendiculous...
Seren...
Serendipitous.
...type situation we find ourselves in.
There's a wicked good chance
that these Saints are gonna show.
And this time, they don't catch us
with our pants down.
This time, we deal with them
proactiviously, huh?
And don't forget Boston's finest.
With their second bite at the apple...
...they've got every reason in
the world to crank up the heat.
And as for the Saints' doting fans,
fuck them.
(GROANING)...
...(CONCEZIO SPEAKING ITALIAN)...
...(SIGHING)
Bad luck.
How would he even recognize us?
You don't remember the fucking
sketches on the news channel?
Shit, that's right.
Fuck's sake.
You know, every time you see
those composites on TV...
...and they catch the guy,
it looks nothing like him.
But ours...
CONNOR: Just our luck, right?
We draw Leonardo fucking
da Vinci as a sketch artist.
And 2 days ago, we looked like
Jesus Christ.
What the fuck we cut our hair for?
Yeah, that's right.
I don't know, it seemed like the thing
to do at the time, though, didn't it?
Maybe we should dye it.
What?
Well, they're always dying
their hair in the movies,
like The Fugitive.
It's covert and shit.
What color would you dye it?
Lighter, I guess.
(LAUGHING) Do you mean blonde?
I didn't fucking say that.
Like California surfer boy.
It's not what I'm saying.
Like gay, gay, gay,
faggoty blonde.
I'm fucking warning you.
'Stay gold, Ponyboy.'
'Stay gold...' Fuck you.
You fucking cunt.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Well, I was fucking mad.
Shit.
What kind of fucking crazy...
I know who you are.
You guys are...
Shut it.
This is so fucking cool, man.
I'm from Boston and I love you guys.
Shit, everybody loves you guys.
Maybe I can get on this thing.
You know, bring some raza into this.
Hey, is it true that you guys say a
prayer before you grease somebody?
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
And an awesome wailing
was heard throughout heaven.
And the terrible hand of the Lord
struck upon the Earth.
And as Almighty God created you,
now he calleth you home.
(GUN CLICKS)
Oops.
Busy signal.
Will have to call us back.
(LAUGHING)
MURPHY: Let's have a shot
while we're waiting.
CONNOR: I think he took a little piss.
That shit was not funny.
It just came out me fucking nose.
(BOTH LAUGHING)...
...(SIGHING) Thank you, Jesus.
Thought I greased my drawers.
(SHIP HORN BLOWING)
No.
I've got connects all over Beantown, man.
Romeo will hook you up like a tow truck.
No.
Why not?
We don't have to give you
fucking reasons. Forget it.
It's because I'm Mexican,
isn't it?
How dare you, sir,
insinuate such a thing?
The fact that you're a greasy spic,
it's got nothing to do with it.
Okay, I'm gonna let you have
that one, but, look, I can do this.
This isn't rocket surgery.
You guys find the bad guys doing
bad stuff and you kill them, right?
Well, it's not that simple, actually.
Yes, it is.
Suppose you're right.
I was just hoping that we was
a bit more artistic about it, I think.
Yeah? Well, you ain't.
Now, what do you plan on doing
when you get to US soil?
We don't really have, you know,
a succinct plan yet, you know, per se.
Haven't really worked it all out,
as it were.
As it were.
Not fully developed, per se.
You two leprechaun dicks
need to chill in the greenroom...
...sipping on some Pellegrino and let
your manager handle the details.
And you'd better have
my Cub Scout badge ready.
Because if you wanna kick
Yakavetta in the nuts,
have him wake up with
a horse head in his bed.
Romeo's got an ace in the hole for you.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
And that's all she wrote.
Everything points in the same direction.
Get out.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Look, I have been stonewalling
the media on this thing.
I've got half of New England thinking
the Saints whacked the priest...
...and the other half
thinking they're innocent.
It's a powder keg.
And we're talking riot gear
at Celtics games here.
Now, I can clear them of this murder...
...and take the piss right out of this thing.
Now, give me one reason why I
shouldn't take this public right now.
(SIGHING)
Walk with me, Chief.
Let's talk.
(DOOR CLOSES)
This is not good.
She's gunning for the boys hard.
This broad trying to put a feather
in her cap is gonna get us all locked up.
I mean, this couldn't be going any worse.
Just calm down.
Calm down? Calm down? You know
they're gonna throw us in the Hoag.
We put half those deranged
sex freaks in there.
I hope you guys like cock sandwiches,
because we'll be eating them
for breakfast, lunch and dinner.
Now, I understand
you've got a job to do, Chief.
But this pint-sized killer is the only thing...
...that puts Yakavetta right
in the middle of this.
And if Concezio even sniffs
that we on to him,
he puts a bullet in Napoleon's head,
plants him at the bottom
of the ocean and walks.
Now it is imperative
that we find this little man.
You've said some dumb shit in your days,
but that... I... You know, that... That...
What? We're all 'assuming'
Smecker didn't tell her.
'Oh, yeah, by the way,
me and 3 Boston detectives...
'are accessories to murder.
Pass the malt vinegar.'
Smecker may have been a lot of things,
but he was a stand-up guy.
And we took an oath.
The 4 of us.
Yeah.
Okay. I was just thinking.
Well, don't do that.
You're no good at it.
Fuck you.
You're as dumb as a fucking heel,
you know that,
you blowjob?
GREENLY:
Fucking, cocksucking, hard-on...
Jesus Christ. Look. We need to
figure out what we're gonna do...
...when the boys show and start
doing what they do best.
Because that's when the shit's
really gonna hit the fan.
But everyone is assuming that
the boys are gonna turn up.
We got no way of knowing that for sure.
Yeah, that could totally happen.
They could not come back.
What dream world did
you two just slip into?
We know the boys.
Is there any part of you that thinks
they're just gonna let this slide?
Believe this.
They're either on their way
or they're already here.
I thought you said your
car was inconspicuous.
Yeah, well, I don't like words
with 'spic' right in the middle.
Besides, it is where I live.
Yeah? Where's that?
Margaritaville?
Hey, I hail from a colorful people.
Besides, you wouldn't know style
if it pitched a tent in your ass.
ROMEO: Ace in the hole time.
Been a lot of chatter about Yakavetta
being in bed with the Chinese.
This here is little Yaka's yeyo.
All right, here's the plan.
Then we skin out, we go to Doc's
for a shot of Irish,
we're at home in time for tacos.
That's what we do.
What?
Well, it's just this plan...
What the fuck's wrong with the plan?
(STAMMERING) It's...
It's genius.
I can even drive an f-lift, man.
Got my Class D license and everything.
That's the fucking spirit.
I'm gonna need a gun.
BOTH: Forget it.
What the fuck, man? I'm in
on this shit. I'm working here.
Okay.
For fuck's sake.
Here's what you're gonna do.
You're gonna consider yourself a
fucking pledge until we tell you different.
Can I consider myself your girlfriend, too?
That's what you get.
Is there a fucking problem?
It's fine.
CONNOR: I'm fucking watching you.
You understand me?
Now, you stow that shit.
Don't you worry, Rome.
Shit like this, it builds character.
Yeah, the character of a little bitch.
(CHUCKLING)
Now, that's just unprofessional.
So, what do you think?
I think Yakavetta killed a good man
just to send us a message.
Well, let's send him one right back.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)...
...(SISTER CHRISTIAN
PLAYING OVER EARPHONES)...
...* Motoring...
...(HUMMING)...
...*...night...
...*...right...
...* And something that rhymes with 'light'
Why?
I don't know.
(SIGHING)
It's not them.
It's them.
A wise man once told me,
'Where a man's actions are firmly
bound to an unshakable faith,
'one's worst nightmares become
sudden, terrifying reality.'
You didn't have to bash me in the skull.
Sorry, man, we got a plan going here.
Technically, I was supposed to
knock you out.
But they gave me this faggoty little gun,
see, and the weight's just not...
Christ, that's a gun?
Why didn't you just point it
at me and say 'scram'?
Scram. Get the fuck out of here. Now.
You got it.
Hey, guys, let's not let this one
little incident get in the way of...
CONNOR: Shut up and get back
behind the fucking wheel.
Jeez.
Well, at least your plan's
off to a winning start.
Go fuck yourself.
Oh, fuck.
That's heroin.
How the fuck would you know?
Fuck you.
I know shit.
(CLEARING THROAT)
What's the symbolism here?
Symbolism?
Yeah. What does this symbolize?
Well, it symbolizes a huge fuck-up.
This is a plan that fell to pieces.
A lot of it don't make sense, which is
why it all makes perfect sense.
MURPHY: Christ,
what the fuck's he doing?
CONNOR: I don't know.
Hang on.
Fuck's sake.
All right, all right.
Christ, he can't fucking see
where he's going.
Shit. Turn to the left now.
Tell him.
Go left. Go left.
What?
That way. Go that way.
Left? Fuck.
I can't believe I let you talk me
into this. Fucking stupid plan.
It's all in the execution. And your
negative attitude ain't helping any.
What? What the fuck?
Negative attitude?
My fucking negative attitude?
Yeah, your negative attitude.
You've got to visualize the end result.
You've got to force it into reality. Believe.
You've got to fucking believe.
I'm about to believe my fist
right up your fucking ass.
You'll do what?
(BOTH GRUNTING)
CONNOR: Not a believer.
That's another thing,
don't be down at me, 'cause
I'm right fucking there, man.
CONNOR: You've got to believe.
This bitch is fast-a-rooney.
Wait.
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
Wait. Wait, hold on.
Uppey-downey.
Shit.
(SHOUTING IN CANTONESE)
Boys, I believe things in our fair, little city...
...just got downright biblical.
Wait, wait.
(SHOUTING IN CANTONESE)...
...(SHOUTING)...
...(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
BOTH: And shepherds we shall be,
for Thee, my Lord, for Thee.
Power hath descended
forth from Thy hand,
that our feet may swiftly carry out
Thy command.
So we shall flow a river forth to Thee
and teeming with souls shall it ever be.
(BOTH RECITING IN LATIN)...
...(SHOUTING IN CANTONESE)...
...(GUNS FIRE)
POPPA: While the wicked
stand confounded,
call me with Thy Saints surrounded.
Ballistics just dug it out.
A.22? You've got to be kidding me.
That's like bringing a knife to a gunfight.
Yeah, or like bringing a really small gun...
...to a gunfight.
I don't know.
Ballistics is reading 3 shooters,
and this is one of them.
I find it hard to believe...
...that one of the 3 most lethal
individuals on the planet...
...just switched over to birdshot.
Maybe we're reading this wrong.
Priest was a frame job, right?
Yeah, maybe somebody's trying
to eliminate some competition here?
Yeah.
No, sir, it's them.
Here he comes.
(MURPHY AND CONNOR CHUCKLING)
Doc.
Boys.
You're a sight for sore eyes. Come on
in here with that. Get in quick.
Get in out of the cold.
Come on.
DOC: Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
(STAMMERING) I saw the news channel.
Are you boys all right?
Sound as an Irish pound, Doc.
Is it too late for a shot?
The Lord told me you'd be coming.
'Doc,' he said.
'They'd be coming.'
And I was to have everything ready.
(STAMMERING) And I have.
I have everything...
It's all set.
(CLEARING THROAT)
This is our Mexican.
Nice to meet you, lad.
They call me... Fuck. Ass.
How you doing, Fuck Ass?
I'm Romeo.
This used to be a speakeasy in the '40s.
I only use it for storage now.
Holy shit.
This is so fucking cool.
Nobody knows it's up here.
You'll be safe.
(STUTTERING)
You can get in and out the fire escape.
Know what this is?
This is our hideout.
We got a fucking hideout, man.
What, are you fucking 5 years old?
You know, Rome,
we got sticks and blankets.
You can make yourself a fort.
Fuck the both of you, man.
This is fucking sweet.
We even got pinball machines, man.
* So let's raise our glass to better days...
...(INAUDIBLE)...
...* Forget the past and our wicked ways...
...* Let's sing together this twilight song...
...* And make this spirit last all night
Lobster dick. Look at me.
Lobster dick.
* All night long
Not this time,
you little shit.
We'll see about that,
old man.
Would somebody please
come over here and...
Fuck.
Me up the...
Ass.
Yes. That's what he done.
That's what he's done every time.
I took you down, old man,
I took you down.
Are you hungry, lad?
I sent Louie out for some sandwiches.
I could eat.
Decent work.
Do you know what I'm thinking
would be a nice match for the back?
That chocolate hide
with the heavy marbling...
...we've been trying to get rid of
for the last 6 months.
We'll make a leather man
out of you yet, son.
Go to it, lad.
I can't help you with that, lads.
But if you need something,
anything, made out of leather,
we'd be happy to do the job.
THUG: How many times
have I been nice to you?
How many times do my people
come here and talk to you?
This song and dance is over.
It's over, motherfucker.
You didn't see anything.
(THUGS LAUGHING)
LOUIE: Noah.
(LOUIE SHOUTING IN ITALIAN)
No, no, no.
We got to call the polizia, Noah.
We got to call somebody.
Noah. No.
(SCREAMING)
You young guys worry too much.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO)
We always bounce back.
(SPEAKS ITALIAN)
Besides, better the chinks than us, right?
(SLURPING)
This is some serious shit here.
(SNICKERING)
Something amusing you,
queer bait?
No, I was just...
You should be focused on the next step.
That shipment of H was gonna square
our books for the next 6 months.
Any thoughts on that?
Yeah, I got some thoughts on that.
I was just thinking,
not too serendipitous for us.
You...
...(EXCLAIMING)
It's like the Roman Empire in here.
You even got concubines and shit.
George.
What gives here?
Oh, a little cannoli,
shrimp cocktail, huh?
I need to see the boss,
right away.
Jimmy the Gofer, la cortina.
Get over here.
(EXCLAIMING)
Hey, boss, I just came by to tell you...
Push the talk button,
numb nuts.
Hello, can you hear me? Over.
I can hear you fine. Now what
the fuck are you doing here?
Copy that.
Everything's in motion.
All our guys are gunning for
these Jesus freaks.
I figure there's no need for me
to be on the streets no more.
So, which one of these rooms
do you want me to take, huh?
Are your ears fucking painted on?
Did I not make it perfectly clear...
...that you're to stay on the streets
until this is over?
I was...
Now get the fuck out of here.
Douche bag.
And don't come back till I say you can
or you're going back to Brooklyn,
you fat fucking waste of space.
ROMEO: You wanna find something in
Boston that don't wanna be found,
my Uncle Cesar is a veterano.
Out the game,
but still got his name.
Yakavetta's gunning for you
muchachos, and hard.
Even posted a reward,
like Jesse James-style shit.
Anyway, any of his guys that
take you out gets his palm crossed.
250 big ones.
(ROMEO WHISTLES)
Quarter mil for us?
'Us'? What are you talking about, 'us'?
(IN SPANISH) Uncle, why do you
isrespect me in front of my friends?
(IN SPANISH) I'm disrespecting you?
(IN SPANISH) A year ago you were
washing my pots and pans.
(IN SPANISH) Well, I don't wash
fucking pots and pans anymore.
(IN SPANISH) I'm a part of this Uncle.
(IN SPANISH) Nephew, this is not
my first barbeque.
(IN SPANISH) He's with us.
(IN ENGLISH) Is he?
And is my nephew here
pulling his own weight?
(IN SPANISH) A lot of heart.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Ahora, Gorgeous George is running
the show right now for little Yaka.
And if anyone knows where he is,
it's that fat, fucking ugly perico.
I'll get it out on the wire.
(SNIFFLING)...
...(SIGHING)
Anybody hungry? Maybe
we should stop at an IHOP or...
Shut up.
Romeo's crying.
Fucking assholes.
Shut up.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, that feels good.
(CONTINUES MOANING)
Somebody had their
Wheaties this morning.
Yeah, get after it, girl.
Oh, that's good.
Hey, let's keep this professional, baby.
No offense, but I don't need you
calling me all the time.
(SCREAMING)
What the fuck.
I'll kill you, you fucking bitch.
(EXCLAIMING)
What the fuck did you just say to me?
I'm sorry I called you that.
How courteous of you to apologize.
Courtesy is so important,
don't you agree?
Yeah. Yeah,
I'm down with that.
Good. Now sit your fat ass down.
Where is Concezio Yakavetta?
I don't know.
Yeah, there's a lot you don't know, hoss.
For instance, you're the only
New York guy, George.
Your blood just ain't quite as
blue as the rest of them, is it?
Explains why you ain't safely
tucked away in some ivory tower...
...with the rest of them bigwigs sucking
on cannoli and cocktail shrimp right now.
That's why you're the one he left
on the streets, George.
Like you know shit all of a sudden.
Somebody's got to run
our legitimate businesses.
Somebody's got to be out there making...
Someone's got to chum the waters.
Bullshit. And I ain't saying
another fucking word to you.
Good. You can just listen.
We know Concezio had that priest killed.
Oh. That's another thing
you don't know, I reckon.
But then why would he
tell you that, George?
You and your boys on the street,
y'all is bait.
Gorgeous George, huh?
Expendable George is more like it.
By the by, you've got a pretty
nice ass for a fat man.
A priest.
Sick fuck, huh?
So, until the Saints get popped,
we're all lambs to the slaughter.
Bing.
And he don't care how many of us
they wipe out in the meantime.
What do you need me to do, Skip?
Down the brugliones.
What, everyone?
North and South?
That could get a little dicey.
Fuck their old grudges.
Grudges have nothing to do with it.
They're all in this.
You know I don't take sides.
I don't care, Jo Jo.
You know I don't.
You don't take sides?
Never me. Never me.
You're gonna take my
fucking side on this, Jo Jo.
You talk to that mick Jimmy Green.
Here we go again.
Jimmy'll tell you that.
Jimmy Green.
I don't care if Jimmy Green hollowed out
your sister like a Chippewa Indian.
You're gonna get in there, Jo Jo,
and you're gonna middle-of-the-road
this fucking thing for me,
and you're not gonna fuck it up.
You tell them everything that we discussed.
Even the panic room thing?
Sure.
Good. Because that's a nice icebreaker.
They'll like that.
You know, I didn't even know
those things were real.
I thought they made that up for that movie.
Remember the one
with the broad and the kid?
The guys in the house?
Panic... Panic Room?
No, the other one.
(LAUGHING) Stop fucking around.
This is serious shit here, Jo Jo.
You tell them we meet tomorrow night.
(LAUGHING) All right.
I'll call you with the fucking location.
Okay.
Fucking thing.
(COUGHING)
Come on, kid.
It was a fucking...
It was a fucking accident.
We can work this out.
He ain't gonna do shit.
(IN ITALIAN) You're Italian Kid.
(IN ITALIAN) Help us out here.
(IN ITALIAN) Think it over.
(IN ITALIAN) I am his friend.
(IN ENGLISH) Fuck him and fuck his friend.
Deal the cards.
He ain't got the balls.
(MURMURS IN ITALIAN)...
...(SCREAMS)...
...(MAN GAGGING)...
...(IN ITALIAN) What did we do?
(PANTING)...
...(SOFTLY) Connor.
God. No.
(WHISPERING)
Why did they use his mug shot?
What? No.
Yeah, you remember when he
said he was all embarrassed...
...because that fellow had to hold up
all his long hair behind his head?
Aye.
That's an arm.
(CELL PHONE RINGING) Hey, Rocco.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
CESAR: I got the info you wanted, mijo.
The place is called Tando's
Tanning Salon on Bunker Hill.
That's where the fucking güero
gets his fake bake at.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
European cut.
Far superior.
* Yeah. You've just been
paid So split now...
...(GROANS)
Lovely singing voice there, Georgie.
We'd like you to sing for us.
Can you do that for me?
(SHOUTING) Can you do that for me?
It's getting hard to be a gentleman
of fucking leisure around here.
I want the name of the shooter you
motherfuckers used on that priest.
What priest?
His fucking name.
I don't know who it is.
That's fucking bullshit.
It's the truth. Concezio didn't
tell nobody what he was doing...
'cause he knew nobody would
have okayed it.
The shooter's an independent contractor.
That's all I fucking know.
Where the fuck is Yakavetta hiding?
Prudential Building,
40th floor.
(CELL PHONE RINGING) Jesus Christ.
MURPHY: You meeting someone tonight?
Yakavetta's racket chiefs.
Street guys.
Your kind of guys. You could take
a real bite out of crime here.
And I can help you.
CONNOR: What the fuck is that?
Nobody forgot what you guys
did to us last time.
Everybody's hiding indoors. They
give out the location an hour before.
My uncle's place is closed tonight.
I got the key.
How does Mexican work for you, George?
Do you like that?
Doesn't matter to me. I think
I just shit my European-cut Speedos.
What's this?
GREENLY: Rosary bead.
Found it pushed under the carpet
near the victim.
Father McKinney wasn't wearing a rosary,
so it's probably been there a while.
The results on all 864 prints
found at the scene.
All matched churchgoers
and clergy but one.
Partial on the priest's watch
is still unidentified.
No. No, that's horseshit.
Everybody gets printed nowadays.
They even are inking up these
snot gobblers in kindergarten now.
It's a brick wall anyway.
We know Napoleon was wearing gloves.
The lab got zilch on the lock and chain.
Even the pennies came up clean.
I'm gonna go powder my nose.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Man. Daddy would knock that out
like Mike fucking Tyson.
EUNICE: Hey.
What? I didn't say nothing.
McKinney wore his watch on his left wrist.
Where was this found exactly?
Right here,
off his left elbow.
Just occurred to me that priests
wear the rosary while taking confession.
She's right.
Dolly, get on the phone...
...and find out which wrist
he wore his rosary on.
Duffy, push that partial through the DMV.
David, you put it through Interpol
just to get an ID now.
Come on, vamoose.
You took your gloves off,
didn't you, cowboy?
Now why would you go and do
a damn fool thing like that?
(PANTING)
GEORGE: Just 2 more to go.
You guys are gonna let me go, right?
I guess we'll just have to
wait and see, won't we?
Jesus Christ, this is some
embarrassing shit.
Don't worry. We worked on a
sheep farm. Smelled way worse.
Although that is right up there.
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
Yo, spicaroo. More nachos
and más salsa, capisci?
Hey, and I need a refill here, pepe.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Whoa. Easy. Jesus.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
How do, David?
Hey.
We just dumped a text message
from George's cell. Just 2 words.
'Silver Peso.' It's a Mexican joint
down by the docks.
Sent it to his enforcer,
Jo Jo Rhama.
Guess gangsters got to eat, too, huh?
I think I'll drop in on their little supper,
see if I can shake things up a bit.
Need a bodyguard?
No, thank you, Mike Tyson.
Bye, now.
Bye.
(SIGHING)
These dagos are getting antsy, man.
I'm getting spicarooed and pepe'd.
All right, calm the fuck down.
You got to stick it out.
Just wait on one more.
(IN ITALIAN) He is not with them.
(IN ITALIAN) It is only the sons.
(IN ITALIAN) They have
a Spaniard with them.
(IN ITALIAN) They will slaughter everyone.
MAN ON PHONE: (IN ITALIAN) Let them.
(IN ITALIAN) If you kill the sons...
...(IN ITALIAN) the father will come.
Gentlemen.
All right. The gang's all here.
Give me my fucking BB gun.
No, Rome.
You've earned your stripes.
Hey, tighten it up.
So?
Where's Gorgeous?
MAN 1: Is that George?
(MAN 2 READING)
What the fuck is that?
It's Irish for,
'You're fucked.'
Que viva México, bitches.
(WHOOPING)
I've seen the light.
You guys have really turned me
around on this.
I'm, like, born again and shit.
Should we let him go?
(PANTING)
You know what I think we should do?
I think we should let God decide
if he gets a second chance.
What the fuck you doing?
What the...
No, man, come on.
Hey, what the fuck you gonna do?
You had best be right with your Jesus, boy.
(GEORGE WHIMPERING)...
...(GUN CLICKS)
Well. Praise be to Jesus.
(GASPING IN RELIEF)
Georgie.
GEORGE: Yeah?
You know all good boys go to heaven.
You know, that was perhaps one of the
finest examples of spiritual guidance
I've ever had the good fortune to witness.
It was wonderful,
wasn't it?
CONNOR: Mysterious ways,
I tell you, mysterious ways.
You know, it's about time
one of your fucking plans...
...(GROANS)
CONNOR: Put it down.
Drop the gun.
Put the goddamn gun down
right fucking now.
Easy, fellas.
And I'm alone.
He's gone.
Who the fuck are you?
My name is Eunice Bloom.
And I'm your new guardian angel.
The torch was passed to me
by a mutual friend.
A mutual friend?
By the name of fucking who?
EUNICE: Paul Maximillian fucking Smecker.
We heard.
He was a good man.
Aye. You have our condolences.
And you mine.
Well, I'm glad everybody...
Who the fuck was that guy?
That, I suspect, was the shooter
you boys have been looking for.
Who the fuck is this broad?
What the fuck is going on here?
Let's speed this up before your
new sidekick's gotta dig any deeper...
...into his impressive vocabulary.
Oh, no, you didn't.
Oh, yes I did.
I am an FBI agent controlling this
investigation from within...
...in order to ensure that you gentlemen
never see the inside of a prison cell.
Now, I am conspiring to do this
with 3 like-minded individuals...
...who have aided you in the past.
Though I have yet to inform them
of my agenda because,
well, a girl's gotta have her fun.
Dolly, Duffy and Greenly?
Hmm, the very same.
How are the lads doing?
2 of them are scared.
One's just horny.
Bet you I can tell you which one.
Bet you can't.
Let's save it for group.
Right now we've got a big problem.
What's that, then?
This simply won't do.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)...
...(INDISTINCT CHATTERING
ON POLICE RADIO)
Here's how it all went down.
A secret gathering of the brugliones.
Topic of discussion...
...(ALL SHOUTING)
Yakavetta's lost control of the streets.
They're fighting over his throne.
This was not the work of the Saints.
Interpol came through.
You were right. 5'5'.
Gotta be the shooter.
That ain't all.
Short stuff's work visa was signed
by a sponsor that doesn't exist.
Look at the date.
2 months after 9/11.
What? I don't get it.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING
ON POLICE RADIO)
Someone maneuvered it through
the system using false information...
...during the highest alert in US history.
Yakavetta's just a gangster.
He ain't got the juice to do that.
You're darn tooting,
he don't.
Irregardless, INS red-flagged it
like a motherfucker.
It's a shit storm.
Something stinks like a pig's ass
in summertime.
Come on.
We've got someplace to be.
It's, like, 2:00 a.m.
There's nothing open now.
It's after hours. I mean,
if you want a drink...
...37 bodies later, and we're
finally back where it all began.
You boys ever heard of
the Southern expression,
'We have an elephant in the living room?'
Hope you fellows brought some peanuts.
What is this?
Who the fuck are you? You're either
vice or IAD. You're IAD, aren't you?
Okay, come on, fucking arrest us.
Arrest us. I'm ready. Come on out.
Hands above your head.
(ALL SCREAMING)
Stop it.
God damn it.
You don't write.
You don't fucking call.
You should be ashamed of yourselves.
Get the fuck out of here.
You knew all along?
MURPHY: Not keeping in touch
with your old friends.
Fucking bitch.
Shame on you.
You're beautiful, babe.
(SIGHING) Thank you.
Oh, thank you.
This is the fellow?
That's the fellow.
He's a Sicilian immigrant,
name of Ottilio Panza.
He'll be front-page news in the morning,
but we have to assume that Yakavetta
already knows we've ID'd his guy.
Can't give him time to plan-B us.
We're hitting him in 48 hours.
That fast enough for you?
Should be.
Where is it gonna happen?
The Pru.
The Prudential?
What are you, cracked?
Why don't you just do it on center ice
at a fucking Bruins game?
That's where the man is,
so that's where we're going.
No guts, no glory,
green beans.
In fact, we could use a few extra hands.
That is, if you boys
can still get your Irish on.
Hey, I got balls for days, pally.
I'm a fucking sack-o-matic.
(LAUGHING) Yeah.
He's a sack-o-matic.
We're in.
All right, you boys have fun. Connor,
Murphy, escort a lady to the door.
You sure you don't want to hear the plan?
I'm not one to sit here and brag, but...
Jesus.
...this one's really Picasso.
Shut your hole.
No, I want to critique your
masterpiece with fresh eyes.
Besides, school night.
Got some homework to do.
What's the matter?
Panza knew you guys were in there
tonight and he just let it happen.
I mean, if he's working for Yakavetta,
why would he just stand by and
watch all his men get taken out?
What, you think maybe we've got
another fox in the henhouse, then?
It's starting to look that way.
Somebody pushed that visa through.
We could have ourselves a genuine
Ghost and the Darkness here.
(PANZA WHIMPERING)...
...(GROANING)...
...(IN ITALIAN) They still live.
(IN ITALIAN) What if he does not come?
What if...
...(SHUSHING)...
...(IN ITALIAN) He will come.
Either that wily old man
is not as clever as we thought...
...or he played me from the git.
You think he played me?
We got a mutiny on our hands.
Every 10-cent wannabe with a gun
is moving on us all over town.
And our fearless leader hasn't even
come out of his pussy room yet.
Capo fucking regime.
I want each one of you
to call your top button man,
the best that you have.
'Cause we are going to
rip this city a new asshole.
Starting tonight,
we reconnoiter our strength on the streets.
Starting now,
we seize the day.
Law enforcement has classified
the Italian immigrant Ottilio Panza...
...as its prime suspect in the murder
of the beloved local cleric.
An all-points bulletin has been issued,
and it appears,
at least for the time being,
the Saints have been cleared
as suspects in the priest's killing.
(MAN SPEAKING ITALIAN)...
...(IN ITALIAN) Foolish, arrogant boy.
Expanded my operations
since I saw you last.
Word got out who may or
may not have outfitted you.
Turns out you got quite
the underground following.
Please, gentlemen. Preferred customers
select from my private reserve.
If I may make a suggestion.
* I'm here if you want me...
...* I ain't gonna push and shove...
...* 'Cause, baby,
all I really want to be...
...* Is balls-deep in your love...
...* Balls-deep in your love...
...* Balls-deep in your love
I feel like that kid who found
the golden ticket in that candy bar...
...in Willy Wonka & the Chocolate Factory.
Charlie.
(SOFTLY) Yeah, Charlie.
And I want an Oompa Loompa now,
Daddy, now.
(EXCLAIMING)
I'll take these.
Have you been crying again?
Yeah. Tears of joy.
Those are queer.
How much?
Oh, no, no.
You boys are on the house.
Obliged.
Well, let's see.
ROMEO: What?
Nothing.
What, are you saying I look gay?
No, you just hail from a colorful...
Hey, you don't know me.
Do these make me look gay?
You look like you might have
seen one up close.
On a sultry Saturday in September,
the Saints saved 17 souls.
Try saying that 5 times fast.
Nothing to be afraid of.
It's all over.
Fucking pussy.
He won't come out.
Special Agent Bloom.
You are hereby relieved of
all obligation to this investigation.
And as of now, you will all report to me.
Special Agent John Kuntsler.
So, how you doing,
Bloomy?
Just fine, Kunty.
You are suspended.
Fine. But I'm gonna take a crack at it first.
EUNICE: They gained access somehow
through one of the service entrances.
What?
Nothing.
What is the matter with you?
This is just some heavy shit, that's all.
I'm just...
I'm just having a period of adjustment.
You're about to have a period of
getting your ass beat.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGING)
This is you.
Fucking be on time.
You ready for this shit,
my dear brother?
Let's do some gratuitous violence.
Meet. Front and center.
Make way.
Each one of you...
...is to stick to the guy who
called you like stink on quim.
Pick your own crews.
You arm yourself to the teeth.
And when these Bible-banging psychos
make their attempt,
it is your job to blow their soulless
hearts right out of their bodies.
(SIGHING)
Okay, here's the situation, Lloyd.
Me and a couple of friends of mine are
fitting to do some killing here tonight.
I'm talking bullets, blood,
custom wholesale slaughter.
You follow me, Lloyd-o?
(WHIMPERS)
Good. Now, I've run into a little snag.
You see, I'm trying to figure out a tag line.
You know, something cool to say
when it's all over,
like, 'We're gonna need a bigger boat.'
Or, 'I'll be back.' But mine, you know?
I've gotta own this thing.
It's creative.
It happened to be a creative plan.
Fucking ridiculous.
Probably based on some
stupid shit you saw in a movie.
And here I am again, all tying
myself up with fucking rope.
What's the deal with you and
the fucking rope? Honestly.
It happened to be a very
useful thing, so shut it.
You didn't get this from a movie, did you?
The Eiger Sanction with Clint Eastwood.
Fuck.
And it worked like a charm for him.
I fucking knew.
Now I'm gonna take the gag off,
nice and slow so it doesn't hurt.
(GROANING)
I know, I know.
This fucking hurts this way.
Fuck. Fuck...
...(SHUSHING)
Fuck.
I know, I know, I know.
I can't believe you, man.
I'm a janitor.
What do I know about guns
and bullets and shit, man?
Well, then, just...
No. I don't care what you're doing here...
...with your fucking friends.
It's none of my business.
I'm just...
I have a wife and a family and kids.
Actually, they're not even my kids, right?
I'm taking care of some
other asshole's kids...
...on a fucking janitor's salary.
I'm not riffing, Lloyd.
Now, I need an hasta la vista line,
toute fucking suite...
...and you're gonna help me think of one.
What the fuck did you do?
I don't know, it just stopped.
Well, fucking get it going again.
GREENLY: It won't turn back on.
It just died.
Shit.
GREENLY: Fucking thing.
Come on.
DUFFY: Come on.
Come on, you piece of shit.
Starting tonight, each one of you limp-dick
fucking slobs is back out on the street...
...earning your daily bread.
ALL: Come on, come on. No.
Shut the fuck up.
Shut up.
(SHOUTING IN ITALIAN)
Okay, what about,
'Take that, you suckers'?
No, that's not cool enough, man.
How much time?
How much fucking time?
GREENLY: 60 seconds.
No, we gotta go right now.
GREENLY: No fucking way.
DUFFY: What are you talking about?
If we're even a few seconds late,
Romeo's dead.
You'd better all dust off your ball bats.
You'd better find your inner gangster.
'Merry Christmas,
motherfuckers.'
That's too sacrilegious.
All right, we've got about 13 floors.
11 more, ball park it.
It's about 15 per floor,
we need... 165.
DUFFY: Dude, wait.
Count it up in 5s.
5, 10, 15, 20...
This is retarded.
Fucking Eiger Sanction.
Shut it and concentrate. 25...
'Cause you got to break bones.
You've got to crush skulls.
You gotta do what you gotta do.
You're gonna need those.
Bang, bang, bang.
You shoot everybody in there,
and then you're like,
'Yo, eat it. Eat it.'
What, are we at a fucking buffet now?
(SIGHING) Fuck.
You guys can't do this.
Are you fucking crazy?
Time.
Jesus Christ.
7 seconds.
Holy shit.
DUFFY: 6,
5, 4...
It's time.
3, 2...
One thing has always amazed me.
How quiet it gets.
You ever noticed that?
It's hard to imagine
that just a few hours ago...
...it was the goddamn O.K. Corral in here.
We're gonna have ourselves a
good old-fashioned shoot-'em-up.
BOTH: And shepherds we shall be,
for Thee, my Lord, for Thee.
Power hath descended
forth from Thy hand,
that our feet may swiftly carry out
Thy command.
So we shall flow a river forth to Thee
and teeming with souls shall it ever be.
(RECITING IN LATIN)...
...(SPEAKING ITALIAN)...
...(RECITING IN LATIN)
Who ordered the whup-ass fajitas?
That's fucking stupid.
It's completely retarded.
Was that the best you could do?
I just...
I couldn't...
...(SHUSHING)
Broke down the door,
didn't you?
(DOORBELL RINGING)...
...(RECITING IN LATIN)
Ding-dong, motherfucker,
ding-dong.
Fucking A.
You said it.
And that, gentlemen,
is the sound of the fat lady singing.
Should we clap or something?
Shut up.
Hey, hey.
Hey.
You hurt her, you piece of shit,
I'll kill you.
She's not on there.
There's nothing on there.
Get a hostage negotiator
down here, you fucking wad.
Get off me.
What is your fucking problem?
He could be in there
all touching her and shit.
Fuck. Come on.
Look, I was listening to you out there.
And that's, like,
exactly what happened.
And that's what made me think
you were the person to talk to.
So, Yakavetta had a partner?
Everybody gave Concezio props for
building the family back up.
'He's such a genius.' What bullshit.
It was the Old Man all along.
Old Man?
Yeah, that's what he called him.
For the last 3 years, every play
we made came straight from him.
Teaming up with the Chinese,
keeping the feud going between
Southie and the North End, everything.
Concezio worshipped the Old Man
like some kind of fucking Mafia oracle.
I have no idea what
his real name is, though.
Concezio always called him the Old Man.
Think. I mean, did he ever use a
surname or a nickname or something?
One time.
Well, what was it?
He called him the Roman.
That's just weird.
The Roman?
What do you think it means?
Feels like our ghost to me.
DOLLY: Well, what's the plan?
'Cause the brothers ain't going nowhere
until we get Panza or they do.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)...
...(DOOR OPENING)
Sack-o-matic, I said.
I've got nothing.
One in the hole.
Fuck you.
1, 2, 3.
DOC: Boys. Boys.
Put them down.
Throw them over.
I'll kill the old man.
Brothers, huh?
Oh, we gonna have us some fun.
So, which one first?
Which one do you love more?
This one?
(GROANING)...
...(SCREAMING)...
...(COUGHING)
Doc. Call a fucking ambulance right now.
You.
Where's the Old Man?
Never.
MURPHY: Just hold on, man.
Help's on the way,
hang in there.
Boys, it's over.
It's okay.
Proudest day of my life.
(COUGHING)
Da.
Easy, boys.
(GUN CLICKS)
Jesus fucking Christ.
I'm gonna blow this motherfucker's
brains out right now.
POPPA: Connor.
Son, Daddy's working.
What the fuck you talking about?
Where is he?
No matter how this turns out,
you fucking die today.
Believe it, motherfucker.
Where is the Old Man?
(GUN CLICKS) No.
(SIGHING)...
...(BOTH WHISPERING PRAYERS)...
...(IN ITALIAN) Make me famous.
(REPEATING DIALOGUE)...
...(GUN CLICKS)
Where?
(SHOUTING) Where is he?
(SHOUTING IN ITALIAN)...
...(BOTH SIGHING)...
...(MEOWING)
You look good, Roc.
You two don't.
Yeah, we had a friend...
I know.
He was a big boy.
If it weren't for us,
maybe the 2 of you would...
Would what? Would never
have stood for anything?
What are you talking about, Roc?
I made my decision and stood
next to you. And it was an honor.
And I wouldn't change that for
the whole world. Not one minute of it.
Now, sláinte.
(ALL TOASTING)
You know, he was sort of a
bad-ass, though, wasn't he?
Shades of Eastwood.
Charlie Bronson.
Duke fucking Wayne.
CONNOR AND MURPHY:
Men build things.
Then we die.
It's in our fucking DNA.
That's what we do.
And when it all falls down...
We build it right back up again.
But this time bigger. Better.
Look. Look what we can do.
Look how fucking beautiful we are.
You think the men that
built all this had it easy?
Hard men.
Doing hard shit.
And that gives me a hard-on.
But not in a gay way or anything.
No, no, course not.
Yeah, goes without saying.
I am so sick of this self-help, 12-step,
leftover hippie generation bullshit.
Now they don't want you to do anything,
right? Just sit there. Don't drink...
Don't smoke.
Don't drive fast.
ALL: Kiss my ass.
Fuck it, do it all, I say.
You think Duke Wayne spent all his time...
...talking about his feelings
with a fucking therapist?
There's no fucking way he did.
John Wayne died with 5 pounds of
undigested red meat in his ass.
Now that's a man.
Real men hide their feelings. Why?
ALL: Because it's none of
your fucking business.
Men do not cry,
men do not pout,
men jack you in the fucking jaw and say...
Thanks for coming out.
(BOTH GASPING)
I am so sorry, boys.
This was all my fault.
There's a few things your dad
needs to tell youse.
Come on, kid, it's good for you,
it's good for us.
We'll take you right out
the back of this place.
(SOFTLY) Easy, Noah.
They'll never touch you.
Oh.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
What, are you stupid or something?
Noah, mio amico.
No more of this.
I can't stop.
Okay, we think of something, eh?
We think of something.
Noah, look.
We got something for you.
My friend...
...(INAUDIBLE)
LOUIE: Bonnavese is always with 2 men.
Both of them, La Cosa Nostra,
many years.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
POPPA: That's how it went for years.
Louie would do all the planning
and I would do the other.
MURPHY: Jesus.
How'd you end up inside, Da?
Back in '75 I did a piece of work.
I come out and the police
was waiting for me.
He set me up.
25 to life.
Why did he set you up?
I can't wait to ask him.
Why didn't you flip on him, Da?
The guy fucked you.
POPPA: He had learned
of the birth of my sons.
* As I turn back the years
with my eyes full of tears...
...* There's some things I can barely see...
...* Just so pure and true...
...* How we loved and no one knew...
...(IN ITALIAN) Hello, my old friend.
(IN ITALIAN) Many years.
(IN ITALIAN) Are you in need?
MAN ON PHONE: (IN ITALIAN)
I am making marinara and alas...
I have run out of tomatoes.
(IN ITALIAN) To help an old friend...
...how many can you spare?
(IN ITALIAN) Don't worry.
(IN ITALIAN) You are in luck.
(IN ITALIAN) I am
in good supply of tomatoes.
Agent Kuntsler, you gotta see this.
We just found...
It's Bloom. She just back-doored
this info from Fed archives.
Jesus Christ,
she's gone rogue.
Get an APB on her.
John.
I want that crazy bitch grabbed up now.
MAN: John, think about this.
Jimmy.
What the fuck are you doing?
Who the fuck is this?
He's in York, Maine. About an hour
from here. But he's off the grid.
Logged on to an FBI database
to get the info.
Only a matter of time before they flag it.
Better get a move on or
they'll get there before you do.
Will they know it's you?
Yeah.
Will you be all right, dear?
I hear Costa Rica's nice.
I never thought I'd ask this of another
human being, but please, kill this man.
Kill this man.
(MAN RECITING PRAYERS
IN ITALIAN)...
...(BUZZING)...
...(SHALL WE MEET
BEYOND THE RIVER PLAYING)
Hello, Louie.
Noah.
We haven't much time.
My garden is...
She's beautiful, no?
But I forget, your eyes are blind to beauty.
You are...
You are a destroyer, Noah.
You know my reasons.
But do you?
You think it's...
You think it's for your father.
No. You were born a killer.
Death, la morte,
it is in the blood.
No.
This is bullshit.
We should go now.
It's only one fucking guy.
Explain these.
You were not there to raise them.
Not one single day.
But how closely they followed
their father's footsteps.
They got your blood,
Noah, tua rabbia.
Your anger.
And you?
What are you?
(IN ITALIAN) I am a creator.
(IN ENGLISH) You see,
we were opposed.
As old as la storia di frog and...
...(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Scorpion.
(AGREEING IN ITALIAN)...
...(IN ENGLISH) Scorpion.
Remember, not a scratch on the Old Man.
Copy that.
Waiting for the signal.
What the fuck is this place?
It gives me the creeps.
Why did you sell me out, Louie?
You can never understand.
25 years.
Try me.
They were building something.
They?
They were creating something.
An empire.
They?
I was helping them.
I used you, Noah,
to destroy their competition,
to cut out their cancers.
I earned my place among them.
Is this your place amongst them?
Because all I see...
...is an old man in a broke-down palace,
sitting in a garden.
The scorpion and the frog...
...both lose everything.
See, without you,
I was no longer useful to them.
They cast me out.
My old man used to tell me
about a place like this.
Back in the woods,
he said that there's this guy...
Why the priest, Louie?
Why all this? Why now?
Because I knew it would
bring you and your sons.
You will destroy the Yakavettas
for me. Clear my way.
And this time,
I will take what is mine. Just...
Just a little piccolo pezzo.
For my old age.
After all, I have never been a greedy man.
(SHALL WE MEET
BEYOND THE RIVER PLAYING)...
...(INAUDIBLE)
ANNOUNCER ON GRAMOPHONE:
Beyond the River,
done by Anthony and Harrison,
Edison Records.
Connor.
Murph.
POPPA: Take me to him.
Take me to him now.
(ALL GROANING)
I'll see you in a minute, Louie.
No, Da. No, please.
God, no.
(GASPING)
Look. Look, boys.
It's so beautiful.
It's a beautiful day.
No.
It is, Da. It is.
It is beautiful, Da.
MURPHY: (SOFTLY) Aye, it is, Da.
POPPA: And they that holdest my name...
...shall come with the shaking of the earth...
...and the roiling of the oceans.
It's a non-extradition country.
Passport under your name.
Money, contacts and a map
to your final destination.
Which is?
The monastery at Saint Escazú.
A monastery?
Monasteries enjoy the protection
of the Holy See.
They're not even subject to local laws,
searches, et cetera.
A sanctuary within a sanctuary.
He's going to take you by boat to
a private airstrip down the shore,
where we have arranged for your travel.
Off the books, of course.
Father, I ain't one to look a gift horse,
but you still haven't told me
how you're involved in all this.
And the second I need to disappear,
you show up with plans
and paperwork in hand.
It's like you knew before I did.
The Lord works in mysterious ways,
my dear.
We wanted you to know
that you're not alone.
We have many resources.
You keep saying 'we.' Now, who's 'we'?
MAN: You ready to go?
Subtitles: Arigon
I hear they party pretty hard
at that monastery.
(SIGHING)
Oh.
I'm not sure I'm in love with that
new look there, Betty Boop.
I attended your funeral,
you son of a bitch.
I know. Loved your shoes.
The skirt was a little risqué
for a funeral, but, hey,
who am I to begrudge someone
their sense of individuality?
(SHOUTING) What is this?
Keep it down.
You don't wanna scare away
my little fishies.
Fuck your fish.
What the hell is going on here?
You are exposed,
young lady.
You're a very clever little girl, Eunice.
That's why I chose you.
Now it's time for you
to put your thinking cap on.
We got all the financial backing
and protection...
...of the biggest corporation in the world.
And 2 CEOs worthy of the public trust.
Now, what do you think is going on here?
You wanna get them out.
I want to get them out,
get them back to work,
take this thing to a whole new level.
Where're they being held?
CROWD: Set them free. Set them free.
CROWD: Set them free.
The Hoag ain't just any prison.
Wrong. That's exactly
what it is, just a prison.
Run by men.
Men, as we both know, are fallible.
EUNICE: Well, whatever we do,
we gotta do it quick.
Those boys aren't safe in there.
SMECKER: Oh, I don't know.
A little birdie tells me
they're gonna be just fine.
(THE SAINTS ARE COMING
PLAYING)...
...* The saints are coming...
...* I say no matter how I try,
I realize there's no reply...
...* The saints are coming...
...* I say no matter how I try,
I realize there's no reply...
...* A drowning sorrow floods
the deepest grief...
...* How long now?
* Until a weather change condemns belief...
...* The stone says...
...* This paternal guide once had his day...
...* Once had his day...
...* The saints are coming...
...* I say no matter how I try,
I realize there's no reply...
...* The saints are coming...
...* I say no matter how I try,
I realize there's no reply...
...(HOLY FOOL PLAYING)...
...* I know there's
something happening here...
...* Do my eyes deceive my ears?
* Can you feel that, man?
* I sure as hell can...
...* Can you feel that, man?
* 2,000 years I've reigned...
...* As the King of Man...
...* And every morning
you felt my guiding hand, yeah...
...* What'd you do to deserve me?
* I spread my wings and my minions sing...
...* I know you heard it, man...
...* Yet my sun still shines on your back...
...* Your mountains, your sins...
...* You gotta come to me...
...* With your arms outstretched, baby...
...* You better come to me...
...* And on your knees...
...* 'Cause I'm your holy...
...* Your holy fool...
...* I am your holy fool...
...* Yes, I'm your holy...
...* Your holy fool...
...* I am your holy fool...
...* Power has descended
forth from my hand...
...* I know you felt it, man...
...* Yet my sun still shines on your back...
...* Your mountains, your sins...
...* Yeah...
...* Yes, I know that you fear me...
...* I call upon you from my holy hill...
...* Sometimes I ask you to live...
...* Sometimes to kill...
...* Oh, yeah...
...* Sometimes I ask you to kill...
...* You gotta come to me...
...* With your arms outstretched, baby...
...* You better come to me...
...* And on your knees
* 'Cause I'm your holy...