Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
"My friend the squirrel
was there this morning.
"He gave me a wink.
"A Glance ...
"I said see you tomorrow."
See you tomorrow.
Agostino, my coffee, quickly!
Agostino!
Pilar! My coffee!
You're serving?
It's her little girl's communion.
You've given her a day off?
A week...
Portugal's a long way.
I won't pay
for you to do their job.
It won't kill me this once.
And I like
being alone in my kitchen.
Everyone has their place...
you're Madame Pujol...don't forget it.
I wake up every morning  and repeat:
I am Madame Pujol ...
I am Madame Pujol ... "
Did your meeting with the German
buyer go well?
Success with them means entertainment
I took him to dinner in Lille
then to the 'Bada-Boom'.
With the pretty girls... will you take me there?
The 'Bada-Boom'?
-Yes.
Don't be ridiculous!
It's not a place for you.
It's not my place in the kitchen
it's not my place at the 'Bada-Boom' ...
Where is my place?
Stop asking stupid questions.
You didn't drink too much?
Let me alone.
You know what the doctor said.
I know!
You're getting more and more jumpy.
It's not easy running an
umbrella factory with 300 workers
Every day fighting the unions,
not to mention the tax department!
Papa said the same thing.
In his time it was a piece of cake.
Fortunately I've been able to fix ...
the mess he created.
That's true.
You brought your energy.
I brought a dowry
of my Papa's factory
I've got to listen to the news.
In the provinces strike orders
have been issued by the unions.
We'll go to our guest
Communist MP Maurice ...
Aagh! Why him?
- While employers won't want
to include measures
favoring workers,
we'll fight ...
Fuck the workers! ...
.. buggering up my factory...
.... arsehole!
[Michèle Torr :"Take me dancing tonight."]
Oh, his drops!
Office of Monsieur Pujol,
...yes?.
Mademoiselle Nadège,
Madame Pujol here.
Oh, hello, Madame Pujol.
My husband got home late last
night from the 'Bada-Boom' with the German
and this morning
he forgot to take his drops.
So if you'd tell him to drop back home,
as soon as he gets in.
I couldn't do that ...
You know the state he gets
in when he doesn't take them
Can I count on you?
I'll tell him.
Thanks. Goodbye.
A good deed done.
Good morning, sir.
What else?
I'd like a word with you.
You already on a
cigarette break?
Excuse us, Monsieur Pujol.
'Morning Nadège.
Your wife called.
What does she want?
"Your drops."
Aagh... she pisses me off!
No touching.
What?
What's this story about a German?
I'll explain.
No need. Keep that for your wife.
You're not gonna make a scene.
Tomorrow night ...
You'll go back to
the 'Bada-Boom'.
It's closed on Thursdays.
Mama, are you there?
Joel! Hello darling.
Happy birthday... I just picked it for you.
Oh, thank you.
How thoughtful.
You're up early.
I dropped the children at school.
Are they well?
Yes, but they're upset
their father's away.
Give me a hand.
You've heard from him?
Jean-Charles finally phoned me
from Toronto.
Things going well?
Certainly...
I think we'll separate.
What?
He travels all the time,
we never see him.
I feel he's not
interested in me any more.
You should go with him on his trips.
And who'd look after the kids?
Me.
No way.
You're too busy.
It's me who'll take charge
of the children's education.
How sad...
...to separate
from Jean-Charles, so soon.
Yes, I know.
But the idea that
he's deceiving me is unbearable.
You've thought about the children?
No, I'm thinking about myself.
Even among the most united couples,
there are empty times.
And then... they go away!
Or don't go away.
You know about that.
How long 've you been
sleeping apart from Papa?
I don't want to
talk about that.
When did he last behave like a husband
with you?
D'you think
I'd go into that!
There's more to life than sex,
little girl.
At your age, perhaps.
Your father works so hard!
In the evening he's tired.
Maybe he's deceiving you.
I forbid you
to criticize your father.
I'm not criticizing him,
It's you.
You've just accepted everything... everything!
You pretend not to see,
but he does just as he wants.
I've always been impervious
to gossip.
And then I have my grandchildren,
my garden, my poems ...
But are you happy, Mama?
Of course I'm happy.
I decided that...
once and for all.
But me, I don't want
this pathetic life.
I'd rather divorce.
How are you going to live,
if you divorce.
I'll ask Papa for
a position at the factory.
That's not a bad idea.
You need to know it's what you want.
Me... at least, I know.
The worst thing for me would be
to become like you: "une potiche"... a trophy wife.
Joel!!!
You do it on purpose, don't you?
Don't park outside the entrance!
I stopped by for
Mama's birthday.
Who's birth...
Forgot?
That bitch Nadège forgot.
She's got other things to think about think.
Buy whatever you want
I'll pay you back.
Papa, you never change.
Tonight try to
be in a better mood.
I need to talk to you.
You know what she wants?
Divorce.
She's trading in Jean-Charles for someone else?
No!
She wants to work with her beloved father
at the factory.
No-way-in-the-world-and-the-kids-good...
Gotta get my drops.
Laurent's not here?
He'll be here tonight.
He's got good news for us.
I'm wary of good news...
...especially concerning your son.
I think he wants to get married.
Great...eh?
Supporting a new family ...
But he's not asking you for anything.
That'll come.
The girl who's got her hooks into him
knows what she's at.
I reassure you,
her family is respectable.
She's the daughter of the Cathedral Square baker,
Floriane Marquiset.
Robert!
My God! But ...
Name of God, dammit!
It seems she's nice.
She's studied piano.
She studied the piano?
Would you've preferred the clarinet?
It's beyond belief for him
to marry Floriane Marquiset.
A Pujol with a Marquiset,
..... it'd be a disgrace.
You're being way too snobbish.
Wait 'til you meet her.
I'll never meet her.
And Laurent will not marry
Marquiset's daughter!
You understand?
If you want my opinion ...
Your "opinion"?
You have an opinion?
All I ask of you
is to share mine.
Be nice,
Just keep to your little poems.
Joel is right.
I'm just a trophy wife.
I lay there in a corner ...
I'm just part of the decor.
Are you challenging me too?
Name me one woman as indulged as you are.
With regard to household appliances,
I'm queen.
You have everything,
you have to agree.
Now the phone.
What a life!
Hello?
Oh ...can't be true!
Dammit!
Oh, damn!
I'm coming.
What's still going? I'm coming.
It never stops.
They're striking at workshop 4.
A strike?
It'll cost me millions.
What'll you do?
What'll I do...fight!
The ... But Robert ...
Be careful though.
I'll go mad...
A strike!
A strike ...
"The rose in the morning
"Opens at noon
"Ephemeral destiny
"Died at midnight."
How's Papa?
Always in a bad mood
with these strikes.
You think it'll get better tonight?
Hopefully.
I'm sure he'll be charming...
being my birthday.
Are you happy the way your studies are going?
I've had a gut-full.
Political Science just isn't my thing.
What is your thing?
I dunno, Mama.
Are you still taking drawing courses?
No time...
... and what's the point?
What a shame, you were gifted.
I wish we had
an artist in the family.
You know what would make me happy?
What?
Come to work at the plant.
Not interested in the plant.
I wouldn't ever want
to work with Papa.
To end with the boss syndrome...
hated by everyone ...
Your grandfather
was adored by everyone.
Mama, paternalism,
It's over, old-fashioned.
Today's man must be a bastard,
orders, unbridled capitalism.
Tell me, when did
you meet this Floriane?
It's been six months.
We met on the train
when I came at Christmas.
That's romantic.
You're sure you're in love?
Yes, Mama.
She's crazy about me.
So much the better.
That makes for happiness.
One Sunday, after Mass
we stopped by her mother's bakery
and got a house special... a Bombe Glacée.
I recognised the beautiful Madame Marquiset
behind her counter,
always so well dressed.
She died
electrocuted by a hairdryer.
You thinking about getting married?
That's what she wants.
When'll we meet her?
Once she's finished
her exams in Paris.
How nice!
Grandma, look what I did
for your birthday.
Fabián, you were supposed
to to wait for dessert.
- Let him.
It's so nice.
Thank you, Fabián.
When's Papa coming?
I dunno.
His schedule
is very mysterious.
What is it, exactly?
Terrorists
with machine guns.
It's fun.
What imagination!
Grandma, I'll do
an imitation of Coluche.
No, Stanislaus,
not that horrible Coluche here.
Yet it's funny.  No, it's vulgar
Paris would like it.
It'd do you good to travel.
Your Jean-Charles never takes you anywhere?
Please Laurent, not now.
That's Papa. I'll get the door.
He's got his key.
I'm coming, Papa. I'm coming.
Nadège? What're you doing here?
I must see Madame Pujol. It's very urgent.
She's is in the lounge.
Mademoiselle Nadège?
Madame, it's terrible.
Terrible?...
... Papa?
Yes. Monsieur Pujol ...
He had an attack?
No. He's locked in.
Locked in?
Yes.
He fought
with the foreman.
The workers have locked him
in his office.
I was sure there was something...
he was so on edge this morning!
Do they have
machine guns?
Stanislaus, Flavian
go upstairs.
You must call the commissioner,
to send a mediator.
We must get the riot squad.
We won't get anywhere with tear gas.
These workers have got outside the law.
We must act with diplomacy.
Obviously.
You side with the left.
Beside you,
everyone is left.
That's enough, calm down.
Mademoiselle,
what do they want
exactly?
They require new
health care.
This is not too much to ask.
The toilets are long-standing grievance.
They're Turkish-style!
It's all a political pretext.
They demand everything now:
Increase in staff...
a Christmas bonus ...
Remove surveillance.
Obviously, that's a lot.
It's that filthy Babin
who's behind it.
He stirs up revolt.
You heard him
on the radio?
That man makes my flesh crawl.
He'll be OK if he takes his drops.
He always forgets.
If I wasn't there ...
...rather... if you weren't there ...
....if we weren't there.
Don't apologize.
Well I'll go ...
Where are you going?
I'm his son.
They can take me hostage in his place.
Anyway.
I appreciate this.
I'm off.
Come on.
They're letting him go?
They talked with him.
It's Hubert
One of the worst.
I hope they'll
come to an agreement.
More and more are coming.
They're waving banners.
They wrote
on the wall:
"Pujol equals...oh!... Hitler."
They're exaggerating.
Besides the little bit
on the face ...
They're getting more worked up.
I'm scared.
Me too.
Nadège, lock the door.
Madame! Madame!
They're approaching the house.
Calm down.
Marie Antoinette found herself
in the same situation.
She still finished
under the guillotine.
What are they shouting?
Pujol ... Fed up ...
Pujol, fed ...
PUJOL, fed up!
What are you doing here?
A moment of relaxation.
Some of the claims
aren't that unjustified.
Model secretary
turns into rabid unionist.
It won't last long.
I'm not turning into anything,
but salaried staff've gotta to take a stand.
You don't know what's what,
you're the boss's daughter.
It's better than the boss's chick.
I forbid you ...
Who is it?
I'll go.
If it's the workers, don't open.
Trust me.
Who's there?
Laurent? Already?
You're not hurt, at least.
Assaulting my brother!
They're madmen.
No, you weren't there.
It wasn't the workers. papa.
Papa?
Robert?
The workers helped me
to see Papa.
I tried to reason with
him to make concessions.
He jumped on me screaming
that I was a moron.
Luckily, the picket line
hemmed him in.
In this case,
it's better I go.
Mama,
they'll laugh at you.
I don't want your father's death
on my conscience.
You want me with you?
No, darling.
It's better I go alone.
It's the boss's wife!
Yes?
Monsieur Deputy-Mayor, good evening.
Madame Pujol?
Can I come in?
Yes, of course.
Yes ...
I'm sorry
to receive you like this.
I'm not here
for a society event.
Good...then sit down.
To my left or my right.
Wherever you want.
What can I do for you,
Madame Pujol?
Monsieur Deputy-Mayor,
I came to ask you
to use your influence
to release my husband.
A dialogue needs to be opened
with the union delegates.
My husband refuses.
I think it would be much better
to negotiate in a friendly manner.
"Friendly manner"?
One worker was attacked!
My husband is impulsive.
His left fist
alone?
Why are you being so aggressive?
I don't see why
I should help you.
You didn't always say that,
if you know what I mean.
Don't bring up the past.
Would our moment of madness be
incompatible with your image?
Or, for that matter, with the image
a perfect wife.
Without you, perhaps I would be.
Don't try to blame me.
After all,
youthful indiscretions
do happen.
You stinker!
It was the same for you
as for me.
You were a girl, boss's wife
and I was a worker.
I betrayed my class.  And I my husband.
Which is worse?
I remember
I was returning from a wedding.
Monsieur! Monsieur!
I'd punctured a tire on the road.
By chance we crossed paths.
- It was my usual route.
I'll help a neighbour
even if I disagree
with their politics.
Hello.
You should have seen
the state of your dress.
Hello.
All stained with grease,
the jack in hand.
I wore a dress in organza
with a pink cape.
I changed your wheel
and you made me smile,
abandoning for a moment
the arrogance of your caste.
Grandpa was a boilermaker.
You refused the tip I offered.
But I accepted a cigarette.
We went to have a smoke together,
in the shade of a walnut tree.
As we went
into the brush.
You must have thought
me an easy woman.
No, Suzanne.
The very next day
you resumed your distance
and firmly drew
the curtain on our adventure.
I was married, a mother.
I had a social status to maintain.
So many times I feared
you'd brag about it.
I can hold my tongue when the honor
of a woman is at stake.
Thank you.
Good.
You want your husband back?
Yes.
But if I get his release
I'll need a return match.
A return match?
Sir, I daren't understand....
....at our age?
No, you misunderstand.
It's no longer a horny truck-driver
facing you.
I'm confused. Forgive me.
No, forget it...
In other circumstances ...
Oh yes?
Let's get off the subject.
I'm thinking about the role you might
play within the factory.
Meaning...?
If reforms are not
applied in the immediate future,
the company will be closed
and 300 workers unemployed.
That's a lot.
Yes, Suzanne.
So? What did the doctor say?
I don't know.
He's still with Papa.
Does he know how
he was released?
Better not tell him.
How humiliating for him!
Freed by his worst enemy.
If the riot squad had been on the job,
we wouldn't have needed him
Don't be simple.
Even the communists have a heart.
That's what destroys a man.
His gaze wasn't the same.
Don't worry, he'll recover OK.
And if I made him
my special broth?
Why not.
You need rest, darling.
But it's not that serious.
You're not
safe from another attack,
and you may have
a pulmonary endema.
You must spend one week
in hospital for tests.
But the factory?
The factory...the factory... it'll fold without you?
I'll leave you.
Here's the prescription.
Monsieur Pujol, I expect you
at the hospital this week.
That's it!
Thank you, doctor.
See you soon.
Have you talked to Laurent
about the Marquiset girl?
Did you tell him to forget her?
You don't understand...he's in love.
You're forcing me to reveal
something unpleasant
You give me no choice.
I have reason to believe
Floriane is partly my daughter.
What do you mean
"partly your daughter"?
Her mother told me.
Her mother's no longer of this world ...
So Madame Marquiset
was your mistress?
Straightaway... out come the big words!
What a fine husband!
Your reaction's a little late.
How was I supposed to know?
It's true that we were....
....discrete.
She was married.
She wasn't arousing
her husband's suspicions.
Exactly.  It's your son's fault.
Of all the girls in the world, that mental defective
had to go and find Mademoiselle Marquiset.
This trumps
the birthday gift that you forgot!
You want me to beg your pardon?
No. You disgust me.
Under these circumstances, you'll agree
that marriage is unthinkable.
They're already sleeping together.
Omigod!
Your banging the Marquiset woman
won't get you into heaven.
Why, f'Godsake?
It's so long ago.
But because ...
it's the straw
that broke the trophy wife's back!
Is everything OK, ma'am?
Yes, OK.
I made my special broth.
That's nice.
It'll do him good.
Cuckoo!
What are you doing here?
I'm here
to give you my little specialty.
Yes.
That can't hurt me.
I was talking about
my special broth.
Mademoiselle Nadège is really
a model secretary.
She made some broth
for your father.
She'll get it in her face.
He's here.
Have him come in.
Who?
The one who freed your father.
That man here?
It is you who ...
- That's me.
But it's the devil!
Hello.
Welcome, Monsieur Deputy.
And thank you again.
The union delegates
feel they have taken the first step.
They require
an immediate response.
It's just that my husband
isn't well this morning.
Tomorrow
he may receive visits.
You don't give a damn about me?
It's the truth...
True, he's very weak.
You want a certificate?
I've done my part of the bargain.
If I plead his case,
it's up to the workers to decide.
So in the absence of negotiations,
I predict a restoration
of the strike.
As for me, I'll predict
my foot up your arse!
Monsieur Pujol!
He doesn't look sick.
What are you doing to me?
Isn't enough
having humiliated me?
Come off it, Papa ...
Shut up, arsehole!
Papa, be reasonable.
You'll strain your heart.
What have you done to me?
I only promised
Monsieur the Deputy-Mayor that
in exchange for your release
you'd consider some requests
...about staff.
That I'm for.
Me too.
For the brainwashing ...
Robert, you do nothing but fight.
You've got to negotiate.
Tell the delegates
that if they want
paid holidays,
they've got to
return to work.
If they want to earn more,
it'll require more work.
You thought I was finished, washed up.
My family was ready
to sell off the factory.
Once
the picket lines are removed,
I'll show you what
a boss is who has two of them!
- Let me tell you
the Works
has decided to review your accounts.
Whadda you mean?
That your Mercedes is listed
as a company car.
Your apartment, your servants,
your home, your boat,
made out to be
company
expenses.
Papa!
Heart attack, as I predicted.
Raise his head.
Press firmly.
My father... a heart-attack.
Send an ambulance.
This is where is anger leads to.
He'll go to hospital now.
What about the factory?
Your father should
be replaced
by someone with power of attorney.  He transferred it.
In this case ...
No. Sorry.
The management of a factory,
Not for me.
Me?
She's worse than Papa.
But then who?
Jean-Charles.
Oh no, not him.
Why not you, Madame Pujol?
You're joking?
It'd be above board.
The founder's daughter,
the boss's wife.
But I don't know anything about it.
You won't really be
Plant Manager.
Just sit in
Papa's chair.
You won't be given any
responsibilities.
Still, I don't know if I ...
Suzanne, do what you're told.
Do what you're told.
Better you than someone else.
We've no choice.
If it's you who's asking me ...
I'ill do nothing to cause you concern.
That's the way.
So you agree?
In the interest of the factory, yes.
It's okay, I'll be fine.
I'm trusting on you
to keep me posted.
Count on me, boss.
Should I take your place, Madame Pujal?
Yes. You do that
very well.
No, Nadège.
I'm going with Papa.
It would have been easier
if you'd been
successor to your father.
You're going with history.
Women everywhere
are taking power.
Go, go home.
You have to speak to Monsieur Babin.
In what state of mind
will you meet the committee?
Conciliation. Provided
they don't ask for too much.
When the workers
demand too much,
it's that the boss
doesn't give enough.
Good. We must prepare
a little script,
so what you
say'll be without stuttering.
That's a good idea.
Me, I'd start with:
"Gentlemen, I come to you
in a spirit of understanding ... "
"Gentlemen"?
It's cold, it's snobbish.
I 'd say "my friends".
I wouldn't recommend that.
These aren't your friends.
Maybe they'll become so.
That'd take action,
not empty words.
Good. Go on.
"In a spirit
of understanding.
"I am just a woman,
but ... "
I can't say that.
It's obvious, isn't it?
I don't apologize
for being a woman.
It's not that ...
You're a misogynist.
We support
women's rights.
I can't say
"I am a woman."
I'll say:
"Yes, I am a woman."
Because whether you like it or not,
I'm a woman.
But I like it.
I like it very much, Suzanne.
They're waiting for you.
Already?
If we want
work to resume,
let's go.
How do they seem?
Not very prepossessing.
The less they're kept waiting,
the better it'll be.
I'd like to get myself ready.
You're fine.
I know what I am.
They can wait.
No, really.
Does the factory say anything to you?
Should it?
When you had the luck to be your father's son
and when you've done Political Science ...
I'm "my father's son?
You are the Pujol son.
It doesn't interest me, all that.
The money, possessions,
benefits.
I'm against the exploitation of man.
Have you told your father that?
Sort of.
What'd he say?
I'd be eaten
by others.
Typical!
Politically...are you engaged?
Politics, protests,
mean very little for me.
Everything is political commitment.
Don't wear yourself out.
What interests you?
You really want to know?
Yes.
Painting, art history,
Kandinsky ...
Ah yes!
Kandinsky, yes.
He was a true revolutionary.
You see that do you care
about politics.
Che Guevara, Georges Marchais,
Kandinsky ...
The politics of art.
I enjoy interacting
ideas with youth.
We should have a drink,
one day, together.
Yes.
What's that?
It's not like you?
It's not too much, Mama?
But why?
You won't present yourslf to the factory
in this outfit!
It's a provocation.
But I wanted to honor the workers.
And I put on all my jewelery.
Just for them... they deserve it.
Let's hope they enjoy them.
Let's go.
It's the dress you ...
Did you recognize it?
I hadn't forgotten.
The committee's
in the union meeting-room.
I've got stage fright.
I'll leave you...
...Miss Nadège will accompany you.
You're abandoning me?
The committee'd take a dim view...
I'm involved in the meeting.
Are you sure?
It's OK... go on.
Call me when you're done.
It's gonna be alright.
You won't leave me, will you?
No, madame.
Is my dress too much?
No, no.
That's fine.
Those men will be in for an eyeful.
How many are there?
Ten, I think.
Hope they're nice.
Gentlemen.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Hello Madame Pujol.
Sit down, guys.
My dear friends,
as you know,
my husband was hospitalized.
I'm standing in for him
until the end of his convalescence.
I am delighted to meet you
to get acquainted,
so we can chat ...
As you are aware,
your husband is precipitating the factory
into a catastrophic situation.
If we're on strike today,
it's not for fun.
We love our work.
We're fed up
I can here you quite well, André ...
No need
to get so angry.
Moreover,
I'm pleased to see
the progress you've made.
My father who took you on
as an apprentice
'd be proud to know you're
still here.
So what are
your concerns, my friend?
Madame Pujol
I'll be very clear.
We will not resume work
until the following claims
have been implemented.
1. Award of the Christmas bonus
to all employees
effective retroactively
January 1.
2. The fifth week
of paid leave.
3. Reorganization
of working time
and standardization of 40 hours
with extra hours
additional 25%
pursuant to Article 1 ...
As Papa said:
"There is no need
"To load the mule
for it to reach its destination. "
In any case,
I agree with you.
Things aren't good here any more.
It's time we once again had
the desire to work in fraternity and solidarity.
Concretely, what does that mean?
I swear on the heads
my children and my father
to examine your demands
with the most sincere attention
to improve
the situation in our factory.
As you know,
I am the wife
of Monsieur Pujol.
So he's my boss too.
So I can understand you.
Except that I'm
not about to strike.
Congratulations, boss.
- Mama? Mama?
So?
How did it go?
They go back to work tomorrow.
That's great!
I knew you could do it.
So you've given in on everything?
No. We negotiated.
You know, I really thought
about the situation.
I want to ask a sacrifice of you both.
I want you to be
at my side.
We are
at your side, Mama.
To work with me.
Joel, I want to propose
you help me with the management.
At the factory, with you?
I know you want to work with
your father. I'm making the proposal.
Thank you, Mama!
You gonna mess my hair!
And I'm going out tonight.
I'm sure it will make things better between
you and Jean-Charles.
And I'll do what?
I've got my Political Science classes.
The experience 'd be good for you.
It doesn't interest me.
We'll find you an
artistic position.
And Floriane in Paris? I can't leave her.
I'd forgotten about that.
On weekends, we'll
have concerts at the factory.
Music doesn't do any harm,
especially to the workers.
So... to us!
To the Pujol-Michonneau factory.
To the Pujol-Michonneau factory!
[Baccara: "Do you speak French?"]
Who's the bourgeois bimbo
with the yokel?
Hey! Isn't it
that woman at Pujol's ...right?
Pujol? Our Pujol?
What are you smiling at?
Imagine Robert's face
if he saw me here, and with you.
The poor man.
Thank you for your help
at the factory.
I couldn't have done it alone.
It was nothing.
You know what surprises me the most?
No.
Is to celebrate the end of the strike,
here with you, at the 'Bada-Boom'.
I know this isn't
my sort of place,
but I've dreamt
of coming.
He brings his clients here.
Tonight, Suzanne
I'm the one who's your client.
[Once Upon a Time: "Come take a walk in the rain."]
Thank you.
Forgiveness.
Couldn't we start again from scratch?
Alas ...
You're the woman of my life
Suzanne.
And if we had
our life together?
It's impossible.
You're forgetting about your mistress.
Who told you about that?
That was a dirty trick.
It is called 'politics'... a demanding rival.
You know, Suzanne,
the old activist in me
begins to falter.
This revolution
I've fought for...
...I sometimes wonder
if I'll ever see it.
I'm still fighting
so generations to come
'll know a better world.
But I've a right to happiness,
haven't I?.
Would you get it from me?
I've got a heavy name to wear:
Michonneau-Pujol.
But you'll change.
How will you introduce me?
Comrade Suzanne?
I can already hear the jeers.
I'll explain to them.
That you also love justice.
You'll share our beliefs.
We'll see a brighter future... together.
.
You'll lose your mayoral sash
and your seat as a deputy.
And I'm a married woman.
But you no longer love that man.
After so much time together,
links get forged,
invisible... but solid.
Of you two, it's Robert
who needs me most.
Oh, Suzanne!
I'm losing you again.
But no, no.
We can go on seeing each other....
....go out together,
dine face to face....
stay good friends.
That's reasonable.
It's our age.
Oh, Suzanne!
Maurice ...
Suzanne!
The demand for umbrellas in India
is up 14% per year.
By increasing our sales by 25%
we'd get ...
43.70% of the market.
Exactly.
Not to mention the climate forecasts
which predict an increase
in rain.
Where it falls,
there we are!
So if I count
one umbrella for every two households,
knowing that there are 110 million people
that's ...
22 million brollies.
Yes, 22 million.
It would be a big market.
The Japanese are already established.
Set all that out clearly for me
and do me a summary
for the sales manager.
And for my daughter too.
Ah? Okay.
What time does my husband arrive?
Ten past eleven.
Make sure I don't
have any appointments.
What's Laurent
going to show us?
Good morning, madame.
Hello, darling.
Good morning, my friends.
Good morning Madame Pujol.
How are you all?
Very well.
Call me Suzanne.
So?
We've finished the sketches
for the new collection
which could be called
The Rainbow Collection.
What a lovely idea!
One, two, three.
Oh! This one's very pretty.
I love these colours.
What d'you think, Nadège?
A bit garish.
But it's the fashion.
It's so original.
Look, Maman. A surprise.
The Kandinsky line.
Oh! It's daring.
That's the high end.
At the same time
revolutionary.
With acknowlegements to Monsieur Babin.
On another tack, we've begun sketching
for the waxed line
But we haven't got far yet.
Your father 'll be happy and
proud of your initiatives.
Hopefully.
They are amazing.
It surprised me, anyway.
Mama, can I talk to you?
Can it wait till this afternoon?
I want to see you
before Papa arrives.
Madame Pujol's office.
I'll be there in 5 minutes.
You're not expected 'til tomorrow.
Yes, yes. Okay, I'm coming.
I have a report that Jean-Charles did for me
that's absolutely wonderful.
Feeling better with him!
I told you so.
This report gives us ideas
on the future of the factory.
Among other things,
reduce staff and relocation to Tunisia
to increase
our profits by 35%.
Can you imagine?
I'll read it tonight.
Have you had any results?
Yes. I hope I'm not
pregnant again.
You told me ...
Are you sure it's his?
What do you take me for?
Excuse me.
You should thank Jean-Charles,
But the priority,
is to restore a harmonious social climate
within the factory.
But we must also
look ahead and modernize.
But modernise without layoffs.
When'll you stop
listening to your communist?
The deputy mayor has nothing to do
with my management of the plant.
I happened to see him
and he was opposed
to my initiatives.
Then read this report.
I'll read it... I promise.
I remember how my papa
was loved by his workers.
He led the plant
for over 40 years
and never a single day
stop working, even in 1936.
Workers
retiring,
were given slippers,
an numbered umbrella
and his autographed photo.
Alas, now we're in 1977.
I haven't forgotten.
Hello, Monsieur Pujol.
Hello, Nadège.
How are you?
Very good.
I've missed you.
Me too, Robert.
One second, please.
I have something to ask you.
About the problem of structure...
the first stand ...
Ah, you do it for me.
- Stop.
They might surprise us.
They're eating.
No. There was a meeting
in the boardroom
on new development strategies.
"Development"?
My arse...yes!
Why you haven't you told me
about this?
And my mail?
A postcard!
I didn't have my favorite little secretary
in my bag.
Enough of this now!
Aren't you happy to see me?
Not like this.
I am no longer the same.
What are you doing, Nadège?
I changed.
I am a new woman
thanks to the woman in charge.
You're having it off with her too?
She, she respects me.
Come and finish
what we started.
I'm aroused!
I've made my decision.
If we're to continue
you've  got to leave your wife for me.
Leave Suzanne?
You're mad?
I've always cheated.
It suits her.
I don't want to live
in the shade.
I won't be tropohy wife number 2.
Nadège!
Suzanne!
You're back?
Just got in.
I wanted to celebrate your return.
I wanted to give you
a surprise.
And I brought a gift from
Greece for the umbrella queen .
You thought of me?
You've changed the decor?
I added
a little color.
It's beautiful!
I knew it would please you.
You're spoiled, Madame Pujol.
He's not mean to me.
Are they
real diamonds?
Here, I thought of you too.
Really?
Turkish delight?
Turkish delight? I love it.
Thanks from my diet.
Leave us please, Nadège.
Very good.
If you can assist
a man in trouble
without becoming skeptical
as to his quality,
if you know how to be beautiful
without being boring,
if you can be strong
without being impatient
experienced
without ageing,
friendly and smiling
even to a savage
if you know how to type,
shorthand, phone,
if you can give birth
during lunchtime
then better than architect,
engineer or minister,
forever protected by the peaks
where it shines,
thou shalt be secretary,
my daughter.
She's completely crazy.
But no.
Me, I like her.
You saw her new hairstyle?
No.
Give her a compliment.
You know me ...
You could force yourself.
I can't put a finger on it,
I don't know what you've done,
but I think you're better than before.
Kiss me?
I am your husband.
You'll have spent 30 years
keeping that in mind.
Like when I was pissed off
during the cruise.
But it was good for you.
You're fit,
tanned ...
I've got energy to spare.
Holidays over
for the guys too.
What holidays?
Last 3 months at the factory.
It hasn't been a holiday.
We even caught up with the strike days.
No kidding!
You received the reports?
Absolutely.
You've looked after everything
I was concerned about.
No, Robert, I assure you.
After the bad times
things have
gone well,
and even very well.
Still, after a strike.
You sat in my chair,
you put on your innocent air,
you've generously
accepted all the changes...
You've been remarkable.
The "Madame CEO" plaque will come off the door
and Madame will return to her
domestic activities.
I'm afraid not, Robert.
Who's the boss here, for God's sake?
Me.
An brief analysis of the situation.....
I represent an employer with a smile,
fair, warm.
I even managed to persuade
your children to join the factory.
Why I should leave?
I have majority control of the
shares, you poor boob.
Do you?
I checked things out
during your cruise.
Papa left me 15%
of the shares.
My sister inherited some.
Add to that the 20%
of Laurent and Joel,
more small shareholders.
In total,
I've got 55% under my belt.
You don't even have that 45%.
Suzanne!
But I'll defend
your interests like a lioness!
You'll be able to live
for yourself!
Golf, fishing,
hunting, bridge ...
You won't miss anything!
So that's me now, the trophy wife?
Sort of.
But you'll soon get the hang of it.
Come in.
Papa? You're back?
Hello.
That sounds like you're going.
Your tricks won't work.
I haven't had the last word.
Laurent has had nothing to do
with all this.
He runs the design department of
Pujol umbrellas ...
I don't give a fuck!
I want my place back!
He's done a great job...
remarkable!
Forget it, Maman...
papa won't change.
I'll miss my train.
Don't be late on our account.
Hi to Floriane and kisses from me.
Hang in there.
"Floriane"?
The Marquiset girl.
He'll see her in Paris.
They seem
to get along wonderfully.
You're crazy.
You've forgotten what I told you?
It still gives me a pain in the gut.
They can no longer see each other.
They're brother and sister.
You don't say!
You're so respectable!
It bores me
to tell it like that ...
Don't get angry.
Go ahead, speak.
Laurent and Floriane can marry
with impunity.
But I'm telling you ...
They are not brother and sister.
Huh?
Think about it!
No! Laurent ...
Yes.
You're lying.
I'll have to go.
Put yourself in my shoes.
I was young, quite cute
completely neglected
by an unfaithful husband.
I am avenged.
I regret nothing.
And I fixed your mistake.
Who...who've you deceived me with?
There are limits....
Just calm down.
My factory, my wife, my son ...
It's the end of the lunch break.
It was good to see you again.
We still have
things to discuss.
I must get back to work.
There's a quiche
for you in the fridge.
I'm not hungry.
Come on, don't sulk.
I put the TV
in your bedroom.
In the afternoon?
You can watch "Madame Today."
Women's work,
you are for it?
It gives an impression
of equality with men.
The husband should earn
enough money
so his wife
could stay at home.
It's our job.
This is not a bad idea.
It brings money.
She may not have
a salary like yours?
It should fullfill them.
If they stay at home
After this break.
Oh, Joel!
My darling!
I'm glad to see you.
My! you're beautiful.
It seems
you work at the plant.
Mama trusts me.
More reproaches!
You're all against me?
But no.
We missed you.
I'm flattened, Joel.
Your mother's finished me off.
I know
She's become another woman.
With her it's all about
"Participation" and "Self-Management."
Jean-Charles is very concerned
about the future of the factory.
But she got things through
that Babin refused you.
Yes... that's it, it's Babin.
She's his toy.
He manipulates.
He's humping her?
Oh, Daddy!
I'd rather not know.
In my opinion, it's a not new situation
I found this.
The bitch!
So it was him.
"Him" What?
She'll pay for this.
Hello. I want to talk
Monsieur Babin.
You have an appointment?
I'm Monsieur Pujol.
Robert Pujol.
Monsieur Babin, hello.
Monsieur Pujol is back.
Back, yes.
And I need your help.
I have a report on measures
planned by my wife.
To undo anything
you did.
What have I done?
The wildcat strike,
my confinement,
all that has been conducted
masterfully.
Then you arrange
to make the report public about
who wants to reduce
staff and relocate.
I will not tell you
your job, Babin.
And I want my job.
Better you convince your board.
Especially your workers.
You are a mass manipulator
Babin.
And with
money to put on the table ...
D'you take me for a clown
who favors employers?
You're a two-faced man
my dear.
What do you imply?
What were you doing with my wife
at the Bada-Boom?
What?
Don't make out innocent.
And expect more.
You were seen with Madame Pujol
in the cafeteria of the Sofitel.
We met to talk about
working conditions at the factory.
With all those precautions
to not be recognized?
We wanted to avoid
talk.
What would
your constituents
and the Central Committee do
if they found
in the local rag
a photo of
incorruptible member
trying to break out the champagne
with Madame Pujol.
Why create a scandal that
will explode in everyone's face??
Why?
Because I am a man betrayed
and I don't care about the scandal.
Listen,
Nothing has happened
between your wife and me.
And 25 years ago?
- My God!
That's me.
Suzanne loves me, then.
It may cost you
if I reveal that your adventure
produced a brat,
my son Laurent.
Laurent?
Your son?
My son?
Alas, yes.
You sure?
Oh, I wasn't there, was I?
Life is strange.
We believe ourselves a hardened old fighter...
and find we're a young papa.
Your blackmailing has made
me the happiest of men.
Anyway, if you
don't organise this strike for me,
Your career is shattered.
Yes. Yes, Pujol.
Our main
competitors, the Chinese.
are very interested ...
Madame Pujol?
My mother's doing an interview.
It makes me happy to see you.
Me too.
What youth, what enthusiasm!
Are you alright, Mr. Babin?
That hair, that smile,
the look ...
Monsieur Deputy-Mayor?
Would you tell them
how the region is proud
to have a woman like me ...
I won't be part of
your personality
worship.
Excuse him, he's a communist.
It makes me happy
see you, you.
Me too ...
I'm all yours.
Could we see
her alone?
Let's go to my office.
I'd rather do it in my car.
In your car?
It's uncomfortable.
Follow me.
You'll look after these gentlemen?
Yes.
Be careful.
Babin's a bit weird.
Yes, I'm coming, coming.
Your husband came to see me.
Is it true, Suzanne
that your son is mine?
That my son
is not his.
Is this gossip
behind my back....
What is this nonsense...
The truth.
Tell me the truth.
One word can make me
the happiest of men.
Is Laurent my son?
I'd wish you that pleasure,
Monsieur deputy mayor...but...
If we look
at the dates ...
my photo
in your locket.
You've got my medallion?
I have been looking for months.
Your husband nicked it from you.
Tell me, ....Laurent?.
No, Maurice,
It's not you.
Really?
So...finally, he's Pujol's.
No. He's neither yours nor his.
Whose is he then?
I've every reason to believe
he's the son of Monsieur Balestra.
The notary?
He was a clerk at the time.
Hard to understand
when you see him today.
I was often in his study
discussing Papa's estate.
He was young, charming.
In his office there was this big leather sofa.
Everything suggests that Laurent
is the son of Monsieur Balestra.
Although, if I were to rely only
on appearances,
he's the image of Gunnar,
this cheerful Swede who gave
tennis lessons
for children,
a tall blond... pretty hefty.
There've been many?
No... no others in May '52.
Poor Pujol married
a bourgeois nymphomaniac.
You can't judge me
by my youthful indescretions.
You've benefited.
I'd put you
on a pedestal.
I happened to come down.
I've only had brief adventures.
That's ancient history.
I've other concerns now.
Exactly...
what's this here?
This is the report by Jean-Charles.
I really must read it.
She'll be angry.
You think I'm going to believe that?
I'm a man killed twice over,
Suzanne.
After the revelations of your husband
I thought, as in a dream
I'd become a father
and your companion. How
could I have fooled myself so much?
You never stopped
being just the same:
'Wifey', locked up
in his world of lies.
And I thought to myself...
a tryst,
in memory of our meeting!
Serves me right.
I beg you kindly
get out of my car.
The factory's over 5 kilometres
And I've got high heels.
This is where our journey ends.
Farewell, Suzanne. Goodbye.
Hey!
Thank you, sir.
You've saved my life.
How am I going to go?
Oops, my skirt!
You travel this way often?
It happens. Why?
It's pretty, isn't it?
Very pretty.
NO TO OUTSOURCING!
Madame Pujol promised
continual dialogue.
It's always the same.
We trust the bosses,
and then before long... go whistle for it!
I condemn the pernicious use
of this report
which I strongly condemn
and do not want to use.
Grandma's beautiful.
Many believed in her.
She continues the politics
of her husband.
We must return to a report
supported by the unions.
I met
the Board of Directors
to find a solution.
Hah!
Don't worry, Mama.
Everyone supports you.
So why the strike?
It's the principle.
Your father's got
shareholders against me.
I reassure you,
they'll be on our side.
Fortunately you're there.
How'd I have got by
without my son?
Thank you, Laurent.
This is normal.
Poor Floriane,
I've kept you from her.
I've learned a lot from you.
How do I look?
You're perfect, as usual.
So let's go.
Hello, my friends.
Following the incidents
caused by the publication
of this report, that I've been accused
of commissioning,
a meeting of this Board
has been called.
I hope we can discuss this in a fraternal spirit.
Monsieur Pujol, you wish to speak?
Yes, Madame Chair.
I would like
in these circumstances of crisis
to propose a vote
at the meeting:
For or against the continuation
of your plant management,
madame,
knowing that I am prepared
to take over the reins
as soon as possible.
Things are clear.
The situation calls
for some urgency.
Good. To a vote then.
Mademoiselle Nadège,
would you record the votes?
Naturally.
Starting on my left.
Do you think I should direct
the factory management?
Yes, Mama. I'll give my 10%.
On top of my my 15%
that's 25%.
Mademoiselle Genevieve Micheneau?
I'll keep my confidence in you, Suzanne
and I give you my 15%.
Thank you, my dear sister.
Monsieur Pujol?
I vote against your direction.
It's 45%.
Okay.
Gentlemen?
Despite the destabilization
you have suffered,
we recognize the value
your work in recent months.
And then,
we submit our 5%.
Madame Pujol, 45 per cent.
Monsieur Pujol 45 per cent.
Leaving only my daughter, Joelle,
whom I have wisely
advised and assisted
during these last few months.
I give my 10% ...
To Robert Pujol, my father.
Thank you, my daughter.
The bitch!
What a bitch!
Laurent, you have a moment?
I have very important things to say to you.
We have nothing to say.
I'm going.
Listen, Laurent
I'm getting older and tireder
and I'm not in great shape.
I put my energy and passion
in developing this factory.
I know that during my absence
You have been remarkable.
I want you to work here,
to one day take over my estate.
If you're trying to soften me up.
It's too late.
It is never too late.
Especially after
what you just did.
I've only reclaimed my position
to make it better for you.
Your methods disgust me.
You'll do anything,
even crush your own wife.
He's warped you!
That Babin.
Monsieur Babin has nothing
to do with this.
Much more than you think.
So you agree
to remain at the plant
to work with your father?
My father?
When you have been
a father for me?
To think that's it's thanks to me
that you're here.
I let you have
a strategic position.
That is how you thank me.
What ingratitude!
Papa would've offered me
the same position.
You're very naive
my daughter.
If you knew what he said when
I asked him to involve you.
Don't be cruel.
But allow me to regret
your lack of female solidarity.
There is no solidarity,
but of competence.
You're your father's daughter.
He's happy to use
Jean-Charles' report.
I beg you, Mama
don't get angry.
When you made me out to be a dummy
who accepted everything!
But you were happy about it.
That's what I thought.  What are you going to do?
What you don't dare to do:
Divorce.
You can't do that.
So your mother's to stay
as the servant-trophy-wife?
I'm entitled to my freedom.
But why ...
Why should I fight you
when I'm your mother?
You want the truth, Mama?
Sure.
I voted against you
because of Jean-Charles.
What d'you mean?
Papa promised to give him
my position for the 10%.
You'll give up your position?
Yes.
That way, Jean-Charles
will stop travelling and stay here with me.
I'm no longer able
to live alone.
I'm pregnant, Mama.
I'm going on maternity leave
and I'll leave my job.
It is monstrous.
You don't have to sacrifice yourself,
and your work, for your husband.
And the pill does exist.
Abortion, too, today.
Jean-Charles is against it.
But it's your body,
darling.
It's up to you.
I made my decision, Mama.
I want to keep this child.
Very good.
I can only rejoice for you.
I ask one thing:
Don't get divorced.
Papa wouldn't support it
and me neither.
Some months later
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Oh, the little rascals.
Jean-Charles assured me
that labor's good in Tunisia .
There may be workers
for almost nothing.
We think it'd be
a good idea.
Suzanne, don't forget
to call the Prefect...
....Christmas for the kids at the factory.
I'll ask Mademoiselle Nadège.
I'll be busy for
the next few days.
What do you have to do?
Haven't I told you?
I am running for election
on an anti-Babin platform.
Are you crazy?
No. Just a woman of the 80s.
Mama, we're still in 1978.
You've knocked me for living in
the past. Now I'm taking the lead!
Hello, monsieur.
I'm Suzanne Pujol.
Delighted.
I am running for election.
When I was little, my father
took us to a farm.
There was one
called Rose.
"Rose"?
I have one called Plum
and the other Falbala.
"Falbala"?
Is that fermented milk?
It's milk that's at 37 degrees
that we mix it with
rennet, and it's is drained.
Then you put them ...
That's it.
Chabichou cheese with nettles.
It is a kind of
Saint-Paulin.
If I'm elected, I'll support
it at the National Assembly.
We really need it.
To you, to us!
Chabichou, it's crazy.
In Chabrechou!
Wait. I'm your candidate.
Look, miss.
Thank you.
Hello, Laurent.
Vote for me.
Madame Pujol
I'm glad to see you.
Nadège, how are you?
Oh, it's difficult.
Everything is back as before.
Vote for me.
I will improve things.
I intend to do.
I wanted to tell you one thing.
What you're doing... it amazes me.
Thank you, Nadège.
I see that a woman can
succeed without a man.
I'm Madame Pujol.
I'm running for election.
I'm for reconciliation
and well-being.
I'm an independent.
You spoke to the priest?
Yes.
He'll vote for us.
That's good.
He's very influential.
That's true.
Do I finally
get to meet Floriane?
No. She's not here.
She doesn't come on weekends?
It's...over.
My God!
You told me nothing.
Not because of me, I hope.
In a way.
You're the the most important woman
in my life.
You're exaggerating.
I'm just your maman.
You haven't introduced me to
that nice young man
who helps us produce the leaflets.
It's Jean-François.
He just came along
and offered to help.
He adores you too.
I can understand why people vote
for us seeing this handsome boy.
You have a family resemblance.
He's Monsieur Balestra the notary's son
.
Your father will be pleased.
About what?
That you've broken up
with Floriane...
His snobbishness about his son with a pastrycook ...
Here, Jacqueline.
March 12,
Vote for Madame Pujol.
You never go out,
but there, it's worth it.
Ah, Nadège.
Hello. Going OK?
You want to get rid of Babin?
Now's the time.
Vote Babin. March 12.
Your father, okay?
Have him come March 12.
Hello. Feeling well?
Remember
March 12, vote Babin.
Very good cheese.
March 12, at the polls.
Thank you. Hello to your wife.
What's this?
Ah, that Pujol woman.
Pass out leaflets, the leaflets!
Babin ...Vote Babin!
Hello, sir.
I consider everyone.
She's had a facelift.
She had to go on a diet.
Hello.
Hello, Madame Pujol.
Good luck.
Madame Pujol, you recognize me?
No.
I worked 40 years
for your dad.
He loved me very much.
Oh yeah?
You know,
I had 11 children.
11 children!
They've all worked at the factory.
Thank you for what you did
for me and my family.
But it's nothing.
Goodbye.
March 12.
I'm counting on you.
Vote Suzanne Pujol.
Is that you, bitch, spreading
propaganda in my factory?
I'd never do
such a thing...
to go against
your interests!
If I find out that you're
the eye of Moscow
you'll be fired.
The tribunal will be delighted
to accept my secrets
about the factory's operations.
I'm not disturbing you, Suzanne?
No. I'm finishing reading
this report.
It's crazy:
They want to scrap
the Saint-Amand-les-Eaux road
Can I sleep with you?
What's got into you?
Listen, I'm still working...
...and you and I are divorcing.
It will complicate things.
You're such a pet.
Why don't you go to the 'Bada-Boom'?
It's closed on Thursdays.
Just a kiss, then go to sleep.
What are you thinking?
About us.
An old story.
No.
Remember our honeymoon?
I remember a wild beach
in the depths of Brittany.
It was a deserted cove.
The sun was setting.
The sea was cool.
She seemed so hot
in your arms.
It seemed so blue
in your eyes.
We were young, beautiful,
heedless.
We loved each other.
Why divorce
after all these years?
What's the point?
So you'll look at me
differently.
I do look at you differently.
Tell me something, Robert?
Will you vote for me?
Joëlle Hersant.
Voted.
Hubert Barbin.
Madame Pilar Sanchez.
Voted.
Madame Gilberte Pacot.
André Ferron.
Voted.
Monsieur Babin!
So how did it go?
Maurice Babin.
Voted.
Monsieur Babin
what are your predictions?
Listen, I'm confident.
Geneviève Michonneau.
Mademoiselle Dumoulin Nadège.
Robert Pujol.
Voted.
Going well?
Yes. An upset.
An upset?
Madame Joelle Pujol de Morette.
Voted.
I hope that you will win.
Thank you.
Hello, Madame Pujol.
Hello.
Suzanne Pujol.
Voted.
Your predictions?
No comment.
Final results are in, mother.
Leave me alone for a moment?
Sure.
Hello?
Good evening, Madame Pujol.
You've got the result?
Yes
Why?
You've not stuffed the ballot boxes.
Seriously,
you're not too disappointed?
Not as much as your husband.
You think so?
Your real opponent
it was not me but him.
Maybe.
We can stay friends?
Your new position 'll
make us meet often.
Of course
Mostly face-to-face.
I look forward to it.
Maman,
people are beginning to arrive.
Excuse me, I must go.
See you soon, Madame Deputy.
Very soon, Monsieur Le ...
...Monsieur Mayor.
Please.
Good evening, everybody.
Thank you for being here.
I ask you kindly
welcome our new parliamentary deputy,
Suzanne Pujol!
Good evening.
SUZANNE! SUZANNE! SUZANNE!
My friends, let me first
thank you
for electing me in the first round.
I also want to offer,
in all fraternity ...
We won! We won!
Yes, we won.
I also want to offer
in all brotherhood
all my respect to our mayor,
Maurice Babin
and all my friends too.
In this moving victory night
I can only have but an emotional thought
for my father
who would have been so proud of his daughter.
And it is in his memory
I solemnly declare that I want
me, Suzanne Pujol
born a Michonneau,
to continue Papa's work,
as a benefactor of this city.
She's divorced the boss?
No.
I do not care.
She's my boss.
She offered me the job as her
parliamentary assistant... I'm going to Paris!
My dream today
on becoming your Deputy
would be to open a huge umbrella
and keep you
close to me,
to shelter you, to pamper you.
Because you are all
children, my children.
Maman! Maman! Maman!
That's what I want to be
for you: A mother!
For 30 years,
I was content
to keep house for Monsieur Pujol.
A few months were enough
to put his factory in order.
So... so why not try with France?
After centuries
of oppression and slavery,
women must
regain power.
It's time to return
to the age of matriarchy
and blessed time of the Amazons.
And I took Mama
for a trophy wife.
If she was, she wasn't a stupid one.
Subtitles: FatPlank / RLB
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org