Subtitles by DramaFever
[April 17, 2015 8:55 a.m.] [5 min.
Before KBS New Employee Inauguration]
No time. Running late...
Lipstick, lipstick...
Hello, you're one of the new hires
at KBS this year, right?
Yes.
- Why are you running?
- I think I'm late to the welcome ceremony.
Do you know where TS-1 is?
Follow me.
Yes?
I have a live broadcast today
so I'm going to be busy.
Yes. Oh no...
Oh my. I'm going to kill myself.
I'll call you back later.
My goodness, what do I do.
I mean, what kind of a...
parking job is this?
No manners.
Uh, oh. Oh no, what do I do.
Which team are you in?
Documentary 3 Days.
I'm following new employees today.
Did you by chance film what happened here?
The car door?
Yes...
The car owner's number must
be somewhere...
[9:10 AM]
[2015 KBS New Employee Inauguration]
We'll begin the ceremony...
- As CEO of KBS...
- I swear...
I swear!
[How do you feel now?] - Even during
training, it didn't feel real.
But, after receiving this and this...
it all feels more real now.
[What's your first month salary?]
- Am I allowed to say?
Around 1,890,000 won was
deposited to my account.
I withdrew all of it in cash and
gave it to my mother.
She cried.
Actually, I was unemployed
for four years.
[Why did you apply to the
Variety Department?]
Um.
Are there reasons that can't be shared?
Oh. Not exactly...
The... the person I like
works in the Variety Department.
So...
She was my senior when I was in
college. We were in the same club.
Because I hoped to work
near her...
If she became a reporter instead, then you
would've taken the reporter's exam?
If she became an accountant, then
an accounting exam?
[Episode 1
Variety Department, Unintended]
- Welcome, Variety Department rookies. [April
20, 2015 11 a.m. - OJT meeting starts.]
I'm Kim Tae Ho PD from the
Variety Department.
- The one that produced 'Infinity Challenge'?
- MBC. KBS.
- Why? I'm Kim Tae Ho. [Kim Tae Ho,
45 years old. Variety Department CP]
I get it. I hear there's someone at
MBC with a similar name as mine?
I came before him.
I'm the original Kim Tae Ho.
- Okay.
- Oh.
I know he's pretty good too.
He has some talent too, I guess?
We have a busy schedule today.
We used to get rookies to just tour
the recording studio for a few days.
But, that's very ineffective.
Since the latest trend is creativity,
competition, and alike...
on the job training (OJT), which
used to be five days long
will be conducted in just one day by
being creative and more economical.
Yes, sir.
If you feel that this condensed
training doesn't
allow you to learn the frame or certain
details of the Variety Department...
you can purchase a good book from
the store later.
There's a book titled
'What is a Variety Department PD?'.
There are many books with similar titles,
but with sub par quality.
So don't get confused.
[What is Variety Department PD? By Kim Tae Ho] -
Others urged me to write this book, so I did.
It's not like I'm trying to sell
my books here.
I don't get that much royalty.
Seriously.
I'm just trying to do a greater good...
by recommending this book.
Oh, when I was preparing for the
written examination
I bought it thinking that Kim PD
from 'Infinity Challenge" wrote it.
I wasn't the only one.
There were many others.
I hear that many copies
were returned.
But because I wrote my name here...
I couldn't return...
Alright, where should we start?
Oh right. There.
'Happy Together'...
Yoo Jae Suk. 'Night Market'.
- Sound familiar?
- Yes.
Hey Kwang Soo...
Oh your show aired yesterday, right?
Here... is what you'll see every morning.
The ratings list.
To us, this is like a report card.
- Uh, don't please.
- Why?
You got seven. Seven?
It's a good rating.
It's not easy to get seven these days.
- With season finales and cable channels...
- Give it to me.
Okay, let's get going now.
Oh, 'Immortal Song'.
Jae Young. Jae Young!
Since it's a music show...
the producer listens to music
all day long.
Hey, you should take it easy.
You'll damage your ears at this rate.
Since this is the new hires' OJT...
unlike training, we're supposed to learn from
observing the workings of the department.
So I came with very high expectations.
The CP has been fervently teaching
us this and that...
But, occasionally,
I found myself confused.
'Should I take down notes to record
what he's saying, or not?'
Everyone, watch me carefully.
Writer Lee Mi Rim, this
week's gag concert tickets?
I don't have any.
You saw, right?
This is very important. Life in the Variety
Department can be summed up in tickets.
What do I mean by that?
From now, whenever you meet people,
all conversations
will eventually end with a request
for gag concert tickets.
It's good to say 'no' from
the beginning.
Why?
Because you won't get any.
She really doesn't give out any.
[Gag concert tickets. Won't get any.] - And
very popular 'The Return of Superman'.
You know 'Dae Han, Min Guk, Man Se, '
Song Brothers. Say hello.
Hello. We are the new employees from
the 42nd class!
Where's Bong Ki?
He pulled an all-nighter again, didn't he.
Will his body be able to survive?
Good quality work doesn't come
out of thin air.
Well, last night, PD Bong Ki...
got plastered, so he won't come in
until the afternoon.
[Noon. KBS Company Cafeteria]
This is 4000 won each.
As for me, I buy like 30 at once.
Don't go out to eat near Hongik University
or Garosu Road for no reason.
Food here is good.
Good for building relationships
with colleagues.
But, most of all, this is where you can get all
kinds of information related to broadcasts.
Right? They are getting divorced, right?
I knew they would since their wedding.
Someone did see the two of them
going to Japan together.
The two of them went to Osaka!
Mr. Choi ran away with the money?
How much did he end up stealing?
- Can I take two?
- Yes.
On really hot days, they
serve chicken ginseng stew.
Occasionally, we get special meal days
like Japanese and Chinese food.
With sushi and sweet & sour pork.
If you check menus through KOBIS
(intranet), you won't miss them.
There's no senior like me.
Telling you guys about things like this...
Hey, it's Girls' Generation.
They will be happy to see me here.
But, it'll be annoying to have a
crowd around us, so let's just eat.
- Are you close to them?
- Of course.
Oh, PD Kim Tae Ho from
'Infinity Challenge'?
[Taeyeon from Girls' Generation]
- Oh, I don't think I know who he is...
[2:30 p.m. 4 hours before Music Bank]
I have a live broadcast today,
and you want me to do OJT?
I'm busy in the afternoon with a
department chiefs meeting and all.
And live broadcasting is good for
learning on the job. This is perfect.
Gosh, I have so many things
going on today.
- I even got into an accident on my way here.
- Accident?
What kind of accident?
Were you hurt?
No, not that kind of accident.
A dent caused by a car door.
Oh... your car got dented by someone's
car door? It happened to me once too.
Older women tend to do that often.
Opening car doors without thinking.
- My car didn't get dented. I did it.
- What?
I'm saying I did it! Because I opened
the car door without thinking!
But, that was really a small dent.
How much will it cost?
- What kind of car was it?
- An import.
Was it my car?
Gosh, an imported junk car?
No, not yours, but an actual imported car.
Really?
Anyways, contact them right away.
If you're unlucky, they might frame
it as a hit-and-run.
I mean why would you drive an
imported car in such a tiny country?
And a huge car at that!
Look at Europe.
Even though their standard of living is
higher than us, they all drive city cars.
That's being sensible, don't you think?
And that's why I drive a city car too.
Even the toll rates are halved.
[2:40 PM - Coffee shop in front of KBS
where celebrity managers hang out.]
Music Bank's PD is in a bad mood
today. Jindo dog ♪3.
Newcomers to be introduced to her
should fall back for now.
The situation is grave.
Why is she all of a sudden
Jindo dog ♪3?
The producer dented another
car on her way to work.
She's upset since she'll probably
have to pay for it.
I wish that car was mine.
Then I could've said it's okay
and become her close friend.
What is Jindo dog No. 3?
Oh that. Since you're new,
you're probably clueless.
Jindo dog is the code word we use
to represent emergency situations.
If it's ♪3, then it's not too serious.
As long as I don't instigate anything
with the PD, no harm will be done.
When it's ♪2, even if you don't do
anything, you might get attacked.
What about ♪1?
You shouldn't be in Yeouido.
It's like wartime.
- Gosh.
- I see...
- Take notes.
- Oh, okay.
Owner of the car 1538, I'm sorry.
This morning in the parking lot, I
made a small mistake and dented your car.
This is the one who will be in
charge of your OJT this afternoon.
The core member, the queen bee, and
the king sister of Variety Department.
I mean the goddess.
Please give me a call.
The goddess, PD Tak Ye Jin.
You, slacker, over there.
Don't you know that personnel in broadcasting
should all have their phones on vibrate?
If your phone rings during a live show,
then that's a broadcast accident.
- I'm sorry.
- And don't say 'I'm sorry' so easily.
We are PDs.
What I mean is that you shouldn't
grovel that easily.
[Tak Ye Jin. 35 years old.
In 8th year. PD of Music Bank]
Well, yes, I tend to become more
sensitive before the live broadcasts.
And there was a small accident
in the morning.
Oh, I messaged the car owner!
But, it shows as unread.
Not reading the message.
I'm sure they will. Yeah.
It's a little weird.
This is camera 1, 2, 3, 4, and
over there is 5.
All connected like this completes
the screen.
It's important to make the calls
accurately.
The most frustrating ones are the ones who put
camera 2 on standby and call 'cut' on camera 3.
Then why bother putting camera 2
on standby, right?
And you know for some shows they
film from above.
- That camera is called a Jimmy Jib.
- Jimmy Jib.
Like camera 5 over there.
Who's that? There's a person.
Associate producers tend to sleep
in recording studios like that.
Doesn't look like sleeping.
Let's take a look...
Isn't she an associate producer for
'Entertainment Weekly'? Shin Hae Joo?
- Who's that next to her?
- It's Ra Joon Mo.
Why is Ra Joon Bal over there?
He said he's going to the Korean
Communications Commission (KCC).
There's a rumor that they're dating.
Is that true?
They must have something to talk about.
Just because a male and female talk, it
doesn't mean they're dating. How tacky.
Look at that. They're dating.
Ra Joon Mo has skills.
How many years apart are they?
How would I know that?
Can you please check the location
of the air shoot.
We can't have those flower petals
falling like last time.
[3:00 p.m. - OJT Break time in lobby]
Oh.
It's you, right?
Yes, it is.
What are you doing here?
Are you here to see Music Bank?
No, I'm a new rookie in the
variety department.
Really? Hey, that's great.
This, here, is Baek Seung Chan.
- We went to church together.
- Actually, it was school.
Oh right, school.
You lived by school in Shilim-dong.
I live in Yeouido.
I have since I was born.
Oh you live in Yeouido?
That's good. It's close to work.
- Okay, see you next time.
- Okay.
I think the wedding ceremony will
be in the fall.
Since he is a bit older than me and all.
Are you alright?
I'd like to be alone.
- Oh! What... what?
[Ra Joon Mo, 35 Years Old]
What are you filming?
Oh... Documentary 3 Days?
You have to film in the washroom too?
Why are you working so hard?
Sorry.
Hello?
I said, let's have our meeting
at 4 p.m. today.
I'm going to the KCC.
I have the thing with the KCC...
The KCC!
Yeah. Okay, okay.
Yes.
To be specific, the KCC is the
Korean Communications Commission.
It's like... how do I put this?
If ratings are a PD's report card,
then the KCC is like the student profile.
If you get one of these things,
it means you did something wrong.
Wait, wait a minute now.
This is going to be aired, right?
I can't say the wrong thing now.
I'll do this part again, okay?
It is a very important institution.
TV is broadcasted to the general public.
Their role is to check for any violations
of the regulations.
As well as guide us to a wholesome
broadcast culture.
However, it is unpleasant to hear
from them.
Whether you're a child or an adult,
no one likes to be lectured.
No, this isn't quite right either...
The one that variety show PD's get
called on the most?
Damage to one's dignity.
But honestly,
we really don't have much dignity.
Either that or smoking.
This one is so hard to notice.
When people smoke behind a tree,
it really is so hard to see them.
Also, failing to wear a seat belt or
filming on top of a railway.
Or failing to wear a motorcycle helmet.
The thing is, all of that is okay
in movies.
You can be really cool. You know...
But, do that on TV and
you'll get a summons right away.
[Why were you summoned today?]
Oh today?
You uttered a vulgar word during
a broadcast. What was it?
It was 'booger'.
The word 'booger' appeared in a
total of 15 episodes.
It was even mentioned in reference
to eating it.
Ah, the thing is...
When eating was mentioned,
it was not about physically ingesting it.
It's an action representative of people
who are lacking and
taking into account that everyone
in this nation can agree...
Was it not possible to replace it with
a more dignified term?
It just wouldn't have been the same
with a word like 'secretion'...
There's something that feels orthodox
about the word 'booger'.
Anyway...
But, I do apologize.
I will rectify that.
To make it worse, it was during meal time,
your show 2 Days, 1 Night!
Do you think viewers would like
that while they're eating?
I don't think they'd like it very much.
I apologize.
It's good that you apologize
quickly, PD Ra Joon Mo.
But, you're always back in here again,
so as for your sincerity...
Gosh, all this over a booger.
Oh! Reporter Kang.
Oh? You're here again!
A PD should be at the station.
Why are you always here?
That's what I'm saying.
Stop writing negative pieces about
my show.
Well, once your show's gone,
I won't be able to write them.
What are you talking about?
I heard your show is getting canceled.
- Huh?
- It's not true?
If that were true, I'm the PD.
Wouldn't I know about it?
It's just common sense.
When a program is getting axed,
the producer seems to be the last to know.
What, seriously...
Where are you hearing these weird things?
Why wouldn't I know my own show? Huh?
I'm... I'm the PD! I am!
2 Days, 1 Night... Season 1.
When Young Suk and Myung Hwan were here,
things were really good back then.
Kang Ho Dong and Lee Seung Gi...
But, in Season 2 things were
a little shaky.
And then Season 3, Yoo Ho Jin
actually did pretty well.
After that, it was passed onto me.
It's all the same really.
A bunch of guys come out and
do this and that.
So, we completely changed everything.
A 2 Days 1 Night with female actresses.
It's innovative!
2 Days... 1 Night...
Can you try being more in unison
and say 2 Days and 1 Night loudly together?
2 Days... 1 Night!
Yes.
For our Spring Special,
we'll be going to Geojedo.
Where? Geojedo?
I can't go.
Let's just stay in Kyungki.
Why do you want to go so far?
I have a gastric ulcer.
Don't feed me stuff like fish extract.
If the toilet is an outhouse like
last time, I'm not going.
And sleeping outside? Do you want to
see me get joint pain and die? I can't.
Yeah.
We should go to some campgrounds
nearby and just shoot.
Just because you go far away,
you don't get ratings.
How can we go to Geojedo?
It's so cold right now.
Other programs seem to have
no problem making it fun without going.
But, the thing is...
It must've been too innovative.
The ratings are, well...
honestly they've hit rock bottom.
That's why there are false rumors
like this going around.
But, times of crisis are also
an opportunity.
I'm not that worried.
[5:00 PM -
2 Days 1 Night Meeting Room]
Can you please sit down?
You're giving me a headache.
Where's Writer Choi?
I just spoke to her.
She's crossing the Mapo bridge.
She'll be here soon.
Things sure are going well, huh?
There are all sorts of rumors flying
around and the main writer is missing.
What rumors?
What's the item for next week?
Do you have it?
Why don't we go to Jejudo?
Last season, where did we go
for our last episode?
Jejudo.
What about Mamma Mia?
That program that got canceled?
- Jejudo.
- That's right!
When a show is truly desperate,
they go to Jejudo.
When you start to think,
we need to go to Jejudo...
your show has come to
the end of its run.
But, last week Infinity Challenge went to
Jejudo and they had great ratings.
Are you stupid?
That show's run by Producer Kim Tae Ho.
Producer? What happened to Miss A
possibly appearing on our show this week?
There was that schedule conflict with
Music Bank you're trying to work out.
- It's not going to work, is it?
- It will!
If I call, it will work out.
Miss A.
If you run a big show like Music Bank,
you tend to get a lot of requests.
Requests from your work seniors,
the Department Chief...
No matter what, you've just got to
reject them all and move on.
If you do everything they ask,
the requests will never end.
Even if the President comes and asks,
you need to know how to say 'No'.
I'll be here longer than the President
anyways, right?
Of course, I'm sure you all will be here
longer than I will.
- What?
- I need to ask a favor.
A favor?
Oh, hold on.
[Joon Bal]
So, what favor do you need from me
Ra Joon Mo PD?
I need Miss A on my show next week,
but because of Music Bank...
- Can you do a prerecording for them?
- No.
I have many singers going on that day.
Gosh, PD of Music Bank...
just do me this favor.
If I take out Miss A, I have to adjust
the entire line-up.
Please don't latch onto me to solve your
issues and take care of it on your own.
So, keep this in mind.
In this industry, you have to have
your own back.
If you're out there helping others,
in the end you'll be left with nothing.
Take care of yourself.
Okay?
Okay, should we slowly head up now?
Oh my...
Wait... just wait.
Let's go in a little bit.
Latch onto her?
Who is she saying I'm latching onto?
She has no clue what's going on.
Is it going to happen or not?
I need to know if I have to
find materials or not.
Just hold on a second!
She shouldn't be this way to me!
Gosh, seriously!
Hey, PD Ra... the Department Chief is
looking for you.
What is it?
You must know something.
What would I know?
I met Reporter Kang at the KCC.
He was saying some strange things.
How did that go, by the way?
Even that, other CP's go to the KCC
on behalf of the PD's and support them.
Did I really have to go there?
You look good in a suit.
And I only have suits for funerals.
- So, you really don't know anything?
- What would I know?
How many times have you been to
the KCC this month now?
What is it this time? A warning?
Still, because I go so often,
there are people who are friendly to me.
There are people who say,
it is very regrettable.
I don't think they will slap us with
a warning this time.
You must be proud.
It really is strange.
How could all the age groups not be
watching your show?
Chief, if you look here... right here...
there are portions with sudden rises.
People have caught wind of it.
I don't know about wind or whatever,
but it's definitely game over, Joon Mo.
Tae Ho.
Honestly, is 5.7 acceptable for a
Sunday variety show?
Back in the day, when I did Super Sunday
with Lim Baek Chun...
the ratings went up to 35.
Our theme song back then was,
the Pet Shop Boy's, Go West.
- It was such a good song.
- It really was.
Chief, these days there are so many
mediums. Today's 5.7 is like a 15.
That's just the excuse people with 5.7
ratings make.
There's just no answer.
Let's just pull the plug.
What?
- Chief!
- It's already been decided.
- Tae Ho, did you know?
- You didn't know?
The entire variety department knew.
The lady who sells spicy rice cakes in
front of the station knew. Why didn't you?
Tae Ho!
Chief...
You, yourself, okayed the idea to have
the older ladies on the variety show.
Yeah I did, so you
should've done a good job.
One year ago, what did you say when
you started this program?
You said if Na Young Seok hit a triple,
then you'd hit a home run.
This isn't a home run.
It's a double play.
Oh... I really didn't know about this.
The game was over,
but here I was by myself...
Like a fool, bunting and stealing bases
all day and night.
Pull the plug?
What do you mean, pull the plug?
I can't do that!
- Didn't you tell him in advance?
- Of course I did.
He just doesn't seem to get it.
He only has old ladies as guests.
He spends all that money and has on
ratings this low. He has no conscience.
Don't you think so?
What if he goes to the union or
something?
What could he possibly say to them?
This isn't a political program with
controversial topics.
We're pulling the plug because it's
unpopular.
Now that I think about it,
Na Young Seok was really good.
Isn't there any way we could bring
him back?
We're going to go to Jejudo.
- We can't do Jejudo.
- How about leodo?
Well, I feel like...
a head of family with elementary,
junior high, and high school student kids
that has suddenly become unemployed.
How am I supposed to take care of them?
How am I supposed to feed them?
I'm blood type A.
That means I'm already very responsible.
This is becoming more important.
What about me?
What happens to me?
You would've talked about what
happens to the PD. Am I gone too?
You have to tell me that
so I can make plans.
You're not going anywhere.
I'm just saying, pick out some new
members and go at it again.
Starting when?
What do you mean when?
Immediately.
Huh?
Look here. Next week, there will be
soccer programming.
The following week, they can play
the highlights. You have two weeks.
I can't do it in two weeks.
Then, should I look at another team
that's been preparing a variety program?
Considering external teams,
we have several.
I'll get it done.
Okay. The most urgent thing now is
letting the team members know.
Chief.
Tomorrow, we're having a one year
anniversary dinner with everyone there.
How can I say that at a
place like that?
Oh yeah?
Well, things got simple then.
- What?
- You can tell them and do a goodbye party.
Then, you can save the cost of a
goodbye party.
When things start to work out,
they really do.
Where are you all meeting?
At Bi Bong, in front of the station.
If it's the dinner course,
it's quite expensive per person.
But, it's not bad for the price.
The Mae Course comes with pine nut
porridge. It's delicious.
Yes, it is. But, will
everyone have the Mae Course?
It wouldn't just be one or two people.
Should we order the Ran Course?
That one is about 30,000 per person.
There's no porridge in the Ran Course.
- You can add it on the side.
- Even the pine nut porridge?
Yes, even the pine nuts.
Then, we'll do the Ran course meal
with pine nut porridge.
So, wait...
We're not filming the last episode?
All you think about is spending money.
Don't you think about the company?
Okay.
Then during the dinner tomorrow
you're going to announce it to
everyone right, Chief?
I told you. You have to announce it
before the dinner.
Do you want to have pine nut porridge
bowls being thrown around?
When a new program starts,
it's like a baby's first birthday.
Everyone comes out to give you blessings.
And you just smile for no reason.
When a program is coming to an end,
it's like a funeral.
Especially when it's a lowly rated program,
nobody shows up.
There are no visitors and no money.
It's very lonely.
I think this line was pretty good.
Don't edit it out.
It was a really good figure of speech.
What was the important thing you
had to talk to me about?
Oh, it's nothing really.
It's not that important.
Is Cindy on Music Bank today?
Yes, she's up for the number one spot.
My second daughter is a fan of hers.
And she just happens to be in Yeouido.
She's riding her bike with her friends.
Oh.
[5:30 PM - One hour before going live]
[Music Bank Dressing Room]
[Cindy, 23 Years Old]
[Debuted 10 Years Ago]
Is the light working okay?
Isn't is kind of dark in here?
It's fine, but what are you doing
all the way here?
Oh, I was just wondering if Cindy
was comfortable with everything.
How's the chair?
It looks uncomfortable.
This chair's been here since I first
started working here in 1997.
It's time for a change, huh?
Oh no, it's really fine.
Um, it's really time for her to go
on live soon.
Oh yes, that's right!
Then, do a good job.
But, how are you for time?
I'm wondering if you could go and
say hello to the Chief.
That's nice of you to suggest,
but the time... and it's a live show...
Oh, is that so?
But, it'll just take five minutes.
Maybe it's too much.
She is in full make up and
her shoes are uncomfortable.
That's true. It would be too much to
go all the way there, right?
- I'm sorry.
- No, no. There's nothing you can do.
Then how's this?
It's too much to go,
so how about some pictures?
Huh?
Come in, over here.
This here is the Department Chief's
daughter, Jang Yae Rim.
Here, say hello and come
stand next to Cindy.
Hi, I'm a big fan. Take a picture.
One, two, three... just one more.
One, two, three... two, three.
One more.
What is this? She's so rude.
Hey, hey. Look at her expression.
Wow, amazing.
Would it kill her to take a picture?
Would her face wear down?
She's rude just like people said.
- What kind of attitude is this to fans?
- Really, how annoying.
Whose dressing room do you want
to visit next?
- EXO?
- Yes please! Yes!
This is why I said I didn't want
to do rehearsals.
Because I'm sitting in here,
all sorts of weird things happen.
Ask them to let me off for the
next dress rehearsal.
But, the main PD is extremely difficult.
And in your eyes...
am I not difficult?
Oh no, I do think you're
extremely difficult.
Have I wronged you in some way?
What?
That's not what I meant.
Well now, just be honest and
speak your mind.
What was I so extremely
difficult about?
- That's not what I meant.
- What do you mean, it's not...
I'm sorry.
What is it you're sorry for?
I'm asking because I'm truly curious.
What are you sorry about?
Cindy?
I think you're going to
have to change.
See-through isn't allowed.
Mr. Car-owner,
you must be very busy.
I didn't receive an answer,
so I'm texting you again.
Once you see this,
please contact me.
Have a lovely day.
Why isn't he reading it?
I'm sure this is the right number.
- Turn it off.
- I'm sorry.
Kids these days.
Hey, just because I use my phone,
do you think you can too?
The customer has turned off the phone.
You will be connected to voicemail.
Wow, he just completely
turned off his phone now.
This guy is no joke.
Ye Jin, about the outfit you
asked Cindy to change into...
Yeah, see-through is not allowed.
Why?
- She says she won't change into it.
- What?
Why?
She says it's the
concept for her new album.
Tell her manager to come in. No in fact,
tell her manager's boss to come in.
Okay.
Why can't she change her outfit?
It's our first comeback week and
it's the concept for her new album.
- If you can just...
- I told you it's too racy for KBS.
Why do I have to keep
repeating myself?
I understand, I'll see if I can
persuade her. Give me a moment.
You can get things done
more efficiently
by communicating with the manager instead
of talking to the celebrity directly.
They're probably shocked since the
producer is personally getting involved.
Producer, you'll just have to
let Cindy wear it. I'm sorry.
- Look...
- Hello?
Hello, Producer!
This won't do. I'm going
to have to talk her personally.
Producer Ye Jin!
Are you going to fight with her?
Fight? With who?
Me and Cindy?
How can I fight with her?
It's more like a scolding.
Holy cow!
- Manager.
- Yeah?
Can you step outside for a moment?
The sound of your
breathing is a bit loud.
Oh, sorry for breathing so loud.
Producer Ye Jin.
Ms. Cindy, I'm Tak Ye Jin.
The producer of Music Bank.
I clearly told you earlier that I
wanted you to change your outfit.
I guess that's too
difficult for you to do.
You must not have gotten the message.
I said I won't change my outfit.
The problem is not the message.
The problem is you're not allowed.
Racy outfits are not allowed
according to KBS policy.
This outfit is pretty, not racy.
Excuse me, the guy with the
tear drop patterned necktie.
Don't you agree?
- Don't you think this is pretty?
- Yes, it's pretty.
See?
He says it's pretty, Producer.
Men like it.
Women like you... who are slightly
old may not see it that way.
Even older women watch
Music Bank with their sons.
They watch Music Bank
with their sons?
Have you ever watched Music Bank
with your mother at home?
I don't recall...
but I think I have, though.
I think it's the respectful
thing to do when the head producer
personally asks you
to change your outfit.
Is it necessary for you to give
everyone a hard time like this?
Okay.
- Good. You understand now?
- Yes. I won't do this program.
What?
It seems I'm a nuisance to
this program.
I'll just leave.
Manager, let's go.
- That's not what I meant!
- Then what did you mean?
Seriously, this won't do.
Everyone, get out.
- Producer Ye Jin...
- Get out!
Sure.
Cindy... you really don't know
what the main problem is right now?
What is it?
It's KBS. The fact that it's a
live broadcast is the problem.
I think this outfit is so pretty,
but the station won't allow it!
I am truly upset!
So... how do you know that
when I haven't been on stage?
It's without a doubt 100 percent!
I guarantee it!
If you perform on stage
with this outfit right now...
- I'll have to answer to the board.
- So what the heck am I supposed to do?
I'm not asking you to do anything
out of the ordinary, so basically...
That outfit you have on is nice, but how
about you wear a jacket with it? Huh?
Showing a little skin instead of showing
everything is considered sexy. Huh?
Producer.
- That is see-through.
- You're right!
That is see-through, but let's
cover it up just a tad bit more.
Don't you think it'll
be so much sexier? Huh?
Is there even a jacket for me to wear?
Oh my gosh, are you going to wear it?
You're going to wear a jacket for me?
Seriously, I'm so honored.
Now I know why you're
all the rage these days.
You're such an understanding person.
Thank you.
Bring her a jacket. She said
she'll record with extra top on.
Did you scold her a lot?
Don't go around spreading rumors
that Cindy got scolded by me.
She's not at a level to be
scolded by producers anymore.
Hey, slacker boy.
- Me?
- Yes, you.
What's your name?
It's Baek Seung Chan.
Okay, Baek Seung Chan.
You must feel very sad right now.
Did Cindy look that pretty
in her see-through outfit?
Are you one of her groupies?
Are you stupid?
- I'm sorry.
- I told you not to say 'I'm sorry!'
I'm in a battlefield right now
trying to win a war!
And you're in a dugout eating cookies!
What a nice way to go.
If you have a mouth,
then go ahead and say something!
If I try to apologize
whenever you reprimand me...
I'm sorry.
I told you not to say 'I'm sorry.'
You tell me not to say 'I'm sorry.'
If I stay still,
you ask me why I'm so quiet.
If you have a mouth,
then go ahead and say something!
And you ask me if I have a mouth.
So I apologize once again.
However, I can't say I'm sorry.
The only thing left is to
shake hands.
[6:20 p.m. just minutes before
Music Bank is about to go live.]
The '2 Days, 1 Night' team said they
were going to give us the final copy.
Why haven't we heard from them?
They're under fire right now.
I saw Joon Mo go to the Chief's office
earlier, and I think he got an earful.
And I heard he went to see
the board in the afternoon.
Okay, bring it over
whenever it's finalized.
Attention, rookies.
As you probably know...
there are many instances where other
programs ask Music Bank for casting favors.
We're pretty much the powerhouse
over the whole variety sector.
At times like this, helping each other
out is a win-win situation.
Granted, you don't agree right away,
but only when the timing is right.
Okay? Watch.
[Joon Bal]
What?
It's about the favor you asked earlier.
About 'Miss A' for next week.
I'll pre-record it for you.
Forget it. I don't need it.
Hello? I didn't hear you.
The reception here isn't very good,
so the calls get dropped frequently.
[7 p.m. Music Bank Live Broadcast.]
She wore the jacket!
Let's use camera four for the first cut.
Zoom out on Cindy's face.
Music standby. Okay... cue.
One, cut!
Two, cut!
Wow!
It wasn't... it wasn't me...
Four cut.
One cut.
Two cut.
Five standby. Cut.
One cut.
Three cut.
Four cut.
- Good job, everyone.
- Good job today.
Tell Cindy's manager I
want to see him immediately.
There's another event, so they
left as soon as Cindy was done.
- Already?
- Yes.
Wow, they ran away because
they're so scared of me.
Right? That's what it is, right?
Oh my gosh.
- Tell her CEO to stop by tomorrow.
- CEO Byun?
He's not the type to come
because you tell him to...
Of course he should come.
Why wouldn't he?
You.
You must've been ecstatic to see
Cindy with her pretty clothes on.
Your reaction was pretty strong back there.
Are you part of the audience?
Sure! Hey... why don't you
be a part of the audience?
You said Cindy's outfit
was pretty earlier.
Go and and tell her exactly
what I said.
That it was very pretty and
it wasn't even remotely racy!
It's your first day on the job.
How was it today?
How do you think it was today?
Joon Mo, where are you?
I have a gathering today
with my team members.
No, I'm going to be late today.
No, I'm going to be more late
than that.
Yeah, I think I'm going to be tired.
Okay, bye.
- Producer, hello.
- Hey.
- Yes?
Are you still working for CEO Byun?
- Yes.
- Who are you managing now?
- Cindy.
- Really?
Yes.
Is that dinner?
I already ate earlier.
This is for Cindy.
We have to get to Suwon by
ten and we're short on time.
Put that down.
What's taking him so long?
Where is he going?
Ma'am, I'd like a maechu kimbap, beef
kimbap, and a fish cake soup to go.
- Okay.
- Producer...
You... go and relay
this message to CEO Byun.
Tell her to at least feed her kids
if she's going to work them to death.
She should at least feed her if
she's going to work her like a slave!
Tell her to dance and sing all day!
I swear, that life-sucking leech!
That Byun-pire!
Are you kidding me?
Don't you know that I
don't eat carbohydrates?
Plus...
are you telling me to
eat this salty soup?
Do you want me to dance
with a swollen face?
What was I supposed to do? The producer
insisted that I feed this to you.
Who is he again?
He's the producer for
'2 Days 1 Night.'
Is he my fan?
I don't think so.
I think he's mortal enemies
with CEO Byun.
Why?
That I don't know.
Our CEO naturally has a lot
of enemies.
You call yourself writers?
You call yourself a producer?
Release the suspension.
I'm going to sleep here if you don't
release the suspension for my kids.
But... if he's mortal
enemies with CEO Byun...
why would he give me this?
I don't know.
Is he a psycho?
[9 p.m. closing time. KBS parking lot.]
Come on, why aren't you
picking up your phone?
- Hello?
- Ah, you answered your phone!
Sir, I'm not sure if you
got my text message or not.
There was a slight accident to your car
while I was going to work this morning.
Where are you right now?
Ah yes, I'm almost at the parking lot.
I see.
By any chance,
are you a KBS employee?
Yes, I am.
My word! Then we're
part of the same family!
Which department do you work for?
- I work in variety show department.
- The variety show department?
The variety...
No way...
You have a nice car.
It's my father's car.
Is that so?
Why didn't you respond
to my text message?
You told me not to
look at my cell phone.
You're right, I did.
Good job.
Ah, there's one more
message I didn't check.
Don't do it!
Come here and take a look at this.
I just scratched it slightly.
Okay.
It's not exactly a slight scratch...
Don't thing about going easy on
me because I'm you're superior.
I'm not that type of person, okay?
Yes, ma'am.
Okay then, I understand.
You understand?
Yes, I can't make a decision on my
own since this is my father's car.
I'll give you a call after I
discuss it with my father first.
Of course you should.
You're right.
Yes, well then... good night, ma'am.
You go. I'll go whenever I'm ready.
I insist you go first, Senior.
Look at this right here!
How am I supposed to get in? Huh?
How can I not scratch your car?
Seriously!
- Then should I take my car out first?
- Forget it! I'm already inside!
Look at this! Look how you parked
your car so closely next to mine!
What about Writer Choi?
I called and he's crossing
the Mapo bridge right now.
Does he live in that area?
He's always crossing...
Or at least change the name
of the bridge or something.
Eat. Go ahead and eat.
But, why are you buying us hanwoo?
How strange.
Is our program getting canned?
No.
- What happened to 'Miss A?'
- Forget it. We don't have to do it.
What the heck?
I found the location and everything.
Please don't make me work twice.
I'm so freaking tired.
- It's true. We're getting canned.
- That's not true!
The program is not getting dropped,
but the members need to be replaced.
It's better this way! The ratings
are low and we can't find an answer.
We need to gather highlights
for the show next week
so let's meet up later.
- Do it on your own.
- What do you mean? It's our business.
Exactly, it's our business and our show.
What about us?
Are we sure we're not getting fired?
That's the important part.
You think this is our
first time having a meeting
without knowing that
we're getting fired?
- Who says you guys are getting fired?
- How are we supposed to believe that?
You didn't tell us until the very end
when 'Sponge' got canned last time.
That's why I took all the
'Sponge' writers with me!
There were 12 'Sponge'
writers back then!
The problem was, there was
no need for all those writers!
That's the type of person I am.
The level is different even if
another program got canned like us.
The producers get the same pay
whether there is a program or not.
This is where you see the difference.
I'm sorry, but what's going
to happen with our manuscript?
What's the percentage when
the highlight episode goes out?
Wait a minute.
Then do we have to find the
materials for the highlight next week?
Is that the problem right now?
It is a problem.
That means more work for us.
Someone might think that
you're doing all the work here.
Producer, I'm sorry but I have
a lecture for grad school today.
If you're done talking...
I'm going to head out firsts.
You saw that?
He always does that and leaves first.
I do all the work.
Oh my gosh... what are we going to do
about the fashion section next week?
We have to cancel it.
I worked really hard in
convincing them to participate!
Seriously, what am I going to say?
Just...
Stop crying!
Hello, sir.
This is the '2 Days, 1 Night' team.
- I wonder if he's in the editing room?
- Can you talk right now?
- Hey, are you in the editing room now?
- I'd like another bottle of soju please!
Ma'am, we asked for
another bottle of soju here!
Okay, then I'll be there in 30 minutes.
['Music Bank' staff is shocked
by Cindy's racy outfit.]
[Kim Tae Ho]
- Hey, don't cry!
- Don't cry!
Producer, you said you were looking
for a writer. Did you find one yet?
[What is it to be an
entertainment producer?]
[An Entertainment
Producer's Understanding.]
[The beginning is not the half of it.]
[The beginning is just the beginning.]
Don't get on my nerves today.
Likewise.
Let's pray.
What for?
Let's just blow out the candle.
What are you talking about?
Our Seung Chan got hired to work at
KBS. The best sight-seeing station...
It's a public broadcasting
station, father.
In our country.
This is a big deal.
We need to pray all together
and give thanks to the lord.
You're right, father.
Congratulation, Seung Chan.
But what made you think of
becoming a producer all of a sudden?
No kidding. I'm not sure
why I wanted to become one.
Seung Chan, you're a 'Music Bank'
producer now, right?
All my friends are so excited!
Will we be able to see the
GOT7 members up close now?
Goodness, let's hurry up and pray!
The candle is melting!
Sure.
Heavenly father...
our Seung Chan got hired to work at
KBS. The best sight-seeing station...
It's a public broadcasting
station, father.
In any case, he got
hired to work at KBS.
It's a huge honor, Lord!
We pray that he does
your work inside KBS.
Also... our eldest son,
Young Chan...
He is studying hard for the
upcoming civil servant exam in 2017.
Granted, this will be his twelfth year.
Please give him the strength
and will to do well this time!
Father!
His wife couldn't make it because
of the constant fights they have...
She couldn't come because
she's not feeling well, father.
She's got a variety of
excuses, doesn't she?
You don't know what it's like.
She got a huge sore.
- It's true, mom.
- Please watch over her health.
- And our eldest daughter...
- Just skip over me, please.
As she requested,
we'll skip over her.
Our son-in-law is the
best urologist in Korea.
For the sake of all men's health in
this country, the gift you blessed him...
- Dad!
- Amen.
- We pray all of this in the name of...
- Why do you always forget about me?
Why did you give birth to me
if you're going to do this?
- Our savior, Jesus Christ.
- Amen.
Blow out the candle!
All right!
Anyway, I am very happy today.
Our son-in-law is a doctor.
Our eldest son is a...
will become a judge as soon
as he passes his civil servant exam.
And now our Seung Chan.
Our family has so many people
with such prestigious jobs.
Why does it count as prestigious?
Producer.
Am I wrong?
Producer!
Subtitles by DramaFever
I'm the one who picked her!
How can I personally tell her to quit?
Who is going to understand you if
you do it that way? Are you a dolphin?
Are you trying to communicate
with an ultrasound?
Then who the heck is
supposed to tell her?
- Tell me what?
- Hello!
Fine, I won't look! I won't look!
Me? In what way am I scary?
Don't worry! I told you I'm
going to work much harder.
I heard you made a mess today. Do you
know you can get fired even as a rookie?
Excuse me?
You have two strikes left. Be careful.
Use this.
This umbrella doesn't belong to me.
I just borrowed it from the lobby desk.
Pardon?
They're going to take it out of my
paycheck if I don't return the umbrella.
- Please return it under my name.
- Sure.
I'm Producer Baek Seung Chan
of '2 Days, 1 Night.'