1x20 - Doppleganger
♪ Beware ♪
♪ Beware the bat ♪
Katana: Previously on
Beware the Batman...
Hi, Major.
It's time for you to come back.
[Grunting]
Batman needs you.
Bruce needs you.
I need you.
It appears you've missed me.
Sync and corrections by masaca
- www.addic7ed.com -
[Grunting]
I'm so sorry, my dear.
That's no way to treat a lady.
This is!
[Phone ringing]
Barbara: Are you okay?
I'm a little busy, Barbara.
[Gunshots]
But no.
Um, that's quite a butter knife.
What do you think
the Bat-prentice has in mind?
I think she's going to knight us.
Oh, then we shall bow.
[Gunshots]
[Gas hissing]
Oh, dear, she's not as good as the Bat.
I concur.
But it's nice to have
a woman around the house.
[Laughing]
[Coughing]
Barbara: What happened?
They got away.
- Barbara: Should I call Batman?
- No, he's been a little... preoccupied.
[Grunting]
[Growling]
[Screeching]
[Gasps]
Perhaps it's time to take a break.
Get out of the cave. Get
some sunlight, see friends.
I only have one real friend.
And even you chose to walk away from me.
You are not the reason I left.
Are we gonna talk about that?
You disappeared for almost eight months.
But I came back when you
needed me, as promised.
I will tell you where I was,
what I was doing, in time.
But right now we should
be more concerned with you.
And Batman.
I'm afraid, Alfred.
Afraid of what might happen
if I put the suit back on.
Then don't. Let Katana
look after Gotham.
And let Bruce Wayne enjoy his life.
I'm sure there's someone who'd like
to pal around with a billionaire.
Harvey: The people want a strong leader.
Mayor Grange let this city get soft.
Time for a new Mayor to toughen Gotham up.
Batman!
What?
The key to me winning
this election is Batman.
Once I'm Mayor, I don't care
what vigilante menace
wants to run around Gotham
in a Halloween costume.
But this is an election year.
So, what exactly do you want from me?
Grange has been on leave for a month.
The writing's there. I mean,
with the right push he's done.
It's the perfect time
to go negative with my
campaign ads, but it's expensive.
What I need is money.
Can I count on Bruce Wayne's deep pockets?
- I don't know, Harvey.
- You don't know!
Why do you think I brought
the great Dane Lisslow,
head of my Special Crimes Unit?
It's not great, just Dane.
Because if you don't write
a check, he'll arrest you.
I'm kidding.
[Laughs]
You've studied Goju Ryu.
- How can you tell?
- The scars on your hands.
You spend a lot of time training.
I've broken a lot of fingers.
Few of them my own.
[Giggles]
I don't know how many
times I sprained a finger
trying to get the governor on the phone.
Have you ever studied Savate?
Only for all of college.
[Grunting]
Ow!
Why are we doing this again?
If you're going to help, even if
it's mostly with your computer,
you should know how to defend yourself.
I know how to defend myself.
[Grunts]
After the Blackgate incident and all
the trouble with the Iron Cortex,
Batman wants me to train you.
Consider it payback.
Cool, now can you let go of my neck?
Oh, I was thinking about
giving myself a code name.
Something mysterious like...
Oracle.
I broke this in Israel
in a Krav Maga tournament.
Good one.
Jeet kune do.
Broke my clavicle in three places.
Got my medal, then passed out.
What is that smell?
It's Parijat bark.
What do you think?
Ah, it's terrible.
That's how you know it's good.
[Giggles]
If you guys are done drinking your mulch,
can we get back to me?
Okay, Harvey, send me your
proposal, and I'll give it some...
Ah, excuse me, I need to leave.
- Is something wrong?
- No, I...
I got some bad bark.
Dinner's on me.
Um, what's your most expensive desert?
[Woman gasps]
[Screeching]
[Grunts]
[Growling]
I know what I saw.
It was a bat.
A human size Man Bat.
Something clearly attacked him, Alfred.
You saw his clothes.
Maybe what you thought you saw
was just a mild hallucination.
I had the same thought until I checked out
all the Gotham crime
reports from previous nights.
There have been several break-ins
at chemical supply companies in
the last month, including one very
close to where I encountered...
what I saw.
Pyg and Toad were breaking
into a chemical factory.
It can't be a coincidence.
Bruce...
Batman needs to get
back out there, Alfred.
Considering your current condition,
- are you sure that's wise?
- No.
But when has Batman
ever listened to reason?
According to the reports, the only
thing stolen after each break-in
had a direct relationship
to DNA sequencing.
Specifically animal DNA.
Katana: Makes sense.
It fits with Pyg and
Toad's pro-animal pathology.
Batman: Tapper chemicals is a leading
distributer of sequenced animal DNA.
There's a 68 percent chance
this is the next target.
[Groans]
Not this time.
Wow, he wasn't kidding.
It is a Man Bat.
[Groans]
[Screams]
- Katana: Are you okay?
- Batman: I'm fine.
Get him, it, into the Batmobile.
Is that what I think it is?
Professor Pyg: Batman,
with a Bat Man.
How pathetically redundant.
Sorry, Batman,
but we'd like our pet back.
Mister Toad, would you be
so kind as to call him?
Mister Toad: Come here, boy.
Who's the good Man Bat?
Okay, freaks, everyone on the ground.
In these clothes, I think not.
Mister Toad, an exit.
[Engine revving]
[Gunshots]
On closer inspection,
these capsules appear to serve
as a hypodermic for the chemical inside.
[Groaning]
Where am I?
He can talk.
Of course I can talk.
Now that you got those things off my neck.
Why were you working with Pyg and Toad?
- What are they planning?
- Working with?
No, you've got it all wrong.
I wasn't working with them.
I was their first victim.
Man Bat: My name is
Dr. Kirk Langstrom.
I was a research scientist trying
to break down the DNA of bats.
I was hoping to develop
a life-saving
serum from their immune system,
which is very resistant to disease.
But others had a
different plan for my work.
Pyg and Toad stole
my research and perverted it,
forcing me to test the serum on myself.
[Growling]
[Glass shattering]
Turning me into what you see before you.
Not an animal, and no longer a man either.
Professor Pyg implanted
those capsules into my neck,
which allowed them to take
control of my mind and body.
Alfred: I'm not surprised.
According to the Batcomputer,
the substance in these
capsules is Scopolamine.
The devil's breath.
A toxin made from Nightshade that
creates a loss of mental control.
The victim becomes mentally bonded
to the first voice it hears.
Sounds like a zombie.
Exactly.
They forced me to rob chemical
depots to create more of my serum,
substituting bat DNA
for the DNA of other animals.
They want to make an animal army
to take back Gotham for all animal kind.
Can you lead us to them?
Yes, but Pyg and Toad got the last
of the DNA they needed
at Tapper Chemicals.
We might already be too late.
[Gasps]
Let the experiments commence.
Professor Pyg: Now, I hope
you're not allergic to cat hair.
Because you're going to be
covered in it soon.
And one of you lucky girls
is going to have the honor
of becoming Mrs. Toad.
Now, Mister Toad,
this is the most important
decision of your life.
Chose with your heart.
Absolutely.
[Panting]
Eenie, meenie, miney...
...mo.
Would you do me the honor
of making me the happiest
man-phibian on Earth?
[Screams]
That's frightened for "yes."
[Sighs]
Langstrom: This is where they held me.
If they have hostages,
that's where they'll be.
Katana: Are we too late?
[Woman screaming]
No.
[Whimpering]
Professor Pyg: That's rude.
How do you expect us to create a race
of human-animal soldiers
if you insist on interrupting?
Why don't we settle this like gentlemen?
That would be dreadfully dull.
[Gasps]
Ssh!
[Whimpers]
Follow me.
Our army is deserting. Mister
Toad, get them back in formation!
[Grunting]
Now, where were we?
[Sirens] It's the police.
That's Gotham PD, not the SCU.
Stay in the shadows.
Put your weapons down! I've got
people here who need help.
We got a call saying Pyg and Toad
were holding hostages at the old zoo.
A call? From who?
Someone calling themselves "Oracle".
[Sirens blaring]
[Grunting]
You are spoiling my wedding day.
Now, be a good bat
and fetch my future bride.
[Grunting]
That wasn't sporting.
Now, let me show you something
I didn't learn in medical school.
Okay, I will give you one last chance
to surrender.
Stay down.
Oh, he's ruined these trousers.
Sweetums.
We are home.
[Growling]
Langstrom, fight it!
Professor Pyg: Do you,
Mister Toad, take this soon
to be non-human to be your
unlawfully wedded wife?
I do.
And do you,
soon to be non-human,
take Mister Toad to be your
unlawfully wedded husband?
[Groaning softly]
That means I do.
Keep going.
If there is anyone who thinks
these two should not be united, speak now
or forever hold your...
The weddings off.
Sit down and behave.
- Professor Pyg: Yes, Sir.
- Mister Toad: Yes, Sir.
[Sirens]
Can't believe I almost married that guy.
Ew. And that he
licked my neck.
It's safe to come out now,
Dr. Langstrom.
I don't know how I
could ever repay you both.
Continue your research, find a cure.
How, when I look like this?
Batman: You're still
Kirk Langstrom inside.
That hasn't changed.
As long as you
remember who you really are,
there's nothing to fear from the Man Bat.
If I need your help how
will I find you again?
You won't, we'll find you.
[Beeping]
Are you two done?
There's only so much macho I can take.
Thank you, Alfred. To Harvey
Dent, Gotham's next Mayor.
What?
You're backing me?
This should answer your question.
Wow!
Well, I am a billionaire.
Dane, take a look at this.
Dane: Yup, those are a lot of zeroes.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Mayor? When I told
you to make friends,
I didn't mean Harvey Dent
- and his "Pitbull".
- I like Dane.
His technique is a little
sloppy, but he can keep up.
He kind of reminds me of...
- ...me.
- Wonderful.
Two Bruce Waynes.
Just what the world needs.
That still doesn't explain Dent.
You know what they say,
keep your friends close...
but your enemies closer.
Sync and corrections by masaca
- www.addic7ed.com -