? COVER ME ?
? WHEN I RUN ?
? THROUGH THE FIRE ?
? COVER ME ?
? DARLING, PLEASE ?
? WHEELS KEEP TURNING ?
? SOMETHING'ŐS BURNIN'Ő ?
? DON'ŐT LIKE IT,
BUT I GUESS I'ŐM LEARNIN'Ő ?
? SHOCK ?
? MONKEY ?
JOHNS HOPKINS,
CANCER.
[WHIMPERING]
DEPARTMENT OF PSYCHOLOGY.
? SHOCK THE MONKEY ?
? SHOCK THE MONKEY
TONIGHT ???
NO ONE'ŐS
GOING TO HURT YOU.
TERI, COME AND MEET
YOUR NEW STUDENT.
WE HAVE A TENDENCY
TO EXPECT--
AS I WAS SAYING.
HI.
VIRGIL, LOOK.
APPLE.
YOU DON'ŐT WANT IT?
LOOK, LOOK.
AH AH AH AH!
MMM-MMM-MMM.
GOOD. CLEAN. RIGHT.
IT'ŐS WORK TIME.
COME ON.
WHERE IS HE?
GOOD. DOG OUT.
GOOD.
HELP WHAT?
HELP FLY?
YOU MEAN THIS?
HEY, ENOUGH.
HOW ABOUT IF I WRITE
YOUR NAME ON IT?
THEN IT'ŐLL BE
VIRGIL'ŐS ALLIGATOR.
NO. NO.
IT'ŐS NOT PLAY TIME.
GOOD, GOOD!
DR. CRISWELL.
WAIT A MINUTE.
IT'ŐS OK.
I'ŐLL BUY HIM.
HE WON'ŐT UNDERSTAND
WHAT'ŐS HAPPENING.
HE'ŐLL BE WELL CARED
FOR...AND WELL LOVED.
YOU'ŐRE
IN THE AIR FORCE NOW.
[CHITTERING]
GARRETT, TIME
TO SEE THE COLONEL.
IN OTHER WORDS,
YOU DID IT TO GET LAID.
CONCENTRATING
ON FOOTBALL.
I RAN
A BETTING POOL.
UNTIL YOU CAN LEARN
TO OBEY ORDERS.
"EXPERIMENTAL PILOT
PERFORMANCE PROJECT."
NO, SIR.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
HOW DO YOU DO?
I'ŐM DR. CARROLL.
YES, SIR.
AND I HOPE THAT I CAN
BENEFIT THE PROGRAM.
GOOD.
NOT YOU. THEM.
NUMBER 5,
RESTABILIZE YOUR APPROACH.
THAT'ŐS RIGHT.
LIKE EVERYBODY ELSE.
THANK YOU.
[LOW-FLYING AIRCRAFT]
HI THERE, FELLA.
GRR!
OK, LET'ŐS GO.
WITH THIS LITTLE FELLA HERE.
HE LOOKS JUST AS SCARED
AS YOU DO.
OK.
HOW YOU DOIN'Ő?
UH, NO FUNNY STUFF, OK?
BE A GOOD
LITTLE CHIMP.
COME HERE.
SHIT.
HEY.
[CLAPPING]
GOOD BOY.
PULL UP,
PULL UP.
GIVE HIM A RAISIN.
NOW GO UP.
GO UP.
COME ON. UP.
PULL BACK. PULL BACK.
THAT'ŐS GOOD.
I'ŐVE NEVER
SEEN THIS BEFORE.
UH...YOU GOT ME.
I'ŐM SORRY.
TURN YOUR HEAD
THIS WAY.
PFFT! PFTT!
PFFT!
WHERE ARE YOU
TAKIN'Ő HIM?
WHO MADE YOU
LORD OF THE APES?
COME ON.
DON'ŐT ASK,
"WHAT IS IT?"
CAN I SEE
YOUR CIGARETTE?
GOOD NIGHT, MAN.
VIRGIL, HUH?
YOU DON'ŐT LOOK
LIKE A VIRGIL.
I THINK
THIS IS YOURS.
SEE YOU LATER,
ALLIGATOR.
HELPING PEOPLE HELP
EACH OTHER--THE UNITED WAY.
HELP.
HI.
I DON'ŐT BELIEVE IT.
HELP.
OH, OUT. HELP OUT.
YOU WANT TO GET OUT.
HEY.
NEW GIRL
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
I SHOULDN'ŐT EVEN
HAVE LETYOUOUT.
WHAT IS THAT?
FOOD.
THAT I CAN DO.
HERE.
YOU DON'ŐT WANT IT?
WHAT?
YEAH?
IT'ŐS A REFRIGERATOR.
THAT'ŐS THE SIGN
FOR APPLE?
WHAT?
YOU WANT THIS?
YOU WANT THE BRUSH?
OK. HERE.
[LOW-FLYING AIRCRAFT]
TIME TO GO TO BED.
YEAH. FRIENDS.
GOOD NIGHT, VIRGIL.
AHH...AHH...
"THE LEFT INDEX
TURNING SLIGHTLY.
TO COMMUNICATE WITH ME.
NO, VIRGIL, YOU GAVE
THE APPLE TO YOUR GIRLFRIEND.
OK, FOOD.
COME ON, FOOD.
NO, WE DON'ŐT.
THAT'ŐS ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
[LOUD CHATTERING]
!
IT'ŐS YOUR FAULT
THAT'ŐS RIGHT.
THAT'ŐS GOOD.
PFFT PFFT!
ETHEL.
YEAH, BLUEBEARD.
LOOKS LIKE YOU'ŐRE
JUST ABOUT READY, PAL.
OH, FINE, SIR.
GOOD.
HEY.
OK. STOP FLYING.
GOOD.
HEY, CHIMP YEAGER,
GIVE ME FIVE.
ENJOY IT.
YOU DON'ŐT WANT IT?
OUT. HURRY.
OH.
OOH OOH OOH!
OK. BIG TIME.
DON'ŐT GO TOO FAR.
GARRETT, I NEED TO SPEAK
TO YOU FOR A MINUTE.
OH, THAT'ŐS GREAT.
KEEP UP THE GOOD WORK,
JIMMY.
HEAR THAT?
WE'ŐRE PROMOTED.
I DON'ŐT KNOW.
OK, BLUEBEARD.
OK. CHIN UP.
GOOD BOY.
HERE, GIVE ME
YOUR HAND.
GARRETT, GO ON IN.
TRAINER, CHECK YOUR PILOT IN
AT THE AIRCRAFT.
GO ON.
TRAINER, EVACUATE CHAMBER.
TRAINER!
EVACUATE CHAMBER.
HERE YOU GO.
PUT THESE ON.
ROGER.
COMMENCING.
SYSTEM LOADED.
OPEN.
RECEIVED MIDCRANIAL DOSE
OF 1,200 REMS.
YO.
LET'ŐS SEE THAT
LITTLE THING THERE.
DON'ŐT WORRY,
YOU'ŐRE CLEAN.
YUP.
[LOW-FLYING AIRCRAFT]
IN CASE WORLD WAR III
HAPPENS.
IT'ŐS THE AIR FORCE.
THAT'ŐS WHAT YOU
GOT TO DO.
YOU'ŐLL FORGET ALL ABOUT
THIS PLACE, MAN.
[LOW-FLYING AIRCRAFT]
[WATER SPLASHES]
GOOD NIGHT, JIMMY.
GOOD NIGHT.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
VIRGIL. I SAID
COME BACK HERE.
GIVE ME YOUR HAND.
OK, GET ON THE SCALE.
WOULD YOU GET
ON THE GODDAMN SCALE?!
GET ON THE SCALE!
GIVE ME THAT.
GIVE ME THAT!
GODDAMN IT, VIRGIL!
COME HERE.
AAAAAAAAHHHH!
[ALL HOWLING]
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
BUT WE HAVE A FRIEND
IN COMMON--VIRGIL.
NO, WAIT.
OK.
BLUE, JUNIORS,
AND RED, SENIORS...
SIT DOWN.
AND THE PAIN
WILL GO AWAY.
WE'ŐLL GET YOU
UP IN THE AIR AGAIN SOON.
WE'ŐVE, UH, GOT
SENATOR DANNIS COMING.
? YOU BABY YOU,
BABY YOU... ???
THANKS, JIMMY.
EXCUSE ME.
COULD I
BUY YOU A DRINK?
TWO BEERS.
YOUR NAME'ŐS JIMMY?
YOU DID CALL ME,
RIGHT?
I DON'ŐT MEAN TO BE RUDE,
SO, UH, EXCUSE ME.
SHE GOT MARRIED,
YEAH. [CHUCKLES]
GO, GO, GO ON.
[WHIMPERING]
AAAH! AH!
GARRETT!
[CONTINUES, INDISTINCT]
COME ON, BUDDY.
LET'ŐS GO.
[WHIMPERING]
AAAAH! AAH AAH!
AH! AH! AH! AH!
[WHIMPERING]
HA HA HA HA!
ROGER.
OF 3,500 RADS...
IF HE TOOK OFF
WITHIN 2.5 MILES
OF GROUND ZERO.
WHY DOES THIS CHIMP
HAVE TO BE IRRADIATED?
INITIATING
LANDING PATTERN.
YOU DON'ŐT HAVE
ENOUGH TIME.
GET HIM OUT
OF HERE, TONIGHT.
UHH! UHH!
OOH OOH OOH!
WE'ŐLL COME OUT
THAT DOOR THERE.
HEY, DON'ŐT WORRY ABOUT IT.
HE'ŐLL MAKE IT OVER.
BYE.
WATCH THE GAME.
MISS? COME WITH ME,
PLEASE?
THE BLUE DEVILS
ARE MORE EXPERIENCED...
[ALARM]
[MONKEYS CHITTERING]
WHOO!
AAAH!
AAAAH!
[SIZZLE]
AAAH! AAH!
AAAAAH!
AAH! AAH!
AAH! AAH! AAH!
GET THE DOOR!
SOMEBODY, GET THAT DOOR OPEN!
LOOK LIVELY, EVERYBODY.
WELL, WAKE HIM UP!
THIS IS DR. CARROLL.
VIRGIL. VIRGIL.
VIRGIL.
IT'ŐS ME.
COME ON.
AHH AHH!
PPFFT PPFFT!
PPFFT!
HOO! HOO!
AAAAH!
THERE ARE MONKEYS
ALL OVER THE PLACE, SIR.
DAMN.
OH, SHIT.
[BEEPING]
SPIKE, GET DOWN.
SPIKE, PUT IT--
GET OFF, SPIKE.
GET GOIN'Ő.
GET OUTTA HERE.
GARRETT, GET OUT
OF THERE, MAN.
2...
NO CONTAMINATION
OUTSIDE.
YEAH.
UNTIL WHAT?
GARRETT!
GARRETT, YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'ŐM SAYING?
JIMMY.
THAT'ŐS GOOD.
GOOD.
OHHH...
HOW ARE WE?
NO RADIATION LEAKAGE
OUTSIDE THE FLIGHT CHAMBER.
GOOD.
GOOD, GOLIATH.
THAT'ŐS GOOD.
GOOD.
THANK YOU, GOLIATH.
ARE YOU BOTH OK?
AND HELP GET THE OTHERS
BACK IN THEIR CAGES.
HE NEVER SHOULD HAVE
BEEN BROUGHT HERE.
SHE SHOULD
TAKE HIM HOME.
IS THAT CLEAR?
THAT'ŐS AN ORDER.
YES, SIR.
GO GET YOUR ANIMALS
BACK IN THEIR CAGES.
COME ON.
EASY.
MMM MMM MMM!
MMM! MMM!
Teri: COME ON.
UUH!
COME ON.
[SIREN]
COME ON, GET
IN THERE, TROOPS.
DON'ŐT WORRY.
I DO IT ALL THE TIME.
[SIREN]
FAR AS WE CAN GET.
YOU'ŐRE MY COPILOT,
BUDDY.
Teri: COME ON, GUYS!
COME ON.
THAT'ŐS IT, COME ON.
WHOA.
WITH YOUR HANDS
IN THE AIR.
EXIT THE AIRCRAFT.
LET'ŐS GO, HONEY.
Man: COME ON,
LET'ŐS GO.
NOW!
OF THE ALL-CLEAR.
OVER.
ROGER. COPY, 15.
HOLDING POSITION.
WHY NOT?
STANDING BY
FOR CONFIRMATION.
HOLD SHORT. YOU ARE NOT
CLEARED FOR TAKEOFF.
YOU ARE NOT CLEARED
FOR TAKEOFF. OVER.
HOLD SHORT! YOU'ŐRE NOT
CLEARED FOR TAKEOFF! OVER!
YOU BETTER ANSWER ME!
GO, VIRGIL!
YEAH!
HEADING SOUTHBOUND
TOWARDS EVERGLADES. OVER.
I'ŐLL CATCH 'ŐEM
AT THE OUTER MARKER. OVER.
HE'ŐS GOIN'Ő IN.
DOWN IN THE EVERGLADES,
145 DEGREES AND...
YES, SIR.
AS CONFIDENTIAL...
MMM MMM!
MMM OOH OOH
UH UH...
MMM MMM OOH OOH...
CAN I SAY
SOMETHING TO HER?
MAKE IT QUICK.
LISTEN.
AAH AAH AAAH...
[WHIMPERING]
WHAT'ŐS THE SIGN
FOR FREE?
FREE.
GO ON.