My love, I앐 coming back
spectacural..
Sensational...
I will revenge to that evil farmer.
I앐 a city type of man.
Did you get married, Bosa?
Too heavy...
Do you need help?
He bought the wedding dress.
I have wedding dress
what you bought for me.
You just can앖 remember.
I didn앖 buy anything..
Boso, give me that stone.
That big one.
Dress with flowers.
After you sold the cow.
Silky one, 100 %.
You wash it only in warm water.
You can't remember or?
Not that one, the big one.
Ok, don앖 be angry.
Youre so heavy.
Come on woman, hurry up!
When I was put the dress,
you said
i look like fairy.
You promised, that you will
take me to the priest.
What priest?
Go down to the bell...
Please...
Fishes and other animals have shape,
what helps them to
move faster in their
enviroment?
Water.
and they breed trough special
organ what압 called?
And that is?
And that is...
Gills.
let me hear everyone...
Amphibians are creatures
who can
live both on earth and water...
In the water they breed trough skin,
And on the earth with...
Lungs.
Smart kids.
And word or two about reptiles.
Reptiles are animals, who doesn앖
have always
same body temperature...
It dependes from temperature in enviroment.
And about birds,
Birds are only animals who
can fly..
Tomic, what are you doing?
Back on your seat.
What spieces we call vertebrate?
We have mammals...
What mammals do?
They breast feed.
They breast feed from the mom.
Teacher, its the best with example
from real life.
I know one guy from my village
He is football player,
every halftime he go home,
to breast feed.
and after that from 30 meters he scores...
That압 the real mammal player.
What the fuck!
Who is this?
That압 turbo mammal.
Farmer.
If you want i can
take care of him.
I앏l show you, you and your care.
You want me to fail the test,
why are you doing this?
I want you to marry me?
Jasna, go outside and say to loverboy
to be quite.
You are crazy!
Man with gray moustach
wants to take you.
Listen go to your school,
and then do crazy stuff!
Here is not allowed!
I don앖 have school.
How is that?
It is closed.
For inspection.
I don앖 care, go somewhere
else,you can앖 stay here.
But I recognized you.
What did I do to you,
to suffer like this.
You destroyed my heart.
I destroyed you?
How did I do that?
You were married, and I was alone,
Waiting, waiting..
What was I supposed to do.
To kill my wife and get you.
If you think about my ex-boyfriend,
the driver,
he was an alcoholic.
I don앖 care about him.
If you think about travel salesman,
he was nice
he promised he will take me to the sea.
In Hungary or?
Youre so naughty.
With him, with him
you cheated on me..
With Trifun.
My stepbrother.
Shoemaker...
Hey, farmer!
Didn앖 I tell you to go
away.
Live my girl alone!
You understand?
I wait for Jasna,
I don앖 know your girlfriend.
Jasna is my girl, stupid.
Did you recognized her also.
Yes, but you will not be recognized.
Wanna fight ?
Stop with that!
You want me to call police.
What ?
You feel sorry for him?
I앐 calling police now.
Don앖 call police,
we just joking with him.
What did they do to you?
My icon.
Are you ok?
I have icon, I need souvenir...
You have souvenir , look
how big it is.
Do I have you?
Wash yourself.
Do it.
Stay here, i go get alcohol.
I don앖 drink alcohol.
Nice.
Not now, I앐 waiting
Come...
Did you light the candle for Trifun?
Yes.
Now you go with us,
you will not regret.
Not now, I앐 waiting Jasna
with alcohol.
There will be plenty of alcohol.
Girls....
People, I앐 waiting for Jasna!
What did he said?
He압 waiting for something!
Good evening, you have reservations?
Krivokapici.
Who's car was that?
Mine, why?
Didn앖 be in gear.
So that's that third man.
Hey kitty!
Welcome, my brother.
What is it, finaly a man,
family is treating, no problem.
He really need's a marriage,
he압 grandpa is dying.
Marriage no way,
but fucking it's possible.
And for friends,
there is always discount.
Listen, keep away from my girl!
What did he said?
He's drunk, and underage...
Who's drunk?
Go away from here.
I don't have that.
I have only sexual services here,
every night is full.
Come to see..
Can't we do something?
That grandpa die happy?
Should we drug him?
Doe's he got ID card?
Don't know but we can fix that.
No, no, not like that.
Have a seat... come..
Sunshine, that's not for you,
i have better stuff.
Extra class.
Experienced woman.
Listen...
This young girls don't know
anything..
They just spread legs...and nothing.
There is no communication.
And with this one, you will enjoy,
and learn.
I앏l give you something good.
I like how you thinkin'.
I want them dead tonight.
Brother, all this smells like
big shooting.
Just without latz of blood,
you know that I hate violence.
I know, I know.
Destroy this place!
What did he said?
Are you crazy...
be quite.
Banda...
Take little one in number 1.
We go.
Brother, but discount?
Come on, what are you waiting?
We go in other pub.
Discount.
Loly, you have extra customer
in number two.
Go now.
Sunshine, the room number two.
Brother...
Are you for some refreshment?
Stupid, customer is always right!
Mister I apologize.
If I sad suck, you will suck.
You will ruin the reputation
of my son.
My son is first to bild the twin towers
in Serbia.
Whore, go out.
You are so tiny.
You are teacher.
Whatever, take your pants off.
Look, look...
Bite, maybe this will
pay you your 50%.
357 or?
You are Jasna's mother.
How you know that?
Midget, see you in hell...
What midget?
He's just the kid.
Shut up whore or you go with him.
Me, whore?
Mother fucker!
Leave the kid alone!
You kid, you didn앖 see anything!
I앏l kill you, i swear...
Come on...
Bulletproof.
My car!
You killed my car!
He was not in gear!
Asshole!
Fucking asshole!
Hey little boy,
pretend, pretend...
Please...
I think you will go back home with
dry dick.
Cane, what happend?
I know, Tomic isn앖?
No, bandits.
What bandits?
Air...air...
What air?
Son go eat something...
Air..air
Mouth on mouth...
Go in the kitchen son, go.
Go my son, this is not for you.
Go now bastard...go eat something.
Little one, you really surprised me,
well done.
Liar!
Bravo!
One was come from the back,
big as giant...
like dinosaur...
and what I do?
I jump, step back, kick him,
take him for neck...
he압 begging for mercy...
and then after comes
four more...
first one I block, kick the second one...
blood all over the room...
I앐 flying trough the window...
What are you doing?
Wait, its not finished yet.
I go up, then strong kick in
the nose,
I fall again...
take the stone from ground..
there was dark..
someone kick me, probably some worker..
or something,...
Come, seat.
You know what?
You are really good liar.
No.
It압 not lie, its just making the story better.
My grandpa say압, what will be if
we only tell the true.
You know what we and grandpa do?
All night we lie to each other.
Creating some story, miracles...
I do it to make you feel better.
You left this in the school yard.
I don앖 need that without icon.
Icon is on repairing,
My teacher said he will fix it.
You are real fancy.
What means fancy?
Like cool, who was dress you?
My stepbrother.
Dead man.
No this one is alive , two
of them.
They took me to the pub.
You았e been in pub?
I was think to buy myself wife, be cause  the testament.
And did you buy?
No, grandpa says I will not find that in the pub,
only beer and fucking.
There was discount also.
You slept with whore in the pub?
No, I was runaway.
You did.
No I didn앖.
I know you did.
That압 not testament.
Did you hear Tomic today?
They speak lies.
My mom just serve the drink's there.
I know.
Jasna!
Mother, what's wrong?
Nothing I just fall.
Should I call ambulance?
No, no.
How did you fall?
I don앖 know, I passed out.
I go get alcohol.
How did you run away?
I jumped through the window.
Does Jasna know something?
No, she  doesn't.
Good, you didn't see or heard
something.
Didn't see, didn't heard.
Why is bell ringing?
I'm calling the priest!
What priest, call my Cane!
I will die when I want.
Priest is not only
for funerals.
Stop it now!
And that dress with flowers?
What I'm keeping.
If there is god's will,
You are not keeping her
for nothing.
Kid, go out, don't disturb the class.
I'll kill you.
Go kid, or i lead you out!
Here, its finished.
Watch the edges, its fresh.
Jasna, we need to go.
Where?
I was dream the grandpa again.
He압 calling me in the sleep.
And for you will be better
to go from this town.
Where?
In my village.
That I show you to the grandpa.
You didn't fill testament.
You should buy souvenir also.
I have icon.
Go in the town,
buy something.
Buy something nice
and pretty.
You have money.
Where is the money?
What did you do with money?
I gave it to your mom.
Why did you do that?
You wanted to buy wife?
You wanted to buy me?
Say it!
Your mom is in big debt Jasna.
You in debt to man with grey
moustache.
He's making problem to
your mom.
He want's to take you also.
Don't worry for us.
We don't need your money.
I don't need it also.
Be there after bell.
This was done by first
demolish firm in Serbia.
They gonna demolish
pyramides also.
Who's gonna demolish pyramides?
That's old theme leave that.
Like americans, whatever
is in the way of oil.
They just sign paper,
and say goodbye pyramides.
If something's on the way
of democracy.
Just demolish!
Now you gonna see...
Officer, lean on it.
The building start's to fly.
You will see a picture tommorow
in the newspapers.
What are you laughing for?
Nothing.
Look at that piece of work.
Be reasonable.
I offer you the most beautiful
girl in town.
And ammount what you write.
I앐 thinking... its nice
when man stays to the promise.
Testament.
Promise at all.
I need to show Jasna to grandpa.
What if she don앖 want?
She will, she will.
You need to ask the girl,
what does she want.
Must be, it압 testament.
Did you tell her?
He didn앖.
But when she find out,
she will be happy about it.
Bosa!
My love...
I앐 here.
Where is Jasna?
For one hour, you take
80 euro.
It's different for half hour.
He is strict but correct.
My son Pajo, is fighting
all his life,
for progress and the better life in Serbia.
Democratic changes in Serbia,
was show true face of my son.
Don앖 suck when my mom
is speaking.
His vision to make the twin towers
in Serbia
And on you is now to decide
will you help him,
to finish his idea.
Come my son, let mom
kiss you.
When my mom is speaking,
no one suck! Understand?
When mom is speaking,
it must be,
Silence,or?
That압 right my love.
Do we have any weapon?
No, only gun.
Only gun?
Let her go, its our woman.
There is bodyguards in the house.
If someone doesn't wanna pay,
call them.
Let me go now, untie me.
No way.
What are you doing?
As I know, you don't work
here anymore.
You know how it goes..
Once policeman, always policeman.
Once whore, always whore.
Mr.President I'm asking myself,
what the woman see in me?
I think they go for beauty.
Do we have any weapon?
Nothing.
If any special request from the customer,
you decide the price yourself.
And that's your money.
Money you take right after
comming in room.
And one more technical thing.
Don't try to runaway.
He will kill you.
Is that wind?
Maybe.
Probably.
Probably not.
Throw the gun!
Fast!
Move that hand!
Jasna,  my marriage offer
is still here.
What is it?
I do everything for money.
Just say it...
Take off your socks,
and put this on.
Why?
We gonna fly.
You steal, you steal from me?
No, no I'm not stealing.
So you work everything for money?
This time you work for free.
You have phone?
Yes.
Write...
I'm writing.
Jasna is free, sign Cane.
Nice name.
065-446-681
If only mom is not alive...
I would marry you now.
Should we kill her?
Hey, don앖 joke...
That압 my mom.
I앐 just joking.
My love I need to go...
Listen...
I앏l be back...
You know what is the most
important in the world?
Nature good, Japanese tourism,
nothing like that...
Beauty.
For you is free, go in.
What?
She's here somewhere.
Where is she?
She's up.
Where up?
She was go with some bats.
What bats, what are you saying?
You shitting me, what bats?
Stupid ass.
I will marry you.
But not like blonde.
No, no you'll need it.
Drive straight to train station.
We will go in Sabac,
to my syster.
That압 only safe place.
Did you said last name Srbjanovic?
Knock, knock...
Who압 home?
Ant...
Why are you not married?
To get family, children.
Look how skinny they are.
I should take them,
not opposite.
Knock, knock,
anyone home?
Good evening.
I was think its mister,
but is miss.
You have telegram, sign here.
There is a latz of towns in Serbia.
You don't like one,then
you move, or?
What are you doing here?
Why what?
It's a big country this Serbia.
Listen, you are strong woman or?
And you should shut your mouth.
I'm taking the kid in the hotel.
Don't touch the kid!
We will see is it daughter like mother.
I will teach her myself.
Why she need's school?
She should not care.
And you...
running away.
Running away from me...
Running.
Shame on you.
Go away from the table.
Hey, kid...
Come to uncle Paja.
Come, come...
Fucking bastards!
Boss, what happend?
What, what happend!
Take me out, fucking
bastard!
Do something!
Should we kill you now?
It압 hurting me,
my love.
Stop it, stop!
I know what to do.
Well done my boy.
I can see you are good man.
My love, with us Serbs, only
people is still good.
Is that my boss hanging?
Maybe you see wrong.
Hey man, are you dead?
Kid, only you will get amnesty.
And you three...so fucked...
Brother, he's so cold.
Little oxygen...
I wanna kill him!
Not on the head!
You wanna let him go.
No, no i don't wanna sin.
Instead of giving us 50%,
you wanna kill us all or?
No, no if I'm in debt,
we can sort that out.
We can go on court,
old serbian tradition.
Why did you kick my
brother in the head.
I want money!
I don't have money.
What is this?
You are so rough...
And what you gonna do
with him?
We kill him.
Suddenly..
No, no.
We will not kill him.
We will castrate him.
Leave that tangs,
I have heavy hand.
Don앖 worry my hand is easy.
Like my grandpa.
Tangs please...
I forgot a icon.
You didn't, it's here.
Now I have everything.
You don't have a souvenir.
Don't kiss me for the souvenir.
So how?
Kiss me for the life.
If there is no life, then
for a souvenir.
So...
What now?
Why are you asking me?
Why not?
You know for klamps,
ask stepbrother.
You ask.
Me?
I앐 driving.
Stebrother, where is your village?
What village?
What did he said?
I didn앖 ask him?
Why?
They been speaking something.
Don앖 shake!
I앐 not shaking.
Stepbrother is speaking
really fast.
Oh my good friend...
Poor friend...
Binocular.
Church bell!
What bell?
Is not good...
Stepbrother, bell is ringing!
It's ringing in your head...
It's over stepbrother.
Grandpa!
It's really ringing.
The church bell!
Kid!
Grandpa!
Grandpa...
I knew it ...it's all over now.
What is over?
What is he yelling?
He said it's over.
Grandpa is dead.
What?
When someone dies, its ringing once...
To call all people.
It's not like that.
It was same with grandma...
That's wedding.
Wait, wait...
Wedding!
Not so loud.
Probably that guy is marrying  Bosa.
No he's not.
Grandpa!
What are you doing?
Leave the dead people
in peace.
Grandpa.
My grandpa...
We are grandson's from
Trifun.
We bring you your grandson.
My Cane!
Didn't I tell you that he will come?
I bought a icon.
Did you bring the wife?
Jasna Nikolic.
Let me see you.
Beautiful, beautiful...
People! Are you crazy!
We have funeral here.
What we gonna do with dead man?
Man is dead, he will start to smell now!
One second...
God can't wait.
Yes he can.
Everything will be allright.
Hey boldie, who are you?
Who are you to stop the funeral?
Do you know that funeral
has advantage on the road.
Who the fuck are you?
Should I shoot them all?
No, no ...
I do it myself.
One by one.
What's this boss?
Shoot a little, to scare them.
Run, run...
What's this Cane?
Criminals are chasing us.
Criminals...
For me look's like fascist.
Third world war.
Second one is not over yet.
What will be...
My friend, this smells
like provocation in large scales.
I think this is only
small incident.
You said the same when
Hitler atacked Poland.
Hitler has attacked Poland
because of hate,
and today's force is gracefull,
she kills from love.
No, no not like this...
This is not the old war, don't...
No, please this is my wedding.
Woman and children in church, hurry!
Music , play!
You two, go in the church!
Grandpa, I앐 not the child anymore.
Do you wanna marry?
I didn't ask her.
We will ask her.
Friend, bells!
Please, because couple bullets
we gonna ruin the wedding.
People, what are you doing?
Where are you going grandpa?
Friend order me to ring the bells.
Why the bell is ringing?
It's good that it's ringing twice,
then people are happy...
Sound's like it's ringing three times.
It's all about how they ring.
They can ring five times,
nine times,
just not once.
Bells is ringing for us.
Priest, remember where did you stop.
I'm just gonna finish something.
He's coming, don't worry...
People are you gonna fuck around,
or get married!
Boss...
Wild pig...
Run!
Now...
He is here!
Do you Zivojin, take Bosa for your wife?
Yes!
Do you Bosa, take Zivojin
for you husband?
Yes!
I pronounce you married.
In the name of father, son,
and the holy ghost.
Amen.
Fucking bastards!
Stupid farmers!
I pronounce you man and wife.
Angel!
Does anyone know results
from Italian league?
All this smells like big provocation...
THE END
Promise.Me.This.2007.SR.R5.XviD-REACTOR
English SRT Subtitles - UF
Original SUBS by EMRINHO
Promise.Me.This.2007.SR.R5.XviD-REACTOR
Translated from Turkish into English
www.paylashturk.com