Hey, you guys,
you can't play in there. Jack.
It's dangerous.
There's nails and stuff!
Should've dumped them
all off at Chuck E. Cheese.
That place
is a nightmare.
I hate clowns.
Yeah, well, it's what
he wanted. He's seven.
When I was seven,
I thought clowns were creepy.
Well, you can tell that to
the clown when he gets here.
OK. You need a drink.
- No, I can't.
- Why not?
Meg?
You're not?
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
You can't say
anything to Kent, OK?
- It's a total surprise.
- Huh?
- What surprise?
- Hey, Dad.
He is...he is coming, isn't he?
Yes. He's just
running a little late.
Just checking. Denise,
pour me a beer, will you?
Hello.
You're kidding.
Well... Is there
somebody else you could send?
Yes, sir.
Oh, no, it's no problem at all.
Oh, it's my pleasure. OK. 'Bye.
Ooh!
OK, I'm coming,
I'm coming, I'm coming.
Hey, honey.
I'm headed out the door.
- Is Jack excited?
- Yeah. Listen.
The Party Emporium
people screwed up
and...there's no clown coming.
I thought you had a backup.
Who double-books a clown?
Listen. Just hurry up
and get home, OK, babe?
- Kent?
- OK, listen.
It's... Everything's gonna be fine.
I'll be home soon.
Hello?
Hey, everybody!
Ohh!
Where's Daddy?
He's gonna miss the clown.
Listen.
Oh...
It seems like there was
a little bit of a kerfuffle, alright?
Ladies and gentlemen!
- May I have your attention?
- He's here!
Please gather around,
one and all,
for the wacky, the wonderful,
Dummo the Clown!
Let's get
this party started, huh?
Where's the number one
birthday boy?
Well, give it up for Jack!
Let's make this
the best birthday ever!
OK, Jack.
I've gotta go back to the circus.
Time for bed.
Mmm... I know it's you, Dad.
No. My name is Dummo.
I hear your dad's
a pretty great guy, though.
Go, go, go, go.
Oh, God. I forgot I was a clown.
You were perfect. Jack loved it.
- Where did you find this thing?
- Ahh...
Where's the zipper?
Slipped right on.
- I have big news for you.
- Oh, yeah?
- Mm-hm.
- Didn't know it was MY birthday.
Ohh...
I...
Mm.
What?
This might be
just a little too weird.
Come on. Make a little...
make a little clown baby, huh?
Yeah... You watch TV.
I'm gonna go take
a shower first.
Don't...
You take that thing off,
I'll give you your present.
Shh!
Kent!
Better not be clown marks
on the couch, sweetie.
Yeah, still a clown!
What time is it?
I think this wig is stuck.
Yeah, you shouldn't
have slept in it, maybe.
Hey, guess what.
The clown is driving you to school today.
- Cool!
- Yeah, cool.
- No, wait. Honey, I have...
- Hurry. Jack's late for school.
I have a crew waiting.
I have to get changed...
'Bye. Love you.
Love you!
Hurry up and eat. Come on.
Dad, hurry!
I'm gonna be late!
Coming!
Ugh...
- 'Bye.
Jack, your lunch!
Jack! Your lunch!
Thanks, Dummo.
Great.
Hey, guys. Sorry I'm late.
It's just tearing the carpet
out on the first floor.
Then we'll talk
about the hardwood.
- Who are you?
- I'm Kent, the realtor.
I talked to Miguel.
I'm sorry. Are you Miguel?
Why are you dressed
like a clown?
You guys have kids?
Ohh!
Arggh! Fuck!
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
Fu...
Ohh!
Oh, yes!
- Can I use this?
- What are you doing in there?
- Need some help?
- No, no, no, no,no.
I got it. It's...
it's looking great, by the way.
Ow.
Oh, this...
..this is a bad idea.
Arggh!
Oh, Dad.
What are you doing?!
I wanted to surprise Jack
with the swing set.
Oh, you scared the crap
out of me.
Well, I wanted
to surprise you too.
Dad, Kent was gonna do this.
Yeah, well,
I'm just trying to help.
Yeah, right. It's freezing.
- Let's go inside.
- I'm making dinner.
The damn instructions
are in Chinese.
Hey, babe!
You just missed Dad.
I thought we were
having family dinner,
but Jack just went down.
If you wanna run upstairs
you can probably say goodnight.
Shadow! Lie down.
You went to work
like that?
You don't understand.
I can't get it off.
- Why not?
- Because I can't.
I broke a hand saw.
I cut my wrist open.
And I really...I really,
really have to pee.
OK. OK, OK.
Kent, just calm down.
Sweetheart,
I physically cannot get it off.
I've been trying all day.
OK, so...so it's...it's stuck.
It's suffocating me.
I'm serious! This is...
- Alright.
- Ow. Ow.
It's not... It doesn't...
It's not gonna come off.
Why are you laughing at me?
So dumb. Now I know
why they call you Dummo.
Alright. Here we go.
Relax, OK? This is what I do.
And if you're really good,
I'll get you a lollipop.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- One.
- Ow, ow.
- Two.
- Ow!
OK, OK. OK.
Alright.
Alright, I'm just gonna do this.
- Are you serious?
- Like a bandaid, OK?
- One.
- Oh! Ohh...
- Two.
- Ooh! Ooh!
Three! Three!
- Oh!
- Shadow! Bad dog!
Ohh! Ohh!
Sweetie, what did you
do to yourself?
Ohh!
- Did you dye your hair?
- It's a wig.
No, it's not.
Sweetie, did you
dye and perm your hair?
I didn't dye my hair!
What the f...
- Daddy?
- Oh, Jack.
Sweetie, let's get you to bed,
alright, honey?
What's Shadow eating?
Daddy's OK.
Ohh...
You're just gonna have to
let the adhesive dissolve.
You definitely don't want
to take any more skin off.
Just take some warm showers.
There wasn't any adhesive.
I'm not an idiot.
Maybe someone's
playing a prank on you.
Who would do that?
What happened to your wrist?
Oh, I, uh...I cut myself.
By accident.
Mr McCoy, if you need
to speak with someone,
we have counsellors
that can help you.
Funny. No.
You don't understand.
There is something going on.
This was a wig.
And the white make-up,
uh... It...
What kind of make-up
do you usually use?
I'm not a clown!
Come on, Jack. Brush your teeth!
Hey, Olive. It's Kent.
Can you do me a favour?
Can you check the property files
to see if the Oakdale place
lists the previous owner's name?
I think the initials are KC.
Uh, OK. Hold...
Let me... Give me a sec.
Let me see if I can find...
You know what?
I'll...I'll come in and get it.
Ohh...
- Hey, Olive.
- Hey, Kent.
Oh...
Oh!
Sorry! Oh...
Sonofabitch.
Still hungry?
Eugh, gross.
I don't know. It looks old.
It smells weird.
- Come on. Anything else? Please.
- I don't know, man.
We sell Halloween costumes
and cheap stuff, not like that.
OK, but who does?
There's, like, a lot.
They're in here.
That one.
Yeah.
I'm calling about
a clown costume
I think might belong to you.
It was found in
Martin Karlsson's basement.
Where's Marty?
Oh. Uh, I'm sorry. Uh...
Martin Karlsson passed away.
I'm the real estate agent
handling the...
Listen to me. Whatever
you do, don't touch that costume.
You understand?
Stay away from it.
Are you still at the house?
I'll be over
as soon as I can.
But don't touch
the costume, please.
I'm wearing it.
Hello?
Uh, that's fine.
Uh, be careful.
It's old and fragile.
It doesn't seem very fragile.
I'm actually having
a pretty hard time getting it off.
Don't worry.
That happens all the time.
The heat from your body
can constrict the moisture
trapped in those old fibres.
Makes it hard to get off.
Oh, that...that...that
makes perfect sense.
I thought I...
..I thought I was going crazy.
We should meet
as soon as possible.
Can you come to my warehouse?
Uh... Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
I can get there.
We'll have
that thing off in no time.
Hello?
Is anyone here?
- Kent.
- Jesus Christ!
- Oh!
- I didn't want to scare you.
- I'm Bert Karlsson.
- Nice to meet you.
Tea?
Uh...
Mm! Thank you.
I've been abroad off and on
these last couple of years.
I haven't talked to Marty
for ages.
Our relationship was, yeah,
complicated.
I'm sorry I never met him.
That is a very old...
traditional costume
from the Nordic regions.
It wasn't until years later
it became a silly character.
The original clown,
he was not funny at all.
So, tell me, Mr Karlsson,
how are we gonna get
this thing off of me?
Very few people know
the true origin
of what we call the clown.
I can show you here.
There.
It lived up in the mountains,
with a skin white as snow
and the red nose,
blistered by the cold.
It lured children out
of the villages into its cave.
Five children.
One child
for every month of winter.
Over the centuries, the legend
of the cloyne was forgotten.
He became the clown.
His white face and red nose,
to make people laugh.
To entertain children.
If only they knew!
Why are you showing me this?
So you can understand.
Ugh!
Oh, shit!
- Ugh!
- Oh, no.
The tea was supposed
to keep you asleep for hours.
Ugh!
I'd go get some more,
but I can't risk you getting loose.
Oh! Wha... Wha...
It's gonna be alright.
Wha...
Decapitation is the only way
to stop the demon.
No, wait.
Wait. Wait.
Wait.
- Ugh! Ugh!
- I'm sorry.
Ugh! Ugh!
Ugh!
- Ugh!
- I'm so sorry.
Ah! Ah!
Ah!
What the fuck?!
I'm sorry. I didn't mean...
What the fuck are you doing?!
It's not a costume.
It's skin. And hair.
Of a demon.
- Honey! Call 911!
- What? Where have you been?!
This maniac tried to kill me.
The guy whose house it was
that had the suit in it.
Look. He thinks I'm a demon.
Honey, we have to
go to the cops.
But you have to come with me,
'cause they're gonna think I'm crazy
if I'm dressed like a...clown.
What the fuck?!
Are you wearing make-up?
Let go of her, Kent!
What the hell is wrong with you?
Walt, I know this seems
a little crazy, a little nuts,
but this guy's a maniac.
If this is a joke,
it's not very funny.
- It's not a joke!
- So take off the clown suit.
I can't!
You think I'm making this up?
He chopped my neck
with a butcher knife!
- Is this blood?
- Yes, it's my blood!
He chopped me
with a butcher knife!
Who did?
Who the hell is that?
He tried to cut off my head.
He thinks I'm...
I'm turning into a demon.
Baby, he...he's crazy.
This is his suit. He did this.
All of it.
Just take the fucking thing off!
- Arggh!
- Oh, Jesus, Dave!
Are you fucking
out of your head?
Baby...
Meet me at the police station.
Please.
You're going to jail, man.
You are going to jail.
I'm trying to help you.
Oh! Oh!
It's...happening.
What are you doing to me?!
Kill...yourself...
..before...
Hey, man. You OK? You OK, man?
Kill yourself.
- Ms McCoy?
- I'm sorry, what?
Right, one last question.
Do you remember what he was wearing
the last time you saw him?
Like a...
..a long coat and a...dark hat.
OK.
If you hear something, you call.
Thank you.
Maybe it's a chemical thing.
You know.
He seems like
Mr Perfect Dad,
but then, suddenly...
Meg, I want you and Jack to
come stay with me for a while.
You got to
think of your family, Meg.
You can't baby him.
You got to tell Jack
his dad's dangerous.
I don't have to
listen to this anymore.
I'm just trying to
make it clear that...
Dad.
He was scared.
Mom... Is this my fault?
No! It's not your fault.
It's no-one's fault.
Just get some sleep.
Goodnight, doll.
Pipe down, fellas. Let's go.
Hey. You left your dirty plate
by the fire.
- Go clean it up.
- Oh, crud.
Don't get lost, lard-ass.
Zip it, Dickinson!
Do you have any food?
All I want is some food.
I've got these.
..should pick him up
are me or my neighbour Denise.
So you got my cell phone.
And my dad's first name's Walt.
So... Try him too.
Thanks. Appreciate it.
Oh, hey, sweetie. Come here.
I'm gonna go, OK?
But who's gonna
pick you up today?
- You or Denise.
- Mm-hm.
And if you see Daddy?
Is Daddy bad?
No. No, no, no, no, no.
He just... He has to do
some grown-up stuff today, OK?
But if he comes
to pick you up?
Say that the teacher
wants to talk to him
and that he should call Mommy.
And...
And that's it.
Mm-hm.
Daddy's coming home soon, OK?
Mwah. 'Bye, doll.
'Bye, doll!
Hey, honey, it's me. It's your dad.
I'm calling to make sure
everything's OK.
See if you heard anything.
Please give me a call and...
Give me a call, OK?
Alright, people.
10 minutes, we're leaving.
- Oh, it stinks in here.
- Oh, gross. What is that?
Hello?
There anybody in there?
Door's locked.
Hello?
Ugh!
Kids, kids!
Just stay away from me!
Are you a clown?
My name's Robbie.
What's your name?
Whoa! You're really hungry.
If you wanna eat, I got some
Cookie Crisps and waffles
and Cinnamon Toast Crunch
and chocolate chips
and chips and some jelly beans
and some beef jerky...
..and some cookies...
..cheese and fries
and ketchup and...
Stay away.
Hi. Want some cereal?
Mr Clown?
Mr Clown!
He's acting crazy.
Well, maybe it was
something he ate.
Is it 'cause he ate
Daddy's clown nose?
Jack, stay right here.
- Stay here.
- Is that Daddy?
Hello? Kent? What's going on?
Jack really misses you.
I'm so sorry.
Tell me where you are.
Tell...tell me you're OK.
I can't take this.
I'm sorry.
This...this is the only way.
Hello?
Mom...
When is Daddy coming home?
Tonight, Jack.
Don't worry.
Daddy's gonna be OK.
Oh!
Thank you.
It's gonna take you all night.
Are you sure?
Yeah. I'll find him.
Yeah, our last big fight,
I was bawling my eyes out.
Kent was hanging out
at one of his properties.
- What an asshole.
- Yeah.
You building a fun house?
Kent?
Are you in here?
Whoa. Oh!
Ugh!
Oh!
- Mr Clown!
- Oh!
No!
Oh, no!
Oh... Oh...
Oh. Oh!
Kent?
No!
Don't open the door.
Kent...it's OK.
No.
You don't...
You don't understand.
I just want to
get you home, Kent.
Look...
..I know something crazy
is happening to you, OK?
I believe you.
OK? I believe you.
We're gonna
figure this out together.
Jack needs you.
I need you.
Kent...
..I'm pregnant.
Take me home.
Please.
OK. It's OK.
Oh...
I can feel myself changing.
What do you
want me to do?
No matter what I say,
you don't let me out.
Promise me?
Promise me.
Promise.
Until we can get you fixed.
OK?
Dr Martin Karlsson.
Children's cancer ward.
Karlsson.
Do you know who I am?
I just wanna talk to you.
I don't know what happened
between you and my husband,
but I just want him back.
I don't know. He, um...
The police are looking for him.
No.
Alright.
Because the suit,
it does things to people, doesn't it?
How do you get the suit off?
How do you
get the suit off?!
How did you get it off?
Who are you?
If you don't wanna help me out,
I'll find another way.
Ma'am, you can't be in there.
I'm leaving.
Hello?
Awww. What's wrong, doll?
Are you crying?
Shut up!
You're such a little bitch.
What's wrong?
Don't you wanna look like a clown,
just like your fag dad?
Ow! Fuck! He bit me!
Mom?
Jack?
Hello?
I'm in the basement, buddy.
Daddy? Is that you?
Sure is, sport.
Did you miss Daddy?
Mommy said if I saw you,
I had to tell the teacher.
Is she here?
I don't think so.
Good. Come downstairs.
I need help.
Mommy says it's OK.
What are you doing
down there, Daddy?
Come downstairs.
I wanna see
my number one birthday boy.
- Hello?
Meg?
- Yeah?
I was picking Jack up
at school today, right?
Yeah, Denise. Thanks for that.
No, I mean, I'm at the school,
and...and he's not here.
Daddy?
I'm stuck, Jack.
I need help.
Oh. Are you crying, buddy?
Hey. Come on, now.
You know you can
always talk to Dummo.
At school, some kids tried
to put paste on my face.
They're always doing that stuff.
Who is?
Colton.
You know what I did
when I was bullied?
I hid, so that
they couldn't find me.
And then, after a while,
you know what happened?
They left you alone?
Hey, Jack. You know
where the bolt cutters are?
Kent?!
J... Jack?!
Oh, Jack.
Oh, God. Oh, my God.
Why'd you leave school?!
Don't ever do that to me, OK?!
Jack!
Where's Daddy?
Where is he?
Yee-ahh!
Shit, dude, don't kill me.
Guys?
You guys really...
I just wanna tell you something.
You guys suck balls.
- Yeah, your mom's balls.
- Come on, man!
Duh. Look at me.
I'm Colton.
- Look, a rocket launcher.
- I don't know where it is.
Don't give a shit
where the rocket launcher is.
- Oh, shit!
- Shit, shit, shit!
Bitch!
Don't come at me
with that rocket launcher bullshit.
Yeah,
rocket launcher's cheap, dude.
Rocket launchers
are for bitches, man.
Shit! Guys, don't kill me.
Stop bitching.
After that bullshit you just pulled?
Come on, Colton. How long
does it take to change a tampon?
Guys, I think
there's someone in here.
Probably Master Chief.
Hey, check this out.
Oh, man - that reminds me
of what I did to Colton's mom last night.
Mr McCoy? Is Jack here?
Colton, where are you?
- Bet he's in trouble.
- Why?
We were ditching class
and we saw this kid Jack
crying on the steps, so Colton
made him act like a clown.
And he called his dad a fag.
So Colton took
this bottle of glue
and was gonna rub it all over
the little douche's face.
Guys, shut up!
But then he grabbed
Colton's hand and bit him.
Colton's gonna beat his ass...
Guys, shut up!
You're done, man.
Grandpa's excited to see you.
You don't want
your little friend anymore?
Jack. Say something.
Jack, come on! We gotta go!
Shadow?
Shadow, what happened to your...
Where is he?
Oh, my God!
Stay the hell away from us!
Don't want to hurt you.
You stay away from us!
You killed my fucking dog!
Please, you've gotta help me
find your husband!
- Get the fuck outta my house!
- No, you don't understand.
That's the detective.
I'm the only one
who can get that costume off.
I found that fuckin'
goddamn costume by accident.
Hundreds of old costumes
used to come through my shop.
One day, there was
a shipment from Iceland.
An estate sale
from some Icelandic aristocrat.
When I opened the crate,
everything was rotted away,
but this costume,
it was perfect.
I'd never seen anything like it.
I was about to sell it
to the Moscow Circus,
but I wanted to put it
to some good use first.
My brother was a doctor
working with children
with terminal illnesses.
He was always trying
to give them hope,
so I thought,
"Why not cheer 'em up?"
When the transformation started,
I asked my brother for help.
He swore he would find a cure.
That's the last thing
I remember.
When I woke up,
the suit was off.
The curse had been broken.
My brother had given the demon
what it demanded.
He had smuggled out
from the hospital
five children close to death,
one child
for every month of winter.
So that's it? That's the cure?
I've spent all these years
trying to find a clue
how to kill this evil thing.
My brother never left the house,
guarding this costume
with his life.
I didn't even know
that he had passed away
when...your husband called me.
Well, why didn't you destroy it?
Don't you think we tried?
We tried burning it. We tried to
dissolve it in acid, everything.
Nothing helped.
We couldn't just toss it
in the ocean and bury it, could we?
What if someone else found it?
Even the smallest piece
carries the curse.
You have to cut off its head.
You can't destroy the costume,
but you can stop the demon.
My husband would never do that.
This belongs to
a child, seven, eight years old.
Where did he go?
Huh?
I don't know. I...
You don't know?
He went to Colton's.
Where's Colton?
Jack.
He's gotta be stopped.
Jack?
- We have to kill your daddy.
- Hey!
Listen to me. Alright, Jack?
It's not Daddy. It's not.
It's that suit.
It's making him do bad things.
But no-one's gonna
hurt Daddy, OK?
You tell us
there's another way.
Help me catch him.
We'll lock him up...
..continue searching.
Hey, buddy, what's...
Shh.
Hey, sweetie. Everything OK?
Yeah, I... Dad, I gotta go.
I can't get into it all right now.
I'm sorry.
- It's just...
- I gotta go, Dad.
Careful.
He could still be in here.
Hey. Hey!
Oh!
Oh...
- Oh!
- Oh, no.
Don't touch anything, OK?
We have to call the police.
Tell 'em what?
He must have digested him
by now.
Spit out the bones.
Oh!
Couldn't have gone far.
It's seven o'clock
on a Thursday.
Where could a clown go
where he's not being seen?
Oh, no.
What?
Hey! You can't go in there
like that.
Why not?
You look like
an escaped mental patient.
Ah.
Listen. You can't trust
your husband.
- Don't.
- My brother, he shouldn't...
You don't know him.
- You don't know what Kent...
- I wish he had killed me.
- If you love him...
- I know.
I'll bring him to you.
I promise.
Happy birthday!
Shit.
There's no sign of him.
Cannonball!
Oh! Gross!
Somebody peed in here.
Greg? Greg?
Greg?
Greg, Mom said we have to go.
Greg, where are you?
Greg?
Greg!
Don't go up there.
Greg?
There you are.
No! No!
Let go of him!
Run, Greg, run!
Mom! Mom!
- Mom, the clown!
- What is it, honey?
- Up there!
- What?
Excuse me. What happened?
There's a maniac dressed as a clown
loose in there.
Get your kids.
Hey. Come. Come on.
See?
It means he's close.
What's that for?
For protection.
Ah.
Kent?
Where am I?
We're here to help you.
I know you're scared.
We're gonna find a way
to stop it, OK?
We just have to get you
outta here first.
Karlsson's here.
He...he wants to help you.
OK, baby?
I remember him.
He's crazy.
He's not.
He's gonna make sure
no-one else gets hurt.
- Enough!
- Kent, look out!
Kent.
No!
Kent, no.
He's gonna help you.
Uh, Kent, I just...
Let me help you, please.
I know you're
still in there. I...
Come on.
There's gotta be another way.
Bring me a child.
Kent?
Bring me one more child
and you can have
your husband back.
Uh... Uh...
A child!
I can't. I can't.
Perhaps I'll find another.
What's his name?
Ah, yes.
Jack!
No.
Find a child
and bring him to me.
Bring him to...
to our favourite spot, babe.
I'll be waiting.
- Wait.
- Open the door!
Come out with your hands up.
Alright. We are coming in.
Police! Stay down!
Stay down on the ground!
Throw your weapons down!
Put it down!
Put it down, motherfucker!
Dad! You got Jack with you?
Yes. Of course he's with me.
He's fine.
Don't worry about it.
He's being awfully quiet.
I was thinking of taking him home.
No, you can't go home.
OK, just...just take Jack...
Just take him and...
and you gotta leave.
Is Kent at the house? Meg?
What did Kent do?
No. It's not Kent, Dad.
Kent didn't do anything.
Sweetheart,
please tell me what's going on.
I'm here to help you.
Dad, I have to...
Meg?
Meg!
I have to go.
Hunter!
Oh, thank you so much.
Are you looking
for your kid?
Um, no. He's safe.
Police have confirmed
that there have been
two fatalities so far,
both of them children.
And now we've received
confirmation that
the authorities do have
at least one suspect in custody,
a 59-year-old man
named Herbert Karlsson.
No word yet on whether or not...
You work
at the dentist's, right?
Yeah.
I'm Annie.
I used to go there.
- OK.
- I was at Chris's birthday party.
Everything went totally crazy.
And I can't find anybody.
And my mom dropped me off,
and I don't know where she is.
I saw you, and I remembered
that you used to be really nice,
even though the dentist
was kinda scary.
You used to call him chrome dome
when he left the room.
Uh-huh.
Can you drive me home?
I'm scared.
You want a ride home?
Please.
I don't know anyone else.
You're so nice.
Sorry I don't know the way.
Oh, it's alright.
We'll... I know your street.
So we'll find your house.
Don't worry.
You're so nice.
Well, you...
You know, I...think
if it were my son in trouble,
I'd wish someone
would help him out, so...
Are we here?
Yeah. This is it.
You're home.
This isn't...
This isn't my house.
This isn't my house!
Hey, it's scary out here.
Unlock it, please!
Please. Unlock it, please.
There's someone out here.
Please. Please unlock the door.
Please! PLEASE!
There's someone out here.
Please unlock the door!
Please unlock it!
Unlock the door, please!
Unlock it, please!
Please!
Get in the car! I'm sorry.
- What are you doing?
- I'm so sorry.
It's not safe out there!
Hey!
No.
Hey. Wait here.
Jack.
Dad, call me back.
OK?
Where are you and Jack?
Home at last.
OK, let's go and have
a little chat with your dad.
Stay close to Grandpa.
Dad! I told you
not to come back here.
- Where's Jack?
- He's OK.
He's up in his room.
Dad, I made a...
I made a mistake.
Listen. I don't know
what happened.
I don't care what happened.
I just don't want you
implicated in this.
Whatever Kent did, it's OK.
I'm gonna help you, OK?
I'm gonna help you.
What are you talking about?
I'll clean up the blood.
No-one'll know.
Baby, you're my little girl.
I love you.
I...
One...child...more!
Ah!
Run, Jack!
Jack!
Clown motherfucker!
Arggh!
Ahh!
Mom?
Don't watch, Jack.
OK, we got him.
Meg...
..help me.
We got him.
Jack?
Jack. Go get that book.
What?
The book Daddy found.
And...and go get more chains.
Why?
Don't you wanna help Daddy?
That's not Daddy.
Jack, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Ugh! Ugh!
Mom.