Good evening.
You're early.
I want to get off early
tomorrow morning.
Ah. Here are the flowers,
the newspaper and the cigarettes...
- that the countess asked for.
- Thank you.
- Has she called down?
- I don't know.
You're always sending only me out
to buy things for her.
You get tipped, don't you?
Oh!
- [Bottle Thumps On Table]
- [Woman Groaning]
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
Without water?
- The water's finished.
- But they...
They will stick in my throat.
They won't do any harm.
Get on.
[Coughing]
I'm still cold, Max.
I really can't think of anything...
Max, dear.
You don't have any imagination.
- And neither do you, Countess.
- [Chuckling]
Silly, silly, silly.
Do you want the usual assistance?
[Sighing]
[Door Opens, Closes]
Go up to 42.
She's waiting for you.
Go to hell. I want to sleep.
I'll go up later.
- You'll go now!
- I'm fed up with her, damn it!
You asked for a month's wages
in advance.
All of it.
I like people
who honor their contracts.
Okay, okay.
Damn her.
And that perfume
she wallows in is muck.
It may be some fancy brand,
but it makes me vomit. Really.
At least she doesn't
smell of fried food, like you do.
Or, uh, mouthwash.
I don't smell of mouthwash.
I'm dripping with Helena Rubenstein's
eau de cologne for men.
For men of distinction.
Ah!
Thanks.
[Chattering]
Some other time.
[All Chattering]
- [Chattering Continues]
- See you soon. Good-bye.
[Man]
My keys, please. Room 25.
- [Man] My key, please. Number 32.
- I'm sorry.
Thirty-two, please.
I think it was...
- What?
- Thirty-two.
Don't you remember?
We had just come back from...
He's a conductor.
He's conducting at the opera.
- So?
- Oh, nothing.
Hello?
Uh, yes, a bottle
of mineral water, please.
Very cold. Thank you.
[Hangs Up phone]
- No, don't call!
- Why? What's the matter?
I'm sorry.
You'll be all right?
Yes.
Yes, I'm fine.
- [Knocking]
- [Man] Come in.
- Good evening, sir.
- Good evening.
- Will there be anything else?
- No, thank you.
- Good night.
- [Gunshot]
- [people Screaming]
- [Gunshots]
- [Screaming]
- [Gunshot]
- Religion?
- Lucia?
Yes, I'm coming.
[Man]
Greetings.
Did you expect me?
Of course.
- [Groans]
- Would you have the same room?
Always.
You seem strange.
Are you worried about Thursday?
No.
If you're worried, you're foolish.
Your case is easy.
After all, there are no witnesses
to testify against you.
You should be pleased. At the moment,
we're only thinking about you.
The professor says
you're a special case.
- He should be here shortly. Show him up.
- Of course.
- [Man] Name, date of birth.
- Emanuel Strauss.
- Address? Religion?
- [Indistinct]
Next.
- Name?
- Hansard, Wilhelm.
- Date of birth?
- Seventh of March, 1920.
- Address?
- [Indistinct]
- Religion?
- Lutheran.
Next.
- Name?
- Klein, Paul.
- Date of birth?
- March 4, 1918.
- Address?
- [Indistinct]
- Religion?
- Jewish.
Next.
- Name?
- [Indistinct]
- Date of birth?
- Address? Religion?
- [Indistinct]
- Were you trying to sleep?
- No.
- Leave me alone, for God's sake.
- Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
I have my worries too.
Of course.
Would you do me a favor?
If I can.
Would you stand in for me
tomorrow night?
- Where?
- Here.
You'll have to wear my jacket...
and just be polite
to all the guests.
- Well, will you or won't you?
- Of course I will.
Thank you.
It's just for one hour.
Good evening, Max.
- [Clicks Heels]
- Good evening, Herr Professor.
Is he in the same room?
- Yes.
- Good.
[Gunshot]
I've managed...
don't ask me how...
to find what the spies know
exactly about Max.
Here. Maximilian Theo Aldorfer.
"Had a career in the entourage
of Karlton Bruener.
"Operated in Hungary
in a section of the office 4-B.
Lives under an assumed name..."
Etc., etc.
"In the Nuremburg archives, see fie
number..." At the head of the page,...
there's a number three which means
a small fry, not worth bothering about.
However, there's a note which says...
"was very friendly with some
very important people."
So it may be that they are
looking for him.
Max had imagination.
He had fun passing himself off
as a doctor...
to have a chance at making sensational
photographic studies.
It's obvious that not one
of Max's patients survived.
But perhaps one did.
Do you recognize anybody?
Yes, perhaps I remember.
Who knows if she survived?
I thought that Mario might
know something about her.
- Who is Mario?
- Mario, that Italian. Try to remember.
He was spared because
he was an excellent cook.
After the war, he married Greta Heller.
They run a restaurant out on the river.
Ah, yes, yes.
We called him up once to testify.
Yes, and he's coming
to the next meeting.
If he knows anything,
he'll tell us.
Good.
Have you seen Max?
He seems upset.
[Buzzer Buzzing]
[Buzzing Stops]
[Phonograph]
[Continues]
What shall I use?
Aluminium.
Otherwise, I won't sleep.
Bert, you should read a book.
Oh, yes, I've tried, Max.
If I read, I think,
and that's worse.
Get up and go out,
and you know how it always ends.
You need a bodyguard.
I'd like to have you.
If I were rich,
I'd hire you to do
everything for me.
Would you?
Yes, of course.
You say that because you know I can't.
- No.
- You don't really want to.
You don't want to wipe anybody's ass.
Be careful.
You're very good at it.
You never hurt.
[Man]
'An interpretation of great elegance.
"This will be remembered
as a considerable event...
in the lyric season
at the..." [Indistinct]
"I must say that inasmuch
as I had no idea...
"what to expect
from Maestro Atherton,
who comes to Vienna on a wave of acclaim
which he shows is fully merited..."
Aren't you listening?
You don't give a damn about them.
But still, I would like
to hear your opinion.
I'd like some peace.
What's the matter? You've always
wanted to hear the reviews.
We've always
gone over them together.
- I want to go.
- What did you say?
I told you I am leaving.
I want to leave this place now.
I hope you realize what a disaster
we have in the first violinist.
Coreline Hader plays along
all on her own like a perfect idiot.
I told you I am leaving!
Lucia, you're out of your mind.
I have to be at the opera tonight.
All right.
So I'll go alone.
Where do you want to go?
Away from this hotel,
away from this city.
And away from this country.
I understand what you feel.
But you seemed so happy
to come here with me.
Lucia, what's come over you?
Anyway, it's a question
of a few days more.
Tomorrow we go to Frankfurt. In three
days, Berlin, Hamburg and that's it.
[Chuckling]
You're absolutely incredible.
- Incredible.
- [Knocking At Door]
- Don't open.
- It's the porter with other newspapers.
- Don't open, please.
- I thought all had been delivered.
Come in.
- Good morning.
- 'Morning. Thank you.
Thank you.
We've planned everything
for one of these evenings.
You can prepare the room.
They're all coming.
I think I found a witness.
You remember Mario the cook?
He knows something.
Couldn't you wait
a little longer?
No. I prefer to close
your case as soon as possible.
But you haven't come
to see the place.
What is it?
Has something happened?
It's the trial.
Klaus is being
a little... hasty.
Sooner or later he had to call you up,
as he has for everybody else.
Be sure to keep your eyes open. You
often read of somebody being turned in.
Yes, you do. Especially
by collaborators like yourself.
I want everything clear in my head.
[Radio: Singing In German]
Will you eat with us?
Yes, Greta. Thank you.
How's business? Going well?
Thanks to him.
He runs the kitchen.
Go on, Greta.
We want to talk.
Yes. See you later.
- Did you see Klaus?
- Mm-hmm.
- Did he say anything to you?
- I saw Klaus.
He was asking me about that girl
you had with you then.
The daughter of a socialist.
She was... [Clears Throat]
She was Viennese, right?
Certainly you are a strange lot.
I won't go to the police.
It's all water over the dam.
Klaus showed me...
He showed me a photograph
of that girl,
so I explained I had no memory.
I said I didn't recognize her.
I want to live in peace,
and Greta feels the same.
Thank you, Mario.
l-I never told anybody how, uh,
you saved your skin.
Sometimes to save one's skin,
there is no price too high.
You can't compare me with you.
I know, I know.
Still, i-it would be nice...
to talk in peace and quiet.
We could go fishing,
perhaps, if you like.
Sure. If we're not too long,
it's fine with me.
- What about Sunday?
- Okay.
Okay, Mario.
[Man Singing In German]
[Man And Woman Singing In German]
[Singing Continues]
[Singing Ends]
[Flute]
[Singing Resumes]
[Singing Continues]
- The car has come, sir.
- Oh, thank you.
I'll be right there.
Well? The day after tomorrow
at the Weber Hotel.
If you take the plane, I'll send
a car to pick you up at the airport.
You're such a strange creature.
Now you wish you were
coming with me, right?
Don't you want to do that shopping
you told me about?
- No.
- I can't wait now.
Take the plane tonight,
or just come with me now.
We can have them
send everything to Frankfurt.
I'm so silly. Come on.
You'll miss your plane.
At the Weber Hotel
the day after tomorrow.
I'll miss you.
Good morning, sir, madam.
Have you made a reservation?
[Water Splashing]
[Mario's Voice]
No sign of a fish here.
A client said he caught
a four-kilo pike just here.
We didn't believe him.
The water's too fast for pike.
A trout maybe,
but not a pike.
What is it, Max?
What are you doing?
No!
[Screams]
[Man And Woman Singing In German]
[Singing Ends]
- How much?
- One hundred shillings.
[Indistinct Chattering]
[Man]... about 200 were accused
by eyewitnesses,
and the other 100 reported
by the Allies' War Crimes Commission.
Another organization
extremely dangerous for us...
is the War Documentation Center
here in Vienna.
They have files on the S.S. leaders,
some 80,000 names.
I'll see to it that I get
my hands on that fie too.
In the meantime, I want you to take
a look at the evidence against Max.
This constitutes documentation
which could be damaging.
This is all due to Max,
on his orders.
He himself transmitted
the orders for execution.
As always, we must find out if all this
is already known to our enemies...
or if I have managed to get
into the archives before them.
And Max can remain in the shadow,
which is what he wants.
We have decided to delve together to the
very bottom of our personal histories.
We have decided to confront them,
speaking without reserve,
without fear.
Remember. We must try to understand
if we are victims of guilt complexes.
If so, we must be
freed of them.
A guilt complex is a disturbance
of the psyche, a neurosis.
Let's not delude ourselves.
Memory is not made of shadows,
but of eyes which can stare straight
at you and fingers which point at you.
Information on existing witnesses
we have from Mario the cook.
We all know him. In particular, Kurt.
He was very useful.
I wanted him here tonight and sent word
to him. Instead, he disappeared.
- Any of you know anything?
- What do you want witnesses for?
Hans, you know all about my life.
Why rake everything up again?
That's my profession. You accepted
to take part in this group analysis.
I know, I know. Somebody speaks
and the others listen.
But in the end, something
happens within one's self.
Something does.
First we were all afraid. Now we're not.
And something else happens, Max.
I play the devil's advocate
in all this, and to do so I...
seek and I find
dangerous documentary evidence,
which I'll give to our colleague
so he can make a nice bonfire.
I also have a nice list
of witnesses I keep an eye on.
And I keep a most
particular eye on them...
because they're not as manageable
as a pile of papers.
Max, you must
have faith in Klaus.
Remember when we had
my trial here?
I felt as awful
as you feel now.
It did me good to speak,
to confess, to defend myself.
It did me good to clash with Klaus
when he accused me pitilessly.
Remember?
When it was over, however,
I felt a great relief.
Perhaps, also, because Klaus
burned some 30 documents concerning you.
Just as he burned yours, Kurt.
Naturally. And now there's no trace of
us in any military archive. Right?
It will be the same
for you, Max.
Klaus?
Klaus, perhaps there are
no living witnesses.
But if there are,
can't we leave them in peace?
Let them forget?
Even if it says 1,000 persons
on paper, 10,000,
it still makes less impression
than one witness in flesh and blood.
That is why they are
so dangerous, Max.
My task is to seek them out,
wherever they are,
and to see that they
are filed away.
Max, our trials
are held in private.
They're also therapeutic, right?
And the more shock value they have,
the more effect they have.
Only eyewitnesses can provoke this...
because they go into details,
they blurt out everything.
You've seen it, haven't you? Only
confronted with their accusations...
can we discover how far
we're able to defend ourselves.
We have to defend ourselves.
The war is not over.
If you want to live hidden away
like a church mouse, go ahead!
But we want back...
the ranks we held.
So we have never given up.
Never given up!
I haven't given up!
I'm still here with you.
And you must be pleased, Max.
I, Klaus, Kurt, Dobson, Bert,
we're all clean.
All evidence has vanished.
I never thought it was quite enough
just to burn all the papers.
I want to be left alone to... Just
to live in peace, like a church mouse.
I would like to get back
to the point.
It's important that
I find the witness...
whom Mario thinks he recognized.
Who is it?
So far, I only know it's a woman.
l-l-I don't know anything
about a woman.
Yes, I want to call Frankfurt,
the Hotel Weber.
Number? Just a minute.
347-229.
Right away, please.
[Hangs Up phone]
The-The-The number I just
gave you for Frankfurt.
Frankfurt. 347-229.
Yes. Cancel.
Cancel.
Yeah.
Hello? Hello?
What about my call to Frankfurt?
There are no lines to Frankfurt.
Why did you come here?
Hmm?
Why did you come?
[Shouting]
Have you come to give me away?
[Shouting] Have you?
Did you? Answer!
Did you? Why'd you come?
Why'd you come?
[Shouting]
Why, why, why?
Stupid!
You!
[Yelling, Indistinct]
Let me get out!
[Indistinct]
[Chuckling]
- [Laughing]
- Ah, no, no. Too fast, too fast.
Too long. Too long.
- Tell me. Tell me!
- I want you!
Tell me what to do. Tell me what to do.
Tell me what to do!
No!
I love you so.
[Max Yells]
[Lucia Laughing]
- Shh.
- [Stops Laughing]
My little girl.
[Buzzing]
[Buzzing Continues]
[Buzzing Stops]
No. Nobody's here.
No. He's gone upstairs.
- He has gone up.
- Where?
Well, they called him.
Will he be gone long?
[Chuckles]
Depends on the lady.
- What lady?
- The American.
The American.
The conductor's wife.
Probably wanted to be cheered up.
- And the, the husband?
- He left.
Telegram... from your husband.
If you want to call Frankfurt,
just pick up the phone.
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Whistling Softly]
- What are you doing here?
- Work, Excellency.
- At this time? What are you doing?
- I told you.
Get downstairs.
It all seems lost.
Something unexpected happens.
Ghosts... take shape in the mind.
How can one pull away from it?
This phantom.
The voice and the body.
This part of one's self.
[Man Speaking Latin]
Amen.
[Organ]
Greta doesn't believe
that Mario's death was an accident.
She has consulted Moritz the lawyer,
but I know him. I can speak to him.
Don't speak to anybody.
I want to have a talk
with Greta's doctor.
Let's go.
- Are you sure?
- Yes. Are you leaving right away, Madam?
- Shall I call a taxi?
- Thank you, and a telegram form, please.
Certainly.
Here you are, madam.
[Lucia's Voice]
Can't join you in Berlin either.
Will meet in New York.
please don't worry.
All is well.
- Will you send it right away, please?
- Of course.