They're waitin' for us, Big Max!
You can't catch me.
Hey Unc, he's comin'!
- You're still not ready?
- We're done.
The baglady again?
It's no good?
You've done it 30,000 times.
Do somethin' else.
I've done it lots,
and you always laughed.
We were in stitches at
Aunt Nunziata's birthday party too.
But do somethin' happier.
The baglady's no good anymore?
You're a riot,
we'll love whatever you do.
You rock!
I'm goin' down,
he's already here, move.
Your attention, please,
we're getting ready.
And now, the big moment...
The moment
we've all been waiting for!
Every woman's dream is here.
He lasted 116 days
in the Big Brother House!
He made the finals, and found
his America right here in Italy!
A big welcome to Enzo!
Keep up the applause
for the bride and groom!
Isn't she the most
beautiful bride in the world?
Tell me she's the most
beautiful bride in the world!
Today these kids have crowned
their dream of love.
Like me, when I left home
a long time ago.
My dream came true
and I hope yours do too.
Hold on to your dreams!
Never give up!
You're the best!
Enzo, my love!
Just look, what a chest!
What muscles!
You had hair when
we split up, now it's gone!
I know, it's your brains,
Honey, tell 'em about
when we were together?
Right, you're...
Now I have a steady girlfriend,
not with the same girl now.
- I'll never leave you.
- Give him a big hand I.
You're such a hunk.
What a hunk!
You gotta go on TV,
Luciano my boy.
What's wrong, sweetie?
She wanted Enzo's autograph.
She'll be mopin' all night...
Don't worry, want a photo?
Papa will get you one.
A big hand for the bride and groom!
Look at this beautiful bride.
She's the most beautiful bride
in the world!
Throw your hats in the air, c'mon!
You too down there, everybody!
Be happy,
these kids really deserve it.
Hold on to your dreams!
Could I get a picture of you
and my daughter?
Come on, sweetie, fast.
Like this?
This side here, right?
- How do I turn it on?
- Quick, please.
Your little finger like this.
Look how nice!
- How do I rewind?
- Okay, all set?
Want one too?
- Quick, we're in a rush.
- Take it, honey.
Okay.
- Where's he going?
- Home.
Where's his house?
- Far away?
- I don't know.
What do you want to tell us?
Can we give you
a good night kiss?
We gotta get an elevator in here.
An elevator! We could croak.
Faster, nephew, I can't stand this.
I got pains in my shoulder,
in my back.
Uncle, stop complainin'.
I'll drop you right here,
if you keep yakking.
What a racket climbin' these stairs,
you sound like
you carried Uncle yourselves.
- We're not so young, you know.
- Night, Luciano.
Maria, it's great.
- Like it?
- Yeah.
My daughter has one too.
It does everything.
Pasta, sauce...
It's great, really handy.
Maybe you'll buy one for yourself.
Wish I could,
I like it, it's really great.
Maria, wait,
there's this poor old soul.
- Not this month.
- Just one sec.
Michele!
I brought you Maria.
Go see Luciano at the fish stand
and get on the list.
Wait, how long's the list?
- Not long, he's first.
- He's really hurtin'.
Don't worry.
- Mrs. De Rosa?
- Teresa, they're callin' you.
Yeah, I heard.
- Nothin' yet.
- What?
Carlo, Ma's goin' out, lock the door
and don't let anyone in.
Everybody else got theirs,
I'm surprised you didn't.
Dunno, I never got it.
But Michele explained
once the deposit's sent in,
the robot comes automatically.
If it came, think I wouldn't say?
I almost called you this morning,
'cause I need the money.
And how! It's 100 euro!
Okay, but maybe you gave the
wrong address or you weren't home?
No wrong address.
Gotta run, I'm in a rush.
Mrs. De Rosa!
This is yours?
No, I saw you, ma'am.
Let me serve this lady here first.
One kilo.
Michele, see what Dora wants.
Half a kilo of shrimp for Filomena.
Hello everyone, hi Michele.
Here's yours
and this is for that lady there.
You can pay Michele.
Mrs. De Rosa didn't give me hers.
- What!
- They all gave me theirs.
Except Mrs. De Rosa.
They delivered them all except hers?
The guy's coming for them,
see what you can do.
Michele, get that 10 euro there!
Come here.
Sure, ma'am, don't worry.
Mrs. De Rosa didn't give us hers.
- How come?
- She's someone you brought.
That's strange, she's trustworthy.
Hello, Ma'am,
could we talk a minute?
Just for a minute.
Excuse me.
How come your robot
hasn't come yet?
Sonny, what can I say,
they made a mistake.
The courier says he delivered it.
They must have got mixed up.
- She says they got mixed up.
- Yeah, right.
- I say she's telling the truth.
- I don't believe her.
Have a little faith.
You got your robot too,
the courier delivered to everybody
so you have yours.
They probably
had the wrong address.
My cousin's sure,
so how can we resolve this?
When they bring it...
Do you have this robot
or did you sell it?
When they bring it to me,
I'll bring it to you.
Ma'am, you already have it.
Don't play dumb.
Okay, so let's go
to your house and see.
- We won't find a thing!
- Let's go see.
There's no point.
Got a guilty conscience?
If you have nothing to hide,
humor him.
Let's go outside and talk.
We'll talk outside
and then we'll go see.
Get her outside.
Maybe it's best.
We'll talk it over outside.
Please, do me this favor.
You're making a ruckus,
I'm friggin' fed up.
Luciano, where are you going?
Michele, you tell him!
What can I say?
No, I'm sick of this!
You gotta go, I have things to do.
- Get out!
- The lady's right.
Convinced now?
Thanks for your patience.
It's okay.
Get out, that's it.
Ma, I'm making pastries,
bread too.
I need that for the pastries.
Shame on you, ma'am.
I was wrong.
What happened to that one?
- It doesn't look so good, but...
- Doesn't look so good?
- Just dirt.
- It comes off.
Who can I give this thing to?
- Don't give me 500, just 250.
- No way!
- Don't yell.
- I'm not yelling.
Calm down!
My customers
want these things neat and clean.
Don't want it? Don't take it.
Michele, hold this.
- Pay me for four.
- Always the same old story.
- What can I give 'em now?
- Nothin'.
It's not my fault.
Here's 2,000 euro,
the rest tomorrow.
- We'll see.
- Four plus one...
- Five.
- Even he can count, see?
- Luciano, you always do this stuff.
- No, it's the first time.
The door.
- I'll be back tomorrow.
- I'll call you.
Happy now '2.
- See what you got me into?
- I don't know what to say.
Take it easy.
Forget your pay this week.
Goddammit, jeeze!
I'm job-hunting,
I have a degree in Economics.
- Why Big Brother?
- I may get noticed and become a CEO.
- It's important to dream.
- I agree.
- Next, 562.
- Hi, good evening.
- Name?
- Ambrosanio Roberto.
- What do you do?
- I study Business Administration.
And my passion's techno music.
- And why Big Brother?
- It makes you popular...
There's tryouts for Big Brother.
- Up there.
- Let's go see.
I play soccer.
- What position?
- Forward, in the D league.
From soccer to Big Brother?
Yes, you can earn more.
Not bad,
Thanks a lot, bye.
And now it's...
564.
Enzo!
Good evening.
- Name?
- Mariarca.
- Last name?
- Tagliamonte.
- From Naples, right?
- Near Naples, Portici.
Why Big Brother?
- To be rich and famous.
- Finally someone sincere.
- Lucia what?
- Magnotta.
- Born in...?
- Naples.
- On...?
- 26 March 1935.
- Sign here.
- You'll land me in jail.
- Nothin' will happen.
- What could possibly happen?
We make the first three payments,
nothin' will happen.
What have you got to lose?
My pension.
It's the only thing
they can't take from you.
- It's what I live on.
- Don't worry!
People die of worry!
Excuse me.
Papa?
You gotta come, there's tryouts
for Big Brother, even Enzo's here.
I can't, I'm busy,
I'd love to, honest.
Talk to Martina.
Papa, come on,
these guys can't do a thing.
I don't know, I'm really busy.
Get off the phone!
Put Mommy on, please, I'm busy.
Maria, what should I do?
I'm busy.
Nah, don't come and don't worry,
I'll handle this.
Maria, get him here.
Leave him alone, he's working.
You decide,
what do you wanna do?
What's he say?
Make him come.
Okay.
We'll be waiting, love you.
What did he say?
He's coming.
Let's go over this:
I send the papers to the factory,
they check them,
and send you the robot,
you call us, we pick it up
and give you your money.
How about an advance?
- How?
- Dig in your pocket and pay me.
I can't, I don't have any money.
Don't worry.
Fine, I gotta trust you
but you don't trust me?
If the robot doesn't come
what can I do?
If it comes and you give me nothing?
Do I whack you?
Don't give me the robot.
- I'll crack your skull with the robot.
- Just relax.
Be quick about it.
Don't forget to call us.
Geppina, ma'am, come in.
How are you?
I brought this poor soul,
let's give her a contract.
Geppina, I know you but,
no offense, ma'am...
- Is it okay with her?
- No problem.
She knows how it works?
- Okay, what's your name?
- Tucci Anna.
I'm here, Luciano's here.
- They've worn me out.
- I got held up.
Come here, what's this face?
Maria, I'm leaving,
I've got a headache.
- I'm tired out.
- Three hours.
They took it all down,
you can't audition now.
Why not?
Think I give up that easy?
What's wrong, sweetie?
That's my girl!
Want me to try out?
Can I always
have that smile if I do?
Okay, I'll show you.
Give me a kiss.
Enzo's there.
Be happy, why the long face?
Guys, a little faster please.
Don't push.
Everyone will get a shot.
Remember me, at La Sonrisa?
- No.
- Three weeks ago.
Tatiana, would you...
For my daughter.
Make it fast, guys.
Would you also...
for my son Vincenzo.
Dressed as a drag queen,
I played your girlfriend.
Blue wig... You remember?
Yeah, I remember.
I'm starting to remember.
I came to do a tryout
but it's all packed up.
It's been a crazy day...
You have to talk to the organizers
at that table there
and on the other side.
I don't organize these things,
tryouts were this afternoon,
they don't last all night.
I know, I'm asking a favor.
What can I tell you?
It's for my kids,
you must have a niece or nephew,
you know when they pester you.
Specially Alessandra, look at her,
she pulls your heartstrings.
“Papa, you got here late...
"“Want to bet I get a tryout?"
"“Show me."
Even faking it,
we can put a camera there.
I don't really care.
- Okay?
- Not really.
Get Beppe for me?
Guys, step back a little, it's hot.
Beppe, a favor, for this guy here,
he's good, worth it.
I know, it's breaking the rules,
but if we could audition him.
- Can you?
- If the camera's still around.
- It might be worth it.
- Get on the platform.
Never give up!
What the fuck's that mean?
Bring the camera for an audition.
- Your name again?
- Luciano.
- Last name?
- Ciotola.
- Where are you from?
- Naples.
- What do you do in life?
- I sell fish.
I run a fish stand.
- How come Big Brother?
- My kids pushed me.
If it works out,
so much the better...
Yes, hello, what is it?
Sure, of course.
In Rome? Sure, of course.
When, more or less?
Yes, I can go to Rome.
Alright, thank you.
So you'll let me know.
Okay, fine, goodbye.
They called me from Big Brother,
just now.
We're going to Rome
for an audition.
- Can I come in?
- Ma?
- Hello.
- Hi, Grandma.
I brought sausages
with broccoli, eggplant,
macaroni omelet.
I'll put it all in containers.
You look good, stop.
You've been at this all morning!
Of course, I have to decide
what to wear!
I'll wear my green pants,
you wear your white ones.
- And on top 7
- Something that matches me.
Mary, I don't know.
Wait.
This one's light, if we walk a lot
it won't stick to you
and looks good on you.
- I'm Luciano Ciotola.
- Here to see...?
Beppe Arena.
Have a seat,
we'll take you inside in a moment.
Thank you.
May I sit down?
Follow me, folks, we're going inside.
Where are the auditions?
- Follow me, you'll see.
- Not there.
They're taking me that way,
see you later.
I made a huge one before.
- Well '?
- All set.
I did like you said,
it was good advice.
I told them everything,
even about the past.
I'm still a little...
It was really terrific.
A psychologist helped me,
he began asking me questions...
you wanna know?
I started talking...
- Good for you, well done.
- We'll let you know.
That's the psychologist.
- Which one?
- This short guy here.
He helped me, he pushed me to talk.
You know, when I get going,
there's no holding me back.
The most incredible thing is
everybody else took 5-10 minutes,
and they kept me an hour!
I was awesome!
I said things
I never even told my Pa.
It was really amazing.
I bet they're still talking about me.
They said "Stop, that's just fine".
They looked at me like this.
- Stunned?
- Yeah, like this.
I shocked them.
Let's go, girls.
Papa said he'd do the tryout
and he did, see?
Yes, it was a real live tryout.
I blew them away!
They didn't say so,
but it's a sure thing.
Put Ma on.
You just can't imagine,
I shocked them.
They were stunned,
didn't say a word.
Put Aunt Rosaria on.
Auntie, you can't imagine!
Auntie, you gotta go on TV too!
Congratulations, lots and lots I.
Thanks a million.
Here you go, all the best.
I'm giving fish away today.
Don't worry.
Luciano's crazy this morning,
he's givin' fish away!
- Congratulations, are you happy?
- Thanks.
Did they call?
The call's comin' here,
the call's comin' there...
This is your last coffee
before you're famous.
- You're already in?
- In my head, yeah.
That's all?
I think more than that.
Vittorio, I always believed it.
Me too, but...
I always said, what are you?
- Somethin' else.
- Yeah, really somethin' else.
- And I believe in you.
- Me too.
Doesn't he belong in the House?
Once I'm in, will you organize
a fan club here?
Vittorio,
what did I say this morning?
- Exactly that.
- I'll handle it.
I'll put money on all the phones
so they'll vote for you.
Then see if you remember me.
- I don't wanna serve coffee forever.
- C'mon, Luciano, it's late.
- Hello, can I help you?
- Half a kilo of clams.
- They're squirting!
- They're alive.
Why do you keep them in water?
- To flush 'em out.
- We don't do that in Rome.
- You put 'em in wine?
- No, in nothing.
But they gotta flush out the sand,
clams live in the sea,
they get sandy,
so the water cleans...
- Anything else?
- A small sea bass.
I'm all out, how about
a nice red snapper?
Fresh this morning.
I never found any sand,
the water surprises me.
That's strange!
Hear that Luciano?
In Rome they keep their clams dry.
So, you're from Rome, ma'am?
- Did you weigh it?
- Just a second.
It's 3/4 of a kilo,
let's call it half.
What brings you here?
- Just wondering.
- My husband's from around here.
Naples?
This neighborhood?
Yes.
- It comes to 23.
- We'll make it 20.
- You're giving us a deal?
- Sure.
Well, goodbye and thank you.
- Maybe we'll be back.
- We're right here.
What I don't understand is
they were looking around.
It's like they were up to something,
whispering...
Did they ask questions?
No, I asked the questions.
One said her husband
was from Naples,
from near my fish stand,
but I've never seen them.
When you went to Rome,
did you say you had a fish stand?
Sure.
So they came to see if it's true,
to check.
- Check what '?
- To see what you do.
If you told the truth.
They send people to check you out,
to see if you're telling the truth.
Why me?
Maybe because they liked you.
Why didn't they say
they were from the TV?
Sure, you think they'd come
"We're from the TV."
Listen to your aunt,
she knows everything.
What do you think, Auntie?
What do I think?
That you shouldn't go.
- Yeah, sure...
- What did I say?
Do I have to agree?
I don't like that show.
Watching's one thing,
going on the show's another.
He has a wife and three kids,
you know?
If he wins Big Brother
he's set for life.
No way, he's not used
to all that money,
he'll spend it all partying.
- Think he's an idiot?
- He's responsible.
Auntie, I'd like to have the problem
of spending money.
- Rather than not.
- Right!
I want that problem too,
I'll help you.
It's better having money to spend
than not.
Auntie, different from you,
know how I see it?
A chance that happens
once in a lifetime,
they say luck only knocks once.
It's a chance, I'll try to grab it.
What is it?
Just lookin'? Take a walk.
You gotta leave, shove off.
How about giving me some?
What? Go away...
Are you deaf or something?
Go take a hike.
Still here?
- Don't you hear me when I talk?
- Gimme somethin'.
Get out of here!
Sasé.
Who was that man standing here,
well-dressed, bald?
- Where was he?
- Here.
- Maybe a customer.
- A customer?
I was mean to him,
I shouldn't have been, for 50 cents.
Good, sometimes you reflect right.
You're starting
to understand important things.
Repentance is important,
after doing wrong,
repentance frees the soul.
Yes, but they were watching me,
who knows what they think of me,
what they're saying.
What do you care?
It's easy for you to say,
you're not being checked.
We all are,
we're all being observed I.
Our Lord observes us,
judges us, guides us.
Want to reconcile your conscience?
The next time you meet the poor guy,
give him 5-10 euro.
I made a mistake.
You can always correct a mistake.
Look how she's sleeping.
Lucia, ma'am?
Ma. Am T.
- She woke up.
- Who is it?
This is Luciano, I'm Michele,
for the robot.
We're here to pick it up.
Then you can go back to sleep.
Can I give you a hand, ma'am?
No, I can still manage.
Here it is.
Give me my money.
Better yet, keep it, it's a gift.
Asia?
If you didn't need it,
why did you have me get it?
I need the money,
give me my money.
Hear me?
I don't want to say it again.
Hold on, ma'am.
You're "giving without receiving",
but this is too much.
Give her the money
and take the robot.
- You get more this way.
- No, you gotta give me my money.
- Wait a minute.
- Let's go.
They're checking on us.
- You idiot, you owe me.
- The Finance Police?
Good god!
Thief, give me my money!
- Who ratted on us?
- I don't know, but they did.
- How?
- I don't know!
But they did,
those guys were watching me!
Good lord, Luciano...
what do we do now?
I'm even risking getting on the show.
I'll break your face,
I'm sick of this show!
We might get in trouble
and you're thinking about the show?
It's not nothing,
just think if I get on?
We're set for life,
all our problems solved!
- If you get on!
- I'll get on.
I'll get on that show, mark my words.
C'mon, you've really lost it.
I haven't lost it!
It's a chance, don't you see?
You're making my heart sink.
Tell me this,
you're focused on that show,
how can we get by without
our little trick, just selling fish?
- I thought something else.
- What?
I thought I'd sell the fish stand.
- Don't make me go berserk.
- What's it giving us?
- Money!
- What?
It's not doing good and besides,
I don't want to harp on it,
but once I'm on the show,
let's say I don't win...
when I get out,
with the money we make,
we can buy 1O fish stands,
100 or as many as you like!
Okay, when they call you,
we'll close the fish stand.
How can we, if I'm gone
for two or three months?
We'll close for two or three months,
when you get out, we'll reopen.
But I want to sell it
so we can fix up the house
with the money,
that way we'll look good
in the interviews.
Besides, if you can't
keep fudging things when I'm gone,
how'll you and the kids get by?
Ever since I got this idea,
I feel good inside.
It's our big chance,
we'll solve all our problems.
I never had a goal before,
but since I got this thing,
my head's spinning.
I feel great inside, I feel awesome.
Please don't give up on me.
C'mon.
That's about it,
the fish tanks, the motor,
it turns on back here
and same over here.
The walk-in refrigerator.
I'm happy, but I'm sorry too.
Let's have a coffee.
Don't worry, Michele!
We'll open a bigger fish stand,
I'll let you run it.
Yeah, okay.
- Why did he sell it?
- We all said not to.
Uncle Luciano!
An unknown call.
An unknown call!
Your phone's ringin'!
Your phone's ringin',
an unknown call.
- The phone?
- Yeah, the phone, do I answer?
- No, no.
- Then hurry!
- How long did it ring?
- How do I know?
The time a phone rings.
- Why didn't you answer?
- You said not to!
I thought there was
at least a number.
“Unknown, do I answer?" "No."
- So I didn't.
- You mixed me up.
Yes.
Absolutely not, no problem at all.
Really?
Yay, they took me!
All Naples is celebrating!
Sorry, we're at the beach.
That's exactly why we took you,
you can see from your face...
that you're a real...
moron!
This is Big Brother calling...
I didn't lie,
I really am big brother.
Why are you being such a jerk?
Is that the best you can do?
You know how much I want this!
Don't make such a big deal.
- Is that all you know how to do?
- I was just joking.
Joking? Fuck off!
Don't talk like that.
You're being crude.
You know what it means to him,
you go making jokes?
Enzo?
- Who is it?
- Here, behind the grating.
Hi Enzo,
it's Luciano, remember? - No.
From La Sonrisa,
the mall, the audition, Beppe.
Right.
- What the fuck are you doing there?
- Don't ask, I had to.
- How did you get here?
- The air ducts.
It's okay.
I'm really sorry, but...
I tried another way,
but they wouldn't let me.
- You could have waited outside!
- I just couldn't.
I'm on the john, you have to leave.
Listen, don't tell me I did all this
for nothing.
The show's starting,
but no one's called me.
You scared me just to ask that?
Okay, don't worry,
if they liked you, they'll call.
Even at the last minute,
but they'll call.
- That happened to you?
- Yeah.
They called me at the last minute.
- So, there's still hope?
- Of course there is.
- You have to keep believing.
- I believe plenty.
- I've invested so much.
- You did good.
Keep believing, always believe.
- So there's hope right to the end?
- Sure.
You don't know
what a weight you've lifted, thanks.
- Never give up.
- Sorry for barging in like this.
- What do we say?
- Never give up!
Fuck off...
Security!
Don't you check the dressing rooms?
Let him talk.
Guys, this is a dream come true.
The evening's just begun,
it's going to be quite a night.
Let's see how they're doing.
Guys, can you hear me?
You're right to be happy because
you're the contestants
on the new Big Brother show.
Let's let them enjoy this moment
while I give you some big news:
The surprises are not over yet,
in fact, next week, on Big Brother,
another two contestants will join.
With incredible, moving stories.
People with incredible stories,
that's you!
He. S in!
Here we go again!
Luciano's not going in, get it?
He's already messed up enough!
- Calm down!
- Calm down?
Don't get so upset, Maria.
Why not, she's right, isn't she?
- What, you think she's wrong?
- Stop!
You're his ma, you should ask him
what the heck he's doing.
- I want to see him happy.
- Yeah, happy on the street.
Take it easy.
- Look what a mess you made!
- Cut it out.
I gotta cut it out?
Where have you been?
Come have a coffee.
- No, thanks.
- All your friends are here.
- I'm busy.
- Just a minute, for your friends.
I looked for you in the House,
but I didn't see you.
Where were you, in a drawer?
They'll take you for sure.
Yeah, they'll reel you in!
Don't listen to them.
You're the best, if they don't
choose you, the show's over.
I'm sure of it.
Let's hope so.
Hi.
Want something to eat?
Don't be scared.
Ciro, give him something
to eat, okay?
What do you want?
- Some pizza?
- Give him this, and this...
This and more pizza.
And something to drink too.
- Give him a big one.
- You're sure?
Over here, eat.
Give him something to drink too.
This makes three, Vittorio.
Can you give him something to drink?
Brandy.
Give him some. What else?
Ciro, that bottle over there,
and this one here.
C'mon.
- I'm paying, Vittorio.
- Sure.
Don't worry Ciro.
Get another bottle.
And more pizza, more pastries.
Give him more pastries.
- More pizza?
- No, I'm all set.
Have a pastry.
This one.
Luciano, if he gets drunk,
you're taking him home.
Don't worry, he's my guest.
I'm so happy to see you!
That's my stuff!
Give me that, give me that lamp!
Come here!
Luciano, what are you doing?
Here, these are for you.
- What are you doing?
- It's okay.
- Okay?
- Just a little charity for the poor.
You're crazy!
Giving away our stuff
after all we've sacrificed!
- Put that down I.
- It'll all come back to us...
- Not once, but a hundredfold!
- No, not that chair, no!
Leave it there!
Put my chair down!
What's wrong, are you crazy?
- What are you doing?
- They're giving me a last chance.
Who?
The people from the show,
they said a hotshot's going in.
That's me, they're watching me,
trust me.
That's it! Understand?
I let you do all sorts of things,
but this is it!
You're sick in the head,
you need help.
You think TV's wasting time and money
on an fool like you?
Stop it, you're sick.
Give it to me!
Somethin' for me?
So you still don't get it.
Go, and don't come back.
You liked all that free stuff?
Go get a job!
Get out of here, and fast!
What are you looking at?
That's the one who got my lamp.
I'll give you something, alright I.
Hey, what's going on?
Don't listen to her, come back.
Get out!
Come back!
Get out of here!
Can't you see
they're sending them to me?
Sending them to you?
Excuse me, could you tell the TV
to stop sending you?
Don't be funny!
Will you get a grip?
It's all in your head, wake up I
I don't need to get a grip,
it's like I'm telling you.
What's the matter?
You gotta help me, he's lost it.
He has this thing
about the TV spying on him
so he's giving people our stuff.
She's lying! Sure, I gave
some things to the poor,
just a little charity.
Now look what she goes inventing!
So now I'm a liar?
- Just a little charity.
- Don't you start saying that too.
He thinks the TV's spying on him
so he's giving away our stuff
to make himself seem...
he's driving me nuts!
You don't understand me,
if that's what you think.
- You don't understand me at all.
- What's to understand '?
You're doing this
because you want to ruin me,
but I won't let you.
Then why's she inventing all this?
Calm down.
I'm not coming back, it's over.
- Go then, if you want to ruin me.
- Hear that?
I said go, if you want to ruin me.
She wants to ruin me,
but I won't let her.
Come down here, talk to her.
Everything okay?
Forget about her.
That's the way she is, sorry...
Come on in.
Something to drink?
Uncle Luciano?
Still not ready? Get moving.
Come here.
Look.
- What's that?
- A cricket.
Look how it moves!
Come and see, Auntie.
Look at that.
Do you think it's normal
having a cricket in here?
I've never seen one inside the house.
How'd it get in here?
From the window.
Right, but did you ever see a cricket
in this house, or anywhere here?
- Not me.
- Never inside.
And so, it's strange.
Let's open the window
and let it out.
A waste of time, it's not leaving.
Let's go, it's late.
I'll catch up with you.
- He's not coming?
- He'll be here.
Excuse me, ladies,
I can't go on like this.
This is getting to be too much.
- What's the matter?
- Just tell me, yes or no.
I keep giving things away, but still
no call about getting into the House.
What call?
If I have to do more,
just tell me and I'll do it.
What should I do?
Be patient, don't rush things.
I have plenty of patience,
it's just that I've invested
everything to get into the House.
Only death has no remedy,
everything else works out.
- You want to get into that house?
- Yes.
- Then you will.
- You say so?
Surely, you need to have
faith and hope.
Don't worry.
- You say I have to go on like this?
- Of course.
Don't worry.
Good luck.
Auntie.
Don't just stand there,
let's go down and see Unc.
Why are you looking at me like that?
Is he eating?
Not much.
He's parked in front of the TV
night and day.
He's depressed.
It's useless beating around the bush,
you love him
or else you wouldn't be here.
You came because you want to be here.
Yeah, he matters to me.
This won't last,
things like this never do.
He'll get up from the TV
and you have to be here.
Don't jump on him when he talks,
let it go in one ear
and out the other, okay?
Then come up here
and let him talk to himself.
He needs you.
She'll go 1.
Let's get going.
Give us a smile.
Look at these nice fritters,
he loves them.
Are they hot?
Let's go.
Luciano, there's a surprise for you.
Come and see who's here.
So, he's kept giving away stuff?
Luciano!
- Maria! How is he?
- He's at home.
It was a real blow.
But he's tough, he'll get over it,
have him come see us.
- Hi, how are you?
- Can't complain.
- Coffee?
- No thanks, I'm in a hurry.
Say hi to Luciano.
How is he doing?
He's doing therapy,
little by little...
I could tell he was losing his mind.
Losing his mind?
Careful what you say!
He's just a little down,
he hasn't lost his mind.
He'll get better
seeing a psychologist.
What psychologist?
A doctor! It's different.
Say hi, tell him I'll come visit.
Don't worry, he'll come see you.
Bye.
It's official, he's lost it.
Look how he moves!
- See him?
- Yeah, he's dancing.
Ever see me dance?
Isn't that my dancing?
- You're saying it's just like that?
- That's my dance!
You can't be
the only one who dances like that.
Look how he moves, those steps!
Ever seen me dance?
Did you invent that dance?
Remember when
I went for the tryouts?
The things I said,
know what they did, those bastards?
They took what's me
and gave it to them.
So, they stole your ideas.
- You don't believe me?
- Could be.
But you're overdoing it.
You're all against me now,
just because I went a little off.
Why don't you believe me?
You weren't at the tryout,
I'm the only one
who knows what I said.
I'm willing to believe you,
but you're overdoing it.
- You're willing!
- What do you care?
You've got this nice family,
a wife, kids...
You're hurting them, they see you
sprawled on this couch all day.
It hurts me hard.
It hurts that they copied me.
You don't care, but I do.
I don't care
if you believe me or not.
What we care about is you.
And I care about all of you, so?
What can I say?
He's a little depressed.
It might be the medication.
It's not the medication,
it's Luciano who's changed.
Laying on that couch night and day.
- What does the doctor say 7
- That it's the Big Brother shock!
“Be patient,
"when the show's over,
your husband will recover."
So, it won't last forever.
I don't believe that anymore.
I can't take it, I'm really down.
I know.
I've tried everything,
I confront him, he gets aggressive,
I go along with him and it's worse.
I don't know what else to do.
Don't take it so hard.
I can't do this anymore.
- I'm scared.
- Hush...
I'm scared!
What if he stays like this?
Don't even say that.
I know someone who could help.
He's always comforted me
in hard times.
I'll talk to him.
Luciano has to feel our love,
love always triumphs.
Today we'll read a powerful
passage from the New Testament.
Here Jesus asks us
to understand ourselves,
to understand the difference
between being and seeming,
between what's true and false.
This is the only way
to understand our limits,
our capabilities.
If we don't know ourselves,
we'll never have the strength
to face life.
But if we learn these things,
we get closer to ourselves.
Often, we run after appearances
and lose ourselves,
and that's not good.
It's not by chance
that someone
knocked at our door today,
a friend of ours
who's having a tough time.
He's asked for our help,
to be part of our community.
He's a richness for us.
We'll help and sustain him.
- Bread.
- Meatballs too.
Meatballs!
- Another slice of chicken?
- Alright.
- Hi, Luciano.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Fine.
- More?
- Just a little.
Pasta? Michele, give him some.
Give that woman some chicken.
Cheese.
Papa, when will you be back?
When will I be back?
Tomorrow.
Come here.
See you tomorrow.
Be good kids.
Your jacket.
Thank you, honey.
- Bye, see you tomorrow.
- Don't worry.