Tonight on the Marriage Ref...
Martin short.
Hey!
You've got to be sensitive
to your wife's needs.
And in my case,
Make sure your personal
assistant fulfills them,
But that's me.
Sarah Silverman.
When you're in love,
You have to support
each other's passions,
And she should support
his love of lord of the rings.
He should support
her love of diet pills
Or whatever her hobby is.
And Matthew Broderick.
Something about this whole thing
is wrong.
One's fizzy, one's dizzy, one's busy,
And they all get mixed together tonight.
You bastard.
It's not a competition.
You're a sex maniac.
This has gotta stop.
He's not a boyfriend!
He's a friend that's a boy.
You look incredibly sexy
right now.
Thank you.
Plus a surprise,
one of the stars
Of late night
comedy controversy.
Now here's the marriage ref,
Tom Papa.
Welcome to The Marriage Ref,
I'm Tom Papa.
Tonight we're gonna watch real couples
with real-life arguments,
And we're gonna give them
the one thing
They've always wanted--
A winner.
So the way we do this
is we watch each couple,
I discuss the issue
with the panel,
They try and sway me
In favor of the husband
or the wife,
And then I make the call.
All right, first up,
Let's traverse
the thrilling nautical skyway
Of the Chesapeake Bay
bridge-tunnel
On our way
to Colonial Abingdon, Maryland,
Where we meet the Arringtons,
Who are trying to sort out a...
Scheduling conflict.
When I first met my wife, tee,
I was just really kind of
captivated by her eyes,
And then I wound up
asking her for a phone number.
It's like, I just knew,
I was like,
"that's gonna be my man."
It's like you got energy
For everything else
that's going on,
But you don't have
any energy for me.
You a sex maniac.
I could be dead asleep.
"wake up. Mmm!
Got something for you."
I'm trying to get ready
to get out of the house,
And you talkin' about
you got something for me.
Babe, if I don't
take those opportunities,
It's not happening.
I could be sick...
I mean, sick.
No.
What is it like?
Like you're retired
to, like, the barn,
You don't come out
running with us anymore?
What is it?
It's like, why even try?
So I go down there
and play video games
And play call of duty,
Because I'm not playing
call of Booty.
All I'm looking for
is some consistency.
But it seems
like consistency--
- I was consistent
with once a week.
That's four time a month!
Come on!
The bible, it says that,
"woman love your husband."
love.
It didn't say "have sex
with your husband
All the time, three, four,
five times a week."
When was the last time
You bought me
a purse or something?
That was when
we were in Atlantic city.
But you got sex [indistinct].
- Yeah!
- Okay.
So in other words,
we have to equate
Me buying you stuff with sex?
- Shopping--if you're bringing
me gifts or something I enjoy,
Sex is what you enjoy.
Step up to the plate
a couple of more times,
And, you know...
I think I step up to the plate.
Babe, if you was in baseball,
They would have you
in the minors.
Wow!
Okay, the Arringtons.
The issue here is...
Well, I think we all know
what the issue is.
Some people want things,
Some people have things,
Some people want things
that other people have,
And some people
just want you to get that thing
Away from them.
I think it's very dangerous,
Because you've got to make sure
That the bedroom
activities, um,
Are an important part
of the marriage,
And they've gotta get
that equation going.
I don't know
why I did that, but...
- It's the testicles.
- Yeah.
'cause that's what it is.
But they gotta figure that out.
One time a week
does not seem enough.
And, um...
I don't think it's enough.
Right.
Thoughts, Sarah?
I don't know, Tom.
It's a real quandary.
Yeah.
That hooked on phonics really
worked for you, didn't it?
I think that sex is important.
If she's not feeling sexual...
Right.
There are other ways...
She can help him in other ways,
Even if she isn't--
- You're losin' me.
What do you mean?
Like, okay, give me an example.
She could give him a hand.
Wow!
Very elegant.
She mentions
the bible at one point.
Uh, Natalie, what does
the bible say
About marital relations?
Oh, lord.
The bible says...
"this at last
is bone of my bone
"and flesh of my flesh.
"she shall be called 'woman, '
"and the man and his wife
were both naked
And were not ashamed."
No wonder they keep one
in every hotel room.
Okay.
There are some tools here
that Therman has,
Which I don't think he's using.
I mean, there is
a romance element to this.
You can't just sit there
and ask for it.
I mean, look right here.
Halfway through that mini-bar,
He could start giving her
handbags she already has.
Yeah.
"Uhh! Got
somethin' for you."
What about the romance?
Don't you think a guy
should be a little, well...
Little touches,
a little something,
Rather than just,
"hey, hey, hey."
It's nice to give, um,
You know, someone a gift
like a purse,
But it shouldn't be
like a payment.
Right.
That makes me crazy.
I don't like that with women.
This has gotta stop.
Yeah.
- This, "buy me--
buy me something."
It's embarrassing.
Yeah.
Buy me something.
You're right.
It was like some sort of
sex-for-handbag hostage swap.
Is that asking
too much, Matthew?
Well, she might mean
be more generous in some way.
True.
You know, it was not exactly,
"if you buy a handbag
of this value,
I will perform the following
one of two options."
right.
- It--I think it's more,
you know,
"be romantic with me."
That would be
the nice way to look at it,
And it's possible
that's what she means.
She might--although,
she might just mean,
"pay this amount
and I'll give in."
- But I must admit--
But it did sound a little
like bartering, you know?
- It did.
- "I got the purse,
You got some love-makin'."
You look incredibly sexy
right now.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
But in her defense,
If his idea
of romantic seduction
Is, "uhh! Got somethin'
for you."
Right.
- That's what my fed-ex guy
says to me.
And he comes
more than once a week.
Line of the week!
That's in the promo.
So what do you think,
panelists?
Who do you think I call it for?
Marty?
Oh, I'd say you
call it for the, um, husband,
Because I think that
the attitude's wrong,
The amount is wrong...
- Uh-huh.
For the husband. Sarah?
If I may, I'd like
to call it a draw, Tom,
Because I feel that--
You know, sex is an important
part of a relationship.
That should be respected.
But at the same time,
He need to learn what gets her,
You know, in the mood for sex,
Or at least in the mood
to want to satisfy him
If she isn't going to be.
Right. That's a good point.
I like that point.
Very clever.
Matthew?
I think Sarah put it
much better than Martin,
First of all.
And...And, um...
You bastard.
It's not a competition.
Yeah, I feel it would be
awkward to say he's right.
I'm not comfortable with that.
Tom? Tom? Tom?
Yes, Marty?
- I'd like to change my vote.
- No. Okay.
- I think it's very hard--
I don't envy you, dude.
I don't think
that it's an easy one.
Well, thank you
for all of that, panel.
But I think I am ready
to make the call.
Let's go to Abingdon, Maryland,
And say hello
to the actual Arringtons
In their actual home.
Arringtons!
Hey!
Hello.
You guys look great.
Thanks for being on our show.
You havin' a good time so far?
Yes, yes, yes.
Yes, a wonderful time,
thank you.
Guys, my call is this.
Therman, you got
a great personality.
You got a beautiful wife.
I'm on your side,
But what I need you to do
is stop by a florist
And just stand on the street,
Stare in the window,
Watch the people come and go.
You and I both know no one
needs flowers to live,
So the question is,
Why is this a business?
Why is the candy store so busy?
Why do romantic restaurants
take dinner reservations?
Tee, you win.
Wow!
You understand
what I'm saying, therman?
Tom, I was
trying to say something.
Tom, I was doing this
for every guy out there.
You know, it starts off
at three and two and one.
I'm just trying
to keep it consistent
Before it goes to none
and I fade away to dust.
Okay, how about
you be consistent, too?
See, that's an example.
"consistency,"
not a romantic word.
That's something you want
from your appliances.
Exactly, consistency, yeah.
I don't mean
you should go crazy.
How about a t-shirt
with a tuxedo on it?
I do all those things, Tom.
Oh, not consistently.
- Bye-bye.
Coming up, another man.
Is he a friend?
Is he a boy?
He's not a boyfriend!
He's a friend that's a boy!
Something about
this whole thing is wrong.
- Next, we choo-choo
into Chesterland, Ohio,
Near the sparkling shores
of Lake Erie,
To meet the Arkenbergs,
Amber and Guy...
And some other guy.
My girlfriend and I
went to this pub,
And he was there.
And we saw each other,
And it was love at first sight.
- My first--
I was in love with--
It was love at first sight.
I knew I was gonna marry him.
It's been blissful ever since.
Blissful?
Matt is
like a girlfriend, okay?
He's like having a girlfriend.
- But Matt's a guy.
- So what?
- Do you realize
you having a boyfriend--
- It's not a boyfriend!
He's a friend that's a boy!
But it is a boy.
He's a--
all right, your man friend.
How's that?
Your man friend.
There are different kinds
of guys, okay?
There's guy's guy.
Guys like you.
Matt is not like that.
I've always been
better friends with women,
And I've always
been a good listener.
I can understand
their problems,
And I love women,
so I like to talk to 'em.
He has more shoes in his closet
Than I could ever, ever afford.
But that's beside the point.
He wears pink,
he loves clothes.
- But you're not underst--
- We relate.
Look, when I met him,
he told me what a stud he was.
He showed me pictures
on his phone
Of all these women
that he's either dating
Or playing
around with right now,
And so I can't understand
how he could be such a stud
And not have any intentions
toward my gorgeous wife.
I can be friends with a woman,
And it's not my objective
to sleep with her.
2012, when
all the planets align,
You know,
something could happen.
If you go to the barbershop
enough times,
You're gonna get your hair cut.
Wow.
The first thing I want to say
To Mr. And Mrs. Arkenberg,
Put the knives down!
So the issue here,
Is it okay for Amber
to have this guy
For a man friend?
What do you think?
I think that jealous people
Are people who can see it
in their own lives to cheat.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
Very interesting.
I don't think people
who would never think to cheat
Are jealous people.
But I see what he's up to.
He's like, "oh, I like clothes.
I like pink shoes."
He's a double Agent.
Sarah, do you feel like
you control those relationships
When you're
just friends with a guy?
Do you feel like it's up to you
If this is gonna turn
sexual or not?
No, I've never considered
Any of my guy friends to be...
Lovers.
But I--when
I'm dating somebody,
I don't see anybody else
in a sexual way.
- Right, but...
- And if--
You know, if you have
a roving eye,
You might be more prone
to be jealous.
Right.
- But, you know,
don't you think--
And then I want to hear
from matth--
But don't you think that...
Don't you think that
Even if it's not about sex,
If it upsets him...
Right.
Then she should be
responsive to that?
I mean, how fascinating
is this, um, guy?
So he toured in Annie once.
Big deal.
Let me point out a couple
of interesting items here
That I didn't like.
Drinking in the afternoon,
Maxed-out porn phone,
And an unaffiliated sideburn.
A sideburn with no head of hair
To explain where it comes from.
Is it part of the beard?
Is it part of the scalp?
Who do you belong to?
So if your boyfriend
had a best friend
Who was a woman,
And they spent
a lot of time with each other,
And let's just say
she was bald with one sideburn,
Would that be a problem
for you?
No. I mean, no.
I mean, Natalie, how many times
Does an average male
have a sexual thought?
- Well, the Kinsey institute
says 52--
Every 52 seconds.
- 52 seconds?
- Yes.
All right, and how long
Is your average happy hour
at a bar?
Two hours.
- Two hours?
- Yeah.
So that's a minimum
of 120 times
That this guy's thinking
about leaping out of his chair
On top of this woman.
And now--and now,
soak his brain
In what looks like 52 ounces
of afternoon alcohol.
You can see why this husband's
a little concerned.
Yeah.
How long has she known
the new gentleman?
They're
old High School friends,
To answer your question,
But they re-connected
on Facebook just two years ago.
Oh.
Oh!
Everybody goes
back on Facebook,
And they're like, "oh, remember,
I had a crush on you
In third grade."
Do they ever do things
all three of them,
Or she only sees him
separately?
Like are there--
are they, uh...
You know, they ever go
to those things
That three people go to?
What is that?
Don't know what that would be.
What is that thing?
Like sack races, or...?
Yeah.
You know, at a carnival.
- Three-legged race
with each leg tied up.
So anyway...
But you know what I mean?
Do they cross-friend?
Are they friends?
Is he friends with him, too?
Um, it's more Amber and mat
They like to shop together,
Take pictures together.
They like to take
pictures together.
- Not together.
- What does that mean?
- She's a photographer.
- Yes.
And he's like,
"take a look at this."
All right, let's take a break.
Stay with us.
Coming up, this TV series
Gets even weirder.
I'm very puzzled
about these people.
I know. If I could
just call on some guy
To help me out right now.
All right, we're back
with the Arkenbergs,
Amber and Guy.
Then answer me this then.
Then if I can
go on the computer
And I'll try to reconnect with
some of my old girls that--
- Just to prove a point,
You're gonna go
and try to find girlfriends?
No, I'll go try to reconnect
with some of the girls
I was friends with
in High School,
And you would be okay
with me--
- And they'll be going,
"I remember Guy.
"he was student council
president.
"he was the hottest guy
in the school.
Hell yeah,
I'll hook up with you."
That was in junior high
When I was
student council president.
All right, Matthew,
I'm gonna put you
on the spot first.
I'm very puzzled
about these people.
I know.
Something about this
whole thing is wrong.
It feels wrong, that's what
the husband's feeling.
The husband thinks it's wrong.
You're getting
heavily into this.
Yeah, the husband is right
to be concerned.
Okay, husband.
Sarah?
- She should support--
If he likes something,
she should support it.
Well, she likes this guy,
she likes hanging out with him.
She wouldn't be hanging out
with him out in the open
If there was something
Shady going on.
It would be, like,
secret text messages and stuff.
But she's open book,
and it's her friend.
Good point.
I like that, Sarah.
- And I want to change.
- You want to change?
- Yeah.
- I'll let you change.
- You want to change?
- You can change.
- That sounded good to me.
- That sounded good to you?
Okay, let's see what
he sounds like to you.
I might change again.
Let me see.
Martin?
- I would say 100%--
There's no real question
to this--
100% on the husband's side.
Because "a,"
it's inappropriate.
And it doesn't even matter
if there's hanky-panky,
And there could be.
But if it doesn't
make him comfortable,
Then she should respect that
more than anything and say,
"honey, you know,
I don't agree with you,
"but there's two men here
and I love you,
"and I want to keep you happy.
And I hope you'll return
the favor to me someday."
So of course
I'm on the husband's side.
All right.
So--
I don't think it's healthy
to tell your spouse
Who they can
and can't hang out with.
Okay, all right.
All right, all right.
I have to say, I mean,
we have a husband,
We have a wife,
we have a husband/wife.
I really wish there was
one more opinion.
Someone who's been
through the fires,
Been through the wars,
and still standing tall.
If I could just call
on some guy like that
To help me out right now.
Whoa.
How are you?
Jay.
How are you, buddy?
How are you?
Thank you, thank you.
I was passing by,
and I heard the argument.
Wow.
What are you doing here?
You know, I'm watching this.
And I think back
to when I was single
And I was working comedy clubs.
Right.
And I had a friend
who was a stripper
Named silver moon.
Now silver moon was my friend.
We never had a relationship,
And I would go to her
for guidance
And ask her questions.
Right.
My wife tended to frown
on silver moon.
So we are no longer friends.
Right.
- And so I gotta go--
see, watching this,
Here's a guy, he says,
"my beautiful wife."
He's jealous.
How many guys married 18 years
Hope their wife
get hit by a bus?
Here's a guy--
You know, here's a guy,
he's jealous.
He's still in love,
and he gets jealous.
So I say, "okay."
And I'm not saying
you have to tell them
Who they can and can't be with,
But if I was the wife
I would respect the wishes
And go, "you know, if it makes
you that uncomfortable..."
- Right.
- Side with the guy.
All right, side with the guy.
Let me know how this
10:00 spot works out for you.
I'd be curious.
Yeah.
It feels kinda comfortable.
- Yeah, yeah.
- I like it.
I think I'm ready
to make the call
With the help
of my friends here.
Let's go to Chesterland, Ohio,
and bring up
The real Arkenbergs
in their real-life living abode.
How you guys doing?
Good. How are you?
Good.
Are you alone?
May I speak freely?
Yeah, we shipped the kids out
till later on this evening.
Okay, wasn't talking
about the kids.
- No boyfriend here.
- Yeah.
I was talking about
your own silver moon.
No silver moons here.
I gotta say when I look at you,
I see a woman that loves
her husband obviously.
I see a woman
that can be trusted.
I see a happy family,
a blissful, fulfilling homelife.
When I see your man friend,
I see a bald, rogue-sideburned
homewrecker.
The dude's gotta go.
You win.
Thank you, thank you,
thank you.
Thank you very much.
We'll see you guys around.
Thank you to Jay Leno,
everybody.
Thank you.
Coming up, manscaping--
Where do you shave the line?
- I don't shave my chest.
- Yes, you do.
I trim, I buzz.
He straightens each strand.
I think he should let
his freak flag fly.
Okay, let's let our sails out
And catamaran
into the shimmering shores
Of Lake Ronkonkoma, New York,
To see what's percolating
with the d'amores.
Debbie and I
met in High School.
37 years we've been together.
You still look 17.
Oh, stop.
- Do I look nice today?
- You look gorgeous.
Why do I have to ask you?
I thought we were
talking about me.
- I'll have a cup of decaf.
- Decaf. Okay, would you--
- But I only want it
if it's freshly brewed
In the last 20 minutes.
I got a new one just for you.
- You do? I'll know.
- All right.
What time
did you brew that pot?
I usually brew a fresh one
at 3:00 when I come in.
Now you want me to drink
from that 3:00 pot?
It's 4:30.
When you pour the milk in,
it's supposed to turn--
Like, it's supposed--
You don't even have to take
a spoon to it.
It's like a good haircut.
I apologize.
Because you didn't
have to hear all that.
All she coulda said to you was,
"can I have a cup of freshly
brewed decaf coffee, please?"
- Listen, you know--
did I bother you?
What's ever good for you.
I'm here to accommodate you.
- Okay, then just bring me
a fresh pot of--
- You know what,
I want a fresh cup of decaf.
Okay, sir.
Do you know
how much it costs them
To brew a pot of decaf?
Three cents.
I'm not worth three cents?
Oh, my God.
See? You see it?
Look.
Mario, look.
It doesn't, like--
it doesn't swirl.
It just sits.
Very, very sad to me.
I need a good two hours, Debbie.
You know that.
Why does it take you two hours?
What is going on
in that bathroom?
- You know, it's the hair.
- I want to come in and watch.
No.
I don't shave my chest.
Yes, you do.
I trim, I buzz.
I buzz.
It looks horrible.
- No, it--no, it doesn't.
To whom?
To who's looking at it, me.
Mario, what are you doing?
I have to blow out my hair.
I have to finish shaving.
I have no cologne on.
I didn't exfoliate.
I have to shave, I shave,
then I take a shower.
Then I come out
and I shave again.
You look good, you feel good.
I feel like [bleep].
- Whoo-hoo!
Well, I think
we're clear on that.
These are two classic
problem areas for couples--
Restaurants and bathrooms.
What do you think?
Coffee, you know,
that's been heating
For more than 20 minutes
doesn't--I agree with her.
Oh, really?
Yeah, and I'm not afraid
To go into a lengthy discussion
About it at a restaurant.
He's going like this.
And, you know, there's
a whole world out there.
So I think that he should--
he should relax.
Natalie,
does Debbie have a point?
How long does coffee
stay fresh in a pot?
Debbie and Matthew
have a good point.
Decaf coffee sitting in a pot
actually goes bad
After about 30 minutes.
Or as she would say,
"30 minutes."
I had an Uncle that used
to gesture like this.
I'll tell you,
I got three reasons
Why that's a bad idea.
Well, I have a feeling that
he has very Curly body hair.
Right.
That he straightens
each strand.
I'm Italian.
I'm hairy.
Underneath this, there's a lot
of nastiness going on.
But two hours?
I mean, in your own home too.
When I have to trim up,
I do it in a hotel.
I'm not gonna make a mess
in my own home.
We have two issues.
Yeah.
We have the coffee.
We have the bathroom.
Which way do you wanna go?
You can split your vote
if you want.
Well, I would say the coffee,
Absolutely, she has a right
to have fresh coffee.
And when it comes
to the bathroom,
He's spending
too much time in there.
What do you got, Sarah?
I agree that the coffee,
You should be able to order
the coffee the way you want,
And--but she could maybe
be nicer about it.
Not that she was rude,
but you know how you do
That, like, apology thing like,
"I'm so sorry, but I just really
like my decaf really fresh.
And I know I'm being awful,
but would you mind--"
You know what I mean, like--
and then--
oh, thank you.
Very good.
And the bathroom, um,
I feel that bathroom time
is private time,
And he can have that
if he wants it.
Okay.
Matthew?
- I think the coffee--
I see she could probably
be a little, you know--
She could be quicker
in saying what she--
She probably didn't
have to explain
The whole reason
to the waiter, maybe.
But I think she should order
however she wants
And whatever she wants.
I side with her.
- Uh-huh.
Bathroom, he should take
as long as he wants.
She should be happy he's gone
for a few hours, right?
All right, I'm ready
to make the call.
Let's meet the actual d'amores
In their bellissima
Lake Ronkonkoma villa.
D'amores, how are you?
We're great.
Thank you.
- Can I please speak?
- Go ahead.
Do you like it better if I say,
"can I please have
a cup of decaf,
But I want it freshly brewed."
Then she brings it, I know
it's more than 20 minutes old,
And I say,
"bring it back."
Is that better?
That's not better.
It's a little better.
Why does Debbie go into
this long speech
About ordering coffee?
Just say, "I'd like a cup
of freshly brewed decaf."
- That's what I said.
- Why put time on it?
If it's not fresh...
I'll know if it's 21 minutes.
When you put the milk in...
Yeah?
It turns by itself.
I don't care what you say.
It's almost poetry,
okay, the way it turns.
Just keep it short.
Decaf, fresh, the end.
Okay, all right,
you're kinda piling on Debbie
A little bit there, but, Mario,
How many times
did you shave today?
Oh.
Mario was up at--wide-eyed--
5:30 A.M.,
I kid you not.
You know what, I think
I'm ready to make the call.
Debbie, in a restaurant,
you're entitled--
You're entitled to get
your coffee the way you want.
But you know what,
I can't take the suspicions,
The accusations,
the "I'll knows."
"I'll know."
I was a waiter.
Just order the coffee
and drink it.
Mario, you win that one.
Wow.
- Mario, two hours in--
Two hours in the bathroom.
The entire cast of avatar
got ready in an hour.
If you're not coming out of
there blue and 15 feet tall,
You're taking too much time.
You're a man.
45 minutes--that's it,
or we're coming in.
Debbie, you win that one.
Whoo!
No.
So...
So what we have here is a tie.
The good news is I have
a way to break that tie.
With this.
Coming up, male exotic dancing.
Well, what he did on the screen
Is outlawed
in about seven States.
All right, Mario's won one.
Debbie's won one.
And here is the tie-breaker.
I believe wholeheartedly
In being an individual.
He's an individual.
He wants to country line dance.
I don't understand
why he doesn't want
To country line dance with me.
If I'm gonna
country line dance,
I will.
- What happened, Debbie?
- Nothing.
♪ I was at a dance ♪
♪ when he caught my eye ♪
♪ standing all alone ♪
When we first got married
and we didn't have children,
There wasn't anything
we didn't do together.
♪ ♪
Do I love
my country line dancing?
Absolutely.
Debbie and I
have hobbies together
And separately.
And it's those separate things
That are very important to me.
♪ blame it on the bossa nova ♪
♪ the dance of love ♪
♪ that he did so well ♪
♪ ♪
♪ blame it on the bossa nova ♪
See, I earn my keep.
So should he be allowed
to do this on his own or not?
Well, what he did on the screen
Is outlawed
in about seven States.
That is line dancing
as done by miss Liza Minnelli.
So I--
Country line dancing.
"country Liza" it's called.
What country?
What country is that?
Brazil during carnivale, 1968?
Well, Sarah,
what'd you think, baby?
Is she dying so much
to line dance?
Yeah, that's a good point.
She didn't even say
she liked it.
She doesn't look like she's
really itching to get out there.
She's itching a lot,
but not itching to get out.
- I like how she does this.
- She's itching a little.
Do you dance, Matthew?
Yeah, once in a while.
Oh, you're a good dancer.
Don't be modest.
Every once in a while
on Broadway.
Yeah.
Bravo!
Thank you for that.
He, uh, danced in two musicals,
And he won two Tonys for them.
Bravo!
Thank you again.
Yeah, he should be allowed
to line dance all he wants.
- He should be allowed to dance?
- Yeah.
Natalie, do we have
any facts on this guy?
Um, you know, they used
to tap dance together
Back in the day,
so this is just--
He's evolved.
All right, I think I know
which way you're leaning,
But, Matthew, you say?
I say dance away.
Dance away.
Sarah?
I think he should let
his freak flag fly.
I say let him dance.
- Let him dance.
- Yeah.
All right,
let's bring them back up.
Whoo!
Debbie, you say you want
to go with him
And meet his friends and stuff,
But the look on your face
tells me you'd rather
Stay at home with a nice,
hot, fresh cup of decaf
Just swirling away.
So I have to give this one
to Mario,
Because when I see him
dancing in the kitchen,
I see the happiest man
I've ever seen in my life.
Mario...
Two out of three.
You win.
Yay!
Whoo!
I think you guys are great.
Debbie, we love you.
- No, you don't.
- I do.
Debbie, I see you,
I see every aunt
That has ever given me
a big hug at Christmas.
This isn't one of those shows
where we make people
Feel better
and try and fix things.
Two out of three.
He wins.
And you know what,
if you really want to get
That coffee swirling,
start the music,
Let Mario hold the pot,
Watch that cream go 'round
like a Kansas twister.
You guys are awesome.
Awesome!
Next, we're going to go
deep into middle earth
And see what's down there.
Coming up, the panel fights
To keep from becoming
completely incoherent.
Diet pills.
She's got a kinda
Celine Dion thing going.
He seemed to have such
a sweet feeling
About those toys.
I think they should
get divorced.
And this month's selection
From the marriage ref
book club--
The bedwetter
by Sarah Silverman,
A poignant, embarrassing memoir
Of a young girl's life.
And there's no real book club.
All right,
next we're gonna amble
Into the heart
of hometown Americana--
Washington township,
new Jersey,
And meet the Hamiltons
Where husband Ash is lost
in a world of his own.
Interestingly enough,
we met on the Internet.
I was in a movie chat room.
Can I press
one of your buttons?
So my nickname was something
that she recognized.
Which was really
kind of bizarre.
It wasn't just a fluke,
and I knew that.
And I knew that that was it
from there on.
I don't have
an unhealthy obsession
About lord of the rings.
Lord of the Rings is overwhelming
our home.
What say you?
And in the long run,
the memorabilia was
To send our son to college.
But I think that was just
a ploy to get all the goodies
In the house, and now the value
Is dropping rapidly.
I am Anduril,
flame of the West.
Let the thralls of Mordor
flee before me.
Lord of the rings
presents a world untainted.
Okay?
It represents
the kind of platonic love
That we don't see often.
I don't even get what
happened in those movies.
The ring was the embodiment
of evil.
Excuse me, when they look
into each other's eyes
And he gets all jealous
of the Gollum.
What, like a son can't look
into his father's eyes
And be like,
"thank you for rescuing me."
He's jealous of the Gollum.
It is the same kind.
He's jealous of the Gollum
that he's spending
Too much time with the Gollum.
He actually looks
kinda mopey at times.
There are times that his eyes
fill up with tears and--
- It is a supernatural burden
that they are carrying.
They're saving the world.
Okay.
Look at all those tubs.
Most of the people
that have this
Are, like, living in their
mother's basement right now.
Ash, if you look on eBay
right now,
They're going
for, like, 89 cents.
- So then we need to keep them.
If they're going for--
- Look, okay, so they're--
- Actually, this is bilingual.
How many Gollums do we have?
But if you look,
they go through
A foreign subsidiary
to release the figures.
What does that matter?
It is the same figure.
It's just something cool.
I got all the bilingual cards
in the star wars stuff too.
It's just cool.
I think you should pick one
And that's it.
I would like to have both sets.
I don't see any harm
in having both sets.
Do you know what a geek
you sound like right now?
Yeah, but it also has sounds.
What say you? What say you?
Should Ash have to get rid
Of his beloved
lord of the rings collection?
She's got a kinda
Celine Dion thing going,
And maybe he doesn't like that.
I think that
when you're in love,
You have to support
each other's passions.
And she should support
his love of lord of the rings.
He should support her love
of diet pills
Or whatever her hobby is.
What do you think, Matthew?
Wow.
My feelings are basically
15 fold.
Wow.
I don't know.
You know, I know typically
When one gets married,
you give up everything you like
And that--the things--
You know, you're not allowed
to take things
From childhood into adulthood.
Right.
This has come to us down
from the Mayan times.
But he seemed to have
such a sweet feeling
About those toys
that I sympathized
And want him to have them.
Look, I have been married
for a long time.
- Uh-huh.
And I think the secret
is you've gotta be sensitive
To your wife's needs,
and in my case
Make sure your personal
assistant fulfills them.
But that's me.
That's Hollywood,
ladies and gentlemen.
What do you think, Sarah?
I think that you have
to support each other
And love each other
and--you know?
And support
each other's habits,
Whether it be lord of the rings
or crack cocaine.
Or something in between.
All right, panelists, who
do you think I should go for,
Husband or the wife?
Matthew, bottom line?
The husband.
All right, Sarah?
I'm gonna go husband,
But I think
they should get divorced.
Marty?
I think that it's his right
to do that,
And she should be patient.
All right, all for the husband.
Let's go to actual Washington
and bring out the actual Hamiltons
in their actual township.
Hello.
Hi.
All right, Betty,
A man's mind needs to be
Partially occupied at all times
By something stupid.
Because it keeps a guy's brain
from doing something else.
And whatever
that something else is,
You don't want him doing it.
Exactly.
Ash, you win.
Oh, that is so not right.
That is so not right.
Anything you would like
to ask the couple?
I had something.
Is it that it takes up
too much room?
Or is it that he still seems
sorta childlike?
Or--what bothers you
about it?
Childlike.
I'm sorry.
Why would I think
that was childlike?
Forgive me, forgive me.
Does he seem
too grown up to you?
No encouragement, please.
You know, Ash,
the more you speak,
The more you lose
everyone's vote.
So I would...Shh.
Thank you, Hamiltons.
Good bye.
And for being
such great sports tonight,
All our couples will receive
a romantic second honeymoon
Furnished by royal Caribbean
international.
So that's our show.
We'd like to thank
our panel of experts--
Martin short,
Sarah Silverman,
Matthew Broderick.
Thank you!
And especially to all
our couples tonight,
Thank you for letting us
into your marriage.
It's worth fighting for.
Now kiss and make up.
Good night, everybody.
♪ oh baby ♪
♪ let's ♪
♪ let's stay together ♪
♪ loving you whether ♪
♪ whether ♪
♪ times are good or bad ♪
♪ happy or sad ♪
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com