"Have some milk."
And I lowered myself
beneath her swollen udder...
...and I sucked the sweetest milk
I had ever tasted.
"Climb onboard," she said.
And as a harvest moon
rose over Cyberland...
...we reared back,
we sprang into a gallop...
...leaping out of orbit.
I awoke, singing...
Leap of faith
Only thing to do
Only thing to do is jump
Only thing to do is
Jump over the moon
Over the moon
Over the...
Moo with me.
Yes. Who is that? Come on.
Yes. Come on, sir.
Don't be shy. Let it go. Moo with me.
Let it rip.
Yes. Let it go, New York City.
Yeah.
Hey, get off, man.
Just calm down.
Take it easy now, all right?
Back off.
Hey, hey, hey. Guys, it's okay.
It's okay. Just keep cool.
Come on, move back.
- Take it easy, all right?
- This is supposed be a peace...
Officer, please.
Look, just keep... Hey.
Please. Everyone, be calm.
Everyone, please.
Oh, my God.
Stop it.
- Get off of me.
- Let go of him.
- Collins.
- Get off of her.
Get off of me.
- Get off of me.
- Get off her.
- Let's get out of here. This way.
- Go, go, go.
Everyone, be cool.
Stop, this is peaceful.
Please.
Benny got exactly what he wanted.
He screws up my show,
he gets all these people arrested.
Cops won't hold them for long.
They'll let them go in a few hours.
- Oh, there they are.
- You all right?
- Yes. Yes.
- Joanne?
- Collins.
- Nice to meet you.
- Angel.
- Oh, it's cold. Let's go inside, okay?
- Yeah.
Hi, baby. Thank you.
Wait, where's Mark?
I don't know, man. Let's wait for him
inside. Come on.
Let's go.
- Hey.
- Hey. Are you all right?
I'm fine. I'm fine. I'm fine.
Tonight on the 11:00 news,
the lead story is gonna be your show.
- How do you know that?
- They bought my footage of the riot.
- They're gonna see the whole thing.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Good work, Mark.
- You serious?
- Yes.
How can I repay you?
Let the boy buy us dinner.
- Okay.
- Oh, no.
Please, no. No, not tonight.
- Please leave.
- What? Why?
You sit here all night,
and you never order anything.
That's a lie. Last week I had a tea.
You couldn't pay.
- Oh, yeah.
- Yeah.
Tonight we can. Come on.
Fine. Just please
don't move the tables.
Let's put these tables together.
- Slide this way. Put these together.
- No. No, no, no.
Hey, Doodles.
Well, if you get back to me,
let's say by early next week...
...we can break ground,
I'm thinking, mid-January.
Benjamin Coffin III.
The enemy of Avenue A.
You got a whole lot of nerve
showing your face here...
...after what just happened.
Listen, guys, this was not my fault.
- Go to hell.
- Jerk.
You put the cops on standby.
- I didn't want it to get out of control.
- Why did Muffy...
Allison.
- miss the show?
There...
There was a death in the family.
Who died?
Our Akita.
- Evita.
You make fun
Yet I'm the one
Attempting to do some good
Or do you really want
A neighborhood
Where people piss
On your stoop every night?
Bohemia
Bohemia's a fallacy in your head
This is Calcutta
Bohemia is dead
Dearly beloved
We gather here
To say our goodbyes
Here she lies
No one knew her worth
The late, great daughter
Of Mother Earth
On these nights
When we celebrate the birth
In that little town of Bethlehem
We raise our glass
You bet your ass
To
La vie
Bohème
La vie bohème
- La vie bohème
- To days of inspiration
Playin' hooky
Makin' somethin' out of nothin'
The need to express
To communicate
To going against the grain
Going insane
- La vie bohème
- Going mad
- To loving tension
No pension
To more than one dimension
To starving for attention,
Hating convention, hating pretension
Not to mention, of course
Hating dear old Mom and Dad
To riding your bike midday
Past the three-piece suits
To fruits
To no absolutes
To Absolut
To choice
To the Village Voice
To any passing fad
To being an us for once
Instead of a them
La vie bohème
Hey, mister.
She's my sister.
So that's five miso soup
Four seaweed salad
Three soy-burger dinner
Two tofu-dog platter
And one pasta with meatless balls
It tastes the same
If you close your eyes
- And 13 orders of fries, is that it here?
- Wine and beer
To handcrafted beers
Made in local breweries
To yoga
To yogurt
To rice and beans and cheese
To leather
To dildos
To curry vindaloo
To huevos rancheros
And Maya Angelou
Emotion, devotion
To causing a commotion
Creation
Vacation
Mucho masturbation
Compassion
To fashion
To passion when it's new
- To Sontag
- To Sondheim
To anything taboo
Ginsberg, Dylan, Cunningham
And Cage
Lenny Bruce
- Langston Hughes
- To the stage
- To Uta
- To Buddha
Pablo Neruda too
Why Dorothy and Toto
Went over the rainbow
To blow off Auntie Em
La vie bohème
- Sisters?
- We're close.
Brothers
Bisexuals, trisexuals,
Homo sapiens
Carcinogens, hallucinogens, men,
Pee-wee Herman
German wine, turpentine
Gertrude Stein
Antonioni, Bertolucci, Kurosawa
Carmina Burana
To apathy
To entropy
To empathy
Ecstasy
Václav Havel
The Sex Pistols
8BC
To no shame
Never playin' the fame game
- To marijuana
- To sodomy
It's between God and me
To S & M
- Waiter, waiter, waiter, waiter.
- La vie bohème
In honor of the death of bohemia...
...an impromptu salon will commence
immediately following dinner.
Maureen Johnson,
back from her spectacular...
...one-night engagement
at the 11th Street lot...
...will perform tribal chants
backwards...
...through her vocoder, accompanying
herself on the electric cello.
Which she ain't never studied.
And Mark Cohen will preview
his new documentary...
...about his inability to hold an erection
on the High Holy Days.
And Mimi Marquez,
clad only in bubblewrap...
...will perform her famous
lawn-chair handcuff dance...
...to the sounds of iced tea
being stirred.
And Roger will attempt to write
a bittersweet, evocative song...
...that doesn't remind us
of "Musetta's Waltz."
Angel Dumott Schunard will model
the latest fall fashions from Paris...
...while accompanying herself
on the 10-gallon plastic pickle tub.
And Collins will recount
his exploits as anarchist...
...including his successful
reprogramming...
...of the MIT retro-reality
equipment to self-destruct...
...as it broadcasts the words:
Actual reality. ACT UP. Fight AIDS.
Excuse me
Did I do somethin' wrong?
I get invited, then ignored
All night long
I've been tryin'
I'm not lyin'
No one's perfect
I've got baggage
Life's too short, babe
Time is flyin'
I'm lookin' for baggage
That goes with mine
- I should tell you
- I've got baggage too
- Should tell you... Baggage
- Baggage
Wine and beer
AZT break.
You?
Me
Mimi
I should tell you
I'm disaster
I forget how to begin it
Let's just make this part go faster
I have yet to be in it
I should tell you
I should tell I blew the candle out
Just to get back in
I'd forgotten how to smile
Until your candle burned my skin
I should tell you
- I should tell
- Well, here we go
- Now we
Oh, no
I know this something is
- Here goes
Guess so, it's starting to
- Who knows?
- Who knows where?
- Who goes there?
- Who knows?
- Here goes
- Trusting desire
- Starting to learn
- Walking through fire
- Without a burn
- Clinging a shoulder
- A leap begins
- Stinging and older
- Asleep on pins
- So here we go
- Now we
Oh, no
- I know
- Oh, no
- Who knows where?
- Who goes there?
- Here goes
- That's right. Come on.
- Yeah.
- To dance
- No way to make a living
Masochism, pain, perfection
Muscle spasms, chiropractors
Short careers, eating disorders
- Film
- Adventure, tedium
No family, boring locations
Darkrooms
Perfect faces, egos, money
Hollywood and sleaze
- Music
- Food of love, emotion
Mathematics, isolation
Rhythm, power
Feeling, harmony
And heavy competition
- Anarchy
- Revolution, justice
Screaming for solutions
Forcing changes, risk and danger
Making noise and making pleas
To faggots, lezzies, dykes
Cross-dressers too
- To me
To you and you and you
You and you
To people living with
Living with, living with
Not dying from disease
Let he among us without sin
Be the first to condemn
La vie bohème
- La vie bohème
- Anyone out of the mainstream
- Is anyone in the mainstream?
- La vie bohème
- Anyone alive with a sex drive
- Tear down the wall
Aren't we all?
- The opposite of war isn't peace
- What is?
It's creation
La vie bohème
Viva la vie bohème!
Five hundred twenty-five thousand
Six hundred minutes
Moments so dear
Five hundred twenty-five thousand
Six hundred minutes
How do you measure
Measure a year?
In diapers, report cards
In spoked wheels, in speeding tickets
In contracts, dollars
In funerals, in births
In 525,600 minutes
How do you figure
A last year on Earth?
Figure in love
- Figure in love
- Eight, seven, six, five...
...four, three, two, one.
Measure in love
Seasons of love
Hey, Mimi. Mimi.
Mimi, give me
your New Year's resolutions.
I'm giving up my vices.
I'm going back to school.
Oh, that's very good.
How about you, Roger?
- Finish a song.
- Yeah, maybe this year?
And who are you two
supposed to be?
- Bond. James Bond.
- And Pussy Galore. In person.
Very nice.
What you want, huh?
Well, you can take the girl
out of Hicksville...
...but you can't take
the Hicksville out of the girl.
Heard you got a job offer.
No, it was just that sleazy news show
Buzzline wants to take a meeting.
We're gonna need an agent.
- "We"?
- Hey, listen, mister.
I am the reason you got on TV
in the first place.
Oh, my God. You know what?
We'll do another protest.
And this time you can shoot
the entire thing for the TV show.
No, I'm not interested, I'm sorry.
What? Why not?
Because working for a show like
Buzzline, that's completely selling out.
Okay. But it's nice to dream.
- Well, maybe.
- Happy New Year.
Happy New Year.
Give me that. I'm sick
and tired of you always...
- Maureen. You're gonna break it.
- Hi, Mark.
- Happy New Year.
- This is not my bar mitzvah.
Give it back to me.
Out of all the years
I've been in New York...
...I've never gone to Times Square
for New Year's.
- Really?
- I don't think I wanna do it again.
- I think that was enough.
- It was a little like a moo-fest.
- Mark.
- What?
Check out the door.
What the hell is that?
Guys, there's a padlock
on the door.
Benny.
Hold on. Hold this, honey.
I saw this on television. Watch.
Baby, what you doing?
You'll see.
Be careful, now.
- You're drunk.
- No, I'm not.
Okay, watch.
- That's so heavy.
- Watch your fingers.
That's my girl.
- Yeah.
- Nothing like Pussy.
- Let's go.
- Here you go, baby.
- Thank you.
- Door open.
- That's a full-service woman.
- That was great.
- Gonna put that trash can back?
- No.
Oh, damn.
Typical.
He took all our stuff.
Mine too.
What a fricking sweetheart.
What do we do now?
Well, technically,
now that you're inside...
...you're squatters.
You can't be arrested.
Benny can't throw you
out on the street.
It'll give you and Roger time
to get some money together.
There's always Buzzline.
Oh, my God,
my stomach doesn't feel right.
You'll be fine.
Is what I'm wearing okay?
Does this look right?
Yeah, you look really good.
Do you think this belt
is too much, though?
- I can't do this.
- Come on.
- Yes, you can. I'll do all the talking.
- What are you doing?
- Stop fussing. We're late.
Oh, my God, look at this place.
Yeah, it's corporate America.
Welcome.
- Hi. We're here to see Alexi Darling.
- Hi.
- Your name?
- Joanne Jefferson and Mark Cohen.
I'm Maureen Johnson.
Maybe you should wait out here.
- But I'm the one...
- We don't wanna come on too strong.
Alexi, Joanne Jefferson
and Mark Cohen here to see you.
Okay. Fine.
Whatever.
How much did I love your footage?
So much.
It reminded me of my Berkeley days.
Fighting the good fight.
- Kudos. Kudos.
- Thank you.
I wanted to let you know that I've also
been working on a documentary...
...about the homeless
and people with HIV.
Great. I love it. So fresh, edgy.
Everything Buzzline's about.
- Really?
- We may dip into the tabloid side.
Guilty as charged.
But we are a news show.
And your client has a fresh eye
to bring real stories to an audience...
...and that's what we want.
We get the real programming...
...he gets the network exposure. Not a
bad way to start a career, by the way.
So, what do you think?
Yes. What about salary?
On commission.
On an escalating scale.
Start at $3000.
You're not gonna get
a better deal than that.
We'll take it.
Congratulations.
- I sold my soul.
- For 3 grand a segment.
You ain't got nothing
without my protest.
Does everything
have to be about you?
Me? You're the one
helping my ex-boyfriend.
He needed a lawyer.
I figured I could help out,
since you got them evicted.
You know what? Why don't the two
of you get an accountant's ledger...
...and a bottle of champagne
and go at it.
Invite the girl you were just flirting with
to join us and I will.
Oh, my God. Come on, Pookie.
I was just being friendly.
- My God.
- What do you want, huh?
I'll do anything.
You want me to be your slave?
You want me
to just obey your every wish?
Tell me what you want.
Commitment.
That's all?
Why didn't you say so
in the first place?
What?
All you have to do is ask...
...and I'm yours.
Will you commit to me?
To be with only me
for the rest of our lives?
I will.
I do.
This can't be happening.
I'd like to welcome everyone...
...and congratulate
my daughter Joanne.
On... On her wonderful choice
of a life partner, Maureen Johnson.
My husband and I would also like
to welcome Maureen's parents...
...Eddie and Nancy Johnson,
into our family.
Would everyone please stand?
And let's raise a glass to toast
the future of Joanne and Maureen.
Hear, hear.
Cheers.
I love you, baby.
Thanks, Mom.
You got engaged.
Thanks, Dad.
- Cheers.
- Thanks.
- Congratulations.
- Hi. Thank you.
Got anything stronger than this?
Only champagne and wine,
unfortunately.
Hi.
Thank you.
You know, Maureen didn't even
let me really congratulate her yet.
I know, because...
- Where'd you get this necklace?
- Oh, just downtown.
Could you excuse me for a minute?
- Hi. Could you excuse us a minute?
- Hi, baby.
Thank you.
- What's up?
- What the hell are you doing?
What? We were just talking.
- Right.
- Pookie, we were just talking.
Maureen, please,
do not do this today.
Excuse me, sir,
can you hold this, please?
- Certainly.
- Thanks.
You know what, Miss Ivy League?
I can't take much more of this.
This obsessive-compulsive,
control-freak paranoia.
- What?
- I didn't pierce my nipples...
...because it grossed you out.
I didn't stay at the Kink Club last night
because you wanted to go home.
You flirted with
the woman in rubber.
There will always be women
in rubber flirting with me.
Give me a break.
Every single day
I walk down the street
I hear people say
"Baby's so sweet"
Ever since puberty
Everybody stares at me
Boys, girls, I can't help it, baby
So be kind
And don't lose your mind
Just remember that I'm your baby
Take me for what I am
Who I was meant to be
And if you give a damn
Take me, baby, or leave me
A tiger in a cage
Can never see the sun
This diva needs her stage
Baby, let's have fun
You are the one I choose
Folks would kill to fill your shoes
You love
The limelight too now, baby
So be mine
And don't waste my time
Crying, "Oh, honey bear,
Are you still my, my
- My baby?"
- Don't you dare.
Take me for what I am
Who I was meant to be
And if you give a damn
Take me, baby, or leave me
No way can I be what I'm not
But, hey, don't you want
Your girl hot?
Don't fight
Don't lose your head
'Cause every night
Who's in your bed?
Who?
- Kiss, Pookie.
- It won't work.
I look before I leap
I love margins and discipline
I make lists in my sleep, baby
What's my sin?
Never quit
I follow through
I hate mess
But I love you
What to do
With my impromptu baby
So be wise
'Cause this girl satisfies
You've got a prize
But don't compromise
You're one lucky baby
- Take me for what I am
- A control freak.
- Who I was meant to be
- A snob, yet overattentive.
- And if you give a damn
- A lovable, droll geek.
- Take me, baby, or leave me
- An anal-retentive.
- That's it
The straw that breaks my back
- I quit
Unless you take it back
- Women
What is it about them?
- Can't live with them or without them
- Take me for what I am
- Who I was meant to be
- And if you give a damn
You better take me, baby
- Oh, take me, baby
- Or leave me
Take me or leave me
- Take me, baby
- Or leave me
- Guess I'm leaving
- I'm gone
Maybe now you two
can get back together.
- Well, actually, I'm...
- Come on, let's go.
Hey, guys, all our shit's back.
Benny, what's going on?
I'm here to put an end to this war.
- What changed your mind?
- Mimi did, actually.
We hadn't seen each other in a while.
So we had dinner, we talked...
...and she convinced me
to rethink the situation.
Look, I regret
the unlucky circumstances...
Circumstance? Benny,
you padlocked our door...
...and you took all of our stuff.
- Right.
Which is why I'm here offering
a new lease. All right?
Rent-free, courtesy of CyberArts.
You might wanna get this on film.
Oh, I see,
this is a photo opportunity.
The benevolent god ushers
the poor artists back to their flat.
Brought to you
by your friendly CyberArts.
- Full story tonight on Buzzline.
- It's not like that, Collins.
Look, we don't need your charity.
Should cover us for a little while.
Where'd you get this?
It's my first advance.
Okay. Congratulations.
Excuse me.
Roger...
...nothing happened.
Benny and me, it's over.
We had a thing once...
...but it was two years ago.
- It doesn't matter.
- It was before I met you.
- I don't care.
Without you
The ground thaws
The rain falls
The grass grows
Without you
The seeds root
The flowers bloom
The children play
The stars gleam
The poets dream
The eagles fly
Without you
The Earth turns
The sun burns
But I die without you
Without you
The breeze warms
The girl smiles
The cloud moves
Without you
The tides change
The boys run
The oceans crash
The crowds roar
The days soar
The babies cry
Without you
The moon glows
The river flows
But I die without you
The world revives
Colors renew
- But I know blue
- Only blue
- Lonely blue
Within me, blue
Without you
The hand gropes
The ear hears
The pulse beats
Without you
The eyes gaze
The legs walk
The lungs breathe
- The mind churns
- The heart yearns
- The tears dry
Without you
- Life goes on
- But I'm gone
- 'Cause I die without you
- I die
Without you
- Without you
It's right...
...that today's Halloween.
It was Angel's favorite holiday.
I knew we'd hit it off
the moment we met.
There was this skinhead
that was harassing her...
...and she just walked
right up to him and said:
"I'm more of a man
than you'll ever be...
...and more of a woman
than you'll ever get."
And then there was this time...
...he walked up
to this group of tourists...
...and they were petrified...
...because, A, they were
obviously lost...
...and, B, had probably never spoken
to a drag queen before in their lives.
And he...
She...
...just offered to escort them
out of Alphabet City...
...and then let them
take a picture with her...
...and then said she'd help them
find the Circle Line.
So much more original
than any of us.
You'd find an old tablecloth
on the street and make a dress...
...and then the next year,
sure enough...
...they'd be mass-producing
them at the Gap.
You always said how lucky
you were that we were all friends...
...but it was us, baby...
...who were the lucky ones.
Live in my house
I'll be your shelter
Just pay me back
With 1000 kisses
Be my lover
And I'll cover you
Yeah
Open your door
I'll be your tenant
Don't got much baggage
To lay at your feet
But sweet kisses I've got to spare
I'll be there and I'll cover you
I think they meant it
When they said you can't buy love
Now I know you can rent it
A new lease you are, my love
On life
All my life
I've longed to discover
Something as true as this is
Yeah
So with a thousand sweet kisses
- lf you're cold and you're lonely
- I'll cover you
With a thousand sweet kisses
- You've got one nickel only
- I'll cover you
With a thousand sweet kisses
- When you're worn out and tired
- I'll cover you
With a thousand sweet kisses
When your heart has expired
Oh, lover
I'll cover you
Five hundred twenty-five thousand
Six hundred minutes
Seasons of
- Love
- I'll cover you, oh
It's true you sold your guitar
And bought a car?
It's true
I'm leaving now for Santa Fe
It's true you're with
This yuppie scum?
You said you'd never
Speak to him again
- Not now.
- Who said that you have any say
- In who she says things to at all?
- Yeah.
Who said that you should stick
Your nose in other people...?
Who said I was talking to you?
- We used to have this fight each night
- Calm down
- She'd never admit I existed
- Everyone, please
He was the same way
He was always
Run away, hit the road, don't commit
You're full of shit
- She's in denial
- He's in denial
Didn't give an inch
When I gave a mile
- I gave a mile
- Gave a mile to who?
Come on, guys, chill.
I'd be happy to die
For a taste of what Angel had
- Someone to live for
- Unafraid to say "I love you"
All your words are nice, Mimi
But love's not a three-way street
You'll never share real love
Until you love yourself
I should know
You all said you'd be cool today
So please, for my sake
I can't believe he's gone
I can't believe you're going
I can't believe this family must die
Angel helped us believe in love
I can't believe you disagree
I can't believe this is
Goodbye
Don't breathe too deep
Don't think all day
Dive into work
Drive the other way
That drip of hurt
That pint of shame
Goes away
Just play the game
You're living in America
At the end of the millennium
Leave your conscience at the tone
And when you're living in America
At the end of the millennium
You're what you own
The filmmaker cannot see
And the songwriter cannot hear
Yet I see Mimi everywhere
Angel's voice is in my ear
Just tighten those shoulders
Just clench yourjaw till you frown
Just don't let go
- Or you may drown
You're living in America
At the end of the millennium
- You're living in America
- Where it's like The Twilight Zone
- And when you're living in America
- At the end of the millennium
- You're what you own
- So I own not a notion
- I escape and ape content
- I don't own emotion
- I rent
- What was it about that night?
- Connection in an isolating age
- For once the shadows
- Gave way to light
- For once I didn't disengage
- Angel, I hear you, I hear it, I see it
- Mimi, I see you
- I see it, my film
- I hear it, I hear it, I hear it, my song
- Alexi, Mark. Call me a hypocrite...
- One song, glory
...I need to finish my own film. I quit.
- Mimi, your eyes
Dying in America
At the end of the millennium
- We're dying in America
- To come into our own
- And when you're dying in America
- At the end of the millennium
- You're not alone
- I'm not alone
- Speak.
Hey, guys, it's Benny.
Look, I was wondering
if you've seen Mimi.
I haven't seen her
in a couple of weeks.
She dropped out of rehab...
...and I'm afraid that she may
have started using again.
- lf you find out anything, let me know.
- Hi, Roger, Mark...
...it's Maureen. Still no sign of Mimi.
- I just wanna know if she's all right.
- Joanne and I printed up some fliers.
- Hey, it's Collins. Just checking in.
- I'll call back if we hear anything.
- You heard from Mimi?
Roger, I spoke to the manager
of the Cat Scratch Club.
- She hasn't shown up for work.
- Roger, are you there?
Look, I just went to the police station
and I filed a missing-persons report.
I spoke to a friend of Mimi's who
said she saw her three weeks ago.
She hasn't picked up
her AZT in a while.
- She's been living on the street.
- Couple of weeks.
It's Collins again. I should be heading
home, like, right around Christmas.
I'm really starting to get worried.
It's getting cold out there.
- It's too cold out there.
- How can she survive?
December 24th, 1990, 10 p.m.,
Eastern Standard Time.
I can't believe a year
went by so fast.
- Speak.
- Hey, it's me, throw down the key.
- Hey, look who's home.
Hey, Collins, don't get
your ass kicked this time.
- Hey. Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas.
Welcome back.
Come here.
Take your key. Hey, man.
Hello, Thomas. Merry Christmas.
- Hey, any word from Mimi?
- No.
You got the projector...
You finished your movie.
- I did.
- Well, I wanna see it.
Okay.
And I thought you guys could use
this to get some heat up in here.
- You shouldn't have done that.
- Thank you.
- Tutoring again?
- Nope.
- You back at NYU?
- Negative.
- Then how'd you get all this?
- I rewired the ATM...
...at The Food Emporium.
Now all you need is the code.
- The code? What code?
- A-N-G-E-L.
Cheers.
Merry Christmas.
Mark?
Roger?
Anyone? Help.
We can't get her up the stairs.
Hurry up, please.
Mimi.
She's been living on the street.
We found her in the park.
She wanted to come here.
No room on the couch.
Just clear off the table,
we'll put her there.
Up here.
Roger.
- You're back.
- I'm back. I'm back, baby.
Rog.
- We need some heat.
- Okay, I'll buy some wood and food.
- It's too late. I'm calling 911.
- Roger?
I'm right here. I'm right here.
It's okay.
I'm here. We got you.
We got you.
I should tell you
I should tell you Benny wasn't any...
I know.
I should tell you why I left
- It wasn't 'cause I didn't...
- I know.
- I should tell you
I should tell you, I love you
Who do you think you are?
Leaving me alone with my guitar
Hold on, there's something
You should hear
It isn't much, but it took all year
Your eyes
As we said our goodbyes
Can't get them out of my mind
And I find
I can't hide
From your eyes
The ones that took me by surprise
The night you came into my life
Where there's moonlight
I see your eyes
How'd I let you slip away
When I'm longing so to hold you?
Now I'd die for one more day
'Cause there's something
I should have told you
Yes, there's something
When I looked into your eyes
Why does distance make us wise?
You were the song all along
And before the song dies
I should tell you
I have always loved you
You can see it in my eyes
Mimi
Mimi.
I was heading
towards this warm...
...white light.
And I swear...
...Angel was there.
And she looked good.
She said:
"Turn around, girlfriend...
...and listen to that boy's song."
You're drenched.
Her fever's breaking.
There is no future
There is no past
Thank God this moment's
Not the last
- There's only us
- There's only this
- Forget regret
Or life is yours to miss
No other road
No other way
No day but today
- I can't control
- Will I lose my dignity?
- My destiny
- Will someone care?
- I trust my soul
- Will I wake tomorrow
My only goal
- Is just to be
- From this nightmare?
- Without you
- There's only now
- The hand gropes
- There's only here
- The ear hears
- Give in to love
- The pulse beats
- Or live in fear
- Life goes on
- No other path
- But I'm gone
- No other way
- 'Cause I die without you
- No day but today
- I die without you
No day but today