Guess how fast we're going now.
I don't care, I'm having a baby!
Hundred and five miles
an hour, you believe that?
Reese, you just passed the hospital!
The baby's coming, he's coming
now! All right, all right, hold on.
Okay, but I think he might be
stuck. Grab onto something. Ready?
One, two, three!
It's a baby boy.
I'm happy that Waffle House
was okay with me coming here
To talk to y'all about my daytoday.
And, y'all, that's
pretty much, in a shell
What it's like to manage a Waffle House.
Ma'am, I don't know what else
you want me to say to them.
And I'm also gonna need to
know where your commode's at.
Okay, let's give him a
round of applause. Thank you.
Okay, next up is Ricky Bobby.
Ricky, is your father here?
No, ma'am. I haven't
seen my daddy in years.
But my mama say he's out racing cars
And, well, dipping his
wick in anything that moves.
Okay, kids, that's enough.
We're gonna move on to Brennan.
Don't pay them no mind, Ricky.
Thanks, Cal. Shake and Bake.
You'll be my best friend forever.
His job is like as a prison guard.
Excuse me, darling. I'm Reese Bobby.
I'm here for career
day with my son, Ricky.
Dad! Hey there, boy!
Man, you got big. How long's
it been? Three, four months?
Ten years. Ten years?
Man, I gotta lay off the peyote.
Mr. Bobby, there's no smoking in here.
It's all right, I'm a volunteer fireman.
Okay, I am a semiprofessional
racecar driver
And an amateur tattoo artist.
And the first thing you gotta learn
if you're gonna be a racecar driver
Is you don't listen to losers
Like your knowitall teacher
here. Okay, I think that's enough.
Your teacher wants you to
go slow, and she's wrong
Because it's the fastest who gets paid
and it's the fastest who gets laid.
Oh, yeah. You know
what I'm talking about.
You people are in the wrong on this one!
So in the wrong!
This is egregious, do
you hear me? Egregious!
We were cellmates together,
Andy. You got payback coming!
Dad!
Don't listen to these people,
Ricky. You're a winner.
You got the gift. Always remember,
if you ain't first, you're last.
If you ain't first, you're last.
See you when you're grown
up. Dad! Come back, Dad!
It's a hot one here in Talladega
And this crowd of over 180,000
is enjoying one heck of a day.
Yo, Terry. Terry, we got the caution.
Bring it in for a pit. Let's work on it.
All right, fellas, let's go.
Looking good. Yes, come on.
Keep it up, baby.
All right, way to go. Go, way to go.
Nice jack work, Ricky.
Hey, Shake and Bake, Cal.
Shake and Bake! Terry, it's
all on you, bro. You go.
Go, baby, go. Wait, what are you doing?
I gotta take a piss. Go, go, go!
It doesn't matter, Lucius.
We're in last place. Relax.
Jeez, I gotta go take
a whiz. Get off my ass.
You see, this is what I'm talking about.
That's why this group right here
is the laughing stock of NASCAR.
Face it, we suck.
It's not always bad to be in last place.
Here's some things we can focus on:
One, we tried hard. And two,
we're still dear friends.
Glenn, shut up.
I see Terry. He's having
a chicken sandwich.
Hey, fellas! These are really
good. You should try one.
That place actually makes a nice sauce.
Let me eat this, then I
gotta make a phone call
Then I'm coming back, all
right? This is the bottom line.
If we don't get that
car back on the track
Our sponsors are gonna shit a chicken.
Now, is there anyone out there
who wants to go fast? Anybody?
I wanna go fast.
Hey, get him a suit. Hurry
up, make it snappy. Let's go.
Hustle up, hustle up. Hey, man!
Remember when we got kicked out of
biology for playing with Matchbox cars?
Yeah! Who's retarded now?
Yeah. Hey, what are
you doing after this?
After the race? Yeah.
I don't know, but it feels like
we're wasting a lot of time.
No, I know, I know.
I'm just excited, man!
Yeah, I know. Yeah. Hey! I love you!
What? Nothing.
Shake and Bake! Get some!
You're my best friend!
Okay, then! I'm in there with you!
I gotta get going! Go, go!
Yeah! That's Ricky, baby!
That's my boy, Ricky!
Hey, Ricky, just remember one thing:
If you wreck that car, that's
200 grand out of your pocket
So let's take it nice and slow, okay?
With all due respect, Lucius,
I'm gonna do some driving.
Excuse me, coming through.
Apparently, we've got a situation
for the Laughing Clown, number 26 car.
Terry Cheveaux is refusing to
drive. One of his crew members
Has taken the wheel.
Hey, just wanted to share a little
piece of personal information with you.
I got a chubby right now
Because this is one of the most
awesome experiences of my life
Because I'm getting to drive a racecar!
I can't believe it! Oh, my God!
Wow, that was cool.
Come on, come on.
The big story from Talladega:
Littleknown jackman Ricky Bobby
places third in the Dennit machine.
Ricky, first of all, where did
you learn to drive like that?
In a car. Car handle really good. Yeah.
Can you speak up, Ricky?
A car. It handled real good.
So, what do you think, Mr.
Dennit? He sure can drive.
He's got guts. Dennit Racing
needs a racer like him.
Come on, Dad. He's just a stupid cowboy.
Look how bad he is in that interview.
Junior, driving has got
nothing to do with interviews.
I just wish to hell you had a
little more stupid cowboy in you.
I felt like I was on a spaceship and....
I'm not sure what to do with my hands.
Be good to hold them down by your side.
We're really happy
with what was going on.
And at the end of the day,
you know, you gotta be happy.
What did you say his name was again?
His name is Ricky. Ricky Bobby.
Ricky Bobby? He's got two first names.
Whatever his name is,
let's get him over here.
Everything ended up fine.
Yeah, okay, everything was fine.
Thanks, thanks. Great job in the car.
Ricky Bobby, a force to
be reckoned with, possibly
In the near future.
Ricky Bobby with yet
another impressive win.
He is dominating NAS CAR.
First or last, baby, you know it!
I've never seen a driver who
wants to win more than this guy.
I could get used to this winning thing!
Dennit Racing Incorporated has
decided to field an additional car.
And, at the urging of Ricky Bobby
Who's been like a son to me, only better
I'm naming Cal Naughton
Jr. As the driver.
All right.
Cal Naughton. Hey
We just want to say to all
you other drivers out there
If you smell a delicious,
crispy smell after the race
It's not your tailpipe,
it's a little bit
Of shake....
And then bake.
Shake and Bake!
That's our nickname.
Get used to hearing it.
And Ricky Bobby wins
With Cal Naughton Jr. Finishing second.
Yeah! Hey, man!
Shake.... And Bake!
Hey, driver! Drive these.
Please be 18.
You want to make this out to Charlotte?
Hey, excuse me, Ricky.
Hey, Dale. Hey, can
I get your autograph?
Sure. Who do I make this out to?
It's for me. I think you're awesome.
Don't tell the other drivers.
I'm not gonna tell anyone.
I'll see you out there.
Absolutely, ma'am, I'd
love to sign your baby.
You're not gonna wanna
wash that forehead.
That's right, Powerade's number one.
Not just for hydration, for vitamin.
No, it's me, it's me,
Susan, your assistant.
Gotta watch it when I
get into autograph mode.
I know, I'm sorry. It's my fault,
I shouldn't have been standing.
I'm Ricky Bobby. Christmas
is right around the corner
And what better gift to give a loved one
Than the Jackhawk 9000?
Available at WalMart.
When you work on your
mysterious ladypart stuff
You should have the right tools
too. So that's why you should use
Maypax, the official tampon of NASCAR.
I'm Ricky Bobby.
If you don't chew Big
Red, then fuck you.
Prune candy.
You happy? I'm very happy.
Hey, I'm Ricky Bobby.
And I'm Cal Naughton Jr.
Urging you never to travel to Tijuana.
Ricky! Ricky! Ricky!
Okay, I'm starting to get sick.
Dick Berggren in Las Vegas,
Victory Lane, for Fox Television.
Ricky Bobby, today's big winner.
Heck of a win for you today
But it seems as if you either win
or crash the car trying to win.
Well, Dick, here's the deal. I'm
the best there is, plain and simple.
I mean, I wake up in the
morning and I piss excellence.
And nobody can hang with my stuff.
You know, I'm just a big,
hairy, American winning machine.
If you ain't first, you're last.
You know what I'm talking about?
That phrase is trademarked
Not to be used without
permission of Ricky Bobby Inc.
Supper's ready! Come on, y'all! I've
been slaving over this for hours!
Dear Lord baby Jesus
Or as our brothers to
the south call you, Jesus
We thank you so much for this
bountiful harvest of Domino's, KFC
And the always delicious Taco Bell.
I just want to take time to
say thank you for my family
My two beautiful, beautiful,
handsome, striking sons
Walker and Texas Ranger
Or T.R., as we call him
And of course, my redhot
smoking wife, Carley
Who is a stonecold fox.
Who if you were to rate her ass
on 100, it would easily be a 94.
Also wanna thank you for my
best friend, Cal Naughton Jr
Who's got my back no matter what.
Shake and Bake.
Dear Lord baby Jesus, we also thank
you for my wife's father, Chip.
We hope that you can use
your baby Jesus powers
To heal him and his horrible leg.
And it smells terrible and the
dogs are always bothering with it.
Dear tiny infant Jesus, we
Hey, you know, sweetie
Jesus did grow up.
You don't always have
to call him "baby."
It's odd and offputting
to pray to a baby.
Well, I like the Christmas
Jesus best and I'm saying grace.
When you say grace, say it to
grownup Jesus, teenage Jesus
Bearded Jesus, whoever you want.
You know what I want?
I want you to do this grace good,
so that God will let us win tomorrow.
Dear tiny Jesus
In your goldenfleece diapers, with
your tiny, little, fat, balledup fists
Pawing at the air.... He
was a man. He had a beard.
Look, I like the baby version
the best, do you hear me?
I win the races and I get the money.
Ricky, finish the damn grace.
I like to picture
Jesus in a tuxedo Tshirt
Because it says, like,
"I wanna be formal...
Right. ...but I'm here to party too."
Because I like to party,
so I like my Jesus to party.
I like to picture Jesus as a
ninja fighting off evil samurai.
I like to think of Jesus,
like, with giant eagle's wings.
And singing lead vocals
for Lynyrd Skynyrd
With, like, a angel band.
And I'm in the front row,
and I'm hammered drunk.
Hey, Cal? Why don't you just shut up?
Yes, ma'am. Okay.
Dear 8pound, 6ounce,
newborn infant Jesus
Don't even know a word yet
Just a little infant and so
cuddly, but still omnipotent
We just thank you for all the races
I've won and the 2 1.2 million dollars
Love that money!
That I have accrued
over this past season.
Also, due to a binding
endorsement contract
That stipulates I mention
Powerade at each grace
I just wanna say that
Powerade is delicious
And it cools you off
on a hot summer day.
And we look forward to Powerade's
release of Mystic Mountain BIueberry.
Thank you for all your power and
your grace, dear baby God. Amen.
Amen. Amen.
Let's dig in!
That was a hell of a grace, man.
You nailed that like a split hog!
I'm not gonna lie to you, it felt good.
Dad, you made that grace your bitch.
Hey, boys, I wanna see
some napkins in the lap.
Boys, how was school today?
I threw a bunch of Grandpa
Chip's war medals off the bridge.
Sounds like a good day.
Texas Ranger, how about you?
Well, the teacher asked me what
was the capital of North Carolina.
I said, "Washington, D.C."
Bingo. Nice.
She said, "No, you're wrong."
I said, "You got a Iumpy butt."
She got mad at me and yelled
at me and I pissed in my pants.
And I never did change
my pee pants all day.
I'm still sitting in my dirty pee pants.
I wet my bed until I was
19. There's no shame in that.
I get emotional because you
guys are working so hard.
I'm just so proud of
you. You remind me of me
Precocious and full of wonderment.
Tell you what, Ricky,
you are truly blessed.
These two are two in a million. I am.
Just like Carley's tatas.
You won't find another
rack like that, I guarantee.
Thank you, Cal.
That's real sweet of you, Cal.
That's real nice. That's one of
the nicest things you've ever said.
Well, I mean it. Stop,
you're gonna make me cry.
It comes from my heart, that's why.
I can't hold my tongue.
These kids are my grandchildren,
and you are raising them wrong.
They are terrible boys.
Shut up, Chip, or I'll
go apeshit on your ass!
I'm gonna scissorkick you
in the back of the head.
Yeah! Yeah. Turn up the heat.
Go on and get some, boys.
I'm 10 years old, but
I'll beat your ass.
Chip, I'm gonna come at
you like a spider monkey.
Like a spider monkey! Go on.
Chip, you brought this on.
The greatest generation, my ass.
Tom Brokaw is a punk.
What is wrong with you?
Chip, I'm all jacked up on Mountain Dew.
I love that.
You gonna let your sons talk to their
grandfather like that? I'm their elder.
I sure as hell am, Chip. I love
the way they're talking to you.
They're winners. Winners
get to do what they want.
Hell, you're just a bag of bones.
Only thing you ever done with
your life is make a hot daughter.
That's it. That is it!
We wanted us some wussies
We would've named them Dr.
Quinn and Medicine Woman, okay?
I work too hard for your bull, Chip.
Come here. You make me hot. Come here.
Everyone just keep eating.
It's on. Come here. Come here.
All right.
I'll hold your hair.
Hey, Stephen. Hey, Ricky.
Got those two tickets
for my special friend?
Yeah, sure do. You know I do,
Ricky. Got them right here, buddy.
Great. Hey, how's your mama's hip?
She's gonna be all right,
thank you for asking.
Appreciate it. Hey,
good Iuck today. Thanks.
That's the saddest thing
I've ever seen in my life.
That boy leaves two tickets
for his daddy at every race
And he never shows up.
That's a shame.
The human heart is such a mystery.
Let's sell these
bitches, huh? Hell, yeah.
Beer money, huh? There you go. Yes.
As the laps wind down,
Jamie McMurray is the leader.
Cal Naughton in second.
Ricky Bobby in third.
What's up, Cal? You ready
for a little ShakeandBakeage?
Hey, buddy. Naughton Jr.
Is letting Ricky Bobby
Draft up to him to make that
slingshot move past McMurray.
Can you believe that he would
do that for his teammate?
Set him up that way?
Slingshot, engage.
And there goes Ricky
Bobby on the outside!
That's how we do it.
Makes his move. Naughton's
giving him plenty of room.
What in the hell is he doing,
guys? Get him off of me.
They touch! They spin!
Snap!
Come on, man!
See you, wouldn't wanna be you.
Look at that! Ricky Bobby's gonna
try to win the race in reverse.
Man, he wants this win bad!
Ricky Bobby wins it in reverse!
Unbelievable! I love that! That is cool!
Jamie, losing's never fun, but here's
something to pick your spirits up.
It's real nice. I got it
at Target. It's on sale.
Yeah!
That's it. Another one. Another
one. All right, man. We did it!
I don't wanna be raining on
your parade, but I gotta tell you
That was some of the dumbest
driving I have ever seen in my life.
Thank you. And I know you won the race
But you're not gonna live forever.
I'm not stupid, Lucius. No
one lives forever. No one.
But with advances in modern
science and my high level of income
I mean, it's not crazy to think I
can't live to be 2 45, maybe 300.
I just read in the newspaper they
put a pig heart in some Russian guy.
Know what? I mean, do
you know what that means?
No, I don't know what that
means. I guess, longer life.
Well, no, he didn't
live. He didn't live?
No. It's just exciting that
we're trying things like that.
Ricky? Hey, Mr. Dennit.
Cheers. Yeah.
She already wasted? Celebrating.
She's celebrating. You
feel pretty good today, huh?
Look, Ricky, early word out of NASCAR
Is your little obscene gesture's
gonna cost you 100 points.
You know how much that costs
us in sponsorship dollars?
With all due respect, Mr. Dennit
I had no idea you had experimental
surgery to have your balls removed.
What did you say? What was that?
Well, what? I said,
"With all due respect."
That doesn't mean you get to
say whatever you wanna say to me.
It sure as heck does. No, it doesn't.
It's in the Geneva
Convention. Look it up.
I remember your daddy used to love it.
This is not my dad This is my team
Used to love it when I used to win.
Now, I suggest you and
your wife, Mrs. Jim Beam
You guys go take a chill
pill. Enjoy the win!
Come on, man! Yeah, Ricky. Okay.
Baby, photo op, photo op. Come on.
Come on, number one.
Hold my hand, baby.
I'll tell you what, though, guys,
that was a hell of a race today.
Shake and Bake in full effect.
It's always been like that.
Me and Ricky, since we
were little kids, man.
We go together like Chinese food
and chocolate pudding. Let's face it.
Yeah, but those are two things
that don't really go together.
We go together like cocaine and waffles.
No, like, for instance, if
I say peanut butter and....
Ladies, right? Yep.
No, jelly. Am I right?
Jelly? You like to put jelly on a lady?
I'm gonna settle this thing.
Let's just get ourselves
A whole mess of cocktails, get
drunk and work this thing out.
Work this thing out. That's right.
So I was talking to Nana on
Saturday, and her birthday's coming up
But I don't know what to
get her. She's gonna be 88.
Get her a coffin.
Hey, Cal, I'm sorry
about wrecking you today.
I mean, but that was for the team.
No, that's cool. That's cool, I know.
I was thinking, though, one time
It would be really awesome if, like,
you could slingshot me in for a win.
Yeah, but Okay, but if you won
How am I gonna win? Yeah.
Think about it. No, I
was thinking about it.
I mean, it's not like
you're finishing 18th.
There's nothing wrong with silver.
Nothing wrong with silver at all.
I'm just kidding you,
man. I don't wanna win.
I'll just bury it down inside.
Bury it deep down in there,
and never bring it up again.
It's painful, and I love you!
Get her a gigolo.
What? A guy to have sex with her.
No, she's gonna be 88 and....
You don't stop liking
sex when you're old.
Well, I was thinking
more along the line of....
Like, she likes afghans and quilts.
She's probably got a million of those.
How many dudes does she have
coming over to have sex with her?
None. Exactly.
Be thoughtful, Glenn.
Don't stop.
What is that?
Someone made a tape of
something dying or something.
Hey, turn that crap
off. What's going on?
I want this music out of my head.
Hey, turn that off!
Turn that off right now!
Why did you stop the jazz music?
Was it not pleasant for you?
No one plays jazz here
at The Pit Stop, okay?
So why is the song on the jukebox?
We keep it on there
for profiling purposes.
We also got the Pet Shop Boys and Seal.
My name is Jean Girard
And I am a racingcar
driver just like you
Except I am from Formula Un.
I am the greatest one
in the whole world.
I have been following your career
with great interest, Monsieur Bobby.
I can't understand a word
you've said the whole time.
Did you eat peanut butter or something?
You sound like a dog with peanut
butter on the roof of your mouth.
I think what you are
hearing is my accent.
I am French.
You say you're French?
We? No, we are not French.
We're American, because
you're in America, okay?
Greatest country on the planet.
Well, what have you given the world
Apart from George Bush,
Cheerios, and the ThighMaster?
Chinese food? Chinese food.
That's from China.
Pizza. Italy.
Chimichanga. Mexican.
Really, smartypants? What
did French land give us?
We invented democracy, existentialism
And the blowjob.
Those are three pretty good things. Hey.
Well, that last one's pretty cool.
You know, the 69 with the
head near the That bit.
We came up with it.
We created the missionary position.
You're welcome. Ricky Bobby
I have come here to defeat you.
Oh, well, there's strikes
two and three right there.
Did you hear what he just said?
Well, welcome to America, amigo.
You are fast, Ricky Bobby
But I am faster.
All right, you let go of me,
you Formula One jazz nutjob!
Like the frightened baby chipmunk
You are scared by
anything that is different.
I will let you go, Ricky
But first I want you to say:
"I love crepes."
Don't you say it, Ricky.
These colors don't run.
I'm not gonna say it. Good.
Hey, look, Frenchy, I thought about it.
So why don't you go
ahead and break my arm?
I do not want to break
your arm, Monsieur Bobby
But I am a man of my word.
Here's the deal. He's not gonna break it
Because I'm gonna slip out
of it right now. Houdini.
Get down, you little pancake.
Someone get me a beer while I'm here.
But you have forced me to do this.
You are now mocking me and
making me look ridiculous.
Just say, "I love crepes."
You know, just to put this in there, I
had a whole mess of crepes this morning.
They're like pancakes,
maybe even better.
Are they the really thin pancakes? Yeah.
They are the really thin pancakes.
It's just a French word for them.
My God, I love those. Put
any syrups you want on them.
I'm saying, think about it.
They come with cheese sometimes?
Yes, of course, a fromagecrepe.
Well, why didn't someone
yell that right away?
You know what's in the crepe suzette?
Oh, I love the crepe
suzette. With the sugar
And lemon juice, Grand
Marnier. Sugar and lemon juice.
I wish I could crawl into
one of those right now.
I'd eat my way out from
the inside. They are tasty.
Either way this goes, could
we get some after we're done?
Absolutely. We're gonna do
that. So, what if you just said:
"I love really thin pancakes"?
That is a fair compromise, no?
That is a fair compromise.
Very fair, actually.
No! Because then everyone would
know I really meant crepes.
That's a pretty good compromise.
Why do you want me to
break your arm so badly?
You don't understand because
you don't understand liberty.
You don't understand freedom.
So you put a crack in my arm like
the crack in the Liberty Bell.
Hey. This is just
between you and me, okay?
I mean, forget all these other guys.
But he did give you a pretty
decent out. But it's your call.
What do you think?
Don't say it. Yeah.
I'm not gonna say it.
Break it, Pepe Le Pew.
As you wish.
He actually did it! All
right. You did it. Back off.
I didn't say it! No, you did not.
Your injury is one of
ignorance and pride.
Hold it right there, Mr.
Fancy Pants Foreigner.
You just broke my bro's arm.
Now you're about to get Tasered.
Say hello to Dr. Watts. Get him, Cal.
I need you all to step away
From my driver.
The hell you talking about, "my
driver"? What are you doing with a gun?
Don't you worry about my gun, Ricky.
Jean Girard is my new boy at
Dennit Racing. He's here to win us
An overallpoints championship,
something you apparently
Have no interest in. He's
gonna usher in a new era.
Mr. Dennit, with all due respect
And remember, I'm saying,
"with all due respect."
That idea ain't worth a velvet painting
of a whale and a dolphin getting it on.
That's good. That's good
fun. That's good fun, Ricky
But that doesn't bother me
anymore because Jean is the future
Ricky, the past.
So, Jean, introduce me
to your new teammates.
Everybody, this is my husband, Gregory.
What?
See you at the track.
Did he just say "husband"?
Sweet Lord. Dennit hired a
gay Frenchman as your teammate.
The room's starting to spin real fast.
Because of gayness.
Cal, I love you. Ricky? Ricky! Oh, God!
Fans and NASCAR, everyone is talking
about this new driver, Jean Girard.
Let's find out a little bit more about
him from our reporter, Davey Wesling.
Talented. Eccentric. Dominating.
These are the words
that define Jean Girard.
Before each race, Jean Girard spends
time with his worldclass horses
Who are also gay.
Jean's days are filled
with sundrenched walks
With his beloved husband, Gregory.
Though Gregory is no stayathome spouse.
He's a worldclass trainer
of German shepherds.
Rolfe, the Nazi boyfriend. Up on top!
Very nice. Very nice.
Only time will tell if
Jean's foray into NAS CAR
Will end up in Victory Lane.
Well, kiss my ass on Sunday.
Lucius, what the hell is
going on? The man can drive.
And check out his crew chief over there.
Won the Nobel Prize
for physics back in '93.
Ladies and gentlemen,
that is a new track record.
As it stands now, Jean Girard is
sitting on the pole, which is, of course
A statement of fact
and in no way a comment
On the driver's sexual orientation.
Put a smile on your face? That's
the future of Dennit Racing.
That make you happy? I'm
just thrilled, Mr. Dennit.
I love seeing some
French guy break my record
While I got my arm wrapped
up like a fricking gordita.
Hello, Ricky Bobby.
What happened last week was
very regrettable and unfortunate
And, as a gesture, I would like to
Sign your cast, please.
Hell, you know what, get my
car off the trailer, guys.
Baby! That's my baby!
Hold on, Ricky. Ricky, Ricky,
Rick. What are you talking about?
Look. I wanna drive. My arm's fine.
So let's get the car off the trailer.
Don't look at me. Get
it off the trailer!
Even with a healthy arm, you don't
have a chance against Jean Girard.
All right, fellas. You heard the
man. Get the car off. Let's go.
You guys heard it.
What's going on? Soon you
will know what it is like
To be defeated by the hands of
somebody who is truly better than you.
As William Blake wrote, "The
cut worm forgives the plow."
Well, let me just quote the
late, great Colonel Sanders
Who said, "I'm too drunk
to taste this chicken."
What's that got to do with this?
I got a message for all of
them. Ready? Shake and Bake!
What does that do? Does that blow
your mind? That just happened!
What is that, a catch
phrase or is that epilepsy?
Shake and Bake. Shake and Bake. What?
Listen, you better be careful because
tomorrow you're going to get beaten.
Beaten real bad, cowboy.
Really? Yes!
I don't want to know. That's news to me.
Tomorrow you'll be in trouble.
I'll rip you a new one.
There's going to be a croissant
I'm going to take away.
I play for keeps!
I give you one option, Monsieur Bobby.
As a sign of humility, if
you kiss me on the lips now
I will return to Paris and you
will never see me again in NASCAR.
The answer is never!
I close my Do you hear me? Never ever!
Well, yes or no? That's sick.
Let me tell you, hold
on. Shake and Bake.
Yeah!
What does that mean? It makes no sense!
This "Shake and Bake," it's nonsense.
Hey, baby. You guys are
so smooth. Thanks, darling.
Cal, you could say that 10,000 times
and it still wouldn't be enough.
It fires me up. I love
it. Say it one more time.
Shake and Bake! Doesn't that feel good?
Yeah! It rhymes, they're
both verbs. It's awesome.
NAS CAR on Fox welcomes
you to Lowe's Motor Speedway
Where tonight we'll go 500 miles.
The big stories tonight are
at both ends of the grid.
Up front, Larry, the surprising
French Formula One driver, Jean Girard.
And at the opposite end of
the grid, Darrell, Ricky Bobby.
I saw Ricky Bobby last night walking
around with a cast on his arm.
Now, I don't know who he conned
into letting him start this race.
Just keep a camera
on him all night long.
I am so excited.
This is a new era for
Dennit Racing, huh?
So serious all the time
about your big race team.
Who cares? But this is
my life. This is my life.
You know what? There's only one
good thing about coming to the races
And that is the
vibrations from the cars.
Oh, I love when them cars whiz by.
Can feel the motor
Running up my legs.
Ricky Bobby, who never met
a sponsor he wouldn't push
Has a Fig Newton sticker
on his windshield.
Think NAS CAR will
blackflag him for that.
He sold the windshield!
This sticker is dangerous and
inconvenient, but I love Fig Newtons.
Ricky Bobby started
this race in the back
But he's making no friends
on the way to the front.
I'm all about getting to the front
tonight, Lucius. Let's go! Let's move it!
Well, he's driving like a man possessed.
I'm not even sure he realizes how
much damage he's doing to his car.
Hey, Ricky. You know you're driving
like a pissedoff teenager, okay?
Where is that Frenchy?
I got you, Pepe Le Bitch.
Oh, Ricky Bobby.
Hey, it's me, America.
Yeah, I'm here.
You have spilled my macchiato.
Look at Girard in the 55.
He's made that car three lanes
wide, but he's still fast.
No, no, no, my friend. This
way also closed. Not this way.
Lucius, what's he doing?
He's everywhere at once.
Guy's dangerous, Ricky.
He's like a cobra. Back off!
Where's Cal? I need
a little support here!
Tell Ricky I'm on my way.
Damn it!
Hey, Ricky, listen.
Cal blew out his engine.
You have no backup. Back off!
I ain't backing off. I'm Ricky
Bobby, I'm the best there is.
He's too good, Ricky. Lay off!
Bobby's boxed in. There's
nowhere to go there.
He's gonna try the outside move
again. I don't know if it's gonna work.
Come on, Daddy!
Come on, Daddy! Whoop his butt!
Send that weird man back to Indonesia.
Come on! Bobby moves to the outside.
Not a lot of room. He's in the wall!
Bobby is sliding,
slamming into the wall.
He's airborne!
Yep. I'm flying through
the air. This is not good.
Ricky! Cool!
Ricky!
Peaches and cream!
The car comes to rest
in a big cloud of smoke.
Ricky Bobby appears to be okay
But that Wonder Bread car is toast.
Fantastic.
Oh, my God! Ricky!
Hakuna matata, bitches.
It's okay, guys, it's just
a wreck. Ricky can handle it.
Now, that's one of the
nastiest wrecks you'll ever see.
Oh, no, no, no.
It's all right. You're safe.
You're safe. We got you. We're here.
I'm on fire.
It's all right. It's all
right, you're not on fire!
You're lying! I'm on
fire! There is no fire.
I'm on fire. I don't
wanna die. Come back here.
But something looks wrong. I mean,
he's running around like he's on fire.
Oh, my God! Help me! I don't
wanna die! Stop, drop, and roll!
You're not on fire,
Ricky Bobby! I'm on fire!
You're not on fire.
But I'm not even sure he even
knows where he's at right now.
This makes us all realize the kind
of pressure these drivers are under.
Mr. Bobby, come on down here.
Help me, Jesus! Help me, Jewish God!
Help me, Allah!
Help me, Tom Cruise!
But how did he get down
to his underwear that fast?
Tom Cruise, use your witchcraft
on me to get the fire off me!
Look. Here, help's coming.
Wait a minute! It's Cal Naughton.
Oh, God! Please don't let the
invisible fire burn my friend!
I got you! I got you,
man! I'll help you!
He's jumping on Ricky, trying
to put the nonexistent fire out.
Now, that's a teammate right there.
This is going downhill fast.
It would be a great time
to go to commercial break.
Help me, Oprah Winfrey!
You know, Larry, there's good days
in racing, and there's bad days.
Ricky Bobby just had himself a bad day.
He's suffering from catatonic shock.
His injuries are minor, but right now he
can't deal with the trauma of the wreck.
Golly, this is a hard decision.
But I have thought about it,
and I want the plug pulled.
Yeah.
Ma'am, your husband's not dying.
He's just taking a nap.
Just look at him. No, I'm not lying.
I've never seen him
make that noise. Ever.
Got more plugs in him
than a Circuit City.
Oh, baby. Mama loves you so much.
Hey, Ricky. It's me, Cal.
Just want you to know, I got
your back, bro. No matter what.
There's something I
want to get off my chest
And it's about that summer when
you went away to community college.
I got a offer to do Playgirl magazine
And I did it.
I did a full spread
for Playgirl magazine.
I mean spread, man. I pulled
my butt apart and stuff
And I was totally
nude, and it was weird.
You probably didn't hear about it
Because I went under
the name of Mike Honcho.
But I just wanted you to know that.
If you could hear me, if it
got into your brain somehow
That I spread my butt
cheeks as Mike Honcho.
"Are you there, God? It's me, Margaret.
Gretchen, my friend, got her
period. I'm so jealous, God.
I hate myself for being
so jealous, but I am.
I wish you'd help me just a little.
Nancy's sure she's going to get
it soon too. And if I'm last...."
Hey, Ricky. Ricky!
Come on, man, wake up.
Are you faking it?
Are you faking it? Fake it!
I don't know how much longer I
can take seeing you like this.
I am not gonna let you die here
Like some kind of vegetable.
I'm gonna put an end to this right now.
Get all this crap off you.
You don't need any of this crap.
This is it. This is how it ends.
This is how Shake and Bake ends.
It's shadow time, buddy.
It's time to go home to Jesus.
Goodbye, buddy.
Oh, wow, you definitely
You definitely still
got some fight in you.
Okay, maybe we give this another day.
Middle. I'll go up to the
middle. Let's play some defense!
I just wanna say thanks, doc,
for taking care of our boy here.
Oh, shit. That's a foul! That's a foul!
Doc, give it to me straight.
Is he ever gonna be able to walk again?
Oh, I'm sorry, I thought
someone had told you. He's fine.
He found that wheelchair in the hallway.
His paralysis is entirely psychosomatic.
But we all need to go along with
this, because he's in a delicate state.
So when you say
psychosomatic, you mean, like
He could start a fire with his thoughts?
No, not at all. It means
it's all in his mind.
I'm saying, sometimes you get a knock
on the head, you get special powers.
It happens all the time.
Read a comic book, okay?
Everyone's real friendly.
It doesn't hurt being Ricky
Bobby. I'm not gonna lie to you.
So how's the physical therapy going?
Oh, I gave that up. Yeah, I gave that up
After maybe the first day. Within
the first hour, I gave that up.
I'm through lying to myself, you know?
It's time to be mature about
this and just face facts.
I bought myself a hundredthousanddollar
Handicapaccessible van
With the captain's chairs and the DVD
plasma screens in the back for the kids.
You all paid up on that?
Yeah. That's all paid in full.
It's parked out there. And
then the next thing I gotta do
Is I just gotta have a sitdown
with Carley and just let her know
That it's okay for her to
seek the comfort of other men.
Because she's gotta run wild. You
can't keep something like that back.
Hold on, man. Hold....
We gotta tell him. Now?
No, I don't care what the doctor
said, we gotta tell him now.
Ricky, the doctor told us
That we should let you work
it out in your own sweet time
But, Ricky, you can walk.
What did you just say?
He's telling you the truth,
man. It's all in your head.
You sick sons of bitches!
I mean, you walk in that door
On your two legs, all fat and cocky
And looking at me in my chair, and
you tell me it's all in my head?
I hope that both of you have sons.
Handsome, beautiful, articulate sons
who are talented and star athletes
And they have their legs taken away!
I pray you know that pain and that hurt.
Don't you put that
evil on me, Ricky Bobby!
Don't you put that on
us! You are not paralyzed!
I am so paralyzed!
No, no, no! No, he needs to know!
Getting a little rough on him.
He's always crying! Tough
love, it is. Tough love.
Wake up, idiot! You
wanna know what I am?!
You wanna see what my life is?!
Don't do it.
You wanna see what's going on here?
Don't you stick that knife in your leg.
Man! Hold on, hold on.
Hold on, now. Walk it
off. Oh, that hurts.
Oh, my! Walk it off.
Stretch, stretch. Stretch it out.
Hey, man. You can walk! You can walk!
I can walk!
I think I touched a nerve. Right there.
All right, we got it, we
got it. Hold it right there.
Maybe don't touch it.
Can you feel it? I can!
We'll use this knife to pry
it out. We'll pull it out.
Now we got two in there.
Just don't think about it.
We're going down a bad
path. Cut around the meat.
I'll cut right here. Stretch it out.
Just take out a plug of
meat. Just like a deer.
We gotta wiggle it a little bit.
That's it. Can you feel that?
Yeah, I feel that. You are back!
I love you guys!
Hey, I'm sorry, guys. I mean, I
hope your boys don't lose their legs.
Thanks, buddy. So when
do I get to drive again?
Well, that's the thing. The doctor
said you suffered major trauma
And he thinks you should
take it slow for a while.
Yeah, so, I was thinking, like,
while you're resting up and stuff
Maybe you could let me win
a few. Well, there you go.
Yeah, that ain't gonna happen.
Yeah. I'm Ricky Bobby. I
mean, you know how I play it.
Yeah. First or last, right, baby?
Don't know what I was thinking. Besides
Dennit Jr. Must be freaking
out. All the money he's losing?
Without me on the track?
I mean, I just laugh
Thinking about him whining all
the time, bitching and moaning:
"Damn, I wish Ricky was here."
You know what I mean?
What?
Frenchy can drive.
Oh, no.
Very good.
C'est la vie and que sera, sera.
It looks like the
NASCAR has gone French.
Well, in other news, Ricky Bobby
Is going to be running some test
laps this weekend at Rockingham
In an attempt to come
back from his grisly crash.
It's one of the hardest
things to do in racing.
To try to bounce back after
a devastating, violent wreck.
Ricky Bobby was traumatized
during the incident.
All right, baby. Come on, now.
But today he gets to strap back into
a racecar for the first time since
To try to show he can
still get the job done.
He's gonna be great. Yep.
He's gonna be great, sure.
Would you stop staring at
me like that, Susan? I swear
You are the weirdest
little girl I've ever seen.
Okay, I'm really gonna open it up!
I missed you, Mama
Speed. Ricky Bobby's back.
Wait, how fast is he going?
Twentysix miles an hour.
What were those things?
Were those the other cars?
Oh, God. So fast.
Go, baby! There you are.
Am I on fire? I'm on fire.
No, no, you're not on
fire. Stretch it out.
It's okay, baby. Take it easy.
Oh, God, I'm gonna get sick. Oh, God.
Oh, he's in his underwear again.
Ricky! Please put your clothes on.
He's in his underwear
again. Go get him, fellas.
Oh, Lord.
You know who's gonna be
number one at Dennit Racing?
Not Ricky? I'm gonna windmill you.
Mr. Cal Naughton Jr.
Come back at him. It's
the only way. Who are you?
Number one. No.
Oh, yes, ma'am. Ricky! Come on, man!
It's embarrassing.
The ninjas are trying to get me.
Oh, my God. What happened?
What happened? He's done. He's done.
That's what's happened.
It's over. He's finished.
What's gonna happen to me?
I feel like I was riding inside an
asteroid or a comet or something.
Yeah, you were going fast.
Look at that. What are we gonna do?
This is ugly. This is bad
for all of us. Look at that.
I gotta go check on cuckoo
bird. No, cuckoo's okay.
Why don't you get over there
and settle down Carley for me?
Could you do that for me? Yes, sir.
There you go.
What began as a day of hope and optimism
For Ricky Bobby and his race team
has ended here in sad disappointment.
There we go, boy.
I lost all muscle
control. Yeah, you did.
He just lost his muscle control
is all. I lost my muscle control.
He's fine. He just can't
control the muscles.
Thanks for the lift,
Hershell. Yeah, no problem.
Jenga!
I love you, Cal.
Good one, kiddo. What
the hell's going on?
Hey, Ricky, nice of you
to stop by for a visit.
What do you mean, a
visit? This is my house.
Baby
Shoot. I'm so sorry.
I really I didn't
want it to be this way.
Hey, what happened to
the family portrait?
You just crudely pasted
your face over mine.
We're getting married, Ricky.
And we're getting matching
leprechaun tattoos.
Isn't that cute? With
a little pot of gold.
Is this some kind of joke?
You guys putting me on?
I was gone three hours. Dennit
just fired me from the team.
Ricky, you and I
We both know that this marriage
has been over for a long, long time.
No! I honestly did not know that!
Ricky, you can't race no more.
I'm not going back to being poor
and dancing at the Wizard's Den.
You know, my old boyfriend Greg?
He still works there and he was crazy.
Baby, stop.
Wait. Hold on. Hold on. Just a second.
Let me make sure I got this straight.
Are you asking me for a divorce?
Yay! Two Christmases!
Cal?
How could you do this to me, man?
Ricky, your marriage was a hollow shell.
It was a cruel charade.
She just gave me the
411 on the whole deal.
And you know what else? You
never let me win one time.
I thought we had a good
thing going. Shake and Bake.
You're doing great. You
just keep it up. Keep it up.
And Mr. Dennit told me
that it's my time now.
Oh, really? That Shake and Bake is dead.
And we just came up with a new nickname.
It's so good. It's so
good. I got a new nickname.
The Magic Man. Now you see me
Now you don't.
That is the stupidest
nickname I've ever heard.
Is it, Ricky?
Because I think you
wish you thought of it.
All right. You got me.
That's an awesome nickname.
I've always had a lot of great ideas.
I also think I might design a car
that's in the shape of a rabbit.
It might poop out little real rabbits
out the back that'll run around the track.
You have live rabbits being
pooped out onto a track?
If I win, I might do a special
thing with David Copperfield
Where he hides in my
car in the passenger seat
And he just flings magic
stuff out the window.
Did you run any of this by NASCAR?
Watch the mail for that invitation to
the wedding, because I want you there.
What?! I know it
That some bad stuff happened
just now, but in time
The wedding's not for a couple of weeks.
Why would I come to your guys' wedding?
You're gonna get over
it and be my best man.
I'm not gonna be your best man!
Baby, he's not gonna
come to the wedding.
Cal, do you realize the implications
of your actions right now?
What's "implication" mean?
We are no longer friends.
Why? What do you mean, "Why?"
You're wrecking my life!
You just lost your wife.
You just lost your job.
Don't throw out your best
friend because of your anger.
That's absolutely ridiculous, man. Ricky
Remember, the field mouse is
fast, but the owl sees at night.
That's kind of creepy, ain't it?
Hey, Ricky, I'll call
you tomorrow. Shut up.
Bye, kids. I'll see
you next weekend. Bye.
Ricky! Boys! Is everything all right?
Mama, we got nowhere to go.
Carley and Cal took everything.
Well, you're home now,
and you got your mama.
Get in here, boys. Come on.
Come on. Get in this house.
Hey, Ricky. Are you on fire?
Nice denim shorts,
dude. Hey, shut up, man.
Hump me!
Now, you watch yourself.
Yes, sir. I'm sorry. I
promise it won't happen again.
Hey, sorry, man.
Hey.
I lost my license.
That's why I'm on the
bus. I'm delivering pizzas.
Motherfucker, what
makes you think I care?
Shut the fuck up!
I was just telling you that because
Like I said, I lost my license. I've
been having a lot of problems lately.
Problems? I don't wanna hear
about your damn problems.
Everybody got problems.
My mama got problems.
She just lost her leg.
My cousin Pookie just lost a testicle.
My dog threw up somebody's finger.
That's a problem.
I really regret opening my
mouth and talking to you.
Sorry. Sorry. Get out of the road!
Hey, come on, man. I'm on a bike. Relax.
Hey, shut up! Idiot!
It's open.
Hugalo's Pizza. We are pizza.
You are pizza? Yeah, we
are pizza. I gotta say it.
Either close the door or come
in. I got weed in here, cowboy.
You got three pizzas that haven't
been eaten just sitting over there.
I know. I've been calling
them all day trying to get you
But they keep sending me
different delivery people.
Trying to get me? Why?
Because I'm your daddy, that's why.
What did you just say?
I said, I'm your daddy.
I'm Reese Bobby.
Me and your mama did it in a Rustler
Steak House bathroom when I was 17.
And then you showed up.
Hey, son.
Son! Son, did this go good? No!
Seems to me like it went
pretty good. You're not my dad.
It got a little heated,
but.... Stop talking to me!
Hey, is that a Huffy? That's
a nicelooking bike, boy.
I can't believe it!
I mean, he's been blowing
me off for 25 years
And now he wants to get to know me?
How the hell did he even find me?
I called him.
Are you kidding me? Mama,
why did you go do that?
Son, you need help.
I know he's a son of
a bitch. He's scary.
But you're a grown man. You're
delivering pizzas on a bike.
How'd you even get hooked up
with him in the first place?
You probably couldn't
tell by looking at him now
But your daddy used
to be a real charmer.
And that night in the ladies' room of
the Rustler Steak House, he chose me.
In a ladies' room? Shut up
in here! I'm trying to sleep!
One of you turds is about
to get smacked in the mouth!
Hey, stop yelling at me, okay?
I'm your dad. You're 7 years old.
Don't talk like that.
Hey. Hey there, Lucy.
How you doing?
Oh, hey there, Ricky. Look, son
I know you don't want me to be here
But I saw what happened to you on
the television. You saw the fear.
I can help you with that, son. Really?
What do you care about me or us?
You never even met your grandkids.
What are you looking at, Popeye?
Shut up, you little potlicker.
I'll put you in a microwave.
Now, you show me the DNA test
And then maybe I'll say
hello to these swamp rats.
You people shut the hell up! I got a
wife in an oxygen tent trying to sleep.
You better shut up or I'll come over
there and rip a hole in that tent.
Yeah, shut up, Frank!
Go shave your balls, you dusty old fart!
Okay, I guess they are my grandkids.
I know you, son. I know you well.
You're just like me. Talladega's
coming up in a couple of weeks
And I know you wanna win
that thing. No, I don't.
Listen, Ricky.
I'm 55 years old and all
I got to my name is a car
And a duffle bag full of
underwear, and sweet, stinky weed.
How much you selling
that weed for, old man?
I know I screwed up raising you as a boy
But just let me help you as a man.
Do it, Dad. Get your
balls back. Go fast again.
Fine. I'll do it.
But I ain't calling you Daddy.
Well, what you gonna call me?
All right, Professor
Dickweed. What's the plan?
Well, basically, what happened
to you is that you saw the fear.
So before you can even
think about any real driving
You gotta make friends with
that fear. So get in the car.
What the hell?! There's a
goddamn cougar in the car!
I know there's a cougar,
I put it in there.
You gotta learn to drive with the fear.
Ain't nothing more damn frightening
than driving with a cougar in the car.
God, where'd you get
that thing? I trapped it.
Been keeping it in my bathroom at
the motel, feeding it old pizza.
Now get back in that car, you hear
me? No, I'm not getting in that car.
Hey, listen to me. If you're calm,
that wondrous big cat will be calm too.
But if you're scared
That beautiful death machine
will do what God made it to do
Namely, eat you with
a smile on its face.
God, he's just following
me wherever I go.
Well, he's just looking at you.
You're saying if I just calm
down, the cougar will be okay?
You got it. Damn it. Okay.
Come on, son. You can do it. Come on.
Oh, come on.
That's it.
And no sudden moves. Like, is
this too fast? Oh, man. See?
That's a little quick.
You see what he did?
You gotta be a little more
deliberate in your movement.
I'm just gonna get in there.
I'm just gonna grab the handle.
I'm gonna get in and drive
that car. I'm gonna do it calm.
Calm. Piece of cake. I was
just trying to stay calm.
Oh, man! Sometime today, son.
Okay, here we go. I'm getting in.
Oh, God, help me!
Ricky! Control your
heart rate. Oh, my God!
Hey, Mama.
Well, hey there, Ricky. How'd it go?
Well, I was mauled by a cougar
Learned nothing about driving, and
my Crystal Gayle shirt was ruined.
But other than that, it went fine.
Where are the boys at?
I dropped them off at Sunday school
at my church about 10 minutes ago.
Anarchy!
Anarchy! Anarchy! Anarchy!
There they are. What in tarnation?
Anarchy! I don't even
know what that means
But I love it!
What in the hell? That is it!
That puts the lid right on the jar!
Mama! Mama! No, Ricky, no.
I will not have my grandbabies
acting like shiftless, wild hobos.
All right, now, you boys
listen up, and you listen good.
Now, I am declaring Granny Law.
And if you do not obey Granny Law
I will paint your back porch red.
Sorry, Granny, but
you're shit out of Iuck.
We make the rules, not you.
Hey!
You're gonna break us like
wild horses, ain't you?
It's the beginning of a new age.
Hey, Derek, it's Ricky.
Just wondering if you can ditch school
And take over my shift
at the pizza place
Because I got strep throat.
And it's bad. I don't wanna
give it to everyone else.
So call me back. You know the number.
Hello.
Hey, man. How's it going?
You wanna come over and party?
Did you just say "party"?
You know what? No. Because
I still hate you, okay?
What are you so mad about?
What do you think I'm mad about?
Come on, man, that was last week.
What about the time you
ran over my leg with a car?
I let that go that
day. Yeah, I remember.
Wind is kicking up.
Are you in the hot tub?
Answer me this: When you're in spa mode
How come the water
level drops in the spa?
Are you pressing the buttons in
the back panel or in the kitchen?
I just started pressing stuff.
Hey, don't press all those buttons.
I'm getting bored. You wanna
come over and play G.I. Joes?
I would love to. No!
Come on. You know what? Screw you, man.
Ricky, man, you gotta
cross over the anger bridge.
Come back to the friendship shore.
"Cross over the anger bridge"?
Yeah, that's where you're at.
You're stuck on an anger bridge.
Can you not see why I'm
stuck on the anger bridge?
Look, I don't know why I'm
talking to you, okay? What is it?
They got bottomless
nachos at Bennigan's.
God, a whole mess of nachos
sounds good right now.
I don't have a car no
more. Can you come get me?
I'll get you. Which one of your cars do
you miss the most? I'll bring that one.
I miss the Hummer. I'm
coming in the Hummer.
Are you ready? Yeah. No, wait.
Okay. Our friendship is done. All right?
You hear? You wanna
hang out in your house.
Come on. Screw you,
dude. I'm hanging up.
Okay, that's it. Bye.
Oh, man, this is absolutely crazy.
I mean, this is borderline reckless.
Don't you get it? You don't drive with
your eyes, you drive with your heart.
This is just dumb. I can't see a thing.
You gotta feel the road. You
gotta let it live inside you.
Are you feeling anything
now? I'm feeling a little bit.
What do you feel? Tell
me what you're feeling.
I'm feeling the worn wood
of the steering wheel.
Yeah. What else? A little bit of heat.
That's you and the car melded together.
Yeah, now I'm really feeling it. I
feel like the car could drive itself.
I bet it could. Start her up.
I'm gonna start this car up.
Attaboy. All right, son.
Drive.
I'm embarrassed. I really
thought I could feel it.
You know what? We better hightail it
out of here. Frank's gonna be pissed.
All right.
No, no, Ricky. No blindfold.
Get this highway clean, come on.
I gotta tell you, Granny, this blows.
How much more of this? I don't know.
How many more times are you gonna
toss me the radio in the bathtub?
Hello? Hey, man. You up?
No. Wake up. I need to talk to you.
I think your house is haunted.
Hey, come on. It's 2:30 in the morning.
I can't sleep in here, man. I'm scared.
Look, there's nothing to be
scared of. It's a new house
There's a lot of creaks
and moans and groans in it.
Put on You got your TV on? Well,
yeah, I fell asleep with it on.
Turn on channel 42. Fortytwo?
Look at them buns. Well,
that is a set of buns.
And down, and down, and
What's she doing exercising
at 2:30 in the morning?
Oh, yeah, that's a really good point.
I don't know why I'm talking to
you. Do you remember that I hate you?
Hey, man, you know what I was thinking?
You're lucky. I'm lucky?
How so? Well, check it out.
I'm sitting here in this enormous
haunted mansion, can't sleep.
You're hanging out at
your mom's. That's awesome.
That's, like, the opposite of awesome.
Well, this is like a hotel room
With someone else's junk in it.
Okay, yeah, well, that someone
else's junk, that used to be my stuff.
I'm just having a hard time, man.
I'm just calling up for some support.
Do you? Do you know
how crazy that sounds?
Hey, one more thing. Yeah?
When you have the stereo on
at the same time as the TV
How do you control the volume on the TV?
Why do you want to listen
to the TV with the stereo on?
Because I like to party.
Why am I still talking to you?
Come on. We were doing good there, man.
I'm taking care of your house good.
I keep snapping back into it. It's
like a trick you're pulling on me.
All right. I'll talk to you tomorrow.
All right, man. Talk to you tomorrow.
Shit.
Get out.
Where did stockcar racing come from?
What?
Hey, stop doing that. How did
stockcar racing get its start?
Bootleggers in Prohibition had to have
cars fast enough to outrun the Feds
Then they started racing
each other. That's right.
If I was right, why'd you
throw another bucket on me?
I filled up three. Now, there's
nothing like driving to avoid jail.
Nothing hones your mind and
your instincts like necessity.
So I taped a kilo of cocaine underneath
the car and called the boys in blue.
Now, the way I figure it,
you got about two minutes
Before they show up
and you do five to 10.
So, what's it gonna be? Fear or prison?
What the hell are you talking
about? Real simple, son.
Cops are coming.
There's a kilo of Colombian bambam
under the car. Time to be a man.
You got hair on your peaches or what?
You're not kidding, are you? Man.
You crazy creep!
Come on, son. What's it gonna be?
Speed or jail?
Grandpa, would you
like to take us fishing
And tell us life lessons and
stories about your childhood?
I got a better idea.
Why don't you boys go dig a
hole and I'll get another beer?
Someone didn't love you enough
when you were little, did they?
Good call. Here, that's worth a nickel.
Tragic.
Son of a bitch, son of
a bitch, son of a bitch.
Oh, man. Oh, man!
Onesixteen. Onesixteen!
I'm going fast again!
Pull over! Pull over!
Pull over? I'll pull over
for you. How about this?
Where are you?
Gotcha.
"Feels good going fast, doesn't it?
By the way, don't try and snort
these Lucky Charms. Reese."
Okay.
There you go, little man.
Hey, Ricky!
How you doing?
Oh, Nana, not my prison
shank. In the can.
There's your
motherflipping driving test.
Mr. Bobby, you are magnificent.
Down, Karen! Get down! Get down, Karen!
It's all right. It's gonna be okay.
Well, son, you are looking
good behind that wheel.
Thanks, Daddy. I gotta tell you,
I feel good. Heck, you know what?
Let's go out tonight, you
know, the whole family.
I'm talking about sitting
down, enjoying a gourmet meal
At a place that's real special.
Hi. Those plates are hot.
Enjoy. You got your own skillet.
Be back to check on you
in a minute. Thank you.
Oh, gooder than grits.
Let us pray.
Dear Lord baby Jesus
Lying there in your little ghost manger
Just looking at your Baby
Einstein developmental videos
Learning about shapes and colors and....
We just have so much to be thankful for.
First off, my sons no longer act
Like retarded gangbangers. Amen.
Also, I got my balls back
behind the wheel of a car.
And most importantly, we thank you
For bringing back our nasty,
delinquent, potdealing daddy to us.
For he was lost, but
now he is found. Amen.
Amen. Amen.
Son, that was lovely.
What a lovely meal. It sure is.
It certainly does look delicious.
I gotta tell you, this is about
a damn perfect evening right now.
It is, isn't it?
You know what we should do?
Every week, we should come
back to this Applebee's
And sit at this table,
and have a family meal.
That's a great idea, Mama.
And order the same stuff.
That would be great. And
I would be delighted, Reese
If you would accompany me to
ballroom dancing on Tuesday nights.
Tuesday night? It's a lot of fun.
I think you'd have a good time.
How's everybody doing here?
Dolly, it's so good. Oh,
it's really, really good.
You know, I just I hate
to be a pain, darling
But I asked for no onions
on my Bourbon Steak.
I am so sorry. I thought
you asked for onions
Okay, okay, maybe don't interrupt me.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to.
Yeah, well, I think you did mean to
And I also think that you meant
to put the damn onions on my steak.
Okay, Reese. Grandfather
Can't we resolve this
conflict without anger?
I'm a veteran and a diabetic! Dad!
Dad! Why are you doing
this? Applebee's has rats!
I found a whole rat in my Cobb salad!
Dad, where are you going?
Come on, frat boy, you wanna go?
What's going on, man? Ricky, let him go!
Things were going good, weren't they?
That's exactly why I had to blow it up.
I don't know what organ
or bone people have
That makes them act right, but I
was born without it. I'm no good.
All those races I won, that
was for you, you know that?
I did just like you told me: "If
you ain't first, you're last."
What the hell are you talking about?
What you told me that day
at school for career day.
You came in and you said, "If
you ain't first, you're last."
Oh, hell, Ricky, I was
high when I said that.
That doesn't make any sense at all.
"You're first or last." You can be
second, you can be third, fourth.
Hell, you can even be fifth.
What are you talking about? I
lived my whole life based on that.
Well, now what the hell
am I supposed to do?
Well, that's the milliondollar
question, isn't it?
Good luck to you, son.
Hey, Dad!
Where are you going?
Does it matter?
Here we go.
Hey, don't bump me.
Oh, man, I'm flying.
Game over. Come on, reset.
Boy, you are a terrible driver, no?
How'd you get on a video game so fast?
Is your name, by chance, Ricky Bobby?
Hey, screw you, man! I
got nothing because of you!
I hate you! Hey, Ricky.
I am on fire. I am on fire.
Susan?
And so then I got a
marketing job with NASCAR.
Really? Yeah, it's great. It's great.
Well, gosh, you look fantastic.
Thank you. I mean,
you've always looked good.
I mean, I'm just I'm happy for you.
Thank you.
But what about you?
How have you been? What
have you been doing?
Well, they want me to race at Talladega
next weekend, but I'm not gonna do it.
Because I'm done. I'm done
with the racing, with driving.
Why would you do that?
Because I've really moved on.
I've sent in my application
to The Real World
So I'm hoping to hear back.
I'm putting a lot of my eggs
into that basket, the MTV basket.
I'm also thinking about
getting a gun and dealing crack.
Being a crack dealer, but not like
a mean crack dealer, but like a....
You know, like a nice one.
Just kind of friendly, like, "Hey
What's up, guys? You want some crack?"
I'm just waiting on those two things
to kind of flesh themselves out.
You know what, Ricky?
I have kept my mouth shut for
a really, really long time.
And I just don't think that
I can keep it shut anymore.
I just have to tell you that I
think you are making a big mistake.
Really? Yes.
Why is it that you always
fall for people who leave you?
Have you noticed that?
Like Carley and your
dad and your sponsors.
And you always have
to prove yourself. Wh?
Well, you gotta listen to me here, okay?
You gotta win to get
love. Everyone knows that.
I mean, that's just life.
Look at Don Shula, legendary coach.
Look at that Asian guy
who holds the worId record
For eating all those hot dogs in a row.
Look at Rue McClanahan
from The Golden Girls.
All three people, all
great champions, all loved.
Do you wanna know why I think
that you should race again?
Sure. Why?
Okay. It's because it's
what you love, Ricky.
It is who you were born to be.
And here you sit, thinking.
Well, Ricky Bobby is not a
thinker. Ricky Bobby is a driver.
He is a doer. And that's
what you need to do.
You don't need to
think, you need to drive.
You need speed. You need to go out
there, and you need to rev your engine.
You need to fire it up.
You need to grab hold of the
line between speed and chaos
And you need to wrestle it to
the ground like a demon cobra.
And then, when that fear rises
up in your belly, you use it
And you know that fear is
powerful because it has been there
For billions of years! And it is
good, and you use it, and you ride it.
You ride it like a skeleton
horse through the gates of hell
And then you win! You win!
You don't win for anybody else,
you win for you. You know why?
Because a man takes what
he wants, he takes it all.
And you're a man,
aren't you? Aren't you?
Susan, I've never heard
you talk like that.
Are we about to get it on?
Because I'm as hard as a diamond
in an ice storm right now.
This is awesome. Yes, it is.
Are you climbing on
the table now? Yes, sir.
I can't believe this.
This is like that Whitesnake
video where the girI crawIs on....
Yeah. Just like that. What's her name?
Tawny Kitaen. She's really good.
She's great. She's fantastic.
Everyone, turn away.
Things are gonna get crazy.
We're gonna make animal noises.
Looks good, damn good.
Yeah. That's good, guys.
Yeah, Ricky, it's good to be back.
Talladega. Talladega.
I missed you dudes.
Even you too, Glenn.
I didn't have a whole lot of money
left, but what I did I put into the car.
We got some lowerend sponsors,
so it's nothing to shout about
But at least we got something to run in.
Let's see what we got, guys.
What are we looking at?
"Julio's thongs for men"?
Come on, what kind
of dude wears a thong?
Yeah, that's messed up.
Perverts, you know?
It's not the best car, but it'll move.
Hold on, now, baby. Let's just see
what this thing's got under the hood.
There she is. Looks like
the Pep Boys threw up.
Damn. Like I said, work in progress.
All right, I tell you what we gotta
do. Since we got no corporate money
We have to build this engine ourselves.
I want you to hit up every independent
driver out there for spare parts.
Yeah, Lucius, that's crazy.
Well, crazy is all we got
right now, okay? So do it.
Now, where you going?
I wanna tell Gerard Depardieu
we're coming for him.
There you go, baby. Give him hell.
Get this engine built. Get it built.
I have not finished.
Monsieur Girard, Ricky
Bobby is here to see you.
This is the one I was
talking about, Ricky Bobby.
Thank you, Bacco. Go.
You're a tough man to
find. You know that, buster?
I prefer solitude the day before a race.
I am being so incredibly
rude, Monsieur Bobby.
Let me introduce you to my lunch guests.
This is my dear old
friend EIvis Costello.
Delightful to meet you, Mr.
Robert. I thought you were dead.
And next to him is hiphop artist,
poet and my brotherinlaw, Mos Def.
I like your driving style.
I'm more of a Tony Stewart man
Number 20 car, myself.
How he gets into those straightaways.
Gets it in the paint. Get her done!
And across from Monsieur Def
Is Breeze.
Hey. You're Breeze or you're
Breeze? Which one of you is Breeze?
Together we are Breeze.
They are like twins,
born from different wombs.
Right. They are God's most
Beautiful mistake.
They do everything together. Everything.
They read the same books.
They do Pilates together.
They walk, talk, sleep
Even go make toilet.
Okay, you're starting
to creep me out, man.
A single plop.
One single plop.
I don't need to hear
about doing a toilet.
You want more examples?
No, you listed like
8000. Less than that.
It's none of my business. More like
I don't know, between five and 10.
Look, I need to talk to you.
Walk with me, Ricky Bobby.
You have a good lunch. Take care, man.
Goodbye, Ricky. Goodbye.
Holding hands with a man makes
me terribly uncomfortable.
It is a sign of friendship
in many countries.
Well, not in ours.
There's nothing sexual about it.
Please don't be worried at
the fact I have an erection.
It has nothing to do
with you. Hey, come on.
Look. Here's the deal. I came
here to tell you one thing.
All right? Tomorrow, I'm coming for you.
Do you know why I came
to America, Ricky Bobby?
Public schools, healthcare
system, giant water parks.
I mean, the same reason
anyone comes to America.
I came here for you to beat me.
What the hell are you talking
about? My husband, Gregory, and I
Wish only for that which
every other couple wishes for:
To tame Komodo dragons in Sri Lanka
And teach them to perform Hamlet.
But before I can do that....
That's dumb. It's not dumb.
It is dumb. Why is it dumb?
I don't know. But before I can do that
I must be beaten by a driver
who's truly better than me.
So you're gonna lose to me on purpose?
No. No?
No!
I will battle you with
the entirety of my heart.
And you will probably lose.
But maybe, just maybe
You might challenge me.
God needs the devil.
The Beatles needed the Rolling Stones.
Even Diane Sawyer needed Katie Couric.
Will you be my Katie Couric?
I feel like I'm in Highlander.
What's the Highlander?
It's a movie.
Any good? Very good.
It won the Academy Award. Oh, for what?
For best movie ever made.
I just want you to know I came
here today to tell you one thing.
That come race time tomorrow,
I'm coming for you, all right?
May God be with you. Yeah.
Because although today I am friendly
Tomorrow will be war!
All right.
Ladies and gentlemen, pull up a chair,
drop the kids off with their aunt
And take the phone off the
hook because it's race day here
At the Talladega Superspeedway.
Hey, guys.
Why so down? Ricky
We were up all night working on the car.
And then something
happened. There was a fire.
Did you say "fire"?
Glenn is dead, Ricky.
I mean, he died last night in my arms
As I held him. Oh, man.
He was so scared, because
you know how little he is.
And death was coming for
him, and he stood there
And with a tear coming out his eyes,
he said, "Tell Ricky, win for me."
That's all that little bastard
wanted, was for you to win.
I wish you could've seen him.
I wish you could've felt
his little heart fluttering.
Sweet Jesus.
Poor Glenn.
Hey, what the hell,
man. Hey, Glenn. Glenn!
I see you. Glenn, what did I say?
I said, "Wait till after
the race." Was he crying?
I'm sorry, Ricky. We were just trying
to give you a little extra motivation.
Well, that is just sick, guys.
It's okay, Susie. I appreciate it, guys.
Just trying to help out
Even though it was weird and perverse.
They're just trying to help,
Ricky. We're a team here.
I appreciate it. Let's
see what's under the hood.
All right, let's have a look.
Hot dog. I mean, that's like looking
up Bridgette WilsonSampras' skirt.
We were up all night working on it.
Like I said, a lot of teams gave parts.
Nice work, guys.
And your sponsors weren't
doing very much, so
Well, we repainted the car.
Well, take a look. Come on, guys.
Well, I like the cougar,
but what company is "M.E."?
"Me" is you
Because it's just you out there.
We don't have any corporate sponsors.
We don't have any fancy team owners.
We have you
And this car, and this cougar
Which symbolizes the fear
that you have overcome.
It's all there for you.
Ricky, this car is like your Excalibur,
the mighty sword King Arthur used
To bring together the
Knights of the Round Table
Until Lancelot betrayed him by laying
with his queen, in the biblical sense.
Okay, Glenn.
Everything cool that
Susan said, you wrecked it.
Guys, let's go win
ourselves a race, all right?
There you go. Yeah! Right?
Let's get out there and win a race.
From Provence, France
Driver of the number 55 Perrier car
Jean Girard.
From West River, North Carolina
Driver of the number 47 Old Spice car
Cal Naughton Jr.
Hey, Carley.
Hey, Ricky. Carley! Hey, baby.
Baby.
Oh, hey, Ricky.
Hey, man. We missed you at the wedding.
You missed me at the wedding?
Oh, man, it was so classy.
We had a Styx cover band
and a nacho fountain.
Check it, it was a nacho fountain
with six kinds of cheese on it.
Liquid cheese? It cascaded down? Yeah.
Are you serious? Amazing.
Six different kinds.
Swiss, Havarti. What was the other one?
Gouda. Cheddar, Gouda.
That's the greatest
thing I ever heard of.
Bean buffet in front
of it. It was awesome.
Don't listen to him. And remember
one thing, he's the competition.
You're not very focused right
now. I need you to focus.
Hey. What?
I'm the Magic Man now.
Okay? Yeah, I know.
So get ready for some tricks
up these sleeves, all right?
Watch your buns, pal.
Baby, that is real good talk.
Like we practiced last night.
I got something to tell you,
you mangy piece of trash.
What? I'm sorry.
I took you for granted, Cal, and
you were a really good friend to me
And I never gave you
your due. It was my fault.
I'll tell you the truth. I'm a
little confused by your tactics.
Tactics? Yeah. I'm
gonna keep acting tough
Until I figure it out. All right?
See you on the track.
Come on, baby. I love you.
I love you too. Come on.
Abracadabra, homes.
Hi, Bill Weber, along with Wally
Dallenbach and Benny Parsons.
Thanks for having us. Today,
Talladega, NASCAR's biggest track
Where the big concern is the big wreck.
And it's not if it happens,
it's where and when.
We have a guy in the race today
that'll probably cause it, Ricky Bobby.
Starting in the rear of
the field, underfunded
And the last time we saw
him, he caused a big crash.
A lot of big stories and some
big questions here at Talladega.
All right, go get them.
You must decide, Ricky Bobby.
Is it foolish pride, or
is it greatness for you?
Hey, Jarvis! Go ahead, Cal.
If you slept with
your best friend's wife
Why would he apologize to you?
Yeah, I know. That's weird.
That's what I'm saying. My
head's all tied up like a pretzel.
I got a pretzel in my head.
Ricky! Come on, Dad!
I've got some big investors coming by.
These guys are bigmoney power players.
If things go right, they could have
us owning half the cars in NASCAR.
So I want you No, I want you to behave.
Oh, really? Quiet.
Should I not tell them
after 14 years of marriage
You're still afraid to
let me see you naked?
That's not a fear thing,
it's a trust thing.
Hey! I was wondering
where you guys got off to.
Baby, this is Ted
Beamen from Halliburton.
Nice to meet you. Over here
Is Dick Tangfield from Dynacorp.
Back there is.... You
have beautiful teeth.
Yes, he does. Get yourselves down there.
Adorable. Make yourselves at home
Grab something to eat, over
here.... Sweetheart, sweetheart.
You're a sweetie pie.
She's very affectionate.
She suffered a recent loss
You taste good too.
So she's a little emotional.
Okay, that's fine. Go ahead, find a
seat. Can we get these guys something?
Jean Girard started from the
pole and is out to a big lead.
As you know, Bill, he's
been doing that all year.
Where are you, Ricky Bobby?
Come face your destroyer!
"Come face your destroyer"?
Listen to how I sound.
I sound like a massive prick.
Come on, baby! Yeah, that's it.
All right, Lucius. Time
to let the cougar loose.
Here we go, boys.
Ricky Bobby, in the
6 2 car, on the move.
He's gone from 26th to 18th place.
Now let's go to John Hannafin, in
the stands with a countrymusic legend.
Thank you, Sean. I'm here with one
of the greatest countrymusic stars
Of all time, Kenny Rogers.
What do you think of the race so far?
It's good. They're going really fast.
John, that's not Kenny Rogers.
In the song "The Gambler," you sang:
"You gotta know when to walk
away and know when to run."
Should Ricky Bobby have
stayed away from racing?
Mr. Bobby's very competitive. If
he wants to race, he should race.
Well, this is John Hannafin with Kenny
Rogers. And now back to you, Bill.
Well, that, of course,
was not Kenny Rogers.
Not even close.
Ricky, you've got Brian Wavecrest
The guy that replaced
you at Dennit, dead ahead.
Bobby working really hard
to pass the Wonder Bread car.
That's his old ride, of course.
We've passed the halfway
mark with Ricky Bobby
Now three car lengths behind the leader.
Maybe subconsciously you
slept with Ricky's wife
As a way of getting back at him
For making you come in
second all those years.
I know one thing, Carley was definitely
unconscious every time we had sex.
Lucius, I got Cal
Naughton dead ahead of me.
Hey, Cal, you should pay
attention. I think he's passing you.
Is Ricky passing me in my subconscious?
No, he's actually passing you.
That's happening right now.
Go, Ricky! Go!
Let's go back to our John Hannafin
Who's in the stands with
an NBA legend, Larry Bird.
Folks, I'm here with one
of the great NBA superstars
A real legend, Larry Bird.
I almost didn't recognize you with
the sunglasses. What are you up to?
Come on, John, pay attention.
I'm concerned. He
might have had a stroke.
Didn't Ricky Bobby
used to drive for you?
Oh, yeah, yeah. He's doing quite well.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. Richard!
Get Cal Naughton's crew
chief on the radio right away.
I believe you have some tickets
waiting for me. My name's Reese Bobby.
Reese Bobby.
Mister, these tickets have been
waiting for you for a long time.
Who needs two? I got tickets!
Tickets, right here, 60 bucks a pop.
All right, Girard, I found you.
Now let's see where this goes.
Bobby's gotten around Naughton
And now he's right behind Girard,
but Girard's gonna block the track.
Man, he's scary good.
Ah, Ricky Bobby.
Now we shall dance, and
yes, it will be a slow jam.
Damn it. Come on, man.
I was wrong about you, Ricky Bobby.
You are not the one to defeat me.
I can't get around him, man.
You tell Cal Naughton
to take Ricky Bobby out.
Hey, Cal, listen. I hate to add
to your tremendous moral confusion
But I just heard from Dennit.
He said to take Ricky Bobby out
of the race or you're fired, buddy.
What are you talking about?
Tell him if he doesn't do it, he's done.
That's right, he'll be driving a tour bus.
Well, you tell Mr. Dennit that
Ricky Bobby is my best friend.
And it's Shake and Bake time.
Cal, I don't like the way
You're talking out
there. Damn the torpedoes!
Come on, man, slingshot
it. Slingshot, come on.
I can't believe it. If it
isn't Mike Honcho himself.
Shake and Bake, buddy!
Shake it before you bake it.
Here I come. Slingshot engaged.
Yeah!
I love you, Cal!
What are you doing? Can't
believe it. Now I've seen it all.
Cal Naughton from Dennit Racing just
helped a rival driver pass a teammate.
Darrell, you tell Brian Wavecrest
to take out Cal Naughton right now.
Right now, you do it. You do it!
Yes, sir.
And the 26 car just ran
Naughton into the wall.
Oh, man.
Damn you, Wavecrest!
The entire field was in that wreck,
and we've only got six laps to go.
Only Ricky Bobby and Jean
Girard got away clean.
It's just Jean and Ricky.
And now the matador shall
dance with the blind shoemaker.
Race officials have completed an
extensive cleanup of the track.
We're ready to get back to racing.
The 200,000 fans are on their feet,
and the green flag is in the air.
Bobby and Girard are dueling
each other for the lead.
No one seems to have the edge.
Go, go, go! Come on, come on, go!
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is the final lap.
By the way, Ricky, I
watched the Highlander movie.
It was shit.
Hang on, baby Jesus,
this is gonna get bumpy.
I've seen a lot of big
crashes at Talladega
But this is the longest
one I've ever seen.
Let's take a quick commercial
break and we'll be right back.
Hungry for both steak and shrimp?
Welcome back to Talladega,
where the long one continues.
No, no! Jean Girard and Ricky
Bobby have wrecked in the last lap
On the straightaway. What a shame.
Oh, God.
It looks like neither Girard
or Bobby will finish this race.
We'd like to thank you for joining
us for NBC's coverage of NAS CAR.
Coming up next, it's Ice
Dancing to the Hits of Motown.
Wait a minute, there's something
going on on the track down there.
Oh, my God, they're
racing each other on foot.
These men will not quit.
Go! Go!
Ricky, Ricky. He's going,
he's going, he's going. Look!
He did it!
Well, I'll be damned.
Good for you, Ricky Bobby.
Yeah! Yeah!
Ricky Bobby wins!
You'll never see anything like
that in a hundred lifetimes.
It was completely illegal and in no
way will count, but that was something.
It was. That was really good.
Monsieur Bobby, by defeating me today
You have set me free.
And for that, I thank you.
I will never shake your hand, ever.
But I will give you this.
Sir, you taste of America.
Thank you.
No, once was good. Once was good.
Boy, that Halliburton. Halliburton's
taken off, haven't they?
Yeah, yeah, we're doing well.
Now there's some stock I'd
like to get my hands on.
Ladies and gentlemen, NASCAR fans
Your eyes on Talladega's
famed Victory Lane
As we get ready for trophy time here
Following an exciting
running of the Talladega 500.
First, a very brief explanation.
Because the drivers that finished
first and second got out of their cars
They have officially been disqualified.
So now the winner, he was
third, he's now number one:
Cal Naughton Jr.!
Yeah, come on, guys!
Give me that thing.
Cal, you're number one!
I've been waiting a long time
for you to say my name, man.
I know it's a technicality,
but I tell you what
You try to take this away from
me, I'll sock you in the face.
Ricky.
Give me that thing.
I can't believe it. I can't believe it!
Cal! Put me down.
I'm proud of you!
Get up here, man. No, you come up here.
You come up here.
Cal Naughton! Cal Naughton. Oh, my God.
For this to happen.... Am I dead, man?
You won the Talladega 500, all right?
I owe you an apology.
Come on. Man, I'm sorry about Carley.
She walked straight up to me
and grabbed me in the crotch.
It's like a tractor
beam of hotness. I know.
Shake and Bake?
No. Never again.
You're right. I was a total dick, man.
From now on
It's Magic Man
And EI Diablo.
What's "Diablo" mean?
It's like, you know....
It's like Spanish for,
like, a fighting chicken.
That's awesome. I know.
With the claws. With
the claws and the beak.
Where did you think of that?
You just Sometimes things click.
I love you, bro. I love you too.
Oh, my God! Oh, my
God, I can't believe it!
Excuse me, guys. Nice job.
Hey, Ricky.
Hey, Carley.
I've decided I can love
you again. You're a winner.
Yeah, I don't think so. Really?
Are you prepared to walk
away from these pearIs
Of delight?
Well.... Yeah, this is
tough. How would it work?
Would Cal move out? Yep, gone.
Kids move back in?
Can I just have a little
refresher? Of course, baby.
This is why you fell
in love, don't forget.
Yeah, I'm in. I'm moving in right now.
I'll drive 100 miles
an hour to your house.
Our house. Our house. Our house, yeah.
No, I'm not. Come on.
It's gonna be awkward.
Hey, baby. Hey.
Wait a minute.
You are ready to walk away
From FHM magazine's
number seven hottest ass
For the girI who forgets
to get your dry cleaning?
Yeah. Yeah?
Yeah. Good luck, weirdoes.
Carley, come back here. Yes, Susie Q?
There's something I've wanted to
tell you for a really long time.
Thank you. Maybe one together?
Susie Q, are those real? Yeah.
Well, girI, you got some game.
We'll see you on down the road. Yeah.
You seen Cal? He's
somewhere around here.
Hey, Cal! Baby, I'm
coming. Thanks, baby.
Maybe one more? Oh, boys.
She's crazy. Oh, thank you.
You did good. Thanks, Mama.
He's amazing.
That was one heck of a day, I gotta say.
That's some nice driving there, cowboy.
Hey, Daddy. Well, hello, Reese.
Well, if it isn't our old
mangy, transient grandfather.
Well said, grandson.
Take that as a compliment.
Hey, Ricky, let me ask you a question.
Who did you win that race for?
Well, I sure as hell
didn't win it for you.
I like hearing that.
I guess if I really gotta think about it
I just went out there and drove.
And knew that no matter what happened
My boys, my mama, and
my lady would love me.
Hi, I'm his lady, I'm Susan.
I painted the car, I.... We had sex.
Is that right? Yeah.
Well, I wish I could've
been there for that.
Son, I'm proud of you.
Yep. Yeah, I think....
I guess things are
Just pretty much perfect right now.
It's making me a little itchy.
Well, what do you say we get
thrown out of an Applebee's?
That sound like a good
idea? You read my mind, son.
You can cuss at Applebee's.
Everybody pile in.
How does one get thrown
out of Applebee's?
You're about to find out. Okay.
Watch, the doors actually open.
Hey, I'm Ricky Bobby.
And I'm Cal Naughton Jr.
We just want to take a moment to talk
to you about snow blindness in cats.
It's affecting more and
more cats every year.
And it scares the living shit out of us.
Ninetyeight percent of us will
die at some point in our lives.
The darkness is creeping towards
you, whether you know it or not.
A little planning can go a long way.
Listen, leaving your
big old corpse behind
For your loved ones to
deal with ain't cool.
That's why you should call
McCreedy Funeral Service.
McCreedy's. They'll find
the hole and build the box.
Bodies that look so good,
you're gonna wanna talk to it.
We like to have a lot of
laughs on the racetrack
But today we wanna talk
about something serious:
Packs of stray dogs that
control most of the major cities.
That's packs of wild, vicious dogs
that are controlling most of....
Sorry.
I like to picture Jesus
like a mischievous badger.
Like a muscular trapeze artist.
Like a shapeshifter or a
changeling, like that guy.
You ever hear of that TV show Manimal?
I like to think of
Jesus as a figure skater
Who wears, like, a white outfit
And he does interpretive ice
dances of my life's journey.
Like a dirty old bum.
He comes up to me, I'm about to sock
him one because he's a dirty old bum.
Then I said, "Wait a minute,
I better not sock this guy.
Something special about him."
Yeah, and it turns out it's Jesus. Yeah.
One, two.... Oh, God.
Not again! No go. No go!
It's stuck. It's stuck.
We got two knives in my leg.
I know, but one is a safety
knife. One is a safety.
It's coming out. It's coming out.
I'm choking on my own spit.
It hurts so bad I'm
choking on my own spit.
Good night, guys. I'm
losing a lot of blood.
Just relax, man. Good night.
Ricky! Wake
Sometimes, when it's late at night,
I dress up like Donna Summers.
You know, I put on the skirt
and the fourinch heels, man.
I love it.
Sorry. Sorry.
I would be honored if you
would let me sign your cast.
And I would be honored
if you'd sign my balls.
Oh, baby, that is a good
one. Hey, what are you doing?
"Don't touch a one of
them. They're mine."
So, what do you think
that story was about?
Doesn't the bear symbolize the old South
And the new dog, the encroaching
industrialization of the North?
Duh. But the question is, should
the reader feel relief or sadness
At the passing of the old South?
Well, how about both?
Oh, I get it. Moral ambiguity.
The hallmark of all early
20thcentury American fiction.
Great analysis, Walker. Thank you.