How long now?
A week.
Did you alert the police?
No.
We worked in the same factory.
They haven't heard
from him either.
You can't reach him?
No.
His cell phone doesn't answer.
He's Spanish;
maybe he went back.
Did he leave you any money?
No.
You have three months'
back rent.
It's hard, on my own,
with two kids.
I can't manage.
You don't work?
No, I took sick leave
to look after the baby.
But I'm struggling.
I wanted to ask you...
Yes?
Could he go into foster care,
just for a while?
Is he difficult?
Sort of.
He cries a lot.
I'm at my wits' end.
I can't cope.
Placing a child in care
is a big decision.
It's a complicated process.
Maybe you just need some time,
or home help.
Maybe.
Let's consider the options.
You need to fill out
a declaration
of marital abandonment
with the police.
You may be eligible for aid.
I'll put in a request
for childcare...
"Several months earlier"
Time to get up, Mommy.
I know.
Come here.
Get up.
We'll be late.
I don't want to work today.
Is your bag ready?
Yeah.
I need to brush my teeth.
Hurry up.
- Mommy?
- Hmm?
Why don't you want
to work today?
Some days are like that.
Get on.
- Hanging on tight?
- Yeah.
Bye, honey.
Be good.
Will you pick me up?
Yeah, ten past 5:00.
Wait outside.
- See you tonight.
Ready?
Not so hot.
Hi.
Hello.
Got a cigarette?
Sure.
Thanks.
I'm Paco.
I'm Katie.
Oh, shit.
Where were you?
Alley B?
No.
Why?
There was a leak.
Get back to work.
Odile, switch stations.
Thanks, Odile.
Sorry, honey.
I got held up at work.
Get on.
My helmet?
Shit.
I left it at work.
Wear mine.
It's too big.
Better than nothing.
- You good?
- Yeah.
- Hanging on tight?
- Good night, honey.
- Good night, Mommy.
- See you tomorrow.
Mommy?
What?
Can you leave
the hall light on?
What's wrong?
I'm scared.
Of what?
I don't know.
I'm here.
Don't be scared.
Sleep tight.
See you tomorrow.
- Good night.
See you tomorrow, Odile.
See you tomorrow.
I owe you one.
No, thanks.
What happened between us
was an accident.
I never do that.
Me neither.
Where are you going?
To a restaurant.
With who?
Some friends.
Will you be late?
No.
Go get ready for bed.
- Good evening.
Sorry I'm late.
I'd given up on you.
But here I am.
Shall we order?
Yes.
Menus, please.
Finished?
Yeah.
May l?
Sure.
How old is your daughter?
Seven.
Where's her dad?
Down south.
I don't see him anymore.
Why not?
He won't see her.
Really?
He didn't want me
to have her.
Does she miss having a dad?
I don't think so.
We're a team.
Do you have kids?
No.
Not that I know of.
Ever been married?
In Spain, when I was young.
It didn't last.
What floor?
High, very high.
- Katie?
- Yes?
Stop. We'll wake up
the building.
Come on.
Am I too hairy?
No.
It's soft.
I never liked it.
I always wanted
a swimmer's body: smooth.
I like it.
It's animal.
Paco, my daughter, Lisa.
Hi, Lisa.
How are you?
Answer.
Don't be shy.
Sorry.
I think I scared her.
She just doesn't know you.
Be right back.
Lisa, Paco might come live
with us.
Will you get married?
I don't know.
We'll see.
We'll be like a new family?
Mm-hmm.
Paco?
The boss wants to see you.
What for?
Don't know.
Take over for me.
Yeah?
Your neighbor called.
Katie's in the hospital.
What will his name be?
What name do you like?
- Ricky.
- Ricky?
Is that a cartoon character?
No.
Where'd it come from?
I don't know.
Got a boyfriend named Ricky?
I don't have a boyfriend.
Mr. Sanchez?
Yes.
How'd it go?
You have a big baby boy.
How's Katie?
Fine.
She's resting.
Good.
It's nice to be home.
- Mommy.
- What?
Come see my room.
What'd you do?
Surprise.
Ah, Paco.
Like it?
It's great.
Ricky's sleeping in my room?
After I stop breast-feeding.
To my son,
the world's most beautiful baby!
- To Ricky.
I just fed him
a half hour ago.
He wants some champagne too.
Here's to you...
Stop it.
Go get the chicken.
I have to feed him again.
Later.
The chicken's hot.
Go eat the chicken Dad made.
He's Paco, not Dad.
White meat, Lisa?
- No.
- A thigh?
I want a wing.
A wing it is.
Want some?
Mom and I don't eat that.
I wanted to give you a treat.
You don't like scrambled eggs?
I don't know.
Give it a try.
You'll see.
It's delicious.
When do we eat, Mom?
When Paco's back.
Where the hell is he?
Lottery time.
Hand me my purse.
Number 34.
Number 26.
And the bonus number is 41.
Well?
We lost, as usual.
Hi.
Where were you?
Out with the guys.
You could've phoned.
Get off my back.
Make your son shut up.
He's your son too.
You've got him tomorrow.
I know!
Make an effort.
I'm gonna work nights
to be with him days!
You wanted him, so pitch in!
Stop nagging!
I'm tired too!
This is hard on me!
He cries all day.
I'm exhausted!
Want your milk?
Stop screaming!
I'm so sick of this!
Mad at me?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
Things are rough at work.
It's hard for me too,
with the rent, the baby...
I know.
Are you sure it's not Ricky?
What do you mean?
You've changed
since he came along.
No, I haven't.
You've changed.
He gets all the attention.
Tomorrow I go back to work.
It'll be like before.
I hope so.
It will.
I'm coming, Ricky!
Listen.
The bottle's not hot yet.
Three more minutes.
I'll be right back.
It's almost ready!
You're okay.
Come on.
Whoa, Ricky.
Swell.
Nice job!
Fucking hell.
What a mess.
What's wrong?
Is that better?
Go to sleep now.
Mom, look.
Hi, sweetie.
How'd it go?
Good, I think.
How many bottles?
Two, like you said.
You're perfect.
Time for your bath.
What, Ricky?
Didn't you have fun with Dad?
Didn't he take good care of you?
Can I help with your homework?
If you want.
But your French is so bad.
Not true.
I have an accent,
but I'm fluent.
Paco!
What?
Come here, please.
What's this?
What?
Shit.
What's that?
A lump.
How'd he get it?
It wasn't there this morning.
Paco, tell me the truth.
Did you drop him?
Are you crazy?
I was careful.
Well, something happened.
Stop it.
Nothing happened.
Stop imagining things.
Look, I don't know.
Maybe I accidentally knocked him
against the crib.
"Knocked him"?
It's just a bruise!
What's wrong with Ricky?
Nothing.
Mommy?
Why aren't you in bed?
I can't sleep.
What is it now?
Is Ricky going to die?
No, don't be silly.
Get back to bed.
Don't cry, my baby.
I'm here.
It's okay.
What's wrong?
It hurts again?
Does it hurt, Ricky?
You'll be all right.
Wait a minute.
My God.
Up already?
I didn't sleep.
What now?
We have to talk.
I just did
my first night shift.
I need sleep.
We'll talk tonight.
No.
It's too serious.
What's too serious?
What you did to Ricky.
Here we go again.
He's got two bruises.
What did you do?
You think I hit your son?
Yes.
Fine.
Where are you going?
Did Paco leave?
Yes, he left.
Ricky, shut up!
Does it hurt?
Must be your lumps.
You're bleeding.
No wonder you're crying.
I'll disinfect it for you.
This won't hurt.
There.
Some cotton...
And two bandages.
Hi, Mom.
Hi.
Did you feed Ricky?
Not yet.
Go get him.
I'll heat the milk.
Ricky?
Mommy, Mommy!
- What?
- Ricky!
- What's wrong?
- He's not in his crib.
No way!
What's this?
You left the window open?
I didn't do anything.
Did Paco come back?
Nobody came.
Ricky?
Ricky.
Ricky, Ricky.
- Ricky.
- Ricky?
Ricky?
Mommy, look.
My God.
How'd he get up there?
I don't know.
Don't move, sweetie.
Mommy's coming.
Come here, Ricky.
Careful.
Come on, Ricky.
Come to Mommy.
That's it, honey.
Almost there.
Ricky.
What's that?
No idea.
I've never seen anything
like it.
What the hell?
His lumps opened?
I don't know.
It's so bloody.
Gross.
They move.
Watch out!
Lisa, give me a hand.
Rinse him off, gently.
Come see.
Look at these.
Like tiny fingernails.
Weird.
Be gentle.
Maybe they hurt.
You okay, Ricky?
Let's clean off the blood.
Really carefully.
Rinse over here.
They're bound to drop off.
Take the towel
and get the sheet.
There.
Hand me the clothespins.
You okay, Ricky?
There.
That should keep him in.
It's like a cage.
But if he goes back up there,
he'll hurt himself.
We'll see the doctor?
No, no doctors.
Thank you.
Listen, Lisa.
What?
Keep quiet at school.
Don't talk about Ricky.
Why?
He's different.
Could someone hurt him?
Yes.
Morning, Mommy.
Morning, honey.
Sleep well?
Yes.
Ricky's still sleeping?
Did he wake up in the night?
No.
Seems he's sleeping
better now.
What are you doing?
Measuring his wings.
They've grown.
Come help me.
Keep still, Ricky.
There.
That's right.
Here.
Hold it for me.
Let's see.
That makes...
1 7 centimeters.
Is that big?
Well...
It's grown 8 centimeters
in a week.
That's big.
Let's tape it down.
We'll give it a try.
Nope.
- No good.
- No good at all.
Stupid idea.
I've got another one.
What?
Come with me.
I've got a plan.
Go get my sewing kit.
Bring me his shirts.
Got it?
Yeah.
Good job.
I've got him.
Like so...
There.
Perfect. Huh?
Suits him.
He's like an angel.
More like a chicken.
Go on, Ricky.
Wow, excellent.
Good job, Ricky.
Did you see that, Mommy?
Bravo.
Mommy?
Will Ricky fly one day?
Without feathers,
it'll be hard.
First, he needs to walk.
Hi, Lisa.
Hi.
Where's your mom?
I'm taking the bus.
How are you?
Fine.
How's your mom?
That's my bus.
Gotta go.
Bye.
Lisa, Lisa, Lisa.
How's Ricky, better?
Yeah, he's good.
Hi.
Can I help you?
Yes, I'm looking
for a book about wings.
Wings?
Yeah, bird wings.
A novel?
No. More of a science book.
- Anatomy?
- Yes, that's it.
Don't touch the food.
Sorry.
Want a bird?
What's
the weight-to-wingspan ratio?
I'm just a butcher.
What's this one weigh?
Let's see.
4 kilos, 300 grams.
4 kilos, 300 grams...
Ricky weighs 8 kilos.
So that means...
Okay. You want it?
No, thanks.
Good-bye.
Excuse me.
I need a child's helmet.
Motorcycle or bicycle?
The strongest, motorcycle.
How old is the child?
A baby.
Babies aren't allowed
on motorcycles.
Whatever's smallest.
Hi, honey.
Hi, Mom.
I got loads of stuff.
How's Ricky?
Shut in his crib.
Get me a present?
No, honey, it's for Ricky.
Look at the cool book I found.
This way,
he won't hurt himself.
Here too.
Get a pillow.
Perfect.
Fasten it tight.
Don't worry.
Help me put this on.
There.
Raise your little arm.
Now for the helmet.
He could've used mine.
Yours is too heavy.
This one's light.
There.
Show us your stuff.
Good job!
Careful.
What's he doing?
Turn out the light.
That's it.
Very good, Ricky.
Are you okay?
Did you hurt yourself?
Good thing we used
the pillows.
Let me take off your helmet.
That's better.
Look at his wing.
You just took
your first flight!
What a good boy!
It's okay now, Ricky.
Here.
And Paco?
What made you think of him?
I don't think of him
now Ricky has wings.
There.
All better.
Did we win?
No, we only got five numbers.
Five numbers?
Let me see.
We won.
2,000 euros.
Less than I thought,
but still.
Ricky brought us luck.
Let's go shopping.
Can we eat out for Christmas?
Maybe, the two of us.
The three of us.
This way, Mom!
Slow down, Lisa.
Here.
It's so crowded.
Show me, quick.
Be right back.
A bit pricey for Santa Claus.
But we're rich now.
Go on, then.
Mommy.
Where's Ricky?
- Look.
- Shit!
He took it off.
Up there!
Quick.
Come on.
Where's he going?
Ricky!
What do we do?
I don't know.
Honey, look!
Ricky!
Ricky, wait!
He'll burn his wings.
This way, hurry!
We'll never catch him.
I want a remote-control baby.
- Ricky!
Ladies and gentlemen,
please leave the premises
as quickly as you can
for security reasons.
An unidentified flying object
has been seen over the aisles.
Set up the ladders.
Turn out the lights,
and he'll come down.
All right.
Loïc, have them cut
the lights.
Right.
Christophe?
Cut the lights, please.
Where's he going?
Fresh foods.
Shit.
Come on, this way.
He'll end up frozen.
Don't be silly.
Hide there, on the left!
Wait, wait.
Go!
I got him!
Don't hurt him!
Remain calm.
If I lose Ricky, after Paco...
You've got me, Mom.
The doctor will see you now.
Is he okay?
He's fine.
Here they are.
Ah, good evening.
Good evening.
So you're the mother?
Yes.
This is my daughter, Lisa.
Nice to meet you.
Have a seat.
Where is he?
Sleeping in a room nearby.
You gave him a shot?
No, he was tired
and fell asleep naturally.
I must say, your son
is a fascinating enigma.
I called several colleagues
and veterinarians.
They're baffled and...
You'll make him a lab rat.
Of course not.
We'll do nothing
unless you approve.
But your son should undergo
extensive tests.
So should you, as his mother.
And his father too.
Does he have
any distinguishing features?
- Yes.
- Ah.
He's very hairy.
I don't think that plays a role.
We'd like to keep your son
in observation.
No way.
I'm taking him home.
Do you have enough room
for him to thrive?
Yes.
Where does he sleep?
In his cage.
- Cage?
- No.
We put a sheet over his crib
so he can't fly out.
Ah, I see.
But your son
requires special care.
For his well-being,
he should be hospitalized.
You think I'm unfit?
A bad mother?
I'm sorry.
This is a hospital.
Break it up.
This way.
Down the stairs.
This is why I want
to keep him here.
Bernard?
You'll get no peace.
Meet us in the parking garage.
This way.
- You okay?
- Yes.
My card.
Don't hesitate to call.
Okay.
The hospital will cover
the taxi fare.
Get in, Lisa.
I'll expect you tomorrow.
Thank you.
Good-bye.
There they go!
Roll the cameras!
Come back, Serge!
Doctor, just a few questions.
No comment.
Just one.
Does the baby really have wings?
We're seeing the doctor
again tomorrow?
No, we're not.
Thank you.
Good night.
Shit.
Stay close.
We saw you on TV, Katie.
Let's see him.
No, we're tired.
Show us your little
freak of nature.
Leave us alone, please.
Just a few questions!
Film them.
Take the keys.
The "flying baby"
apparently lives
with his mother
in a council flat.
She's a factory worker
and a single mom.
Awhile back, she was living
with some foreigner.
But he left.
It's just her
and her daughter.
I'd hear him crying,
but I never imagined
he was bizarre.
The mother refuses
to talk to journalists.
The only footage of the baby
comes from cell phones.
The poor quality
suggests the whole thing
could be a hoax.
I'll go get Ricky.
No, leave him.
This is all his fault.
You woke me up, Ricky.
There you go.
Happy now?
Be right back.
Stay put.
Mommy, the doorbell.
If it's journalists,
don't open.
Who's there?
Me.
Morning, Lisa.
Morning.
You're prickly.
Is Katie here?
Lisa?
Go to your room
so I can talk to Paco.
You're back?
Yeah.
I'm back.
I saw you on TV.
Why didn't you tell me
about Ricky?
It's amazing.
I lost your phone number.
You're still a bad liar.
Forgive me.
Paco's back.
Maybe he wants to take you.
You'll leave us.
You're upset?
Why?
Because he left
and never took care of you?
But he loves you.
He's your dad.
What'd you say?
You're right.
You don't leave
someone you love.
Where is he?
With Lisa, in her room.
I want to see him.
Where were you?
What'd you do?
I was in Paris.
A friend works
in a restaurant there.
I washed dishes,
did a little plumbing.
Were you with women?
Nothing serious.
I thought of you.
I missed you, Katie.
Did you miss Ricky?
Of course I did.
He's my son.
You let him out?
He wanted a cuddle.
Hi, there.
Incredible!
Ricky.
Amazing.
He seems scared.
Ricky!
Careful!
Come down, Ricky.
Come down, honey.
We've gotta catch him.
Gently, don't hurt him.
Come on.
That's it.
I got him.
Give him to me.
It's okay, sweetie.
Poor kid.
You're all right.
He can't stay here
with those things.
Shut up.
Can't you see he's suffering?
He needs help.
He's my son;
it's up to me!
Paco, look.
Well?
A minor injury.
Next time it could be worse.
No bandage?
No need.
But this is
a hostile environment.
What'd I tell you?
As you can see,
your son's wings are extensions
of his shoulder blades.
Part of the same bone.
They'll continue to grow.
If we operate,
it would be similar
to separating Siamese twins
who share bones.
They'll cut off his wings?
Listen.
The risks are minimal,
but it's quite painful.
And if we don't operate?
As I told your wife,
this is new territory.
Without the proper care,
he could wither away.
What should we do?
I don't know.
Listen, I've been thinking.
I have an idea.
We won't let anyone
take him away.
But I was thinking...
We need money to care
for him properly.
Maybe we could negotiate
with certain journalists.
Let them film him,
you know, for money.
That's why you're back?
To make money off your son?
I came back for you.
And Ricky.
And Lisa.
So we can start over,
be a real family,
in a new house.
I don't believe you.
I left because you accused me
of hitting my son.
So please, trust me now.
Look at us.
Imagine the new life
we could have, thanks to Ricky.
Hi, everyone.
Good to see you.
Hi, Bernard.
Glad you could make it.
Thanks for the permit.
We're about to start.
Hello.
How are you?
Fine. Hello.
Hello.
- Good crowd, huh?
- Yeah, yeah.
Is he coming?
Yes.
His mom's bringing him.
Great.
Excuse me!
Can we get an interview?
Not yet.
Can you believe it?
All this for Ricky.
Hello.
Come stand over here.
Who's that?
The journalist
I negotiated with.
Lisa, stay close.
Ladies and gentlemen,
these are Ricky's parents,
Mr. and Mrs. Sanchez.
We're not married.
What you're about to see
is utterly amazing:
a flying baby.
Please keep quiet
so as not to frighten the baby.
He's very shy.
Thank you.
All set?
Make him fly!
Wonderful.
Go on.
Look, he's flying!
Katie, the string.
Shit!
You let it go.
Ricky?
Ricky!
Come on.
Follow him.
He could be attracted to...
What?
The reflections on the water.
Fly, Ricky, fly.
- Ricky!
Ricky!
Ricky, come back!
Good evening, Mr. Sanchez.
Evening, Doctor.
Well?
They're searching for him
around the lake.
- Paco?
- Yes, Lisa?
Could a hunter shoot Ricky?
I hope not, honey.
Don't you worry.
Go see your mom;
she needs you.
Lisa's right.
What'll become of him?
He'll get attacked or starve.
This is all my fault.
She'll blame me forever.
Not if you stay together.
Miss.
Here.
Excuse me.
I saw you on TV.
You're the flying baby's dad.
That's me.
Want to make me
a flying baby too?
"Ricky Sanchez. Distinguishing
features: Two Wings."
Good, huh?
At work, they said
they'd take you back anytime.
Really?
With your experience.
Okay.
Seagulls.
What is it now?
I can't sleep.
Come back to bed.
It's Sunday.
I'm going for a walk.
Where now?
The lake.
Please, Katie,
pull yourself together.
You must accept
that Ricky's gone.
He's somewhere else now.
You think he's dead?
It's unlikely he survived.
Ricky?
My baby.
Ricky.
Ricky, my baby!
Don't go!
It's me, Mommy.
Do you recognize me?
Ricky, it's Mommy.
Easy, honey, easy.
Oh, my love.
How you've grown.
Your wings are so big,
and you can walk.
Are you okay?
You won't tell me?
You're mad at me.
Is that it?
I didn't want to leave you.
When I let the string go,
I didn't want to lose you.
But flying,
you were so beautiful.
So beautiful.
My Ricky.
Is that Mom?
She's got her keys.
I'll get it.
I forgot my keys.
Why are you soaked?
I love you.
# Once I wanted
to be the greatest #
# Greatest,
greatest, greatest #
# No wind or waterfall
could stall me #
# And then came the rush
of the flood #
# The stars at night
turned deep to dust #
Thank you.
# Melt me down
into big black armor #
- Hanging tight?
- Yeah.
# Leave no trace
of grace #
# Just in your honor #
# Lower me down #
# To culprit south #
# Make 'em watch
a space in town #
# For the lead
and the dregs of my bed #
# I've been sleeping #
# Lower me down #
# Pin me in #
# Secure the grounds #
# For the later parade #
"No animals or flying babies
were harmed
during the making
of this movie."