Subtitles by DramaFever
[10 years later, the border
between Joseon and Later Jin.]
[Episode 39]
Look!
It seems like our Joseon citizens
have escaped from Later Jin again!
Sound the alarms
and alert the General! Quickly!
Yes, sir!
Hang in there! We're almost there!
We'll be under Joseon protection as soon
as we reach that tower! Hang in there!
The Joseon prisoners have run away!
Catch them! Catch them all!
General.
Are you okay, Miss?
I... I think this is the end for me.
What are you talking about? Didn't you
leave your husband behind in Hanyang?
You need to go back and see him again!
Get up now. We just have
to pass that tower over there.
Our Joseon soldiers will protect us!
Get up now. Quickly! Quickly!
General, you can't do that.
Those people are Joseon citizens.
They are innocent prisoners who were
captured by the Later Jin soldiers.
Those people have escaped
so they could survive, sir.
Don't you think I know that?
However, what about the treaty we
agreed upon when we surrendered to them?
If they don't serve their time...
not a single one of them
will be able to return to Joseon.
If we accept them, then the Later Jin
will see it as an act of war.
General, please!
Get the soldiers ready. We will
shoot them if they try to cross over.
What... what is that?
Are the soldiers aiming their guns at us?
Look here! We're from Joseon!
We're Joseon citizens, you punks!
Oh my gosh, what do I do?
Where... where do I go?
Ma'am, are you okay?
Oh my! Oh my, look at this sweat!
Goodness, this sweat.
I'm fine. I'm still... I'm still...
Oh my! Oh my, this won't do.
I think we need to notify
Lord Joo Won right away.
No, he's in the palace right now.
Today, there's going to be...
Ma'am! What do we do?
Oh, goodness!
Oh my goodness, the baby is ready
to come out. It's ready to come out!
- Princess!
- Ma'am!
This won't do. We don't have time
to wait for the midwife to come.
Ma'am! Your Highness!
Your Highness!
Your Highness, please push
a little more! Your Highness!
Your Highness!
A little more. Just a little more!
So, how is it going?
It's taking longer than we expected.
There is still no news yet.
How many hours has it been already?
Ma'am, is Lord Joo Won
inside the royal library?
The crown prince is in the middle
of his studies. Why do you ask?
There is an urgent message
from Lord Joo Won's residence.
Princess Jungmyung is in labor!
What?
[Crown Prince Sohyun]
It's been two hours already.
I can't believe there isn't any news yet.
Please focus on your studies,
Your Highness.
Worrying won't change anything.
Teacher, does it look
like I can study right now?
Look at this. I'm so nervous
that my hands are all sweaty.
Next is the Book of Odes.
The consumption chapter.
Please look kindly upon me
just this once, Teacher.
Your Highness,
why are you being so fretful?
When a woman is in labor,
there is nothing a man can do.
You must be calm at times like this.
- Teacher!
- Your Highness, it's Court Lady Kim.
There is an urgent message
for Lord Joo Won.
You may enter.
What's going on?
You must return home immediately.
Princess Jungmyung has started her labor.
What? Princess Jungmyung?
When?
It's so soon. When did it start?
How is her condition?
- Teacher.
- Yes?
You told me to be calm and prudent.
What's going on here?
Your Highness.
The truth is, Princess Jungmyung
had two breached pregnancies before
and she suffered very much
trying to give birth to them.
You said there's nothing a man can do
when a woman is in labor.
You know quite a bit.
Forget it, Teacher.
Then... how about we call it a day, okay?
We must continue your studies.
Even if it's late tonight.
Of course.
How can I avoid your nagging?
Don't worry, and just go.
Well... please excuse me then.
Yes, yes.
- Quickly, quickly!
- Yes.
Okay, so how is her condition right now?
He's always been so rigid,
like a birch tree.
At times like this, he is such
a worry wart, don't you agree?
When it concerns Princess Jungmyung.
Yes, it seems so.
How is the Crown Princess doing?
Father!
Man Young.
- You came.
- Yes, Father.
How is Princess Jungmyung?
Joo Won!
Goodness! It came out!
It came out!
It's another strong and stout son!
What about the Princess?
How is she doing, Ok Joo?
Oh my word, look at him smile.
How can a newborn baby
be so sweet like this?
Weren't the two young masters
like this, too?
My husband was hoping for a little girl.
Goodness, what are you talking about?
There are people who can't have sons
even if they try. You have three.
Princess.
Husband.
Hello, sir.
Congratulations, My Lord.
You must've been so worried.
I had no idea you were in labor.
Why did you come here?
This wasn't anything to worry about.
Nonsense. There's nothing more
important than this for me.
Husband.
I should've been by your side.
- I had no idea.
- No, it's fine.
The baby was in a hurry to come out.
But, what about the palace?
What about the Crown Princess?
It's your first grandchild, Your Majesty.
What?
My first grandchild, you say?
- Is it a boy this time?
- Yes, Your Majesty.
The Crown Princess finally gave
birth to a son, Your Majesty.
My goodness.
What good news.
Congratulations, Your Majesty.
It's been such a long time since the
palace had something to celebrate over.
Yes, it has.
Sukwon...
This country has only been in turmoil.
The Crown Prince and Princess
have given me such a joyous gift.
Princess... good job.
Thank you so much.
[Gang Bin]
Your Highness.
In a difficult time like this.
Still, I can't believe I have a son.
Is that so?
Princess Jungmyung had a safe delivery
and the Crown Princess
also gave birth to a son?
Yes, My Lord.
That is what they say.
It seems we have hope again.
Even so, new life will always be born.
Don't you think a day like that
will come for this land, too?
Husband.
Yes, Princess.
That will happen for certain.
It's a war, Your Majesty!
The Later Jin's army is closing in!
Your Majesty, we must flee!
The palace will be seized!
To where?
Where do we flee again?
Granted, the Later Jin's army
could not be stopped.
- Ma'am!
- Your Majesty!
- Princess.
I pray...
I pray you and this country
will be safe... I pray...
- Mother!
- Ma'am!
- Your Majesty!
- Mother!
- Ma'am!
My Lord. Lord Won Ik.
You guys...
will have to endure this difficult time.
Forgive me...
for leaving first.
My Lord!
Lord Won Ik.
My Lord.
We've lost many precious people.
Please save us!
Please let us rest in Joseon!
Sir! Sir!
Please do not return us
to the Later Jin!
I beg you! Sir, please save us!
Sir, please...
Why are you taking us back
to the Later Jin?
We don't want to go back!
Hey, Soo Deok.
Am I doing this right?
Come on now! Since you've never been
married, of course you don't know!
Hand it over.
Honey.
- You still have a ways to go?
- No, it's almost done.
What about the feast?
What feast?
It's just going to be a modest meal.
I'm just going to make a
couple of jeons, that's all.
I see.
Goodness, that's better than
nothing in this day and age.
It's more than enough.
Oh my, where did you get
these peppers? They're so tiny.
Your Highness, congratulations
on the birth of your first son.
Thank you, Prince Bongrim.
If Mother was alive to see this...
She would've been so happy.
[Prince Bongrim]
However, hope will come, Princess.
Ma'am.
- Mother.
Man Yong. Man Young.
The two young masters
wanted to see their little brother.
Sit down.
What do you think?
Even in the midst of tribulation,
we must end it.
That's only if we do not give up.
Court Lady Jung, prepare the coach.
I need to leave.
Pardon? Ma'am, what do you mean?
How can you leave right now,
in your condition?
I'm all right and we don't have
time for this, so please hurry.
- You came, Lord Ryoo.
- Yes.
Are the other officials who
want to see me here as well?
Huh?
Yes, they're all inside
the assembly hall right now.
Seriously, it would be nice
to get some rest on a day like this.
Seriously, this is quite annoying.
I swear.
Father.
Is that so?
An incident like that
occurred at the border again?
During the last war against Later Jin...
About 50,000 of our people
were taken as prisoners.
But we couldn't do anything
to bring them back.
The prisoners decided to escape
and risk their lives so they could live.
Goodness, everyone knows that.
- Teach us what we don't know, Lee Pan.
- Secretary.
Do you think Lee Pan
is trying to teach right now?
He is telling us the officials
should not forget about those people!
Therefore, we've been negotiating
constantly, have we not?
By returning the
prisoners to the Later Jin.
Yes, of course we're doing that.
But you know it is not
an ideal situation, Father.
You're right.
I hear the wealthy nobles have
been making deals with the Later Jin
in order to get their
captured family members back.
Because of that, the price of the
prisoners is going up drastically.
Later Jin is refusing
to negotiate with us.
I swear...
Father! Over there!
So Jung!
- Father!
- My baby! My precious daughter!
There's no need to worry anymore.
It's all fine now.
- Goodness...
- Take it.
It's okay, it's okay.
This is the money we promised.
Yes.
But there are rumors going around
that our own officials are
involved in those deals as well.
Because of that...
the price of the prisoners have increased
to several thousand pieces of silver.
The poor and weak citizens are not
capable of getting their family back.
Your Majesty!
- Your Majesty!
Please stop the illegal dealings
of the nobles!
If this continues...
People like us will never be able
to get our family back, Your Majesty!
Your Majesty!
So, it's settled.
Due to the officials' selfishness,
the people have no other choice!
In the end, the Joseon people are risking
their lives to flee their imprisonment.
But we are forcing them to return!
Yes, well... that's very unfortunate.
Our hands are tied behind our backs.
The Later Jin will throw a fit
if we don't return the prisoners.
Talking about this without
taking any proper measures...
Why do you think this happened?
Why do you think we're in this situation,
and we can't do anything about it?
You startled me.
Why are you taking your anger out
on me? Is this war my responsibility?
That's right! It is your responsibility!
It's a crime that we can't do anything
about it. It's all our responsibility!
I mean, seriously,
what is the matter with him?
Did we feign ignorance,
or am I Huang Taiji?
Why is all of that my responsibility?
Come to think of it,
you kind of look like him.
Really? That barbarian
dares to look like me?
Yes, I've seen a
picture of him before...
That's enough. Now is not the time
to be talking about nonsense like that!
And you.
Tell it to me straight.
Rumors are that your father
secretly got your sister back
by dealing with the Later Jin.
Is that true?
And that he gave them
1,000 pieces of silver in return.
The thing is...
Look, I'm Kim Gyung Jing.
Fine, it's just between us.
The truth is, we gave them
500 pieces of silver on top of that.
- What?
- Be quiet!
1,500 pieces of silver, then?
That rotten barbarian's word
doesn't match up.
At first he only asked for 1,000 pieces
of silver, but he knew we had money
so he just kept asking
for more and more...
Look here! Look here, Gyung Jing!
Are you serious right now?
Sir, why are you worried
about such a thing?
Then... was your daughter
supposed to wait for her death?
Of course not.
But as a man of power...
Yes, because of your high position
you were able to make such a deal
with the Later Jin through me.
I did my best to help you out,
but it seems this is all my fault.
Somehow, I feel sad about it.
No, not at all!
That's not right, either.
You're the one who got me connected
to the Later Jin. You're our savior.
Please drink, My Lord. It's a rare tea
I bought from a Later Jin merchant.
Ah, yes, yes.
Thank you.
Well... this is definitely different.
Now then, I believe it is
your turn to interfere, sir.
A problem just occurred with Later Jin
they're hoping will be taken care of.
- When you say 'problem'...
- What do you think it is?
The prisoners who recently escaped
are causing them a headache.
Well... Sir... I'm not very
familiar with that issue.
My Lord, the Later Jin are
planning something grand right now.
And that plan will be revealed soon.
I do not think it is wise
to test their patience at a
time like this, don't you agree?
If there is a problem...
we must take care of it for them.
Yes, if it's about that incident,
I've received a report about it as well.
I heard our army was returning the
escaped prisoners to the Later Jin
but they were attacked by
unidentified individuals.
That's not the only thing.
There are rumors that they are scheming
with certain officials of this court.
If not, that would be impossible.
Your Highness, by any chance, do you
know anything in regards to this incident?
We must be very careful right now.
But I'm afraid that Your Highness
might get caught up in this mess.
There is no way.
You're talking nonsense.
Like you said,
we must be very careful right now.
So, I'm going to get
to the bottom of this.
Your Highness.
Crown Princess, I must
speak to you for a moment.
Sure, what is it?
Princess Jungmyung
is waiting for you outside.
She wants to pay her respects to you.
Is that so? Princess Jungmyung is here?
Princess Jungmyung.
Welcome.
Your Highness.
Prince Bongrim, you're here too.
Yes, Ma'am.
I heard news of you several days ago.
Is it okay for you
to already move around like this?
Regardless, I need to pay my respects
to the Crown Prince and Crown Princess.
Is it not a joyous occasion the
whole palace has been waiting for?
Please come inside, Ma'am. My son and
the Crown Princess are waiting to see you.
Yes, Your Highness.
Father.
The former queen was a thorn in my side,
and when she finally died...
I thought my time was coming.
Princess Jungmyung and the
crown princess all have sons.
Why can't I have one?
You must be at ease, My Lady.
Then the baby will come to you.
But I can't be at ease.
I am not in the King's favor right now.
Plus, Kim Ja Jeom,
who always looked out for me
is now out of the king's favor
and is working outside of the palace.
I hear all of that
is the Crown Prince's fault.
His Majesty trusts
the Crown Prince very deeply.
I hear he confides in him
about many national affairs.
Kim Ja Jeom was pushed aside
because of that.
And behind that...
was Princess Jungmyung.
I'm sure that sly fox was there.
The Crown Prince took her husband
as his teacher.
Yes, but the king is not
suspicious of it at all.
I'm telling you, it's strange.
No matter how much I tell him,
he pretends not to hear it.
Even if I tell him that the Crown Prince
follows the Princess more than him.
So... you came to pay your respects
to the crown prince and his princess.
Yes, Father.
Then, Aunt Jungmyung as well.
I'm sure that's the case
for Aunt Jungmyung, too.
Since it's the law for the royals
to pay respects to each other.
Absolutely, Father.
A royal grandson is born. It would be more
of a problem if she didn't come at all.
Yes, that is why I came.
It would be more of a misunderstanding
if I did not come and pay my respects.
You made the right decision, Ma'am.
In any case,
I had to see you immediately.
Is there something going on,
Your Highness?
It is about the border incident.
It seems the officials
will start an investigation soon.
- An investigation will start?
- Yes.
It was decided at the meeting
initiated by Yong San.
He's handsome.
Look at this rascal.
He looks exactly like you.
This innocent and stubborn-looking face.
He's going to be exactly
like you some day.
Is that an insult?
To become like me some day?
No way, I'm so jealous of you.
You have three kids already.
But... shouldn't you get married again?
Once was enough.
Not a chance.
In Woo.
It was a forced marriage.
And she suffered every day for it.
She lost her life during the war, too.
That kind of tragedy
should never happen again, Joo Won.
So, there's no time for us to be
dilly-dallying around like this.
Princess Jungmyung.
Gam Jo Gam, what about
the favor I asked of you?
This is the money you received
from selling your land, Ma'am.
You can trust him.
It was an urgent sell,
but he sold it for a good price.
Thank you.
Please sell the rest of my other
properties as soon as possible.
But Ma'am, why do you want
to keep selling that good land?
That is none of your business.
All you have to do
is sell it for her, got it?
I'm going to go outside the palace
to get some fresh air.
If anyone is looking for me,
just relay that to them, Princess.
Your Highness.
Must you do this?
Isn't there another way?
Princess, what do you mean?
I am your wife.
I know what you are thinking.
Princess...
But Your Highness... I am scared.
If His Majesty finds out what you're
doing with Princess Jungmyung...
Yes, I know.
I know that by doing this
I am going against my father's will.
Your Highness.
But I can't allow our innocent people
to die in a foreign land.
They have lost their faith
in this country's rule and government.
Now it's our turn
to risk our lives for them.
My Lord!
- My Lord!
- What happened?
Has there been any word
from Jang Bong Soo?
Yes, they will be
taking the path to Uiju.
It seems they will be
reaching the country safely.
My Lord.
Sir. Jang Bong Soo.
Oh it's you, Ja Gyung.
I received word
that you would come here.
Good.
Here.
This is the gunpowder we're going to use,
from the Weapons Bureau.
And this... is money given
to us by Princess Jungmyung.
What about you, sir?
Are you really going to join us?
That's right.
I'm going to join you guys today.
My wife is one of those prisoners.
How can I just give this to you and leave?
Sir.
My Lord.
- Is everyone here?
- Yes, My Lord.
But the young master has still not...
What happened?
He received a message during
training and left right away.
Is that so?
Princess Jungmyung.
My Lord.
Everyone is waiting.
Please come inside.
Let's start the meeting now.
As you all know, Later Jin is being more
aggressive due to the prisoners escape.
But... just what on earth
are you all doing?
Where and who is causing this mess...
How is it that we can't find out?
- Please let us go!
- Please save us!
- Don't send us back!
- Please save us, sir!
Please!
Soldiers and a boat to Later Jin
will be waiting for us.
- Let's go.
- Yes, sir.
Sir, please save us!
Please do not send us back!
- What are you doing? Let's go!
- Sir! Sir!
Sir! Sir!
- Get going!
- Please!
- What is going on here?
- General, I think it's an attack!
- They're trying to save the prisoners.
- What?
How did they know about our plan?
You must not shoot the prisoners!
We have to save them, no matter what!
Do not retreat!
We cannot let go of these prisoners!
General, it's impossible! Their guns
are much more advanced than ours!
What?
We must retreat, General!
The gunpowder is almost gone!
- We will die if we continue!
- Damn it!
Really? So, who is that person?
Every time there is an attack...
They come armed with guns and firepower!
And time after time...
They knew the secret whereabouts
of the prisoners!
Hurry! We must leave immediately
and get them to safety!
Thank you! Thank you!
It's okay.
Let's go. Can you walk?
Wife.
Honey.
Sir.
Wife.
Without a doubt,
they have money and power.
And they have intel.
- Is the money in transit?
- Yes, Your Highness.
The rescued prisoners were being chased.
The money will be used
to find them a new place to live.
What about the gunpowder and weapons?
That is being provided
by the Weapons Bureau.
The Weapons Bureau will be audited in
several days. Will there be any problems?
I'll take care of that from my end,
so do not worry.
My Lord.
Lord Gang Joo Seon is still safe.
He has not been able to get any
particular information, Ma'am.
And...
these secret border missions will continue
and be provided for by the east palace.
And without a doubt, there is a
powerful supporter behind that movement.
We must find him.
We must find that power, no matter what.
Many more eyes and ears
will follow us from now on.
All of you will have to be very careful.
I will not give a single innocent life
to the enemy anymore.
Yes, even if that means I have to
disobey every royal command and law.
To me, it's more important than a royal
command and more precious than any law.
This country.
I am going to protect
the lives of my people.
- Your Highness.
What did you say?
The army at the border got attacked again?
Yes, Your Majesty.
They were unable
to return the prisoners to Later Jin
because of the surprise attack last night.
They lost everyone, Sire.
So... will those barbarians
send a special envoy again?
Are they going to send one
and insult me again?
- Where is Later Jin's emissary?
- He's waiting inside right now.
Look here, sir!
Do you think we went easy on you during
the war so we could be insulted like this?
Please calm down.
We still do not know who the culprit is.
It is only a scheme
to save the poor souls.
Joseon has no intentions
of going against Later Jin.
If that is the case,
then you must show us that loyalty.
Our Khan is looking kindly upon you, sir.
- Don't you think this is unfair?
- Please do not worry.
The officials are involved now,
and the prisoners will be captured soon.
No, no. That is not enough.
Once you catch those prisoners, Joseon
will have to submit to us completely.
The Khan has finally made a decision, sir.
Chief Inspector.
- When you say it's Khan's decision...
- Yes.
So, that titled envoy
will come to Joseon soon.
Ma'am, you're here.
Have you heard the news?
I heard Jang Bong Soo's wife
was rescued last night.
- Is it true?
- Yes, Ma'am.
They've been traveling all night and
she's hiding in the storage right now.
Thanks, Eun Sol. Here you go.
Go ahead and changes your clothes first.
Oh my word, that lovely face of yours.
I can't believe how much you changed.
Ms. Ok Joo.
Change your clothes quickly and
let's get you something to eat, okay?
Eun Sol.
Yes, I'll go and make
some porridge for her.
- Great.
- Hey... wait for me.
You can't make that by yourself.
Change your clothes first.
I'm... not sure if I deserve
this kind of hospitality.
What do you mean?
You did nothing wrong.
I hid behind our child during the war.
I don't deserve to live.
Woman, are you serious right now?
What about me?
Haven't you thought about me?
- Huh?
- Honey...
We lost our only child during
the war against those barbarians.
When I found out you were captured
by them, how do you think I felt?
I was sick with worry if you got
hurt or if you were even alive.
- Every day was torture for me.
- Honey.
I swear to you, nothing happened to me!
If something did happen to me,
I'd rather die...
Stop! That's enough!
Don't say such things.
Who cares if something did happen.
It doesn't matter to me.
You're back, and that's all that matters.
That is all that matters.
One of the rescued prisoners
was Jang Bong Soo's wife?
Yes, Your Highness.
This all thanks to your support, Sire.
If you had not given us
that intel about the border...
We would not have been able
to save those prisoners.
No, Princess Jungmyung.
If it wasn't for your strength and support
I would not have had
the courage to continue.
Your Highness.
But this is only the beginning.
Because of these past events
any officials connected to Later Jin
will pursue you more aggressively.
Also, I don't know
what kind of countermeasures
Later Jin will attack us with.
- And the King will comply.
- I know.
But we will come up with a plan as well.
More than ever, you must protect
yourself and your family first.
Do you understand?
Yes, Your Highness.
You too, Sire.
You've come
to the east palace again, Ma'am.
Prince Bongrim.
Please forgive me, but I would
like to talk to you for a moment.
Do you have the time?
Find out if there's anything going on
between the Crown Prince
and Princess Jungmyung.
If you find evidence
that they have conspired together...
you will be able
to turn the King's heart around.
Get the coach ready.
I'm going to see the Crown Princess.
Yes, Ma'am.
Prince Bongrim, what do you mean by that?
You want me to keep my distance
from the Crown Prince?
No, you know very well
what I'm talking about.
The whole world knows that you and
the King are at odds with one another.
You're afraid that the King will spurn
the Crown Prince because of me.
I'm very sorry for saying this.
I'm the Crown Prince's brother, Ma'am.
Moreover, I have no choice
but to look out for him.
Prince Bongrim.
My father and brother's relationship
must not break.
The royal family has suffered many
tragedies because of these problems.
So, please do not leave
even a trace of bad luck behind.
If you care about Prince Sohyun...
Please... please do this.
I've already received your gifts.
Why are you giving me
these trinkets again, Sukwon?
Princess, saying those words
is not enough to communicate my heart.
Words are not enough to express one's joy.
I have always wanted to support you.
When the former queen was alive,
I could not bring myself to interfere.
I was afraid it wasn't
my place to do that.
Sukwon.
But from now on,
I will support and take care of you.
I have seen the Crown Prince grow
since he was a little boy.
Granted, I'm not his birth mother...
But the Crown Prince is like a son to me.
Thank you for those kind words.
I am happy to know that you
think of him with a mother's heart.
Princess.
My Lord.
Did anything happen last night?
What about my father?
It's hard to see your face these days.
Father.
What is it?
Did something happen?
No. I have matters to attend to
at the training center.
There are also things I have
to take care of right away
due to the border incident
several days ago.
I wanted to talk to you about that.
Come inside.
What is this? Just what in the world...
What does all this mean?
Father, what should we do?
This is a royal letter from Later Jin.
How can I give this to the King?
I swear...
Father, I'm the secretary,
and I have to give this to the King.
I'm really scared.
Father, can't you
give this to him instead of me?
What if he gets angry
and throws something at me?
Ah goodness.
By any chance, is this what I think it is?
Later Jin's plan that
Kang Joo Seon talked about?
Damn it.
Goodness.
Did you just say the Khan
has sent a royal letter?
That's right. It probably arrived
at the palace by now.
Just what on earth is
the letter about, Father?
What is it that it's making you
so nervous like this?
Father.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty.
How dare they! Those damn barbarians!
Sir, then you mean...
The one thing we're afraid of
is coming to fruition.
The Khan's true ambition
is being revealed.
I heard you two were here.
- We need to talk...
- Princess Jungmyung.
Princess Jungmyung.
What is the matter?
Did something happen?
Your Highness,
what should we do about this?
Where is that letter the Khan has sent?
Father!
- Father.
- Your Majesty.
What is this, Crown Prince?
What are these barbarians talking about?
They want us to be under their rule now?
And they want me to call
that bastard my king?
Also... what is this?
They want the Joseon army to join theirs?
Sir, then that means...
Yes, that is correct, Ma'am.
It's a declaration to Joseon
to cut off all ties with the Ming dynasty.
But, Joseon cannot do that.
How can the royal family
and officials do that?
That is why this should be considered
another act of war, Princess.
Yes, this is a second declaration of war.
Subtitles by DramaFever
Later Jin is full of confidence now.
They plan on conquering Joseon.
Ultimately, the Crown Prince
must get involved.
He must greet the Later Jin's party.
Both of them will get into trouble.
You must stop the Crown Prince.
When the country is in turmoil, shouldn't
our family prepare the next king?
The Crown Prince.
The Crown Prince, you say?
I'm telling you what you need to do now.
That war is going to happen again.
That is why it breaks my heart more
because I have to go
against my father's will.
Uploaded by: simasuk1
Subtitles ripped by vikisubstitle
Uploaded by: s
Uploaded by: si
Uploaded by: sim
Uploaded by: sima
Uploaded by: simas
Uploaded by: simasu
Uploaded by: simasuk
Uploaded by: simasuk1
Subtitles ripped by vikisubstitle
Subtitles by DramaFever