My name is Bridget.
I witnessed a murder.
Just get up on the stand,
tell the judge what you saw.
And we'll protect you.
I know Jimmy's got my back.
I thought I'd be safe.
Turns out I was wrong.
You testify against him
tomorrow, you're dead.
You can't trust the feds.
I can trust you?
I'm not asking you to trust me,
I'm asking you to run.
Bridget: I ran to
my sister Siobhan for help.
Siobhan killed herself,
and I assumed her identity.
It was so easy. I saw a way out
and I took it.
I'm in labor. I need to
get to the hospital.
You did great.
Siobhan, the girls are so beautiful.
You asked to see me?
Yeah.
I want a paternity test.
♪ Don't hang it out ♪
♪ for everyone to see ♪
Woman:
She takes my breath away.
♪ I'd rather keep it ♪
♪ locked without a key ♪
♪ I'll never know ♪
♪ what might have been ♪
♪ if I wouldn't have
let myself... ♪
You look beautiful.
Thank you.
Your union has withstood
more than its fair share
of trials and tribulations...
And yet, here you stand today,
more in love than ever.
Hey.
Oh, thanks.
I, Andrew Martin,
pledge myself to you.
I promise to love,
honor, and cherish you.
I...
Siobhan Martin...
Pledge myself to you.
I promise to honor,
and love and cherish you.
(Applause)
(Mellow jazz playing)
- Break it up, you two. Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Thank you for all your help.
Thank you.
(Gasps)
I can't believe I
finally got my one-year chip.
Felt like it took 20.
I-I wouldn't have gotten this
without my sponsor Malcolm.
And this is because of him.
When I was using, I didn't
care about anything.
And I didn't mean anything to anyone.
In the last seven months,
I really learned to
let people in.
And they'd let me in.
Feels good to say that...
Life is good.
(Chuckles)
And I'm walking down
the aisle in less than a week.
Technically, it's a vow renewal.
But it feels like the first time.
Just my husband and my stepdaughter
in, uh, Turks and Caicos.
(Chuckles)
But before I do, I...
I have to tell them my secret.
Just remember...
When you come clean, you stay clean.
Which is why I am going
to tell them tonight.
I'm finally going to tell my family
who I really am.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
Do you have any idea
what you stand to lose?
My family.
My sobriety.
Your life.
You're finally safe as Siobhan.
Don't get me wrong,
I think it's great
that you want to be honest but...
But outing yourself as Bridget
Kelly isn't the smartest move.
Bodaway wants her dead,
not Siobhan Martin.
I know what the risks are.
But they don't outweigh the damage
that I am doing to
the two people that I love.
I made up my mind.
I can't walk down that aisle
until I tell them.
Do you really think there's gonna be
an aisle to walk down,
once you tell Andrew?
I don't know.
(Sighs) I never knew it would be
this hard to sign my name.
I don't know how to thank you, Tim.
This buy out is
saving martin/ Charles.
I'm a businessman, Andrew.
Not a Saint.
My advisors are calling it
a tax write-off.
Well, regardless of
your intentions...
I'm indebted to you.
Damn right you are.
Tim, it's nice to see you.
Lovely to see you too.
Am I interrupting?
I can go.
Not at all. We were just,
uh, finishing up.
Is everything all right?
Yeah... yeah I, um,
I wanted to make sure you'd be
home for dinner tonight.
I'm going to cook.
Really? What's the occasion?
No occasion.
Just 'cause.
Isn't that sweet?
Uh, did I mention
we're renewing our vows?
I know you were sleeping
with Siobhan Martin.
I'm going to destroy you.
I will make you and Siobhan
pay for what you did.
Congratulations to you both.
I should get going.
Take care, Siobhan.
You too, Tim.
I think Mr. Arbogast
might be a little more apropos,
seeing that he's my boss.
Andrew, I know that
this is less than ideal, but...
It's better than
the alternative, I know.
This way, he's saving my investors
from financial ruin and me from jail.
No offense, but I don't think
you would fare too well in jail.
(Chuckles)
And besides,
I couldn't stand to be away
from you for that long.
Conjugal visits would not cut it.
(Chuckles)
You know, I'm so grateful to
be given an second chance.
Sometimes I feel I don't deserve it.
Everyone deserves
a second chance, right?
Hey.
What did the doctor say?
We're doing beautifully; They'll
be ready to leave next week.
I mean, we got to
sign this first, though.
Which means the girls are
finally ready for some names.
You settle on any?
Portia and Regan.
(Laughs) Come on, Siobhan.
I was thinking more
"Franny and Zooey,"
little less Shakespearean tragedy.
Uh...
Look, I gotta go pick
the boys up from school.
But, before I go, I wanted to
talk to you about something.
I want to move to Chicago.
You said you were ready to leave.
You said that we could take
the money you stole
from martin/Charles
and go anywhere I want.
And I want to go to Chicago
to be close to my family.
Sounds like you've
already made up your mind.
Look, I'm just,
I'm just done with all of this.
The lies, the scheming,
I need to get away from it all.
Henry, I have two little girls
in intensive care.
The only thing that I've done
is lose sleep.
- There's no scheming on my end.
- But the fact is,
you still hate your sister.
And you said that you'd be
willing to give up on revenge
if it meant losing me. But I
have a hard time believing that.
You wanted Andrew to kill Bridget,
thinking that she was you.
But you were wrong about Andrew.
He didn't want you dead, so...
What if you were wrong about Bridget?
I mean, is she really
to blame for Sean?
You've got to start giving
people the benefit of the doubt.
I've got my boys back.
And the only thing that is
keeping me in New York is you.
And the only thing that's
keeping you here
is your vendetta
against Bridget, so...
Sweetheart, if we
are going to move on,
you gotta move on.
Machado: Agent Wiegler,
you wanted to see me?
Wiegler: Thanks to that hard
work you did in New York,
you're back on active duty.
But it comes with a condition.
Vic, you're too good an agent to
be suspended again.
So, effective immediately,
you're off the
Bodaway Macawi case, for good.
No offense, Royce.
I made a promise to
put Bodaway behind bars.
- If I just had a little more time...
- I'm sorry, but
did I give the impression that
this was up for discussion?
Look, we've tried doing it your way.
I made allowances because I know
your connection with the victim.
I reassigned you under Torrance,
hoping that he was gonna
reign you in.
We both know how that ended,
now, don't we?
You almost got arrested, Vic.
Now you have a choice:
Starting today, either you sever
all ties to Bodaway Macawi...
Or find yourself another job.
Jimmy:
Hi, Siobhan.
Bet you thought you'd
never see me again.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Oh, I'm not here to hurt you.
Really?
'Cause last I heard, you were serving
a life sentence for murder.
Yeah, well, Christmas came early.
What do you want from me?
Well, it's not what I want,
it's what Bodaway wants.
Well, I'm sorry, but I can't
help you with that.
I don't know where Bridget is.
The last I heard
from her was September.
To tell you the truth, I don't
give a rat's ass where she is.
The plan's changed.
I'm sick of being Bodaway's bitch.
So, why are you coming to me?
'Cause you're going to pay me,
just like last time.
... Eventually acquitted of the
murder of his younger brother...
Hey.
Can I get a whiskey
and a beer, please?
This Bodaway trial's all
this town's talking about, huh?
Name is John, by the way.
I'm not from here, obviously.
Thank you.
You know where a guy
can get a good steak?
This ain't Brokeback Mountain, pal.
You want some action,
go two towns over
to the circle bar.
I'm not hitting on you, buddy.
Actually, more like hitting you up.
I got a job for you.
You're guarding Bridget Kelly, right?
Word on the ranch is
her safety's
not exactly your priority.
And I've got
an inside source that says
you're working for Bodaway Macawi.
But I could pay you double.
I'm not working for anyone.
And even if I was,
you couldn't afford me.
But I can.
Bridget, what are you doing here?
It's Siobhan.
I'm the good twin.
And I'll cut right to the chase
so John here doesn't
talk your ear off.
You're going to scare
Bridget into running.
Actually, you're going to
scare her into running to me.
And for that, I will pay you double.
Fine... triple, if I have to.
But you're not leaving this bar
until you say yes.
You okay?
Yeah.
It's just a lot.
Well, looks like
you're doing all right.
50 k's a drop in the bucket for you.
But it's plenty to make me disappear.
Why should I pay you one cent?
You're an escaped convict.
All I have to do is call
the authorities and turn you in.
Last I checked, 911 was free.
Yeah...
But that would end up
costing you a lot more.
See, not only does Bodaway
not know I was working for you;
he doesn't know
that Bridget had a twin.
If you refuse to pay,
I got to keep working for Bodaway.
Which means
I got to find your sister.
And since nobody's got a damn clue
as to where she is,
I could always tell Bodaway
that you're Bridget.
(Footsteps)
Hey.
What's going on here?
Um, I'm packing for Chicago.
(Chuckles)
I figure, once the girls get
released from the hospital
and the doctors give them
the okay to get on a plane,
then we'll come and meet you.
If that's still okay.
If it's still okay?
It's better than okay.
It's great.
I mean, you know, it's not New York,
but you're going to love Chicago.
Mmm. Well, we can see about that one.
I just... I'm ready
for us to be together
and move on with our life.
You know, my sister
has been sending me listings,
and she found a place
that she really loves.
It's on the lake.
It's near good schools and museums.
And each kid can have their own room.
I mean, the only thing is,
it's out of my price range.
I thought we were buying
this house together.
You have no idea what that means
to hear you say that, but...
I mean, I...
I don't know
how long it's going to take
to sell this place,
and there's just a lot of stuff
to work out before we buy anything.
No.
Not if I give you the money
for the down payment.
(Laughing): You don't even know
what the asking price is.
Come on, I'm doing what you said.
I'm giving the benefit of the doubt.
I just want us all to be
together... as a family.
All right, so what do you want first?
The bad news or the worse news?
Those my only two options?
All right, give me the bad first.
An unidentified body
was discovered in Hoboken.
Uh, there's no DNA
or dental records yet,
but the face structure scan
and bone proportion
suggest it could be Malcolm ward.
Now, I know it's probably not a shock
after finding his wallet
on Daniel Eknath's body,
but still...
I'm really sorry.
Yeah, me, too.
Well, if that's
the bad news, what's worse?
Jimmy Kemper escaped
from prison yesterday.
I figured you'd want to know,
considering you were the one
who put the guy behind bars.
Andrew (Laughing):
Right.
"So long, suckers!"
"Sucker!" That's what he said.
"S-sucker""
your mouth goes to
the side like that.
"Sucker."
It's true.
Those were his words, not mine.
Rough day?
Oh, um... sorry.
It was a bit hectic.
Well, all you have to do now
is sit back
and enjoy this delicious meal
you prepared.
(Cell phone buzzing)
Actually, there's, uh, something
I wanted to talk to you both about.
Juliet:
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, you guys.
Andrea's boyfriend just broke up
with her in a text.
I have... I have to go call her.
Juliet, sit.
That was rude.
Which I guess means
she's doing better.
Therapy was a good idea.
And vacation.
The most needed trip of the year.
- Andrew...
- Actually, I'm glad it's just
the two of us,
'cause there's something
I wanted to share with you, as well.
Do you mind if I go first?
No. Go ahead.
(Chuckles)
I've been working on my vows.
I know the first time
around, we just...
Repeated "I do,"
but this is different.
I wanted to say something special.
I found a poem,
"marriage song."
May I read you a bit?
Of course.
"There is my dove,
"my loved one.
"None with her can compare.
"Her beauty shames the day-star
and makes the darkness light.
"Day in her radiant presence
grows seven times more bright."
When I found it,
I knew I was reading about you.
For the rest of our lives,
I promise to find you in every poem,
to see you in every work of art,
to hear you in every love song.
I'm amazed by the power you have
over my heart, Siobhan.
I, uh, can't get over...
How you've stuck by me
through everything.
(Sighs)
You've made me a better man,
and I just hope that I can continue
to be the husband that you deserve.
It's beautiful.
Thank you.
Now it's your turn.
I...
After that, it can wait.
(Sighs)
Going somewhere?
What are you doing here?
Had you followed.
Didn't think you could be trusted.
Guess I was right.
I'm a fugitive, remember?
Wanted for two murders
I didn't commit
because I was covering your ass.
I got no choice but to run.
But I thought we had a deal, Jimmy.
We do.
We do, and I'm...
I'm honoring it.
Look, I...
I found Bridget, all right?
She's... she's here.
She's in New York.
And she must have found a sugar daddy
'cause the bitch
is living the... the high life
over on park Avenue going by the name
of Siobhan... (Grunts)
Martin.
(Whispering):
Yeah... yeah...
I'm one step ahead of you.
When you told me
that Kemper made you run,
I never would have guessed
that your sister
and Delario were behind it.
It just doesn't make any sense.
Why would Siobhan pay someone
to make me run to her
only to kill herself
a few days later?
I don't know.
But I did some digging.
Cop buddy of mine
slipped me John Delario's file.
Turns out there's a record of him
being in the Hamptons September 8.
He had lunch with your sister...
A long lunch... at Tipton's reef.
They talked for hours,
and they left together in his car.
So they were still in contact.
Yeah. I'm gonna head up
to the Hamptons later
and see what else I can dig up.
In the meantime,
I want you to take this.
No, I don't like guns.
You have to protect yourself.
I don't like the idea
of you and Kemper
running around in the same city.
Kemper's long gone by now.
Really, it's not...
What?
Necessary?
If memory serves, the last time
you turned down a gun,
it ended up saving your life.
Okay. Thank you.
It's pretty quiet around here.
Is that a good thing?
I haven't told them.
I was going to last night,
and then Andrew read me his vows.
That pedestal he puts me on, it...
It's a long way to fall.
But I...
I know that you're right.
This isn't a fantasy; It's real life.
And when I do tell them,
it'll be over.
So what are you going to do?
I'm still going to tell them.
Tonight.
At your going-away party?
After.
I want one last night of the fantasy.
♪ Don't shut me out ♪
♪ forget who I was ♪
♪ what I was about ♪
♪ oh ♪
♪ look hard enough... ♪
Hey. What's that?
You had a paternity test done?
You were sleeping with Tyler.
I needed to know
if the twins were mine.
Look, Siobhan,
we're going to start
a new life together,
and I want to trust you.
I really do.
What's it say?
What I knew it would always say:
The girls are yours.
(Chuckles)
Thank you.
You just made a hard
decision very easy for me.
I'll be reachable by cell and e-mail.
And Claudine has all the
contact info for the resort,
just in case.
Have a safe trip.
Thank you.
You know, I'm a lucky man, Tim.
I get to marry the woman
of my dreams twice.
Andrew, wait.
There's one other thing.
I didn't really know
if it was my place,
but I can't be a hypocrite.
I attacked you for your dishonesty,
but now I need to tell you the truth.
Greer:
I haven't seen Andrew around.
Is he hiding someplace?
Oh, he's coming from work.
He said he might be a bit late.
Speak of the devil.
I just found out that everything
between us is a lie.
Excuse me?
I know about the affair with Henry.
Um, guys, what's going on?
I am not having an affair with Henry.
But you were...
For over a year.
Don't even try to deny it.
Arbogast told me everything:
How he hired a private investigator.
Showed me phone records,
hotel receipts.
Do you guys need some privacy?
I can ask the guests to leave.
I think that's a great idea.
Because there aren't gonna be
any nuptials to celebrate.
(Guests murmuring)
This marriage is over.
Daddy, dad...
Dad, wait.
Henry?
How much was that down payment?
Uh, I didn't put down the payment.
My balance is drained.
Somebody must have
hacked into my account.
Bridget did it last time,
but there's no way she would
know about this one.
Bridget didn't steal from you.
I did.
What?
I wanted to take away
the one thing that meant
something to you.
You know, kind of like
you took away everything
that meant anything to me.
I don't understand.
I grew anxious,
and so I called the hospital
about the paternity test.
I knew the results before
you opened the letter.
All that talk to me about honesty,
and you were lying?
The test
was a test!
I wanted to see how you would
handle the truth.
Because the funny thing is
I could handle
not being the girls' dad,
but I cannot take another lie.
I mean, does anything
come out of your mouth
that is actually the truth?
Everything that I have done is
so that we can be together.
Henry, I love you.
That's the truth.
Well...
I don't love you anymore.
Now I'm gonna go out.
And when I get back, I want you gone.
Henry, I don't have anywhere to go.
I don't have any money...
Well, I'm sure you'll figure
something out.
You always do.
The last of the guests are gone.
Thanks.
Where's Juliet?
I sent her to my place.
Give her a chance to clear her head.
I can't believe this is happening.
I had every intention
of telling him...
Just not like this.
Yeah, but you know,
maybe it's for the best.
Now that everything's
out in the open,
maybe you really can start fresh.
What's wrong?
Um, you know, I think I just
feel like being alone
if that's okay.
Yeah, of course.
Just know I'm here for you.
I do.
Call if you need anything, okay?
(Phone rings)
Mrs. Martin.
Bodaway Macawi's in New York.
What?
Jimmy Kemper found me.
Threatened to tell Bodaway
that I was Bridget.
Now Kemper's dead...
Which can only mean one thing.
Please, agent Machado,
you're the only person
that can help me.
Mrs. Martin, look, I'm sorry,
but my involvement in
the Macawi case is over.
Why?
Because my job depends on it.
And considering I've already
lost everything else,
I just can't afford
to lose that, too.
But look, you have every right
to be concerned.
The second we hang up, I'm gonna
call the New York office.
I gotta go.
No, Mrs. Martin, wait!
(Sighs)
I know you probably don't
want to talk to me right now,
but you deserve to know the truth.
I love you more than I ever thought
it was possible to love someone.
My life... completely changed
when I met you seven months ago.
Seven years.
(Chuckles ruefully)
No.
Seven months.
I didn't cheat on you with Henry.
Andrew, I...
I'm not Siobhan.
I'm Bridget.
Obviously, there were things
about my wife
that I didn't know, but suicide?!
There's just no way!
It happened.
I was there.
I'm sorry that this...
Don't you dare apologize!
There are no words to make up
for what you've done!
You looked me in the eye and cried
about your drug addict,
prostitute sister.
And little did I know that I was
sleeping next to her
for the past seven months.
I never intended for it
to go on this long.
I was only doing it
to protect myself.
I never thought...
I was gonna fall in love with you.
I so wanted to Siobhan
to have changed.
I guess you believe what
you want to believe, huh?
(Sighs)
Like I needed to believe that
you might forgive me.
That somehow you might...
Love me for me.
(Chuckles)
I do love you...
... But it's all a lie.
Don't say that.
You know that's not true!
Andrew, I only did this
because it was the only way
that I could protect myself.
I told you, take it easy.
Will you lay off...?
It's a party.
(Glass breaks, body thuds,
woman sobs)
Shay?
(Shaylene gasping)
Bodaway:
I know who you're working for, Saylene.
I work... for... you!
(Gasping)
(Grunts)
I ran as far as I could.
It's a miracle
that Bodaway didn't get me.
But the cops did.
I have so many
regrets about what I've done.
The basic tenet of NA is truth, and...
And all I've been doing is lying.
But the one thing
that I have no regrets about...
Is loving you...
And Juliet.
I stayed sober because
I had two people whose expectations
I wanted to live up to.
I'm so sorry.
And for what it's worth,
(sighs)
I'm a better person for loving you.
You need to leave.
You know you can stay
as long as you like.
London, honey,
help me set up the guest room
so we can give Siobhan
and Juliet some privacy.
How could you do this, Siobhan?
I mean, I thought you and daddy
were happy together.
And I thought that the three
of us were finally starting
to become a real family.
We are a real family.
And I didn't have an affair.
Then why would Mr. Arbogast say that?
Because...
I'm not who he thinks I am.
Oh. Hey, Andrew.
What are you doing here?
I've been wanting to do that
since the day I met you.
Say something.
I knew you were
too good to be true...
Bridget.
Juliet, I...
Don't bother!
You think my mom's an awful person?
You are exactly like her.
Actually... worse.
She's sick.
What's your excuse?
♪ Make it happen ♪
♪ make it happen... ♪
(Horn honking)
Ready?
I don't want to go to the beach.
And I can't stay at home.
Come on, sweetheart.
Remember what I said?
It can be me and you
against the world.
No matter what...
We always have each other.
Okay.
(Laughs)
♪ ♪
(Thud, crash)
Hello?
Andrew?
(Sighs)
(Grunts, chokes)
Hello, Bridget.
You have the wrong girl.
No! I'm not Bridget!
(Grunts)
(Groans)
I can't leave things
with Juliet like this.
I mean, I don't even know if
Andrew's gonna let me see her,
I just need the chance
to be able to tell...
Oh, my God.
Solomon: Bridget?
Solomon, call 911.
Bridget, what's happening?
Bodaway's here.
Bridget?
Bridget!
Damn it!
You can't hide forever, Bridget!
This ends tonight.
(Footsteps grow quiet)
(Gasps)
(Yells)
Stop!
Juliet!
What the hell?
Drop the knife!
Easy.
I said drop it now.
Andrew?
(Grunts)
(Choking)
Machado:
FBI! Freeze!
(Bridget gasping)
Mrs. Martin, it's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay, Mrs. Martin.
It's okay.
Oh... what are you doing here?
The second you hung up,
I got on a plane.
But where's Juliet?
I heard her yelling.
No, no.
I spoke with your husband.
He and Juliet have been in
the Hamptons since midnight.
Officer:
It's clear.
Then who was Bodaway attacking?
Ma'am, visiting hours are over.
I'm sorry.
I know.
I don't have anywhere to go.
We don't have anywhere to go.
I might be able to find you a cot.
I have to get my old life back.
Officer:
We're releasing the scene now.
Aren't you glad you took that gun?
I got something to show you.
Ugh, now what?
Surveillance footage.
Turns out Delario rented
a boat at the same marina
that your sister docked her boat at.
September 9.
The day... Siobhan died.
That's not all.
4:17. That's...
Three hours after my sister drowned.
♪ She was made ♪
♪ to blow you away... ♪
Siobhan's alive?
♪ And she don't care ♪
♪ what any man say... ♪
(Clears throat)
Oh, Siobhan, what?
It's 3:00 a.m.
It's Bridget.
(Sighs)
But you know that already, don't you?
Yeah.
Where is she?
I don't... I don't know.
I kicked her out earlier.
It's over between me and Siobhan.
She was here.
In New York.
That's who Bodaway
attacked in the apartment.
What are you talking about?
Why did she lie to me?
Why did she want me to think
that she killed herself?
Because she knew that someone
was trying to kill her.
♪ Well, now she's long... ♪
And she wanted you to take her place.
♪ Yeah, now she's long gone... ♪
For what you did to Sean.
♪ Like Moses
through the corn... ♪
Siobhan wanted me dead?
♪ Long gone, like Moses
through the corn ♪
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com