1
00:00:00,040 --> 00:00:00,040
23.976

2
00:00:01,600 --> 00:00:06,400
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org

3
00:01:20,080 --> 00:01:22,200
Happy endings are the best?

4
00:01:22,600 --> 00:01:23,960
Shit!

5
00:01:24,160 --> 00:01:25,120
I told you...

6
00:01:25,280 --> 00:01:26,880
I hated romantic comedies

7
00:01:27,000 --> 00:01:27,680
Yeah...

8
00:01:27,760 --> 00:01:29,840
A Jackie Chan flick
would've been better

9
00:01:30,080 --> 00:01:31,800
She wanted to see
this, huh?

10
00:01:35,440 --> 00:01:36,400
That girl...

11
00:01:36,720 --> 00:01:39,000
Tell her to just stay
in the theater forever

12
00:01:39,160 --> 00:01:39,920
Hey!

13
00:01:40,080 --> 00:01:41,320
Just spend the rest of
your life here, okay?

14
00:01:41,520 --> 00:01:42,840
- Yeah?
- What?

15
00:01:43,760 --> 00:01:45,800
Directed by Moh Jee-eun

16
00:02:00,400 --> 00:02:03,200
A PERFECT MATCH

17
00:02:04,240 --> 00:02:06,200
I'm gonna live happily
ever after

18
00:02:06,800 --> 00:02:08,320
America has too
many divorces

19
00:02:08,480 --> 00:02:09,880
I'll never divorce!

20
00:02:10,160 --> 00:02:13,320
I'll meet a nice girl
and have a happy marriage

21
00:02:20,840 --> 00:02:22,520
Hi, when will you finish?

22
00:02:23,960 --> 00:02:26,960
Shin Eun-gyung

23
00:02:29,600 --> 00:02:32,400
Jung Joon-ho

24
00:02:32,520 --> 00:02:34,440
I think I've seen you...

25
00:02:38,720 --> 00:02:39,800
My family is

26
00:02:40,040 --> 00:02:42,520
So Confucian that ever
since I was a kid

27
00:02:42,880 --> 00:02:45,600
Grandpa made me read
a lot of books on Confucianism

28
00:02:46,120 --> 00:02:47,640
Would you like to
hear some?

29
00:02:48,200 --> 00:02:49,040
Pardon?

30
00:02:50,000 --> 00:02:53,000
That's why I always have
it with me on paper

31
00:02:54,480 --> 00:02:57,040
Confucius says
I became learned at 10

32
00:02:57,520 --> 00:02:59,720
self-aware at 30
unchangeable at 40

33
00:03:00,240 --> 00:03:01,360
enlightened at 50

34
00:03:01,640 --> 00:03:04,120
wise at 60
and desireless at 70

35
00:03:04,560 --> 00:03:06,920
Knowing what you know

36
00:03:07,200 --> 00:03:08,720
and don't know is knowing

37
00:03:08,800 --> 00:03:09,600
What could he be like?

38
00:03:09,840 --> 00:03:11,120
Probably nothing great

39
00:03:11,920 --> 00:03:15,320
Let's go take a look

40
00:03:34,600 --> 00:03:35,880
Excuse me

41
00:03:38,000 --> 00:03:39,360
Think I can do well?

42
00:03:41,200 --> 00:03:42,600
Don't be too nervous

43
00:03:42,600 --> 00:03:44,520
Just be your natural self

44
00:03:45,640 --> 00:03:46,960
30 minutes left

45
00:03:49,760 --> 00:03:50,920
Are you hurt?

46
00:03:51,000 --> 00:03:52,880
No, I'm okay

47
00:03:55,920 --> 00:03:59,400
Think there's
a right girl for me?

48
00:03:59,520 --> 00:04:02,160
Confucius said
sandals need a match, too

49
00:04:02,320 --> 00:04:03,160
Today...

50
00:04:03,280 --> 00:04:04,880
She'll be just your size

51
00:04:04,960 --> 00:04:06,600
So don't worry too much

52
00:04:06,720 --> 00:04:09,680
Confucius said that, too?

53
00:04:21,280 --> 00:04:22,360
Wait!

54
00:04:25,040 --> 00:04:27,080
Your face turns white
when you drink, right?

55
00:04:27,320 --> 00:04:30,920
Instead of coffee
have a drink with her, okay?

56
00:04:31,400 --> 00:04:34,120
But it's our first meet
and it's the daytime

57
00:04:34,240 --> 00:04:36,840
The girl you'll meet
is very nice

58
00:04:37,040 --> 00:04:38,960
But she likes to drink

59
00:04:39,160 --> 00:04:40,240
I see

60
00:04:40,600 --> 00:04:42,120
Let's hurry it up

61
00:04:42,320 --> 00:04:43,600
Sorry folks

62
00:04:43,880 --> 00:04:45,320
And about that Confucianism

63
00:04:45,640 --> 00:04:48,480
It's important
but not in front of the girl

64
00:04:48,720 --> 00:04:50,760
Well, I wish you luck

65
00:04:50,960 --> 00:04:53,280
Sir, you can do it!

66
00:04:53,560 --> 00:04:54,320
I can do it!

67
00:05:04,320 --> 00:05:06,520
Why isn't the elevator working?

68
00:05:06,680 --> 00:05:08,200
You're telling me

69
00:05:10,160 --> 00:05:12,400
My style is ruined for today

70
00:05:12,720 --> 00:05:15,400
How many calories
would six floors be?

71
00:05:15,760 --> 00:05:16,600
Anyway

72
00:05:18,080 --> 00:05:19,080
Hyo-jin

73
00:05:22,280 --> 00:05:23,160
She's got charlie horse again

74
00:05:23,320 --> 00:05:24,840
Cut her leg off

75
00:05:25,080 --> 00:05:26,760
Unbelievable

76
00:05:35,120 --> 00:05:40,040
Hi!
We're getting married!

77
00:05:40,240 --> 00:05:42,640
I love you honey!

78
00:05:48,720 --> 00:05:50,920
Hyo-jin, you've done it again

79
00:05:52,040 --> 00:05:52,560
Very Good!

80
00:05:52,640 --> 00:05:54,320
Because of my son's marriage

81
00:05:54,640 --> 00:05:57,800
I take him to Buddhist
mass every morning

82
00:05:58,360 --> 00:06:01,520
What's wrong
if he went on eight blind dates?

83
00:06:02,160 --> 00:06:04,400
He's handsome
and talented

84
00:06:05,400 --> 00:06:08,800
Regardless
don't count the last date

85
00:06:09,600 --> 00:06:12,400
Your son was
an hour late last time

86
00:06:12,680 --> 00:06:15,280
He hardly takes calls
so it's hard to fix a date

87
00:06:15,560 --> 00:06:16,920
And he's always late

88
00:06:17,160 --> 00:06:20,560
I'm sorry but
I can't cancel the last one

89
00:06:20,880 --> 00:06:22,280
You can't?

90
00:06:23,040 --> 00:06:25,760
Then I'll take
my business elsewhere

91
00:06:26,600 --> 00:06:29,160
Ouch, my head!
I give up

92
00:06:29,600 --> 00:06:31,400
Do as you like

93
00:06:31,920 --> 00:06:35,480
Then what other company
will you go to now?

94
00:06:36,000 --> 00:06:37,840
- Look here, Miss
- Min-ah!

95
00:06:38,080 --> 00:06:39,680
Your house is on fire!

96
00:06:42,920 --> 00:06:45,000
Ma'am

97
00:06:47,200 --> 00:06:48,680
We have a reason

98
00:06:48,680 --> 00:06:49,880
for setting 12 dates

99
00:06:50,000 --> 00:06:51,080
for our clients

100
00:06:52,560 --> 00:06:54,280
Can't you think of
those dates

101
00:06:54,440 --> 00:06:56,600
as helping him with
his karma?

102
00:06:57,360 --> 00:06:58,280
They say even a monk

103
00:06:58,440 --> 00:07:00,440
Without karma can't
be helped by Buddha

104
00:07:00,600 --> 00:07:02,920
- Hello? Mom?
- Are you Buddhist?

105
00:07:03,120 --> 00:07:04,880
Now I have someone
I can talk to

106
00:07:09,240 --> 00:07:10,760
Call that working?

107
00:07:11,000 --> 00:07:13,080
Then I'll see you later, sir

108
00:07:13,360 --> 00:07:14,920
Is she trying to set a date

109
00:07:15,120 --> 00:07:16,680
Or find one herself?

110
00:07:17,440 --> 00:07:18,640
Look at Hyo-jin

111
00:07:18,760 --> 00:07:21,760
Her guy has a PhD at KAIST
a nice family, and handsome

112
00:07:22,680 --> 00:07:24,000
Learn from her

113
00:07:25,560 --> 00:07:27,080
He looks slimy, huh?

114
00:07:27,520 --> 00:07:28,120
Pardon?

115
00:07:28,360 --> 00:07:29,480
Park Hyun-soo

116
00:07:29,800 --> 00:07:32,520
I thought I handed
all his files over to you

117
00:07:32,800 --> 00:07:35,320
He'll probably be late
or won't show up again

118
00:07:35,600 --> 00:07:37,120
Good luck, Hyo-jin

119
00:07:37,400 --> 00:07:39,440
It's out of my hands now

120
00:07:57,400 --> 00:07:58,680
Park Hyun-soo

121
00:07:59,680 --> 00:08:03,560
You have four dates left
so finish them in a month

122
00:08:03,760 --> 00:08:06,360
If you show up late
or not at all again

123
00:08:06,600 --> 00:08:08,280
I'm going to
you personally

124
00:08:09,080 --> 00:08:12,600
Don't forget about
your date at six tonight

125
00:08:14,480 --> 00:08:16,840
You're scary Hyo-jin

126
00:08:17,160 --> 00:08:18,560
So what did he say?

127
00:08:18,960 --> 00:08:20,920
He didn't answer
so I left a message

128
00:09:43,520 --> 00:09:44,600
Hello?

129
00:09:45,400 --> 00:09:48,200
Have you forgotten about
your date tonight?

130
00:09:48,560 --> 00:09:50,280
Where are you now?

131
00:09:57,200 --> 00:09:58,440
Are you alright?

132
00:10:00,960 --> 00:10:02,800
Park Hyun-soo
by any chance?

133
00:10:13,800 --> 00:10:14,760
Sir...

134
00:10:15,400 --> 00:10:17,920
you're supposed
to arrive on time

135
00:10:18,040 --> 00:10:19,040
and...

136
00:10:21,520 --> 00:10:23,800
Next time watch
how you dress

137
00:10:24,000 --> 00:10:26,960
Being well-dressed
for a date is polite

138
00:10:27,280 --> 00:10:29,240
Please hurry to your table

139
00:10:29,440 --> 00:10:31,040
I'll be going now

140
00:10:36,880 --> 00:10:38,200
Wait

141
00:10:46,000 --> 00:10:47,440
You have a long tail

142
00:10:59,520 --> 00:11:00,480
Bye

143
00:11:10,480 --> 00:11:12,000
- Wait
- Here you go

144
00:11:38,800 --> 00:11:40,240
What?

145
00:11:45,160 --> 00:11:46,120
Excuse me!

146
00:11:46,520 --> 00:11:48,480
Wait!

147
00:11:53,120 --> 00:11:57,360
You can't end
it this fast

148
00:12:00,400 --> 00:12:05,080
Did you ask to
see her again?

149
00:12:06,000 --> 00:12:07,840
Oh, right

150
00:12:09,680 --> 00:12:12,680
What was her number again?

151
00:12:21,480 --> 00:12:23,240
Hello?

152
00:12:24,360 --> 00:12:26,520
Hi, one sec

153
00:12:27,760 --> 00:12:30,440
What was her name again?

154
00:12:44,280 --> 00:12:45,680
Park Hyun-soo

155
00:12:45,880 --> 00:12:48,000
You have three dates left

156
00:12:48,320 --> 00:12:50,200
You said nice girls
are your type

157
00:12:50,400 --> 00:12:52,400
So what type is that?

158
00:12:55,440 --> 00:12:56,560
Park Hyun-soo

159
00:12:58,000 --> 00:12:59,200
Yes?

160
00:12:59,440 --> 00:13:00,760
What did I say?

161
00:13:01,800 --> 00:13:03,320
Oh right

162
00:13:04,480 --> 00:13:08,720
The nice type of girl
my mom likes, I think

163
00:13:16,560 --> 00:13:19,520
Anyway
how could you drink so slow?

164
00:13:52,920 --> 00:13:55,360
- Are you okay?
- Of course

165
00:13:59,920 --> 00:14:04,400
Try this and it'll work

166
00:14:09,720 --> 00:14:12,280
That's okay
it happens to me, too

167
00:14:15,200 --> 00:14:16,680
- I see
- But

168
00:14:16,840 --> 00:14:18,880
Your eyes

169
00:14:21,280 --> 00:14:23,680
I'm okay
it doesn't hurt

170
00:14:23,920 --> 00:14:25,320
No, your eyebrows

171
00:14:26,600 --> 00:14:28,160
No boyfriend, right?

172
00:14:29,480 --> 00:14:31,360
You seem like you don't

173
00:14:33,960 --> 00:14:36,760
No, I have a boyfriend

174
00:14:36,760 --> 00:14:38,760
Wanna see his picture?

175
00:14:41,400 --> 00:14:42,800
Hello?

176
00:14:43,440 --> 00:14:45,800
Yes, I'll be going in soon

177
00:14:46,000 --> 00:14:47,040
Bye

178
00:14:49,480 --> 00:14:51,160
And your name is

179
00:14:53,040 --> 00:14:53,800
Kim

180
00:14:53,800 --> 00:14:55,720
Hyo-jin, Kim Hyo-jin

181
00:14:55,880 --> 00:14:58,240
Right, Kim Hyo-jin

182
00:14:58,360 --> 00:15:00,160
So it was
Kim Hyo-jin

183
00:15:00,720 --> 00:15:04,120
Sorry, I can't remember things
I don't care about

184
00:15:09,360 --> 00:15:11,760
Hello?
where are you?

185
00:15:13,640 --> 00:15:17,640
Don't you have a nice guy
out of your clients?

186
00:15:17,920 --> 00:15:19,400
Don't disgrace my job

187
00:15:19,880 --> 00:15:22,120
I don't look at
my clients as men

188
00:15:22,240 --> 00:15:23,640
That's the ethics of my job

189
00:15:24,520 --> 00:15:27,000
Kim Hyo-jin is number one!

190
00:15:27,960 --> 00:15:29,160
Don't give me that
job ethics crap

191
00:15:29,200 --> 00:15:30,440
Just hurry

192
00:15:30,720 --> 00:15:33,320
And grab a nice guy
if there is one

193
00:15:33,480 --> 00:15:36,000
You only get to see
your man once a week

194
00:15:36,240 --> 00:15:38,520
He's not good for you

195
00:15:38,680 --> 00:15:41,160
A week is enough
and I like it that way

196
00:15:41,520 --> 00:15:45,480
What a career woman
we have here

197
00:15:45,680 --> 00:15:48,640
Then take care of him at least

198
00:15:49,040 --> 00:15:50,480
And listen to me carefully

199
00:15:50,920 --> 00:15:54,560
If people our age don't have
someone something's wrong

200
00:15:54,720 --> 00:15:56,600
You know
like if they're really ugly

201
00:15:56,840 --> 00:16:00,440
Or if something's really wrong
with their personality

202
00:16:00,920 --> 00:16:02,120
You bastard

203
00:16:02,640 --> 00:16:05,320
Anyway
are my eyebrows strange?

204
00:16:06,160 --> 00:16:07,600
Come to think of it
they are

205
00:16:07,760 --> 00:16:09,360
How come
they look like that?

206
00:16:09,600 --> 00:16:11,280
They look like
singles' eyebrows

207
00:16:12,640 --> 00:16:14,040
Really?

208
00:16:14,400 --> 00:16:15,600
Let's drink

209
00:16:15,800 --> 00:16:18,440
Anyway, this bowl is
really cute, huh?

210
00:16:35,120 --> 00:16:37,440
Look at you

211
00:16:37,680 --> 00:16:39,880
Envious?
Want the same?

212
00:16:40,120 --> 00:16:41,200
You're crazy

213
00:16:41,360 --> 00:16:43,920
Hyo-jin, come here

214
00:16:43,920 --> 00:16:45,960
Can a man and
woman be friends?

215
00:16:46,160 --> 00:16:48,080
That's nonsense

216
00:16:48,240 --> 00:16:49,800
It's impossible

217
00:16:50,080 --> 00:16:52,400
- But possible for us
- All thanks to you

218
00:16:53,240 --> 00:16:54,480
- Grateful, huh?
- Of course

219
00:16:54,760 --> 00:16:55,680
Very grateful

220
00:16:55,840 --> 00:16:57,000
Since you're not sexy

221
00:16:57,200 --> 00:16:58,400
We've been able to

222
00:16:58,400 --> 00:17:01,480
keep our frail friendship
for 20 years

223
00:17:05,400 --> 00:17:09,240
You picked on me ever
since primary school

224
00:17:09,600 --> 00:17:12,200
- Come here
- Look over there

225
00:17:37,120 --> 00:17:38,440
Gotcha! What in the heck?

226
00:17:38,680 --> 00:17:40,360
Look at your face

227
00:17:40,680 --> 00:17:43,720
People will think
you're an abused wife

228
00:17:43,880 --> 00:17:44,800
Don't worry

229
00:17:45,040 --> 00:17:46,520
I can cover it with my hair

230
00:17:46,960 --> 00:17:49,000
Hyo-jin, sure you'll be okay?

231
00:17:49,120 --> 00:17:52,920
Remember I said I'll marry
you if you don't by thirty

232
00:17:53,160 --> 00:17:54,360
So what now?

233
00:17:55,120 --> 00:17:55,720
Forget it!

234
00:17:55,880 --> 00:17:57,560
I won't marry
you if I'm single at sixty

235
00:17:57,680 --> 00:17:58,600
See you later!

236
00:17:58,920 --> 00:18:01,480
Hey, Hyo-jin wait

237
00:18:03,760 --> 00:18:04,800
Here

238
00:18:06,280 --> 00:18:09,120
Nice job!

239
00:18:09,400 --> 00:18:10,760
Wait

240
00:18:14,640 --> 00:18:15,560
Hello?

241
00:18:16,000 --> 00:18:16,680
Yeah

242
00:18:17,360 --> 00:18:20,360
What?
The air gun?

243
00:18:20,800 --> 00:18:22,680
Hello?
Hello?

244
00:18:23,120 --> 00:18:24,720
I got hung up on

245
00:18:25,200 --> 00:18:26,280
What's with the air gun?

246
00:18:26,520 --> 00:18:28,080
Who was it?
your man?

247
00:18:28,400 --> 00:18:30,320
No, it's Hae-in
and she was balling

248
00:18:30,880 --> 00:18:31,920
Why'd she want the air gun?

249
00:18:32,720 --> 00:18:34,400
Hey!

250
00:18:34,520 --> 00:18:38,040
It's past your bedtime
so where are you going now?

251
00:18:38,480 --> 00:18:39,360
Look at you

252
00:18:39,600 --> 00:18:41,400
Hey, I'm gonna tell your parents

253
00:18:41,600 --> 00:18:43,720
that you're running wild
with your dad's air gun!

254
00:19:01,680 --> 00:19:03,080
I'm gonna kill you

255
00:19:13,040 --> 00:19:14,240
Before you take action

256
00:19:14,240 --> 00:19:15,880
don't you need a drink first?

257
00:19:16,080 --> 00:19:17,080
How about karaoke?

258
00:19:17,160 --> 00:19:18,160
If you sing and drink

259
00:19:18,360 --> 00:19:20,240
You'll muster up
more courage

260
00:19:21,880 --> 00:19:22,840
Think so?

261
00:19:48,080 --> 00:19:49,040
Hae-in

262
00:19:49,920 --> 00:19:51,480
That's enough

263
00:19:52,080 --> 00:19:53,200
It's already the 27th time

264
00:19:53,320 --> 00:19:54,280
Bastard

265
00:19:54,480 --> 00:19:55,480
Rotten bastard

266
00:19:55,960 --> 00:19:56,840
Son of a bitch

267
00:19:57,880 --> 00:20:02,320
How could you betray me
for a one-month fling

268
00:20:02,640 --> 00:20:06,600
after we went out
for seven years?

269
00:20:16,720 --> 00:20:17,640
Hyo-jin

270
00:20:18,040 --> 00:20:20,280
In that movie Fanny Pink

271
00:20:20,600 --> 00:20:24,520
The odds are greater
for a woman over thirty

272
00:20:24,800 --> 00:20:25,720
To get hit

273
00:20:25,720 --> 00:20:30,200
by an atomic bomb
than to find a nice man

274
00:20:30,480 --> 00:20:32,480
You believe that?

275
00:20:33,400 --> 00:20:38,000
- One of our clients
- Be quiet, and listen to me!

276
00:20:38,960 --> 00:20:39,960
They're right

277
00:20:40,360 --> 00:20:41,720
Know why?

278
00:20:43,360 --> 00:20:44,760
Because...

279
00:20:45,360 --> 00:20:50,760
there isn't a nice guy
in this world

280
00:20:54,520 --> 00:20:57,960
Hyo-jin
how many bullets are there?

281
00:20:58,600 --> 00:20:59,880
One bullet maybe?

282
00:21:00,360 --> 00:21:01,760
One isn't enough

283
00:21:02,200 --> 00:21:04,320
That bastard has two hearts

284
00:21:04,400 --> 00:21:08,080
If not, then how could
he love two women?

285
00:21:31,080 --> 00:21:32,360
The sun's up

286
00:21:32,800 --> 00:21:34,240
Revenge or not
I'm sick of it

287
00:21:34,640 --> 00:21:36,480
Just tell him
to get married

288
00:21:58,240 --> 00:22:00,920
Are my eyebrows weird?

289
00:22:04,240 --> 00:22:06,120
Now that
you mention it, yes

290
00:22:06,120 --> 00:22:07,280
Gross

291
00:22:07,440 --> 00:22:09,480
They look like
singles' eyebrows

292
00:22:11,840 --> 00:22:13,280
Should I slash my wrists?

293
00:22:13,920 --> 00:22:15,000
Hae-in!

294
00:22:15,920 --> 00:22:16,880
What?

295
00:22:20,080 --> 00:22:22,120
Here's a present

296
00:22:22,320 --> 00:22:24,800
If you feel lonely or sad
use this tambourine

297
00:22:25,080 --> 00:22:27,080
And don't worry

298
00:22:27,280 --> 00:22:29,120
I'll introduce you
to a good guy

299
00:22:30,160 --> 00:22:32,200
Here

300
00:23:04,400 --> 00:23:05,360
Oh, I'm sorry

301
00:23:06,480 --> 00:23:07,440
Oh, I'm sorry

302
00:23:08,080 --> 00:23:09,080
What the hell?

303
00:23:39,120 --> 00:23:40,480
Hello

304
00:24:17,520 --> 00:24:18,880
One sec

305
00:24:19,800 --> 00:24:21,640
Have an eyebrow trimmer
by any chance?

306
00:24:21,840 --> 00:24:22,920
Trimmer?

307
00:24:24,160 --> 00:24:25,360
Here

308
00:24:33,040 --> 00:24:34,080
What?

309
00:24:34,360 --> 00:24:36,840
They look like singles' eyebrows?

310
00:24:37,360 --> 00:24:39,640
You're telepathic

311
00:24:58,240 --> 00:25:00,000
Hello

312
00:25:00,680 --> 00:25:01,560
Excuse me

313
00:25:04,680 --> 00:25:06,120
Lee Kang-hyun speaking

314
00:25:06,760 --> 00:25:08,760
Hello, sir
Yes

315
00:25:25,040 --> 00:25:26,240
Hello

316
00:25:26,720 --> 00:25:27,760
Hi

317
00:25:28,040 --> 00:25:31,200
Didn't forget
about tonight, right?

318
00:25:38,520 --> 00:25:39,680
Happy birthday!

319
00:25:41,760 --> 00:25:42,680
What is it?

320
00:25:42,800 --> 00:25:45,360
I'm less older by
the lunar calendar

321
00:25:45,360 --> 00:25:46,880
Who cares?
Just do it!

322
00:25:48,400 --> 00:25:50,440
By the lunar calendar!

323
00:25:51,880 --> 00:25:53,480
Okay!

324
00:25:56,200 --> 00:25:58,360
Hyo-jin, not meeting
your boyfriend today?

325
00:25:58,600 --> 00:26:00,560
He has a lot of work to do

326
00:26:00,640 --> 00:26:02,960
So he's coming over late

327
00:26:03,240 --> 00:26:04,840
You're lucky to have
a guy like him

328
00:26:05,120 --> 00:26:08,400
Who comes all the way
to Seoul every weekend

329
00:26:08,680 --> 00:26:11,640
But they say
people look worse in person

330
00:26:11,800 --> 00:26:13,160
So what are you gonna do?

331
00:26:14,200 --> 00:26:15,880
Gonna see a midnight movie?

332
00:26:17,640 --> 00:26:18,480
Perhaps

333
00:26:18,600 --> 00:26:21,720
Hyo-jin, you'll be
the first to get married

334
00:26:22,920 --> 00:26:26,800
Actually, I have something
to tell you all

335
00:26:30,000 --> 00:26:32,520
That you're getting married?

336
00:26:32,640 --> 00:26:33,680
I'm right, huh?

337
00:26:34,160 --> 00:26:39,240
Don't say that
it's my birthday today!

338
00:26:39,280 --> 00:26:43,400
I hate hearing
that the most!

339
00:26:56,240 --> 00:26:58,080
You guys have
misunderstood me

340
00:26:59,800 --> 00:27:02,120
I'm not getting married

341
00:27:02,560 --> 00:27:05,520
Because I hate dealing
with family customs

342
00:27:06,720 --> 00:27:08,720
In other words
marriage is business

343
00:27:08,880 --> 00:27:12,520
No one has married
because of real love

344
00:27:12,880 --> 00:27:16,600
A woman who doesn't want
to marry is selfish

345
00:27:16,720 --> 00:27:18,840
A guy who doesn't is a playboy

346
00:27:18,960 --> 00:27:20,960
That's society's prejudices

347
00:27:21,200 --> 00:27:22,960
If we get involved

348
00:27:45,840 --> 00:27:50,040
The number you have dialed
is no longer in service

349
00:27:50,160 --> 00:27:53,000
Please check the number
and try again

350
00:29:12,480 --> 00:29:13,560
Thanks for lunch

351
00:29:13,680 --> 00:29:14,640
Me, too

352
00:29:14,880 --> 00:29:17,960
I'll treat you all to
a great lunch one day

353
00:29:18,920 --> 00:29:19,680
Always promises

354
00:29:19,840 --> 00:29:20,880
I'm sick of it

355
00:29:21,840 --> 00:29:24,040
I'm serious
it'll be my treat

356
00:29:25,760 --> 00:29:27,960
Kim Hyo-in
your eyebrows look better

357
00:29:30,000 --> 00:29:31,600
Who is she?

358
00:29:31,920 --> 00:29:34,880
Isn't he that troublemaker
Park Hyun-soo?

359
00:29:35,120 --> 00:29:35,960
Are you serious?

360
00:29:36,080 --> 00:29:38,440
- Who is she?
- Know her?

361
00:29:38,640 --> 00:29:39,800
Girl friend?

362
00:29:39,920 --> 00:29:42,160
He looks
much better in person

363
00:29:43,000 --> 00:29:44,680
Oh my goodness

364
00:29:44,840 --> 00:29:47,200
Anyway
who's Kim Hyo-in?

365
00:29:47,600 --> 00:29:50,600
You're right
who's Kim Hyo-in?

366
00:29:52,880 --> 00:29:54,840
I told you
it was Kim Hyo-jin

367
00:29:57,520 --> 00:30:00,320
I know! I know!

368
00:30:00,480 --> 00:30:02,360
Relax, relax

369
00:30:02,360 --> 00:30:04,840
Breathe

370
00:30:07,400 --> 00:30:09,600
The phone, phone

371
00:30:10,960 --> 00:30:13,160
- I told you to eat one serving!
- 911! 911!

372
00:30:13,880 --> 00:30:14,760
119! 119!

373
00:30:15,920 --> 00:30:18,280
Oh my god!

374
00:30:22,400 --> 00:30:24,320
Have a nice day

375
00:30:34,280 --> 00:30:35,360
Hello

376
00:30:35,800 --> 00:30:38,120
My name is Kim Hyo-jin

377
00:30:38,920 --> 00:30:40,520
Lee Kang-hyun speaking

378
00:30:41,840 --> 00:30:43,400
The revisions are done

379
00:30:43,600 --> 00:30:44,960
So tell them to
confirm quickly

380
00:30:48,080 --> 00:30:50,040
Sorry
it's a call from work

381
00:30:51,240 --> 00:30:53,200
Find it next to the file

382
00:30:54,480 --> 00:30:55,600
Can't find it?

383
00:30:57,200 --> 00:30:58,800
Where are you?

384
00:31:04,800 --> 00:31:05,840
What?

385
00:31:06,000 --> 00:31:07,760
The code seems
to be changed?

386
00:31:08,480 --> 00:31:11,320
The team leader was
supposed to do it

387
00:31:19,200 --> 00:31:20,560
He's really awesome

388
00:31:20,880 --> 00:31:22,800
He was the hunk of
our club in college

389
00:31:23,480 --> 00:31:25,440
Any man
who doesn't betray is fine

390
00:31:26,160 --> 00:31:27,600
But is it okay
for me to do this?

391
00:31:27,920 --> 00:31:30,160
It's only been seven days
since I broke up

392
00:31:30,360 --> 00:31:31,160
They say it
takes three times

393
00:31:31,160 --> 00:31:33,280
as long to forget everything

394
00:31:33,400 --> 00:31:34,200
What are you talking about?

395
00:31:34,400 --> 00:31:37,280
You dated him for 7 years
so you'll wait 21 years?

396
00:31:37,440 --> 00:31:39,400
Hurry so you can
have your revenge

397
00:31:40,160 --> 00:31:41,640
He's a man of few words

398
00:31:41,840 --> 00:31:43,080
handsome

399
00:31:43,280 --> 00:31:44,960
and well-versed

400
00:31:45,960 --> 00:31:47,080
Height?

401
00:31:49,840 --> 00:31:51,520
Sorak Mountain

402
00:31:52,440 --> 00:31:55,360
There was a heavy
rainfall warning

403
00:31:56,720 --> 00:31:58,720
Those great members

404
00:31:59,280 --> 00:32:01,520
Hyo-jin, you remember

405
00:32:01,680 --> 00:32:02,960
Yang-soo and
Yong-suk, right?

406
00:32:03,440 --> 00:32:05,560
Yong-suk is
at Samsung SDS now

407
00:32:05,720 --> 00:32:09,160
Yang-soo got married
and immigrated to Canada

408
00:32:09,480 --> 00:32:12,200
As I expected
that great guy

409
00:32:12,600 --> 00:32:13,920
Was as I expected

410
00:32:14,880 --> 00:32:15,840
Anyway...

411
00:32:16,160 --> 00:32:19,760
Anyway, we climbed up the mountain
with all that we had

412
00:32:19,920 --> 00:32:24,160
Then dark clouds with thunder
and rain suddenly appeared

413
00:32:24,320 --> 00:32:27,080
But we couldn't
give up halfway

414
00:32:27,280 --> 00:32:31,080
So we gave it all...
(I thought he was handsome)

415
00:32:31,240 --> 00:32:33,320
We got to reach the top

416
00:32:33,440 --> 00:32:39,400
So we finally reached the peak
(Long time ago... )

417
00:32:40,680 --> 00:32:42,120
The peak!

418
00:32:43,960 --> 00:32:45,320
That's funny

419
00:32:45,520 --> 00:32:47,800
Wow, I didn't know you liked
mountains so much
(A man of few words?)

420
00:32:48,040 --> 00:32:49,440
That's right, you like to travel

421
00:32:49,560 --> 00:32:53,320
You should ask a favor from Hae-in
(Long time ago)

422
00:32:53,520 --> 00:32:55,840
If you take a trip
come to my office

423
00:32:56,080 --> 00:32:57,680
We have lots of discounts

424
00:32:57,840 --> 00:32:58,880
I will

425
00:32:59,200 --> 00:33:00,840
Thank you

426
00:33:01,320 --> 00:33:02,560
Then

427
00:33:04,240 --> 00:33:09,000
We listened to what
we cherished for ten years

428
00:33:09,320 --> 00:33:10,760
Ozzy Osborne's

429
00:33:11,120 --> 00:33:13,400
Good-bye to Romance

430
00:33:14,000 --> 00:33:16,360
Good-bye to Romance

431
00:33:17,080 --> 00:33:18,600
Ozzy Osborne

432
00:33:18,960 --> 00:33:21,560
He really is a man of few words
ruled the world at one point
(You're well-informed)

433
00:33:21,880 --> 00:33:23,720
The band was powerful

434
00:33:23,880 --> 00:33:25,720
without the use of effects

435
00:33:27,400 --> 00:33:28,520
Stage performance?

436
00:33:29,160 --> 00:33:30,680
It was awesome

437
00:33:32,040 --> 00:33:35,720
He cracked a chicken's neck
and the blood

438
00:33:39,600 --> 00:33:41,640
Marilyn Manson
can't compare

439
00:33:41,840 --> 00:33:44,360
They need to retire!

440
00:33:45,200 --> 00:33:46,280
Hae-in

441
00:33:46,440 --> 00:33:48,120
You probably know already

442
00:33:48,640 --> 00:33:50,360
Aren't we the rock generation?

443
00:33:50,760 --> 00:33:53,240
A rock artist's dictionary
was our bible

444
00:33:53,480 --> 00:33:55,280
When I memorized a page

445
00:33:55,440 --> 00:33:57,120
I ate it raw

446
00:33:57,360 --> 00:34:00,920
Back then
I ate a lot of paper

447
00:34:01,160 --> 00:34:03,720
I was a walking
rock dictionary

448
00:34:06,960 --> 00:34:07,880
Hae-in

449
00:34:08,640 --> 00:34:10,880
Wanna memorize it

450
00:34:11,360 --> 00:34:12,880
starting from A?

451
00:34:14,680 --> 00:34:18,800
Air Supply, ABBA
ACDC, Aerosmith

452
00:34:19,080 --> 00:34:20,600
Alan Parsons Project
Bad Company

453
00:34:20,880 --> 00:34:22,600
Black Sabbath
Beatles, Chicago

454
00:34:22,880 --> 00:34:24,680
Deep Purple, Pink Floyd

455
00:34:28,680 --> 00:34:31,680
How come you
look down lately?

456
00:34:31,920 --> 00:34:33,880
Sad that I'm getting
married in two days?

457
00:34:34,760 --> 00:34:35,760
Don't make me talk

458
00:34:35,840 --> 00:34:37,520
I'm about to fall apart

459
00:34:39,160 --> 00:34:40,520
Hyo-jin

460
00:34:40,880 --> 00:34:43,120
You're upset that
I'm marrying

461
00:34:43,280 --> 00:34:45,320
on your birthday, huh?

462
00:34:45,720 --> 00:34:47,680
Right? Right?

463
00:34:47,920 --> 00:34:49,360
Stop it!

464
00:34:49,640 --> 00:34:51,520
I'm already upset that
nothing's going right

465
00:34:51,640 --> 00:34:53,400
My leg's gonna rip

466
00:34:53,640 --> 00:34:55,480
Joon-ah
can I ask you something?

467
00:34:55,920 --> 00:34:58,280
This guy can't remember
this girl's name

468
00:34:58,360 --> 00:35:00,680
It's not once
but after seeing her twice

469
00:35:00,840 --> 00:35:02,480
So what kind of
person is he?

470
00:35:02,880 --> 00:35:04,160
Simply...

471
00:35:04,240 --> 00:35:05,760
that he's not
interested at all

472
00:35:06,200 --> 00:35:07,680
So what's he like?

473
00:35:08,200 --> 00:35:11,520
No, it's not me

474
00:35:12,280 --> 00:35:15,120
One of my clients keep
forgetting a girl's name

475
00:35:15,560 --> 00:35:17,400
I better introduce him
to someone else

476
00:35:26,160 --> 00:35:29,320
Lively like Meg Ryan
dignified like Annette Benning

477
00:35:29,520 --> 00:35:32,120
and unpredictable
like Nicole Kidman

478
00:35:32,280 --> 00:35:33,440
That's my type

479
00:35:36,280 --> 00:35:39,600
If possible
I'd really like a younger guy

480
00:35:39,720 --> 00:35:43,760
Guys around my age
are too worn out

481
00:35:44,000 --> 00:35:44,800
You should know

482
00:35:44,920 --> 00:35:48,120
Also, never a guy with
a B blood type

483
00:35:48,400 --> 00:35:51,680
I've been through
too many of those

484
00:35:55,280 --> 00:35:59,840
Mom, which type of girl
did you oppose?

485
00:36:04,560 --> 00:36:08,120
No girls whose last name
starts with vowels

486
00:36:08,320 --> 00:36:10,240
Mom, when are you gonna
pick me up?

487
00:36:24,480 --> 00:36:28,120
All creation is made of
Ying and Yang

488
00:36:28,320 --> 00:36:30,400
Everything has both attributes

489
00:36:31,280 --> 00:36:33,320
You need a Ying to
have a Yang

490
00:36:33,520 --> 00:36:36,680
And you need a Yang to
complement a Ying

491
00:36:38,160 --> 00:36:40,960
But since I went through
Chi training for a long time

492
00:36:41,480 --> 00:36:43,760
I'm filled with Ying

493
00:36:45,680 --> 00:36:47,720
So I need Yang's energy to
balance my Chi

494
00:36:48,200 --> 00:36:50,560
And to train more

495
00:36:52,400 --> 00:36:54,080
I don't care about
anything else

496
00:36:54,640 --> 00:36:55,760
I just...

497
00:36:56,920 --> 00:37:01,400
Need a man who can train
with me together

498
00:37:09,080 --> 00:37:10,480
A woman cop

499
00:37:11,440 --> 00:37:13,480
Who sees things long term

500
00:37:13,880 --> 00:37:16,720
Kids these days are impolite

501
00:37:17,360 --> 00:37:19,080
But a mother cop

502
00:37:19,640 --> 00:37:21,120
never compromises

503
00:37:22,000 --> 00:37:23,040
Okay?

504
00:37:27,720 --> 00:37:29,000
A nice girl

505
00:37:33,520 --> 00:37:35,280
A for personality

506
00:37:35,480 --> 00:37:37,040
A for family background

507
00:37:37,160 --> 00:37:38,920
A for assets

508
00:37:39,160 --> 00:37:41,160
A+ for looks

509
00:37:41,400 --> 00:37:44,120
Total score, 95

510
00:37:45,320 --> 00:37:46,400
It's down again

511
00:37:46,480 --> 00:37:47,480
I knew this would happen

512
00:37:47,720 --> 00:37:49,000
Computer giving you
trouble, too?

513
00:37:51,400 --> 00:37:56,160
So how are your
meetings lately?

514
00:37:57,080 --> 00:37:59,840
As a matter of fact
I even have one today

515
00:38:00,080 --> 00:38:02,120
It's probably
too much for you

516
00:38:02,400 --> 00:38:04,200
If so, then tell me

517
00:38:04,360 --> 00:38:06,200
He was my client anyway

518
00:38:06,400 --> 00:38:07,560
I should take care of him

519
00:38:07,920 --> 00:38:09,160
Don't you agree?

520
00:38:20,680 --> 00:38:23,720
- Darn, I missed it again
- I'm sorry

521
00:38:23,840 --> 00:38:25,400
Is that you, Hyo-jin?

522
00:38:25,680 --> 00:38:26,720
Oh, hello

523
00:38:26,920 --> 00:38:28,400
How long has it been?

524
00:38:28,600 --> 00:38:29,480
Good to see you

525
00:38:29,680 --> 00:38:31,400
You've gotten very pretty

526
00:38:31,600 --> 00:38:32,960
What a coincidence

527
00:38:33,200 --> 00:38:35,080
Oh yeah, my card

528
00:38:35,440 --> 00:38:37,520
I think I've run out

529
00:38:38,000 --> 00:38:39,680
Do you work near here?

530
00:38:39,880 --> 00:38:41,600
Yes, at this marriage
service company

531
00:38:43,280 --> 00:38:44,720
You're a couples manager?

532
00:38:45,680 --> 00:38:48,240
I'll have a card somewhere

533
00:38:48,480 --> 00:38:49,760
My card is

534
00:38:50,040 --> 00:38:52,560
Wow, you're
a couples manager

535
00:38:52,800 --> 00:38:53,880
Where is...

536
00:38:54,080 --> 00:38:56,280
Why don't I have one
when I need it

537
00:38:59,400 --> 00:39:00,360
It's my card

538
00:39:00,520 --> 00:39:03,440
Call me later
I need to marry soon

539
00:39:03,440 --> 00:39:04,920
It's green Call me

540
00:39:05,120 --> 00:39:06,160
- Bye
- Good-Bye

541
00:39:06,320 --> 00:39:08,280
Call me for sure!

542
00:39:18,360 --> 00:39:19,480
Hello?

543
00:39:21,080 --> 00:39:26,560
What was her name again?

544
00:39:27,560 --> 00:39:29,360
Mr Park, next time...

545
00:39:29,520 --> 00:39:32,360
insert her name and
number in your phone

546
00:39:32,560 --> 00:39:35,440
And when you're done
you can check your phone

547
00:39:44,720 --> 00:39:46,560
If people eat
something sweet

548
00:39:47,560 --> 00:39:48,960
they feel better

549
00:39:56,360 --> 00:39:57,640
Eating sweet potato
cake with milk tea

550
00:39:57,680 --> 00:39:59,200
is delicious

551
00:40:02,400 --> 00:40:06,520
Which side is
the window to you?

552
00:40:09,320 --> 00:40:10,640
To my right

553
00:40:11,600 --> 00:40:13,120
It's my left for me

554
00:40:16,800 --> 00:40:18,240
So then?

555
00:40:26,640 --> 00:40:29,000
Check the memory
and trace it directly

556
00:40:29,280 --> 00:40:31,080
I'll go in and
check it quickly

557
00:40:31,800 --> 00:40:33,040
Okay

558
00:40:38,800 --> 00:40:40,040
Over here

559
00:40:43,640 --> 00:40:44,880
What are you doing there?

560
00:40:56,680 --> 00:40:57,880
Are you okay?

561
00:41:03,640 --> 00:41:05,360
Wipe it off with this

562
00:41:08,760 --> 00:41:10,480
- You have some here, too
- Here?

563
00:41:11,000 --> 00:41:12,000
A little more

564
00:41:16,480 --> 00:41:17,560
- There
- There

565
00:41:20,080 --> 00:41:21,160
You go first

566
00:41:22,160 --> 00:41:24,960
You shouldn't walk
ahead of people

567
00:41:25,120 --> 00:41:28,440
You should match
a woman's pace

568
00:41:29,360 --> 00:41:31,000
I'll give it a try

569
00:41:32,400 --> 00:41:34,000
So what were you
going to say?

570
00:41:35,880 --> 00:41:36,200
Oh right

571
00:41:36,320 --> 00:41:37,640
Well...

572
00:41:39,160 --> 00:41:41,120
What are you doing tomorrow?

573
00:41:42,160 --> 00:41:43,320
Tomorrow?

574
00:41:43,920 --> 00:41:44,400
yes

575
00:41:46,000 --> 00:41:47,720
My friend's wedding
is tomorrow

576
00:41:52,160 --> 00:41:53,680
You said you have
a boyfriend, right?

577
00:41:54,240 --> 00:41:55,400
Then you'll probably
go with him

578
00:41:55,920 --> 00:41:56,840
Pardon?

579
00:41:58,320 --> 00:41:59,440
Oh right

580
00:42:01,960 --> 00:42:03,840
To be honest

581
00:42:06,200 --> 00:42:07,400
One sec

582
00:42:09,880 --> 00:42:10,680
Hello?

583
00:42:11,960 --> 00:42:13,680
Hyo-jin! Hyo-jin!

584
00:42:14,240 --> 00:42:15,240
Hyo-jin!

585
00:42:20,560 --> 00:42:23,920
Come here, my buddy

586
00:42:25,360 --> 00:42:26,440
My buddy

587
00:42:26,840 --> 00:42:28,520
Hyo-jin, come here

588
00:42:30,360 --> 00:42:31,560
Come here

589
00:42:31,880 --> 00:42:33,280
Hyo-jin
what do you want?

590
00:42:34,120 --> 00:42:35,040
Just tell me

591
00:42:35,200 --> 00:42:36,960
I'll steal
everything for you

592
00:42:37,520 --> 00:42:39,480
This?

593
00:42:43,320 --> 00:42:47,080
Or do you want this?

594
00:42:49,200 --> 00:42:50,280
No?

595
00:42:53,320 --> 00:42:54,440
Damn it!

596
00:42:55,640 --> 00:42:57,320
Who put this here?

597
00:43:02,120 --> 00:43:05,000
I've been drinking

598
00:43:05,960 --> 00:43:07,280
Why?

599
00:43:07,760 --> 00:43:11,880
Because I feel great!

600
00:43:12,960 --> 00:43:14,040
Lady!

601
00:43:15,000 --> 00:43:16,840
Lady, you're so pretty!

602
00:43:17,280 --> 00:43:18,960
Where are your manners?

603
00:43:18,960 --> 00:43:20,000
Okay, okay

604
00:43:20,200 --> 00:43:21,040
But Lady

605
00:43:21,520 --> 00:43:25,840
When tomorrow comes
there's one less bachelor

606
00:43:26,480 --> 00:43:32,960
You're looking at
him right here!

607
00:43:36,840 --> 00:43:37,760
Hyo-jin!

608
00:43:38,080 --> 00:43:40,320
Hyo-jin
get your butt over here

609
00:43:46,000 --> 00:43:47,520
Hyo-jin
I can't get married

610
00:43:48,880 --> 00:43:49,640
Because...

611
00:43:50,840 --> 00:43:53,840
What's so great
about her daughter?

612
00:43:54,800 --> 00:43:58,480
My future son-in-law

613
00:43:59,440 --> 00:44:02,440
I mean mother-in-law

614
00:44:02,920 --> 00:44:10,800
She thinks
I'm no better than a dog

615
00:44:11,200 --> 00:44:13,080
Yeah, I'm a loser with no job

616
00:44:13,800 --> 00:44:15,600
But isn't
she being too harsh?

617
00:44:16,680 --> 00:44:20,800
Hyo-jin
I never told you, huh?

618
00:44:21,600 --> 00:44:24,960
That lady is fat as hell

619
00:44:25,160 --> 00:44:28,320
She's a pig

620
00:44:39,560 --> 00:44:41,320
Stop acting
unlike yourself

621
00:44:41,720 --> 00:44:43,200
Sober up and
Let's go home

622
00:44:43,440 --> 00:44:44,960
Your wedding is tomorrow

623
00:44:50,400 --> 00:44:51,560
Hyo-jin!

624
00:44:54,640 --> 00:44:56,120
What should I do?

625
00:44:57,600 --> 00:44:59,880
I should be
responsible for you

626
00:45:01,040 --> 00:45:02,080
Lady!

627
00:45:03,280 --> 00:45:05,640
I'm responsible for her!

628
00:45:06,880 --> 00:45:11,840
When she turns thirty
she's supposed to marry me

629
00:45:43,760 --> 00:45:44,920
Hyo-jin

630
00:45:45,960 --> 00:45:49,040
I can't get married

631
00:45:49,800 --> 00:45:51,160
I won't
I won't

632
00:45:51,800 --> 00:45:54,920
I can't leave you
alone and get married

633
00:45:55,320 --> 00:45:57,560
I'm gonna cancel it

634
00:45:59,520 --> 00:46:01,600
Think I'm kidding?

635
00:46:04,280 --> 00:46:05,320
Joon-ah

636
00:46:06,320 --> 00:46:07,920
I lied to you
about something

637
00:46:08,280 --> 00:46:09,880
What?
About what?

638
00:46:12,960 --> 00:46:13,960
Actually...

639
00:46:15,000 --> 00:46:17,000
I broke up
with my boyfriend

640
00:46:17,760 --> 00:46:18,840
What?

641
00:46:19,120 --> 00:46:21,160
That bastard!

642
00:46:21,360 --> 00:46:23,080
I'm positive
that you told

643
00:46:25,720 --> 00:46:28,200
He went to America last year

644
00:46:29,760 --> 00:46:30,600
He said this before he left

645
00:46:31,920 --> 00:46:33,200
You're great as a girlfriend

646
00:46:33,440 --> 00:46:34,760
but I'm not sure as a wife

647
00:46:37,640 --> 00:46:39,040
What could he mean by that?

648
00:46:40,760 --> 00:46:42,440
He was my first love though

649
00:46:44,000 --> 00:46:45,240
I liked not being ignored

650
00:46:45,320 --> 00:46:46,880
when I said I had a boyfriend

651
00:46:52,720 --> 00:46:53,840
But Joon-ah...

652
00:46:54,760 --> 00:46:57,160
I think
I like someone

653
00:46:58,960 --> 00:46:59,880
But he is...

654
00:47:01,000 --> 00:47:03,680
Someone
I have to set up

655
00:47:06,400 --> 00:47:08,440
I'm afraid to love

656
00:47:08,720 --> 00:47:09,960
and just wanna live like this

657
00:47:13,080 --> 00:47:14,280
I'll be okay

658
00:47:14,960 --> 00:47:17,560
Since I have a bad memory
I'll forget him soon

659
00:47:21,840 --> 00:47:23,840
Where am I?

660
00:47:24,400 --> 00:47:26,400
Hyo-jin, I'm cold

661
00:47:26,560 --> 00:47:28,400
Mister!
close the window

662
00:47:42,880 --> 00:47:45,240
Hyo-jin, I'm cold

663
00:47:46,640 --> 00:47:48,520
Joon-ah
what should I do?

664
00:47:50,040 --> 00:47:51,480
What should I do?

665
00:47:58,120 --> 00:47:59,480
Now for...

666
00:47:59,760 --> 00:48:01,480
the bride and groom's
walk down the lane

667
00:48:01,680 --> 00:48:02,600
Everyone please give them

668
00:48:02,800 --> 00:48:04,760
A warm round of applause

669
00:48:04,920 --> 00:48:06,480
May the walk begin!

670
00:48:08,840 --> 00:48:10,360
It's so childish

671
00:48:10,560 --> 00:48:12,040
He acts the way he looks

672
00:48:12,200 --> 00:48:15,360
How could he have the wedding
on Hyo-jin's birthday?

673
00:48:15,520 --> 00:48:16,920
You're right

674
00:48:28,560 --> 00:48:30,080
Looks as if the groom

675
00:48:30,080 --> 00:48:32,040
likes his mother-in-law more

676
00:48:32,600 --> 00:48:34,760
I'm not even good
to my folks

677
00:48:34,880 --> 00:48:36,840
So when I think
about my in-laws

678
00:48:37,040 --> 00:48:38,760
It fucking makes me sick

679
00:48:39,600 --> 00:48:42,800
Guys
I'm marrying an orphan

680
00:48:43,200 --> 00:48:44,280
You're right

681
00:48:44,280 --> 00:48:45,240
I hate family customs

682
00:48:45,640 --> 00:48:47,280
I'm marrying an orphan, too

683
00:49:03,200 --> 00:49:04,720
Congratulations
you look so pretty

684
00:49:04,880 --> 00:49:05,680
Hae-in

685
00:49:06,800 --> 00:49:09,400
Thank so much for
introducing me to him

686
00:49:10,800 --> 00:49:13,440
Look how pretty this ring is

687
00:49:13,520 --> 00:49:14,440
Jealous, huh?

688
00:49:24,160 --> 00:49:26,680
- Meeting your boyfriend later, huh?
- Please, eat dinner together

689
00:49:26,800 --> 00:49:27,800
Forget it

690
00:49:28,000 --> 00:49:30,400
You'll be much happier to spend
it with your man

691
00:49:30,600 --> 00:49:31,840
Let's leave them alone

692
00:49:32,240 --> 00:49:33,000
Don't worry

693
00:49:33,200 --> 00:49:34,880
I'll get you
a present later

694
00:49:42,000 --> 00:49:43,640
Must be happy, asshole

695
00:49:44,160 --> 00:49:48,400
Hey, can't you stop cursing?

696
00:49:57,120 --> 00:49:58,160
It's a ring!

697
00:50:06,120 --> 00:50:07,240
Is it fake?

698
00:50:11,360 --> 00:50:12,760
I'm so jealous

699
00:50:12,880 --> 00:50:15,560
He hasn't fixed
that habit yet?

700
00:50:16,360 --> 00:50:17,560
Think he can?

701
00:50:17,720 --> 00:50:19,360
She's gonna kill him
on their first night

702
00:50:19,520 --> 00:50:21,240
Let me try it on once

703
00:50:21,480 --> 00:50:22,440
It's so pretty

704
00:50:33,520 --> 00:50:35,160
Hi
you've reached Kim Hyo-jin

705
00:50:35,320 --> 00:50:37,960
No one's home now
so please leave a message

706
00:50:38,240 --> 00:50:39,160
You better!

707
00:50:41,360 --> 00:50:42,240
Hyo-jin

708
00:50:42,560 --> 00:50:43,520
It's your mom

709
00:50:44,040 --> 00:50:46,560
Did you eat seawood soup
for your birthday?

710
00:50:47,400 --> 00:50:49,480
Your father feels
much better now

711
00:50:51,480 --> 00:50:53,640
The air here is
really nice

712
00:50:53,920 --> 00:50:55,680
Tell her to get married
before I die

713
00:50:55,800 --> 00:50:58,080
Honey, it's her birthday
for goodness sakes

714
00:50:58,240 --> 00:50:59,240
Be quiet

715
00:51:27,200 --> 00:51:29,280
A dove forms groups

716
00:51:29,520 --> 00:51:31,040
Because it is faithful

717
00:51:31,200 --> 00:51:33,400
it loves first mate forever

718
00:51:34,160 --> 00:51:36,160
This white dove is a female

719
00:51:36,640 --> 00:51:37,800
The purple one is a male

720
00:51:37,960 --> 00:51:39,400
They are common couple

721
00:51:41,400 --> 00:51:42,600
Because the male gets in heat

722
00:51:42,680 --> 00:51:46,360
it kisses to the female passionately
and expresses passion

723
00:51:47,920 --> 00:51:50,280
A stranger approaches
to join them

724
00:51:52,120 --> 00:51:54,280
But the male drives him

725
00:51:54,760 --> 00:51:56,240
The reason why
the male beats its wings

726
00:51:56,320 --> 00:51:59,080
it wants to tread the female

727
00:53:31,520 --> 00:53:33,680
What happened to your hair?

728
00:53:34,720 --> 00:53:36,040
Well, nothing

729
00:53:38,320 --> 00:53:40,600
My goodness
Hyo-jin

730
00:53:41,600 --> 00:53:42,520
I can't believe it

731
00:53:45,200 --> 00:53:46,440
Park Hyun-soo!

732
00:53:49,960 --> 00:53:51,760
What are you
doing here so early?

733
00:54:01,200 --> 00:54:02,400
Have some coffee

734
00:54:05,000 --> 00:54:05,920
Here you go

735
00:54:06,280 --> 00:54:07,200
Thank you

736
00:54:07,400 --> 00:54:08,600
And for you

737
00:54:10,200 --> 00:54:12,640
Oh, thanks

738
00:54:13,000 --> 00:54:14,960
You were my client
before remember?

739
00:54:15,680 --> 00:54:17,960
Hi, I'm Song Min-ah

740
00:54:18,400 --> 00:54:19,560
Hi

741
00:54:20,080 --> 00:54:21,640
That's unfair of you

742
00:54:21,840 --> 00:54:23,880
You never visited
when you were my client

743
00:54:24,320 --> 00:54:27,200
- Must be very busy
- Yes...

744
00:54:28,840 --> 00:54:29,640
Hyo-jin

745
00:54:29,840 --> 00:54:31,560
I think your computer
is broken again

746
00:54:32,280 --> 00:54:33,880
You should check it

747
00:54:35,120 --> 00:54:36,160
Computer?

748
00:54:37,320 --> 00:54:38,320
Right

749
00:54:51,280 --> 00:54:52,520
Slimy picture, huh?

750
00:54:54,920 --> 00:54:57,280
My mother likes it though

751
00:54:57,960 --> 00:54:59,080
What's wrong with this thing?

752
00:54:59,880 --> 00:55:01,440
A machine doesn't lie

753
00:55:01,680 --> 00:55:02,760
Let me take
a look at it

754
00:55:03,680 --> 00:55:06,560
Engineers are so marvelous

755
00:55:07,080 --> 00:55:08,960
Why is this picture here?

756
00:55:09,160 --> 00:55:11,200
Hyo-jin, your boyfriend
is so handsome

757
00:55:11,360 --> 00:55:12,440
Getting married
next year, right?

758
00:55:12,680 --> 00:55:13,800
Has it been a year now?

759
00:55:14,080 --> 00:55:17,120
Hyo-jin is good at dating
and with her work

760
00:55:17,760 --> 00:55:19,320
She's so talented
at her job

761
00:55:19,640 --> 00:55:24,000
I always set others up
but when will I get married?

762
00:55:25,440 --> 00:55:26,800
His picture is better

763
00:55:30,280 --> 00:55:31,280
Let's see

764
00:55:41,560 --> 00:55:45,000
Isn't this too big
for protection?

765
00:55:45,240 --> 00:55:46,640
Goodness
what's this for?

766
00:55:49,040 --> 00:55:50,640
One moment

767
00:55:50,760 --> 00:55:51,440
Sorry

768
00:55:52,520 --> 00:55:54,240
I can't believe it

769
00:55:54,240 --> 00:55:55,440
Is it a real gun?

770
00:55:55,560 --> 00:55:56,960
- I think it is
- Let's see it

771
00:55:57,120 --> 00:55:58,520
Oh my
it's so frightening

772
00:56:03,640 --> 00:56:04,640
Since you've
signed up

773
00:56:04,840 --> 00:56:07,640
you'll go on 12 dates for a year

774
00:56:07,920 --> 00:56:09,840
We'll also include events
into your schedule

775
00:56:12,160 --> 00:56:14,480
I see you didn't
write down your type

776
00:56:16,560 --> 00:56:18,280
Let me be frank with you

777
00:56:19,160 --> 00:56:20,880
Please set me up with
Park Hyun-soo

778
00:56:22,560 --> 00:56:24,040
I know that
he's a client here

779
00:56:25,520 --> 00:56:27,480
And please don't tell him

780
00:56:28,560 --> 00:56:30,560
Please set it up
as quickly as today

781
00:56:31,640 --> 00:56:32,520
Today?

782
00:56:34,320 --> 00:56:35,880
I'm sorry
it's a call from work

783
00:56:37,800 --> 00:56:38,960
Lee Kang-hyun speaking

784
00:56:39,880 --> 00:56:41,160
Yes, sir

785
00:56:42,520 --> 00:56:43,800
The text hasn't
come in yet

786
00:56:43,960 --> 00:56:45,240
So you'll need to hurry

787
00:56:47,520 --> 00:56:49,560
772 at gigic dot com

788
00:56:51,240 --> 00:56:53,120
No, it's g-i-g-i-c

789
00:56:53,360 --> 00:56:55,160
GIGIC

790
00:57:02,160 --> 00:57:04,840
I told you not to press it

791
00:57:10,320 --> 00:57:12,440
I can't believe it

792
00:57:12,440 --> 00:57:13,640
He's there on time

793
00:57:14,200 --> 00:57:15,680
But he always
said he was busy

794
00:57:17,200 --> 00:57:19,280
Now he shows up regularly
and even at the office

795
00:57:19,760 --> 00:57:22,600
He must've made up
his mind now to marry

796
00:57:24,240 --> 00:57:25,960
Now that we know
he's here, let's go

797
00:57:26,440 --> 00:57:27,640
Wait a minute

798
00:57:27,840 --> 00:57:30,440
We have to take care of
our clients to the end, right?

799
00:57:32,040 --> 00:57:33,880
What if everything
goes well?

800
00:57:35,080 --> 00:57:38,560
If it doesn't work out
he has one more left

801
00:57:39,280 --> 00:57:40,480
Set me up next time

802
00:57:41,200 --> 00:57:41,920
No, no...

803
00:57:42,160 --> 00:57:44,040
The manager won't forgive me

804
00:57:45,640 --> 00:57:46,520
This is a secret

805
00:57:46,760 --> 00:57:48,400
But I think
the manager likes me

806
00:57:49,320 --> 00:57:50,280
Really?

807
00:57:50,440 --> 00:57:51,360
I'm serious

808
00:57:51,560 --> 00:57:52,640
He should tell me directly

809
00:57:52,760 --> 00:57:55,080
Instead of always flirting

810
00:58:04,880 --> 00:58:05,840
Wait a minute

811
00:58:28,000 --> 00:58:29,040
Oh no...

812
00:58:29,320 --> 00:58:30,360
What is she doing?

813
00:58:30,640 --> 00:58:32,000
They must know
each other

814
00:58:34,000 --> 00:58:35,000
How have you been?

815
00:58:35,360 --> 00:58:36,240
It's been a long time

816
00:58:36,800 --> 00:58:40,080
What are you doing here?

817
00:58:40,200 --> 00:58:42,280
No, but he's mine

818
00:58:42,560 --> 00:58:44,840
How could she?

819
00:58:47,760 --> 00:58:48,600
Where are you going?

820
00:58:48,920 --> 00:58:49,680
Hyo-jin!

821
00:58:50,240 --> 00:58:51,120
Darn!

822
00:58:52,400 --> 00:58:53,240
I can't believe it

823
00:58:53,880 --> 00:58:56,560
No matter what
Hugh Grant is the best

824
00:58:57,320 --> 00:59:00,000
Those eyes make
a woman melt

825
00:59:00,760 --> 00:59:03,200
Shit, isn't he fucking great?

826
00:59:03,520 --> 00:59:07,120
That's why Hugh Grant's romantic
comedies can be forgiven

827
00:59:07,680 --> 00:59:08,520
Ethan Hawk is my babe

828
00:59:08,800 --> 00:59:12,120
He looked so cute
in Before Sunrise

829
00:59:12,720 --> 00:59:13,920
No, his legs are too short

830
00:59:14,160 --> 00:59:15,080
His lower half is flimsy

831
00:59:15,240 --> 00:59:17,000
Dicaprio is my type of babe

832
00:59:27,200 --> 00:59:30,280
Now I can understand
Shim Eun-ah in Tell Me Something

833
00:59:31,800 --> 00:59:32,720
What about her?

834
00:59:33,120 --> 00:59:35,120
She axed her lovers
and mixed them up

835
00:59:35,720 --> 00:59:38,040
The nice legs
of a cute guy

836
00:59:38,840 --> 00:59:41,040
The torso of
a warm-hearted guy

837
00:59:41,560 --> 00:59:43,560
And the arms of
a caressing guy

838
00:59:43,960 --> 00:59:47,240
She tried to put together
a perfect man

839
00:59:47,440 --> 00:59:48,240
Why?

840
00:59:48,480 --> 00:59:51,320
Because no perfect
fucking guy exists

841
00:59:52,440 --> 00:59:53,920
Wasn't the corpse her dad's?

842
00:59:54,200 --> 00:59:55,920
You sure
you saw that movie?

843
00:59:56,120 --> 00:59:59,960
She tried to put
her dad's throat on that corpse

844
01:00:00,600 --> 01:00:03,080
Then are you sure
you saw it?

845
01:00:04,000 --> 01:00:06,320
It was that cop's throat

846
01:00:06,560 --> 01:00:09,080
It was the last piece
to her perfect man

847
01:00:09,720 --> 01:00:10,720
It's not her dad's

848
01:00:10,920 --> 01:00:13,040
Her dad's throat was
found in her freezer

849
01:00:13,520 --> 01:00:15,280
Found? When?

850
01:00:15,560 --> 01:00:16,520
Yeah, in the freezer

851
01:00:16,640 --> 01:00:18,560
She stored it
there to keep it fresh

852
01:00:18,960 --> 01:00:19,760
But I saw that movie

853
01:00:19,880 --> 01:00:22,000
Hey, is his head some
watermelon then?

854
01:00:22,280 --> 01:00:25,600
- Han Suk Gyu and Moon Sung Gun was...
- Watch a movie through your nostrils?

855
01:00:25,720 --> 01:00:28,360
Why don't you put your head
in the freezer?

856
01:00:28,640 --> 01:00:30,560
- They was stabbed with a knife...
- You be quiet!

857
01:00:30,760 --> 01:00:32,760
Who cares how
I see a movie

858
01:00:32,840 --> 01:00:34,320
Because you're talking nonsense

859
01:00:36,240 --> 01:00:39,200
When I imagine Hugh Grant's
toad eyes move

860
01:00:39,680 --> 01:00:41,320
your taste is like a tadpole

861
01:00:41,840 --> 01:00:42,920
Remember Bridget Jone's Diary?

862
01:00:43,200 --> 01:00:45,000
Hugh Grant looked haggard, huh?

863
01:00:45,400 --> 01:00:47,920
Hey, is Ethan Hawk your babe?

864
01:00:48,800 --> 01:00:50,920
Cage babe
Dicaprice babe, shit

865
01:00:51,240 --> 01:00:53,320
Any slimy bastard is her babe

866
01:00:53,520 --> 01:00:54,760
Don't fall in love

867
01:00:55,000 --> 01:00:58,720
You're much older than
those assholes, old lady

868
01:00:59,080 --> 01:01:00,000
What?
Assholes?

869
01:01:00,320 --> 01:01:01,200
What did you say?

870
01:01:01,440 --> 01:01:02,120
Say it again

871
01:01:02,280 --> 01:01:04,040
If you insult my babes
you're insulting me

872
01:01:06,120 --> 01:01:06,920
Stop it!

873
01:01:07,000 --> 01:01:07,840
I said stop!

874
01:01:08,040 --> 01:01:09,000
What's wrong with you?

875
01:01:09,400 --> 01:01:10,480
Are you teeny boppers?

876
01:01:10,840 --> 01:01:12,600
All you do is talk is
love or marriage

877
01:01:12,720 --> 01:01:13,920
but have you ever
fell in love?

878
01:01:14,000 --> 01:01:15,840
Or loved someone?

879
01:01:15,960 --> 01:01:16,720
Go!

880
01:01:16,840 --> 01:01:18,800
Go live your life instead of
like the movies!

881
01:01:20,400 --> 01:01:21,120
Not going?

882
01:01:21,440 --> 01:01:22,160
Then I'll go

883
01:01:24,720 --> 01:01:25,840
What's up with her?

884
01:01:26,000 --> 01:01:27,400
What gives her the right to
shout like that?

885
01:01:27,520 --> 01:01:28,400
What a shame!

886
01:01:28,520 --> 01:01:30,120
Miss!
some more eels here

887
01:01:30,160 --> 01:01:30,840
And chicken gizzards

888
01:01:33,800 --> 01:01:34,920
What's the matter?

889
01:01:35,680 --> 01:01:36,360
Take off

890
01:01:37,480 --> 01:01:38,920
What's wrong with you?

891
01:01:42,640 --> 01:01:44,200
I can't do anything
because of you!

892
01:01:44,200 --> 01:01:45,200
What did I do?

893
01:01:46,760 --> 01:01:48,640
Thank you for setting
me up before

894
01:01:50,160 --> 01:01:52,960
I won't need
any more dates

895
01:01:55,280 --> 01:01:56,720
Congratulations

896
01:02:01,040 --> 01:02:02,440
He's my ex-boyfriend

897
01:02:02,640 --> 01:02:04,120
We broke up before
I went to America

898
01:02:05,520 --> 01:02:07,240
I tried to get back
together with him

899
01:02:08,560 --> 01:02:09,760
but it didn't work

900
01:02:10,640 --> 01:02:12,960
If both his mother and
wife were drowning

901
01:02:14,000 --> 01:02:15,520
he said
he'd save his mother

902
01:02:18,960 --> 01:02:21,400
Maybe Korean guys
don't suit me

903
01:02:24,640 --> 01:02:26,320
One sec, it's business

904
01:02:27,880 --> 01:02:29,000
Lee Kang-hyun speaking

905
01:02:30,600 --> 01:02:31,440
Oh hi!

906
01:02:32,440 --> 01:02:33,360
Yes

907
01:02:34,440 --> 01:02:35,440
You like the cover?

908
01:02:36,200 --> 01:02:37,120
Fantastic!

909
01:02:38,440 --> 01:02:39,600
Sorry, one moment

910
01:02:39,960 --> 01:02:41,040
Hyo-jin

911
01:02:41,600 --> 01:02:43,920
Do you offer
international marriages?

912
01:02:44,200 --> 01:02:45,120
Pardon?

913
01:02:46,360 --> 01:02:47,520
It was a joke

914
01:02:48,120 --> 01:02:50,560
Yes, sorry about that

915
01:02:54,240 --> 01:02:55,240
What did she say?

916
01:02:55,520 --> 01:02:56,440
What's this?

917
01:02:56,560 --> 01:02:58,040
Wedding invitation?

918
01:02:58,240 --> 01:02:59,920
Concert tickets

919
01:03:00,160 --> 01:03:01,920
You're lucky
it's sold out already

920
01:03:02,160 --> 01:03:04,520
Can I have them instead?

921
01:03:07,120 --> 01:03:08,640
Hyo-jin

922
01:03:11,120 --> 01:03:12,360
Constipated?

923
01:03:12,720 --> 01:03:14,480
What don't you
look so good?

924
01:03:15,520 --> 01:03:17,360
Let's have a drink
when you feel better

925
01:03:17,600 --> 01:03:19,880
I'll treat you to
a real good time

926
01:03:20,040 --> 01:03:21,200
Just let me know

927
01:03:21,360 --> 01:03:22,840
Today

928
01:03:23,360 --> 01:03:25,520
Sorry, today will be a bit hard

929
01:03:25,880 --> 01:03:28,160
Let's do it another night

930
01:03:28,760 --> 01:03:29,920
No, today

931
01:03:30,000 --> 01:03:31,400
Right now

932
01:03:39,120 --> 01:03:41,560
This is my close friend
Hae-in

933
01:03:42,280 --> 01:03:43,600
Over here

934
01:03:44,120 --> 01:03:46,280
My boss
who believes in free sex

935
01:03:49,880 --> 01:03:50,880
Hello

936
01:03:51,000 --> 01:03:52,360
Yes, hello

937
01:03:54,000 --> 01:03:55,560
Come on

938
01:03:55,720 --> 01:03:56,640
Drink

939
01:03:56,680 --> 01:03:57,160
Bottoms up

940
01:03:57,360 --> 01:03:58,640
Cheers!

941
01:04:04,160 --> 01:04:05,080
Hae-in!

942
01:04:05,680 --> 01:04:07,080
Hae-in!

943
01:04:07,640 --> 01:04:08,640
Know this?

944
01:04:08,840 --> 01:04:12,040
That all your lovers are
variations of your first love?

945
01:04:12,360 --> 01:04:14,000
So if you fail
at your first love

946
01:04:14,240 --> 01:04:17,960
Attempting suicide is
the natural the thing to do

947
01:04:18,280 --> 01:04:21,080
So I tried it twice

948
01:04:21,320 --> 01:04:22,760
But it didn't work out

949
01:04:22,840 --> 01:04:24,320
You attempted suicide?

950
01:04:24,360 --> 01:04:25,840
What method did you use?

951
01:04:26,360 --> 01:04:27,320
Wrist!

952
01:04:27,520 --> 01:04:31,240
I stuck my wrist out
but the blade was dull

953
01:04:32,520 --> 01:04:34,000
Look
only my forearm got torn

954
01:04:34,200 --> 01:04:36,320
Yeah, it doesn't work, huh?

955
01:04:36,560 --> 01:04:37,480
You tried it?

956
01:04:37,640 --> 01:04:39,160
I failed at it, too

957
01:04:39,400 --> 01:04:41,480
Should I jump off
a roof next time?

958
01:04:41,760 --> 01:04:42,720
No, not that

959
01:04:43,040 --> 01:04:45,160
If you screw up
you'll turn into a vegetable

960
01:04:45,400 --> 01:04:48,440
Then what's the best way
without any pain?

961
01:04:48,720 --> 01:04:50,840
Well, I thought it over, too

962
01:04:52,240 --> 01:04:53,960
Manager!

963
01:04:54,600 --> 01:04:57,400
What will you
do with your car?

964
01:04:58,320 --> 01:04:59,560
Full house!

965
01:04:59,680 --> 01:05:02,560
It's the first licence plate
I've seen with a full house!

966
01:05:06,000 --> 01:05:09,240
Seoul 51, 8815

967
01:05:09,480 --> 01:05:10,920
I guess my car's a full house

968
01:05:11,920 --> 01:05:13,840
Bingo!

969
01:05:14,120 --> 01:05:15,720
I've hitjackpot!

970
01:05:19,240 --> 01:05:21,360
So what about your car
Hae-in?

971
01:05:22,960 --> 01:05:23,760
Aces

972
01:05:23,960 --> 01:05:25,080
9110

973
01:05:26,360 --> 01:05:27,560
Weak

974
01:05:28,440 --> 01:05:30,680
Well, it's the highest pair

975
01:05:31,320 --> 01:05:32,400
Must be nice

976
01:05:32,600 --> 01:05:34,440
What's so nice about it?

977
01:05:34,760 --> 01:05:35,560
Hae-in

978
01:05:36,680 --> 01:05:38,080
What's so good about aces?

979
01:05:39,440 --> 01:05:41,440
Nevermind that

980
01:05:42,320 --> 01:05:44,680
Hae-in
let's go for another round

981
01:05:45,840 --> 01:05:47,560
I don't trust men

982
01:05:47,880 --> 01:05:50,480
No, my friend's
having a card game

983
01:05:50,560 --> 01:05:51,920
for his divorce anniversary

984
01:05:53,000 --> 01:05:55,600
What a great friend to
have a divorce anniversary

985
01:05:55,920 --> 01:05:57,680
- Isn't he?
- You only play poker?

986
01:05:57,920 --> 01:05:59,440
No, I play blackjack, too

987
01:05:59,560 --> 01:06:02,240
Know how to
play blackjack?

988
01:06:02,440 --> 01:06:03,880
Hae-in

989
01:06:05,960 --> 01:06:08,000
It's this way, Hae-in

990
01:06:09,040 --> 01:06:12,240
Hae-in
we have to go this way

991
01:06:14,600 --> 01:06:16,760
I'm sorry

992
01:06:20,760 --> 01:06:22,400
Sorry

993
01:06:28,480 --> 01:06:31,200
Sorry, but my foot

994
01:06:31,280 --> 01:06:33,960
Please, the car mister

995
01:06:38,920 --> 01:06:40,280
You should be careful

996
01:06:45,160 --> 01:06:46,960
You're lucky
it didn't get worse

997
01:06:48,720 --> 01:06:49,960
Don't make her drink

998
01:06:50,160 --> 01:06:52,240
and look after
your girlfriend better

999
01:06:53,400 --> 01:06:54,680
Look at this bruise

1000
01:06:55,120 --> 01:06:56,440
Your whole body is scarred

1001
01:07:14,280 --> 01:07:16,360
It'll sober you up

1002
01:07:41,200 --> 01:07:45,000
My dad has been sick
ever since I was ten

1003
01:07:45,640 --> 01:07:48,640
Maybe that's why I feel
at ease at the hospital

1004
01:07:50,000 --> 01:07:52,000
It's not only
because of my dad

1005
01:07:53,080 --> 01:07:55,680
I get hurt frequently
you see

1006
01:08:11,560 --> 01:08:13,480
I worked at a trading firm
right after college

1007
01:08:15,160 --> 01:08:17,200
but after three years
I fell into a slump

1008
01:08:17,520 --> 01:08:20,320
Then I saw this job ad
and I felt it was perfect for me

1009
01:08:21,360 --> 01:08:24,000
Ever since college
I set a lot of people up

1010
01:08:24,400 --> 01:08:26,760
Every one of them
got married

1011
01:08:33,640 --> 01:08:34,840
I'll take that

1012
01:08:34,920 --> 01:08:36,440
Oh, thanks

1013
01:08:44,320 --> 01:08:45,760
When I come to the hospital

1014
01:08:46,120 --> 01:08:49,280
I sometimes wished
my husband was a doctor

1015
01:08:50,120 --> 01:08:52,360
So if my computer has a virus

1016
01:08:52,800 --> 01:08:54,840
I wish my husband
was an engineer

1017
01:08:55,240 --> 01:08:56,680
I guess that's
what you mean

1018
01:08:58,800 --> 01:08:59,960
Yes

1019
01:09:39,440 --> 01:09:40,480
By the way

1020
01:09:42,480 --> 01:09:43,360
if...

1021
01:09:43,840 --> 01:09:46,800
your mother and wife were drowning
who'd you save first?

1022
01:09:47,840 --> 01:09:49,120
My mother, of course

1023
01:09:50,520 --> 01:09:53,840
A young woman can
swim and survive

1024
01:09:54,360 --> 01:09:56,840
But my mom needs to
be saved by me

1025
01:10:09,360 --> 01:10:11,720
I'm conservative
and contradicting

1026
01:10:13,040 --> 01:10:17,120
The type to hurt others
easily and selfish

1027
01:10:18,160 --> 01:10:22,040
Think a guy like me
can meet a good person?

1028
01:10:23,440 --> 01:10:25,240
Since I'm not one myself

1029
01:10:29,360 --> 01:10:30,560
Don't worry

1030
01:10:31,080 --> 01:10:32,640
I'll introduce you to a nice girl

1031
01:10:34,760 --> 01:10:36,040
You have my word
till the end

1032
01:10:52,680 --> 01:10:53,920
Hyo-hin, are you okay?

1033
01:10:54,120 --> 01:10:55,600
Training for the Olympics?

1034
01:10:56,280 --> 01:10:59,200
Hyo-jin, make sure
you win the gold medal!

1035
01:10:59,400 --> 01:11:01,320
Yeah, go for the gold

1036
01:11:03,240 --> 01:11:04,800
No, I can do it

1037
01:11:37,080 --> 01:11:39,400
I've been married
for 14 days, 20 hours

1038
01:11:39,720 --> 01:11:41,960
54 minutes
and 21 seconds

1039
01:11:42,440 --> 01:11:45,240
22 seconds
23 seconds

1040
01:11:46,520 --> 01:11:48,040
Who cares about
your friends

1041
01:11:48,680 --> 01:11:49,760
Are you that happy?

1042
01:11:51,520 --> 01:11:54,760
Wait for me

1043
01:11:55,600 --> 01:11:58,400
Give this back to Hae-sun

1044
01:11:59,040 --> 01:12:00,000
What's this?

1045
01:12:00,640 --> 01:12:03,840
Why is it so wrapped
up like this?

1046
01:12:05,200 --> 01:12:07,440
I gave this to you

1047
01:12:07,560 --> 01:12:10,240
but thanks so much
for returning it

1048
01:12:10,480 --> 01:12:13,240
Hae-sun cried and
went berzerk over this

1049
01:12:14,320 --> 01:12:15,360
Hyo-jin

1050
01:12:15,880 --> 01:12:16,760
Come here

1051
01:12:16,920 --> 01:12:18,880
Point out
any guy you want

1052
01:12:18,920 --> 01:12:20,680
Then I'll bring him
right to you

1053
01:12:20,840 --> 01:12:22,760
Tell me who

1054
01:12:24,040 --> 01:12:26,280
- How about him?
- Isn't spitting a misdemeanor?

1055
01:12:26,440 --> 01:12:28,640
- Yeah, a three-day detention
- No criminals

1056
01:12:30,320 --> 01:12:31,960
Then what about him?

1057
01:12:32,400 --> 01:12:35,840
His tie sucks
no taste at all

1058
01:12:36,040 --> 01:12:38,200
Come on
you're being too picky

1059
01:12:38,360 --> 01:12:40,600
That's why...

1060
01:12:40,680 --> 01:12:42,240
You don't have a guy
right now

1061
01:12:42,960 --> 01:12:44,280
Let me pick one for you

1062
01:12:46,760 --> 01:12:50,320
How about him?

1063
01:12:50,680 --> 01:12:52,400
Not bad, huh?

1064
01:12:55,120 --> 01:12:56,240
He looks like a playboy

1065
01:12:56,680 --> 01:12:59,280
Conservative and picky
he's an F

1066
01:13:00,640 --> 01:13:02,320
Damn it

1067
01:13:02,600 --> 01:13:04,040
Come on

1068
01:13:04,320 --> 01:13:07,000
He looks to be successful
and nice enough

1069
01:13:07,640 --> 01:13:09,040
You're colorblind

1070
01:13:09,360 --> 01:13:11,120
You don't know
how to see men

1071
01:13:11,360 --> 01:13:13,840
Coming from
a guy's perspective

1072
01:13:14,000 --> 01:13:16,560
He's a great guy, okay?

1073
01:13:16,680 --> 01:13:18,880
It's him, end of story

1074
01:13:19,680 --> 01:13:22,320
No, the guy next to
him seems better

1075
01:13:23,920 --> 01:13:25,400
Who?

1076
01:13:25,560 --> 01:13:26,240
Next to him

1077
01:13:26,480 --> 01:13:27,320
Where?

1078
01:13:28,680 --> 01:13:29,800
That little twirp?

1079
01:13:31,040 --> 01:13:32,720
Give me a break

1080
01:13:32,920 --> 01:13:35,120
Your taste got weird

1081
01:13:36,000 --> 01:13:38,360
You've completely
lost your mind

1082
01:13:38,520 --> 01:13:40,840
I'm successful enough
so a younger guy is fine

1083
01:13:44,120 --> 01:13:45,280
Yeah?

1084
01:13:46,920 --> 01:13:47,680
Wait

1085
01:13:47,840 --> 01:13:49,280
Oh no!

1086
01:13:49,440 --> 01:13:51,400
Hey, I'm running late

1087
01:13:51,520 --> 01:13:53,280
Hyo-jin, I'll call you later

1088
01:13:53,280 --> 01:13:55,360
- Come later, okay?
- Joon-ah!

1089
01:14:09,480 --> 01:14:10,320
Excuse me

1090
01:14:12,600 --> 01:14:14,720
That guy told me
to ask you out

1091
01:14:19,560 --> 01:14:20,840
Wanna go to a club?

1092
01:14:48,880 --> 01:14:51,120
There's an event
tomorrow, right?

1093
01:14:52,200 --> 01:14:54,880
Yes, tomorrow's
your last chance

1094
01:14:55,400 --> 01:14:58,640
You'll definitely meet someone
you'll like there

1095
01:14:59,840 --> 01:15:01,120
Thanks, Hyo-jin

1096
01:15:22,920 --> 01:15:24,360
Lee Kang-hyun?

1097
01:15:24,840 --> 01:15:27,080
Hello, it's Kim Hyo-jin

1098
01:15:27,920 --> 01:15:29,640
Are you busy?

1099
01:15:30,400 --> 01:15:32,960
Well, I called about our event

1100
01:15:52,000 --> 01:15:54,760
Place them
one after the other

1101
01:15:59,280 --> 01:16:00,160
Song Min-ah!

1102
01:16:00,280 --> 01:16:01,800
Stop standing around and work!

1103
01:16:02,480 --> 01:16:04,560
Why always pick on me?

1104
01:16:06,920 --> 01:16:08,200
Please take
your number card

1105
01:16:08,440 --> 01:16:10,080
Look over the list carefully

1106
01:16:10,240 --> 01:16:12,600
and mark the name
or number of your choice

1107
01:16:12,840 --> 01:16:15,360
Also, don't forget

1108
01:16:15,560 --> 01:16:16,840
that there are
three blanks on the back

1109
01:16:17,000 --> 01:16:18,200
Thank you

1110
01:16:21,600 --> 01:16:23,880
You should rest
instead of being here

1111
01:16:24,120 --> 01:16:25,560
Thank you
Don't worry

1112
01:16:26,680 --> 01:16:27,760
Sorry I'm late

1113
01:16:27,760 --> 01:16:29,400
How do you feel?

1114
01:16:30,440 --> 01:16:31,440
Welcome

1115
01:16:33,040 --> 01:16:35,400
Hyo-jin!
Kim Hyo-jin!

1116
01:16:45,480 --> 01:16:49,600
Now we will begin
today's event

1117
01:16:50,600 --> 01:16:54,080
You ladies have always
had only one type, right?

1118
01:16:54,280 --> 01:16:56,040
A rich guy
who dies early

1119
01:16:57,040 --> 01:16:59,560
Ladies, you're overreacting
at the moment

1120
01:17:01,280 --> 01:17:04,360
All of you are
still feeling very awkward

1121
01:17:04,680 --> 01:17:06,360
Guys, how about
we clench our fists tight

1122
01:17:06,440 --> 01:17:07,160
Hey

1123
01:17:07,720 --> 01:17:08,960
Look after your
clients instead

1124
01:17:09,480 --> 01:17:10,840
One just arrived

1125
01:17:11,080 --> 01:17:14,280
Ready and
one, two, three, success!

1126
01:17:14,880 --> 01:17:15,600
Very good

1127
01:17:15,880 --> 01:17:17,680
Ladies
you're supposed to clap

1128
01:17:18,760 --> 01:17:21,320
You can't sit still

1129
01:17:21,480 --> 01:17:24,440
When I count
one, two, three...

1130
01:17:24,520 --> 01:17:25,600
What took you so long?

1131
01:17:26,720 --> 01:17:29,200
Hyo-jin
who are you waiting for?

1132
01:17:36,200 --> 01:17:37,120
Got a question

1133
01:17:37,320 --> 01:17:38,280
Yes?

1134
01:17:39,080 --> 01:17:41,840
Your ex is better than
starting over again, right?

1135
01:17:45,880 --> 01:17:47,120
A tardy student

1136
01:17:53,360 --> 01:17:54,120
What a relief

1137
01:17:54,280 --> 01:17:55,760
I thought you'd be too busy

1138
01:17:56,480 --> 01:17:58,400
During the event

1139
01:18:11,160 --> 01:18:13,560
You're late, and what's with
your clothes again?

1140
01:18:26,040 --> 01:18:27,160
I worked the night shift

1141
01:18:30,280 --> 01:18:32,800
Find someone you're
interested in and jot her down

1142
01:18:33,000 --> 01:18:34,800
You can mark up
to three on the back

1143
01:18:36,160 --> 01:18:37,160
Good luck

1144
01:18:37,520 --> 01:18:41,920
I can mark just one
if I'm interested, right?

1145
01:18:48,680 --> 01:18:51,480
It hasn't hit me yet
that it's my last chance

1146
01:18:57,960 --> 01:19:01,920
Two, two, three, four
five, six, seven, eight

1147
01:19:02,360 --> 01:19:05,000
When you receive
a massage

1148
01:19:05,160 --> 01:19:08,840
if you close
your eyes it becomes kinky

1149
01:19:09,000 --> 01:19:11,880
Guys, just try to relax

1150
01:19:12,080 --> 01:19:13,280
and don't think otherwise

1151
01:19:13,400 --> 01:19:14,240
Now relax

1152
01:19:14,280 --> 01:19:15,920
One, two, three, four

1153
01:19:16,520 --> 01:19:18,880
Now everyone
raise your hands

1154
01:19:28,040 --> 01:19:29,640
What are you doing there?

1155
01:19:30,280 --> 01:19:31,440
Come and eat

1156
01:19:32,960 --> 01:19:34,040
Coming

1157
01:19:37,400 --> 01:19:38,280
What were you doing?

1158
01:19:38,440 --> 01:19:39,680
Here's our next contestant

1159
01:19:43,520 --> 01:19:44,200
Hello

1160
01:19:46,040 --> 01:19:49,000
My mom told me to
come here no matter what

1161
01:19:53,480 --> 01:19:55,280
Mom, I'm in
an interview

1162
01:19:58,440 --> 01:20:02,520
Yes, his mother has called

1163
01:20:04,440 --> 01:20:06,520
Anyway
well done gentlemen

1164
01:20:06,760 --> 01:20:07,480
and please return
to your seats

1165
01:20:07,640 --> 01:20:10,720
We have a lot of
unique people today

1166
01:20:13,320 --> 01:20:14,240
Is there any water here?

1167
01:20:14,480 --> 01:20:15,920
On the last table

1168
01:20:16,440 --> 01:20:17,920
- The next guys
- Fun, isn't it?

1169
01:20:22,760 --> 01:20:24,040
- I'm not eating
- Why not?

1170
01:20:24,200 --> 01:20:25,400
I see a special gentleman

1171
01:20:25,680 --> 01:20:27,440
One has just arrived

1172
01:20:27,560 --> 01:20:29,560
He looks to be very brave

1173
01:20:29,640 --> 01:20:31,600
Let's have him
up on the stage

1174
01:20:31,800 --> 01:20:33,280
Please come up

1175
01:20:33,840 --> 01:20:36,200
A big round of
applause everyone

1176
01:20:41,720 --> 01:20:43,240
Sir, why were you so late?

1177
01:20:43,880 --> 01:20:45,280
Stuck in traffic?

1178
01:20:46,400 --> 01:20:48,200
Please introduce yourself

1179
01:20:49,160 --> 01:20:50,400
Hello everyone

1180
01:20:51,080 --> 01:20:53,320
Within the past year
Seoul has changed a lot

1181
01:20:53,360 --> 01:20:54,040
I just arrived

1182
01:20:54,160 --> 01:20:57,320
At a Seoul research center
after being in America

1183
01:20:57,440 --> 01:20:59,200
Hi, I'm Kim Yong-jin

1184
01:21:00,040 --> 01:21:01,640
Nice to meet you

1185
01:21:02,240 --> 01:21:04,520
Now I know
what it's like

1186
01:21:04,680 --> 01:21:06,560
to be lonely
after living abroad

1187
01:21:07,000 --> 01:21:10,440
I've finally come to my senses
that I should really get married

1188
01:21:12,000 --> 01:21:13,160
Wait a minute

1189
01:21:13,800 --> 01:21:16,440
Then how come
you're so late getting here?

1190
01:21:16,680 --> 01:21:19,160
It may be very hard
you to marry by this year

1191
01:21:19,240 --> 01:21:20,520
What do you think?

1192
01:21:22,320 --> 01:21:23,880
I'm confident I will

1193
01:21:24,120 --> 01:21:25,560
I've given it a lot of
thought for a while

1194
01:21:26,280 --> 01:21:28,800
All I need to do
now is meet a nice woman

1195
01:21:29,120 --> 01:21:31,360
And considering
my appearance

1196
01:21:31,560 --> 01:21:33,920
I don't think I'm any less
than the others here

1197
01:21:35,080 --> 01:21:36,320
Yes, thank you

1198
01:21:37,720 --> 01:21:38,520
Great

1199
01:21:38,760 --> 01:21:41,240
I'm going to give
a special chance

1200
01:21:41,360 --> 01:21:43,040
to our tardy student

1201
01:21:43,040 --> 01:21:47,080
- Yeah, I've seen him before
- Seen anyone you like?

1202
01:21:47,320 --> 01:21:48,200
Yes

1203
01:21:48,360 --> 01:21:50,160
Can you be quiet?

1204
01:21:50,440 --> 01:21:53,040
Then you'll be proposing
to her out in the open

1205
01:21:53,200 --> 01:21:54,080
Okay?

1206
01:21:54,280 --> 01:21:55,720
Please take this

1207
01:21:56,080 --> 01:21:57,520
Now are you ready?

1208
01:21:57,720 --> 01:22:00,240
A propose to some lucky girl

1209
01:22:00,840 --> 01:22:02,800
- Go!
- Go!

1210
01:22:03,200 --> 01:22:05,040
Give him a round of applause

1211
01:22:08,600 --> 01:22:10,280
There he goes

1212
01:22:10,600 --> 01:22:12,760
Who will this woman be?

1213
01:22:16,360 --> 01:22:17,800
There she is!

1214
01:22:23,800 --> 01:22:25,000
But why isn't she accepting?

1215
01:22:26,160 --> 01:22:27,240
She likes the heart

1216
01:22:27,840 --> 01:22:29,640
But not the man perhaps?

1217
01:22:31,080 --> 01:22:34,080
Could she like someone else?

1218
01:22:36,880 --> 01:22:39,120
School was easy for him

1219
01:22:39,400 --> 01:22:40,440
But I guess marriage isn't

1220
01:22:41,360 --> 01:22:45,040
I'll give our gentleman
one more chance

1221
01:22:45,600 --> 01:22:49,600
A stunning dance sometimes wins
a girl's heart, right?

1222
01:22:50,040 --> 01:22:51,880
Cue music!

1223
01:23:13,320 --> 01:23:16,200
KAIST PhD
Seoul Research Center

1224
01:23:22,120 --> 01:23:23,600
Lee Kang-hyun speaking

1225
01:23:24,080 --> 01:23:24,840
Yes

1226
01:23:25,240 --> 01:23:26,240
What?

1227
01:23:26,600 --> 01:23:28,280
I can't hear you too well

1228
01:23:30,000 --> 01:23:32,320
Oh no, she's leaving

1229
01:23:32,400 --> 01:23:33,640
That's too bad

1230
01:23:34,360 --> 01:23:36,720
But he can't give up
so easily

1231
01:23:36,920 --> 01:23:38,840
Kim Yong-jin, hurry
and go catch her

1232
01:23:38,960 --> 01:23:42,880
Let's cheer him on with
a big round of applause

1233
01:23:43,080 --> 01:23:45,080
Clap your hands

1234
01:23:45,280 --> 01:23:48,160
I'll go to the office
now to look for it

1235
01:24:07,760 --> 01:24:08,960
Today it's

1236
01:24:13,240 --> 01:24:13,880
Not working?

1237
01:25:01,200 --> 01:25:03,640
Is that you Hyo-jin?

1238
01:25:29,160 --> 01:25:30,080
Hyo-jin!

1239
01:25:30,320 --> 01:25:31,320
Kim Hyo-jin!

1240
01:25:56,360 --> 01:25:58,080
Hyo-jin, wait!

1241
01:25:58,800 --> 01:25:59,800
Hyo-jin!

1242
01:26:16,680 --> 01:26:19,480
Hurry! Hurry!

1243
01:27:52,280 --> 01:27:53,920
Hyo-jin
where are you?

1244
01:28:00,520 --> 01:28:02,080
I looked all over for you

1245
01:28:08,200 --> 01:28:09,840
You dropped this

1246
01:28:13,120 --> 01:28:14,920
Park Hyun-soo

1247
01:28:16,200 --> 01:28:17,320
I'm sorry

1248
01:28:21,360 --> 01:28:23,000
You're my agent, right?

1249
01:28:24,840 --> 01:28:26,320
I've found a nice girl

1250
01:28:28,280 --> 01:28:29,760
Introduce me to her

1251
01:28:36,360 --> 01:28:37,720
I'll find her
and set it up

1252
01:28:39,560 --> 01:28:40,720
I'll definitely set it up

1253
01:28:41,360 --> 01:28:43,000
before I resign

1254
01:28:49,120 --> 01:28:51,120
Kim Hyo-jin

1255
01:29:02,920 --> 01:29:07,280
Three sweet potato cakes
must mean you're very upset

1256
01:29:12,160 --> 01:29:14,640
Hyo-jin, which side
is the window on?

1257
01:29:19,720 --> 01:29:20,480
To my left

1258
01:29:21,960 --> 01:29:23,160
It's on my left, too

1259
01:29:43,160 --> 01:29:46,080
That was
the best event yet

1260
01:29:46,400 --> 01:29:48,520
An electric spark of love

1261
01:29:49,280 --> 01:29:51,840
Anyway, how many
couples got sparked?

1262
01:29:52,000 --> 01:29:53,800
700 couples
70 percent

1263
01:29:54,200 --> 01:29:55,760
- The best record yet
- 70 percent

1264
01:29:57,280 --> 01:29:58,520
We'll make
big news tomorrow

1265
01:29:59,080 --> 01:30:00,480
But it wasn't intentional

1266
01:30:00,680 --> 01:30:02,240
It was a definite accident

1267
01:30:03,080 --> 01:30:04,080
Grow up

1268
01:30:04,520 --> 01:30:05,400
Song-min!

1269
01:30:05,760 --> 01:30:08,880
don't you know that
love can't be predicted?

1270
01:30:15,760 --> 01:30:16,720
My ace

1271
01:30:21,680 --> 01:30:22,680
I'm taking off first

1272
01:30:22,960 --> 01:30:24,840
Where are you going?

1273
01:30:25,960 --> 01:30:29,200
Hey, I thought the boss
was in love with you

1274
01:30:29,400 --> 01:30:30,880
You're right

1275
01:30:32,040 --> 01:30:33,760
Grow up
Bye Bye

1276
01:30:35,600 --> 01:30:37,640
This sucks

1277
01:30:40,400 --> 01:30:44,040
If you get to know me
I'm really nothing special at all

1278
01:30:45,440 --> 01:30:48,240
My company's stocks
are rock bottom

1279
01:30:49,640 --> 01:30:50,720
We're in a lot of debt

1280
01:30:51,400 --> 01:30:52,800
and near bankruptcy

1281
01:30:54,480 --> 01:30:57,440
But you already
know my schools

1282
01:30:57,960 --> 01:30:59,640
My yearly salary

1283
01:30:59,960 --> 01:31:03,080
And even...

1284
01:31:03,200 --> 01:31:04,640
The number of spoons
in my home

1285
01:31:09,480 --> 01:31:10,280
Girls

1286
01:31:10,560 --> 01:31:12,000
That's the guy, huh?

1287
01:31:12,120 --> 01:31:14,120
Oh my goodness

1288
01:31:14,480 --> 01:31:16,000
That rotten girl
Hyo-jin

1289
01:31:18,560 --> 01:31:20,560
Oh no
they're holding hands!

1290
01:31:21,960 --> 01:31:24,160
Slice it off!
Slice it off!

1291
01:31:24,640 --> 01:31:26,720
It's like some ending
to a romantic comedy

1292
01:31:26,880 --> 01:31:29,560
It's not a romantic comedy
if they don't kiss

1293
01:31:29,680 --> 01:31:31,040
They're gonna do it!

1294
01:31:32,040 --> 01:31:34,880
I can't see
but I think they did!

1295
01:31:35,040 --> 01:31:36,960
Really?
They kissed already?

1296
01:31:37,000 --> 01:31:37,640
I don't know

1297
01:31:37,760 --> 01:31:39,400
I can' see

1298
01:31:39,480 --> 01:31:40,120
away!

1299
01:31:40,480 --> 01:31:43,760
But it's important

1300
01:31:43,760 --> 01:31:45,160
Anyway
it's a happy ending!

1301
01:31:46,040 --> 01:31:46,920
This movie is over

1302
01:31:47,720 --> 01:31:48,760
I'm hungry
Let's go eat

1303
01:31:49,000 --> 01:31:49,800
Oh yeah
remember that great place?

1304
01:31:49,920 --> 01:31:50,920
Excuse me

1305
01:31:51,040 --> 01:31:51,640
Where is that?

1306
01:31:51,720 --> 01:31:52,280
delicious?

1307
01:31:52,520 --> 01:31:53,280
I'm over this way

1308
01:31:53,560 --> 01:31:55,360
If you have some time

1309
01:31:55,480 --> 01:31:58,000
It would be nice
if we could have a drink

1310
01:31:58,600 --> 01:32:00,840
I'll treat you
to a great time

1311
01:32:02,440 --> 01:32:18,440
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org

