Keung!
Uncle!
I didn't think you were
picking me up!
- Look at you!
- Uh oh!
How is your English?
My English is okay for simple things.
- Is Amy's English good?
- Yes
I was hoping you two could
take care of the supermarket.
I know people who can
help you immigrate here.
Like you and my father
running the supermarket
for over 20 years? No thanks!
I like Hong Kong.
To be honest, if you say no, I will sell it.
(Keung)
You're my uncle,
I'll let you decide.
(Uncle Bill)
Aren't you tired of being a cop?
(Keung)
Cops deal with new things
everyday. It's exciting.
(Uncle Bill)
Are you still a cop?
(Keung)
I'm a Leutenant now.
Very good.
(Keung)
So, is my uncle's fiancé beautiful?
(Uncle Bill)
Well, she's different. And beauty
is in the eye of the beholder.
(Uncle Bill)
I can't wait for you to meet her.
Wow, Uncle Bill, this
place is really beautiful!
(Uncle Bill)
This area is of course beautiful.
(Keung)
Is your supermarket in this area?
(Uncle Bill)
If it were here, I would have it made!
Our supermarket is in the Bronx.
(Police)
Hey stop!
He went that way!
Stop!
Wow, Uncle Bill, this looks
like a really tough area.
You'll get used to it after
you live here for awhile.
It's important to mind your
own business in New York.
Honey I'm home!
She must be at the market.
Uncle, your place is huge!
It's more than 3,000 square feet.
If I had a place like this in Hong Kong
I wouldn't have to work anymore.
You've never seen these pictures before.
The supermarket in the old days.
Your father was the lion,
and I was the Joker.
Your father was a good
fighter back in the day.
But his kung fu was no match
for the robber who shot him
when he tried to retrieve
a lady's stolen purse.
Let bygones be bygones.
I'll wash my face and
take you to see the market.
And you can meet your aunt-to-be.
Hey Uncle, you still practice with this?
No way. If your father hadn't made it
I'd have thrown it away a long time ago!
You still practice?
Just sometimes.
Cool trick!
My nephew, call him Keung.
Keung, your kung fu is
really good, Number 1.
Keung's kung fu is good of course.
Danny is my next-door neighbor.
Don't you have to be in school?
I'm on my way.
- Let's help him downstairs.
- OK.
Study hard.
Let's go.
This is for you.
Don't play with it in class.
- What was that?
- I gave him my old video game.
That poor kid.
He has only one sister,
and she neglects him.
You see? Here we are. It's so close.
This place is the result of more than 10 years
of hard work by your father and me.
Are you drawing a cartoon?
Uncle Bill, why are you painting
this place if you're selling it?
Fresh paint makes it look
better. I can impress the buyer.
How come they haven't
painted this side yet?
You go inside, I'll look around.
Can I help you?
I'm Keung.
I'm Uncle Bill's nephew.
Ah, you just arrived?
Yes, I did.
Here's a litle gift for my aunt-to-be.
Not everyone here is your new aunt.
She is Mrs Cheung, here
to arrange the wedding.
Sorry.
Are you surprised to see
your aunt to be is black?
Yes, a little bit.
Soon, the yellow, black, and
white people will be one.
They will only be known
as the people of the earth.
Wah, I'll be there in a minute.
- Go and help your aunt
- OK.
- Uncle Bill
- Hi, Wah.
I've brought you a buyer.
Elaine
She's the one I told you who is very
interested in buying the market.
Feel free to look around.
OK.
My shop is the only one
in these seven/eight blocks.
We have a lot of regular customers.
That makes for great business!
Business is even better during the summer.
Right.
- Elaine, please come in and sit down.
- OK.
Please sit down.
Would you like something to drink?
Oh, I'm fine, thank you.
Ah, we can look outside through this mirror!
The boss has to keep an eye
on everything. Right Uncle Bill?
All the information is here.
One has to work hard to make
money in a foreign country.
I spent twenty years of my life on this shop.
Why are you selling the market
if you are doing so well?
Uncle Bill doesn't want to sell it.
But his future wife wants to
buy a farm for raising horses.
Race horses, you know?
Uncle Bill, can you bring
down the price a little?
I've been honest with you. Last year
I turned down an offer of $220,000.
I want to be nice to you.
My final offer is $220,000.
You must be happy with that price?
Are you?
Not really.
I would have to pay the
legal fees and everything.
They would add up to
2 million Hong Kong dollars.
What is two million HK dollars?
That's only enough to buy
a parking space in Hong Kong.
Right.
What?
You don't believe me?
No, I believe you.
But what to do with existing employees?
You can keep them. They are very reliable.
If you buy this shop, you are the boss.
If you don't want them,
you can dismiss them.
No, I think they're very hard-working.
Their salaries are low.
I will think about it.
Can you sign here to certify
I've come with a client?
What is it?
Uncle Bill
This is my nephew, Keung.
You just got here?
He is Wah.
Uncle Bill, somebody named
Stephen Lo just sent a car over.
Yes, tell him to wait for me.
You can sign them for me.
Just a routine procedure.
OK, no problem.
I've stocked up a lot of goods.
I've got everything here.
This is the store room. People can live.
Feel free to go up and have a look.
Yes, it is very convenient.
Good fortune to you.
And to you also.
Old customers. They have credits with me.
Their business alone is enough
to keep the store running.
Let me show you around. Come.
You can see the graffiti all around.
But our place is a lot cleaner.
Everybody respects my
store because of its history.
Take your time to think about it.
Make sure you come to my wedding
This is my only first marriage.
I definitely will.
You must come.
We'd better go.
- OK
- OK. Bye bye.
Oh Stephen, come here!
Wow, this car is beautiful!
Yes, it's an antique.
I told my boss that I took
the car to get a check-up.
You'd better be careful with it!
Don't worry. I rely on
it to pick up my bride.
It means more to me than you.
This is my nephew, Keung. Stephen.
Yes, we just met.
This is a little something for you. Take it.
Oh, that's not necessary.
Please take it. It'll bring luck.
Thanks.
Don't scrape the car.
Don't worry. I'll sleep with it tonight.
Uncle, your friend's car!
Uncle, get up!
Stop!
Uncle!
Uncle, open the door!
Uncle Bill!
It's freezing!
Can I get you something to drink?
I've got it.
My name is Keung.
I heard the other day.
You are macho Keung. Come, sit down.
Thank you.
I heard you wanted to buy the
supermarket. Have you decided?
You're talking business now?
No, I was just looking for
something to talk about.
But you sit next to me?
You are the one I know best,
other than my uncle & aunt.
Yes, same here.
Do you think Uncle Bill will cut the price?
If you are serious about it,
We can lower the price a little.
Can you make that decision?
Half of the supermarket belongs to me.
Thanks for coming!
Uncle Bill, congratulations to us?
To us?
Yes, I want to buy your store.
Really?
Keung said he'd give me a good deal.
Keung, you are great to
fix the deal so quickly!
Should I first pay the deposit?
No need. Let's get it done quickly.
- We can even skip to the lawyer's fee.
- Good!
Uncle Bill, Uncle Bill, the
bride is waiting. Hurry up!
It's a deal. I won't sell it to anyone else.
Take care of the guests for me.
You go ahead and do your thing.
You buy it because I give
you a small discount?
I was going to buy it anyway. But
it's even better with the discount.
Good luck then.
I'll be there in a minute.
Ah-Keung, I have the stamped contract
Remember to give it to Elaine.
Take the money on the table.
I'll be back in a week.
The whole house is yours.
Ah-Keung, you're great!
Uncle Bill, I'm ready.
(Uncle Bill)
It's OK. We're leaving now!
I have already signed this.
Thanks.
- The check.
- Thanks.
Sign on the red one.
OK.
Would you give me a 20% discount card?
What? Mine is only a small business.
And what's the use of giving
you one? Aren't you leaving soon.
And, when are you leaving?
Uncle Bill said he would go back to Hong Kong with me after the honeymoon.
Will you come back?
Wait...
He has already stolen a lot of chocolate.
This is a tell-tale mirror!
Don't worry.
Let me settle the score with them.
(man in Cantonese)
What's going on?
Thank goodness you speak Cantonese.
This guy wouldn't pay for his drinks.
He stole some things, and is making a scene.
You say we're stealing?!
Thieves?
Robbers?
Shoplifting bastard.
Ah-Keung!
Stealing? Bullying women?
Apologize to her!
I'm sorry.
I should say sorry instead.
My arm!
Don't show up here anymore,
or I'll beat you up each time.
Watch your step.
Thank you. Thank you.
Are you OK? Did they hurt you?
No.
Ah-Keung...
Were you hurt?
How did you some of that? It was like...
(imitates martial arts noises)
That's Chinese kung-fu.
With Chinese kung fu,
remain calm while attacking.
See if your opponent is unprepared. Then strike! But you have to act quickly.
Aim for the sweet spot of their guard.
Hit there while covering here.
Everyone has a weakness.
Translate for them. I'll clean up.
I'll tell you when I find out.
Need some help?
I have to do this myself. I
can't rely on you always.
Thanks.
It's okay, calm down.
I can't get down!
Of course you can, if you let go.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I should get an electric one.
That would be easier.
Go inside, I'll do it.
Hey, wait!
Your groceries.
Here you go.
- I'll put the contract in the bag.
- Thanks
Oh, I forgot to pay.
Don't worry about it. It's
your payment for protection.
Wow, then I should take more.
Then I'll charge you.
Hurry, lock it.
This needs a new spring. Bye-Bye.
I was attacked.
How old is your sister?
Where is she?
What are you looking for?
My uncle will kill me.
Where you going?
What happened?
Two kids stole something this morning.
Ben tried, but couldn't catch them.
What happened to you?
Uh, I fell last night.
I apologize. I lost your contract.
If both contracts of the
sellerand buyer are lost
Can the deal be cancelled?
Why?
This whole thing was a fraud!
Not tell me that people come and steal.
And someone came this morning
to get their "protection money".
I told him I didn't have it. He said
he'll come back this afternoon for it.
Ben told me that you always
paid this money before.
Why didn't you tell me this
before you sold it to me?!
Look at the walls. They're
already filled with graffiti.
Looks worse than your face!
Good fortune to you!
Stop!
Remember, these people are bullies.
You must act tough with them.
It's them from yesterday!
Where is he? Is he too
scared to show up? Tell us!
- I don't know. He doesn't...
- Hold it, hold it.
Do what you want!
She said "no probrem".
You made the right choice.
Don't provoke them any further!
Shut up bitch!
Don't!
What?!
Are you okay?
Some robbers came, but
the cops have them now.
Oh, you're so heavy.
It's alright now.
Is your sister home?
Probably not.
I see.
Let me get your wheelchair.
Ah-Keung, come, come!
What is it?
Come! Ah-Keung, come, come on!
There!
You home?
- Keung, come bring my wheelchair.
- OK.
Your sister's never home. What does she do?
I thought you said she was still in school.
She has all kinds of jobs.
Wow, so she works hard to support you.
That means she loves you very much.
So just be a good brother to her.
Listen to her, and study hard.
It's not your fault.
Even if you legs don't work,
you can still do stuff, right?
It's probably okay.
I have a girlfriend.
Break up with her!
Why do you want me
to date your sister?
I'm sure she has many boyfriends
who will take care of her.
It's OK. Let's forget about the past.
Oh, one night she called the cops
when there was a thief in the building.
Let's try your new cushion.
Come.
Good fortune to you, girl.
Don't!
Our supermarket has a good reputation.
Our suppliers include every big company.
We're the only supermarket carrying
these items within seven/eight blocks.
And we have many regular customers.
And their business alone can
keep the supermarket going.
I live upstairs. Feel free to look around.
- OK, OK.
- This way
Why sell such a thriving business?
My boyfriend in Hong Kong
wants to get married.
I don't actually want to sell it.
How's the law & order in this area?
Does anyone demand protection money?
Protection fees? This is a foreign
society, no one demands protection fees.
What's the price?
Someone offered me $300,000.
But I refused the offer.
But I like you guys. So I'll
sell it to you for that price.
$300,000?
You can't buy a parking space in
Hong Kong for that kind of money.
That's true.
We have a small warehouse.
I'll show you.
- Good, good.
- OK.
I only sold it to you for $220,000.
I lost so much on renovations and repairs.
I hope you will succeed. Then
give me back the money.
Keung!
Ah, Mr. Wah.
I took some goods earlier,
and I came here to pay.
Have a nice day! Bye-bye.
Wow, so much graffiti everywhere!
Yes, it's everywhere.
Yes, on all the buildings. Except
ours, because everyone respects us!
We'll think about it.
You work as a dancer?
Aren't you scared of the tiger?
Do you like this job?
What's wrong?
Nothing. You dance very well.
(Keung)
Don't hang around those guys,
and spend more time wtih Danny.
He needs your care.
Don't let the situation change
you. You have to change it.
What would you like?
Is Danny home?
I've never trusted men.
I thought you were different.
What happened?
The store was destroyed!
You ran off with their girl!
You even told them that
you're the boss of the store!
What are you trying to do to me?!
Elaine!
What's going on?
Sorry.
I'm the one who should say sorry.
I lost my control just now.
I shouldn't blame you.
I should have known
That a decent store sold at a
low price would have problems.
You said you were the
boss to protect me.
I don't blame you.
I'm grateful for your help.
It's not your fault.
It's mine.
I shouldn't be so greedy.
I thought I was getting a good deal.
I should have just paid the protection fee.
And turned a blind eye to people stealing.
And everything would be okay.
However...
I thought you would protect me.
I don't care if you want to listen.
Do you think you can always gang up?
Go around, beating people, stealing things, extoring people for the rest of your lives?
Your so-called "home"
is just like garbage!
Why do you have to be
the scum of society?
I hope next time when we meet
we wont' be fighting each other.
Instead we will be
drinking tea together.
Danny, are you okay?
Here, catch!
They're very different. The
big one alone is worth a house.
Wow.
Did they answer?
Go to school and wait for me.
Is the quality okay?
Hey! Ah-Keung...
Do you like it? The new
renovations are beautiful!
I thought about it. Uncle Bill
was doing some things right.
I'll pay the protection fees. There
are thefts in ever supermarket.
We open again tomorrow.
- Very beautiful.
- What's wrong? Stomach ache?
Can we go somewhere quiet?
Why a quiet place?
Look...
Wow, glass doesn't shine like that.
Are these real?
They're definitely real, stolen!
Come on, let's go.
What should I do?
Why should I care after
what they did to the store?
I'll take two or three
stones as compensation.
Please don't. Peoples' lives are at stake here.
If it's so serious, why not call the police?
If I call the police, there'll be more
trouble. I don't know what to do.
They won't notice if I took few pieces.
What's wrong?
He said to come to the supermarket.
Ah, he knows about my new renovations.
That's why he told you to come.
Don't worry. He's just trying to scare you.
- Where are you going?
- Bathroom.
You don't need diamonds in the bathroom.
Come on, I'm not joking.
Supermarket?
Elaine, open up!
Why?
Come here, quick!
I'm busy!
Hey, Elaine, are you OK?
No! No! I'm ruined, I have nothing!
Don't be like this. I can see you.
So what? You can see me,
everyone can see me!
I don't care anymore!
Don't worry, I'll fix it the damages.
You asshole! It's all your fault!
You're trying to ruin me!
Haven't you done enough to me?!
What do you want from me?!
- I don't want anything!
- Do you want me to die?
- You're killing me!
- Calm down, please!
Oh, the phone.
Quiet, I have to figure out
a way to save my friends.
Save me first!
I'll give you a diamond, okay?
You'll give them all to me?
No, only one. I need the rest.
Just one...?
I'll give you the biggest one.
You promised! Protect it!
I'll call the cops, they can help.
What are you doing?
Looking for diamonds!
Father watch over me.
Are you sure?
Leave it to me.
Get him! Over there!
Look at that! Great!