We shall not cease from exploration
And the end of all our exploring
Will be to arrive where we started
And know the place for the first time.
T.S. Eliot
After the game is before the game.
S. Herberger
Man...
... probably the most mysterlous
specles on our planet.
A mystery of unanswered questlons...
Who are we? Where do we come from?
Where are we golng? How do we
know. What we thlnk we know?
Why do we belleve anythlng at all?
Countless questlons
In search of an answer.
An answer that wlll glve
rlse to a new questlon...
... and the next answer wlll glve
rlse to the next questlon and so on...
... and so on.
But, In the end, Isn 't It
always the same questlon?
And always the same answer?
The ball is round.
The game lasts 90 minutes.
That's a fact. Everything
else is pure theory.
Here we go!
RUN LOLA RUN
- Manni?
- Lola?
What's up? Where are you?
Where were you, damn it?
I got there too late.
But why today?
You're always on time! Always!
My moped got ripped off.
It doesn't matter.
Yes, it matters!
What's wrong?
It wasn 't my fault, Mannl.
I went to get some clgarettes.
I can 't belleve how fast the guy was.
There was nothlng I could do.
He was gone before I got outslde.
I even took a taxl.
That dumb-ass drove east. They've
got a Grunewald St. There too.
When I notlced, It was too late.
I was so screwed up because
of our moped, I dldn 't reallze.
- Doesn 't matter. - And when
I got there, you were gone.
- It doesn 't matter now.
I'm done for. - But why?
Help me, Lola! I don't know what to do.
You weren't there, and I messed
it up. I blew it. I'm such a jerk!
Just calm down. Now, what happened?
Just tell me what happened, okay?
Lola, he's gonna kill me. I'm gonna die.
Stop it! You're scaring me. What's up?
- Dld you get caught? - No, but
that would have been somethlng.
Everythlng went really great. We drove
the cars there, and those guys came.
They pald and that was lt. Easy as ple.
I got waved across the border...
... and then theydropped me off out there.
I went to see that cyclops,
and he was flnlshed In no tlme.
And everythlng was on tlme,
ex cept for you.
You woeroe n't t hnoeroe
- Then what?
- Nothing. Not even a phone booth.
I couldn 't even call a taxl,
so I walked to the subway statlon
On the traln, there was thls bum...
... who somehow fell down. Suddenly,
these Inspectors showed up.
And I got out llke always.
An old reflex.
The bag!
I'm such a fucking amateur!
A dumb-ass!
Thls could only happen to me! If you'd
plcked me up, It wouldn 't have happened.
I was so out of lt.
You're always on tlme!
- Dldn 't you call the next statlon? - Sure.
But It was too late. The
fucklng bag was already gone.
And that bum has lt.
That plastlc-bag freak!
He 's on a plane to Florlda or Hawall...
... or Canada or Hong
Kongor Bermuda or whatever.
What about Ronnle?
- He 'll klll me. - You gotta tell hlm.
Forget lt!
- Why? - He won't believe a single word!
I kept a carton of clgarettes
once. He notlced rlght away.
He doesn 't belleve anybody.
The job with those Mercedes
was a kind of test.
To see if he could trust me. Shit.
How much was there in the bag?
- 100.000
- What?
100.000. A test.
Shit.
See! I knew you wouldn 't come up
wlth any Ideas. I always sald...
...someday you wouldn't know what
to do. Not when you die. Sooner!
You said, ''Love can do everything.''
So find 100.000 marks in 20 minutes!
At 12 by the water tower around
the corner, Ronnie said. In 20 minutes.
Run away, Manni!
- No.
- Why not?
Nobody escapes Ronnie.
I'll go with you.
When Ronnie gets here in 20 minutes
I'll be a goner.
- Stop it, Manni!
- What for?
You can't get me 100 grand either!
He'll rub me out, and all that's
left of me will be 100.000 ashes...
...floating down the Spree to the sea.
No more Manni! You can't do a thing!
Shut up!
Listen.
Wait for me. I'll help you. Stay put,
I'll be there in 20 minutes.
- Okay?
- You gonna pawn all your jewelry?
Where are you?
In a phone booth downtown
in front of the Spiral Bar.
Okay, stay where you are.
I'll come up withsomething.
In 20 minutes, okay?
What the hell. I'll go over to
Bolleand get that 100 grand.
C ut it out!
Ronnie said they make 200 grand a day
so they must have 100 grand by noon.
You're nuts! Don 't do a thlng!
Just stay In that damned booth!
- That's it. I'll rob the store.
- Have you lost it?
Don't do a thing! Stay put, I'm coming!
Then what?
I'll think of something!
In 20 minutes I'll be dead
unless I steal the money!
- No, wait!
- What for?
I'll get the money somehow.
I'm going there at 12
if you aren't here.
Okay. Who?
Who?
Dad!
Lola, are you going shopping?
I need shampoo!
Of course, I knew that
Sagittariuswas your ascendant.
Sure, the more I think about it.
I don't know.
Yes, but you're married too.
Watch where you're going!
Bitch!
It's worst at night.
I wake up and can't fall asleep again.
And then I'm afraid.
Me! Afraid of the dark!
I've never been afraid of the dark.
I've never even been afraid before.
But I think about us...
...and I just think
it'll keep going on like this.
That you wouldn't dare...
And then I ask myself
what I'm doing here.
How long will this go on?
The secrecy, all this damned lying?
Should I grow old, waiting for a man
who won't stand by me?
Hey, you need a bike?
50 marks, as good as new.
No!
AND THEN
Hey man! I know that!
It's not my fault it's so much money!
500? What am I supposed to do
with 500 marks?
Thanks.
Your phone card!
I have to go. Meyer will be
here in a minute.
Ca n we nm eet ate r on?
- Do you love me?
- What?
Do you love me?
Why are you asking me now?
Yes, damn it!
Then decide.
Not now.
You have to decide sometime.
But why now, here, at once?
Because I'm pregnant.
Look who's here!
Our little princess, Lola!
What a rare pleasure.
- Why the rush?
- Please, let me in.
Little Miss wants to see Big Daddy?
Sure thing.
Sorry.
AND THEN
Tell me, do you want to
have a baby with me?
Yes.
Lola?
Dad.
Your daughter?
I'm Jutta Hansen
from the board of directors.
- Sorry to interrupt. It's urgent.
- It's okay. I was just about to...
What are you doing here?
Nothing.
Listen...
...if I told you I needed your help...
...more than I ever have before and
you're the only one who can help me...
...would you help me?
- You look terrible.
- Would you help me?
- What happened?
I can't explain now.
Would you help me?
With what, damn it?!
I need 100.000 marks immediately.
What?
I need it within
the next five minutes or else...
- Or else what?
- Something terrible will happen!
I don't understand.
What's going on here today?
Please, Dad! You've got to help me! Please!
- I don't have 100.000 marks.
- What about my life insurance?
What about it?
It isn't worth 100.000
Please, Dad, I'm serious.
This isn't a joke!
Yes, it is, Lola!
You can't be serious!
- If you don't help me, he'll die!
- Who'll die?
- Manni!
- Manni? Who's Manni?
My boyfriend, for over a year!
I don't even know him.
Why will he die?
It doesn't matter!
Okay. Come with me.
- You're going to help me?
- Of course.
Go home and go to bed.
And tell your mother I won't be
home today or tomorrow or ever again.
I'm leaving you guys
and I'm marrying another woman.
We're going to have kids. I'll try to be
happy because she only wants me.
I'm so sick of hearing
''All you do is work.''
''You always play the boss!''
Maybe I do, but so what!
You guys have no idea!
I'm so tired of being
blamed for everything!
Sure, Daddy's money is good enough
right? Well, not anymore!
Not anymore.
Besides, I'd never have
fathered a freak like you.
- But you did, you jerk!
- No, I didn't!
You're not mine.
Now you know.
The guy who sired you left
before you were even born.
Throw her out, please.
Conm e on! Get h e r out of h e re!
Well, we all have our bad days.
See you around.
My dear.
What's wrong?
Do you have the time?
This afternoon?
All right.
No, forget it. It's okay.
Yeah.
Walt!
Don 't do lt!
Mannl, please!
Walt!
Walt for me!
I'll be rlght there.
Please.
Mannl, please...
... walt!
Lie down on the floor. On the floor!
Lie down on the floor.
Hands behind your head, and keep quiet!
Open the registers!
Open all the cash registers!
Open them!
Open them, and lie down!
I'll shoot anyone who bugs me!
Lola, where were you?
I couldn't get here faster.
Will you help me?
Can't we just get out of here?
Not anymore. You see the shit I'm in.
Why didn't you wait for me?
I did. You got here too late.
So, are you with me?
Put your hands up! Hurry up!
Conm e on!
Drop your gun!
Hurry up!
Don't move.
The safety is on.
- How does it work?
- The little lever on the side.
Kid, you don't know how to use...
Don't move.
Conm e h e re
Cover me. I'll grab the cash.
Hurry, before the cops come.
Don't move!
Do you love me?
Sure, I do.
How can you be sure?
I don't know. I just am.
I could be some other girl.
Why not?
- Because you're the best.
- The best what?
The best girl.
In the whole world?
Sure.
How do you know?
I just know.
You think so.
Okay, I think so.
- You see?
- What?
You aren't sure.
Are you nuts, or what?
What if you never met me?
What do you mean?
You'd be saying the same
thing to someone else.
- Okay, if you don't want to hear it...
- I don't want to hear anything.
I want to know how you feel.
Okay.
My feelings say...
...you're the best.
Your feelings?
Who is ''your feelings'' anyway?
It's me.
My heart.
Your heart says
'' Hi, Manni. She's the one. ''
Exactly.
And you say, '' Thanks for the info.
Talk to you soon. ''
Exactly.
And you do whatever your heart says?
Well, it doesn't really ''say'' anything.
I don't know...
...it just feels.
So what does it feel now?
That someone's asking
rather stupid questions.
You aren't taking me seriously.
Lola, what's wrong?
Do you want to...
...leave me?
I don't know.
I think I have to make a decision.
But I don't want to...
I don't want to leave.
Stop!
Lola, are you going shopping?
I need shampoo.
Of course, I knew that
Sagittariuswas your ascendant.
Sure, the more I think about it.
I don't know.
Yes, but you're married too.
Excuse me!
Watch it, you stupid cow!
Fucking bitch!
AND THEN
Hey, you need a bike?
No.
- 50 marks, as good as new.
- But it's stolen!
500? What am I supposed to do
with 500 marks?
Tell me, do you want to
have a baby with me?
Yes.
Even if it isn't yours?
Look who's here! Lola, our...
I'm in a hurry, please!
Please let me in!
Courtesy and composureare
the queen's jewels.
Let me in, please.
A little anger is good for the heart...
...the circulation, the skin.
What kind of love is that?!
- If you hadn't neglected me...
- I have a family!
I can't leave a sick wife and three
kids just to please her highness.
Your wife is drunk
from morning to night!
So what!
What do you know?
Can't you see you're interrupting?
Hi, Dad.
Why didn't you knock?
What's going on?
What do you want?
Is she your daughter?
Shut the door.
What do you want?
I need your help.
- You see that I'm busy.
- There's no other way.
Damn it! Why did you
have to show up here now?!
I have a problem.
Do you understand?
Who's that slut?
That's none of your business!
Lola, leave.
Go home.
Leave me alone.
I can't!
Why not?
I need money.
Then get a job.
I will, but I need the money now!
Okay, just so you get out of here.
How much?
No, I need lots more.
What do you mean, ''lots more''?
A whole lot more!
Aren't you ashamed barging in like
this? Can't you see we're busy?
I don't give a shit, you stupid cow!
I have other problems.
Don't you dare...
What?
What's going on?
It just isn't your day today.
Doesn't matter.
You can't have everything.
You're coming with me.
Have you lost your mind?
- You think you can do anything you like?
- Shut up! You go first.
Kid...
...you don't know how to
use that thing.
Let me make a suggestion.
Stay back.
- Listen, we can talk this over.
- Fuck off!
AND THEN
Shit!
The combination.
Quiet!
What the heck are you doing?
Lola, there are cameras everywhere.
You'll never get out of here.
The police will be here in a second.
You said they always come too late.
Bag it. 100.000
Come on, kid.
Leave your daddy alone.
You don't want to
hurt anyone, do you?
I don't know.
- I don't have it.
- Why not?
There's only 88.000
I'll have to get the
rest from downstairs.
Okay, get going!
Go, go!
Hurry up, man!
100.000
In there.
Bye, Dad.
I don't believe it.
You want to get killed, kid?
Attention! This is the police!
The building is surrounded.
Come out with your hands up.
What a ruckus!
Do you have the time?
Get out of the way!
Give me a lift, will you?
- Are you nuts?
- Wait!
Walt, Mannl! I'm comlng.
I'm almost there...
Walt!
I'm gonna make lt!
What would you do if I died?
- I wouldn't let you die.
- Yeah, but...
...what if I were fatally ill?
- I'd find a way.
- What if I were in a coma...
...and the doctor said
''One more day''?
I'd throw you into the ocean.
Shock therapy.
Okay, but what if I died anyway?
- What do you want to hear?
- Come on, tell me.
I'd go to the isle of Rügen
and cast your ashes to the wind.
And then?
I don't know. It's a stupid question.
I know what you'd do.
- You'd forget me.
- No!
Sure, you would.
What else could you do?
Sure, you'd mourn for a few weeks.
It wouldn't be so bad.
Everybody's real compassionate.
And everything's so incredibly sad,
and everyone feels sorry for you.
You can show everyonehow strong you are.
''What a great woman, '' they'll say.
''She's pulling herself together
instead of crying all day. ''
And suddenly, this really nice
guy with green eyes shows up.
And he's super sensitive
and listens to you all day.
And you can talk his ear off.
And you can tell him how tough
things are for you...
...that you have to look after yourself
and you don't know what'll happen...
Then you'd hop onto his lap and cross me
off your list. That's how it goes.
What?
You're not dead yet.
No?
Lola, are you going shopping?
I need shampoo.
Of course, I knew that
Sagittariuswas your ascendant.
Sure, the more I think about it.
I don't know.
Yes, but you're married too.
AND THEN
- Watch out!
- Sorry.
I bet you're sorry!
Fries and a sausage.
Give me another one.
I'll be damned.
Life's really crazy
sometimes isn't it?
Come on, kid.
I'll buy you a drink.
You need a bike?
A special price. 70 marks.
Mr. Meyer?
Is everything okay?
Tell me, do you want to
have a baby with me?
Yes.
Mr. Meyer Is here.
- There's something else.
- Not now.
Mr. Meyer asked If he should
parkor If you're comlng out?
I'm coming.
This is the nicest present
you could give me.
I'll see you later?
Hi there.
- Hi there, Ms. Jäger.
- Hello.
- Nice to see you.
- Hello, Mr. Meyer.
Wait!
You know what?
I just had a strange encounter.
Yes, with your daughter!
- With whom?
- Your daughter.
Shit! Shit!
You've come at last, dear.
Thanks.
Wait.
So I decided, it'd be best
for me not to have kids.
I work so muchthat
they'd never see me.
Watch out!
What can I do?
Come on.
Help me.
Please.
Just thls once.
I'll just keep runnlng, okay?
I'm waltlng.
You wanna get killed?
- How does this work?
- You buy chips...
...and gamble them away.
You can't go in there like that.
I have to.
99 marks 20. What kind of chips?
One for 100.
You're short.
Please.
Place your bets, please.
Your bets, please.
No more bets.
Twenty, black, even, pass.
No series.
1.500 on black.
100 and 400.
3.500 for 100 marks on 20.
Here you are. 3.500.
Come with me, please.
Just one more game
Please place your bets.
Twenty, black, even, pass.
Please hurry.
I need a plastic bag.
Stop!
That's mine!
I know!
I'm sorry.
What about me?
At least give me that.
What're you doing here?
I'll stay with him.
What happened to you?
Did you run here?
Don't worry. Everything's okay.
Come on.
What's in the bag?