British Airways flight 297 from London
now arriving at gate 12.
Hi.
Rooms are at 39 bucks
day rate, 29 bucks overnight.
- Well, it's cheaper to stay overnight.
- Damn right!
Days are for sex.
Sex costs money.
- Want a room or not?
- Yes for a week, please.
That will be 203 bucks in advance.
It will be unit 13.
Check-out at noon
Thursday night.
No, I'm fine.
Thank you.
What's up, man!
Come here!
Open Gate 6!
- Are you alright?
- Yeah.
Glad you could make it, bro.
What the fuck did you go to Chicago, anyway?
Are there not trade back home?
Their expensive lake views
and corn fed American pussies, why ask?
Jesus. Are you on the streets
long enough again?
Okay I'm here, Reese.
You said you make it worth my while.
Listen.
Somebody is a dog track.
And they think it was me.
- But you are innocent.
- Of course I am.
The bad guys wore masks.
Plus, one of them got
accidentally killed by the cops.
The car is getting north bound
in Lower Wacker  and Van Buren.
I see it.
- Goddamnit!
- Shut fuck up.
What the fuck happened, Reese?
Fucking crooked cops getting on duty!
That's what fucking happened.
Bastards!
Get out!
Get the fuck out!
He's got a gun!
Drop the gun!
You in the truck,
let me see your hands!
Put them up!
Let me see your hands!
Get in the car.
No witnesses, no money,
no conviction, right?
How much did they get?
- These bad guys?
- At least half a million.
Maybe more.
Okay, I'm interested.
Where?
I had to toss it.
- Where?
- Dan Ryan expressway.
Asshole!
Reese, what the fuck are you doing?
Our money!
Shut the fuck up, will you?
Do you think it's still there?
- It's not there.
- Then where is it?
Well, it landed on this guy's car,
you know. A white-do.
- Okay, what kind of car?
- An old car.
Old station wagon.
Wood on the sides, you know?
Yeah, wood on the sides.
Shit!
Fucking piss!
Son of a bitch!
Why me?
Ten zillion fucking cars in goddamn
Chicago and this motherfucker ass...
Jesus Christ.
You want to shower first?
No, you go ahead.
Okay.
Don't be down, Sam.
It will all work out.
You want me to pick you up at work?
No, I'll meet with you.
The walk will do me good.
- See you later, then?
- Yeah.
Damn!
What the hell are you doing, man?
Jesus Christ, Reese!
Are you fucking crazy?
Fucking keep it down!
In Chicago, Reese.
The car capital of the northern USA
and you expect me to find one fucking car.
- Forget it, your boy got lucky.
- Listen to me.
This barney came into his
lock only two days ago.
The trail is still hot to
the street or snatch.
He'll use cash and that's what set him
apart from the other worker and folks.
First thing he'll do is buy
a new car , cash...
and that's how you get him.
Now split is 50-50.
Are you in or out?
I'm here, aren't I?
I'll give my best shot.
- You're the sales manager?
- Yeah, that's me.
Can you help me?
I'm sure as hell try.
If somebody comes in here
and buys a car for cash...
what do you do?
Cream in my calvins.
What official things do you do?
Well, since there is no bank,
there's no loan application,
no insurance, papers to fill out
and no loan officer, see.
But the only thing we
do on a cash deal...
is to document the state tax
and licensing.
- How?
- It's a form.
Here.
But I gotta tell you
cash is rare.
Once, maybe two times a year
do I see a cash deal.
Is this document
method of payment?
Right there on that line, see?
You have to list the bank,
the finance company ...
or you stamp it "cash".
- And where do this go?
- Chicago DMB, Central Branch.
Thank, buddy.
Hey, you're welcome.
You rude fucking gumba.
I can't imagine why he's late,
Mr. Dale.
He knew we're meeting
at 10:30.
I believe this is the very nature
of our problem, Ms. Phelan.
Buying a house
is a major responsibility.
I do not think Mr. Phelan is facing his
commitment in a responsible manner.
You and your husband are 120
days behind in payments.
This constitutes serious careers
to an institution of this small size.
Mr. Dale, we know where we stand.
We've been unemployed.
We're both working now,
we'll catch up.
You're asking much of this institution
to reschedule your loan...
especially in view of
Mr. Phelan's tardiness...
both in legal payments
and today's appointment.
- Where have you been?
- I'll tell later.
Mr. Dale, our banker.
Let me guess.
You being the weany that you are,
you're not gonna
reschedule our payments.
Is that right?
What?
What did you say?
Under the circumstances,
I do not believe this institution ...
can accommodate you,
Mr. and Mrs. Phelan.
Stop, Sam, talk to him.
This is our house!
I'm afraid you have to pay
the full amount you owe
or Midwest Savings and Loan
will be force to finalize foreclosure proceedings.
Mr. Dale, please.
We have paid on that house...
every month on time for 5 years.
Doesn't that count for anything?
What exactly is the full amount?
With penalties and interest,
comes to $7603.12.
Okay.
Here.
1 thousand, 2 thousand, 3 thousand,
4 thousand, 5 thousand, 6 thousand, 7 thousand ...
and...
- One, two, three ...
- 12 cents.
Four, five, six.
You got four singles?
Four.
Yeah.
Thank you.
U.S. $ 7605.
Leslie, come on.
Wait, my sweater.
You owe me $1.88, bastard
and want it by noon tomorrow.
- Where did you get it ?
- Straight from heaven, baby.
No, really, Sam, where?
I was on the Dan Ryan
expressway, right.
And a police chase went by,
and it just crashed onto the hood of my car.
Did it dent the car?
Dented? Jesus, honey, forget that.
Come on.
Oh my God.
How much is there?
I don't know.
You wanna find out?
How much, how much?
Okay.
It comes to $618,127.
Wait, plus $7605 we give
that asshole Mr. Dale which makes...
- Did you see his face?
- Yeah.
I thought he was gonna pee in
his pants when you call him a weany.
How's it about when you
hit him up with $1.88?
- Bastard!
Okay.
Counting the $7605
we gave the bank totals...
$625,731.
My God!
We're rich.
Sam, we can't keep it.
- Yes we can.
- No. It's probably dirty money.
Yeah, of course it is.
It's cash.
I don't want some Colombian drug
lord kicking our door down.
Hey, nobody saw it, Les.
If I hadn't picked it up, it would've just
laid on the ground for somebody else to find.
It's free and clear money.
Nobody in this world knows we have it.
What it was robbed
from a bank or something?
So what?
Banks are insured.
Come on!
What are we gonna do?
You wanna play John Q dipshit
citizen and turn it over to Chicago PD?
Those crooks in blue, you know,
they'll just steal it for themselves anyway.
No, no, baby, no way.
This is our money.
Alright?
God sent it to me right out of the sky.
A million car hoods
in Chicago, this suitcase hit mine.
That's fate.
- They would be insured, right?
- Yeah, of course, they would.
Come on, this is our money, baby.
The mortgage is paid up.
You can have all the
stuff, you can finally buy.
New furniture, paint the house.
Well ..
Leslie, over $600,000.
Allows us to spend anything we want.
All our dreams come true, baby.
You're right!
My God!
- What first?
- Well, there's a pretty big dent in the car.
- New car!
- Yeah.
What will it be, man?
I'm looking for Zeke.
Wrong joint.
No Zeke here.
Come here.
Back there.
Thanks.
I was told I could buy tools.
I've got tools.
What's your preference?
Sears? Stanley?
Snap On?
I was thinking more on the lines of Ruger,
Smith & Wesson, you know?
Can I get me keys to the
Motor Vehicle Department?
That's two chairs,
dining room set...
sofa, big screen plasma TV.
What about a bed?
Bed, bed, bed ...
We definitely got to
have a bed, don't we?
Definitely.
Right this way.
This is perfect.
- Hi.
- Hey!
Okay, they'll deliver our stuff
tomorrow between 1 and 4.
Alright.
Give me that.
Very swanky.
Buick.
Kia, maybe.
Can I help you?
Yes, excuse me.
Is that your Toyota?
No, it's my wife's.
Why?
- Who is it Glenn?
- I don't know who the hell he is. Who the hell are you?
Excuse me.
Hey motherfucker!
What? You're driving around
you see a nice car...
- you wanna get in my face
and ask me one question?
- What?
It looked like to me
your casing the joint.
Get him, baby.
You better get the fuck out of this
neighborhood before I bust
a cop in your white boy ass.
Coz you don't want this.
He don't want this.
- He don't want this.
-  No, he don't want this.
Listen up,
Glenn the fucking plumber.
You blacks think y'all
so fucking bad.
Well, you aren't.
You think all white
people fear you.
We don't.
Now shut your fucking mouth...
or I'll put you in the
fucking emergency ward.
Got it?
Did you hear that accent?
Yeah, ain't no regular white boy.
- Come on, let's just go.
- Is he Spanish?
Hi.
Mr. Bearshit Tenderfeet?
No, no, no. Pronounce this way please ...
Bahadurjit Tejinderpreet.
I can helped you, please.
Yeah, helped me.
Nice Chevy over there.
Oh yeah, my Chevrolet.
Great American automobile.
I like it too much.
Chevrolet.
Big favorite for you, Arabs,
is it?
Arab?
That's bullshit!
I'm Sikh from India!
I don't make no 9/11.
I make 9/9! My beautiful store!
Mr. Melvin Goldberg?
Who wants to know?
- I'm from Bavarian Motor Works.
- The what?
BMW.
Bavarian Motor Works.
Your new car there.
Yeah, well.
So?
I'd like to ask you a couple
of questions, if you don't mind...
- About your new Beemer.
- No, thanks. Beat it.
My company is offering $100
for a simple 5-minute interview.
Yeah.
Come inside.
Yes!
So ...
How long have you had the car?
Eight days.
Do you like the BMW?
Hell, yes.
Don't everybody?
Even those goddamn Mercedes
fools are changing to BMW now.
Aren't you gonna write stuff down?
I've got a good memory.
How long, did you say,
you finance the car?
I didn't say.
Why the hell do you
wanna know that anyhow?
Just helps us to determine
buying trends and sort them out.
24 months.
It says you paid cash.
Exit!
Who the hell are you?
Get the fuck out of my house!
Sit down.
Fuck you!
Get the hell out
Or I'll throw your ass out.
The suitcase?
Where is the suitcase, Goldberg?
The money.
Where the fuck is it?
I'm sorry, mister.
I'll replace the cash, I promise.
So, it was you?
- Yeah?
- I did it.
But I'll put it back, honest to God.
What do you mean? You spent it all.
You spent half a million?
What?
- No, no ...
- Talk to me Jew motherfucker.
I work for Gen-Am.
I stole the money.
I admit it.
But I did, because they
are extorting the customers.
They're rip offs man.
They're chaining the public.
I'll pay it back though, honest.
Was your old car a station wagon?
No way!
You a cop?
If you're fucking lying,
I'll kill you...
and I'll kill you fucking slowly.
I traded a pickup
truck for that BMW.
A 1993 Ford F-150.
Call them, mister.
Yeah.
I stole the money,
but not with a suitcase.
I used a paper bag.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
Enjoy.
To the good life and the
fulfillment of our wildest dreams.
To my husband may
he ever be so lucky.
Sammy.
We should do that more often.
What got into us?
Cash.
Morning, Mr. Phelan.
Good morning, Mrs. Phelan.
Sleep well?
Yes, I did.
Ready for breakfast?
Yeah.
Breakfast too, huh?
Indeed.
Nothing is too good for
Mr. Lucky, Sam Phelan.
- Eat.
- I will.
I'm headed for the shower.
Hi
Mr. Sam Phelan?
Yeah, you're early we weren't
expecting you till noon.
I doubt you are
expecting me at all.
You're the Chunky Chicken
franchise rep, aren't you?
No.
Okay, I'm sorry.
I thought...
What can I do for you?
I'd like to talk to you about
your new Range Rover.
I'm from the factory.
Yeah, right.
- It's kind of bad timing.
- It will only take a minute.
Yeah, okay, come on in.
Just a minute though.
Sure.
Thank you.
Take a seat.
I was just about to make
a coffee if you want one.
No thanks.
Looking to invest?
Oh, yeah. My wife and I we want
to start our own business.
Yeah?
Recently consumed cash, did you?
Listen, mister, I don't
have a holding time here so...
Sorry.
So, were you enjoying the Range Rover?
What do you mean, how it handles?
Stuff like that?
It's great, we love it.
How does it compare
to your old car?
That's no comparison.
What was your old car?
It's a Buick station wagon.
Piece of crap.
Was it the one with
the wood on the sides?
You said you're from the factory.
What factory?
Hey, listen...
I think you better leave now.
This...
business you want...
you're looking to invest...
What? Half a million...
in cash?
Hey, listen, I'm actually expecting somebody,
So, I gotta, I gotta clean up...
and I'm gonna have
to ask you to go.
I'm not leaving, Sam.
What do you mean
you're not leaving?
Who the hell do you think you are?
I'll call the police.
Look, we don't smoke in this house.
You have something of mine.
I've never seen you before.
What are you doing?
Please!
You can't do that, alright?
Goddamn it!
Stop!
What is he doing?
Stop him!
No, no, no!
Don't, don't!
Okay...
Hang up the phone.
Go ahead, hang up.
Where is my money?
We have...
most of it, that is.
We spent some.
What are you talking about?
We don't have his money.
Save it, Leslie.
I know the truth.
How much did you spend?
- About $70,000, I think.
- Where's the rest?
Some's here and
some's in the bank.
- In the bank?
- Several banks, actually.
Avoiding the IRS, huh?
Smart.
Dangerous, though.
Funny how money
corrupts, isn't it?
Okay.
Here's what we gonna do.
Sam...
go get the rest of the cash
left here in the house, okay?
- Well...
- Do it now.
Leslie...
gather up receipts.
You and I, we'll talk about
exactly how much you spent.
You do keep receipts, don't you?
$625,731.
Not a bad hole.
Not a bad hole at all.
Okay.
It's noon.
Banks need time to gather
up large sums of cash...
So while Leslie is figuring
and I'm counting...
You're going to phone, Sam,
and call everyone of those banks ...
you put my money in...
and tell them you'll be down there today
to pick up that cash. You got it?
What is your total?
$74,316.47.
It's more than the $70,000
that you said, isn't it?
I guess I forgot about
some of the other stuff.
That's perfectly natural.
Everything looks so nice too.
That big-screen TV,
the Range Rover.
It looks really good.
Thank you.
So...
So, $625,761 gross...
minus the $ 74,316.47...
equals...
$551,414.53.
Correct.
$551,414.53...
is the figure we'll
concentrate on.
Gotta get all that house
stunning cash back, right?
Ready, Sam?
I only got through
to a couple of them.
That's okay, we can
call them on the way there.
Let's go visit those banks.
That's good.
Go on.
65, 66 ...
Great.
Next bank.
Well, that was fun, wasn't it?
Leslie...
Go and get your calculator.
Sit down.
Okay.
Subtract these figures
from our running total.
$54,557.
$13,660.
$83,000.
$15,236.
What's that leave?
$268,184.53.
Where's the rest?
We left some with my mother.
With Mommy.
Who could be safer
than Mommies?
You aren't being busy
little bees, are you?
Good job, I got here when I did.
How much?
$265,000.
We sure trust
Mommy, don't we?
So, U$265,000 subtracted
from our new balance of $268,184.53...
leaves $3184.53.
Where does that go?
Low as change, right?
That kind of money goes for candy,
cigarettes, that kind of stuff, right?
We don't smoke.
No?
That's too bad.
You don't mind if I smoke
in the house, do you?
Thank you very much.
Alright,
let's get back to business.
We will add this $3184.53
the  $74,316.47 deficit...
We'll already have less the money
you spent before I got here, right?
That comes to what?
$77,501.
It's been a long day.
I'm hungry.
Leslie, why don't you slip into the
kitchen and cook us up a nice meal?
That way, we don't have to go out anymore.
We'll all stay together.
Isn't that something nice?
Go on.
Very good, Leslie.
I liked it.
But what was it?
Eggplant, tofu
and veggie steaks.
Veggie steaks?
We don't eat red meat.
Why not? Scared to
get mad cow disease?
Alright.
I think I'll go and watch
a little big-screen TV.
Then we all better turn in. Gonna look
brighter now with your granny tomorrow.
You're sleeping with us?
Is that an invitation?
You know what I mean.
Yes, I know.
You can sleep on the couch.
Thanks.
What have you got us into?
- Me?
- Yes.
Now you point the finger.
That's funny. You didn't mind
spending it yesterday.
I'm calling the police.
Put the phone down.
Put the phone...
Give me that!
Stop it!
Give it to...!
Look, let's just weigh it out.
Okay, if we call the cops now, they'll
ask questions, lots of questions.
That'd be trouble and we'll
lose what little we have left.
Tomorrow he'll be gone, we still
have all the stuff we bought.
Those are pretty cool stuff.
It's not so bad.
No, that is what I was afraid of.
I wish you never found
that goddamn money.
Let's just go to sleep, okay?
- Hi, Mom.
- Hi, honey.
Mom, you know that carton
we left with you?
We need it back.
Honey, you said you needed
it kept safe. I hid it, dear.
That's fine Mom,
but we need it back now.
Really, sweetie, it couldn't
be safer than where it is.
What couldn't be safer?
Well, whatever is in the box, of course.
Go and get it.
Mom, please, go get the box.
Who the hell do you think you are?
I'm one of those people
you'll never meet...
as long as you're a
straight and honest citizen.
Now, what would you have done if we
turned the goddamn money over the police?
But you didn't,
did you, Sam?
So there's no way of ever knowing that.
Hey, come here.
Give it to me.
You took some,
didn't you, Mommy?
- How much did you steal?
- Hey come on, that's enough.
I didn't steal a cent.
- I just borrowed a little.
- Mother.
How much did you borrow?
About $600.
It was a loan!
I needed it! I'm on fixed
income. I was gonna put it back!
Mother, we left that with
you for safekeeping.
I just took a little peek, honey.
There was so much.
It wasn't yours!
Well, it wasn't yours either, was it?
Here's a lesson...
when it comes to cash,
nobody can be trusted.
Like mother, like daughter.
Switch the engine off
and give me the key.
Stay put.
Both of you .
Sam, what are we doing?
I don't know, Les, alright. I don't
even know what we should be doing.
Do we even have a right here?
I don't know anymore.
Of course we have no right.
He's forcing us to do something
against our will.
Yes, he do, huh.
Coz we are the ones who took the money
you know, we decided to keep it.
We knew it wasn't ours.
Hi, there.
I'm just checking out.
You owe me $58.
We don't give no refund.
What?
No refunds.
I paid you $203 for seven days,
at $29 a day.
I only stayed five days.
You owe me $58 for the
two days I won't be staying.
What, you got shit
in your ears, mister?
I said no goddamn refund!
Now get on down the road
before I call the cops.
Next, I'll break your arms, your leg...
and finally your neck.
Now...
just count all the
money you owe me...
and hand it over.
Maybe forgetting something.
What?
You want a receipt?
My day.
What about my day?
Have a nice day?
Good.
I will.
- Thank you.
- Same to you.
Okay.
Let's go.
Leslie?
Okay...
I need to go back out.
But I need you both
to stay in the house.
Can I trust you to do that?
Yes.
Did you see the blood on his shirt?
He took out a guy
in that motel today.
He's crazy.
We gotta call the police.
We should have called it yesterday.
We can do it tonight
after he's asleep.
I found them.
How fucking nice work, bro.
I recovered $547,433.
That's fucking brilliant, Pyke.
Fuck me!
There's more of it.
Really? How much?
- Some $78,298 still outstanding.
- Where is it?
They spent it.
That's okay, fuck you.
We still got $250k a piece, right?
No.
I'm going after the rest.
What do you mean?
Come on, bro.
Give me a fucking break!
Please, just this once.
- They spent it, bro, it's gone.
- It's not gone.
It's just be misplaced.
I'll get it replaced.
Okay.
Have it your fucking way.
As usual.
Do what you fucking like.
I'll see you when I
get out of this shithole.
Let's talk about the rest
of the money you owe.
What are you talking about?
We spent the rest, right, it's gone.
And now we have to get it back.
The outstanding deficit is $78,298.
What?
Why don't you just take the Range Rover,
take the new furniture, take it all?
I don't want your goods, Sam.
I'm not a merchant.
I'm more like a banker.
I require cash.
We don't have $78,000l!
$78,298.
We don't have that, either.
You know what?
Can't you just leave?
You have $500,000 plus.
Just leave us alone!
We're sorry we spent some.
We felt God smiled down on us.
We were wrong.
We're sorry.
Nothing is free, Leslie.
Not in this life.
You knew that money
wasn't yours.
And you spent it.
Now you have to pay.
What are you gonna do?
Kill us?
We don't have it!
Let's not discuss
consequences.
Let just focus on how you're
gonna get my money back.
Good food, Leslie.
Better if it was meat,
but good all the same.
Sam cooked it.
Real domestic, yeah, Sam?
Okay, there's something I need
you both to do for me now.
What's it?
I need both of your personal cell phones.
Get it.
Thank you.
Leslie, could you go to the kitchen
and ring your phone, please?
Yeah.
I noticed another jack.
Where does that one lead?
In the bedroom.
Can you bring the phone
from the bedroom, Leslie?
- Yes
- Thanks.
We're coming to the tricky part
of this recovery action here.
And I wanna keep
it private, don't you?
We're getting to a place now
where you and Leslie...
have to dig into your own pockets.
And you know when that happens people
want to make call to somebody.
Strange thing.
Human nature, I guess.
They always want
to make that call.
Now, why don't you two tell me your
plan in getting the rest of my money?
We don't have a damn plan.
We can sell the Range Rover,
it's worth about $ 70,000...
sell new furniture and I don't know,
borrow the rest from friends.
Just to borrowing from friends, good luck.
The Range Rover, okay.
But the furniture, no, it takes too long.
I'm giving you five days
from right now.
And if we can't do it by then?
No consequences in advance.
You learn consequences
only when a line is crossed...
and a decision is made.
Oh yeah.
It's in pretty decent shape.
- I'll give 47 for it.
- What?
Wait a second,
what are you talking about?
We paid almost $70,000
a week ago, cash.
Yeah, yeah.
No.
You see, I sold you a new vehicle
and you brought me back a used one.
It's only got 190 miles on it,
for Christ's sake.
Tell you what I'm gonna do,
and it's my best deal ever.
I'll give you $53,000 for it
and I'll throw in the old car for you.
How does that sound, huh?
Can you deliver it  in cash?
So $ 53,000 from $78,298...
leaves an outstanding deficit
of $25,298.
Can't you just give us a goddamn break?
Do you mean,
I'll assume your debt?
The answer is no,
I won't.
Look, we can't get any more.
You still own a house.
Goddamnit, Leslie!
You are not getting our house, bastard!
I don't want your house, Leslie.
I was thinking
more along the lines of...
cash refinancing.
No.
Not our house.
Will we stop this crap now?
This shit has gone far enough!
Sam, this fucker is full of shit!
What can he do
in broad daylight?
Let's just get out, Sam, walk away.
Get out the damn jalopy.
Leslie, you make
a decision now...
and you live with the consequences after,
remember that?
Fuck you.
It is an idle threat, Sam.
That's all, he's bullshit!
Get in the car, Leslie.
- He's bluffing.
- Get in the car.
He's a damn bully.
We can walk away.
- Let's go.
- Let's call the police.
Where?
Where the house is financed.
Mr. and Mrs. Phelan, is it your
wish that this gentleman be privy...
to your personal financial affairs?
Yeah, sure.
Why the hell not?
What was the original purchase
price of the house?
The original purchase price
was $200,000.
Purchased when?
Five years ago.
What is the amount
of their monthly payment?
$647.70 a month.
Term of loan?
29 years.
How much down?
Well, 10%,
$20,000.
So, if down payment being the same as equity...
they day they bought the house
that's $20,000 equity...
- And still have that amount today, yeah?
- Well, yes, technically, yes.
They've been paying monthly
payments, faithfully...
for the last five years...
which comes to $38,862, right?
38,862.
That's correct.
So, discounting interest,
they've paid down about $13,000...
and a mortgage debt,
is that right?
Yes.
That's just about right, yes.
So they still owe $167,000.
Now, during these past five years,
the property has appreciated.
Well, yes, of course.
But we can't be certain on how
much without an appraisal.
Yeah, nevertheless, it has appreciated.
Let's use a conservative figure,
say $20,000 over five years.
That sums easily to what?
$4,000 per year.
I would say that's optimistic
would you?
No, that sounds reasonable.
Okay.
So, discounting appreciation
with their original down payment...
they have $53,000
equity in the house.
And as such, I see no reason
why this institution...
should not lend them a
$25,298 they seek...
less than half
their existing equity.
Well, I...
We quit our jobs.
- You're unemployed?
- Yeah.
Are you familiar with the
Newer Dock Home Equity Loan?
Yeah, of course.
Yeah?
You see, the Newer Dock requires
no employment, no income or assets.
Lenders do not verify any information
beyond the credit profile
- and value of the property.
- Of course.
The Phelans have equity.
They could easily get
a loan equal to 80%.
Well, I don't know that this bank
has ever issued a New Dock loan.
I don't know that we can do it.
Their credit rating...
Listen...
I think you're missing
a big opportunity here, Mr. Dink.
It's Dale.
- Mr. Dale.
- Yeah, whatever.
We could go elsewhere for the money...
and I'm sure your branch manager
would be very unhappy to lose a business...
especially in view of the fact
that this institution...
holds the first mortgage.
But it's urgent.
These people
need the cash today.
Name your terms.
At today's prices, they have more
equity than necessary...
more money for the bank if you decide
to foreclose, you get me what I mean here?
It's a sweet deal.
There might even be a
promotion in it, somebody...
Perhaps, I could consider a
small home equity loan...
you know, for urgent home repairs.
High interest.
Well, of course.
Well...
we take the fair market value...
times 80% loan to value...
and equals $86,000...
minus the compound interest
over the term of the loan.
I can lend $11,421.89.
That's the maximum on a pure
equity loan of an unemployed applicant.
They'll take it.
Make a bank draft to cash.
They'll redeem it here.
So, Sam...
how are you gonna get
the remaining $13,876.11?
Why are you keeping me at this?
The money isn't even yours anyway.
That's where you're wrong
The money is mine...
and I will keep it until a superior
power takes it from me.
And so the question remains.
How will you pay me the $13,876.11
that you owe me?
There's your fucking
11 cents!
Thank you, Leslie.
Why can't you just
leave us alone?
I understand your frustration...
I do...
but I must have the full amount.
We don't have it and there's no
place else we can get it.
So, you're just gonna have to kill us
or whatever it is...
Slow down.
Look, everybody's overreacting.
Let's just all settle down, okay?
We'll have a nice meal,
we'll watch some big-screen TV...
and in the morning,
we'll work something out.
You still have another four days.
Les? Les, come on, wake up.
Wake up, wake up.
- What?
- We're leaving.
C'mon, get dressed.
Here.
- What?
- Let's go.
- He'll hear.
- Fuck him. Come on.
- Let's go, let's go. Come on.
- Okay.
Okay.
Out for a midnight stroll?
I understand this is your first
experience in a situation like this...
So I'm go to overlook
tonight in discretion.
But understand this.
Until I get my money,
you will not leave this house.
You will not phone anyone
or meet anyone...
unless I give my permission.
Is that understood?
- Is that understood?
- Yes.
Leslie?
Yes, fucking yes!
Okay?
Now get back to bed.
Good morning.
Everybody sleep well?
What the hell is this?
I did a little shopping
while you people are sleeping.
Meat.
Why don't you slip over to the stove there, Sam,
and cook up some eggs and meat for Leslie and me?
What?
Eggs, Sam.
I want eggs.
Are you gonna cook or not?
- I'll do it.
- No. I want Sam to do it.
He's a domestic man,
aren't you Sam?
What are you doing?
Stop it.
I just want him to do.
That's all, Leslie.
This is ridiculous.
It's the elementary school crap!
What's it gonna be, Sam?
Whatever.
Eggs, no big deal.
And meat, Sam.
Make mine scrambled
will you?
How do you like your eggs,
Leslie?
Fuck you.
It's easy for a woman, isn't it?
No physical threat,
without fear of reprisal.
You can just simply open
your big beautiful mouth...
and say whatever foul things
that comes into your head, right?
Come, sit by me.
Sam.
Go in there and rob it.
Bring me the money back.
- Wait, what?
- Are you crazy?
Hey, I can't do that!
Shit!
Get on the way, you can do it, Sam.
You'll be surprise how easy it is.
You see, the majority of men are
cowards, ain't that right, Sam?
All women are cowards.
Fear of this gun will drive them
to obey every command...
just as you obey mine.
Now, get in there and do it.
Running time for my orders, Sam.
I want my fucking money.
- Now, go in there and do it.
- Alright, alright. Just relax.
Sam?
Your phone.
Fuck.
Hello?
Sam, it's me.
I want you to keep the line open.
I wanna hear everything that's
going on in there, you understand?
If you get ugly, the line goes dead,
your wife goes dead with it,  you understand?
Yeah.
Give me all the money!
Paper or plastic?
Jesus Christ, I don't care!
Fuck you!
It's good, ain't it?
Give me the gun, Sam.
Count the money for him, Leslie.
He seems a little nervous.
Let's see how you did, Sam.
How much, baby?
$464.
That's not a great score, Sam.
Why didn't you get the coins?
What do you mean, I didn't get the coins!
I didn't I'm supposed to!
Now, you got that from the movies, right?
That's what stupid movies get you.
Money is money.
You get it all.
Okay.
That's $464,
subtracted from...
the balance of $13,876.
that comes to $13,412...
left to get.
Your turn.
Not me.
Why?
Because you're a woman?
The vagina gives you
special privileges, does it?
You, American women
always want equality.
Well, I'm giving it to you.
And get the change this time.
Leslie?
Same deal.
You get killed in there
and Sam he pays the price.
Okay?
Got it.
Raise your hands!
Give me the money, asshole!
Come on, come on!
Put it in a bag!
The coins too!
Come on!
And give me a pack of cigarettes.
What kind?
- I don't care, the green ones.
- Menthol?
Just give me a goddamn carton!
Get on the floor!
Get down and don't move
for 5 minutes or you die!
Give me the gun.
Physical power over others
tastes sweet in the mouth.
Especially for a woman...
who doesn't often
get the experience.
Feeds you like mother's milk.
It's almost sexual, isn't it Leslie?
Hey, where did you get those?
I took them.
Oh, you shoplifted.
Shoplifted?
Okay, count all the money, Leslie.
$525.87.
My haul was bigger.
Leslie?
The day's total haul is $2128.16.
Subtracted from our
outstanding total leaves...
$11,283.84.
Ain't no great shape, folks. $2,100
for a whole day's work.
Actually, it's $2128.16.
Turn on the TV, Sam.
It's time for the news.
Go.
You're watching
WGN, News at 9.
Sit by me, Leslie.
Armed robberies occurred today
in the Chicago area.
Two men and one woman held up
a liquor store this morning...
and escaped capture.
Police believed it's the same trio...
that went on to rob six more
convenience store in an all day crime spree.
Police estimates, the robbers
got away with over $10,000.
That's bullshit!
There was a lie about the take.
Insurance fraud.
Everybody's crooked.
Everybody.
Police have compiled
the sketch of the trio.
Isn't that stupid? Those drawings
never looked like anybody.
In the history of the world, they've never
caught a criminal based on those stupid things.
99 Store manager
Bahadurjit Tejinderpreet...
who has been robbed
more than ten times.
I know that guy.
Bearshit Tenderfeet.
I've been robbed by
the best thieves in Chicago!
These are amateurs!
Fuck him!
The getaway car was a cream-colored
station wagon, believed to be a Buick.
Shit!
In other news...
- They know our car.
- They don't know anything.
They got no license number,
no photos, no names.
Detroit made ten zillion
of those cars. Relax.
Anyway,
Tomorrow, we'll use my car.
You're sideling up to side.
I'm not sideling.
- You sat beside him, Les.
- You cooked his meat.
Sam, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
We're both scared of him
and we have a right to be.
He's dangerous.
He's crazy and he's making us crazy.
I'm so sorry.
Empty the register, man.
Let's go!
Come on, hurry up, hurry up!
Don't do anything stupid.
Getting the hang of it, Sam.
Give me the gun.
- What kind of gun is this?
- The kind that scares people.
Now give me.
But what kind?
It's a Star Caliber 9mm,
Parabellum, semi-automatic...
pistol double action.
Made in Spain.
It weighs 39.68 ounces
and has a 4-inch barrel.
It fires a 120 gray...
metal jacketed bullet at
a mussel velocity of 1247 ft/sec.
Okay, now give me the fucking gun.
I said give me the fucking gun.
Nine millimeter.
Sam, what's happening
to us?
I watched you today.
You liked that gun.
Jesus.
Shut up, Leslie.
- Sammy!
- No, shut the fuck up.
Get the money!
I can't!
Family needs more money!
Get the fucking money now!
No!
Goddamn you!
That girl's a natural, Sam.
Let's go!
Don't say one fucking word to me!
Totals out to $5295.52.
It's not bad at all.
But we still have an outstanding balance
of $5988.32 and only one day left.
Turn on the TV, Sam,
it's time for the news.
Why don't you turn it on yourself?
Okay, Sam.
The threesome struck again today,
robbing ten different establishments...
in Cook County.
Ten in one day!
It could be a record.
Captain Johnson said he's never seen
such a desperate run of robberies.
The getaway car they're using now
is a black Lincoln, with no license plate.
If caught,
the two men and one woman...
face armed robbery charges...
which carries a 20 to 50-year prison term.
Actually...
when Leslie pistoled the old chink,
she'll be answered to robbery with aggravated assault...
It is life.
I made you do it, but I
didn't mean you like it, did I?
I wasn't me who made
your panties wet...
when you were robbing those people
was it Leslie?
Fuck you, alright!
I will not let you do that!
Stop it!
Stop hitting him, stop it!
Stop it, no!
Come on.
You okay?
Get the fuck out of here!
What do you think?
Grab my pistol
so you could get my gun?
What?
Are you offended I rejected
you offering your pussy?
Get back to bed, Leslie.
We can start downtown...
and make our way south to Cicero.
No.
One more score.
We'll hit a bank.
Too risky.
The banks are out of your league.
That kind of job requires
preparation, planning.
Gets another layout of routines.
This will be alright, son.
The bank I'm thinking about,
I know everything I need to know.
We'll stick to the small stuff..
What's the matter?
Ain't you got the stomach for it?
I want to finish with this shit.
I'll never get a full $5988.32
taken to the small stuff.
Or you'll give a time extension, is that it?
You're giving me a pass?
Okay, Sam.
You get your bank.
What?
You got any clean pantyhose?
Banks are two-man job.
I'm going in there with you.
We got no longer
than three minutes, okay.
Leslie, you keep the monster
running and stay cool.
No more games, or Sam he pays the price.
A little late for fucking games.
Let's go.
Robbery!
Get down!
Everybody!
Nobody fucking moves.
Once you play hero, you're killed.
Get on the fucking ground!
Everybody!
- Bag all the money!
- Yes, sir!
Bag it up!
Nobody moves!
Open the bolt!
Stand still there!
No one fucking left here.
You, get down!
Go down the stairs!
Don't fucking move!
Come on, move it!
Fucking get down!
Leave the money and run.
The alarm has been triggered.
You'll go to prison.
What the fuck are you doing?
Move, now!
You fucking stay down!
Come out ! Come out!
Get off!
How much did we get?
Are you fucking crazy?
What the fuck did you just do?
We owe $5988.32.
Here it is.
Now, are we done with it?
That's right, Sam.
Our business is finished.
Give me the gun.
I said, give me the gun.
Give me that fucking gun, Sam,
or I'll leg really fucking badly this time.
You believe me?
Yeah, I believe.
You don't got the stomach for that.
You don't have any idea what
the fuck I have the stomach for.
Sam!
What do you hope to accomplish
with no fucking bullets, you buddy folk?
Sammy!
If you make a move here,
I'll get down and I'll kill you.
- Believe me?
- Yeah.
- You believe, motherfucker?
- Yeah, I believe.
Goddamn right you do.
What's your name?
- What?
- Your name. I wanna know your fucking name.
Pyke.
Pyke?
Pyke what?
Kubic.
Pyke Kubic.
Watch out!
Go!
I'm gonna kill you both!
- I'm gonna kill you both!
- Fuck you!
- Take the gun, Les!
Fuck you!
A bizarre incident
was reported by police today.
Over $15,000 has been
anonymously returned...
over 27 convenience stores,
9-9 and grocery marts...
with over $10,000 returned
to a Park and Savings Bank...
in repayment for the rush out
robberies that occurred last week.
It appears, the robbers
experienced remorse and sent...
the exact amount of stolen
cash back to each establishment.
The robbers even sent extra money
to two persons...
who were hurt during the course of the crime:
An older Asian woman and a savings and loan manager.