Buster Keaton in The Saphead
Directed by Herbert Blache
Written by June Mathis
"The New Henrietta" was a
Broadway play in which...
Douglas Fairbanks scored
a major success in 1913.
It was first filmed with him
1915 under the name THE LAMB.
When it was to be
remade by Metro in 1920,...
Fairbanks himself suggested Buster Keaton
for his former role.
Keaton was then under an
exclusive contract with...
Joseph M. Schenck who agreed
to loan him to Metro.
It was Keaton's first appearance
in a feature-length film.
THE SAPHEAD'S great success earned Keaton
star billings in his subsequent films.
A little street where money is everything-
and everything is money.
Nicholas Van Alstyne- known, loved, and
feared as "The Old Nick of The Street."
Old Nick's very private
secretary -- "Mr. Musgrave."
"You tell him that Jim Hardy
from Arizona is here."
"I used to pal with this old boy out west."
"What the blazes brought you east, Jim?"
"The Henrietta mine -- she's the all-fired
biggest proposition I ever seen."
"Jim, you know more about a mine
than anybody on earth -- except me --"
"I want a broker -- send for Watson Flint."
"If you say the Henrietta is that big --
watch me gamble on her!"
Mark Turner had succeeded in
marrying Old Nick's daughter -
- but had never succeeded at anything else.
MARK TURNER
BROKER
His morning mail as usual was
all bills and no business.
"There's a girl outside that
wants to see you personal."
I am destitute and very ill. I must
see you. Henrietta Reynolds
"Your wife's outside, sir."
"Go back and tell her she'll hear
from me in a day or two."
"I came to invite you to lunch."
"I'm afraid you'd find me rotten company."
"I work like a dog, Rose --
but I don't get anywhere."
"Your father's commissions are
worth a fortune to a broker -
- but he never gives me an order."
"I'll have a talk with Dad about you
-- when he gets home this afternoon."
Old Nick's castle.
Bertie Van Alstyne, Esquire,
his father's hope and pride,
breakfasts early -- in the afternoon.
"I want to talk to you about
the way you treat Mark."
I am destitute and very ill. I must
see you. Henrietta Reynolds
"You keep away -- I'll see her,
and try to get your letters back."
"If you'll stop talking I'll see
what I can do for your Mark."
Bertie had been in love for years and
decided something must be done about it.
Nick's ward, Agnes, was the girl
Bertie loved. He had confided this -
- to his sister and his valet --
but had never mentioned it to her.
"Agnes has telegraphed that she's
coming home from school today."
"Don't get excited ----
you'll have plenty of time to meet her ---
- the train doesn't arrive until 6:30."
"What's happened to you lately?
Getting home at daylight -
- and having a picture of Henrietta,
the dancer, in your room--"
"I am leading a fast life because
I am in love with Agnes."
How to win the modern girl
by Judith Blakely
How to win the modern girl. THE Modern Girl has
no use for the old-fashioned man. She prefers -
- sports to saints. Few girls now-a-days can
resist a dashing, gambling, drinking devil.
Agnes was to arrive at the Grand Central -
- so Bertie went to meet her
at the Pennsylvania.
Six-thirty at the Grand Central.
Agnes was an orphan --
whom Nick has brought up as his own child.
"Nobody met me."
"The saphead! I suppose he
forgot all about you."
"Ask Hutchins to let me know
as soon as Mr. Bertie comes in."
"Mr. Bertie is never home before
three in the morning, Miss."
"I was waiting for someone
-- but she didn't come."
Trash
The Gay White Way
failing to cheer Bertie - his friends
try the side streets.
"I'm having rotten luck --
lend me a couple of thousand."
"Are those things worth
two thousand dollars?"
"What are they made of?"
"I'm awfully tired of this --
would you mind very much if I stop?"
"Your winnings, Mr. V.
-- thirty-eight thousand."
"Are you quite sure you can spare it?"
Bertie sees a chance to get
a real reputation as a sport --
"Will you see to arresting me, please?"
Morning
RAID ON GAMBLING PALACE.
SON OF NICHOLAS VAN ALSTYNE
AMONG THOSE PRESENT.
Young Men of Prominent Families
Given Free Ride to Police Station.
"But they might come and
take him to jail!"
"Is it true you were in that
dreadful place?"
"I was there because I love Agnes."
"If you love Agnes, why
didn't you meet her?"
"I did -- but she didn't come."
"Bertie -- you've changed somehow."
"I heard you tell Rose that you
loved me -- and I love you, too."
"I've tricked you into loving
me -- when you know the truth -
- I'm afraid you won't
care for me any more."
"Tell me --"
"I'm good!"
"I've tried my best to get over it --
but I can't -- and I still kneel down -
- and say my prayers every morning --
before I go to bed."
"Bertie, who is Henrietta?"
"I bought her picture-
but I never met her."
"Agnes, you'd better go."
"You've got to get out and
shift for yourself --
- this is the last check you'll get
from me!"
(Cashier's Check)
Bankers Trust Company
10,000 $   -  Nicholas Van Alstyne
"How can you be so cruel!
I love Bertie,
whether you do or not,
and I'm going to be his wife!"
"If you've had the impertinence
to ask Agnes to marry you--"
"-- I suppose I've got to give
you a little more."
Bankers Trust Company
1,000,000 $
"Not another cent!"
"Not another word about marrying
Agnes until you go to work ----
- and make something of yourself!"
Poor Bertie-- cut off with a million --
moved into humble quarters at the Ritz.
Watson Flint -- Nick's broker, and a
friend of the family.
"I've got to go into business
like you and Mark Turner."
Dearest Agnes, you wanted me
to go into business so I have gone.
"I bought a seat on the Stock Exchange
for a hundred thousand dollars."
"A hundred thousand dollars
for a seat?"
"Well, furniture is way
up now-a-days."
"I want to show you an
engagement ring."
"You asked me to look
after it, sir."
"If father won't let us marry, perhaps
you'll keep it to remember me by."
"No matter what Uncle Nick says, I'll
marry you whenever you want me --"
"We can't now, Bertie --
we must make arrangements first --
- let's say next Tuesday!"
"Leon, we're to be married
secretly Tuesday evening --
- please make all the arrangements."
"It would be a wonderful
surprise for her --
- if we could only get it
ready in time."
"We must!"
You can never be sure a woman will
be on time -- even for her wedding.
"I'm going to marry Bertie tonight."
"But, Agnes -- you mustn't run away
-- we'll have the wedding here!"
"Get out one of her little white dresses
-- and she can wear my wedding veil."
"I'll manage father, and send
for the Reverend Murray Hilton."
"I took you into business
because Rose wanted me to -
- and you're making good!"
"I've given you power of attorney because
I'm going on a cruise Wednesday -
- and you'll be in charge
while I'm away."
"Bertie and Agnes are going
to be married tonight --"
"Perhaps they've locked her up."
"All right -- let 'em be married in here
-- or down cellar -- or on the roof --"
"-- but I won't see them."
"I have called for Agnes."
"I'm through with you --"
"-- and as for Agnes, she
has disobeyed me --"
"Now ask Bertie to forgive you."
"We're going to be married here!"
For the Minister
"Anything else?"
"I'll put one in every pocket -- then when
the minister asks me -- there you are!"
(Address)
Henrietta Reynolds
518 S. Vine St, Omaha, Nebraska
"If I die -- promise me you'll put
these into Mrs. Turner's hands."
"I want Mrs. Turner!"
"Henrietta is dead -- and I gave her my
sacred word I'd put these into your hands."
A dying mother appeals to you -
Have mercy on my little one. -
- The letters from her father which I send
with this will tell you the rest.
Henrietta Reynolds
"I'm sorry this blow has come, Rose
-- I've tried to keep it from you --"
"Bertie, these belong to you
---- they're from Henrietta."
Bertie's valet had planned a great
surprise for the bridal couple.
Tortured by thoughts of Agnes
-- Bertie hopes a visit to -
- the Stock Exchange may
help him to forget.
"This is a new member
-- Mr. Van Alstyne."
"Mr. Turner wants to see you at
Van Alstyne's office right away."
"Do all these seats cost a
hundred thousand dollars?"
HE'S NEW
MAKE HIM WELCOME
Knowing that the truth about Henrietta
Reynolds must soon come to light,
Mark has induced Nick to go on
his yachting trip as planned.
With Nick out of the way, Mark sees
a chance to clean up a fortune -
- before his relations with Henrietta
Reynolds are discovered.
"Mr. Van Alstyne notified
you that I would be in -
- complete authority here during
his absence -- ?"
"I want you to sell 'Henrietta
Mine' until you have -
- knocked the price down
fifty points!"
"I can't accept a commission
of that size without security."
"Great heavens, Turner! -- these securities
belong to your father-in-law!"
"While he is away they are mine."
Bertie's introduction to the Floor
grows more and more informal.
"All they do here is knock off hats --
but I enjoy it -- it occupies the mind."
"I'm going out to get some new ones
so I can play it again."
The raid on Henrietta.
"They've started a raid on 'Henrietta'
-- you ought to be on the Floor!"
"When I want your advice
I'll send for you!"
"Mr. Tildon of the National City is here."
BIG SLUMP IN HENRIETTA MINING STOCK
"Mr. Van Alstyne won't return for a week
-- and Mr. Turner is in charge."
"Tell Turner if we don't receive collateral
by three o'clock we'll be forced to -
- throw Van Alstyne's
holdings on the market!"
"Thank God you've come, sir!"
"Thank God!
I was seasick--"
...PA           ...HEN               ...INP
200...67          200...37...        ...
"Call up Mr. Tildon -- and send to
the Stock Exchange for Mark Turner!"
"Mr. Turner hasn't been
on the Floor today!"
"Mark Turner is responsible for
this raid, sir."
"Because he's a cheat -
I found out he was responsible for -
- that Henrietta girl, and put
the blame on Mr. Bertie-"
"I'm sorry to hurry you --
but it's two-thirty,
and your securities must be in the
bank before the market closes."
"It's almost three o'clock.
There's nothing on earth I can do."
"You're too late. Flint's on the Floor now,
knocking the last breath out of -
- the 'Henrietta' -- and I can buy your
holdings for next to nothing!"
"Get the police!"
"All the police in the world can't prevent
your losing control of the Henrietta Mine -
- when the gong rings in the
Stock Exchange!"
-HENRIETTA
-HENRIETTA!
-HENRIETTA!!
-HENRIETTA
"Sir, you're insulting me!-- and I demand
that you stop yelling that woman's name!"
HENRIETTA!
HENRIETTA
"They're all yelling that
woman's name at me --
- and I can't make them stop!"
"Bertie, listen! -- I'll tell you
something that will stop them!"
"Every time you hear a
man yelling 'Henrietta' -
- you grab him and
say -- 'I TAKE IT'!"
It seems to Bertie that
the whole Stock Exchange -
- is taunting him by yelling
Henrietta's name.
"She's up forty points and
going like a rocket!"
Van Alstyne's Henrietta Pounded to a Pulp
...HEN                                   LAST
7000...94...97....... 105.....
"I've been saved, Flint!
-- saved by a miracle!"
"It was no miracle -- it was Bertie!
He's the latest member of -
- the Stock Exchange!"
"He's bought a cottage on Long Island
-- this is his address."
"I have been on the Floor of
the Stock Exchange."
"Why, my boy -- you've saved 'Henrietta'!"
"I mean the Henrietta
mine! Now get dressed,
because I've sent for
Agnes and the minister."
THE END
Subtitle By : Reza Fa