Directed by Jess Franco
- Have you got a light?
- No.
Fantastic. I want to stop smoking anyway.
- Please buy me a drink
- No.
I don't need cigarettes or drinks.
You don't want cigarettes
or nothing to drink?
No, you can get those things anywhere.
All I need is a boyfriend.
Is that so?
Right.
What's next?
Oh, you.
Oh, this is so good,
but wouldn't it be even better at home?
No, I'm just visiting.
We can't do it where I'm staying.
You can come back to my place.
It's small, but I can do as I please.
- That would be great. Where do you live?
- It's not far. It's near Bahía Baja.
That doesn't mean anything to me.
I don't know this area.
- I only arrived three days ago.
- Oh, did you?
- Will you show me the way?
- I've got a better idea.
- I'll drive you to my place.
- Please do.
- Fine.
- Can you get past?
Yes. It's rather cramped in here.
- Oh, wow!
- What?
- You're very well-built.
- That was just the gear stick.
- Oh, I see.
- Yes.
Let's see if I can get used to your stick.
It is yours, isn't it?
Well, yes.
Stop that, darling. I'm not insured
against accidents, you know.
- All right.
- Postponed is not abandoned.
You can get out now. We're there.
- Tell me, is this really your place?
- Yes.
- I'll be damned!
- It's small, but it's mine.
If you call this small,
you must be pretty spoilt.
I prefer quality to quantity.
Good evening, mademoiselle.
- Good day, Sarah. ls everything OK?
- Everything's fine.
- Hello.
- Monsieur.
- Not bad.
- What?
Your little place.
Mademoiselle.
Thanks, Sarah.
A sip of champagne is all that's missing.
Thank you.
Cheers.
- Or would you like to eat something?
- No, this will do, thanks.
Mademoiselle.
We're ready.
Cheeky monkey!
- You may undress me now, Sarah.
- Yes, mademoiselle.
Take it off.
And my knickers as well.
No, not the stockings. As a lady,
I have to keep some sense of decency.
Yes, mademoiselle.
Now the gentleman.
But take off his socks.
Yes, mademoiselle.
Would you get up so that I
can undress you, please?
Hello.
But wait.
This bloody glass!
You like that, don't you?
You're in for something even better.
Stay right here.
I'll be back in a minute.
Edna!
Edna. At last you're back.
Where have you been all this time?
I'm at the end of my tether.
- I need you. I need you.
- I'm with you now. Calm down.
What a horny thing you are!
You haven't brought a man!
You're alone!
Just wait, Sis. A really well-built guy is
in the lounge, waiting to make you happy.
Release my arms.
Bring him here. I'll be good.
OK.
All right.
There you go.
Calm down.
That guy will be with you in no time.
I need him.
But promise me that you'll be sensible,
despite your sensuality.
I'll promise anything,
as long as you stay
You must watch, like you always do.
Watch me, the way I used to
watch you as a child. Please!
You must promise to watch us.
I like it best that way.
Will you? Yes?
You enjoy it too, don't you?
Go...get him.
You can come upstairs now.
Here I am.
Come here,
I need you.
- Come to me.
- What do you want?
You know what I want.
- And who are you?
- Edna's sister, Milly.
Where is Edna?
What does that matter right now?
Come here. Come to me.
I need you. Kiss me.
Kiss me.
I can't stand it any longer.
Yes. Yes. Yes!
Don't stop. Carry on.
Oh, yes!
- Is it good?
- Yes.
- Are you ready?
Now it's my turn.
Yes.
Wonderful!
- Do you want more?
- Yes.
I'm going crazy.
Lie down.
Yes.
I can hardly bear it.
Can you go on?
Yes.
- Come on, lie down now.
- I'll do anything you want.
Oh, stop.
Wow!
Are you awake?
I wanted to tell you,
and please don't laugh,
You're the first person...
who has ever satisfied me.
And I think I love you.
Was it all... a dream?
Good morning, Milly.
Did you sleep well?
Yes, thank you.
What time is it?
It's past ten o'clock.
I let you have a lie-in.
But now it's time to take your medicine.
Dr Barrios should be here any minute now.
He'll tell me off if he finds out
how late you were given it.
Thank you.
- He can be quite pedantic.
- I know.
But he's a handsome man, isn't he?
I don't like Dr Barrios.
Don't you?
I think he is particularly
fond of you, though.
And you're greatly indebted to him.
A famous specialist like him
doesn't need to see you this often.
He goes to a lot of trouble for your sake.
I'm sorry. You're right, of course.
The main thing is that you realise it.
And now, it's time for your injection.
- Turn towards me, please
- OK.
- Did it hurt?
- No.
Hello, Dr Barrios.
Good day, Sarah.
- Where is she?
- In her room.
- And Edna?
- Mademoiselle is still in bed.
- Don't wake her up.
- All right.
Wee Willie Winkie runs through the town
With his big willy under his gown
- Good morning, Milly.
- Good morning, Doctor.
- Is your willy as big as Willie's?
- No, but it serves its purpose.
Turn over, please.
It doesn't satisfy me, though.
We'll see about that.
Keep still.
Hey, that hurts!
Long and thin, a woman won't grin.
I see that you're in a good mood.
- You must be feeling better today.
- Despite your willy, I feel fulfilled.
More fulfilled than ever before.
I've had other men...
but never one like him.
Last night I was made happy,
with true passion.
I feel that life is worth living now.
I don't usually see them again,
but maybe Edna will allow
this one to come back.
Well?
Not bad.
- I'm pleased to hear that.
- So am I.
Nurse Maria,
it might be a good idea if you took
Milly for a swim in the sea today.
That would be wonderful.
I haven't left this room for six months.
You're a kind man.
You flatter me.
But no longer than an hour.
If it was half as long,
I'd be just as happy. Goodbye.
Bye, Milly.
- Would you come with me for a moment?
- Yes, doctor.
- We have something important to discuss
- What's the matter, Charles?
You like Milly a lot, don't you?
- Yes, but...
- Milly is very sick.
She's a nymphomaniac,
and now she's having hallucinations.
Like that man she claims was here.
That's how paranoid schizophrenia starts.
We must start using new, stronger drugs.
I will start a new treatment today.
Inject her with this from now on.
This box contains 24 ampoules,
enough for four days.
We must observe how she
reacts to this, understood?
You must keep an eye on her at all times.
This will make Milly sleep even better.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
- You know what this stuff is like.
- Maria, trust me.
We are both trying to help Milly.
You must cooperate, as agreed, Maria.
Yes, but...
- I have to go and see a patient now
- Charles?
- Yes?
- I apologise.
- It's all right.
Don't worry, it will be fine.
I know, that's why I'm apologising.
You know you can rely on me.
- When will I see you again?
- I'm afraid I don't know.
You know how busy I am at the moment,
but I'm sure it will be soon.
I'll come over on Thursday in any case.
Call me if anything happens.
Certainly.
See you soon.
Ciao.
Is anything wrong?
Why would anything be wrong?
It's time for your injection.
Oh, right, the injection.
- It's so cold!
- I don't think it is.
Hold on to me.
Come on, let's get back into the water.
- Are you enjoying it?
- Very much so.
Be careful. No.
- I've swallowed some water.
- It's good for you.
You can talk, you cow!
Just you wait!
No, no!
Please stop now.
I'd like to get out. I'd like to sunbathe.
- Are you staying here?
- No, I'll come.
- Oh, I love the sea.
- So do I.
- I want to go swimming every day.
- That's up to Dr Barrios.
- Convince him that exercise does us good.
- I'll talk to him.
- Thank you. What would I do without you?
- You're welcome.
- Are you coming?
- Yes.
Stop laughing, dammit!
- Don't trip, Maria.
- I won't.
I nearly did.
Isn't this a wonderful day?
Your skin is exceptionally beautiful.
You're going to get sunburnt.
Didn't you bring any suntan oil?
You have porcelain skin,
but it can't take the sun.
Let me do it. I'd like to pamper you
a bit, in honour of the occasion.
- Maria, you're a good person.
- Quiet now.
Maria?
You are so dear to me.
Maria. Oh, Maria!
Wake up, Milly!
You've woken the whole
house with your screams.
You've had another bad dream, haven't you?
It's over now.
I'd like to go swimming again one day.
You're not allowed to swim, child.
- Didn't we swim in the sea today?
- What makes you think we did?
So it was only a dream after all.
Good night, Maria.
Good night. Sleep well.
- You can go to bed. You deserve it.
- Thank you. Good night.
Edna?
I'd like to ask you something,
and I want an honest answer.
Please tell me the truth.
Am I insane?
I think you're much better.
That's not what the doctor told Maria.
He said that I was on the verge
of...paranoid schizophrenia.
What an idiot!
Why did you have to hear that nonsense?
We'll have a chat tomorrow,
but right now you need to rest.
- Good night, little one.
- Good night.
- Hey! Hey, don't run away, little girl
- No!
No!
Hey, you.
- I've got you now, you hussy
- Yes.
- Ouch! You bit me, you minx!
- That's my temperament. Kiss me.
No, no, I can't go on.
No!
Sarah, come in.
How are you?
Is Milly asleep?
Yes, fast asleep.
- Come to me.
- Yes mademoiselle, I'm coming.
- I love being with you.
- Stop talking so much and get undressed.
Hurry up...
Mademoiselle, you look lovely.
Oh, this is wonderful.
I want to have a go now. Lie back.
Yes.
Edna?
I want it too. Edna!
Don't be cruel. Let me join you. Please!
Edna! I beg you!
I'm going crazy.
- That's good.
- Carry on, mademoiselle.
Edna!
Please release me.
Edna, take pity on me.
Yes.
Help me.
Please!
Oh, my body's on fire.
I can't bear it any longer.
I need help.
Help! Who will help me?
Milly, I will help you as best I can.
Yes, please do.
Help me, Maria.
Please.
Please!
I don't have a man to offer you,
but perhaps this will help you.
I don't care what it is.
I don't care at all, Maria.
You've got to save me.
Come...or I'll die.
Come...yes.
- Christina!
- I'm here.
- What's taking you so long?
- I'm on my way.
Are you looking for
something special, sir?
Oh, I must have come to the wrong person.
At last.
Good evening, Countess.
You haven't come here for a long time.
Yes, that's right.
Even though you're always here.
Absolutely. Provided
I'm not busy, that is.
So you're free right now?
Would you like to be busy?
It would be a pleasure.
- How much would that cost?
- You've always been generous.
- I pay for discretion.
- Well, then, pay.
He's prepared to cooperate.
- Your sister's become rather pretty.
- That's not her.
Milly's unwell.
I've never seen her like this
- I'd say that those injections...
- Quiet. That's nobody's business.
Oh, Sarah, the gentleman
would like to have a bath.
Come with me, please.
Hang on, what's this all about? I'm clean.
- That's her.
- Sounds like a lioness.
I've scrubbed him from
top to toe, mademoiselle.
Thanks, Sarah.
I'll leave you alone with her now.
Screw her until she's exhausted.
- I am discreet and capable.
- Yeah, yeah, I got that. There you are.
As generous as always.
I'll make a special effort for that.
I'd appreciate that.
Come, Sarah.
Hello, lioness.
Let's see if I can tame you.
You have screamed enough.
- The Taming of the Shrew.
- No! You bastard, don't touch me!
- Leave me alone.
- Carry on just like this. It turns me on.
- I beg you, please don't. You wretch!
- Spread your legs. Wider.
- Don't do it!
- Lift your ass.
You like it, don't you?
Like old times.
You like to be taken like that, don't you?
I can see that you love it, you pig.
You can't get enough, huh?
See.
Are you coming, baby?
Please wait out there.
Excuse me.
The professor would like
to talk to you, Countess.
Thank you, just a second.
Sarah, would you take Milly home?
I'll be back in a little while.
- Please.
- Thank you.
Your sister is an extraordinary case.
I would have liked to
examine her more closely.
An extremely interesting case.
Unfortunately, I must
return to Prague tomorrow.
You see, your sister is on
the verge of killing herself.
What are you saying?
Well, one might say that your sister
is seeking refuge in schizophrenia.
She is making no effort
to resist it whatsoever.
She wants her delusions.
She's trying to depersonalise,
to destroy her own ego.
If she succeeds,
she'll have to be locked up.
That's a great responsibility.
Once you've decided to do that,
there will be no going back.
Pity.
She's charming...and intelligent.
Please, how can I help Milly?
All the answers I can give you
sound very banal...
no alcohol,
no cigarettes,
no exposure to anything violent,
or anything which might shock her,
no sexual contact,
as that would be very harmful.
And no masturbation. You must ensure that.
I'll give her a prescription.
Go and get it from the pharmacy.
It will delay the progression of the
illness by days or even months.
However...it will not
restore her lust for life.
That will require something else.
This is the only effective medicine.
I would still like you to give me
a letter with your diagnosis.
All right.
Only a little more information would
be needed for a precise diagnosis.
I could make some helpful suggestions
and explain my opinion from
the medical point of view.
Yes,
I would be able to write that down
for you, if that's what you want.
Oh, yes, please do.
You're the world's most
leading psychoanalyst.
Your expert opinion would be
incredibly important to the doctors here.
Oh, taxi!
To Bahía Baja, please.
I'll gladly read it to you again.
Now..."My last will and testament.
"In full possession of my mental
faculties, I, Hermann Wilhelm von Stein,
"appoint, as sole heir to my assets,
my youngest daughter...
"Milly Antonie von Stein.
"For the time being, my oldest daughter,
Edna Luise von Stein, is to manage them."
Etc, etc, etc.
“On Milly's 21st birthday,
the assets will become her property.
"In the eventuality of her death,
disability or mental illness, however,
“the entire assets will become the
property of my daughter, Edna
"who will be obliged to support her sister
"in the event of her disability
or mental illness, by any means possible."
Well, in a few days...
in six days, to be precise,
your sister will come into
possession of your current abode,
your country house in Italy,
and bonds worth 12 million dollars.
I'm afraid that we must prevent
the execution of my father's last will.
Why? What are your motives?
Why should we do something like that?
My sister is insane.
What's written in the will has come true.
My father must have foreseen
that this might happen.
My sister will never be sane again.
Have you got any proof?
This is a certificate from one of
our most famous diagnosticians -
Professor Sebesky.
We'll just sell everything -
the houses, the bonds and the title.
And then we will go far away from here,
and we will live like princes.
Yes, my beloved, but first this drama
must be played out until the end.
Yes.
With a lot of heart.
Yes, and I'll applaud when the little
hypocrite is hospitalised on her birthday.
That hussy will spend the rest of
her life in a mental institution.
How you hate her!
Oh, the good girl, the pretty thing,
the untouched innocent,
Daddy's darling - I hate her.
That old bitch is
calculating and perverted.
Her sweet manner and gentle
smile won't help her now.
Stop thinking about her.
Think only about our future,
and about my convincing
acting over the past year.
Yes.
It deserves a prize...
an Oscar perhaps.
You old rascal!
I did it all for you.
No, you did it all for
yourself, you scoundrel.
Charles, I love you.
CARLOS BARRIOS
Kiss me
The water is pleasant.
Why don't you come in?
It will do you good. Come on.
All right.
Good?
Is the water too cold for you?
No.
- Have you ever seen fish mate?
- No.
Neither have I,
but I can imagine how it's done.
The male approaches the
female and circles around it.
- She ignores him and swims away.
- Like this?
Yes, but he won't give up
and keeps on following her.
Until she feels attracted to him
and lets him get closer.
Then he tries to touch her body gently.
- Like the way I'm touching you now.
- I think I'm falling in love with you.
- Do you think that's bad?
- Love is never bad.
I'm glad you say that.
You're always so kind to me.
Enough of this now.
Come on, let's get out of the water.
It's late, we must dry
ourselves and get dressed.
That was lovely.
Come on, we must hurry.
Your sister will be back soon.
Can we go swimming once
in a while, from now on?
Of course.
Would they fire you, if they saw us?
I hope not. It would be awful
to live here with no one but my sister.
How dare you disobey my strict orders?
Milly is incurably ill.
She is unpredictable and highly dangerous.
I hope this will be the last time
you let Milly out of her room.
You can do anything you want with her,
but only at home, do you understand?
You needn't worry about me, you know.
I refuse to destroy
somebody in this manner.
It's unfair and inhuman.
I'll go of my own accord.
Go, if you're determined to,
but you will go empty-handed.
You can shove my money up your arse!
I know her well.
You'll never see her again.
I don't give a damn,
as long as she doesn't tell on us.
Don't worry.
I'll deal with this.
Well...
I'm going to have to have a word with her.
- Come with me in my car
- Never.
- I'm asking you to.
- Sod you!
That's enough, OK? I need to talk to you.
Come on, get in.
How could you be so wrong about me?
What a devil you are!
- Why am I always taken in by you?
- Why?
- What about Edna?
- But, darling!
How could I ever feel
anything for that iceberg?
I want to fleece her, you know that.
Once I've got the money, you and I
will go away and never come back.
If only Milly wasn't there.
How we've tortured the poor thing!
Don't think about it.
She really is insane.
She always has been.
I'm not sure.
I don't want anything
to do with this any more.
You're absolutely right.
Let's forget about it.
Darling, tell me the truth.
Are you serious when you say that
we will go away to live together
once you have the money?
It's my dearest wish.
And what should I do until then?
Go and visit your sister.
Under the circumstances, it might be
better not to mention this to anyone.
I'll stay in touch.
I should know better, really,
but what have I got to lose?
- Hey, Tom.
- Hey!
There you are.
Thanks.
- Would you like a drink?
- Rum, please.
One double rum, please.
I wanted to ask you a favour.
It's something which demands tact.
I wanted to discuss it with you first.
- You know I'm not stingy.
- And you know I'll do anything for you.
- I want you to do something unusual.
- I'm always ready.
That's what I thought.
- What can I do for you?
- Not so fast.
The main thing is that you
keep your mouth shut.
What? That's my speciality.
Let's go.
So, you're in the picture.
- Yes, I am.
- Come on, then.
But we do it first, or I won't cooperate.
I'll keep my word, and
with great pleasure.
- Sarah.
- Yes, mademoiselle.
Come on.
Darling.
Mademoiselle,
shall I take Monsieur upstairs?
We must get him in the mood first.
Isn't that right, darling?
Yes, mademoiselle.
I'll undress Monsieur.
Excuse me, may I?
We don't want to lose any time.
Let's see the bare facts.
Let's get those pants down.
Right...that's...it.
You behave as if you hadn't
had a man for a long time.
- What a prime specimen!
- It really is a beauty!
- Come on, help yourself.
- May I undress you, mademoiselle?
Come, take me in your arms.
That's enough, mademoiselle.
Remember Milly.
You're right, Sarah, thank you.
Give me a kiss.
And who will kiss me?
We didn't want to exhaust you too much.
You still have a job to do.
Your wish is my command.
I'm always at your service.
Milly is chained up, so you can
do to her whatever you like.
And she enjoys it too.
- I'm looking forward to it
- Have a good time.
- She's in that room up there
- OK.
Edna?
Who are you, then?
Has Edna sent you?
Then come...and take me.
Go on.
Not bad.
Let's get going straight away.
Do it.
Do it!
Oh, this is so amazing! It's fantastic!
Good! Wonderful! Yes, it's
wonderful! I can't bear it.
Yes...yes!
Oh, you're so good at this.
Yes. Oh, yes!
Yes. It's so wonderful. Yes! Yes!
This is so good.
Give it all you've got.
Oh, harder.
Yes, more! Yes!
- Yes.
- Good?
Yes, more.
Careful.
Watch out. I'm going crazy.
What's the matter?
What's wrong with you?
Are you feeling sick?
Edna! Edna!
Edna!
Sarah!
What's wrong?
What happened, mademoiselle?
Oh, my God!
Wake up.
He's not breathing.
Was it a heart attack?
- He's dead.
- How could that happen?
He collapsed.
It was horrible. I couldn't move.
What did you do to him?
- Get him off the bed.
- Sarah, help me get him off Milly.
Quickly! Quickly!
Oh, God, hurry up! Quickly!
- Oh, God. I'm going insane.
- I can't get his leg free.
Hurry up. Pull him away.
- Pull!
- It's getting tricky now. Pull.
- Take him away.
- He's so heavy!
- Wait, I'll help you.
- Yes, give me a hand.
We must get rid of the body somehow.
Sarah, help me undress him.
It's better if he's found naked.
Yes, mademoiselle.
Stop crying!
Now it's getting serious.
You've killed someone, little sister.
No! No!
We must drag him down
the stairs to the door.
Yes, mademoiselle.
Pull the other arm. That'll work best.
We'll put him in the car
and dump him in the sea somewhere.
If he is ever found,
they will think that he drowned.
- That's a great idea, mademoiselle
- Thank you.
I knew I'd see you again.
It wasn't a dream.
You were really here.
And you made me happy.
I was looking for you.
I knew that our first encounter
was only the beginning.
Do you understand?
I want to rescue you.
I will get you out of here.
Oh, yes, please.
I can't stand this place any more.
Do it before it's too late.
You'll recover. I know it.
You'll recover with me.
They'll be here in a minute.
I must get out of here.
Trust me.
My name is Joe. Joe.
And I love you.
Just a second. Thank God.
Is she still in chains?
I've taken them off her.
Good evening.
- Doc?
- Yes?
How about a little shag?
For me, patients are sexless.
I'm offering you my bum
for your pleasure anyway.
Good girl.
That's where you'll get your injection.
Oh, is that it?
This is so good.
Edna?
Edna!
Help!
I want to get out of here!
Let me out! Please let me out!
Open the door! Please!
You're dead.
No!
And they fucked happily ever after.
- Excuse me, may I?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- Would you like to hear another one?
- Everything went as arranged.
- I'm very glad.
So am I, mademoiselle.
...A piece of ice is an ice floe.
The gentleman wants to leave today.
- Was he happy with everything?
- I think so.
- Another one?
- No, we must go now.
- Milly is turning 21 at midnight.
- Little Milly's turning 21?
Milly? It's me, Joe.
Joe, it is you...yes?
- What happened?
- It was horrible.
I...I was having hallucinations.
- There was a dead man.
- Calm down.
Milly, those were no hallucinations.
The guy is alive.
I saw him when I
sneaked into the building.
I saw him drive away,
and then I found you unconscious.
I didn't imagine it?
The man died when we
were in bed together.
That was a few days ago.
He wasn't dead that night, either.
I swear he wasn't.
He left with your sister
and the other woman.
The man looked very happy.
Your sister gave him money.
I had suspected that.
Yes, I had sensed it.
I didn't want to admit to myself
that she could be so wrong and evil.
I'll make sure that this nightmare
is over once and for all
Forget your sister and
what she did to you,
and forget your room in this house.
You must trust me.
I don't have to go back into that room?
- Oh, Joe. Are you really flesh and blood?
- Yes.
- And you're really here?
- Yes, I'm here, and I love you.
Come on.
Joe.
Yes. Yes!
You've made it, darling. It's midnight.
- That calls for champagne.
- Indeed.
- Are you happy, mademoiselle?
- Yes, I am.
- You deserve it, mademoiselle
- Thank you.
Here we go.
And now the third one.
Right.
- What the hell? Let's go for it.
- Yes, I want some.
There you go.
The champagne is served.
Excellent!
Long may she live, our charming Milly
Let's drink to her birthday.
No, you're biting me!
- Just you wait! I'll show you!
- No, I'm ticklish!
Mademoiselle, play with my body.
- Hold me, I'm scared.
- Don't be scared. I'm with you.
All this will be over soon.
- I can hear their car. Hold me.
- It's all right, Milly. Leave it to me.
Oh, Joe, what are you doing?
Are you planning to leave?
- She's coming with me.
- She can't.
Yes, she can. Milly is an adult now.
She wants to be free of her family's love.
Milly, that's not possible. You're sick.
I don't think so.
Vacate the house within three days,
or I'll inform the police
of your activities.
Please hand me the keys to Milly's car.
Charles!
What should I do?
He wants to go away with Milly.
He wants me to give him the car keys.
Should I give them to him?
Yes.
You don't have a choice.
Come on.
Charles, I don't care. I've got you.
I'll go and pack a few things.
I want to leave with you immediately.
Charles! Where are you going?
Charles!
You can't just leave me behind like this.
No! Don't go away!
You bastard!