Subtitles brought to you by the Inheritance Team@Viki.
Episode 49
The patient was involved in a motor vehicle accident.
He is unconscious, and sustained severe trauma to his head and chest.
Defibrillator!
I can't get in touch with you.
I... am at the airport right now.
Call me as soon as you get this message.
Shock!
Where have you been with your cell phone turned off?
I was worried about you.
I met with Chae Won.
What for?
I met with her, and
gave her a plane ticket.
Plane ticket?
Yes.
By now,
they will be sitting side by side on the plane.
Seriously, why are you doing this?
What are thinking by doing all of this?
I had to do this.
I did it because I feel bad for Se Yoon and Choon Hee.
I'm protecting the last bit of conscience I have left.
I feel bad for Chae Won and Choon Hee too, but
all it's not going to get fixed by doing this.
Right now you are
just making it worse.
Let's...
get a divorce.
What?
I did this with
the worst case in my mind.
Without any conditions,
I'll just do as you wish.
Hello.
Is this Lee Se Yoon's residence?
Yes, that is right.
Who is this?
This is the Emergency Department of Sae Han Hospital.
Emergency room?
Why isn't he picking up the phone?
Excuse me.
Yes, what can I help you with?
There is a person I'm supposed to be catching a plane with, but that person isn't picking up the phone.
Can you check the passenger list?
I'm sorry, I can't do that due to the Personal Information Protection Act.
I see.
Se Yoon's Mom
Yes, Mother.
I'm at the departure gate right now, but we didn't meet yet because I couldn't get in touch with Se Yoon.
What?
Emergency room?
Doctor! Doctor. Doctor.
Our Se Yoon... What happened to our Se Yoon?
He had a cardiac arrest when he arrived to the emergency room.
After receiving immediate treatment, heart function has been restored.
How in the world...?
Then, is he alright now?
Due to trauma from the car accident, his blood vessels ruptured, and blood has accumulated in the subdural space.
If he doesn't get the blood clot removed surgically, then it could kill him.
Then, can he recover if he gets the surgery?
The outcome is poor if it's an acute subdural hemorrhage.
Though it varies.
Even with surgical interventions, 60% of patients could die.
Honey!
No... It can't happen...
That can't be Doctor, it can't.
Please save our Se Yoon.
It can't, I beg you doctor.
I'll do my best.
Mother!
What about Se Yoon?
Surgery...right now...
Surgery...started...
I'm sorry...
I should have gone to you a little earlier, Se Yoon.
Give me another chance...
One more, please Se Yoon.
Please speed up more.
Hurry.
Let's go there fast.
I'm going as fast as I can.
I'm sorry, Se Yoon.
I'm being a burden to you to the end.
It's all my fault.
If I hadn't called him,
this accident wouldn't have happened.
Why did I do something that I wasn't even told?
It's not your fault, so
don't blame yourself. It's not your fault.
Wait for me, Se Yoon.
Mom is on her way, wait..
Chae Won!
Mom.
Se Yoon. What about Se Yoon?
He is in surgery right now.
What did the Doctor say?
Will he be fine after the surgery?
He'll be alright, right Unni?
If he just receives the surgery, he'll be fine. Right Brother-in-law?
Choon Hee.
What is it?
Is it very serious?
All he needs is the surgery, right?
We arrived at your house safely, sir.
Yes, you've worked very hard.
The world is quite small.
You and I used to be neighbors.
Until recently, I lived in this neighborhood.
My house was right next to yours.
You're lying too much.
Why would someone who used to live in this neighborhood be a substitute driver?
Yes, well I...
because of personal reasons it just turned out that way.
You've worked hard.
Yes, please go inside.
My bedroom is lit up brightly.
Did someone move in already?
Coco!
Mom is having a hard time so stay still.
Agashi.
Mrs. Park!
Welcome back, Agashi.
You're not even alone. You had a hard time, right?
Do you know what a good baby this is in my womb?
As soon as I got on the plane, I slept soundly.
When did you come, Mrs. Park?
I came a while ago. I cleaned the house,
went to the market, and made kimchi.
I missed your kimchi so much Mrs. Park.
This is great.
How is your Mom?
She's better.
She can sleep without sleeping medicine.
And she laughs once in a while.
That is a relief.
I'm hungry.
Aigoo, look at me.
Let's go inside, quickly.
Coco.
Something bad can happen!
What would happen if you take so many pills at once?
I'm so burning up inside! What should I do then?!
Something bad can happen, Mom!
Death is the worst thing that can happen.
Leave me alone.
Why are you suddenly crying?
When you say things like that, my heart feels like it will burst.
If it wasn't for me, you and Oppa wouldn't have gone through all this.
I really want to die.
I understand, Joo Ri.
I won't get angry in the future. Don't cry.
Don't cry, Joo Ri.
I'm back.
Where have you been all day that you're coming back just now?
I started my job as a replacement driver.
What?
Until I find a suitable job, I think of this as an experience in life.
Aigoo, aigoo.
Aigoo.
Aiyoo...
My precious child...
How did he end up like this?
Since I have committed so many sins,
I'm paying for them now.
Mom, really, why are you taking it so seriously?
I told you I'm just doing it for the experience.
I'm really good.
Aigoo, how did I raise you?
How in the world could something like this happen?
What am I supposed to do?
Why is Mom overly sensitive today?
Ok, ok! Dry you tears.
I bought chicken, so eat it up.
Here.
Mom, here.
Aigoo! It's fine.
Right now, do you think
I'm in a mood to tear up a chicken leg?
Aigoo Mom! Really, this
won't taste good if it gets cold. Hurry!
I bought you the kind that you like, fried.
Is it warm?
Of course, it's warm.
Why are you guys being like this in front of food?
If someone were to hear you, they would think we were killing a chicken.
Se Yoon...
Open your eyes.
Mom is here.
Chae Won... Chae Won is here, too.
Se Yoon, wake up, please!
Doctor, how come he's not waking up?
By any chance, did something go wrong with the surgery?
As you heard from Dr. Kim, the surgery was successful.
However...
What do you mean?
Since trauma to the brain was severe,
we don't know what will happen after the surgery. We'll have to monitor further.
There could be other complications.
What do you mean "other complications"? Perhaps, he'll never regain consciousness?
Unfortunately, there is a high probability that may happen.
That can't happen, Doctor.
Absolutely something like that cannot happen, Doctor!
We cannot let that happen, Doctor. Please make our son wake up!
Please!
Se Yoon...
Se Yoon, try to open your eyes.
Your mom is here, Se Yoon.
Se Yoon, open your eyes...
Please...
Se Yoon...
Don't worry too much, Choon Hee.
Our Se Yoon will wake up soon.
After the anesthesia wears off, and he sleeps the night,
he'll wake up
as if nothing happened.
I should not have come back.
If it weren't for me,
our children wouldn't have such a difficult time.
Our Se Yoon wouldn't have to leave for the States.
And, he wouldn't have been in the car accident.
What are you saying?
When you think about it, it's all my fault.
Only if I didn't steal our Se Yoon
from the maternity ward that day...
My greed and sins
have led to today's tragedy.
I should have been the one to get punished...
Why our Se Yoon...?
If you don't want me to go, I won't go.
If you don't want me to go to the U.S. branch, then I won't.
I am sorry.
Be healthy,
and stay well.
I'm sorry.
Only if I wasn't stubborn to the end,
this wouldn't have happened.
I am too ashamed to see you.
Nothing bad will happen.
After he sleeps well tonight,
he will wake up tomorrow morning.
Ok.
He should.
Seriously, how many first loves do you have, Oppa?
Didn't I tell you that all love is first love?
So,
to propose to your first love from your 30's,
we went to look at the rings,
and you sang in front of me to practice. Is that what happened?
Thanks, Kang Sook. You helped a lot.
This is so embarrassing. So embarrassing...
What kind of embarrassment is this?
You wife, what did you do well that you are drinking?
Why am I your wife?
How am I your wife?
Look at you...
How could you yell at me when you are the one who's done wrong?
I haven't done anything good, but I haven't don't anything wrong either!
You haven't done anything wrong?
You fooled around with that gigolo guy behind my back.
And you still haven't done anything wrong?
Tell me honestly.
If that gigolo had proposed to you, you would have said ok, right?
No, it's not like that.
What do you mean, "it's not like that?"
You were so into him that Bo Reum, and I were nothing to you.
Look, you can't even answer me.
Even though we have stamped the divorce paper, as a human being, you shouldn't act that way.
You have to have a conscience.
Truthfully, we were happy.
Because living was hard,
my heart grew cold.
Since Oppa said I was pretty, he was attentive,
I felt my heart softened.
I only got treated as a wife by you.
It's been a while since I was treated as a woman. I was happy.
I thought if I could only spend one day with someone like him and die, I'd have no regrets.
It wouldn't be enough if you begged on your hands and knees.
What are you saying right now?
Why should I beg you? I have not done anything wrong to you.
Bo Reum's mom! Kang Sook!
I'm curious about something.
About what?
How did you find out about me meeting with Oppa, and started to follow me?
Did Aghassi tell you?
No, that's not what happened.
The day you got your flower present...
You sent the text to me in error that was meant for that gigolo.
After that, I became suspicious, and started to follow you.
They say you can only steal if you're used to it.
Gong Kang Sook, you're really pathetic.
But, why did you act like if you didn't know anything?
Unlike someone else, I don't have anything, and I'm not educated.
How could I hold on to you?
If you met a nice guy, I should just wish you happiness.
That's what a man should do.
Are you being sincere?
Of course.
You're pretty good.
But,
just don't forget one thing.
Like I only have one heart, my love is only for you.
Bo Reum's dad.
Sook, you're...
the first and only love of my life.
Thanks.
Thanks, Bo Reum's dad.
And, I'm sorry.
Why are you sorry...?
I'm the one who has committed a crime for giving you a difficult life.
No...
You're not a criminal.
You're a good guy.
Kang Sook!
I did wrong.
I'll never cheat on you.
You're Lee Se Yoon's guardian, right?
Yes, so...
This belongs to Lee Se Yoon but
I wanted to give it earlier, but I must've forgotten.
Do you like it?
I'm going back to Seoul right now,
so Se Yoon go to your mom.
Chae Won.
Chae Won!
I'm sorry, Se Yoon.
If I hadn't done that back then,
this wouldn't have happened.
For the last time, just once more...
Give me one more chance.
Please...
Why? Are you feeling unwell?
I've no appetite.
Even if you don't like it, eat it Mom.
If you continue like this, it can be a big problem.
What am I to do when I don't have any appetite.
Even when I'm sitting still,
my stomach feels like it's on a roller coaster ride.
I feel naseous and
everything is about to come up from my stomach and
I feel like I'm going to suffer like this and
not able to live out my age.
Come with me to the hospital Mom.
Aigoo, forget it.
It's without a doubt the emotional disorder so what the point in going to a hospital?
Be it emotional or internal illness, let's have a doctor check you out first.
Forget it!
Why waste money?
Mom, seriously!
You scared me.
Please just listen to me.
Yeah, Mom.
If you leave illness from emotional stress alone for too long, it can lead to a serious illness.
Go and come back safely.
Fine.
I said fine.
Let's go.
I'm going to go park the car, so on go in first.
Aigoo, alright.
This car is the size of a nostril.
Excuse us, excuse us.
Wait, who is that?
Isn't that Lee Se Yoon.
Wait a moment.
Where did this person get hurt to come here?
He was in a car accident.
Car accident?
Where are you taking him right now?
We are in the process of moving him from a critical care unit to general admission.
Hey, Lee Se Yoon.
Open your eyes. It's me, Kim Cheol Gyoo.
This patient has not gained consciousness?
We aren't sure.
You're interfering with moving the patient, so please move.
Oh...ok.
He was in a car accident? What is this now?
The edema reduction in the brain went well, and the pressure on the brain decreased.
So, the area operated on has recovered.
But, why is he still unconscious?
We are utilizing every medical method, so
let's wait and see.
Then, you don't know when he will regain consciousness?
Yes. To determine whether he would regain consciousness or avoid disability,
it is a bit premature to decide at this moment.
We should wait and see how it develops.
Only,
if the coma state continues for more than 4 months,
then the likely of recovery
diminishes to less than 15%.
So what your saying is, that our Se Yoon..
No, it can't be. Not four months...not even four days!
Please, please save my son.
Calm down, that definitely won't happen.
Don't worry ahead of time.
What are you doing here?
Chae Won.
How did you know about this?
We came here for my mom's check up because she wasn't feeling well.
I happened to see him in the hallway as I was passing by.
I overheard it in passing, but
it sounds like he hasn't been able to regain consciousness, is that right?
Se Yoon,
will regain consciousness for certain!
Until he regains consciousness,
be it a year or 10 years,
until the day I die, I will protect him.
Chae Won.
Therefore,
there is no way that I am coming back to you.
Stop waiting for something that won't happen.
So please,
don't persist in staying and lurking around my vicinity.
Please find your own path and go.
This is my last request.
Choon Hee.
Se Yoon,
watch over him.
I'm leaving.
Unni...
Perhaps, Se Yoon...
wants to be with you too.
The last person he wanted to see
was you.
All the mother-son affection you couldn't share until now,
share it now.
Also,
if you ever need me,
call me anytime.
Ok?
You...
I'm sure would know how to do it
and take care of him.
Our Se Yoon,
look after him well.
My son,
you're giving me an extra opportunity to be a mom, right?
Because you know that mom is so frustrated and upset
over being separated for 30 years.
You wanted to give me a chance to stay without regret,
so you're doing this on purpose, my son?
Just...
where did he-
Hey!
Where did you go that you are just coming back now? I had to get a checkup all alone.
Is that so? I just happened to meet someone that I know.
Hand me the prescription. I'll go fill it for you.
What business does that woman have here?
Pretend like you don't know.
Let go of me.
Last time when I went to Chae Won's factory,
I said some harsh things, so
I felt yucky all along.
This is good.
What's wrong with you?
Lee Se Yoon.
Has been admitted into this hospital.
Why?
He was in a car accident.
Car accident?
How badly is he hurt? Is it serious?
We're back.
Did Se Yoon wake up?
Not yet.
You mean he's still unconscious?
Ah, longer it lasts worse it gets. What to do?
What about Hyungnim?
Didn't you guys go together?
She's with Se Yoon.
We are going to switch later on tonight.
Which room in O-Neul (Today) hospital is he in? I should go there.
Later, Mother-in-law.
She wanted to be alone with Se Yoon,
that's why we came back.
You should go when things calm down a bit.
Ok then.
Aigoo.
What can we do for my poor puppy?
We're going to have a heat stroke at this rate.
Are you okay, Honey?
I'm fine.
Don't worry about me,
just go home and rest.
Don't suffer with me.
How is this suffering?
I heard they dropped an unbelievable amount of flyers, but there's not an ant in sight.
Let's just call it a day and retreat?
He's right, Honey.
Let's just fold and go home.
I can't do that!
This is my first Fan Autographing in my life,
I can't stop here.
Start the music.
In a moment,
Teuroteu genre's Psy,
Teuroteu genre's Gentleman (Psy's follow up hit to GangNam style)
Ddool Uh's Gang Jin's autographing will take place.
To the first
10 fans
we're planning on giving
Gang Jin autographed CD "Ddool Uh."
Run here as quickly as even your eyebrows would blow.
This is when you turn on the Ddool Uh!
Ah ci! (Come on)
Who is that there?
Isn't it Husband Kang?
It looks like it.
It is him.
Sister-in-law is there too.
Just what is he doing over there?
It looks like he's having a fan signing.
Not a single soul is seen, Mother-in-law.
♫  Even if living gets to be hard,
♫ I shouldn't get stressed out. ♫
♫  Love makes me cry.. ♫
I think we should go and increase the head count, Mother-in-law.
Let's go home.
What?
We don't have time.
Quickly.
Bo Reum's Mom.
Bo Reum's Mom, are you here?
Yes, Mom?
Yes, you
quickly make some noodles.
Why noodles?
♫  I won’t ever cry again,
♫ I will show you a smiling me.
♫  I don’t want to stop, I want to keep going
♫  a little more, dear heart.  ♫
♫  Because I have you, who is looking at me,
What is this?
♫  I can withstand this. ♫
What's going on?
This is mom's order to provide man power to Kang Jin's fan autographing event.
Man power support?
Mom!
Now,
we're about to put on an event that will
cool your hot summer with a singer Kang Jin.
Now Teuroteu genre's Psy's Kang Jin fan event is
taking place across the street from the town center.
There will be cool summer noodles for the first arrivals.
Come down and eat the cool noodles
and get Kang Jin's autograph too.
Here. Please come down.
Welcome.
This is a 4th generation noodle.
Please taste it.
You can't only eat the noodles,
you must also get an autograph.
Yes.
Kang Jin? I've never heard of that singer.
Why don't you just sing us a song, live?
♫ Ddool Uh, ddool uh, ddool uh ♫
♫ Break down this blocked world, ddool uh ♫
♫ just look ahead and run ♫
♫ Break down my life, just ddool uh ♫
Thank you.
♫  Even if living gets to be hard,
♫  you shouldn't receive any stress. ♫
♫ Love makes you cry. ♫
♫ Money makes you feel bad about yourself. ♫
By the way, I don't see that "being?"
That being?
You know, the In Jeol Mi brushed with sesame oil.
Your first love.
First love?
Tell him to get lost.
Thanks Mom.
Roof-top Gigolo can at least
belt it out!
What do you mean roof-top gigolo? How can you say such things, Mom?
Aiyoo, mannerless wench.
You come after me with fire in your eyes
if I say anything half bad about her hubby!
I'm kidding, kidding.
Be it a year or 10 years,
until the day I die, I will protect him.
Me going back to you?
It'll be best to stop hoping for something that won't happen.
Yes. Did you call a substitute driver?
To the Tae Sang Group headquarter?
Yes, yes. I understand. I'm extremely fast.
I'll be there within 10 minutes.
Go ahead and count only to ten, okay?
Ok.
Did you call a substitute driver?
Yes.
I'll drive you safely to your destination.
Where would you like to go, Costumer?
The terrace land on the Han River?
Ok.
I'm going.
Stop peeping and keep your eyes on the road, shall we?
Yes, I'm sorry.
Seriously!
What kind of driving is this? Will you straighten up?
That's her voice.
I guess at least you didn't forget your ex-wife's voice.
It's been awhile,
Driver Kim.
Why are you here?
Business.
Business?
I have some ideas to think about for business.
Ah, I see. Ideas for your business...
I see. How did you find out that I was a substitute driver?
The fact that Kim Cheol Gyoo has become a complete pauper and is driving cars for people
has even reached Paris.
What did you say?
I'm hungry.
Let's not go to the Han River. Let's go somewhere close by to eat,
Driver Kim.
Isn't it possible for you to buy a meal
to an ex-wife you haven't seen in a while?
Why aren't you driving?
Where is this place?
This is a train-station cafe.
This is the only place I can afford to buy you a meal in my current position.
Portion's big, taste is good...within the city of Seoul it's renown as the best drivers' cafe.
Okay, I like it.
Lend me your hand.
Asking for all kinds pomp and procedures...
Wa-wah-what is this?
What?
Why is your belly like this? Are you sick?
I'm pregnant.
P..pr...
Pregnant?
Were you remarried in that short time?
Where's the baby's father?
Why did you hit?
Is that something a baby's father should say?
Baby-daddy?
Wh... Who? Me?
Wow I'm going to go crazy!
Just once.
I got drunk and made one mistake. Not even twice but just once!
And you can get pregnant?
I know, right?
You have some skills, babe.
Really, how can in just one try can you be pregnant?
What kind of...
You sure are repeating "just once" a lot.
Do you want me to name the child in our belly "just once?"
Can you joke in a time like this?
Ms. Na Hong Joo.
Look me straight in the eyes and say it.
Is this really my baby?
Are you absolutely certain?
Oh, okay! I'm sorry.
Sorry! Really, I'm sorry.
I won't say to be responsible for this so
don't feel burdened.
Not that it's a burden but
it's just so sudden, that's what...
I'm... saying.
How are you feeling?
Do you have any morning-sickness or...?
The baby in my tummy is so sweet not at all like us.
As you can tell, I don't have morning sickness and don't have any discomfort.
I'm glad.
How is it going with the ex-wife?
I guess not so good?
Ahjumma!
Can you bring out one more Jab-Chae-bob (chop suey rice), please?
You want to order another Jab-Chae-bab?
Are you throwing a banquet? When are you going to eat all this?
Ai! Small scale...
I'll pay for the meal.
Well, I'm not saying that because I have no money to pay for the meal or anything..
It's time for you to get up now.
Wake up and take a walk with mom and
take a trip together. Hm?
You're here.
I'm glad you're here, Chae Won.
Tonight, I'll stay with him.
Mom, why don't you go home with dad.
No, it's okay.
I'm sure you're tired from working all day at the factory.
Why don't you let Chae Won take over tonight?
Mother-in-law is waiting at home with bells on.
Yes, Mom.
Let me have a date with Se Yoon too, please.
I understand.
Se Yoon,
Mom's going to go now
and come back early tomorrow morning, okay?
Take care of him.
Okay.
Drive carefully.
♫ We still have much to say...♫
♫ We still have much to do...♫
♫ Maybe I'm bad?♫♫ Is someone taking good care of you? ♫
♫ Maybe I'm still saying goodbye...♫♫ I think ♫
I'm here.♫ I'm living a life frozen in time. ♫
Because I was worried about you all day,
my battery is completely drained.
♫ I should not think of you...♫
Can you recharge me?♫ because we have parted ways. ♫
♫ Why am I so dumb like this? ♫♫ Is this all that I could be? ♫
♫ I think I still love you.♫
Recharge initiate!
♫ All I do is worry about you...♫
Recharging Initiate!
Ai, hurry up and recharge me. I'm completely out!
♫ Me, who's in your eyes...♫
♫ If I could only see myself again...♫
♫ In your mind... ♫♫ I am right here. ♫
Recharging Complete!
♫ If I could only get into your heart ♫
Recharging complete.
♫ again... ♫
♫ in your eyes... ♫
What's this?
Since you've recharged me
I feel energized.
What are you talking about?
What do you mean Sun Bae (Se Yoon) is in a coma?
Are you serious? I've been saying it the whole time.
Why do you ask again?
He was in an accident and received a brain surgery
but he still hasn't gained consciousness for few days.
If his condition continues, could he
be in a permanent vegetative state?
Why do you say such an unlucky thing?!
Why do you shout so loudly, you scared me to death!
Of course I'm saying it because I'm worried. Worried!
If I think about it now
Se Yoon really was a genuine person.
Hey, hey, Joo Ri! Where are you going in the middle of your meal?
I'm done.
I'll be right back!
Aigoo, that girl just shout aloud and...
I'm back.
Ai...hey, you worked hard.
Wash your hands before you sit down.
Mom will make you a plate.
I don't have any appetite.
Why don't you have any appetite?
Why? Did something happen?
Is there something going on?
Hong Joo,
came back to Korea, Mom.
That being...what's there to gain by coming back?
Hey,
do you have her contact information?
I'd like to meet with her.
You Mom? Why?
I've been thinking that we've given too much of alimony.
Even if it's little, we should get back some of that money
and buy a decent apartment...
MOM!
Aigoo!
Hey you scared me half to death! Why in the world are you all shouting?
I almost dropped (lost) a baby! ("drop" = colloquialism for losing a baby. Typical expression when one is shocked.)
Are you pregnant too?
What?
You...imbecile.
How in the world this old mom be pregnant?
Cham (Man, I just don't understand...)
You uncaring thing,
how can you so cruelly cut off communication without even a phone call?
Was the attachment you and I formed so shallow?
I'm sorry.
I thought that me disappearing
was the best way for the children.
I'm so sorry.
Are the kids the only thing that you care about and not the family?
Your father was
until the end
missing you so much.
I'm so sorry.
I made such a terrible filial sin, I'm sorry.
I'm sure father-in-law understood all.
Definitely,
he was so pleased with the Soo Yi (burlap wrap for burial) you made for him.
By the way,
Se Yoon should regain consciousness soon. I'm worried.
Don't worry about that.
Your father isn't someone who'd just spectate up in heaven.
He will use what leverage he has over the Great Jade Emperor
to have Se Yoon return to the way he was, so don't you worry a thing.
That's right.
Listening to this, I think Mother-in-law is right.
Let's just tie down all our worries!
I'm sorry.
I made you worry so much.
And,
thank you for welcoming me back.
My mom likes it!
Yes?
I came.
I was too worried so I came even though it was shameless.
I'm sorry.
No reason to be sorry.
Se Yoon would be happy to see you.
Sun Bae,
why are you lying down like this?
Get up please.
I had such a hard time over Eun Seol's car accident,
how can you be down like this too?
I didn't have a chance to apologize to you properly for all the bad things I've done.
What am I supposed to do with you lying unconscious like this, Sun Bae?
Get up, I beg you.
Get up and listen to what I have to say, please?
I don't know if God would listen to a prayer from a bad girl like me, but
I'll pray that Se Yoon wakes up soon.
Thank you.
You are having such a hard time...
Unni (older sister)
I can start to understand how you felt now that I'm in a difficult situation.
And sometimes I feel like I'm being punished for all the bad things I've done.
I feel like that.
I've been too harsh to you in the past.
I didn't give you proper respect as an older person,
belittled you,
wrongly frame you.
I should have stopped mom when she did those things.
instead I did worse than her next to mom
and tormented you..
I was immature.
If I came to my senses a little earlier...
Unni and I, aside from being sisters-in-law,
do you think we could have perhaps have been good friends?
I'm off.
Before you come to meet me, won't you go meet the flower first?
Then, we would never ever fight
without talking bad about others
and through talk of lovely things.
What is it again?
What again? You say?
You can't say "what again" to the customer.
I better call your company and complain that they should train their drivers better.
Why do you keep calling me back and forth?
I have a check-up scheduled for today. I want you to go with me.
Don't you think you should at least do this much as a father of the baby?
Well, you're right but...
Open the door, Driver Kim.
I said, open the door!
This woman is really...
Wider!
Yes, ma'am.
I'm going crazy here.
Stuff I saw on TV is happening to me.
As you see,10 fingers,
10 toes,
two ears, mouth, and nose. Everything is fine.
When we take a detailed sonogram,
babies don't position their bodies favorable so usually
it's so hard for the mother.
But, the baby doesn't want the mother to work so hard.
All of it's 10 fingers are spread.
I see.
Is the baby healthy, Doctor?
Yes,
kidney, lungs, liver, spine, everything is normal.
I think it's moving!
Is it yawning, Doctor?
Yes,
it seems so.
Wow! It's so amazing!
Look, look, look, right Honey?
I mean, Hong Joo.
Chi (oh, please.)
Is there anywhere you feel uncomfortable?
Around my lower back there is some.
That's because you gained weight suddenly.
It's good for the husband to massage the area before bedtime.
It's good at calming the fetus as well.
It's been over a month since he has been moved here, Doc.
When will he wake up?
In the case of this patient, the condition isn't simply an unconsciousness or unawareness but
it has progressed to a vegetative state.
A vegetative state?
When the condition is prolonged in this state for more than a month,
it is accurate to assume he will not regain consciousness.
Then,
forever
he cannot wake up...
is that what you're saying?