Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Gun Wook.
- Gun Wook. Shim Gun Wook!
- You're getting wet.
Shim Gun Wook!
Hello?
What?
Shim Gun Wook has disappeared?
Shim Gun Wook.
You...
You're here?
Stop right there.
Shim Gun Wook.
He's someone who messed with me.
You think I'm just going let him be?
Shim Gun Wook, Shim Gun Wook
- He's someone who messed with me...
- Where'd he go?
You think I'm just, you think,
you think I'm just going to let him be?
Where did he go?
Whoever does it, it has to get done,
whoever does it, it has to get done...
You! What the hell are you up to?
You think you can scare me like this?!
I should have cleanly gotten rid of you
like your parents twenty years ago!
Shim Gun Wook, come out.
Come out. Come out.
Come out like a man!
Shim Gun Wook! Come out!
Come out!
Where are you? Come out!
He's not outside either.
Did you find him?
Yes, Chief,
I came to the hospital,
but Gun Wook has disappeared.
You're not coming?
Go in on your own.
I don't want to see him much anymore.
I hope nothing has happened.
You don't think anything has, do you?
I'm not going to come looking
for you anymore.
Be well with Gun Wook.
After all, he's not in good condition.
I'm dumping you right now.
Go on.
Shim Gun Wook...
will probably need you.
Okay, I'll be going then.
Thank you, Tae Seong.
Gun Wook...
Gun Wook, are you here?
Gun Wook.
Gun Wo...
What are you doing here again?
What is all this?
Ask Gun Wook when you see him.
Gun Wook... is alive?
Is he alive?
Yes.
He's alive.
Where is he right now?
I was looking for him just now also.
Where did he go in his poor condition?
What do you mean his poor condition?
What's wrong?
He couldn't even recognize me.
He couldn't recognize you?
He's very unwell.
The two of you must be much closer
than I thought.
The news that he died,
and that he was alive,
you knew all of it.
What is this stuck to the walls?
Gun Wook was seeing me and
you were seeing Tae Seong.
Were the two of you planning
something against our family?
Is that what's important right now?
You feel only how wronged you
were in being deceived, don't you?
What about Gun Wook who couldn't
help but do what he did?
What about Gun Wook's scars?
Stop.
Why do I have to hear that sort
of thing from you?
And, from someone who's going to
marry Tae Seong?
It's over between Tae Seong and me.
Why?
Because Tae Seong turned out
not to be my father's son,
you no longer want to marry him?
Well, since there was never any love...
What do you mean?
So, you're saying it doesn't matter what
Tae Seong feels?
So, Tae Seong...
isn't Chairman Hong's real son?
No.
Tae Seong is alone now.
If Tae Seong has never been a son
of Haeshin from the start,
I wonder, would you have even dated him?
Right now...
It makes no matter to me what
position he's in.
What's important to me now
is who is this man that I want to be with.
So, I can't be with Tae Seong.
That...
would be unfair to Tae Seong too.
Yes, Chief, what about Gun Wook?
They say he's been moved to
another hospital.
Right now, I think it's better if
you just waited.
Okay. Anyhow, that's a relief.
I understand.
And, I thought it wouldn't taste good.
Oh, hello.
Shim Gun Wook's attendant told me
to give this to you, and I forgot.
To me?
What could it be?
Detective Lee,
- get an arrest warrant issued.
- A warrant for who?
Madam Shin Myung Won.
You are under arrest for aiding and
abetting a murder.
You have the right to remain silent...
What are you talking about aiding and
abetting a murder?
- Beom Woo,
- Yes?
- you do it.
- Yes, Sir.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say...
What is this? What are you doing?
Let go of me!
What do you mean aiding and abetting
a murder?
Let go! What is this?
Name.
- Ask my lawyer when he comes.
- Shin Myung Won.
Name.
Why do you ask when you know already?
I'm trying to conduct a questioning here!
Shin Myung Won.
Name.
He prepared everything impeccably.
And how was Shim Gun Wook?
I suppose he couldn't forgive
the 2 faces of Shin Myung Won.
And so, he drove Shin Myung Won
to kill him the same way she killed
his parents,
and is forcing her to answer for that crime.
And to think she deceived Hong Tae Seong
for all those years.
Shim Gun Wook was shocked
to hear about that as well.
Because Hong Tae Seong was
a victim like he had been.
Because of one person,
a great many people
led some very difficult lives.
What do you think will happen?
The evidence is so clear-cut that
we don't have much of a chance.
But, thankfully, Shim Gun Wook is alive,
so it won't come to the worst.
What's going on?
Mother tried to kill Shim Gun Wook?
Why?
I don't know, either.
Shim Gun Wook's side has submitted
evidence.
I'm really going to have to see that guy.
Whoa.
This is seriously cool.
Unni!
It's too much of a waste to
just return this.
This is really nice.
Hey, leave it in the case.
I'm going to return it.
Just a sec.
Unni...
Unni, there's something engraved on it.
What?
"To Jae In."
"Be with me."
Be with me.
If you stay with me,
I think I could bear it, without swaying.
Tae Seong, a woman who sincerely loves you
will turn up soon.
Put it in the box.
Ah, Unni, it's too much of a waste
to give it back!
Aye, I would look pretty cool
if I were wearing it.
Shim Gun Wook!
Shim Gun Wook, open the door!
Do you have to lock Madame Shin
in jail?
Will that make you feel better?!
Huh?!
You still can't shake that rage?
Are you that bitter about getting
kicked out?
Even if the life you believed in turned out
to be lies, it makes no difference.
Don't even retaliate.
You'll only end up living recklessly,
and the hurt you bring to anyone
along the way can't be erased.
Feel wronged and bitter?
There's nothing we can do about it.
Because that's you...
and...
that's me.
[Subsidiaries Collapse One After the
Other "Will Haeshin Be Ruined?"]
[The Two Faces of Haeshin "Social Work
in the Front, Murder in the Back"]
The prosecution will please begin
questioning.
Defendant Shin Myung Won, on July 14th,
you told Kim Seong Jong to kill
Shim Gun Wook, correct?
No.
Why would I have such a trivial
person killed?
Judge, we have a recording of
the defendant's conversation.
Please allow us to play it here.
Please do so.
Shim Gun Wook.
He's someone who messed with me.
You think I'm just going to let him be?
Whoever does it, it has to be done.
Why? Are you scared?
I'm not someone who will wait a long time.
Be warned,
Manager Kim, that this is your last chance.
Defendant?
That's your voice on the recording, correct?
Yes, that's correct.
You ordered the killing of
Shim Gun Wook, correct?
No, I did no such thing.
Those are words I said in anger.
I will ask you once again.
Did you order the killing of Shim Gun Wook?
No.
I told you I did no such thing.
The defense shall now question
the defendant.
The defendant merely spoke in
a moment of anger.
But in actuality,
you didn't have any intention
of murder, did you?
None, whatsoever.
What wouldn't a person say in anger?
When seeing someone you hate,
you say "I wish he were dead",
"I wish he'd disappear from my sight".
Everyone says that sort of thing.
But do they actually kill anyone?
Prosecutor, when you say,
"Oh my, this is killing me",
do you die?
You don't, do you?
Just because I said that, I would kill him?
Am I crazy?
To do such a thing?
When Chairman Hong had collapsed and
was bedridden,
in the hospital room,
Shin Myung Won told me
to get rid of Shim Gun Wook.
What is this?
At that time, were you actually
going to kill Shim Gun Wook?
No.
I contacted Shim Gun Wook,
and informed him of her intent.
You know Shin Myung Won, don't you?
No.
I don't know that person.
I submit as evidence transcripts of
their phone conversations.
When she found out he was alive,
she was mentally obsessed.
She told me to kill him again.
When did I?!
I don't know that person.
Someone is trying to trap me and
has conspired with all these people.
But it'll never happen.
You think I'll be taken down like this?!
I don't know that man!
I don't know him!
Defendant, please be silent!
We submit this video as evidence.
You! Where are you hiding?!
You think you can scare me like this?!
I should have cleanly gotten rid of you
like your parents twenty years ago!
Where are you? Come out!
Where are you? Where are you?!
That's a phony. Someone messed with
a computer
and made that unbelievable piece
of garbage.
They schemed to put me away.
They've joined with Shim Gun Wook!
They've all schemed this!
I didn't kill him! I didn't kill anyone!
I've never killed anyone!
I didn't do it, didn't! I didn't kill anyone!
I didn't do it, I didn't!
I didn't kill anyone, I didn't.
I didn't kill anyone.
I didn't kill anyone!
Defendant,
please give your final statement.
The nature of this disgraceful issue
is entirely humiliating and unpleasant
for Haeshin Group and myself.
But to expose the truth,
I'll bear with the indignity.
I am a woman who raised
someone else's child like my own.
The boy that once might have been my son...
Would I have really ordered him killed?
What do I have to be anxious about?
What am I lacking?
This is merely
the wicked scheming and a trick laid out
by a vengeful madman!
So dirty.
Disgusting.
Murderer.
You can't do this!
Come out!
Gun Wook lost his family to you!
And lost his identity!
You've taken every shred of his life!
Your lies will absolutely be exposed!
You'll pay for the rest of your life
for your crime!
That manipulative girl is having
a complete tirade.
She can't make her way into our family.
So of course, she must be bitter and angry.
A thing like you, how dare you... to me.
Moon Jae In.
Have you met with Gun Wook?
How is he?
He seems healthy.
He says he'll be back soon,
so just wait a little longer.
Ah, take this.
What is this?
I was examining it, thinking it could be
evidence,
but something else was recorded on it.
Moon Jae In, are you listening?
This is the truth behind the world
you respected.
What are you going to do now?
You decide.
I'll always be in the same place.
Hong Tae Seong.
Hong Tae Seong,
you kill your brother,
turn your father into a dummy,
and toy with your little sister?
So, did you have a nice reunion
with your father?
What did the chairman call you that night?
"Tae Seong".
Didn't he call you that?
- You should go...
- Let go!
I should have my say before I go.
You can't even recognize your own father
and make him collapse?
You kill your flesh and blood?
You don't believe me?
You're Hong Tae Seong.
No matter what anyone says,
don't forget you're Hong Tae Seong, okay?
The children got switched?!
But, we even had his DNA tested...
I'm sorry.
I threw away the real thing
and brought in a fake.
Ultimately, you lost your parents,
your siblings, everything.
I won.
Got it?
Young Master,
I'm sorry for speaking so late.
The day of the accident,
you said you wanted to see me.
Actually...
Tell me.
Actually, to block you,
Madam Shin told me never to say anything.
But since you know everything now...
What did Mother just say?
Gun Wook... is really Tae Seong?
Father's son,
my little brother?
Has Mother left?
Tae Seong...
So, did you have a nice reunion with
your father?
What did the chairman call you that night?
"Tae Seong".
Tae Seong!
Dad!
Tae Seong's here!
Now try saying it.
Dad.
That's right.
Tae Seong, I'm your dad.
You look familiar for some reason.
This is our first meeting,
but you really look familiar.
Hello,
I'm Shim Gun Wook.
Shim Gun Wook's mother,
the woman named Chae Yeon,
worked at the reception desk at our company.
So I thought for sure he was the son.
I found it strange when they said he wasn't.
To cover up Madam Shin's wrongs,
I committed too big of a crime
against Shim Gun Wook.
But, I never thought you would help
Shim Gun Wook.
When I went to prison instead
of the chairman,
I lost my wife.
The chairman told me, after 3 years
in prison,
"You did good".
He had no interest whatsoever
that my wife was ill and died.
My feelings of loyalty and illusions
of Haeshin were shattered.
So, I went to Shim Gun Wook's
parents' grave.
I begged for their forgiveness.
I thought that was the only way
my feelings of guilt might be erased.
I, who couldn't protect that child,
am also someone who should be punished.
[Non-possession, Beop Jeong]
Happy Birthday to you...
Wow, people even have birthday
parties at a barbecue place.
Well, I guess they did set it up
nice like a restaurant.
Right, Unni?
Hey, I know the people well here,
so eat in moderation.
All right! What do you think...
Oh, Jae In! Welcome.
Your little sister, right?
- Yes, she is.
- Hello.
Well, I think it would be okay
if you joined Chief Kwak.
That man must have no cases.
Let's go, let's go.
- Uh? Hello.
- Yes, hello.
Oh? Hello!
- Oh?
- She's my little sister.
- Ah...
- Oh? So, you know them, yeah?
We're joining.
Looks good.
- Have you been well?
- Yes.
It totally melts in your mouth,
totally melts.
- But, is there no rice here?
- Rice...
There's nothing we don't have here.
Take a look.
This side is cheap stuff.
These on the front are better.
For now,
please bring one beef short rib stew...
Beef short rib stew.
And bring another order of sliced beef
to grill.
- Sliced beef?
- Unni, I'm going to eat a lot.
Okay, eat a lot.
So, have you met up with Shim Gun Wook?
I thought about dropping by his place,
but it would be hard to see
a big empty place.
[Resignation]
I just need to write it like that, right?
Tae Seong,
there will never be any abandoning
of anyone ever again.
Right now, I can look after you,
look after Haeshin,
and look after the family.
Noona,
I'd like to look after someone myself
and live on my own abilities.
Don't pay any attention to public notice.
You're Haeshin's Executive Director.
I don't want it.
Even if I come work at Haeshin,
I'll make it on my own ability.
Not as someone's son,
but just as an individual...
That's how I want to live.
Tae Seong...
Aye! If I'd have know it would be like this,
I should have graduated college
when he put up the tuition money.
But, do you know what's truly a relief?
When you think about it,
the two of you are not related
in any way.
You're not each other's flesh and blood.
It's neither of your faults.
So, don't be too upset.
Can I give you a hug?
Are you not going to see the guy?
Didn't you say no one would be
abandoned anymore?
Didn't you say you could look after
the family?
Then look after him too, to the very end.
He's family, after all.
I'll call you Shim Gun Wook
for the last time today.
Because Gun Wook and I
still have things to sort out.
I didn't regret meeting you.
For the first time in a long time,
I felt fluttering
and trembling.
So, I... thought you truly...
When, you first approached Mo Ne,
I knew your feelings weren't sincere.
And even knowing you were
that sort of person,
I... couldn't stop myself from being
shaken by you.
You and I... how are we...
Gun Wook.
Did you miss it?
Did you want to come back,
even if it was like this?
Do you know?
After you were kicked out,
it was very difficult for me too
and I felt really confused.
Even though I knew that you,
as a small child, haven't deceived us,
I felt betrayed.
And I was angry.
I'm sorry.
I hope that you might find some solace
that it was hard on me too.
When some time passes,
things will work out somehow, won't they?
And...
Gun Wook,
from now on,
I'll try my best to be able to
call you Tae Seong.
Tae Ra noona.
Tae Seong.
Noona.
It's okay, Noona.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
I'm sorry, Tae Seong.
Noona, I'm sorry.
Chairman!
Chairman, your hand.
Tae...
Tae Seong.
You were here?
Why is he here?
Executive Director Hong,
what brings you here?
I came to eat.
Have you been well?
Yes.
And you?
Me, well...
I'm trying to figure out what to do.
But, have you not seen the guy yet?
He's probably going through
a really rough time.
Be with him.
It turns out I was living with everything
that was his.
They say he's Hong Tae Seong.
What...
What are you talking about?
The real Hong Tae Seong.
Mother had switched him and me.
She must not have been able
to tolerate a son he had with someone else.
Impossible.
He's back.
Go and see him.
The real Hong Tae Seong, Father's son.
The target of his vengeance
was ultimately his family.
Yes, hello?
Manager Kim, it's me, Mo Ne.
Shim Gun Wook, where does he live?
But, I'm not Miss, I'm Hong Mo Ne.
Hong Mo Ne.
Hong Mo Ne likes Shim Gun Wook!
My little brother?
Hyung.
[Hong Tae Gyun]
It's hard, isn't it?
You didn't know.
You lived so long wanting vengeance.
And now, hearing they were your family,
you no longer feel the resentment.
And you're sorry,
and you're feeling regret.
That's what family is.
No.
What I did, what I caused...
No, those people,
I'm sure they've forgiven you.
They might even be wanting to see you.
Your family, no matter how they hurt you,
you can forgive them all, right?
Guess who I am.
My name is Moon Jae In.
And, who are you?
Why don't you answer?
You need to answer that you're
Hong Tae Seong.
Again.
I'm Moon Jae In.
And, who are you?
I'm Hong...
Tae Seong.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Ay, where has that girl gone?
Ah, Moon Jae In!
This won't do.
Yeah?
Unni, where are you?!
Oh, Gun Wook's house.
Really?!
Can I come visit?
I don't know.
Don't you know I have Gun Wook
ahjussi in the palm of my hand?
Would it be okay if you came?
I'm coming.
Okay.
Where are you?
You think you can find it?
Come out and meet me at the big
main street in our neighborhood.
Ah, Gun Wook, pick up a little
around the place! I'll be right back!
Mo Ne.
You think because I was in the US,
I wouldn't know anything?
Mo Ne.
I hear you're the one who's done
all this to our family.
You'll hurt yourself. Put down the gun.
Shut up!
And what's Jae In unni?
Me, Tae Ra unni, and is Tae Seong oppa next?
What? Do you want to destroy
Tae Seong too?!
Don't do this, Mo Ne.
Don't come any closer! I'll kill you!
Why are you doing this to us?
Don't do this, Mo Ne.
Don't call my name.
If it wasn't for you, I wouldn't have
been like this.
I could have lived happily.
It's because of you I've become
like this! You made me like this!
I wish you were dead. I wish you were dead!
- Uh? What was that noise?
- Unni!
Oh, you're here?
Wow, I'm finally going to
Gun Wook ahjussi's house, yeah?
See?
See how great it is when you live without
worrying about that life-saving rope?
Life-saving rope?
Gun Wook ahjussi once said
that he was going to climb the
life saving rope and climb way up there.
What's so great about what's up there?
Going up there is basically going up
to the heavens.
That's no good.
Put down that gun, Mo Ne.
Huh.
- Mo Ne...
- You call my name again and I'll really kill you.
I'm sorry, Mo Ne.
You're sorry?
What are you sorry for?
What are you sorry for after all this?!
What?
Are you afraid I'm going to kill you?
Is that it?!
Mo Ne,
I understand what you're saying,
so couldn't you call me Oppa
one more time like long ago?
Long ago... What's long ago?
You're nothing to me now.
Nothing.
Not even nothing.
I can't.
Those peppers are spicy!
Put lots in a stew.
Let's eat these with Gun Wook ahjussi.
- Looks good.
- I can't wait.
Is his place nice?
His place is really nice.
- Come on in.
- Okay.
Oh, I told him to clean up.
Ohhh!
Where did he go?
Gun Wook.
C'mon, where are you hiding?
- Unni, it's really nice.
- Hey, Shim Gun Wook.
Gun Wook must have gone somewhere.
Ay, where has this ahjussi hiding?
- No, I think he isn't home. Where did he go?
- Unni, don't worry about it.
This ahjussi loves playing tricks.
- What is this? He left his phone, too.
- Whoa.
Did he go to buy ice cream for you?
Hey, Won In...
Do you know what Gun Wook likes best?
How would I know?
What is it?
A traditional home-cooked meal.
I'll have to make it for him a lot.
Make him tons, tons.
But, I don't know what foods he likes.
This.
Sausage?
Besides that.
He must have some favorites.
I guess I'll just ask him later.
Sure, ask him!
Hey!
Wait! Let's eat it when Gun Wook
gets here.
Ay! I'm hungry.
Why isn't Ahjussi coming?
Didn't you say you ate a lot of
meat earlier?
That's that.
Why didn't he take his phone?
The soup's gonna get all cold.
This looks like the tastiest meal
you've ever made.
You think?
Yeah.
- I won't eat, I won't, I won't. I won't eat!
- Just wait.
Why isn't this ahjussi coming home?!
You're sure he isn't hiding?
This I confess to you
Please listen carefully to
what I'm saying right now
The memories of us loving one another
Please pretend none of it ever happened
This I confess to you
Please listen even if this is hard for you
I'm sorry.
My adopted American parents
need me urgently.
He's going to the US?
Suddenly?
Tae Seong, that child...
They're doing well, both of them.
All of this is my fault.
Father.
Tae Seong, and your mother too,
you look after them.
I don't want to lose anyone anymore.
Don't worry.
Mother will be released on bail soon, too.
What about that child?
A lot of time has passed,
but he'll come back home.
When he comes back,
then it would be nice
if we could bury everything
and laugh as we have dinner.
Yes, Father.
It will happen that way.
So Dam,
if you want to become a beautiful princess,
they say you have to smile
a hundred times a day.
You can do it, right?
Especially, in front of your mom,
make sure you smile even more.
That's how you can become
beautiful like your mom.
Your uncle who loves you.
Tae Ra noona,
Mo Ne,
family.
Gun Wook, did you write this?
Jae In, Won In.
Family.
A package came!
I don't know who sent it.
There's no address.
But what is this?
"What would the world look like through
the eyes of the one you love, Jae In?"
Uh.
Gun Wook sent it.
Huh?
Gun Wook must be back.
Unni!
Gun Wook!
Shim Gun Wook.
I'd like to announce that
Vice Chairman Hong Tae Ra
has been elected the new Chairman
of Haeshin Group.
What would the world look like through
the eyes of the one you love, Jae In?
Jae In, I've had this thought.
If I could see the world through
someone else's eyes,
what would it be like?
Jae In, are you doing well?
You have to be happy no matter what.
Because, if you could look at my world
through those eyes,
then I'd be able to smile and laugh too.
In the night,
in the deepest blackest darkness...
I can't tell which is the sky,
and which is the ground.
I can't tell if a glow is from a flame
or from starlight.
I can't distinguish one from the other.
Where is the place that I'm to go?
[Public Notice]
[Name: Unknown, Sex: Male]
Could it be heaven?
Could it be hell?
[Age: Between 20 and 30]
[Cause of Death: Presumed accidental self-shooting]
[Description: Estimated height 180cm,
long scar on the right side of the back... ]
[Course of Action: Burial]
[Contact: Department of... ]
Gun Wook, where are you?
Is the world you see now
a happy one?
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Translator: meju
Timer: szhoang
Editor/QC: snoopyvkd
Coordinators: mily2, ay_link
Because my thorn, that grows
day by day, hurts you
I try my best to hide my tears but
They're exposed when I stand in front of you
Even though I painfully push you away
You're always at the same place in my heart
I guess my never-ending love for you
Would not let me send you away yet
Because your scent still lingers in me
I cannot forget you yet
The alien ET.
He had supernatural powers,
but they were all friends.
- Hoy hoy.
Why can't I have a Gumiho friend?
[My Girlfriend is a Gumiho]
The fox has disappeared!
Why are you doing this to me?
I liked you?
How can I pull that off?
You can't let me go.
You're mine.
Why me, why?!
You're looking for information, right?
The person you are desperately seeking,
is currently at Dongbo Charcoal Grill.
It's really not a big deal like I thought.
Will we be able to catch her alive?
Dae Yong!
Don't come any closer!
You stayed alive because of me,
but now you'll die.
[My Girlfriend is a Gumiho]
Watch dramas legally at
dramafever.com | crunchyroll.com