SEVEN CHANCES
One beautiful summer day,
when fragrant flowers were in bloom,
Jimmie Shannon met Mary Jones,
and he wanted to tell her
he loved her.
When Autumn had cast its golden glow
and the flowers had faded and Died,
He still wanted to tell her
he loved her.
When winter came and the leaves
had fallen one by one ...
... And the snow had covered the hills and valleys...
... He still wanted to tell her
he loved her.
However... when nature had changed again,
Bringing forth spring-time with its
beautiful buds and blossoms...
... He still wanted to tell her
he loved her.
Jimmie was the junior partner of the
firm of "Meekin & Shannon",
Brokers, that had been tricked into a
financial deal that meant disgrace...
... And possibly prison...
Unless they raised money quickly.
A lawyer, unknown to the firm,
with good news for Jimmie.
7-- And to my grandson, James Shannon,
I hereby bequeath the balance of
my estate amounting to...
"This man has some kind of
a legal paper with him !"
"Maybe it's a summons !"
"He's not in."
"Let's go out to the
Country Club."
And to my grandson, James Shannon, I hereby
bequeath the balance of my estate amounting to...
"Your grandfather has left
you the sum of..."
"Seven million dollars."
"Providing..."
"...you are married by seven o'clock on the
evening of your twenty seventh birthday."
"When is your twenty-seventh birthday ?"
"Today !"
"There's plenty of time..."
"You've got until seven o'clock
tonight to get married."
"Maybe Mary might marry me."
"Mary, you're the only
girl I have ever loved."
"Will you marry me ?"
"I must hurry back to the country club and..."
"...tell Billy it's all fixed..."
"...and we'll be married today."
"Why today ?"
"My grandfather left me a lot of money..."
"...providing I marry some girl today."
"I don't mean some girl... I can marry any girl !"
"I... I mean, it don't matter who I marry, but
I must wed someone !"
"He said he must wed someone, and
it might as well be me !"
"...and so you see, dear, how much better
it is to give him a chance to explain."
"Then, Mr. Shannon, you've got
to marry some other girl."
"I couldn't marry any other girl."
"But, you'll lose this fortune."
"I don't want the money..."
"... it has already cost me
the only girl I ever loved."
Dear Jimmie
Jimmie Shannon
Don't you dare marry anybody else.
Mary.
P.S.
I think I will be home all day.
"Take this to Mr. Shannon,
and ride for your life !"
"... and we'll lose our reputation
our friends, Even our liberty..."
"... unless you do marry !
... We're partners;"
"... if you won't do it to save yourself,"
"You must to save me !"
"Who will I marry ?"
"How many of these girls
do you know ?"
"You have seven chances."
"Would you marry me ?"
"Will you marry me ?"
"I'll propose to this one for you."
"Have you ever thought of
getting married ?"
"Constantly !"
"Would you marry a man who
loves you better than his very life ?"
"Wait a minute...
I'm proposing for him."
"Who bats next ?"
"Wrong party."
"Meet me at the Broad Street church
at five o'clock..."
"I'll have a bride there if it's
the last act of my life."
"You try and have one there
too in case he fails."
"In case two show up,
I'll marry the other one."
On Duty
Miss Smith
"Yours ?"
"Are you going to
try to raise it ?"
"Do you think anybody
would marry me ?"
THE DAILY NEWS
LEADING AFTERNOON PAPER LARGEST CIRCULATION
STAGE - ENTRANCE
Julian Eltinge (1881–1941)
Mr. William Dalton, one of the greatest drag performers
in the history of the American Theatre.
WANTED, A BRIDE
James Shannon, Prominent Young
Broker Falls Heir...
to $7,000,000 if He Is Married Today.
ALL HE NEEDS IS A BRIDE
Girl Who Appears at Broad Street
Church In...
...Bridal Costume By 5 O’Clock
Will Be the Lucky Winner.
By the time Jimmie had
reached the church...
He had proposed to everything
in skirts, including a Scotchman.
NIAGARA FALLS
Destination: RENO
"Ladies, you are evidently the
victims of some practical joker..."
"I must ask you to leave the church
as quietly as possible."
Jimmie Shannon, Don't you dare marry anybody else.
Mary.
P.S.  I think I will be home all day.
Barbershop
"What time is it ?"
Clock Repairing
"Bring the minister to Mary's house."
"I'll try to get there somehow
before seven o'clock !"
TURKISH BATHS
LADIES DAY
"You've killed him !"
"I know a short cut...
we'll head him off !"
"I'm too late !"
"And we're not going to be married ?"
"But Jimmie... Don't you think we could
be happy without the money ?"
"Mary, there's nothing before me
but failure and disgrace,
...and you mean too much to me
to let you share it !"
The End
Typed by : Reza Fa.