( beeping )
( clock chiming )
Man: Holly.
Holly.
What time is it now?
Just ten minutes later
Than when you asked before.
And do you think
he'll get here in time?
He'll be here any minute now.
Take it easy, John.
Do you really have
to tell him tonight?
Yes. Tonight.
I feel that it may be my last.
Now, now, now.
You know you're
going to get better.
Holly...
What's become of your passion
For cold, scientific fact?
( bell ringing )
There he is now.
Hurry.
( ringing )
I believe
my uncle's expecting me.
I'm Leo Vincey.
Yes, I can see that.
Hi, Vincey.
Come on in.
Thank you.
My name's Holly, Horace Holly.
Glad to know you.
Confound your English fog.
Our ship was a whole day late.
Well, thank heavens you're--
you're here in time.
Time?
What's all the rush?
Your cable said,
"catch first boat,
Greatest adventure
in the world."
What's all the mystery?
You'll hear all about
that from your uncle.
But there's one thing
my cable didn't say--
John Vincey's dying.
Good lord.
What of?
Radium poisoning.
Hmm.
I haven't seen the old
man since I was a kid.
He never quite got over
Our side of the family
going american.
Why did he send for me?
There's no time to explain
that now, every minute counts.
Come along in.
I'm sorry, sir, I couldn't
get here any sooner.
Never mind that, my boy.
There's no time for
explanations now.
Come closer.
Holly, did you ever see
such a striking resemblance?
Extraordinary.
I'd already noticed it.
Look at that portrait.
Holly, turn on that light.
He does resemble me at that.
Or should I say
that I resemble him?
That is your ancestor of
a dozen generations ago.
Really?
John Vincey in the 15th century.
Wow. I must say we Vinceys
Have a way of looking
like each other.
I have no time for
explanations now, my boy.
I'm a man of science.
I'm not superstitious.
If I were,
I might imagine
That your resemblance to a
man dead nearly 500 years
Is fate's way of showing me
That you will find again
what he discovered.
What is that, sir?
The means of overcoming
man's enemy.
Man's enemy?
My enemy, your enemy,
The enemy of all
living things.
Careful, John.
That is what I mean, Leo.
That is the swinging
march of man's enemy.
Time, bringing death--
Invisible, relentless death.
I guess nobody can stop that.
Who knows?
A lot of men have believed
that they could--
Ponce de Leon,
Who searched for the
fountain of youth,
Or those 15th-century alchemists
Who tried to discover
the elixir of life.
But what connection
has all this with me
Or John Vincey over
there on the wall?
That's what your uncle's
going to tell you.
Holly, get me the box.
Listen to me carefully, Leo.
I haven't time left to
tell you more than once.
Uncle John, I don't think
you should exert yourself--
Please, please.
What I am going to
tell you is a secret
Handed down in our family
from father to son.
The first John Vincey there
Did not go on his last
great adventure alone.
His wife left their son
in England to go with him.
For five years, they
vanished from the world.
Then, one night in a town
in northern Poland,
A woman--
ill, starving, dying--
Collapsed at the door
of an English merchant.
He took her in and heard
her ravings of hardship
And fantastic terror.
And that woman was
John Vincey's widow.
Before she died, she
became more coherent,
Begged for someone
to write a letter
To her family in England.
Here's the letter,
Dictated by that dying woman
Almost five centuries ago.
( chuckling ) Yes,
it is something of a puzzle.
Doesn't she tell
what happened to John Vincey?
Here.
"so he was killed
Because he refused
to abandon me."
Does it give any idea
where they went to?
Not much, mentions
the land of muscovy.
Russia, eh?
Or siberia
or kamchatka--
All known as muscovy
in the 15th century.
The place
where he was killed
Was far, far north.
She escaped
with their English servant.
They fell in
with some natives
Who guided them
back across a glacier
Over what she calls
the schugle barrier.
And there,
death struck again.
Holly, read it.
"then a great beast
sprang on our guides
"and killed them all.
"my servant giles
killed the beast,
"but died
of his grievous wounds.
So I was left alone."
But what about the discovery
you spoke of?
What'd they find?
John: Read on.
"in this strange land,
we saw the flame.
"and he who stands therein
comes forth unharmed
To triumph over death."
But John Vincey
died there.
Why, if he found this,
uh, this flame?
Because he was murdered.
But you are scientists.
Do you really
take all this seriously?
Seriously?
Come, my boy.
I'll show you
how seriously.
Come into the laboratory
where Holly and I
Have done our lifework.
In the beginning,
I was as skeptical as you.
Then Holly and I,
Years ago...
In this very room,
Began our efforts
to reproduce
John Vincey's
life-prolonging flame.
We failed.
But our researches
in radioactivity
Carried us far enough
to make us believe
That such an element
really exists.
An element
to preserve life?
Yes.
Seventeen years
in this room.
There's one other thing
we ought to show him, John.
Here.
Can you make out
the inscription?
Holly: It means, "here burns
the flame of life."
That is the sole possession
Vincey's wife had left.
She sent it to the son
she never saw again.
It's all so mysterious,
it doesn't make sense.
This thing's gold,
not an unknown element.
To be sure, it's gold.
It's only the symbol
of the flame of life
John Vincey found.
Don't you understand?
I'm afraid I don't.
Flame destroys life.
A thousand volts of electricity
will destroy life.
But increase
the frequency,
And you may safely
take a million volts
Through your body.
And the radiation
from this unknown element,
This flame of life,
May be a million degrees hotter
than any fire we know,
Or it may be
as cold as ice.
( chuckles )
that's too much.
A cold flame?
Did you ever hear
of a man being burned
By x-rays or radium?
Mm-hmm.
Did he feel himself
being burned?
No. No more
than I did myself.
This flame of life, Vincey,
is pure radiation,
The most intense
and flame-like radiation
In the whole universe.
Radiation from what?
From the unknown element.
Do you really believe
such a thing exists?
We no longer believe,
we know it exists.
Our experiments prove that.
That's right.
And they also prove
something else.
This element cannot be
artificially produced.
Only nature,
only god can produce it.
But where?
In a glacial region
of volcanic character.
That's largely guesswork,
isn't it?
No!
Not if the family legend
is true,
And I believe that it is.
I believe that John Vincey
found that flame
And that it still burns
Somewhere remote
and mysterious,
Offering eternal life.
That's why I've sent for you.
You're a Vincey,
The last of us.
Holly can't do it alone,
But he'll go with you.
John Vincey was an explorer.
It's in your blood, too,
And the love of-- of adventure.
Don't look upon this
as a deathbed wish.
If you should try,
If you succeed,
I shan't be here.
But I hope that
somehow I shall know
And somehow share in your triumph
When you say...
"here burns...
The flame of life."
Uncle John?
John?
John!
( shouting )
( wind howling )
( barking )
( barking continues )
Holly: Let's hope this
chap has some tea.
Leo: I'll take mine with
a big reindeer steak.
( man speaking foreign language )
Fine old northern hospitality--
Nothing in the world
like it, they tell me.
Northern hospitality, eh?
( speaking foreign language )
( second man speaking
foreign language )
Well, I'm blown.
I thought you were some of those
Infernal wandering chantos.
Can't take any chances with them.
Don't we know it-- stayed
with a tribe of 'em last week.
Planning to stay here
the night, I take it.
We hope so. Come 20 miles today.
Come in.
Sit down, both of you.
There's a big stew on the
stove just about ready,
Plenty to go around.
( hesitantly ) yeah,
I'm--I'm glad of that.
Hey!
How about supper?!
Do we eat or don't we?!
Huh? Oh, that's my daughter Tanya.
Sit down.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Now, then, gents,
Do I understand you want
to do business with me?
We heard you had the post
furthest up country.
We thought you might be able
To help us get some
natives to go on.
Where do you want to go?
Did you ever hear of
the schugle barrier?
Why, yes. I've heard
natives talk of it.
Leo, at last, we're on our way.
On your way where?
Over the schugle.
You're crazy.
Why?
You'll never get a native
to guide you there.
We'll pay him well.
That ain't the point.
They're afraid to go, I tell ya.
Why?
Because no one who got
over ever came back,
So far as I know.
Well, why didn't they come back?
What lies beyond the schugle?
More of the same, I suppose.
Of course, the natives
have tales about it.
Well, what do they say?
I never paid much attention
to their foolishness.
I can tell you.
You can? What is it?
The natives say that
beyond the schugle,
There are terrible dangers.
They say--
( whack )
Bah!
Yes? Go on.
Why, it's just a sort of legend.
Holly: What is the legend?
A long time ago, they believe,
A woman came out of the country
That lies far beyond the schugle.
What sort of woman?
A white woman.
She told them that she had
escaped from a strange place.
Strange?
And if a man finds the way there,
He will never die.
( snickering )
the catch in that
Is he dies before he gets there!
Hold your trap, Tanya,
you gab too much.
Wait.
Is there anything in
the story about fire?
A flame?
Anything you can connect with this?
No, I don't think so.
What's that?
Gold, ain't it?
Yes.
It is gold.
I see.
Well, now you begin to make sense.
So that's what lies
beyond the schugle.
No. You don't understand.
Gold isn't what
we're interested in.
Ah.
Suppose I could get
a few natives to go on.
How much could you pay them?
Anything they asked.
Well, that's liberal enough.
Money no object, eh?
Lads...
No one can say old Dugmore
ever let a white man down.
I'll get natives to go.
I'll run the outfit myself,
And you needn't pay me a penny.
How's that for an offer?
What?
What about those dangers
you talked about?
I'll be frank with you gents--
I figure it's worth some risk
To be a partner in
what you're after.
My dear sir, that's absurd.
You can't be a part in
what we're looking for.
I said a partner.
You try to keep me out of this,
And I'll fix it so that
no native in these parts
Will come within a
thousand miles of ya.
( sinister chuckle )
take it or leave it.
Dugmore: Tanya, here.
( wind whistling )
( dogs barking )
I tell you again, Dugmore,
you're crazy.
You can't take a girl up there.
Oh, stop rowing about it.
I'm sick of hearing it.
We don't know what
we're getting into.
What's your idea, then?
To leave her here alone
With no one around
for 400 miles
Except a lot of wandering chantos
Who'd like to get even with me?
Anyhow, we want
somebody to cook.
My dear, has anybody
taken the trouble
To ask you what--
what you want to do?
I want to go.
There, you see?
She wouldn't leave
her poor old pa.
Well, if there were
anyplace to leave her,
I wouldn't let her come along.
Think you'll be all right?
I'm all right.
Come along, let's go.
Let's go.
( man speaking foreign language )
( speaking foreign language )
( dogs barking )
Leo: Hey, Dugmore!
Look.
That may lead to a way
over the schugle barrier.
What do you think?
Well, let's hope so.
We've followed that
cliff for a week
Without finding a way through it.
Anyhow, it'll be a
shelter from the wind,
And the dogs can't
go on without a rest.
( man speaking foreign language )
Hurry up with that food, Tanya.
It'll be ready as soon
as I get it thawed out.
Hmm.
I wouldn't mind being
thawed out myself.
Leo, this is no place to camp.
But Dugmore says the
dogs need a rest.
I don't like it.
Sitting down here
under this wall of ice,
It's--it's dangerous.
What's the matter with you now?
What's dangerous?
( rumbling )
There you are.
Well, what of it?
You've heard that
several times lately.
In this narrow place,
Any noise might start vibrations
Which might cause an avalanche.
Merely shouting might do it.
Aw, pipe down.
Who's lived in the north
for 20 years, me or you?
Lecture yourself out
of that, professor.
You...
Hurry up with that grub.
I still don't like it.
( sniffs )
Mmm, smells good.
Tastes good, too--
snow rabbits.
The ones I shot?
Oh, I'll fix that.
You don't have to help me.
But I want to.
You think having me
along is a nuisance.
Oh.
We couldn't get
along without you.
I wish you really meant that.
I do, honest.
Because I can cook?
( chuckles )
well, not only that,
But there's another reason...
Your father.
If it weren't for you, I couldn't
get along with him for a minute.
But with you here, I find
him at least bearable.
I know.
That isn't very
nice of me, is it?
I can't blame you, but...
I understand.
He's your father.
You see, I was brought up
By the Russian sisters
at Yuroshi.
The convent broke up
about a year ago,
And--and he came and took
me to the trading post.
He said he was my father.
Oh, I begin to understand.
Well, it's all right, really.
But it isn't all right.
When we get back from this trip,
I'll teach him how a girl
like you ought to be treated.
If I had a daughter like you,
Don't you think I'd love her
and show her that I do?
Would you?
Why, of course I would.
I don't see how he
can help loving you.
Why, you're...You're--
Vincey!
Vincey! Holly! Holly!
What's up?
The natives have just
come down from the glacier,
Shrieking something
about a white man.
Let's go up and see
what it's about.
( speaking foreign language )
They'll show us
the way.
( speaking
foreign language )
( shouting
in foreign language )
( growling )
Come on.
By the lord Harry.
What a beast.
Holly, what is it?
Unless I'm barmy, it's--
it's a saber-toothed tiger.
Think of it, man!
That's a new one
on me.
Saber-toothed tiger--
They've been extinct for
thousands of years, haven't they?
In all known parts
of the world, yes.
But here...
They must've been preserved in that
ice for-- for 400 to 500 years.
They must've camped
in this glacier.
Look how that man's dressed!
Holly, the servant--
The faithful servant who
was with John Vincey's wife.
What'd the parchment
say, remember?
By Jove, Leo, you're right.
He killed the great beast, but
died of the wounds it gave him.
And she escaped
alone, remember?
Holly, we found our way,
the way to the flame.
Look.
That stiff's got a chain
around his neck,
And there's a ripped canvas bag.
It's gold.
This ice ain't so thick,
and with this ax--
Don't be a fool!
You heard what Holly said
About any vibration
causing an avalanche.
Oh, the professor
says a lot of things.
Come on,
let's get out of here.
Dugmore!
( rumbling )
Dugmore!!!
Stop it, you fool!
Aah!!
Ohh!! Aah!!
There's no hope for the others.
You know that.
I know.
No sledges, no food,
and no way back.
And no way forward.
Holly, look.
This was covered by the glacier.
It may lead through the barrier.
Tanya?
All right.
At least this is a
shelter from the wind.
Interesting formation.
Pity there isn't more light.
Oh, I'm tired.
Poor kid, you've had
a tough time of it.
Leo! Leo, Tanya!
Come quick!
Look.
There's our way.
Our way? Where?
What are you talking about?
Don't you understand?
They're fumeroles,
volcanic formation--
One hour ago, ice, glacial ice--
And now, volcanic heat.
I get it--
what uncle John talked about.
We could never get through.
Of course we can.
Listen, Tanya,
When I wanted to leave
you at the trading post,
What'd you say?
Why, I said I wanted to go.
All right, come on.
Sulfur, of course.
Phosphorus, too.
That accounts for the glow.
Well, that's the last of 'em.
Can't we rest a bit?
Look, there's more light.
Yes, and another opening.
Aah!
Just a minute, Leo, give 'em a
chance to show if they're friendly.
Try your lingo, Tanya.
( speaking foreign language )
We--we greet you, my friend.
Nagu-da.
Other natives:
Nagu-da, nagu-da.
Nagu-da.
Thank you.
Say it to him, Leo.
Well, what does it mean?
"good day" or "how are
you?" or "greetings"
Or something of the kind.
Don't--don't judge
'em by their looks.
They're most probably
a very friendly people.
Show your confidence in them.
You know what it means, Tanya?
No.
( speaking foreign language )
It's all right, we're coming.
( shouting in foreign language )
( all shouting in foreign language )
( laughing )
Well, they seem awfully pleased
to see us, don't they?
( shouting continues )
Thank you, thank you.
Nagu-da.
( giggles )
You see?
I was right.
They're just kind,
hospitable, simple people.
I'm not sure they're so simple.
( shouting grows louder )
Leo, do you realize
what we're eating?
Some sort of melon.
It's a pre-melon,
something like papaya.
What of it?
Tropical fruit here in the arctic?
It means there's some
sort of fertile country
Somewhere beyond these caves.
It may be what we're looking for.
( drumbeat plays )
All: ( chanting ) huh.
Huh!
This doesn't look
so good to me.
Huh!
Nonsense.
I suspect it's a
ceremony of welcome.
Huh!
( beat quickens )
Huh! Huh!
Huh!
Leo.
Steady, Tanya, steady.
Huh!
What's up now?
As I told you, a
ceremony of welcome.
Huh!
Huh! Huh! Huh!
I don't like this.
Oh, nonsense, it's--
it's most interesting.
( drumbeat and chanting
continues )
Come with me.
Aah!!!
Uhh!
Leo!
( man shouting in
foreign language )
( continues in foreign language )
Are you all right, Leo?
( speaking foreign language )
Nagu-da?
( continues in foreign language )
( all talking at once )
( speaking foreign language )
I...I-I-I thought...
Steady, Leo.
Leo, you are hurt.
( man speaking foreign language )
Holly, watch him.
Tanya: Wait, please!
Old gentleman...
My friend, him very sick.
No can walk.
You get out...Out.
Let him...Ride.
Oh, Holly, I'm trying to tell him
That Leo can't walk
any further.
Holly: You old idiot,
Can't you see for
yourself he's hurt?
( speaking foreign language )
Oh!
Holly, he's dying.
No, no, Tanya.
Bad concussion, I'm afraid.
( with accent )
do not be afraid.
He will not die.
But--but how can you
know English?
I have a wise teacher
who knows all tongues.
( speaking foreign language )
But wait, wait.
Who--who was your teacher?
What is this place?
Where are we going?
What--what's gonna happen?
You will learn your fate
from hash-a-mo-tep.
( speaking foreign language )
Tanya, Tanya.
It's all right, Leo.
( speaking foreign language )
I say, this is incredible!
What is this place?
Country of kor.
Kor?
Tanya, think of it--
You're seeing something
That nobody ever dreamed existed.
Hush.
Aren't you interested?
No.
( shouting in foreign language )
( continues shouting )
( continues in foreign language )
( plays slow drumbeat )
That mountain...
There are stairs
and a great door.
What is it?
It's the palace
of hash-a-mo-tep,
Hollowed in the heart
of the mountain.
( chimes )
( speaking foreign language )
( continues in foreign language )
( woman speaking foreign language )
Woman:
Speak in English, then,
So the strangers may understand.
Returning from the journey
on which you sent me,
I passed the place where
dwelled the peoples
Of the caves.
I weary of those people.
There, I found these strangers
fighting for their lives.
The cave people would
have killed them.
Against my order,
known these many years
That any stranger must be
brought to me unharmed?
Have not their fathers
and their fathers' fathers
Taught them that my word is law?
They await your
judgment, o queen.
They shall not go unpunished.
What is your name, stranger?
Holly, o queen.
Welcome, Holly,
Though you are not
he for whom I wait.
But I don't understand.
Why should you?
What do you know
of immortal dreams,
Immortal memories?
But who are you?
I am yesterday and
today and tomorrow.
I am sorrow and longing
and hope unfulfilled.
I am hash-a-mo-tep, she--
She who must be obeyed.
I am...I.
But you speak my language.
How is that?
I learned it from
a countryman of yours
Long ago.
What's that?
You mean there's been
another Englishman here
In your lifetime?
Who? How long ago?
See that the strangers
are well-treated, Billali.
I will decide later
what they shall do.
And the other one?
The other?
A young man, wounded in the fight.
I thought--
( angrily ) you thought?!
Bring him to me at once!
( speaking foreign language )
It's not enough
that I should wait in hope
Unending years in pain.
Then you forget my orders,
disobey my commands.
Who gives you leave to
think contrary to my will?!
Nearer, bring him nearer.
That's it!
Aah!!!
John Vincey...John Vincey!
( gasps )
Oh, my love...
My dearest love.
At last.
You're hurt.
Billali...
Billali, take him to my chamber.
Through the forbidden door?
Yes.
And bear him gently.
( speaking foreign language )
Please let me go with him!
Who are you?
You are his wife?
No! I'm nothing to him!
But he needs someone!
He will not be alone.
Tanya: No!! Leo!!
Oh, please, please let me go!
Let me go with him, I tell you!
Let me go! Leo!
Leo!
I--I just had to see how he is.
What gives you so much courage?
Can you help him?
He will wake from his
sleep refreshed and well.
There's no need to fear.
Are you sure?
Yes. Look if you will.
Then leave.
How often have I watched
beside him lying so.
But now, this is warm.
Flesh.
He needs nothing you have to give.
Go now.
Go before he wakes.
And forget him.
He is not for you.
( rings gong )
Why do you hate me?
Hate you?
Why, you're nothing.
Nothing.
Once, long ago,
A woman like you
destroyed my happiness.
The same thing shall
not happen again.
How's Leo?
Leo?
You know, my friend.
Vincey.
Vincey. Oh, yes.
Have no fear.
She will heal him.
I see.
Look here...
You're the most important
man in the country, aren't you?
I have served she continuously
for more than half a century.
What?! Half a century?
You're joking.
You think I'm too young?
Oddly enough, I wasn't
thinking about you.
What are you doing?
It's an old English custom.
What is it?
Smoking. Don't you smoke?
Smoke and fire.
Do you worship the flame?
Of course, old boy.
Don't you?
It will soon be time
for the yearly offering
In the hall of kings.
There you may see the
sacred fires rekindled
If she permits you to be present.
You think if I showed her this?
( gasps )
What's the matter?
What does it mean?
Are you tired
of life?
Then question she concerning that.
But tell me...
Who is this who stands in fire?
Ask no more questions,
I tell you.
It is she's own secret.
Put it away.
Very well.
I thought that you might know.
How should I know?
She goes alone.
Alone?
On such a long journey?
Long journey?
No. There in the hall of--
You're cunning.
I said too much already.
Well, just tell me
one more thing.
How long has she ruled
over kor?
All her life.
But...
Tanya, what's happened?
She wouldn't let me stay.
She is with Leo.
You saw him?
He's still asleep.
She says he'll be well
when he wakes.
Oh, but, Holly, Holly, I'm afraid.
I--I feel something evil about her.
She would not let you
stay to speak with him?
You mean that she is
planning to keep us apart?
What nonsense.
Leo will have something
to say about that.
You think so?
But you may see him.
She has commanded that you
both be present at the trial.
You mean the trial of
the men who attacked us?
Punishment of the men
who injured him.
( speaks foreign language )
What does it mean?
She knows Leo.
She says he belongs to her.
She called him John Vincey.
But, Holly, how could
she know John Vincey?
How could she?
I want to believe it.
Suppose it's true?
Suppose it's true?!
Did you dream I was
watching while you slept?
I dreamed of a man
dead for centuries.
And you called me by his name.
Dreams are only memories
In the endless flow of time.
Who are you?
Drink.
( speaking foreign language )
Had I known you were coming,
You would've been welcomed
like a king.
Where are my friends?
Take the food.
Be strong again.
But Tanya, the girl who was--
She is here in my palace.
I remember vaguely.
Someone brought us here...
And you said--
what?
It's all foggy now.
Who are you?
You do not remember?
How can I?
I've never seen you before.
I was so sure
when you came at last
You would remember.
I was so sure
you could not forget.
I have summoned slaves
to attend you.
Later, you will hear
my judgment on those
Who dared attack you.
But wait...
Tell me, how is it
you speak my language?
And still, you do not understand.
I say, Tanya, what--
what's the meaning of this?
Where'd you get that outfit?
From the old man.
Billali?
He said I was to put it on
and look as well as I could.
I wonder why he cares how you look.
Good. Young man will be pleased.
How is Leo?
That, you will soon
discover for yourself.
Come.
If he's well, he will go
back to his own country?
Oh, yes.
Why, of course he will.
Then, I hope he'll soon be
well enough to travel.
Tanya...And Holly.
Glad to see ya, how are ya?
That's just what
I was gonna ask you,
But there's no need.
Listen, Leo, I think
I've got some big news for you.
Leo, are you sure
you're all right?
How do I look?
Want me to squeeze ya
and try my strength?
( bugles sound )
Listen to this, I pumped
old Billali about the flame--
Shh!
She summons you.
Sit near the throne.
Go ahead, o king.
Aw. Come on, the both of ya.
You alone.
You two, come with me.
Huh?
Well, Leo, I'll see you later.
Got lots to tell you.
There are marvels to be seen today.
A stranger shares the throne,
Where I may scarce approach.
Hmm.
Come.
I've summoned you, Holly,
That you may observe how
justice is meted out in kor.
Let the prisoners stand forth.
( speaking foreign language )
( grunting )
You earth-born people...
You haunters of darkness,
How you try my patience.
Point out those who
were reckless enough
To lay hands upon you.
Well, I'll point out
those I'm sure of.
Those two men there.
And this one.
This man.
I believe he was the leader.
That's all.
Only four, out of all
those men, attacked you?
That's all I'm sure of.
They will die.
What?
They shall be put to death.
But I don't want that.
Would you spare them?
Oh, yes...A christian.
I'd almost forgotten.
I remember in the market
place of Jerusalem,
They spoke of a man who
taught mercy and forgiveness.
A man who died
So that others might live,
As though death
could beget life.
Tell them to stand up, Billali.
( speaking foreign language )
( speaking
foreign language )
( continues
in foreign language )
( whimpering )
Aah!!
No!!
How could you be so calm
And send people
to their deaths like that?
Silence!
Is the girl
also tired of life?
I'm not afraid of you.
Tanya.
She: There is an end
of my indulgence.
Come away, Tanya.
Leo: Yes, Holly,
go with her.
I'm the one
who spoke out of turn.
We don't want
these fellows butchered
Just because we
had a fight with them.
Punish them if you like,
but-- but not that.
Do you think I'm cruel
for the sake of cruelty?
Then why do you torture them?
How do you think I
rule these people?
It's not by force.
It's by terror.
My empire is of the imagination.
Still, I beg you, stop this.
( speaking foreign language )
Thanks. That makes
me feel a lot better,
All of us.
And don't hold anything
against Tanya.
What is that girl to you?
Nothing, I...I feel
responsible for her.
May I--do you mind if I go now?
I'd like to tell her
everything's all right.
Go, then.
Yes, Billali?
The prisoners...
Are they to be turned
back to the caves?
No. Kill them.
All?
All. Kill them.
Make an end.
Would I could kill
my fears so easily.
She's wicked, I tell you.
Don't be too hard on her, Tanya.
She's strange...
And wonderful.
Well, after all, she didn't
go through with it.
She would've killed
them, except for you.
Listen, Leo, I've got it.
Got what?
We're going to find out
everything we want to know
Through you.
Good idea, huh?
What is there to find out
Except how to escape
from this horrible place?
You should've seen Billali
when I showed him this.
Almost knocked his
forehead on the floor,
Frightened out of his wits.
Said it was she's secret.
Well, why didn't you tell me?
All in good time.
We don't know the secret yet,
But I'll wager pounds to pence
That you're the one person
who can get it from her.
Leo, please don't go to her.
Don't you worry, Tanya.
Holly, I'm going to get
to the bottom of this.
If she knows where
the flame burns,
We're going to find it.
Leo...
It's hard to be kept waiting
when one has waited so long.
You must have known I'd come.
Do you think blind chance
brought you here?
I came because of an old story.
A woman escaped from this country
And told of a strange adventure
And died.
She left this for her son.
This woman was the wife of--
John Vincey.
John Vincey died 500 years ago.
How can you know his name?
Think back, far back.
Oh, my beloved...
You will, you can--
Another life, a far-off
forgotten place...
This place.
And my voice uttering words
you vowed to remember
Through endless time.
Think.
Your voice?
You...Were you the same?
Always to you, always,
Offering all, wanting all.
You mean, we...
I can't believe...
I have no memories.
I will show you how to look
across the mist of time.
That one moment out
of all the centuries.
That one instant when
I felt myself beloved.
Who was that man?
You do not know?
No, it can't be.
I dare not believe it.
You will believe.
Come.
Do you wonder whose feet
have worn away this rock?
Once, this stair
was new and level.
But I've passed here day by day.
And, see, my sandals
Have eaten off the solid stone.
Now, in a moment, you will
remember that other life.
I...I see myself.
Swept by the tides of time
Back to my arms.
Centuries ago, you
were someone else,
As I was this man here.
No, no. I'm the same.
My life and youth endured.
All through the years,
I've mourned here
where your body lay.
But now...
You are reborn,
And my mourning has ended.
Your coming is the sign
of my forgiveness.
Forgiveness?
For what?
I know why you've come to call.
You seek the flame of life.
Even as I came, a young girl,
So many lives ago.
I took the burden of
immortality upon my shoulders
And wore it through
unbelievable years--
Dark, with a loneliness
Through which there
shone a single light,
Fixed and unwavering--
The hope of love...
And so I waited,
Waited for a bridegroom
Whose passion for life
would be as fierce as my own.
You came, John Vincey,
And I loved you.
For one moment, you were mine.
Then you turned from me.
You had not come alone.
And, in my jealousy, I...
I killed you.
Again, I waited, seeming
longer than before.
But I knew you must return.
Your love of life must
be stronger than death.
And now you're here,
Nothing shall stand between us.
But I'm not John Vincey.
Oh, my love.
Take away my eyes.
Let darkness utterly shut me in,
And still my ears
would know the sound
Of your unforgotten voice.
If I could only remember.
If you've forgotten me,
Then that woman who
held you in spite of me...
You've forgotten her as well?
Yes.
I've forgotten.
She wasn't beautiful.
She had no wisdom such as mine.
Yet, you could never
quite leave her.
I've forgotten everything but you.
Everything--
no, no.
Now, as then, we two are
made of different clay.
Until you are as I
am, come no nearer.
Today, in the hall of kings,
The priest makes
sacrifice in gratitude
For my enduring youth.
Then you shall come with me
And share my secret.
Leo!
I say, Leo, what did you find out?
I've seen John Vincey.
What?
I tell you, I saw him!
Now, be reasonable.
John Vincey's been dead
for--for 500 years.
I--I tell you, I--
I saw him lying there.
Holly, it was I, myself.
Now, one thing at a time.
You mean a mummified body
that looked like you?
No, no, Holly.
I saw myself lying there.
Are you trying to make me
believe in reincarnation?
Rats! You knew before
That you were the image
of John Vincey.
We both knew that.
She has been waiting
for me to come back.
She says I am John Vincey.
Leo, don't listen to her!
Let's get away
while there's time.
Holly, she is going
to show me the flame.
What? Do you hear that, Tanya?
Well, why didn't you say
so in the first place?
When?
When do we go?
You are not
to see it.
But you said--
I said she promised me the secret.
Well, then, I see.
Only you?
Yes.
Oh.
You can't stay here.
You'll go back the way
we came, you and Tanya,
As soon as the temple
ceremony is over.
You'll be protected.
Then I go to the flame.
Leo...
Don't lose your head,
Use it!
I haven't lost my head.
I've found memories
you can't even imagine.
I've seen strangeness,
beauty, power--
Yes, immortality--
And I can share it.
But only I.
Those are her terms.
What man would say no?
Be fair.
Very well.
I'll take Tanya
back with me.
But let me tell you
one thing, Leo--
You're a fool,
And you'll die
for your folly
Like your ancestor
John Vincey.
Leo.
I'm sorry, Tanya.
Don't think of me,
think of yourself.
I am thinking
of myself.
To live forever, it's--
It's what all men
have dreamed of.
What's the use of living
a thousand years,
If you're going on
being cruel and selfish?
Is a thousand years of that
any better than 70?
But people would
change, grow good.
Has she grown good?
Yes.
Did she let
John Vincey escape?
Would she
let you escape if...
If you loved me?
Tanya, I...
You're not tempted as I am.
Think of it-- never to grow
old, never to feel age.
I can't give it up.
You will live here
in this--this tomb...
Always young
with her.
You will never know
age nor grief.
That isn't the kind
of love I want.
What is it you want?
Why...
Why..
Just two people
to live together
And to love each other.
To laugh
at little things and--
And sometimes cry
over big ones.
To share what--
whatever comes along.
And to grow old together.
And, someday,
When one is gone...
To hope to be
together again somewhere.
That isn't much
to offer, is it?
Compared to kingdoms
and power and glory
That will never change.
Tanya...
Hail, Vincey!
Hash-a-mo-tep
sends me to tell you
That the festival
of the sacred well
Will begin
at the setting of the sun.
You and Holly will be guided
through the hall of kings.
And Tanya?
The lady may not come.
No woman may view
the ceremony of the well
But the maidens
of the temple.
I don't want to see
any more ceremonies.
I'm going
to talk to Holly again.
Tanya...
Man: Stop--
Tanya: I must,
I've got to talk to her!
( speaks foreign language )
Oh, why can't I
make you understand?
( speaking
foreign language )
I'm sorry, I...
They wouldn't let me pass,
and I had to see you.
Well?
You--you
are sending us away.
You will return
to your own country.
Yes, I know.
Leo told us.
But...Please...
What is it you want?
Let Leo come with us.
Send him away, too.
Send him away?
Are you mad?
Please.
He came here
following a dream--
A dream men
have followed
Since the first son
saw his father die.
He alone, of all men,
has realized that dream,
And you ask me
to send him away,
To send him back to you
And your little mortal love.
No, no. Even if he
never loves me...
Why, I have
to make you understand.
It's not for myself.
I'm pleading for him.
You're pleading for him?
What can you or the world
you live in offer him
That will last longer
than a miserable human life?
After the festival
in the hall of kings,
There will be slaves
waiting at the outer wall
To guide you in safety
to your little world.
Go now.
Go if you fear my anger.
Then if you
won't send him back,
Well, will you
let me stay here
Where I
can see him sometimes?
What harm can that do?
What can it
take away from you?
You will have everything.
You will have him.
I shall have nothing
If you take away
being near him.
I'm taking nothing away
from you that was ever yours.
He has been mine since...
Why do I stand here
talking with you?
Go now!
Why are you afraid of me?
Afraid?
You are afraid.
And now I see why.
Because I'm human,
and you're not.
Because I'm young,
And you know love
belongs to the young.
Your magic
makes you seem young,
But in your heart,
you're old, old!
You were young once like me,
but now you're old,
And it's too late
for love forever.
He will never love you.
I know that now.
Keep him here!
Make him king
over your slaves and savages!
But he
will never love you!
Never! Never! Never!
Go!
( sobs )
She came here
from his arms.
The sacrifice
within the hour
In the hall of kings...
He shall sit beside you
on the throne
And watch her die
And not know.
Who can be blamed
if she wanders away,
And no one can find her?
Send men to search.
Show concern
for his sorrow.
All the while knowing
that he watched her die.
And she,
through her veil,
Saw him watching.
Tanya: What is this?!
Where are you taking me?!
( speaking
foreign language )
( continues
in foreign language )
( women speak excitedly
What is this?
What are they doing?
It is she's command.
She sends you
as an offering to the flame.
No! Leo!
Leo!
Foolish one.
Would you
destroy him, too?
If he could hear you,
if he knew your fate,
What could he do?
Let him try to save you,
And he will be set upon
by soldiers and priests.
He will die with you.
But he shall not know.
( speaking
foreign language )
( slow drumbeat plays )
( speaking foreign language )
( sounding )
( marching music plays )
This is a happy festival
for kor...
The happiest of all
for me.
That girl
they're bringing in,
What does she do?
She carries to the gods
my gratitude
For the gift
of enduring life.
Carries to the...How?
You shall see.
Is she a dancer, too?
No...
She will not dance.
( gong chimes )
( music ends )
Is this
a human sacrifice?
It's the immemorial custom
of the people of kor.
Is that...?
No, it can't be.
Who is that girl?
Who is it?
Is it Tanya?
It's Tanya!!
( shouts
in foreign language )
Take her
to the stairs.
( crowd shouting )
Through those doors!
( crowd screaming )
( shouting continues )
( wind whistling )
Ohh!!
Aah!!
Ohh! Ohh!
You found my temple,
But you came
the dangerous way.
Here is what you sought.
So the flame of life
has leapt from the earth
Since time began.
What does the flame
or anything else matter now?
I want no power
you have to give.
I want nothing
He thinks he loves you now.
I can wait.
Wait?
For what?
For you to grow old.
Until then,
you will be cared for
As my dearest possession.
And he?
He will bathe in the
flame and be as I am.
You will grow old,
withered, ugly.
And when at last, repelled,
he turns from you,
I shall be standing
by his side unchanged.
And if I won't go
in the flame?
You have no choice.
If you refuse,
the girl shall die.
Kill me, then!
You mean, if I refuse
to go in the flame,
You'll have her killed?
Oh, Leo,
I'd rather die now.
I'll always love you,
Tanya.
No, no.
Trust me.
Believe in my love.
I'm ready.
No, Leo,
it's a trick!
How do you know you
won't be burned alive?
If I stand in the flame
And come forth unharmed,
Then will you follow?
I will.
Don't think you can
go unpunished forever.
Somewhere, there's a power
That won't let such
wickedness and cruelty go on.
Your hair will whiten.
Your eyes will lose
their brightness.
Your cheeks
will wrinkle.
Your limbs will wither...
While I defy the years
and laugh at time.
I call upon the flame
most powerful, most swift--
Preserver of life
and youth and beauty.
Your eyes will lose
their brightness.
Your cheeks
will wrinkle.
Your limbs will wither.
While I defy the years
And laugh at time.
Now do you believe
I spoke the truth?
My love.
I can't see you clearly.
( gasping )
My eyes...
The flame.
My voice sounds strange
to my ears.
( sobs )
( wails )
( sniveling )
I die.
I die!
( sobbing )
Have pity on my shame.
( sighs )
I remember, long ago,
A garden...
In the sun.
Dead?
Dead!
She cannot die!
A party of slaves
that were to guide you.
The gold symbol...
We'll be safe.
She told me.
The greatest secret
in the world,
And we're turning
our backs on it.
Holly: "she staggered
to the ground,
"a withered creature,
incredibly old.
"and so she died
terribly and pitifully
"even as her lips
spoke of eternal life.
"but though she was dead,
"the power of her golden symbol
reached out and held us safe.
"and so, after
incredible adventures,
"we escaped to the outer world.
"and thus we lived
to record the story
In this manuscript."
It seems as though
it couldn't have happened.
Why, no one could believe it
Unless they'd been there with us.
Now that we're safe
in this friendly world,
Do you know, I
feel sorry for her.
We never shall know
what really did happen.
I sometimes think
That her bathing in
the flame a second time
Was an overexposure
To that terrifically powerful
unknown element.
And sometimes I think that such--
Such inhuman immortality
was never meant to be,
And some greater power than she
Reached out and--
and destroyed her.
After all, Holly,
Perhaps there is
no real flame of life.
I think there is.
What?
Yes. Right here.
Holly: Here?
In this fireplace--
The flame in any fireplace
In any home where two people
live and love each other...
And in their hearts.