So rare to find
A friend like you
Somehow when you're around
The sky is always blue
The way we talk
The things you say
The way you make it all okay
And how you know
All of my jokes
But you laugh anyway
If I could wish
For one thing
I'd take the smile
That you bring
Wherever you go
In this world
I'll come along
Together we dream
The same dream
Forever I'm here for you
You're here for me
Two voices
One song
I really like
that Teresa.
And for the bridge,
let's try E-flat for two bars,
then D-flat then
back to A-flat.
Yeah, nice.
Let's try it.
I never wanna see her again.
She's so not my
friend anymore.
Hey, Stacie.
Had a fight
with Courtney?
You mean the
backstabber?
You're best friends.
Can't you two work it out?
What's the point of
even having friends?
They just
turn on you.
Not real friends.
Real friends care even
if you make a mistake.
Yeah, right. I think they
let you down when it counts.
You're not the only
person to think that.
I know a story about best
friends who thought that, too.
Of course, they lived in a
world with good and bad magic,
flying serpents and
a diamond castle.
Yeah...
One day, they had
a terrible fight.
That's what put them
in danger.
What happened?
Well, it started with music.
Music?
What do you mean?
They loved
to sing together.
Like Teresa
and I do.
If I could wish for one thing
I'd take the smile
That you bring
Wherever you go
In this world
I'll come along
Together we dream
The same dream
Forever I'm here for you
You're here for me
Two voices
One song
And anywhere you are
You know I'll be around
And when you call my name
I'll listen for the sound
If I could wish
for one thing
I'd take the smile
That you bring
Wherever you go
In this world
I'll come along
Together we dream
The same dream
Forever I'm here for you
You're here for me
Two voices
One song
I really like that.
So do I.
It sounds magical
somehow.
Everything sounds
magical to you, Alexa.
That's because
I believe in magic.
And wishes.
And dreams
that come true?
Always dreams
that come true.
Good, then it's your
night to do the dishes.
What?
My dream
come true.
You know, Liana,
I also believe in witches.
Evil witches who chase
unsuspecting girls
with soapy dish cloths.
Alexa, look.
What?
Come here.
Oh, watch out for
that slippery spot.
Now, look.
They're beautiful.
Two perfect hearts.
They are perfect.
They almost look...
Magical?
Precisely.
I think they
look pretty magical, too.
What if we made
them into necklaces?
Necklaces that have the
secret power to grant...
A wish!
Exactly.
Best friends today.
Tomorrow.
And always.
What is it?
My stomach's growling and all
we have at home is bread and jam.
Whoa!
Flowers.
I don't like
this, Liana.
Do you think it'll be over soon?
Maybe if you wish
on something magical.
Liana, it's beautiful.
I love it.
What about yours?
The perfect match.
Oh, Liana...
I know.
Well, let's salvage
what we can.
That's it. All the
flowers we have.
Even if we sell them all,
the money will never last us
until next
growing season.
Of course it will.
It has to.
Now what would
you like for lunch?
Looks like we have
bread and jam or
jam and bread.
You know what I would wish for,
if these stones were really magic?
More. More food than
we can possible eat,
more house than we
could ever explore,
more clothes than
we could ever wear.
Then we'd never have to worry
about another thing ever again.
Except how insufferable we'd be.
"Butler, I can't possibly wear
all these beautiful dresses.
"It's horrible."
"How dare those princes invite me
"to five different balls
on the same night?
"I can't possibly
go to all of them."
Good day,
ma'am.
And to you, Miss.
She looks...
Starving.
Excuse me,
ma'am.
Please, may I
share this with you?
But it's
your lunch.
I'm not very hungry.
Go ahead.
Thank you.
Please, take one
of my treasures.
I couldn't.
You don't want to hurt her feelings.
Well...
Maybe this.
There you
go then,
a nice present
for a nice girl.
Thank you.
One,
two, three.
I guess the fancy carriage will
have to wait until next year.
Right, Liana?
Liana?
Now, that
is magical.
Isn't it?
We should give it back
to that poor old woman.
She didn't know
what she had.
Unlike us. We have
bread and jam.
And jam and bread.
And a ruined garden.
We have
work to do.
I'm blindfolded
On this carriage ride
That they call life
Keep trying to make it
Through that next turn
Knuckles white
And holding tight
So here I go
Taking the curve
But I know that
I'm never alone
I think of you
And how you never let me go
I feel
Connected
Protected
It's like you're sitting right
With me all the time
You hear me
You're near me
And everything else
Is gonna be all right
'Cause nothing can break this
Nothing can break this
Nothing can break this tie
Connected
'Cause nothing can break this
Nothing can break this
Nothing can break this tie
Connected
This is weird.
'Cause nothing can break this
Nothing can break this
Nothing can break this tie
Connected
Connected inside
Sing the chorus
again, please?
It's beautiful.
Uh... Sure. And you
have a beautiful voice.
Oh, thank you.
I haven't sung
anything in so long.
I really miss it.
Are you real?
How did you get
in the mirror?
Oh, I'm nobody.
Nobody at all.
Just pretend
you never saw me.
Wait! Don't go.
Yes, stay please.
Two Voices.
One, two, three.
If I could wish for one thing
I'd take the smile
That you bring
Wherever you go
In this world
I'll come along
Together we dream
The same dream
Dream the same dream
Forever I'm here for you
You're here for me
Three voices
One song
She's singing. Melody,
the Muses' apprentice.
I love
Singing solo
Don't miss
Our old trio
I'll have the castles
All to myself
You'll remain trophies
I've put on my shelf
The world will be wicked
And all will bow to me
Bravo, mistress. Bravo!
Interrupting me
again, Slyder.
She's alive.
I sense her
singing somewhere.
See?
The apprentice is living?
Hmm... Did you really
think I wouldn't find her?
Always the optimists.
But the world is
really a very small
and dark place.
Just how I like it.
Slyder,
bring her to me.
With pleasure, mistress.
Together we dream
The same dream
Dream the same dream
Forever I'm here for you
You're here for me
Three voices
One song
Wait, please
don't go away.
I won't. This is
too much fun.
I'm Liana and
this is Alexa.
Can you tell us
your name?
It's Melody.
You must have
a favorite song.
Would you
teach it to us?
Please, we'd love
to sing with you.
I... I shouldn't.
We're fast learners.
Well...
It goes like this.
Believe
In all that can be
A miracle starts
Whenever you dream
Believe
And sing from your heart
You'll see
Your song will hold the key
Believe
In all that can be
A miracle starts
Whenever you dream
Believe
So...
And sing from your heart
She's in the mirror.
You'll see
Your song will hold the key
You have to hide me,
he's seen me in the mirror!
Who's seen you
in the mirror?
Slyder.
We have to hide.
We have to hide now.
The cellar, go.
Liana.
Just go. I'll
be right there.
Come out, come out,
wherever you are.
Sing, why don't you?
I led him here.
A-ha!
Some friends you have,
leaving you behind like that.
No.
No, no, no!
There's
nothing left.
Nothing.
It can't be.
This is all my fault.
Throw me far away
before he comes back.
Why? What does
he want with you?
It's Lydia,
his mistress.
She must know
I have the key.
The key to what?
The Diamond Castle.
A diamond castle?
My home.
The birthplace of music.
Every time
a new song is sung
anywhere in the world,
a diamond appears
on the walls.
I lived there with Dori,
Phaedra and Lydia.
The three Muses of music.
They took care of
the Diamond Castle
and I studied as
their apprentice.
They were all friends,
playing different kinds of music,
but Lydia wanted to be
the one and only Muse.
What happened?
Dori and Phaedra believed
music was for everyone.
Lydia was furious
and vowed to get the
Diamond Castle for herself.
She found an ancient cave
filled with magic,
and transformed her flute
into an instrument
of dark magic.
With her new powers,
she came back for the Diamond Castle,
to spread her darkness
everywhere.
The Muses hid their musical instruments
along with the castle,
and gave me the key,
in case anything
should happen to them.
The Muses tried to
reason with Lydia,
but she just
turned on them.
I ran and ran,
but Slyder was chasing me.
And then,
I saw my only chance.
I hid.
But I dropped my whistle
and Slyder broke it,
trapping me in the mirror.
I was so afraid.
I never said a word,
until I met you two.
And now, look.
I've ruined everything.
But if you
have the key...
Do you know where the
Diamond Castle's hidden?
Yes, near the
Seven Stones,
far to the west.
Can Lydia
be stopped?
I hope so.
I think if I play
the Muses' instruments,
I can break her spells.
No. No. Liana,
we've never been farther
away than the village.
Melody, what happens if Lydia
destroys the Muses' instruments?
She wins.
She has it all.
Our world will be nothing
but shadows and sorrow.
Kind of like
our home.
Exactly like
Lydia and Slyder
did that to us.
They'll do that and
worse to other people.
Can we let
that happen?
You want me to say no, don't you?
It's the three of us now, Melody.
Really?
The three of us?
I like that.
What about that serpent?
Will he come back?
Not if I don't sing.
And I love singing.
I found her,
mistress.
Where is she?
I'm in no mood
for games, Slyder.
Here, here. She's
hiding in the mirror.
I saw her singing
in the mirror.
Oh, really?
Melody...
Auntie Lydia would like
to have a word with you.
Melody?
Where did
you find this?
She was singing with two
other girls near a cottage.
One with light hair
and one with dark hair.
Take me to them.
It's beyond
beautiful.
Look, Melody.
We made it,
the Valley of Flowers.
Mmm.
I smell roses.
Liana.
Snake!
Cutest snake
I've ever seen.
Okay, okay, I was only
trying to protect you.
Look at you.
Aren't you the
cutest thing?
Where'd they
come from?
There's nobody
for miles.
They must
be lost.
Look,
they're friends.
We can't leave
them here.
They'll starve.
Hey, hey,
that tickles.
What do you think, Melody?
She's a keeper right?
Aw, look at
her sparkly little eyes.
Sparkles, I like that.
I hereby name you
Sparkles.
And what should
we call that little one?
Your name is Lily,
like the beautiful flower.
Can we keep them?
I think we have
room for two more.
Oh, I bet you little guys
are hungry though, aren't you?
Don't even talk
about food,
my stomach has been
rumbling for miles.
Ah! So, that's
what I was hearing.
I thought
it was thunder.
Or stampeding horses.
Enough.
Or jump
roping elephants.
Mmm!
Smells like
roast chicken.
I'm starving.
Go ahead, you
haven't eaten all day.
We'd love to, but we
don't have any money.
That's where the
smell is coming from.
Am I drooling?
I think I'm drooling.
Have you seen him?
Well, have you?
Who?
Those good for
nothing musicians.
They were due
here an hour ago.
I should never
have hired them.
I told myself, "Edgar, don't
hire those rascals again."
Oh, but did I
listen to myself, no!
When are
they coming?
They're getting
restless.
Hold your horses,
they're coming.
Actually, they're here.
That is, we're here.
We're the
substitute rascals.
Uh... Musicians.
We are?
We are.
We're very good and
we'll only cost you...
A meal.
I mean, two meals.
And two
doggie bags.
Hmm...
How do I know
you can play?
Where
is the music?
You're hired.
Hey!
Perfectly good
mashed potatoes.
Think I could get them to
throw some gravy this way?
Come on.
Give us some music,
will you?
Who are they?
Good evening.
Hello.
Here we are
Far from home
Little bit hungry
And a little alone
But it's all right
Yes, it's all right
'Cause in this room
There might be friends
Can't see how the story ends
But it's all right
Yeah, it's all right
We can start
Anew
Can't go back
So we gotta go on
We'll stick together
Staying strong
There's a diamond castle
In my mind
And someday soon
We're gonna find it
Somehow things are looking up
Feeling like we've
Changed our luck
I can see life
In a new light
Can't stay long
Passing through
Don't know where we're
Going to
But it's all right
'Cause we just might
Find a way
That's true
Can't go back
So we got to go on
Cheeky they are,
taking our place.
Not bad though.
Not bad, for girls.
And someday soon
We're gonna find it
We're gonna find
The perfect place
For us to be
And hear our
Melody set free
Wait, wait...
I feel something.
It's very faint.
Can't quite make it out,
but it's just about...
Oh, I think I got it.
Oh, just take me
to her. Now!
Yes, mistress.
We're gonna find it
Can't go back
So we got to go on
We'll stick together
Staying strong
There's a diamond castle
In my mind
And someday soon
We're gonna find it
Someday soon
Thank you.
And for our
next number...
Mashed potatoes.
We're going to
take a little break.
You've earned your keep.
Thank you.
Two maidens were stealing
A gig from two kind men
Whose singing was magic
They were both so handsome
How did you get to
be so good-looking?
Genetics.
Ah!
One girl fair and pretty
And one a dark beauty
One wearing orange
And one...
Well, you know perfectly well
nothing rhymes with orange.
In this song you belong
With lads like us
You belong
Hey!
That's for leaving
without a goodbye.
Sorry,
that was meant for me.
I feel for you.
Far be it from us to
spoil a happy reunion.
Come on, Alexa.
No, no, my apologies.
That was ancient history.
Uh... Ian.
Hey!
Smells like mashed
potatoes, too.
They skipped out.
Incredible.
We always
get the girl.
Ah!
Wait, the story
is not over.
I'm guessing they
left it on purpose.
So, we could
return it.
Would a
girl do that?
It is possible.
The only polite thing
to do is find them.
Definitely.
Nice to see
you too, Bertha.
I'm looking
for two girls.
One light haired,
one dark haired.
Did they
pass this way?
I...
I don't remember.
Really? Memory
escapes you, does it?
Oh, look at all
these sad, sad faces.
So, deliciously
dreadful.
Let's try again,
shall we?
Where are the girls?
Out back,
down the trail.
You have
to be kidding.
No, they were
really cute.
Too cute for
their own good.
What is it, Sparkles?
We better get
out of here.
Why? What's
wrong?
Slyder!
Lydia.
So, you know
my name.
I wonder who could have told you.
Leave them alone.
Ha! Doesn't take much
to fool Slyder, I see.
Give me the mirror.
The mirror, now!
I don't think so.
Oh, you won't.
What will I do?
No!
The mirror.
Never!
How on Earth...
Run, Alexa, run!
Slyder, get them!
Don't look back!
Up we go.
Not late, am I?
Not yet.
Go, go, go!
Watch out!
Ye of little faith.
Wherever did
you come from?
Is that how you
say thank you?
I'm sorry,
thank you.
We were almost...
But you weren't.
Timing is everything.
Your handkerchief.
Thank you.
Jeremy.
Liana.
My brother Ian.
My friend Alexa.
An honor, milady.
You're twins.
What? No!
Really?
Mum should
have told us.
I feel cheated.
Duped.
Hoodwinked.
They think
they're charming.
Rakish.
Roguish.
Is he gone?
Is anybody hurt?
Hmm?
I don't understand,
how'd you escape
Lydia's flute?
I don't know.
I avoided the spell by
disappearing, but you...
I just don't get it.
Mind us asking what we've
gotten ourselves into?
There were two...
No, no, 20 men. Uh... Soldiers.
Lashing swords
everywhere.
I finished off
scores of them.
But in the end,
the girls escaped.
Quiet, I'm thinking.
Oh, that's good.
You go right ahead. Think away.
Hmm...
Has to be, yes.
They wear stones from
the Diamond Castle.
And here we are,
the Grand River.
Do you know
this place, Melody?
This is good.
Really good.
We just have to make it
across to the Seven Stones.
I wonder...
Ian, do you remember those odd
rocks we passed last spring?
Yes, I do.
Something almost
magical about them.
Melody, what do the
Seven Stones look like?
Here.
Well, there you go,
same place.
I know exactly
where it is.
Wait! The sign
shows a bridge.
Probably washed
out long ago.
But it would be
so much faster.
No, not really.
We're doing fine.
Shall we
carry on, Ian?
Oh, straight ahead, old boy.
Straight ahead.
Sparkles.
Lily.
Be right back.
We could just
keep going.
We could.
But we won't.
No.
Here, Sparkles!
Here, girl.
Something's wrong.
Looking for
these morsels?
Put them down.
Now why would
I choose to do that?
Common courtesy.
I know you and you.
Double trouble.
You owe me!
Ancient history,
mate.
Meat, you two.
He's got a point.
And a rather
sharp one, at that.
Thank you for
releasing the dogs,
you'll free the
gentlemen, next.
Free them?
I'm gonna eat some.
Those boys?
They'll give you indigestion.
Don't care.
Collecting on
an old debt.
They owe
you money?
No, lives.
They wanted to cross my bridge.
But there isn't any bridge.
Course there is,
if you answer my riddle.
And they failed,
just like everyone else.
Ask us your riddle.
If we answer correctly,
you let them go.
If we don't, you have dinner
for tomorrow night, too.
It's a deal.
Are you ready?
Of course.
What instrument
can you hear,
but can't see
and can't touch?
It's a trick. There's no
instrument like that.
Final answer?
No.
Melody, what
do you think?
I don't know.
You play every
instrument I know
with either your hands
or your mouth.
Right. Your hands
or your mouth...
Your time is...
The answer is,
your voice.
You can't see it or touch it,
but when you sing,
everybody
can hear it.
Yes.
No! No, no, no.
Can't be done.
No! No! No!
Is it real?
Yes.
Nobody knows my riddle.
Impossible.
Unthink...
Pity, I was rather
looking forward to dinner.
Hey!
Girls...
Wait for us.
We can't.
Meet us at the
Seven Stones.
What's wrong with
that picture?
Everything.
I can't do it
anymore, Liana.
We've been walking for hours.
Are you okay?
Do we have
a little water?
We ran out.
About an hour after
we ran out of food.
Oh.
I know.
Alexa, I see
something.
And it's
not that far.
This mansion,
it's beautiful.
I wonder if someone
royal lives here.
Hopefully someone
generous and royal.
Who can spare a bed and some food.
You've come
at last.
Welcome.
Welcome, miladies.
Sparkles, no!
What may
we serve you?
Could you spare
some bread and water?
Please, this
is all yours.
The grounds,
the house, everything.
Ours?
The legend.
It's been foretold
two friends,
best friends, will come
to live in the hall.
For years, we've been
tending the hall
until the rightful
owners arrive.
You must
be mistaken.
No. It's just as
the legend foretold.
I can't
believe it.
I don't
What do you
think, Melody?
You know, the Muses sing songs
about legends and destiny.
This really
could be yours.
So, if
it's ours...
Do you think we can eat something?
Yes. Go, eat.
Oh, of course you get your share.
You don't have to
do tricks for your supper.
What's mine is yours.
Oh!
They're
beautiful.
Try one on.
I look like
a princess.
Oh, Liana,
it's a perfect home for us.
More food than we could ever eat,
a beautiful
dress every day
and a gorgeous
garden.
But we can't stay.
Why not?
It's ours.
We're finally having
some good luck,
why can't
we enjoy it?
Maybe we can come back after we
take Melody to the Diamond Castle.
If we come back.
What do you mean?
Trolls, serpents,
evil magic.
We may not live
to come back.
We promised Melody
we'd help her.
And we did.
We've taken her this far.
I can't go
any farther.
I can't.
But, we promised.
You gave your word.
Let Ian and
Jeremy do it.
I'm staying here.
You don't mean that.
Yes, I do.
Please, don't argue.
You've done enough.
See, even
Melody thinks so.
Stay with me.
If we don't stop Lydia,
we'll all be living under a dark cloud.
No laughter, no music,
just sadness everywhere.
Why us?
Why can't somebody else do it?
Because Melody
is our friend.
You're choosing
Melody over me.
No, it's
not like that.
If you were really my friend,
you'd understand.
You're right,
I don't understand.
Come on,
Sparkles.
Ready, Melody?
We are going to
the Seven Stones.
No, Lily.
I can't believe
she did that.
Liana?
Liked the manor,
did you?
So terribly
tempting.
How did you know?
Because I was
there first.
Did the servants tell
you about a legend?
Yes, they said
that two...
They were under
your power.
Mmm-hmm.
Now, give me
the mirror.
I don't
have it.
You hurt her.
No mirror,
mistress.
So, the other
girl has it.
Where is
your friend,
or should I say
ex-friend?
I don't know.
That doesn't
work on me.
Bold words for a girl who
no longer wears her necklace.
As long as you and your friend wore
your guardian stones, you were protected.
But now...
Where is she?
Going to the
Seven Stones.
Slyder, get the
girl and the mirror.
And this time,
do it right.
Yes, mistress.
This must be it,
right?
The Seven Stones!
We're here!
We're really here.
You did it.
Just down there is the misty
glade and the Diamond Castle.
I wish Alexa
were with us.
Yes, well, she
made her choice.
Liana, I know
you miss her.
Miss her?
Why would I miss her?
We've only been friends for
as long as I can remember.
She's been with me through the
best and worst times of my life.
She knows me better than anyone
else in the entire universe.
I feel like a part
of me is gone.
What is it?
Put me down.
Mistress Lydia
will be glad to see you.
Welcome, darling.
I have nothing
to say to you.
Aw!
That must be because
you're lonely.
Alexa, won't
you join us?
Alexa!
She told me where to find you.
Friends are highly
overrated, don't you think?
And here it is.
Ah! So much trouble
for such a little apprentice.
Melody, I know
you can hear me.
Melody,
come out now.
Oh,
stubborn girl.
Walk, Alexa, walk.
Alexa, no!
Stop, stop!
She only
listens to me.
And I'll only stop her
if Melody asks me to.
Anything to say,
Melly Belly?
Stop her, Lydia.
Girl, wait.
I want the key to
the Diamond Castle.
Let my friends go.
Ha! The key first,
and show me
where the castle is,
then I'll release them.
Okay.
But we come right
back to let them go.
Oh, there's
a good girl.
Meet me
outside, Slyder.
When you're ready.
Alexa, Alexa,
wake up.
It's me, Liana.
On behalf of my
great mistress,
the one and
only Muse.
Aw.
Nothing like
a sad ending.
West, I presume?
Yes.
No sign of them.
Must have gone
without us.
Disappointing.
To say the least.
Oh, hang on.
Okay, okay,
what's the rush?
Where's Liana?
Why do I have
a bad feeling?
Where are they, girl?
I'm sorry,
Alexa.
Why did I
ever leave?
I'm so sorry.
Lily?
That's Alexa's
necklace.
We were both wearing the necklaces
when Lydia couldn't mesmerize us.
Drop, Lily,
it's okay.
Please let
this work.
Best friends, today,
tomorrow and always.
Liana,
where are we?
In trouble, but then,
what else is new?
What happened?
Lydia has Melody.
No!
They're on their way
to the Diamond Castle.
We have to stop
them, but how?
We're going
to climb up,
together.
If you want me to believe
the Diamond Castle is here,
give me the key.
The key...
Now, or I throw
you in the pond
and your friends never
come out of the cave.
The key...
Is to place diamonds
in the diamond.
And that is...
The boulder.
Ah, I see it.
Now what?
Each slot
holds a diamond.
Placed in
the proper order,
the castle will
then be revealed.
Where do I begin?
I'm so sorry, Liana,
about everything I said.
Me, too.
Lily, come back.
Whoa!
Jeremy.
Liana.
I see you'll
follow us anywhere.
Look at that. Again you show
up just when we need you.
Timing is
everything.
Here.
Mmm-hmm.
And then to the
right, two spaces.
Ooh, the last one.
So horribly exciting.
Where's
the castle?
You see, there are
a few more steps.
You actually think
this mad plan will work?
It has to.
Once Lydia finds the castle and
destroys the musical instruments,
nobody will ever
be able to stop her.
What you think,
Ian?
Doom, disaster,
catastrophe.
So, we're in then?
Definitely.
You've been
playing with me.
I just...
Diamonds aren't
the key at all.
You think your friends
will come rescue you.
You fool.
You can't be the only
Muse, Lydia, it isn't right.
The Diamond Castle's
meant for everybody.
Great singers don't need a chorus.
Mistress?
Go, Slyder,
and make it snappy.
Slyder,
what is it?
What?
So far...
So good.
Oh, I knew
they'd come.
A waste of a trip.
Come to me.
No, don't
listen to her.
Back off,
beastie.
I liked
that guitar.
Into the water
and drown.
No! Liana,
Alexa, stop!
Stop!
How did you...
Do you believe
in magic?
My flute, now,
or I break the mirror,
then she never
gets out, never.
Wait!
The flute.
Don't do it.
Don't let her have it.
You sound like someone who
wants to stay in there forever.
No, but I will
to stop you.
No!
Melody!
Pathetic child.
Give it
to me.
Save Melody!
Hey, Slyder,
over here.
Nice serpent.
Nice.
Well done,
mate.
All in a
day's work.
You good girls.
No!
No! No! No!
I... I can't
believe it.
She's gone.
It's over,
finally over.
Melody, can
you hear us?
Everybody all right?
Lydia's gone,
but so is
Melody.
There must be some way
to bring Melody back.
The Muses'
instruments might do it.
But we don't have the key
to the Diamond Castle.
I hate to be a spoil sport,
but I don't see any Diamond Castle.
I believe it's here.
How can you believe
what you don't see?
Sometimes what's real...
Is something
you can't see.
What if Melody's
song is the key?
Hidden beneath the ground
Is the spring
That feeds the creek
Invisible as the wind
That you feel
Upon your cheek
And every breeze that whispers
Reminds us constantly
Sometimes what's real
Is something you can't see
Believe
In all that can be
A miracle starts
Whenever you dream
Believe
And sing from your heart
You'll see
Your song will hold the key
Liana, Alexa.
Don't you
look precious?
Not a word about
this to anyone.
Home.
Ian, have
you see this?
The Muses' instruments are up here.
If we play the
instruments now?
The Muses
will come home.
Lydia!
Quick,
the instruments.
No!
Believe
Your song will hold the key
Your song will hold the key.
Believe
What?
No!
Your song will hold the key
Believe
Make it stop!
Your song will hold the key
Believe
What happened?
You're a tough
act to follow.
Liana, Alexa
for the beautiful music in
your hearts, which saved us all,
we anoint you
Princesses of Music.
Thank you.
No, thank you.
Without your sacrifices,
we would not be here.
And this is
for you, Melody.
You are no longer
an apprentice.
You are
a true Muse.
Thank you.
You have proven
your worth.
You now replace Lydia
as the third Muse.
For your courage and kind aid.
Thank you.
Many thanks.
Odd looking.
Whoa!
Wicked!
Oh, right.
Will you stay with us?
We can have rooms
near each other.
Live in this
beautiful castle?
Once, I would have said
yes in the blink of an eye,
but now, I just want
my old home back.
It was more
than enough.
We thought you might say that.
Plant these in
your garden at home.
It's not an accident
The time we spent apart
But now we're so close
I can always find you
Right here in my heart
You've given me
Something I need
And I don't ever
Want it to end
Because of you
I know I've found
My strength again
I feel connected
Connected
Protected
It's like you're sitting
Right with me all the time
You hear me
You're near me
And everything else
Is gonna be all right
'Cause nothing can break this
Nothing can break this
Nothing can break this tie
Connected
Connected inside
Do you suppose
they need an escort?
Someone has to keep
them out of trouble.
Goodbye.
Farewell.
- Farewell.
Thank you.
I'll come visit.
I would have hated it if
Alexa and Liana didn't make up.
Me, too.
Best friends
stick together.
Do you think Courtney's
sorry for what she said?
Only one way
to find out.
What do
you think?
I'm sorry for
what I said.
Maybe you should
tell her that.
Yeah...
Yeah.
Thanks, Barbie.
Bye, Teresa.
Well done.
Timing is
everything.
Now, where were we?
Two voices
One song
Subtitles by LeapinLar