16 total strangers
stand before you
ready to take on the most
extreme adventure ever created.
In this real-life
social experiment,
there are no games, no votes,
and above all else, no rules.
They may do whatever
they have to
to win a $500,000 prize.
And the only way out
is to forfeit and go home.
Eight hours ago,
these adventurers boarded
a private plane in London
with no knowledge
of where they were going.
Their adventure begins now.
You may remove your blindfolds.
Contestants, you are
about to participate
in an unprecedented adventure.
Nothing of its kind
has ever been attempted before.
And the playing field?
One of the most remote
and foreboding places
in the world--
the Siberian wilderness.
500 miles of dense woodlands
surround you in all directions.
This region of
Russia is so remote,
that there are no roads
to connect the cities.
Most places are only accessible
via helicopter.
You have surrendered
all modern conveniences.
You will now attempt
to live as people did here
100 years ago.
Your goal?
To survive until
the end of winter.
Those of you who remain
until then
will have 500,000 dollars
to divide amongst yourselves.
Do whatever you need
to do to get there.
The choice is yours.
In this experiment,
you'll be allowed
to govern yourselves completely
with no interference
and no help.
We will abandon you
with a camera crew
to document your adventure,
but the world you know
is gone--
slate wiped clean,
and you will start
a new civilization.
- Are you ready to begin?
- Yes.
- Yeah.
Okay.
2 miles due east...
are the remains
of a primitive settlement,
an outpost where fur traders
would stop
to barter their wares.
But one day in 1908,
this settlement
was found abandoned,
fire still burning,
food still cooking in pots,
but its 14 inhabitants
had mysteriously disappeared,
never to be seen again.
We've recreated this settlement
exactly as it was
100 years earlier.
We only hope that you don't
suffer the same fate
as the previous residents.
Through the woods,
red flags marked
the path taken
by the fur traders
to find the settlement.
You will follow this same path.
However, at the end of the day,
only 14 of you will remain.
The last two to arrive
will be sent home immediately.
So get there as quickly
as you can,
and find yourself
a place to live,
because this will be
your home for the duration.
Fortunately, you've all packed
for a wilderness vacation.
However, there is a twist.
On this show,
your bags will not be
joining you.
What?
You will be competing
with just the clothes
on your back.
- Are you ready?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Then the game has begun. Go!
In darker times,
Siberia was the location
of the gulags,
prison camps that needed
no fences,
because escape
into the formidable woods
was futile.
Natives named this region
The Valley Of Death.
Tunguska is the location
of one of the most mysterious
events in recent history.
It was feared by the locals
as a cursed place.
This is where our contestants
will compete
to see if they have the strength
physically and mentally
to endure.
This is Siberia.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
As soon as Jonathon
said "Go"...
I think it was a bit
late off my mark.
I was in the last position
for a quite a while,
so I was a little worried.
This guy's pretty fast--
uh, Johnny.
When I looked up
and started running,
all I saw
was him in front of me,
and in my mind, I-I knew that
I had to just keep up with him
and not be one of the last two,
or it was game over.
We came to this one flag,
and everyone kept on running
just the obvious path--
wide-open path.
And in a game like this,
you have to
make your own choices.
You choose to follow someone,
or you choose to make
your own path.
She was faster than half of
the guys out here.
She's just kind of this--
this warrior viking princess.
That's one of the reasons
that I was following her.
Right after we dropped
the blindfolds
and he said "Go,"
I turned around,
just bolted and started
looking for flags
and had one guy trailing
pretty close behind me,
but, you know, for the most
part, I whipped everyone's ass.
We still had all our layers on
from being on the flight
and everything,
so it was getting hot,
and everyone was getting tired.
- The two boys are ahead.
- I think they took a shortcut.
Three are missing.
You know, there's
something about Carolina.
I-I feel like I recognize her.
I just can't figure out
from where.
When I heard, uh, Neeko
kind of fall in there,
I think he might have been
doing some laps.
Come on, let's go.
I didn't exactly
start off with a bang.
- Hey, guys.
- Guys.
Come on.
We got a man down.
And, uh, I saw
that he had fallen,
so I went back and got him.
Try to put some pressure on it.
A little bit of pressure.
- All right, well, don't put some pressure.
- All right.
We're gonna get you there
either way.
I think it's really
honorable that, you know,
he really took the time
to help someone else,
even though it meant it could be
the end of his role in the game.
Being nice is one thing,
but we can't forget that
this is a competition.
Of course I was trying
to throw them off the course.
They were just begging me
to just take it out
and get rid of it.
What are you doing?
Are you allowed to do that?
We all want to win,
but we do have to play it fair.
I believe in life you have
to play fair to win,
and then life rewards you back.
Then I see the settlement,
and I'm like,
you know,
"touchdown, I made it."
And, uh, I just went
straight to one cabin.
Taking this one here.
I know a lot of people
are making a big mess
about being out here 'cause
they're all from the city,
but, you know, I feel
kind of at ease.
I grew up on the farm
and outside,
so it's not really
a big deal to me.
I kind of enjoy it, actually.
I open the door and I see,
uh, that Sabina
just sat down on the bed.
I see that you got here
first, huh?
How did she...
get here before me?
We had to go through mud pits.
We had no idea
what's inside the river.
Aah!
I don't run too fast.
The last two back at the camp
go home.
I think we were,
like, number two or three,
like leading the pack.
I swear I saw this rock.
Are you sure you know
where you're going?
I thought I was.
We were running.
We were on a good path.
But, um, we certainly
just were met
with these huge forests.
I'm pretty sure we
came this way already.
Okay. Let's go back.
We got lost, obviously
uh, the size is a little
disappointing but...
- Ah!
- Whoo!
- I can't believe we made it!
- Home sweet home!
I think we have arrived!
Whoo!
When I made it, I was so
incredibly relieved.
I was so extremely
overwhelmed and happy.
Honey, I'm home!
Yeah, when we got there,
it was--
it was a relief.
And then we saw the cabins,
and that was a relief, too.
It felt really good
to arrive at the settlement,
especially after our trek
there-- a huge sigh of relief.
But also I was really impressed
with what they had given us.
I thought maybe we might be
in huts or,
you know, imagining
what it could look like.
And it was a-- it's actually
a pretty self-sufficient
little settlement.
I'm taking this bed
if nobody minds.
- It smells in there.
- Anything not claimed?
- There are floors.
- I'm gonna get this one.
You made it so quick.
What's your name?
- I'm Sabina.
- Hi, Sabina. I'm Carolina.
- Nice to meet you.
Okay. Oh, and...
I will take...
- I will take this one.
- Hey.
- There are just two guys here?
- Yeah.
- And it's nine or ten of us?
- Uh-huh.
So we are missing, what,
four or five more people?
- Yeah, how many are we missing?
- It was-- it was 16.
Anybody get hurt on the way?
- Yeah, a little bit. - The kid with
the glasses turned his, uh...
- Kid with the glasses?
- Yeah.
Couple ankle tweaks, I think.
Yeah, well, survival
of the fittest, right?
One less person to worry about.
Nobody really
gave a crap except Tommy.
Tommy came back for me,
and I was telling him,
"There's no way you're gonna--
you're gonna carry me
all the way to this camp.
We don't even know how far
it is."
Dan had the mentality
that I was just
gonna leave him in a swamp
somewhere.
We don't know where we are.
Uh...
If I already carried
you 3/4 of a mile,
I'm not gonna stop just because
we're at a bog
and leave you here now.
I mean, I already put that
energy in.
I'm gonna see it through.
It was just at a point where
where I was kind of realizing,
hey, we might not make it.
- I'm pretty sure we're lost.
- No, we're not lost.
That was his choice. I didn't
ask him to come with me.
Got it.
We decided to go back.
We followed exactly where
all the people went.
We looked for the flag.
There was no flag.
Until we actually found it.
So someone cheated
and took the flag
and threw it away.
- But we found it.
- There. Come on.
So we're one, two--
the cocky guy.
- This guy...
- This cabin for girls--
they just have six beds.
You know? We have six as well.
- There's two of them, and, uh...
- 'Cause we got one more--
- nine or ten. - Two more open.
Three-- two more open beds.
They'll be sleeping
on the ground.
I noticed something
that probably, uh,
ended up helping me.
She did something.
She picked up the flag
and she tossed it.
She wasn't trying to help me
out, but inadvertently she did.
The first rule
of the wilderness--
- keep your feet dry.
- Right?
Even thought it hurt,
you know, he kept--
he kept reassuring me that,
yeah, we're still ahead,
we still got this.
You got it.
- You all right?
- Yeah. Yeah. I got it.
You're all right.
She is incredibly fast.
I-I used to play football,
and I-I was barely
keeping up to her.
You know what? Um...
- Oh, look, look, look, look, look!
- Oh, my God!
- There are two of them.
- Yay!
I can't believe they made it!
- Oh, look, look, look. - Yay!
- There are two of them.
I can't believe they made it!
- Will you give us some
help over here, guys? - Yeah.
You see the camp,
and you're relieved
to be there.
Let's make it to the seat.
Why-- why don't you lift him
on that side?
It was-- it was
a really good feeling.
It was actually like, okay,
if I can get this ankle
healed up,
I've got a chance to at least
make the effort.
- Nice to see you guys.
- Thanks.
Right there-- that's
the boys' cabin.
Um, I honestly
thought we were last.
I figured there was a lot
of people there
- when we got there.
- Making way. Making way.
- Can we clear one of these
lower beds, guys? - Yeah. Yeah.
Careful, careful in your foot...
Yeah, he carried him
to the finish line,
which is, uh, in my opinion,
uh, stupid.
Why are you gonna help
your competition?
But, hey, I guess he's
a nice guy,
and, you know, that's
the most important thing to him,
but being nice isn't
gonna get you the prize.
The money would be great,
'cause I could use it,
um, to help others, honestly.
I would like to start
a charity,
and I think that would be
a-a good place to start.
You are gonna get the sympathy
vote the entire time.
- I mean--
- Right. Right.
- That's-- I mean...
- I feel like I earned it.
I think you're faking it.
It's a good idea if you are.
Is everyone here?
Are we the last?
I was kind of starting
to think,
hey, this might not be
good news for us.
Where were you guys?
I don't know. We were just
running around lost.
I had no idea where
we were going, and--
- Which way did you go?
- Ah, jeez.
Well, when you guys all
broke off through the field,
well, we went the other way.
And then we were just
running around in circles
and we couldn't even
find the flag.
And when we did find it,
it was on the ground.
Aw.
- I'm sorry.
- Sorry.
When I found out that we were
the last two people there
and we were getting eliminated,
I was-- I was angry.
I was totally angry
and upset because, you know,
I've been waiting months
to get on this show.
And I didn't plan on
leaving the first week.
I'm a competitor.
I work hard and-- and I never
give up on anything.
We were just running
around in circles, man.
That's all we were doing.
After traveling and, uh,
coming all this way
and planning and--
and all that, um...
yeah, it's disappointing.
- Hi, guys.
- Hi.
I see you all made it
in one piece.
Can I get everybody to come
around here real quick?
I just want to have
a chat with you all.
First off, I want to
congratulate you all
for making it to your new home.
Unfortunately, two of you
weren't so lucky.
As would have happened
a hundred years ago,
some settlers would have died
or been injured
on their way and never made it
to this remote outpost.
Berglind, Harpreet,
please step forward.
Say good-bye to your friends.
You're going home.
Win that money, man.
Good luck.
Bye.
It's a total bummer, like...
If I could go back,
I swear to God
I would have stuck
with the pack,
but you can't go back in time,
unfortunately,
so I'm just gonna have to keep
pushing forward.
I did my best,
so, um... it was a decision
I took.
I went. I-I went
in the opposite direction.
But it was my decision.
You know, you always want
to win, of course.
But if you don't,
you just gotta take it
and walk away with pride.
For the 14 of you who remain,
this village will be your home
for as long as you can bear it.
Behind me is the Revealer.
Periodically, it will open,
and it will grant you an item
that will aid in your survival.
How you use this item,
or who possesses it,
is completely up to you.
If you wish to leave,
or if you need help,
just down that path
where Harpreet and Berglind
just walked to,
there is a safe zone
with a button
that will summon a helicopter.
Once you cross the line
of the safe zone,
you are out, and have
forfeited the competition.
But just remember, there are
no support staff on site.
The only way to get help
is to go to safe zone
and press that button.
That is the only rule.
There are no other rules
on this show.
Settlers, welcome to Siberia.
I wish there was
a couple more rules, honestly,
but at the same time,
if that's what we signed up for
with no rules,
then that's what it is,
so I-I don't really
feel bad about it.
I feel like I've got, like,
a little bit of an upper hand
in... a lot of ways.
Um...
just because I don't think
other people
are willing to do
what I'm willing to do.
I'm not the kind of guy
that's gonna go
attack somebody
or steal something.
I'm gonna try to be fair
to my fellow man,
I guess you could say.
Well, for myself,
I'm a little shy,
and so it's hard for me
to make alliances.
You know... I can't get
"voted out."
No rules kind of has
a double-sided meaning to me.
It's exciting because
anything can happen.
For him to say
"no rules," basically that means
you have to keep an eye
on everything, in a sense,
so you're in charge
of your own food,
you're in charge of
your own clothing. Everything.
It's just on you, without anyone
there to tell you yes or no.
And that's gonna be kind of hard
when it comes to arguments,
because there isn't someone
who has the rulebook
in their hand to tell you
what's what.
We don't want
a "Lord Of The Flies" situation
on our hands.
- Six beds, right?
- There's only six beds.
Someone has to sleep
on the floor.
I'm not sleeping on the floor.
I'm just saying that.
I'm just putting it out there
straightaway.
I was just like,
nuh-unh-unh.
That's not gonna happen.
I think it's fair that
the people who got here first
can stay, and the person
who doesn't can,
you know, compromise.
Because I think you were out,
you know, talking to people,
which isn't a problem,
there's nothing wrong with that,
but... but then you can't
expect to just come in
at the last minute
and still get a spot.
Did everyone hear me?
Did everyone hear me then
clearly saying I'm not
sleeping on the floor?
- I'm not sleeping on the floor.
- Well, someone has to sleep on the floor.
Well, it's not
gonna be me, so...
Why wouldn't it be you?
She got a little bit
upset at her.
Um, I guess Esther's not used
to sleeping on the floor.
I don't think it would have
been such a big deal.
At least we're sleeping
somewhere
and not just out in the woods.
You said whoever gets here
first should have the bed,
and I was here first.
So, what? You don't believe me?
Well, the thing is, no one
saw you get here first.
Did-- I mean, did any
of you guys--
I mean, I didn't see--
I didn't see you walk in.
If everyone thinks it's okay
to sleep on the floor,
then, please, volunteer, but
I'm not sleeping on the floor.
I... I mean,
you're just gonna have
to compromise this one time.
I'm not sleeping
on the floor, honey.
Look, you know what? This has
been a lovely bonding session.
I think I'm gonna see if there's
some room with the guys, so...
Just don't push me too far.
And I felt really bad
for Irene,
because she was just trying
to defend herself.
It seems like Esther's
a strong personality
and sort of came at her
a little bit,
and when she decided-- Esther
just decided to leave
and go sleep with the boys,
poor Irene just kind of
broke down a little bit.
You don't have to
feel bad, okay?
I'm just, like-- it's, like,
the first couple days,
and I don't want to make
any enemies.
- No, don't worry.
- Don't worry.
- I mean--
- I'm pissed off. I mean, I'm--
- I-- if it was me...
- I know, right?
I would offer to share a bed.
And we still have a situation.
Like, we have six beds, too,
and seven guys.
What'd you do?
Well, I don't--
I have my bed.
I marked my bed
as soon as we came in.
You want-- you want to
sleep in my bed?
- Would you let me sleep in your--
- Well, I would have to--
- I promise I will... I will behave.
- No touching?
Me and Esther--
first of all, I think she's hot.
That's why I'm kind of proud
that she's-- she chose me
to share a bed with.
I just want other boys
to see that.
I want them to be jealous.
That means they're gonna be
emotional and weaker.
Did you check the water
in the barrels over there?
- No, there was--
- No water?
- That's just dry.
- They're empty?
Yeah, we're gonna have to
go looking.
Maybe they--
Yeah, there's this box thing
that we were told about,
and it reveals things.
Oh, yeah, they're
gonna give us something here.
Every time I get excited
thinking it's gonna be food.
- I hope it's a treat.
- Mm-hmm. Maybe water.
A watery treat.
It looks like a Halloween box
in the middle of some
horror movie. Um...
It looks pretty strong, though.
Do we have to
open it or something?
At first, we had to, like,
beat on it a little bit.
We didn't know what it was.
What was that?
- Look, there--
- Hey, hey, hey.
- There you go!
- Guys.
Good lookin' out.
What does it say?
"The fly agaric is a mushroom
native to Siberia.
It is consumed by the local
Evenki natives
and was long used in their
shamanic rituals."
I think it was, like,
our first clue
to a food source.
"This important foodstuff
is plentiful in the region,
but beware...
because these mushrooms
are poisonous unless boiled."
- Great.
- I hate mushrooms.
Yeah, someone saw mushrooms
down the walk...
But they were like this-- they
were, like, the size of an ant.
That's not gonna feed us.
They were tiny.
I feel like if there's not
a leader of the group,
we're all-- we're all done.
We're done.
Did they look like that?
Who saw them on the walk?
- Hold on, hold on. Guys.
- Hey, guys.
I don't care. He can
talk to anybody he wants,
tell them what to do,
and that's-- that's up to them.
I don't-- he can tell me what
to do, but I ain't gonna do it.
- We split, or let's go
together to get... - Wood, fire...
Who wants to do mushrooms?
- Mushrooms.
- I will.
I'm happy to take
the leadership position.
Coming out here now and being
thrown in this situation--
it's-- it's like second nature
for me
just to always jump ahead
and take that stand.
Water comes first for me.
Fire is-- is pretty much
number two.
And a lot of the people
in the camp were like,
"Why do you gotta boil water?"
And if you don't boil
your water,
you want-- you want parasites
inside of you?
They'll knock you out
of this race.
They might even kill you.
- Have you made one before?
- Long time ago.
Boy scouts.
You know, I'd start a fire
back in the day.
I thought I remembered it
better than I did.
- 'Cause I don't see this being...
- You do a hole...
- Useful.
- It fits the wood, then you spin it around
some of this tinder.
Sometimes I exaggerate,
or lie-- whatever.
Hold it underneath.
Rubbing two sticks
together making a fire--
it's not like "The Flintstones"
where you do it
and it just happens,
so I guess a bunch
of people were getting going
with the sticks, trying to get
a fire started,
and again, mushrooms, water--
if you don't have the third
piece of the triangle--
the tri-force--
you can't eat.
You can't drink.
Everything was
confiscated, apparently,
and I guess whatever
I could sneak in my boot,
they didn't really do
a frisk-search like they do
before you go into a cop car,
so I managed to sneak in...
my own fire starter.
Ahh!
- Yeah!
- Go get mushrooms! We got water.
Miljan, Tommy, and I went out
to look for mushrooms.
Um, we didn't find mushrooms,
but we found a river,
and that was a nice bit
of relief.
No, I-I know. Like,
you get used to it.
Oh, this feels so nice.
This feels so nice.
Come on, Esther. Don't you
want to get wet?
I haven't got any other
clothes.
I thought girls like you would
want to get wet.
He's weird.
He's a funny one,
but our sense of humor--
we-- we just click.
Here's two groups
trying to make fire.
I mean, we're there with all--
collecting wood,
we're-- we're struggling,
and he's just there chilling.
Don't you want to help?
I mean, all the guys
are helping.
The girls are helping.
There's a group
that's out there
just looking for food for us,
and you're just chilling here.
They're not
looking food for me.
I can take care of myself.
I'm not trying to help
everyone else
because, uh, at the end
of the game,
I want to be the last one
standing, which means
there's less people that I have
to split the money with.
You know, I don't really
need their help.
I'm self-sufficient
on my own.
because, uh...
no rules, right?
Johnny seems to be
one of those guys
that is all "me, me, me."
I don't like Johnny.
I don't even call him Johnny.
He's "Country Boy."
The whole thing with Country Boy
is he's not playing by
the rules of the land.
The rules of the land
is everybody right now
has to do something.
As far as the "no rules,"
that's just, uh,
that's what the producers
and the reality show set up,
that there's no rules.
Oh, but there's rules.
And people need to adhere
to them.
Everyone's doing stuff
to try to survive at least,
and he's just like,
"Nope. I'm tanning."
I mean, what the hell is that?
Yeah, you know, I'm working
on my tan. I'm doing it for her.
You know?
She'll appreciate it later.
- Oh, my God, it's working!
- Oh, my God.
- Yeah.
- Oh, God, that's-- I see it.
- Come on, come on.
- There you go. You got it.
- I think it's gonna work. It's gonna work.
Stand it up.
You got this!
- Just let it go.
- Keep blowing. Keep-- ooh. Keep it.
Blow.
Keep going, keep going.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
Oh...
No, we're gonna lose it--
lose it.
- You blow on it. - No, not-- not
too much, or we'll blow it out.
Don't blow it out. That's fine.
Hero of the day was Dan,
my man. Uh...
I guess there was some reason
why I had to have carried him
all that way.
Yeah, it was a really cool
moment.
I-I did-- it-- for the first time
in the camp,
I felt like I finally
got some...
some respect, which I wasn't--
I wasn't getting at all.
Yeow!
Dan, Danny, Danno--
uh, he's a cool guy.
Starting the bonfire with his--
with his glasses? Genius.
None of us would have thought--
thought of that, you know?
So he instantly gained
my respect
from just-- from just
that one moment.
We have a lot of water.
- No mushrooms?
- But we found water.
- We found water just fine. No mushrooms.
- We've got water!
Water's the most
important thing.
We can live days
without food, but...
- You guys got water?
- We got water.
Oh, my God!
- Hey! Everybody!
- What's up?
They went to get mushrooms
and they came back without mushrooms.
- But they got water!
- Why'd you come back?
Well, now you gotta go
back out again.
- You gotta get the mushrooms.
- There is none.
I was just like, come on.
Seriously?
Sam... yeah.
Sam and I probably
wouldn't be friends.
When I get hungry,
I get a little mean.
I get a little ornery.
And that's not a good thing.
They wouldn't have given us
a clue that there was mushrooms
- unless there was!
- Give me a minute. Just give me a minute.
The mushrooms-- we can
find mushrooms tomorrow.
The most important thing--
we got fire and water.
- You can survive till-- - And what
are you gonna do in the meantime?
Watching Sam arguing,
just bark at people,
was, uh, pretty funny.
I-I can tell you that they're
gonna get sick of that.
Just the first day,
trying to start a fire,
took us forever, and...
we haven't even
found food yet.
So I...
It's a little worrying.
I was thinking about that.
What's up, girl?
Go.
- I didn't...
- Oh, I see.
...officially bring anything.
What does that mean?
- Well, you know how they--
- They took our bags.
- Yeah. Um...
- Did you smuggle in some stuff?
Yeah, I did, actually.
A constant question--
is this person being real
with me?
Because I know I'm...
I'm censoring things,
I'm filtering things for
the sake of this competition.
So where is everybody from?
I am from Montenegro,
right across from Italy,
on the Adriatic Sea,
next to Croatia.
- It's a small--
- I like your accent.
- Yeah, me, too.
- Thank you.
It's really exotic.
I don't know Miljan that well.
He's always making jokes,
trying to keep things light.
I just don't trust him.
I don't trust Miljan.
We don't really know
anything about each other.
We're just starting to know
each other now a little bit.
What about you, Daniel?
I'm from a very, very
small town in Minnesota.
- What do you?
- Well, I work a lot with computers.
So...
He's joined us.
Hello.
- Oh. Hello.
- How's it going, guys?
Oh! Maybe we should
speak to him.
Pull up a seat.
- Here, come sit.
- You can tell us your life story.
- Is that what we're on now,
our life stories? - Yep.
Mm-hmm.
- You guys hungry at all?
- Oh, I'm starving.
- Yeah.
- Very hungry.
I picked, uh, some berries
in a berry patch I found.
- It's not much, so...
- Oh.
- Oh-ho-ho.
But, uh, if you guys want
a little treat,
I was gonna pass it around.
- Yeah. That's nice.
- Very nice of you.
- Have you tried one?
- Yeah.
- Are they poi--
- And they're okay?
They're not poisonous.
All right--
are you sure?
I'm just kidding.
Johnny is
very interesting to me.
He seems very cocky.
He has some problems.
He's a little bit asocial.
I'm gonna break him slowly.
So what do you do?
Um, I've spent the majority
of my, uh,
adult years as a model.
So I've lived--
I was born in Australia,
but I've lived... mm,
in many countries, traveling--
- Oh, my God.
- What is that?
What is that?
Maybe we should go
we should go inside.
- What is that?
- It's probably just a bear.
I don't know, man. That didn't
sound like a bear to me.
- We can't leave the fire--
- Wait, wait. Shh, shh!
What was that?
Oh, my God!
Get in.
- Sam, can you come with us?
- Huh?
- Can you come with us?
- Just go. Yeah, just go.
- Just go, just--
There was this crazy sound
that came out of the woods,
and it was like a...
I don't know,
like a growl or something.
I work with animals,
and I've never heard
an animal like that before.
_
I have absolutely no idea
what happened last night.
Zero.
It really scared me.
I mean, of course.
We're in Siberia, and there's--
there's gonna be wild animals
out here,
but I don't know...
I found something really odd.
I woke up. I was up.
I went outside.
Just kinda, you know,
looking around,
and then I saw this frog.
I just went up to it,
and that's when I saw,
you know, I'm like, okay,
that's not normal.
Johnny. Johnny.
Come here, man.
Check this out.
Look at this.
Daniel found a mutated frog.
He had three back legs.
One more leg, that means one
more person we can feed, right?
Y-yeah, you know...
I don't know.
Annie, Natalie, and I
set out to look for mushrooms.
And we were spreading out,
looking around.
It wasn't really going so hot.
When was the last time
you said,
"I'm gonna go pick some mushrooms?"
One of the only vegetables
I don't eat.
I will today.
Uh, it's actually
not a vegetable.
- Fun fact.
- Oh, right.
Fungus. Whatever.
And we started
walking out and looking.
We couldn't find anything.
And then Tommy just
kept going deeper and deeper,
and we were getting farther
and farther away
from the settlement,
and, you know,
we're still new here.
I didn't want to stray too far.
I was getting a little nervous.
This is a good area!
I'm just gonna look
around here!
I know, but we don't
want to go that far!
We're far from the camp!
Well, just stay
in earshot, okay?!
Maybe--
We're not playing
Marco Polo with you!
Maybe you should
come back this way!
Polo!
What is that?
We were just gonna go
get some water at the river,
and we discovered this shed
in the middle of a field.
And, um, we tried to open
the door, but it was locked.
You know what? I don't think we
should tell anyone about this.
- No, I think we should tell everyone.
- No.
- Why not?
- Because we don't know what it is for.
And we don't want everyone
to come here
and start grabbing things.
I don't trust them.
Let's just go pretend
like nothing happened.
- Okay.
- Like, don't tell anybody.
Yes!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God, this is awesome.
So Annie and I were the ones
who found the mushrooms,
which was great, 'cause
everyone's so starving,
and you could tell people were
starting to get cranky
and starting to wear on people.
I feel bad for Tommy, though,
because this was, like,
- his little mission.
- I know.
We just kind of stumbled
upon those mushrooms,
and they were the same kind
as in the picture
that, uh, that was
in the Revealer.
- We got mushrooms!
- Whoo!
- Yes!
- Oh!
We get to eat!
Yay!
I mean, there wasn't that many,
so we are really
gonna have to divide them up.
Just a little bit of water
just to give them a quick rinse.
So we needed to make sure
that we cooked them
long enough, because
I know I don't want
anybody getting sick.
Does anyone know
how much water actually--
We're gonna have
gourmet mushrooms.
Maybe we should use our own
sweat as salt,
- as a...
- Oh...
_
- We lost Tommy.
- Pick that up.
He was going really far,
really deep into the woods.
I know I personally didn't want
to stray that far from camp.
Thank you, Estrogen, for saying
a prayer for the rest of us.
Did you call me "Estrogen"?
Yeah, yeah-- has no one ever
called you "Estrogen" before?
- No. - That seems like
the easiest nickname ever.
- Be a gentleman. Be a gentleman.
- I quite like it.
There's-- there's a bit
of estrogen here.
Anyone have a watch?
What?!
Who is--
- Oh, my God!
- It's one of the cameramen.
The head is bleeding.
- Oh, fuck!
- Oh, my God!
The cameraman was
bleeding from the head,
and it was huge.
I mean, I couldn't get
that close,
but from as far as I was,
I could see
that it was a big head wound.
So it freaked us all out,
because nobody was telling us
what was going on.
Nobody would give us any answers
about what happened to him.
Okay, everyone,
just go back to doing
what you were doing!
- What?
- We don't know what happened to him?
I have no idea.
- He's okay...
- He doesn't look fine to me.
Wh-what do you mean, he's fine?
He's fine.
Just go back and, uh...
They're not gonna
tell us what happened.
He didn't look fine to me!
What happened?
- Where are they taking him?
- We don't know yet.
How can-- how can we continue?
What's the difference
if you tell us inside?
- You can tell us now.
- What was he saying?
Does anyone understand
what he was saying?
He was saying something.
I couldn't understand him.
I guess he was speaking
Russian or something.
I wish I knew what
that guy was saying.
Something about "I saw them,"
"I saw... I saw them."
"I saw them."
- How do you know that?
- Hmm?
How do you know that?
My grandmother.
- And the producers would be a little more
concerned. - Well, we'll just wait and see.
- Let's just wait and--
- Looked like one of the younger ones, huh?
He had the...
What the fuck is out there?
We still don't know
what really happened.
Hey. Tommy had a cameraman
with him, I think.
- Are you sure? We saw him--I--
- Wait--
- I haven't seen him since this morning.
- ...for mushrooms, but he--
- I saw him.
- We were looking.
- Where?
- You saw him?
Yeah.
- Oh, you've seen him?
- When?
In the forest, back there.
Sabina--
that's a mystery.
I can't put my finger on it,
but there's something
going on with her, like she--
she knows something.
I'm gonna turn back
and look for him.
He'll probably be by himself.
Night's gonna be here soon,
so, yeah--
I'm not going out there.
- Look at what happened to him.
- I'm staying with Esther.
- What happened to that guy.
- I'm going.
I'm going.
- Who wants to come, come with
me right now. - Stay together.
- Natalie, you staying?
- No. I mean--
- The people who saw him should come.
- Are you gonna stay with them?
Maybe you should wait until
we find out
- what happened to that-- that cameraman.
- Who do we have, guys?
- We saw him--
- I'm staying.
Sabina saw him,
so she should--
Oh, there's the host!
Everybody, I just need you
to gather around the campfire.
There's been...
a very serious...
accident involving Tommy.
Um, and unfortunately...
it's fatal.
- What?
- Oh, my God.
- Now...
we've been discussing whether
or not to go on with this.
Um...
but we've decided that
that choice should be yours.
So I need you
to take some time now
just to-- to think about it,
and decide if you'd like
to continue.
If you decide to opt out,
we will be giving each of you
5,000 dollars...
- Oh! My God...
- Just-- just head to the--
- I can't believe we're talking
about money right now. - I--
this is just...
Do you know how?
We're still waiting
to find out.
I'll be coming back
at the end of the day
to get your answer, okay?
I've just realized now that...
I don't think the show cares.
I don't think that
production cares.
What I don't understand is,
this is supposed to be a game.
How did somebody die?
I mean, how do
the-- the producers of the show
let this happen?
How were they not prepared
to make sure that we're safe?
I understand there's challenge.
There's a challenge out here,
and it can be dangerous,
but nobody's supposed to die.
It's a game.
It's just ridiculous.
And there wasn't
an explanation.
I mean, there was, but it wasn't
a good one, not to me.
I just... I...
I want to know more.
I need more evidence.
Something concrete.
Just looking for this red...
...mushrooms,
these--
not seeing any anywhere.
They should be red.
White dots on them.
It's really not going too hot.
Ahh! Help! Help!
Aah! Aah! Ah-aah! Aah!
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com