Look at me.
Look at the kite.
Jack..
Oh, I've seen that outfit before.
I can't remember when.
- Last night.
- Last night!
These things do return.
God, my head is still pounding
like a drum.
You party hard.
Yeah, well, you don't look
worse than I am.
I didn't drink as much as you.
History of my life, Sara.
Psychiatrist by day,
party animal by night.
I thought you've told me
you weren't a lawyer.
I'm not, yet.
Excuse me.
- Yeah.
- Hey, Jack. It's Shelly.
- I've been calling all morning. You ok?
- I'm ok. What's up?
I was worried.
You worry too much, Shelly.
What's going on?
Frank Parks is been calling.
He needs to speak with you immediately.
Patch him through.
I had fun last night,
Miss. Pollard.
Me too.
Thanks for the wine-tasting,
Dr. Gramm.
Jack.
Hey, Jack, I've got Frank Parks.
Go ahead.
- Hey, Frank.
- Jack.
We got another one.
Oh, no. The same?
Every detail.
Right down
to the lateral laceration.
It's the Seattle slayer again.
- Where are you now?
- Look, Jack.
There's a tape.
You're gonna wanna see it.
Jack, are you still there?
Yeah.
Meet me at my office, okay?
Sure, Jack.
Where to?
114 Western, please.
Quickly.
Welcome back, Seattle.
We're continuing our interview
with John Forster..
Who was convicted for the death
of Janie Kay, nine years ago..
Based on the eyewitness testimony
of her twin sister, Janie Kay.
John Forster was dated to die at
midnight, at Walla Walla Penitentiary.
- Do you mind changing it?
- John Forster.
What's your reaction
to the State..
Thank you.
Idiot!
Congratulations!
For what?
I was referring to the hottie that
you left with the party last night.
She was a quite piece of ass.
- Remember her name?
- Yes, I do.
Sara Pollard.
Is that a cut on your nose?
You didn't have that before I left.
I fell out of the bed.
FBI hit here yet?
- Yeah, 2 minutes in the conference room.
- Okay.
Any calls?
New York Times, Washington times,
Newsweek.
They all wanna know if you have a quote
about Forster's execution.
- What else is new?
- Kim Cummings called twice.
- She was worried about you too.
- Kim knows this procedure.
Apparently not.
She's in your office.
Jack Gramm Associates.
I put those case reports
you wanna me to look at on your desk.
I thought Lauren and Leeza showed
real insight and ability.
The others were pretty much
working the math.
Yeah.
Don't you have Federal Agents
waiting for you?
Yeah.
I' see you in class.
I'll take them trough today's work
if you run late.
Thanks.
- Thank you, Kim.
- Bye.
Janie Keith came by
to give you a present.
Dr. Gramm.
I'm sorry.
I don't know if this is appropriate..
I just wanted to..
I just wanted to mark the day.
Thank you, Janie.
I'm glad that my sister Janie
hasn't been forgotten. Thank you.
For everything.
You went out of your way.
You are busy, so I'm just..
I'm gonna get out of here.
We did good, Janie.
We did good.
All right.
Thanks.
Can I help you?
You are one of my students?
Hi.
- Jack.
- Yeah.
I'd like to introduce you to Jeremy
Goober, with attorney general office.
Jeremy is in charge
of the Seattle slayer task force.
Dr. Gramm, it's so good to meet you.
This is a really big honor for me.
Sorry about the..
Oh, this is such a beautiful
conference room too.
And this special agent
MacTire from the FBI.
Dr. Gramm.
Pleasure. Have a seat.
Hey, big fellow?
Yes.
Jeremy.
Seattle slayer task force.
Well, okay.
I'm sure you have a lot of questions.
I'll do the best I can to answer them,
but first I..
No. First I think we should all
have a cookie.
These are from Janie Kay, whose sister,
Janie was murdered by John Forster.
- Jeremy?
- Sure, thank you.
- Frank?
- No, thanks, Jack.
No?
Mr. MacTire?
You are a good sport, Jeremy.
A little milk maybe,
what do you think?
Shelley, we got milk, don't we?
Bring in three glasses.
Nothing for me, Jack.
All right, make that two.
No, make it three.
Maybe you have a change of heart.
So, let's see..
I can assume..
That last night crime scene..
Was very much like
Forster's previous crime scene, right?
- They totally match, yeah.
- What totally matches?
I have in here..
- Halothane on the breath.
- Subdued by Halothane.
- Rape.
- Yeah.
The body was hung up side down.
Yes.
And..
Slashed throat.
- And where this takes us?
- Looks like a copy cat.
- It could be. Maybe
- Could be? Maybe?
- Maybe.
- It's a stage scene. Maybe what?
Maybe,
and this might be far-fetched..
But what if the perp
worked with Forster..
And these stage scenes were intended to
throw some doubts on his guilty verdict?
- Go with it.
- Possibly providing him..
With a stay of execution
or even a new trial.
Goal star, Jeremy.
Big goal star.
I mean, that's exactly what I think
is happening here.
No, I'm sticking with copy cat.
Of course there is
another possibility.
- Yeah?
- Forster is innocent.
- Wrongly convicted.
- No!
The task force is aware..
That your expert opinion
was critical in convicting Forster.
But then why he walked
his first trial?
Procedural error.
Why is he never been tried in any
of the other five pending murderers..
That you've attributed to him?
You realize that it is the dude of my
office to ensure that an innocent man..
Is not executed tonight.
You do understand that?
Look, Jack. If you have any
reconsideration of testimony..
Or anything new you wanna lay
on the table..
Now it would be the time.
Would you say it was fair
to characterize..
Your attitude towards
John Forster..
- As a personal vendetta?
- If we're been fair, yeah, sure.
It's a personal vendetta. I have a
personal vendetta against Ted Bundy..
And Gacy and about 10 or 15
other serial murders..
- That are on the streets right now.
- Jack, please.
That's helpful.
There is one other issue
that we need to address.
Milk maid.
What's going on here?
Do you know a woman named
Dale Morris?
Yes.
How?
- She's a student of mine.
- She's just a student of yours?
Dr. Gramm, we're federal agency here.
You don't wanna be lying here.
- We had a relationship.
- You've been very cryptic right now?
He had a professional relationship,
not a sexual relationship.
About a year ago her father died.
She was very troubled.
I treated her as psychiatrist.
I don't sleep with my students,
Mr. Goober.
Neither I sleep with my patients.
Now what does this have to do
with anything? Anyway.
Jack.
Dale Morris was murdered
last night.
She's the third and latest victim.
When was the last time
you saw Dale?
Well..
I saw..
I saw her last night.
To our impossibly
difficult professor.
We say thank you..
For making our lives miserable.
The pleasure is all mine.
We're celebrating.
You're celebrating
Forster's pending execution?
No, we're celebrating his conviction,
not his execution.
It was an overturn so we're happy
about that. We worked hard on this case.
We have a tape
that was left on the crime scene.
We're gonna play it for you now.
This message is for
Dr. Jack Gramm.
You got the wrong man.
Forster is innocent.
Please, don't hurt me anymore.
Don't hurt me anymore.
You gonna let me go, right?
You said you'd let me go.
I've read what you want me and..
Jack, it goes like that for about
an hour, before she dies.
Why do you think she was reading you
that message, Dr. Gramm?
Dr. Gramm?
In Dr. Gramm own words..
He analyzes a mental puzzle.
So they're no actual tangible pieces
per say.
He made a guess based on what
happened to Kate.
A guess based on his intuition,
a personal bias, ego.
And he sold that fiction lock, stock
and barrel to the jury.
What is it?
The girl that was killed
last night..
- Was Dale Morris.
- Dale?
Oh, my God.
Okay, let's see..
We have our investigators coordinated
with the FBI..
I wanna know everything Dale Morris did
on the last 24 hours.
I wanna know where she went,
who she talked to.
Can you please have Dr. Gramm's car
ready, please. Thank you.
Thank you, Shelley.
For what?
- I don't know. For everything.
- I hate when you do this, Jack.
Every time you o this,
I think you gonna end up dead.
Just don't ask me to marry you
again.
Why not?
We're perfect for each other.
Yeah, yeah. Except that I'm gay
and you're commitment phobe.
That's why we're perfect.
Thanks, baby.
Dr. Gramm is a world known expert
in forensic psychiatry.
What is forensic psychiatry?
I mean, is not the same profession
that destroyed MacMorton's life..
By conjuring up images
of child molestation?
None of the charges were ever proved.
And the accused, though innocent..
Was public crucified.
Jack, look. Look at the kite.
Jack, come here.
Yeah?
Hello?
You have 88 minutes to live.
What?
You know how long 88 minutes can be,
don't you?
- That's 11:45 am.
- Who is this?
- Tic-tac.
- Who the hell is this?
Tic-tac.
What were you saying?
- Jack Gramm Associates.
- Shelley?
I want you to set a trap and
and a trace on my cell.
What's going on?
I want you to contact
a wireless carrier..
And have them find out who made
that last phone call to me.
- Jack, I could be more helpful if..
- Just do it.
Just do it. I need it, all right?
And call me when you get it.
John Forster was an Eagle Scout, which
counts for his facility with ropes.
He also worked
in a veterinary office..
Where he had experience using
the animal tranquilizer Halothane..
Witch he's used to subdue
his victims.
Halothane. Sorry, I'm late again.
Thank you, Kim.
I see that the size of our class
is dwindling once again.
It could be because
you keep booting everyone.
My favorite student, Mike Stempt.
Okay. The legal distinction between
sanity and insanity rests upon what?
- Free will.
- The concept of the free will.
And what is
the most important thing..
One should remember
when entering a court-room?
That insanity it's a legal concept.
It's not a medical or psychiatric term.
But despite the fact that insanity
is a legal concept..
It doesn't mean
that someone is not sick.
Yes, Lauren.
Of all the serial killers
that I've interviewed and studied..
Witch include our boy Bundy,
Dahmer, Gacy..
None of them was legally insane.
This is not saying
that they were normal.
I could argue that
they couldn't help themselves..
Precisely because of
their mental disorder.
Well, if you wanna argue, Mike..
School of law is across campus.
Come on, Dr. Gramm.
It's ingenuous to pretend that
our presentations are not arguments.
We create a narrative of the crime
and the criminal.
Narrative is based on facts.
Based on logic.
We don't walk into a court-room
and advocate set scenes, do we?
We don't take sides.
We check our views at the door.
You mean you want us to pretend
we don't have an opinion?
We have opinions, Lauren,
but we just keep them to ourselves.
Share them with your dog,
if you have to.
Not with your parrot,
because it talks back.
It is that kind of logic that's gonna
get you in a law school across campus.
I've been there. I've done that.
Well, my condolences.
So, where is..
Dale Morris? She's absent.
I don't see her.
That's her first.
I didn't take her for a quitter.
Anyone who has her phone number,
please, contact me after class.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Shelley.
Tick-Tack, doc.
You have 83 minutes to live, Dr. Gramm.
So where was I?
Bundy versus Forster.
- What?
- Bundy versus Forster.
Thank you, Lauren.
You're welcome.
What we're gonna explore today is
the similarities and dissimilarities..
Say, from Ted Bundy's motives,
let's compared them to John Forster's.
Dr. Gramm,
your phone is ringing.
- Jack, are you there?
- Shelley. What's going on?
The call was made
from a cell phone.
One of those you buy
and pay minutes for it.
Registered to whom?
- Look, I know you're in class, but..
- Yes, who is registered to it?
A Kate Gramm.
Jack, it's a common name.
It doesn't have to be your sister.
It's just a coincidence.
It's not a coincidence.
- It's not a coincidence.
- Jack, I'm loosing you.
Shelley?
Goddamn it!
Have you found out who my phone
is registered to by now?
Poor Kate. If it was Kate,
you'd like to call her?
I'm gonna find you, you here that,
you son-of-a-bitch?
You're barking up the wrong tree
on this one.
I'm gonna find you.
She suffered
for such a long time.
You remember how long,
don't you?
You still feel guilty about her?
You feel guilty about
falsifying the evidence?
For lying under oath?
Tic-tac, doc.
You have 79 minutes to live.
Do you find this funny, Albert?
Who were you calling on
your phone?
Let me see your phone.
I was just..
Let me see that goddamn it phone.
I was just checking
the Mariners score.
- You were what?
- I was checking the Mariners score.
Okay, what is the score?
The score.
What's the damn score?
It's 3 x 1 Mariners.
B1.
- Oh, my God, I can't believe it.
- What does it mean? What's the problem?
Look.
What?
What's going on here?
It says that Dale Morris was murdered
last night.
- Is that true, Dr. Gramm?
- Yeah.
You knew it?
You knew it and you didn't tell us?
- You knew and asked for Dale's number?
- Is it the slayer?
- It could be.
- It could be?
Well, the police haven't released
any information yet.
- Are we all in danger?
- I can't believe you didn't tell us.
- Dr. Gramm?
- Lynn Johnson.
Someone just called
a bomb threat.
Everyone is to evacuate the building
immediately. Thank you.
Come on.
Grab your stuff.
I'll get your papers
of presentation, Tom.
I got the slides, Kim.
All students, faculty and staff
must evacuate the building.
I repeat.
Everyone must evacuate the building.
All students, faculty and staff
must evacuate the building.
I repeat.
Everyone must evacuate the building.
Please,
remain calm e do not run.
Proceed to the door
to the end of the campus.
I repeat.
We must evacuate the building.
Jack? What are you doing?
Get going.
All students, faculty and staff
must evacuate the building.
What was that on the screen?
Some student playing a joke
or something.
You of all people know that it breaks
school laws to proceed by a threat..
You need to report this
to the campus security immediately.
Carol. I get threat like this,
three or four times a year.
Your incredible arrogance
will slap the shit of you, Jack.
I wish you'd disclosure
your true feelings about me..
Before we became
such good friends.
Maybe you should stop hiding behind
your assessments about other people..
And start assessing yourself..
Cause you need to get over your past
and go on with your life..
Cause what you're living
isn't one.
It is not what you tell
your patients?
- Gum?
- Thank you.
I'll call campus security and let
them know you're on your way.
Where did you go last night?
When you left the bar.
Home.
Were you alone?
Screw you.
Roger.
We're on it.
Yeah.
The press got a hold of Dale's name.
It's all over the news.
Yeah, I know that.
And Forster's attorney is going
to the court and try a stay.
A stay?
On what grounds?
They're claiming that these..
Murders prove that the real killer
have never been brought to justice.
Nonsense. They're just trying
to buy time. They're desperate.
They're also claiming that you falsify
testimony and concealed evidences.
Well, it's all loose.
Goddamn it.
Who is that guy?
What about Dale Morris?
Did we find anymore of her?
She was murdered
in her apartment..
Between the hours of two
and six am.
- Any sign of force entry?
- No.
Does Forster still have that group
visiting him on prison?
He's like a goddamn rock star.
Website and all.
I want you to pull a background check
on all my students..
And get back to me.
Damn.
Oh, no.
Okay.
Kim?
What are you doing here?
I'm getting my car,
it's parked here..
Like it's every day
I come to the campus.
That was really horrible.
Just horrible what you did in class..
- It's was little low for you.
- I was looking for potential suspects.
That's what I was doing. What did you do
after you left the party last night?
I didn't end up drunk in bed
with an strange like you.
You left the party with Dale Morris,
the girl that was murdered, didn't you?
- Yes, I did.
- So what did you do? Where did you go?
You're not seriously
considering..
Where did you go?
We went to the Hickory Stick.
We had a drink, two drinks.
- And then?
- And then I went home alone.
- You have anyone that can verify that?
- No. No-one can verify it.
Come on. I've been your
teaching assistant for two years.
I'm your friend.
I'm here to help you, if you let me.
Follow me.
Who did that?
What does that mean?
According to a anonymous
phone call..
That means I have
72 minutes left to live.
Can I borrow your cell phone?
I've broke mine.
These are my car keys.
Can you take that around front
and meet me there in ten minutes?
- I have to go to the campus security.
- Okay.
Call me on my Blackberry
if you run late.
Okay.
Shelley. You gonna have to reach me
on Kim's cell phone.
What happened to yours?
- I broke it.
- What?
You have her number, don't you?
Yeah, I do.
Listen, just forward all the calls,
okay, to Kim's cell.
Please, thanks.
Dr. Gramm.
Hey, Mike.
Everyone is pretty upset
about Dale.
Yeah, well, that's understandable.
Considering the circumstances.
I have a question about
John Forster.
Yeah? What?
Well, I've been going through the trial
transcripts in Kate's history..
Why would you do that?
To understand your process better.
How you come to your conclusions.
And?
What?
Is it possible that Forster
is innocent?
No.
You won't even consider
the possibility?
No.
You're completely convinced the scenario
you put together is the only one?
First of all,
I didn't put together a scenario.
I recreated the crime scene.
Second..
I didn't convict Forster.
A jury did.
But the evidence
was circumstantial.
No DNA, no murder weapon.
Nothing directly linking Forster
to the crime, except your narrative..
- And Janie Kay's testimony.
- What's your point?
Just that your testimony
was very convincing.
That's my job.
To be convincing.
I thought it was to be right.
Help!
Somebody, please!
- Lauren.
- Dr. Gramm.
What happened to you?
He's wearing a leather jacket.
He's out there.
I bit his hand, it's bleeding.
If his hand is bloody, you can get him.
- You're okay?
- Go get him now! I'm fine!
- Watch my car!
- It's a police action!
There's been an assault.
- I wanna see your hands.
- Back off!
- Roll the window down.
- No!
I'm a forensic psychiatric
with the FBI. Here.
Okay?
Open the window now.
- Yeah.
- See? Well, roll down the window..
And let me see your hands.
Let me see your hands.
If you have nothing to hide,
you can show me.
Look, I'm trying to go home.
What?
Okay, sorry.
Excuse me.
There's been an assault.
I wanna see your hand.
Okay. Be cool now!
There's been an assault.
I gotta check your hands.
I'm a forensic psychiatric
with the FBI.
Sorry.
I couldn't find him.
Here.
This is stupid.
I'm so stupid.
- How I could be so weak? Such a wimp.
- It's not your fault. Come on.
I can't believe I let him get away
like that. I should've fought back more.
Stop beating yourself up?
What exactly happened?
He came from behind. He put this rag
over my mouth and I bit his hand.
- The rag had an odor?
- Something sweet..
It's Halothane, right?
- Yeah.
- He's the one.
Probably.
I let Dale's murderer get away.
Stop beating yourself up
and tell me something.
Tell me something. Could you
identify him if you saw him again?
He came from behind,
I didn't see him.
Let's go to the campus security,
you'll tell the everything.
Hello.
This woman has just been attacked.
Are you okay?
I think so.
What's your name?
Lauren Douglas.
And who are you?
Jack Gramm.
The famous Dr. Jack Gramm?
Then Johnson Fonsen
have you be coming in.
Is there someone to interview
Miss Douglas now, please?
- Jimmy?
- Yeah.
- You wanna check out this girl?
- Wait a minute.
Right this way.
What's going on here?
The person who attacked her
may still be on the campus.
What the hell you guys doing?
We got all these guys out
on the bomb squad.
Excuse me for one moment.
It's a little crazy around here.
Jimmy, get off the phone
and interview Miss. Douglas, please.
I'll be right there.
Why won't you seat here?
Okay, you okay?
- Jack Gramm Associates.
- Shelley? Get Frank..
- And pass him through when you get him.
- Okay.
Okay, thank you.
I don't want you going back to your
apartment until the locks are changed.
I don't have anywhere else to go.
After you talk
to the officer here..
Go back to my office.
Shelley will find a place to stay.
Okay.
- Come on. It's gonna be all right.
- Sorry for all the troubles I caused.
Miss. Douglas. Right this way.
- Right in here.
- I'm sorry.
- Yeah?
- I left a word for Frank.
Okay.
There's been another incident.
The Forster's case it's your thing,
right?
Wrong, it's not my thing.
I saw your testimony
on Court TV.
Yeah, right?
Fill those out.
Yeah, I follow
the big crime cases.
They fascinate me.
When Dr. Jack Gramm
takes the stand.
You come up with things
I didn't think off.
- This here, this is just a job until..
- Until you pass the police's exam.
See? How did you know that?
Just a guess.
That's the thing about you.
You know how to put two plus two
and you make it four.
Or five.
There are times that you know.
I'm not gonna be a campus cop
to a bunch of snob-nosed rich kids.
Especially these rich bitches..
My car was vandalized.
The window was smashed.
There's a number on the body.
Look into it.
Dr. Gramm?
This is Johnny D'Franco,
from campus security.
Can you get me Lynn Johnson?
- Jack Gramm Associates.
- Shelley?
- Did you find Frank?
- No, not yet. What the hell is going on?
Well, I received a threaten phone call
saying I have 88 minutes to live.
11:45h this morning,
and my time is up.
Pull out my risk assessment file.
Anybody rating "e" and above..
I want you to cross reference
against Forster.
And when you find Frank..
Ask him if Sara Pollard or any of my
students ever visit Forster in prison.
Sara Pollard?
She's the girl I met at the party
last night.
Call Wong Lee..
And have him make a list
of all the phone numbers..
Forster called
on the last 72 hours.
Where should fax the list?
My apartment.
And run a check on Kim.
Kim?
Yeah, just do it, okay?
Hello.
Jack.
- Damn it.
- The car is out front.
- Drive Squaid.
- Good.
You're okay?
You look a little freaked out.
Yeah. You have..
- A battery for your phone?
- Yeah, I do.
- What the hell is this?
- What are you doing?
Goddamn it, what is this?
What are you doing with a gun
in your purse?
Jesus, why don't you just announce
to the world?
I don't think they've heard you
in English Department.
- Why the gun, Kim?
- For protection.
- Where did you get it?
- I have a permit. My dad is a cop.
- Why you need a gun?
- I don't. My dad thinks I do.
Why?
I have a crazy ex boyfriend,
okay, Jack?
Oh. Jesus. God.
Yeah, I really know how to pick one
or what?
The judge said if he threats anyone
he goes back to jail.
Back to jail? What jail?
Prison, actually.
Walla Walla.
That's where Forster is.
Come on, let's go.
Special Agent Parks.
Frank, it's Jack.
I'm at the university campus.
We got a problem here.
Someone attacked one of my students
and tried to knock her out with Halothane.
- That's the Seattle slayer.
- I know, hold on.
Give me a second.
Yeah. There's a security guard
on this campus, his name is D'Franco.
I don't like him.
He's suspicious.
I want you to take him in
for questioning, okay?
Also get a warrant
and search his place.
Jesus Christ, Jack.
You know I can't just get a warrant
without sufficient grounds.
Just get a warrant, Frank,
come on.
Do you think he is the slayer?
- To link Forster on the outside?
- It's possible.
Listen, I checked the names
that Shelley, of the students.
And there's no record of Lauren Douglas,
Kim Cummings or Sara Pollard..
But you gonna love this.
Mike Stempt visit Forster four times
over the last six weeks.
Mike Stempt. What was his reason?
Research.
He had written permission.
No, no, no.
I didn't give him any permission.
Written or otherwise.
Well, it's your signature, Jack.
I got a copy right here.
Hold on.
That.. Hold on a second.
That ex boyfriend of yours.
What is his name?
Guy LaForge.
Run a check on a parole
named Guy LaForge.
He served time at Walla Walla
with Forster.
And I'll call you back
when I get to my apartment.
All right.
Do you think that Frank is working
with Forster?
Someone is.
- I got you Johnson.
- Yeah.
They've found a backpack
in your lecture hall.
What? With a bomb in it?
No. A photo, dynamite,
and a time with a note addressed to you.
What did it say?
Tic-tac.
What does it mean, Jack?
I call you back.
- You are okay?
- Yeah.
What the hell was that?
Probably somebody
trying to scare us.
Who do you think would do
something like that?
Does your boyfriend drive
a motorcycle?
Yeah.
Except he's not my boyfriend
anymore.
Yeah.
How does it feel to know you
won't live through another night?
56 minutes.
Tic-tac, doc.
Let's go.
Guy LaForge.
He isn't a boyfriend, is he?
The only thing that got me out of
Texas was my books marks.
And when I left for college,
I had that, but not much else.
So I tried to fit in.
I drank too much.
Thought too little.
And I met Guy.
And he was this English..
Working class rock star
wanna be.
And I fell for him.
And I married him..
When I graduated.
He didn't take to well to my aspirations
for higher education.
In fact he didn't really want me to leave
the house. And when I disobeyed..
He got filthy drunk
and he beat me.
That's when he got arrested
and I divorced him.
I've been trying to make up
for lost time ever since.
- You know, Forster is trying to kill me.
- Forster is in prison.
Yeah, I know. He's got someone
on the outside trying to..
To do the job.
He's gonna kill me.
If I don't get him first.
Whoever is working with Forster
must be close to you.
- A friend even.
- I don't have many friends.
That's a plus.
It's a real pleasure to look at everyone
you know as your would be murderer.
Paranoia is a normal state of mind,
huh?
Where is Errol?
I don't know. I'm a temp.
The agency sent me.
Dr. Gramm?
There's a package for you.
How did you know my name?
I don't.
It was a question.
Yeah.
- There's no return address on this?
- No.
Who delivered it?
A courier. But there was another
person here at the same time..
- looking for you.
- Who?
- What was his name?
- No, I didn't get it.
When he walked in I was on
the phone with the plumber.
- He said he would be right back.
- Okay.
You want me to pull the
surveillance tapes for you?
That shouldn't take more than an hour
to get someone up here with the keys.
- I don't have an hour.
- No?
Hey, you know, he was also wearing
leathers. He had a motorcycle helmet.
That's Guy. He was here.
If he comes back,
don't send him up to my apartment.
Yeah.
- Hi, Dr. Gramm.
- Hi, Eva.
How did Guy know
we're going to be here?
How does even know
where you live?
Oh, Walther P99.
That would blow a hole
through anything.
What?
I grew up around guns.
Maybe he didn't know I was gonna be
here, maybe that's why he showed up.
I'll verify where he went after
the party last night.
There's a Lauren Douglas to see you.
Should I send her up?
Okay, send her up.
He got that right, didn't he?
Hey, what's that?
This?
It's a chemical detector.
It sniffs out vapors.
Custom agencies are using it.
And?
It's not a bomb.
That's good.
Yeah.
- Hi.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah. I'm better, thank you.
- What do you have?
- I went to see Shelley like you said.
She tried to fax you over some papers,
but the machine was down.
So I said I'd bring the risk assessment
profiles over myself.
I didn't know you had company.
Dale told me how good you're with her
when her dad died.
She was so grateful.
Dr. Gramm?
Yeah?
If there's anything I can do
to help you find Dale's murderer..
- Will you let me know?
- Of course, yes.
Thank you.
Can I call you a cab
or something?
No, Mike is gonna give me
a ride.
- Okay.
- Thanks for these..
Bye.
All those people
have threatened you?
Well, you know,
it comes with the territory.
How come you never mention that
in class?
How many students end up going
into this field anyway?
Not very many
with you booting all of them.
Yeah.
Can I ask you
a personal question?
No.
How come you never
got married?
I mean,
you're a pretty good prospect.
You obviously make a shit load
of money.
Why would I get married?
I'm a target for any nut
with a grudge.
I can't afford emotional
attachments.
Yeah, but don't you want kids?
Don't you want a family?
I'm too old for kids.
You're too young for me, Kim.
If you want me to leave, Jack, all
you've got to do is say it & I'm gone.
No, I don't want you to leave.
I need you, Kim.
You are smart
and you are important to me.
Really, you are.
Okay.
- Yeah.
- Jack, it's Shelley.
What the hell happened to you?
Where have you been
Making calls for you, four lines
simultaneously. The fax is down.
I know, Lauren Douglas came over
and brought some papers with her.
Jack, you better turn on MS-NBC.
Why?
Forster got a judge to grant
his request for an interview.
He's on, live.
This is gonna heat things up
When looking for a home..
A real estate agent is really important
in you life. You need someone..
Shelley. Listen to me.
I want you to send some of the boys
to my apartment, all right?
There may be someone down at my lobby
in biker leathers when they get there.
Okay?
- You got a name?
- Yes, his name is Guy LaForge.
Put a photo
on the FBI wire, okay?
If you are not granted
another stay of the execution..
Are you prepared to die?
You want me to call the police?
No, no, let Frank handle it.
He'll know what to do.
As prepared as any man can be
to pay for something he didn't do.
Listen.
You didn't message over a package
to my apartment, did you?
No.
There is a lot of people out there
that believe in your innocence.
And I'm grateful.
You know anyone that might have?
- No.
- I'm grateful for their prayers.
- Everything goes to your office.
- And support.
What about Pollard.
Find anything on her?
You didn't actually paid her,
did you, Jack?
- Pay her, what do you mean?
- She works for a escort service.
Escort service?
You didn't know?
No, I didn't know.
What? She told me she was a lawyer.
A student lawyer.
What are your thoughts
this time?
Well, Stephanie, that's one thing
I don't have a lot of..
You got a number for her?
Yeah, a phone number
and the address.
I know the address.
Let me have the number.
If Dr. Gramm was with us right now,
what would you say to him?
555-1352.
He knows that I didn't do this.
- There's only one..
- Thanks.
Other person in this world
who knows I've been framed.
That it was a set up.
That I'm totally innocent.
And that would be the forensic
psychiatric Dr. Jack Gramm.
I guess what I'd say to Jack Gramm..
I'd say, "Why me"?
I understand that you've suffered
a great loss with your sister.
I feel your pain, Dr. Gramm.
- Pick it up, damn it.
- But that doesn't exonerate you..
From false accusing me of things that
you know I did not, could not have done.
Pick up, Sara.
If I can be convicted
of this voodoo forensic science..
Think about it.. Who is safe?
Shelley?
I want you to get MS-NBC.
- I want to talk to that son-of-bitch.
- I would be the last.
Jack, I really don't think
that's a good idea.
It's a good idea. Just get them and
when you get them call me back, ok?
But I find hard to believe that
Dr. Jack Gramm can be out there..
Psycho battling innocent people
into the death chamber.
Who is the murder now, Jack?
Yeah?
Who is the murder now?
Jack?
We got D'Franco in custody.
I got the warrant.
The guys are on the way
over to his place.
Did he say anything about Forster?
A quite bit, but nothing useful.
What about Guy LaForge?
He hasn't checked in with
his parole office in six weeks.
Well, he was at my apartment building
less than an hour ago.
And he said he's coming back.
Listen, Frank.
I got a call
a little while ago..
Saying I have 88 minutes
to live.
Jesus, Jack.
Why 88 minutes?
I don't know.
You have any idea
who this caller is?
You better find Guy LaForge
before he gets here, okay?
Listen, let me call you back.
Jack?
Shit.
Mom.
Dad.
Jack.
There's someone in here.
And he wants to talk to you.
Where are you?
Please, come home quickly!
I'm here with a man.
It is not what
you want me to say..
Jack, come here now!
Help me. Help me.
Jack, what is that?
My sister.
Oh, my God!
That's horrible.
Who would send that to you?
There's only two copies
of this tape in the world.
One is..
locked up in custody of NYPD.
And the other..
Is in a restricted access room..
In my office file cabinet..
With the highest
security measures.
So you're thinking it was stolen.
Of course it was stolen.
You think I stole it?
You left the bar yesterday night
with Dale.
One of the last people to see
her alive. Maybe the last.
Jack, you think I stole the tape
and killed Dale?
Have you lost your mind?
I don't have clearance
to your restricted access room.
Why Guy LaForge was at the bar
last night?
He was trying to protect me.
From what?
- From you.
- From me? He knows about me?
- Yes.
- What does he know about me?
He knows I have
a silly girlish crush on you.
Jack. Hold on a second.
I just got an email
from Mike Stempt, okay?
He saw Guy at Darby's Club
last night.
When Mike left at 3 am,
Guy was still sitting there..
And they've bounced a beer
until 6 am.
So there's no way that Guy
could have killed Dale Morris.
- Yeah?
- Did you listen to the tape, Dr. Gramm?
Why did you leave the little Katie
all alone?
Why, Dr. Gramm?
She'd still be alive today if you
hadn't left her all alone to die.
Now it's your turn.
In a glaze of glory!
Tic-tac, doc.
You have 37 minutes.
Yeah?
Hey, Jack, I got MS-NBC on the line.
I'll patch you through the prison.
- You're sure you wanna do this?
- Shelley.
There's been a breach in my place,
in my most secure area.
Did you ever give anyone clearance
to go into my secure files?
Jack, what are you saying?
Did you ever let
an unauthorized person..
Into my secure files area?
No, never.
To anyone.
Ever.
Okay.
Now put me through the MS-NBC.
Frank?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, turn on the MSN-BC.
They've granted Forster
a live interview.
I can't, Jack,
I'm in the car.
It's all right. They also will cast.
You just turn on 750 AM.
I'm phoning in.
Wait a second. You think is such
a good idea? With all the court actions?
I think he's behind everything. I think
he's behind the phone calls, threats..
I'm gonna try to get inside his head.
Make him crack.
Okay?
You wanna stay on the line, please?
- Dr. Gramm?
- Yeah.
You're on the air.
I've been told that we have Dr. Gramm
joining us by phone.
- Dr. Gramm, are you there?
- I'm here.
Have you been watching
the interview?
- Is that what you call it?
- What would you call it?
I don't know, I don't call it an
interview. I call it an entertainment.
I call it a performance, maybe.
You must have got something to say
or you wouldn't have called in.
Oh, yeah, I think it's very interesting
that Forster talks about forgiveness.
I just want him to know that
his victims have not forgiven him.
Look, you've lied under oath,
Dr. Gramm, and you know it.
This is not about me.
This about the women you've raped..
And tortured and murdered.
- Women like Janie Kay.
- I have nothing to do with her death..
- And you know it.
- Nothing to do with her death?
There was an eyewitness,
a twin sister who identified you.
She was at the scene
and identified you.
She was drugged
and beaten so badly..
She said that she couldn't
be sure, but you..
You bereaved her until she said
it was me.
Interesting that you didn't say
that you're innocent.
- I had nothing to do with the death..
- No, I don't. I know you're convicted.
You're convicted by a jury.
You were trialed and convicted,
that's what I know.
Trial? That wasn't a trial,
that was an inquisition.
And the jury believed your lies.
You had to cause pain, suffer and death,
so you could feel alive.
Wait a second.
Pain and suffer is something that you,
forensics, know how to inflict.
Even your idol, Ted Bundy,
ultimately, identified his victims.
How about, man,
identify your victims?
How about?
The bodies of Terry Hines, Alicia Smith,
Samantha Green. Where are they, man?
Come on, where are they?
Give these people's families closure,
man! Give them closure.
You're on national television now!
Millions of people are watching you.
Come on!
How about your colleague in London,
in the Clark case?
Putting in an innocent mother
for murdering her baby? Well done!
Well done, doctor. You must be so proud
of being part of an elite fortunate.
Fortunately for her,
her conviction was overturned..
When the doctor's testimony
turned out to be an absurd.
Quack, quack, Dr. Gramm?
You now what?
Why don't you take a good look
at your watch?
A good look.
Now imagine what it'd be like to be
minutes away from your own death.
To hear the ticking of a clock..
And know that your time on earth
is drying to a close.
Thank you.
There's another package for you,
Dr. Gramm. Should I send it up?
This has just got in.
A three judge panel of the Nine Circuit
has just granted John Forster..
A stay of the execution.
What?
Are you serious?
You hear that, Frank?
Yeah, I heard.
Forster got the stay.
I got him going, didn't I?
No cigar.
Why did you send me
on a wild goose chase, Jack?
What do you mean,
wild goose chase?
D'Franco is not a serial killer,
he's a serial groupie.
So he's a groupie so what?
What's the big deal?
I've just got a call from Jeremy Guber
from attorney general office.
You are wanted for questioning
on the murder of Dale Morris.
What?
What are you talking about?
They've found physical evidence at
her apartment that implicates you, Jack.
What evidence?
Jack..
You know I can't say.
What you mean, you can't say?
What does that mean?
- Frank?
- There's someone to see you..
Mister, you can't go up there.
You told the doorman
to don't let anyone up.
It's all right, don't worry.
Don't worry, no-one is getting in.
The state attorney general
has just announced that his appealing..
Is taken to the State Supreme Court
immediately.
Jack. There's smoke.
We'll keep you informed
with further developments.
There's smoke here too.
It's your boyfriend.
Let Kim go.
Let her go now
and no-one will get hurt.
Guy, I'm fine.
There's no problem here.
The building is on fire.
That's a problem.
- He's got a gun.
- Okay. Listen to me.
I know this man and I know
he's not gonna hurt me again.
You have to trust me, Jack.
Please, open the door.
- Do it quickly. There's smoke up here.
- Kim.
Guy, I'm coming out.
We can calm things down, okay?
Guy, look at me.
I'm fine. There's no problem here.
- What are you doing with him?
- I'm okay. There's no problem.
Guy has been shot.
No!
On the roof there's a fire escape.
Okay?
- When I say "go", follow me.
- Okay.
Do you think he is dead?
- He doesn't look good.
- We should go back up there.
I gotta go back there
and help him.
No. You can't go up there.
Man.
- Yeah?
- Jack, I need to talk to you.
I need two minutes to clarify
something?
Shelley, I can't talk now.
I'll talk to you
when I get to Sara Pollard apartment.
Miss. Lewinsky.
Are you okay?
- I'm just a little bit dizzy.
- Come.
Because I didn't see
a device with a timer.
Get the bomb squad,
this is the second one.
Go.
- Get her some oxygen.
- All right. We got her, sir.
Let's go outside.
You gonna be all right.
Jack, I don't see the shooter,
do you?
Jack.
- He's got a gun.
- Where?
Where the hell is he?
- Jack!
Get down!
- Kim!
- Keep moving!
Kim, where are you?
Go, go, go!
Move back!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm gonna live.
Here, let's go.
Where are we going?
To Sara Pollard house.
She's the girl I was with
last night.
That's funny.
It worked in the garage.
Why did you do that?
I don't know.
I had a feeling..
Are you okay?
What next?
I don't know.
- Okay, let's get out of here.
- Okay.
- Is that your cab?
- Yeah.
Okay.
I give you a hundred bucks..
You let me drive it.
I'm just going across town.
A hundred bucks?
A hundred bucks plus tip.
How is that?
All right.
I can not believe that.
Guy is dead.
He is. He is dead.
Shit.
You have not to say, huh?
It's just another day
in the life of Jack Gramm.
Okay.
Can you wait outside the cab
for a minute?
- You bet.
- Thanks.
You asked me about
my kid sister.
Okay. It was a long time ago.
She was staying at my apartment
in New York City.
She was 12, I was 28.
And I was late for a meeting.
Very important meeting.
A meeting
that was gonna change my life.
It was gonna make me
into somebody important.
Make all my dreams come true,
so..
I went to this meeting
on my dissertation.
And I left her there by herself.
I could have taken her with me.
I could have left her with friends.
I could have postpone
the meeting.
But I chose not to,
because I was in a hurry.
Anyway, I left her there alone.
At that time I was working
in a case..
And this guy had strangled
six women.
We were very close to nail him.
He was upset
and he wanted to get back at me.
So he came to my apartment,
only I wasn't there.
And that time I wasn't concerned
with security.
I was careless so..
He broke the door down..
And he went in.
And did..
Things..
To my baby sister.
Katheryn, was her name.
Katy.
He did things that you wouldn't do
to an animal..
That was bred for slaughter.
Anyway..
When they caught him..
He laughed..
And said..
It took him 88 minutes..
It took him 88 minutes
to have my sister dead.
Jack..
He is in prison now.
Coming up for
his fifth parole hearing.
I left New York.
Left all that behind me
and came here, to Seattle.
You know,
it seemed the perfect place.
It's on the far off corner..
Of the continent of USA.
To see if I had
a second hanged in me.
Whoever stole that tape..
Knows the meaning of 88 minutes.
Is that enough?
Let's go.
If Sara is not home,
we don't have a search warrant.
Well, we don't need a search warrant.
We're not gonna arrest anybody.
We're just breaking in.
Not a good sign.
You can't say
I've never give you anything.
This looks familiar.
When did you take it?
I guess it doesn't matter,
does it?
It just might.
- Okay, check out that way.
- Okay.
Oh, Jesus.
What is it?
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
Calm, Kim.
- Calm, Kim.
- Oh, my God. She is dead.
It's okay.
- Who would do that? Why?
- Calm, Kim.
- Who could torture someone like that?
- Just, breathe.
- Breathe, breathe.
- Okay.
- Breathe.
- Oh, God.
- Control. Take control.
- Okay.
I'm in control.
- Are you in control?
- Yeah.
- Okay, good. Let me show you something.
- Okay.
That is my signature.
Forged.
Credit card receipt.
This whole place
is filled with my DNA.
The police is gonna come here.
They gonna know I was with Sara.
They gonna think that I killed her.
- Your phone.
- Yeah.
Answer, Jack.
Yeah.
- Jack?
- Carol?
Carol?
Did you here the tape with
your sister's 88 minutes of suffering?
I sent it to your apartment.
What are you saying, Carol?
What is this?
The Porsche was a close call.
I called Frank and told him
you murdered Sara after you killed Dale.
Think you are so smart..
Invincible and unbeatable.
John Forster is giving you a death
sentence and he is about to be free.
How ironic.
You've got 18 minutes left.
Meet me at your office alone.
Tic-tac.
What is it?
It's Carol.
She wants to meet me at the university,
at my office.
Let's go.
- Come on.
- Okay.
Shelley? What the hell
are you doing in here?
I need to talk to you.
That poor girl.
That poor.. poor girl.
- It was me.
- Sit, sit.
- Shelley, sit down.
I broke the security protocol.
Why?
Well, about six weeks ago..
I had a drink in your office
with a student of yours.
A couple of drinks, actually.
And she made an advance,
and..
It was late, but the office was
jammed with people working still.
And when we woke up she left.
She didn't have a briefcase..
She didn't have anything
she could put the tape in, but..
But somebody else must have.
Somebody else did,
while we're sleeping.
Who was this girl?
What's her name?
It was Lauren.
Lauren Douglas.
And here is the..
It's a picture
from the security cameras.
This is the person that must have
rifle through my files..
And found the combination
to your vault and took the tape.
That's not a person, Shelly.
It's a hat and a coat.
And this the photo ID of everyone that
has visited Forster on the last month.
Oh..
Can you ever forgive me?
If I can't forgive you, Shelley..
I don't deserve you.
Understand?
I want you to call Carol
and patch her through to me.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Kim?
Hi, can you transfer me
to Lynn Johnson office, please?
Kim?
Where are you going in such a hurry,
Jack?
Is there something upstairs
that you don't want me to see?
There's a woman named Sara Pollard
upstairs very dead.
You can see her, if you'd like.
Look, I'm a straight shooter,
right, Jack?
- Yeah.
- And you'd never screw me over, right?
Oh, come on.
Why are your finger prints all over
Dale Morris apartment?
- They are?
- Yeah.
And you were right about the Halothane
on the blood stream.
What you failed to mention is the fact
that your semen is in her vagina cavity.
Is your semen in Sara Pollard?
Where the hell are you going
with this, Frank?
Can't you see this is a frame?
Forster is coordinating
this whole thing from prison.
- Can't you see that?
- Yeah, right.
It is Forster's semen on Sara Pollard
it's yours, Jack?
Somebody hired Sara Pollard
to be with me last night..
Then killed her..
Took my semen
and deposit into Dale Morris.
Do you have any idea
how absurd that sounds?
No, it's not absurd.
I don't have time to explain,
Frank.
Carol isn't answering.
What? What?
Get the names of all the women lawyers
who work for Forster.
I want their names and ages.
- Look, I know how you operate, Jack.
- What the hell are you doing?
I know how you use people.
It's no secret you're a womanizer,
you drink too much.
How do I know that you haven't gone
completely over the edge?
- Oh, man, I can't believe it!
- How do I know?
- I don't know what you do anymore.
- What did I do, Frank?
Did I send myself a tape?
Did I blow up my car?
Did I set my apartment on fire?
Did I fire bullets at myself?
For God sakes, Frank, wake up!
- What the hell.. What are you doing?
- I have no idea who you're anymore.
You don't?
- I got Gramm. I'm bringing him in.
- No, you're not gonna do this.
Frank. Frank.
Just give me some time.
I can untangle this. okay?
Just give me..
Here, give me some time.
Don't move
or I'll blow your head off.
Don't point a gun at me, Frank.
Don't point a gun at me.
Please.
I wanted to sync up our watches,
that's all.
All right, Jack.
What do you need?
I need time.
I need ten minutes. okay?
Here, let's sync up now.
At 11:40, meet me at my office
at the university.
Kim? What happened?
I know you're only trying to help me,
but don't go to my office on campus.
You understand? It's dangerous.
Don't be a hero.
When you get this message,
call me back A.S.A.P.
You understand? It's Jack.
Yeah.
There's still no answer
at Johnson's office.
Hold on. Yeah.
- Jack?
- Kim..
Whatever you do, don't go to my office
on the campus. Do you understand?
You have 14 minutes.
What?
It was me, Jack.
I set you up.
I had a computer dialing service
call you up..
Rearranging times,
using electronic altered voice.
Kim, this is no time to joke.
Meet me in your office
in ten minutes, Jack.
11:40. Don't be late.
Kim!
Oh, shit.
Man..
Yeah.
Hey, Jack, I got the names
of the women on Forster's legal team.
They were three.
Hannah Baker, 53.
Rosane Caputto, 47, and..
Lydia Doherty, 28.
And Lydia Doherty, 28.
How did you know?
Cause her name is on the signature sheet
you gave me.
I want you to do a search
on Lydia Doherty.
I want you to get all the information
you can.
Fax it to my office on campus.
Okay? Do it now.
Hey, another hundred bucks
and I'll wait.
What the hell
are you doing in here?
This is Lauren Douglas bag.
It was stolen today.
I found it in your desk.
Halothane.
What is it doing here?
What are you doing in here?
This is what you used
to kill Dale and Sara?
Or do you have no idea
about this too?
Oh, sure I do.
I left all this stuff in my desk
so you'd come along and find it.
You convinced the jury
that Forster was guilty.
How do I know you didn't kill
these women too?
Who sent you here?
Yeah.
I'd like to report a suspect..
- In the Seattle Slayer case.
- What the hell..
- Dr. Jack Gramm.
- Put down the goddamn phone!
What's the matter with you?
Who sent you here?
You think I'm too dumb
to figure it out from myself?
Yes, I do.
Because whoever sent you here is deeply
involved in the Slayer killings.
Lydia Doherty.
- Lydia Doherty.
- What the hell is that?
Yeah?
Come to the Stern Building now.
Corner office, seventh floor.
Alone.
You have five minutes, Jack.
- What are you doing?
- I'm not moving.
I don't have time to explain this.
Get away from the door.
- Come on!
- You're gonna shoot me?
Yeah.
I'm a bad shot.
Frank, when you get this message
I'm gonna be at the Stern Building..
On the seventh floor.
Get there as soon as you can.
Oh, God.
Punctual, Dr. Gramm.
I'm gonna give you a B+
for effort.
Lynn Johnson is indisposed, but
I'm sure she'd say hello, if she could.
As for your old friend, Kim,
she didn't quite make the grade.
- Lydia.
- You got the name right.
Lydia Doherty.
Copy cat murderer.
God, I wish Forster
could see your face.
You look so totally clueless.
I hope that's not a gun
you're holding.
Is that a gun, Dr. Gramm?
What do you want?
Is that a gun?
- I have a gun.
- Then do this.
Put it on the floor..
And slide it to me.
To me.
Okay.
You slide it.
One more time, slide it to me.
Slowly.
And move back.
Better.
I'd like to talk to John Forster,
please.
This is his appeal attorney,
Lydia Doherty.
They monitor his calls.
- You gonna implicate him.
- The brilliant Dr. Gramm..
And his psycho gamble,
is that it?
Sorry for the trouble I caused,
Dr. Gram.
You know that I did, Dr. Gramm,
with honors.
Dale told me how good you're
with her when her dad died.
She was so grateful.
But despite the fact that insanity
is a legal concept..
It doesn't mean
that someone is not sick.
Have him call me on my cell.
He knows the number.
- What do you want?
- What about you start with a confession?
- I confess.
- To what?
To what? To everything.
I confess.
I want you to speak clearly
and I want the truth.
Where do I start?
- Janie Kay.
- Janie Kay?
I coached her.
Shut it off.
- Shut it off.
- I am.
Go again.
I coached Janie Kay.
- In what trial?
- I coached Janie Kay..
In John Forster's trial. I coached her.
She perjured herself.
I gave false testimony.
And John Forster was convicted.
Based on an unlawful testimony.
It's my little present for John.
Thank you.
What are you doing?
Are you assessing me?
Are you looking for a weakness,
Dr. Gramm?
I'm just wondering what is next.
Aren't you gonna offer
to make me a deal?
Sacrifice yourself
for Kim and Carol?
Be the hero.
Well, that wouldn't fly out, would it?
I'd offer, but it wouldn't fly.
Rejected.
Have any other moves?
Or you spent so quickly..
I could move my eyes, like this,
e look behind you.
To see if there is someone there
with a gun pointed to your head.
- How much time I got left?
- You have about a minute.
Jack.
Enough time for your last words.
I'm not gonna deny you those.
All this torture,
all this torment..
For an infatuation?
It's not an infatuation,
don't demean me.
Well, if it's not an infatuation,
what is it?
Stop, please!
I went through great lengths
to pull this off.
John really appreciates
the quality of my work.
Timing the phone calls..
Perfecting the ropes and plus
implicating everyone close to you.
Coaching Carol and Kim.
All the while staying invisible.
It was me, Jack. I set you up.
You know what I don't understand?
How, in God's name,
does anybody give up their free will?
How you do that?
- 45 seconds.
- I saw you.
You came to my class,
I remember you.
You were intelligent.
An individual.
You challenged things.
You challenged me.
You challenged ideas.
You're your own person.
How could you ever allowed yourself
to be so manipulated by this guy?
30 seconds.
You're gonna take the fall
for this guy?
If that's what he wants,
so be it.
You see, Jacko..
I'm a true believer.
You better believe
that's an FBI agent..
With a gun pointed right
into your head..
At this moment.
Believe it.
- No more kidding.
- Believe it.
- I believe your time is up..
Dr. Gramm.
God.
Jack!
No!
Again!
I got you. I got you.
It's okay.
It's okay, sweetheart.
Requesting immediately MT help.
At the UNW Campus,
Stern Building.
I repeat.
Immediately emergency
medical technician.
Multiple stab wounds.
There you go.
That's okay.
Don't move.
Yeah.
This is officer Finnegan
from the State Penitentiary Walla Walla.
I'm placing a call from John Forster
to his attorney Lydia Doherty.
Put him through.
Go ahead.
Lydia.
Did you finish with Gramm?
- She's downstairs.
- Gramm?
Put my attorney on the phone,
please.
She's indisposed.
Look, you're meddling her.
You shouldn't be meddling in.
You seized a naive junior lawyer
on your legal staff.
You realized that she's damaged
psychologically and..
Genius, isn't it?
Susceptible to your craps.
And what you do?
You get her to kill people for you.
So you can stay alive.
That's an innovative legal strategy,
if I have ever heard of any.
Dr. Gramm, I'm flattered
with your imagination.
But you're grasping in straw.
She becomes a student of mine,
no less..
You keep her on the appeal process,
but she's still your lawyer..
So she has unlimited access
to you..
So you can plan
your copy cat murders together.
And then you can get a new trial.
And live happily ever after.
Isn't that the case?
Dr. Gramm, I want you to listen
very closely..
Because when I get out of here..
I'm gonna go out and
have a nice meal..
Stop by your grave..
And piss all over it.
Now, please, put my angelical attorney
on the phone.
She's dead.
It's over, Forster.
Except for the clock,
that goes tic-tac.
Tic-tac.
You got 12 hours to live.
All right, fellows..
- How is Lynn Johnson?
- Well..
She just threw out of the house.
She didn't want me to be late for class.
Jack, I have to ask you
something.
Was Lydia telling the truth?
Did you coach Janie?
You believe Forster killed those people?
All those people?
- Yes.
- Janie's sister and everybody?
- Beyond reasonable doubt?
- Absolutely.
- What would you have done in my shoes?
Don't answer it.
Think about it.
Justice..
And truth.
Where do they intersect?
Hi.
Hello, everyone.
John Forster is dead.
His execution is not a cause..
For celebration.
Nor is a vindication.
It is a chapter..
In the road to justice
and recovery.
I personally..
Don't believe
in capital punishment.
I do believe..
In the rights of the victims.
That they deserve recompense.
No matter how significant
or insignificant it may be..
In comparison
to the loss suffered.
I've suffered such a loss.
And like some of you here..
I've spent
those sleepless nights..
Trying desperately to..
Squelch down that
bullish instinct for revenge.
And I have wondered..
Jack, look at me.
Look at the kite.
If this pain will..
- Ever abate.
- Smile!
I've learnt..
That time does not heal
the wound.
It will though, in its most..
Merciful way..
Plant the edge ever so slightly.
So..
What is the first thing..
One should remember
when entering a court room?
SubText:
NoRMITA.326