[PLEASE COME BACK, MISTER]
Get out of here right now!
Why? I thought you said
that you were lonely!
I'll make sure that you
never feel lonely again!
Live with me. Okay?
Let's live together.
Do you think I came back here
just to get my payment?
I'm the Branch Manager
at Sunjin Department Store.
Also, I'm not sure if you're aware,
but I'm Chairman Cha's son
who he's been keeping hidden.
Wow, Mr. Young Soo
was such a wonderful guy!
To think that he'd keep my existence
a secret from his family, too!
For me, who's lived
as a loner all my life.
Mr. Young Soo's family was
pretty much what I'd always wanted!
I was always so jealous of him for that.
Oh, so that's why you couldn't call
your father or brother by those titles.
Yes, Father!
That's why I had to treat.
Mr. Young Soo's family affairs
as if they were my own.
I can have a place to stay comfortably,
and you don't have to sell your home!
It's a win-win situation!
Go to a hotel since you have
so much money!
Since I'm the Branch Manager
I need to set an example
for others and not spend frivolously.
I'm completely against it.
The fact that a stranger is in my
home makes me uncomfortable
and I don't want to have to deal
with you at home, too.
No can do. No way.
No. If I'm satisfied with your service,
I can throw in a bonus.
If I feel satisfied here,
I'll give you more for rent.
Or I'll take some money off your debt.
Then, we don't have to move
and I don't have to transfer schools!
Right? Right, Mom?
I like it!
But... won't satisfaction
be quite subjective?
I'm not one who is
stingy with compliments.
Oh!
Every time you feel satisfied, you
can put a sticker of praise here.
- Right?
- All right.
If this whole sheet is filled up
I'll render all your interest null
and void, and pay you rent!
I'm not someone who's obsessed
with asking for money, you know.
Mommy... please?
Fine. But in exchange, you're leaving
this house when that sheet is filled up!
I'm quite picky when it comes
to food, so just cook as you usually do.
Also, treat me like I'm family.
That's all I want.
Here.
What are you doing? Take it already!
What's this?
My rent for two months,
in advance.
Use this to pay back your debt.
There needs to be a house
if I'm going to be staying here!
Um...
Thanks, at any rate.
And what's with this
"at any rate" business, huh?
If you're thankful, can you
make me a cup of coffee?
[EPISODE 9]
And what are you doing?
Oh, good thing you're here!
Don't worry about anything,
and just come at me.
Come at me!
I heard you went to Cha Jae Gook's house.
Please, stop messing around.
No, you stop messing around.
You're the one who handed Yoo Hyuk
over to Na Suk Chul, right?
Don't worry about it.
Yoo Hyuk said he'd live righteously
but you dragged him into a life of sin.
Do you really feel okay with
yourself after having done that?
I want to tell you to go your own way
but then I'd be worried for
Song Lee Yeon without you around.
It's a bit complicated now,
but just wait for a bit.
I'll get your store back
for you guys, too.
What the hell? Do you and your brother
take pride in being nosy?
Leave.
Don't worry. I'm going to leave
in a month even if you beg me not to.
Well, that's good.
What the heck? Why are they so quiet?
How motherly of her.
Ah, this is nice.
Ah, this feels so nice.
Father, I brought some water.
Yes. Thank you. Go to sleep now.
- Yes, good night, Father!
- Okay.
You little runt. Are you going
to yell at your mom again?
No, you can't! No!
- Are you going to do that again, or not?
- I won't! I won't!
I missed these sounds.
Excuse me. Excuse me!
I really can't deal with this anymore.
Oh, Honey! I had a crazy
dream last night!
In my dream, I died, but...
Are... are you okay?
I feel like this scary dream in which
you don't recognize me will never end.
Because I'm dead.
Seriously?
Did someone ask you to prepare
something extravagant?
I told you to just prepare
what you usually do!
This is how we usually eat.
As if! The table's legs look like
they'll break from the pressure!
Are you really going to
continue acting this way?
You know, she's been preparing all
this since really early in the morning.
Just let her off the hook.
Exactly, Father! Why do you
keep treating me like an outsider?
Would family be treating
each other like this?
Happy?
Mister... what about the grape stickers?
Grape stickers?
As if!
When have beef and fish ever been on
the same table together in this house?
You shouldn't treat people
like they're strangers!
Whoa! Is this your car, Mister?
- Of course! Get in!
- Awesome! Yay!
Um... wait!
Hey! Han Na!
- This is so fun!
- Yay!
Hey, um, aren't these my clothes?
"I gained five kilograms, so here."
That's what you said
when you gave them to me.
What, do you want them back?
Take them off.
Wow, you're so pretty, Thunder Girl!
Switch with me.
Wow!
But, you know, this place is familiar.
What?
What the hell?
Wang Joo Yeon!
Thank you for helping us
with the shoot, President.
That's not something that I did.
Branch Manager Lee Hae Joon
was the one who...
[LEE HAE JOON]
Branch Manager? I think you've
misunderstood something about me.
I've never received a bribe
in my entire life.
Because my family lives abroad
and I'm the sole breadwinner
I may have received
a teeny, tiny one, just once...
Why not save those excuses
for President Cha instead?
Well, he's the type to say that our
company will take no responsibility
even if you die from
overworking yourself, though.
- Hello, Branch Manager.
All right! Play, all of you! Play!
This department store
is doomed to fail anyway.
What good would it do to
work yourself to death?
Did anyone tell you to
That's all you'll hear, anyway.
So take it easy!
People who work hard nowadays
end up being made into fools!
Sir, as a part of the Chairman's family,
you really shouldn't be doing this here.
- Miss Young Won.
- Yes, Branch Manager?
Here, sit, sit. Is your hip okay?
No... um, I mean, yes.
Sir, retail workers cannot be sitting!
Have you ever stood for 10 hours
straight on the retail floor?
No, sir.
- Please, rest.
- Yes, sir!
Here. Eat up. Eat and live.
Here, say "ah".
Ah.
Branch Manager! Eating is really
strictly forbidden...
- Only eat a little bit, okay?
- Branch Manager!
It's the end of everything once you die.
Take care of yourself.
Your legs hurt? Sit down!
Hungry? Eat!
Sleepy? Sleep.
What's up with him?
I heard that he was using a dead
person to try and be President, but...
What are you saying? He's the savior
of the wronged! A lion of justice!
He's totally my type!
He's the first superior I've had
who worried about my hip!
Are you still mad at me?
Ms. Wang Joo Yeon.
If you have time to be doing this,
spend more time honing your craft
instead of stumbling over
your lines again!
You have a special guest
here today. Come and see.
Hello, Director!
Oh, Ms. Song. Is this minor
role really okay with you?
Of course! I've been
a star since my debut
so I've always wanted to try
taking on a minor role like this.
But is it really okay, especially
at this department store?
I'm okay. That's okay!
I'm fine, really!
Me too!
Why is this woman so late, damn it?
Branch Manager, I've
brought the products.
We're late.
We're late! Come here!
- But where are we going?
- Just get in!
I'm buying you
an amazing lunch today.
But if we're late, they'll
be no spots, so let's hurry.
What are you doing? Come on.
Welcome.
Is this the spot where you
ate with Manager Jung?
What did you eat?
Order the same thing you two did.
What are you doing?
I'm not here to play. You need to know
my tastes so you can adjust accordingly.
Understand?
Excuse me.
- Please enjoy.
- Let's eat.
It's been so long since just
the two of us have had a meal.
This is the first time, though.
There was always someone
who'd watch over me when I ate.
Give me meat.
Synced & ripped by bozxphd
Subtitles by DramaFever.
From now on, let's have
meals together often.
What's with this shoddy look?
You're going to walk around my
department store dressed like that?
What's wrong with my look?
Do I look too beautiful?
I guess you have no shred
of pride or refinement left now, huh?
I never threw away my refinement.
What are you so damn confident about?
All right, good work!
I'm the Branch Manager!
Han!
Oh, you're here. So, how is it
living at the house? Is it doable?
Well, you know. Kind of, yeah.
What, are you being kept up all night?
I've progressed a bit.
We just had lunch together.
Oh, nice! What did you have?
Spicy beef soup!
- Geez! You idiot.
- What?
She said that she likes it!
Do I need to beat some sense
into you? Get over here!
- You idiot!
- No, stop!
- No, stop! Ow!
- You punk!
The kid is watching!
Where did you leave the kid
while you're prancing about like this?
Dad!
Oh, uh, Cha Young Chan!
Um, what's going on?
Young Chan came to see Mommy
working at Daddy's company!
Uncle gave me this. This.
[HEART SIGN]
Oh, really? Wow, he made
you such a great thing!
I'll have a good shoot and go,
so don't worry about me.
Let's go.
Let's leave our families
out of this, shall we?
Did someone who knows the importance
of family do that to Kim Young Soo?
All right. Ready, action!
Give me just one chance.
Looks nice. Those clothes
really do suit you.
Don't be depressed, and
live your life as best as you can.
And don't ever appear
before me ever again.
Why, I ought to...
And just what kind of trouble are
you planning to cause this time?
Let go, damn it!
Those clothes really do suit you.
Don't be depressed, and
live your life as best as you can.
Huh? What is this?
Cut, cut, cut, cut!
Move back! I said, move back!
Get out of there!
Ms. Song! You're beautiful!
Good luck! You're beautiful!
All right. Ready? Action!
- Director!
- Cut, cut, cut, cut, cut!
- Hey, come to your senses!
- Yes, sorry, sir.
Wow, you're totally stealing the show!
- Right?
- What are you talking about?
You're so much prettier
than the main character!
You're sexy, adorable,
elegant, and confident!
You're the best. Seriously!
Oh, you're so pretty.
Should I put a stop to the shoot?
No, just leave them as they are.
- Over here.
- Here?
Synced & ripped by bozxphd
Subtitles by DramaFever.
Oh, so sour!
Ma'am. What's for dinner tonight?
Branch Manager,
what are you talking about?
Should we go home together today?
No, sir. That's fine.
Won't it be scary, going home
alone? Won't you be lonely?
Can't this be construed
as sexual harassment?
- What did you say?
- Can I talk to you for a second?
Follow me.
Um, fine.
- Hey. Lee Hae Joon.
- Y-yes, ma'am?
Do I look like a pushover to you?
Is that why you're following me
around and being annoying?
Being... annoying?
Yeah, being annoying.
I was trying to let you off the hook
because I need to get by,
but I can't take it anymore.
Is being an asshole a
prerequisite for being affluent?
My husband is the one who
has a debt to you, not me!
I don't owe you anything.
Dissatisfied? Then fire me.
Or get out of my house!
No, ma'am.
Also, how old are you?
A teensy bit younger than you...
You don't even look that old, and
yet you keep talking down to me?
Watch yourself, punk.
Oh, get out of my way!
I'm leaving.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm sorry.
Wow, she's so passionate...
No, no! Stop!
Good job, Shin Da Hye. You have to
show him that you're not a pushover!
But, he won't fire me, will he?
Ow!
- Are you all right?
- Yes. I'm fine.
- Then, excuse me!
- Ah, yes. You too.
To be called out to the department
store... this is a real honor. sir.
What's with that girl, Hong Nan?
What's her relationship with Lee Hae Joon
that she and Song Lee Yeon
hang out together all the time?
Actually, I have a guy who
used to work for Han Gi Tak...
- Han Gi Tak?
- Yes.
He said that that's his younger sister.
They grew up at the orphanage together.
I'll look into it more carefully, sir.
But, sir. Is the selling of the
department store going well?
I don't think that's a question
that's proper for you to be asking me.
But still, it's good for me
if you're doing well!
And there's the franchise agreement
that you promised me.
Our business started
as a construction business
so we have a very
strongly established foundation...
Save that spiel for
your other thug buddies.
Also, if you have time to try and
aggravate me by talking about such things
manage your men better.
What a joke.
See you again, sir.
Oh yeah, also, don't just
appear out of nowhere.
I thought you were a discarded newspaper,
and almost walked all over you.
Synced & ripped by bozxphd
Subtitles by DramaFever.
Wow, he's stepping all over me
oh so nicely today, too.
What do you mean, a newspaper?
I'm a refrigerator box,
at the very least.
That bastard.
He sure is charismatic.
All right, here!
It's my first time eating
spicy rice cakes at a place like this!
Wow, they're so good!
Here, Young Chan!
How is it?
- It's so good!
- Really?
Eat up, my child!
It doesn't take much to get
you two excited, does it?
You worked so hard today,
Ms. Song! Here, eat up!
Eat! Here, have some more!
Here! Say "ah!"
- Oh, so pretty!
- Stop feeding me!
Here's some for our Seung Jae,
too! Here, say "ah"!
Say "ah", punk!
Oh, Manager.
Sit down.
Just a minute, okay?
The incident with Han Na's dad
has caused you a lot of grief, right?
It was my mistake. If I caused
a misunderstanding, I'm sorry.
She was totally getting
the Cinderella treatment!
So did you just turn around
like an idiot, Kim Young Soo?
What was I supposed to do?
You know, that day 10 years ago
when Lee Yeon ran off to that bastard...
Is it good, honey?
I still regret it, and wonder
what would've happened if
I'd been a less cowardly man?
Hey! Are you going to lose her to another
guy and shed tears of blood, like me?
What do you mean,
lose her to another guy?
Go get her, like a real man! At least
you're not stuck in a woman's body!
- Hello, sir!
Yeah. I'm not Kim Young Soo
anymore. I'm Lee Hae Joon now.
Ms. Shin Da Hye.
Why is that guy here?
- Listen closely to what I'm saying.
- Sure, sure.
I'm planning to prepare
a nice grassy meal for dinner.
I won't just wait for you
to look at me anymore.
Don't wait. I'm not going
home with you.
- Ms. Shin Da Hye.
- I'm begging you.
Leave me alone.
If I were going to do that,
I wouldn't have bothered to come here.
Are you okay?
Ow! Ow!
- Let go! Ow!
- Ow!
That's not what I meant to do!
Here, here!
Just why are you doing this to me?
Wasn't it nice?
You crazy bastard.
Hey! You cursed at me! Hey!
Damn it, I'm going to go crazy!
Han! I did what you said
and dislocated my wife's hip!
I told you to do it like a man.
I never told you to dislocate her hip!
Really? So, what should I do?
You don't have time to
do things step by step.
Do everything that you
couldn't do for her before.
It's just a dream,
but it still tastes so great.
Good morning!
What is all this?
A present for you! The store is closed
today, so don't worry and just relax.
All right, you cook, and you clean!
Let's get going, people!
Oh, put this in the living room.
Wait, there's no space.
Second floor it is, then!
All right, move, move, move!
All right, when your hip hurts,
come upstairs and do this.
Sit here, and settle in.
Ah, ah, feels so nice.
Father, feel free to come upstairs
whenever your hip hurts, too!
Hey! I don't like other people barging
in and disturbing the order of my home!
Send all these people out, right now!
- Um...
- All right.
We'll do everything ourselves,
so just sit back and relax.
Yes, child. We'll take care of it!
Wow, it's all finished!
Synced & ripped by bozxphd
Subtitles by DramaFever.
- It's a bit bland.
- No, no!
- It won't be salty!
- No, no more!
All right, time to put
Han Na in now! Let's go!
All right!
Hey, spar with me! Come on!
You scared? Huh? Taste my fists of steel!
Help me with these.
Hey, Honey! What? You put
mayonnaise in fermented soybean stew
and you want to know how
to make it good again?
What the hell... that's the kiss
of death for that stew.
There's no way you can make that taste
good even if Ms. Maya intervened.
You weren't satisfied
with putting out her hip
so you want to rid her
of her sense of taste, too?
Oh, whatever.
I'll take care of it for you.
I'll be right there.
Are you crazy? You're going to some
person's place to make them food?
No! You can't hang out
with the Cha family.
No, that's not it. I have to save
an idiot from utter culinary failure.
I guess you can call it loyalty.
Loyalty, my ass.
That won't do. I need to see what kind
of person he is with my own two eyes.
Wait, where are you two going? Hey!
- Hello, Father!
- Oh, yes.
This is the nationally famous
actress, Ms. Song Lee Yeon.
- You know of her, correct?
- Hello.
Oh, yes! Yes!
This is, um, really not a stranger.
How do I put this...
Er, um, she's a friend
who's like family to me!
- She's my only friend.
- Yes!
Yes, Missus! We're just friends.
I did well, right, honey?
- Ta-da!
- She doesn't like flowers.
- Wow, they're so pretty!
- Oh, so she does like them!
All right, then. Shall I go
and assess the situation?
Where's the kitchen?
Wow, you're so fast!
I actually used to be a chef...
I mean, I have the blood
of a chef in me! Yeah!
- Right?
- But, um...
Why do you live here, Branch Manager?
- That's because...
- He's a loan shark.
He's afraid we're going to sell
the house and run off so he moved in.
That entire family is like that.
You know, I know this guy
quite well, and he's really...
No second chances, all right?
Yes, sir.
He has tons of good traits!
For example, um... um! Um!
Oh yeah. He's really good-looking.
And he's so tall. And on top of that,
he has chocolate abs!
And the most important thing is that
this place right here, is, you know...
is a total weapon of mass destruction...
What is wrong with you?
And this is the bird's name.
Goose, crested ibis, pigeon
seagull, woodpecker, and... huh?
Brown-eared bulbul?
Food is all about that
handmade taste!
- Say "ah"!
- Ah!
Wow, you're shooting a melodramatic
movie at someone else's house, huh?
Mom, what's a brown-eared bulbul?
- What do I do?
- Brown-eared bulbul!
What did you say?
A brown-eared bulbul is a
close friend of sparrows!
Oh, men....
No, no, you can't!
No! Share them before you delete them!
No! This is my own private affair!
- Whatever!
- No! No!
- No!
- Get out of my way!
Not this! No!
You bastard!
Wow, how could you use
this sort of strategy?
Um, what are they doing in there?
Honey, want to have a drink with me?
You can't, ma'am.
Huh? What are those noises?
- Ah, Roxie!
- Ah!
Don't do it. Don't erase it.
Why are you doing this again?
Share it with me.
Don't do this to me. I'm spoken for!
- Want to be friends with me?
- Excuse me?
You don't have any friends, right?
I don't have any, either.
Oh, sure.
[WOULD YOU LIKE TO DELETE THIS FOLDER?]
I just want to watch it with you!
Is that so hard? Huh?
No!
That's something that I really needed.
I keep questioning my own identity.
Look at me. I'm on the brink of insanity!
I'll get you something
else, I promise. Don't cry.
Who's crying?
18 plus 5 is?
23!
- Wow, Young Chan!
- That's correct!
Wow, you're so good at playing
with younger kids, Han Na!
Young Chan is so cute! I wanted
a younger sibling just like him.
My dad said that it was okay if
I didn't have younger siblings.
He said he didn't want to share the
love he had for me with another child.
He said that he just needed me.
I see. So, you can be his big sister.
Really? Is that really okay?
Of course. You'd like that
too, right, Young Chan?
Yes.
Time to eat! Let's eat!
- Father, take this.
- Ah, yes. Thanks.
Have some of this, Han Na.
- Eat up.
- Okay.
Is it good?
And here's some chicken.
Eat up and get big and strong, okay?
Does that taste good?
- Eat up, Mister!
- Oh, thanks!
What? You don't like carrots?
No, I'm really good at eating them!
Here, Han Na. You eat up, too.
Okay! Wow, it tastes so good!
Father, have some of this.
Oh, Han Na should be the one
to eat something so delicious!
Here, eat up. You like fish, after all.
Okay. Mom, eat up since your hip hurts.
Oh, what a cutie you are.
No, you have it, Han Na!
No, you have it, Mom!
What are you doing, not eating?
You still have a lot of growing to do!
Hurry and eat up!
Uh, yes.
Oh, Father, if he grows any more,
he'll shoot through the ceiling!
Well, we can just use him as
a telephone pole, then!
Then I'll leave him behind,
so you can use him as a telephone pole!
Eat up, all of you!
Um, did your husband work
at Sunjin, by any chance?
Yes.
He's the only one who treated me kindly
when I was a star and
also when I was a divorcee.
Well, I guess there's one
other person who did, too.
Mr. Lee Hae Joon.
Yes, like that. Yep, just like that.
Good job, my Han Na! Yep, just like that.
No, you cut that one too short.
One more time. Good! Here, too.
Wow, good job!
Um, I'll bid you farewell
here and go now.
Those weren't empty words.
We're really friends now, okay?
Please come over again!
See you again, Missus!
What do you mean, see you again?
Let's go.
- Have a safe trip home.
- Yes.
- Get some rest.
- Goodbye!
Let's go back home, too...
Let's have a drink somewhere
before we go back home.
Don't worry about Han Na and Father.
They're the type to fall
asleep quickly, anyway.
I don't want to eat alone.
Then I'll choose what we eat.
Sure.
You know, about Mr. Pathetic...
He seems like a nice guy.
Right? He really is an okay fellow.
- But not him.
- What do you mean?
Don't get involved
with the people at Sunjin.
I don't want to see you get
tangled up with them too...
Me, together with Mr. Pathetic? Never.
Then, what is it?
Does he like that woman?
In truth, he was quite close
with her deceased husband.
Is this "My Mother and
Her Guest", or something?
Mister, do you like
hard boiled eggs, too?
I like hard-boiled eggs, too.
How about I hold you tight
for the first time in a while?
Mister, I think that my rib broke.
Let's date, honey.
Oh, you're so cool!
This Big Bro of yours
will hold you tight.
Oh my!
Come over here! I'll hold you
so tight that your ribs break!
Get over here!
They make a really good
pork cartilage dish here.
- I don't like pork.
- But you like pork belly.
Pork belly? My husband liked it.
I didn't really like it.
- Can I get chicken feet?
- Yes.
Do you keep in touch with your family?
My mother passed away
when I was very young
and I do have a father,
but I can't call him that.
What about a person that you love?
I did have one.
I thought that this person and I went
well together, for about 10 years.
But I don't think it was
the case for the other person.
If everything I knew was a lie,
what becomes of my love?
The other person just did whatever
they could to satisfy you, is all.
Wouldn't it have been hard on them,
if it was that way for 10 years?
You're different from
what I heard about you, too.
What did he say about me?
That you couldn't hold your liquor.
It's not that I can't.
It's just that I didn't drink.
Three glasses do the trick
when I can't fall asleep, though.
Ow, that hurts!
Despite what he said,
please don't bother us
when we're getting
our lives back together.
I'm sure that you'll be happy
after playing hero for a bit
but for us, this is our everyday life.
We are the people who have
to live on without Young Soo.
And who will take his place?
- That's none of your...
- Can't I take his place?
Can't... I like you, ma'am?
[EPILOGUE]
Damn it!
It's fire!
Synced & ripped by bozxphd
Subtitles by DramaFever
[PLEASE COME BACK, MISTER]
- Ah!
I don't have much time left.
Are you with me?
- Revenge?
- No!
You shouldn't say things
like "revenge" so carelessly!
I can give Da Hye
what she wants the most.
And what's that? Huh?
- Stop it!
- I wonder why you're here.
I came here to reclaim that.
Once I bite, I never let go.
Why aren't you contacting your mom?
- Song Lee Yeon!
- I'm sorry.
No!
I was busy, so I
forgot to tell you, but...
I missed you, ma'am.