Welcome, everybody,
to the hottest ski week in the world.
It's the annual spring ski pageant
and ski school director,
Reid Janssen, kicks things off
with an exhibition of skiing
that we've come to expect from him.
Yes, Reid has made this pageant his own.
Five grueling days for whom
Reid Janssen calls "serious skiers only. "
For Reid Janssen,
winning isn't everything,
it's the only thing,
and the competition here is fierce.
Each instructor is determined to prove
that he and his ski school section
are the best,
and Reid himself appears more determined
than ever to let no one dethrone him.
Come on, let's go!
Bend your knees, bend your knees!
I'm sure the last skier to beat Reid,
Dave Marshak,
head instructor for Section 8,
is preparing to do just that,
although he's curiously missing
from Reid's pre-pageant ski exhibition.
Slalom, downhill and freestyle.
Skiing is what it's all about
and this week promises
to be a memorable one.
The instructors will soon have
their ski school recruits before them,
so they are no doubt busy
trying to figure out a way
to defeat king of the mountain
Reid Janssen.
- We are leaving, now.
- Cool out, Reid.
- How.
- Hi, Dave.
Hi, Reid.
Shut up.
I say this is your last year.
And there's nothing you can do about it.
You're too late, Reid.
I've already put into motion
an elaborate plan,
a series of events diabolically designed
to rid this mountain of you
and your satanic presence forever.
Before you think
about getting me off this mountain,
you're gonna have to win first.
- Okay.
Have you seen your recruits yet?
- Recruits?
Who are you people?
I'm Ed.
Wow. We're gonna need all the help
we can get.
Sorry. Excuse me.
It's okay.
Come on, Lori.
He's cute, but look,
there's First Section.
Oh, yeah.
- What's your name?
- Paige.
Next.
I'm here to register.
Name?
Roland.
Roland. First name, John. Montana.
That's a long way, Roland comma John.
Where do you ski?
This little place in Montana.
You probably never heard of it.
Did you ever ski Sun Valley? Jackson?
No.
Who do you ski with?
Mostly myself.
Yourself.
And I suppose
you think you can ski with us.
Well, you guys are supposedly the best,
aren't you?
No, we are the best.
We're talking about you.
Maybe this'll help.
A letter of recommendation!
- How sweet.
- Look, I came here to ski, all right?
Yeah, well, you paid your money,
so you'll ski.
But not with us.
Well, then who do I ski with?
- Roland. That would be...
- Section 8, wouldn't it be, Derek?
Right, Reid. Section 8.
You go out the door, take two rights,
it's behind us.
"O, what a rogue and peasant slave am I!
"Is it not monstrous that this player here,
"But in a fiction, in a dream of passion,
"Could force his soul so
to his own conceit...
"For what?
"For Hecuba!
"What is Hecuba to him, or he to Hecuba,
"That he should weep for her?
"He would drown the stage with tears
"Cleave the general ear
with horrid speech,
"Make mad the guilty and appall the free,
"The play's the thing
"Wherein I'll catch
the conscience of the King. "
Let's go skiing.
Hit some slopes or what?
- Yeah, right.
God. See that?
- Well, it wasn't bad.
- He really...
- Did you see that?
- We saw that, but it was...
He was... He was all right.
- I saw that.
- It was passable.
- Are you erect?
- Can we do that?
Warm-ups are over
and it's time
for the All Star Ski School individual
and team competitions to begin.
The first event will be the slalom.
And stepping into gate number one
for Section 8 is Fitz Fitzgerald.
And in gate number two,
it's Erich Blor wearing the red uniform
of First Section.
Come on, push it, push it! Come on!
Skiers are competing for spots
in Sunday's final competition
where all times are applied towards
determination of the team cup winner.
Next up is Derek Stevens of First Section.
And opposite him is Ed Young
from Section 8.
Erich and Derek give First Section
a strong two-three punch
behind leader, Reid Janssen.
Stepping in now is the chief instructor
of Section 8
and former individual champion,
Dave Marshak.
While Marshak is always one
to ski well,
particularly in the freestyle event,
the team cup has always eluded him.
Next up is
director of the All Star Ski School
and the man who sets the standard
for others to follow,
number one, Reid Janssen.
Reid crosses the finish line
with a time of 29.55 seconds,
the only skier under 30 seconds so far.
That's him!
- Yeah?
- Yeah!
The final skier of the day
is a late arrival, John Roland,
skiing for Section 8.
- Go, go, go!
- Go, John, go!
Well, this newcomer could be
a welcome addition for Dave Marshak.
But it's too soon to tell
if Roland is only a one-day wonder
or if he'll fit in with the rigors
of the competition.
29.898 seconds
is John Roland's finishing time,
putting him in second place.
Here you go.
- Great!
- Stick with us, kid, you'll go far.
Push, push, push, push!
How could you let one of those idiots
even contend with us?
That guy was pretty good.
How come he's not skiing with us?
Shut up, you pussy.
How do you expect to impress anybody
with the way you looked
on the hill today, huh?
Ken, you wanna get over there
and do sets with Derek?
You ladies look nice today.
Level eight?
What is this, lawn bowling, huh?
Move it to 12, come on!
Eight?
And you, come on,
move your knees, let's go! Move it!
Help. Help. Guys?
Guys, help!
Help!
Here, I'll help you with those.
They look really heavy.
- Thanks.
- Hey,
did you know you have really big muscles?
- You do.
- Thanks. Yeah, thanks.
- I'll get up now.
- Okay, thanks.
I did not mean to do that. No.
Guys.
- I'm... I'm sorry.
- That's okay.
Go away, I'm busy. I did not...
Howdy, boys!
- What are you doing here?
- I'm an ambassador of goodwill.
And who might you be?
Trying to cop a cheap feel
at the expense of my lady?
I'm simply helping
a damsel in aerobic distress.
What kind of men are you
who leave a struggling young lady
without anyone to spot her?
Shut up.
Wait, wait, I know who you are.
Throw his ass out.
Go ahead. Do with me what you will.
Beat me savagely
and leave me in the gutter to die.
Someday we will run naked
under a full moon!
Scum.
Don't worry, Paulette,
it'll never happen again.
Okay.
I hope I don't have to be
the one to tell you this,
but ski school is not
about learning how to ski.
You must be Ed.
Okay, party at the lodge at 7:00,
courtesy of
our esteemed ski school director.
Hot tubs at 11:30, contents TBA.
Let the games begin!
Okay, how many for chocolate hot tubs?
Duh!
What are we gonna fill the hot tubs with?
Women?
Good, good. Glad to have you with us.
Now, I don't know why you all came here,
but I suspect
a couple of you wanna sleep with me.
And, frankly, that scares me.
Entertain no fears.
We'll have you hooked up in no time
with what, to what, I'm not exactly sure.
Anybody have
anything else to add? Johnny?
- Let's win the race tomorrow.
- Of course, absolutely, win the race.
Any ideas on how we are going to win
this race?
Partying.
Party.
Party!
- This is not a party.
- It's a still life.
Everyone still has their clothing on.
Oh, my God. I think I've heard
this song at my dentist's office.
I don't know if I can do this, Dave.
This is totally and emphatically
against my principles.
No one said it was gonna be easy.
Now look closely, my friends,
because what you are seeing
is the beginning of the end.
And it's up to us to do something about it.
Who's with me? Me.
- Me.
Welcome to my kingdom.
I will bed you all
before the night is through.
Pardon me.
Just a minute, that's my wine.
I'll be right back.
Paulette, I'm looking forward to it.
Do you have the time?
Time? Of course.
I'm... I'm sorry.
- No, it's okay, no, no.
- I'm...
I'm just gonna run upstairs
and change, okay? It's okay.
Change? What a good idea.
Definite possibilities.
And the only thing holding us back
is gravity.
She's not interested.
You are. Here, have a carrot.
You're registered
with the ski school, right?
Yeah.
Maybe I could give you
some personal instruction.
I could, too.
No, thanks. I think I can manage.
Hey, we're First Section.
Hey.
What does that mean, "First Section"?
You know, First Section.
Johnny.
Thanks, but no thanks.
Damn it, who's messing with the lights?
Where did he go?
Hello? Oh, it's you.
Well, Reid was telling some of his friends
that he was gonna sleep with me tonight.
I don't know.
I haven't made up my mind, you know?
I don't think
it's worth playing games with him.
Well, of course there's someone else.
He's... He's really cute
and I think his name is Fritz or Fitz.
I'm in love.
- I'm all shook up.
- I know he doesn't have any money,
but I don't know, there's just...
There's something about him.
Listen, I'm gonna get dressed
and I'll call you downstairs. Bye.
Paulette, you're killing me.
You're killing me.
Not now, Dave. Not... Not now.
Someone's trying to make me look bad.
A couple of up-tempo songs like this...
This party could get out of control.
Let's check it out.
Hey, buddy, looks like you're out of here.
Come on!
Yeah, you heard what he said.
- Come on, let's go...
- Guys, I'm telling you,
this isn't good for your karma!
Dick wad.
Play with these, fag.
Obviously not music lovers.
Perhaps the end
is closer than I thought.
They leave us with no alternative.
Well, you know what this means.
- Payback. Yes, I think so.
Should we be doing this?
I don't know. We'll find out.
Oh, look, champagne.
Looks expensive.
I don't think anyone will mind.
Here's a way to keep you warm tonight.
What?
Oh, right.
Why are you looking at me like that?
Sorry.
It's all right.
I think I hear someone.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I don't hear anyone.
Security!
- Who's the chick?
- Kid learns fast.
Nice semi-formal evening wear, I say.
All right, guys, what's going on here?
Anything is possible.
I like your attitude.
Now, as the authority figure in your life,
here's what I want you to do.
- Johnny's got potential, don't you think?
- I think so, yes.
How's the family?
Oh, Mom's okay, Dad's got tonsillitis.
Thanks for asking.
- Oh, darn.
- Yeah.
Johnny, my sister asked about you.
- How is Brenda?
- She's fine.
And tell little Curtis I said hi.
Right.
Hey, babe.
- I've had my eyes on you.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
I want you.
There's this little thing
that really turns me on.
I like to tell you what to do.
Just say the words.
I'll do anything you want.
Do you want to be with me, right now?
- Okay!
- No.
I want you to answer the questions
with the words that I use.
That's what really turns me on.
So do you want to be with me right now?
I really want to do it with you right now.
Can you wait for that to happen?
I can't wait for that to happen.
- Really?
- Really!
Give me five minutes
and I'll go upstairs and slip into something
a little more comfortable.
Now, when you come inside,
don't turn on the lights
and don't say a word.
Take off your clothes
and then slide into bed
right next to me.
This word thing has got me totally hot.
Derek, I've never met anyone
who has a way with words like you.
Remember, room 220.
Room 220. Where I'm gonna do you.
LORl: Hey, Erich, great party.
Yeah.
Can I ask you something?
Your wish is my command.
Do you wanna have sex with me?
I wanna have
outrageous sex with you.
It's very interesting.
Do you wanna run your fingers...
- Let me see the manual.
...all over my body?
I wanna run my fingers
all over your body.
Do you wanna tickle me
till I'm breathless?
Here you go.
Make it happen.
I want you to see this film
so you know what makes me tick.
Don't you have another dress
to change into?
Excuse me, ladies and gentlemen.
May I have your attention for a minute?
There's something very important
I'd like to share with you.
I've been fortunate enough
to have the vision to know what I want,
and the courage to go after it.
That's what this film is about.
If you understand this film,
then you understand what I'm about,
and what my All Star Ski School
can make you about.
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
Do you remember what it was like
the first time you put on skis?
For Reid Janssen,
it was like nothing he'd ever experienced.
Skiing became the dawn of possibility,
the commencement of life.
For Reid Janssen, it became crystal clear
what to do
with the gifts bestowed upon him.
He created the All Star Ski School,
his mission of a lifetime.
Hi, baby.
Just close your eyes and fantasize.
Now, when I come into the room,
I don't want you peeking.
It might take me out of the mood.
Chicks dig me!
Frighteningly easy.
God, I'm good.
- Reid?
- Yeah, babe.
You're not paying any attention to me.
God, I love it when I do that.
I think you'd rather make it
with Erich or Derek.
Yeah.
I wanna run my fingers all over your body.
Just say the words.
I'll do anything you want.
I want to have...
What the hell's going on?
...outrageous sex with you.
I can't wait for that to happen.
This is some kind of joke.
Somebody set this up.
Your wish is my command.
- This is the good part. Yeah, yeah.
- I like the next part.
This is not my film.
My men are not homosexuals.
This is a fraud, can't you see?
They're not even in the same room.
- You did a good job.
- Thank you.
Excellent work there.
- Hey, come on, let's go.
Reid, Reid, Reid!
Hey. Don't come back here again.
Marshak, crawl back
in your hole and die.
We came, we partied, we conquered.
Yes!
The mountain is ours. Let's dance.
Hi.
Hey.
There's no more champagne.
Johnny?
Yeah?
What's happening here?
I don't know.
I do.
What is happening here?
Don't worry, it's okay. No strings.
So, Derek, don't worry about last night.
I've already scammed
on three babes today.
- The master.
- Yeah. I'm giving one to you.
Way to make that homo stuff work for us.
You got it, Big D. Catch you later, huh?
Don't do that.
My client would like to inspect
the property,
but she feels the price is not too far off.
Yes, I think it's an excellent price
when you consider the upside potential.
Did you see those projections
I left for you?
Yes, I'll hold.
Reid, these people are worth millions
and they're depending on me
and I've gotta depend on you,
but you are fucking me up.
You see, they're buying the mountain.
When they do,
I'm going to end up owning a major share.
Now, if I own a major share,
you're going to own
a little piece of that pie yourself,
do you understand?
So I'm gonna tell you one last time.
You and your clones have to start
taking care of business now.
Then why don't we just throw
the scum out now?
Because Dave Marshak is
some kind of goddamn folk hero
to a lot of people around here.
In order to toss him out,
I've gotta have one hell of a good reason.
You got it?
Yeah, I got it.
Looks like you didn't get much sleep
last night, Reid.
I think the caffeine and the crack
is really hurting you.
Pay attention, Marshak.
You're in deeper than you think
and we're gonna bring you down.
In fact, if I were you, I wouldn't
even bother showing up on the slopes.
You and your merry pranksters
don't belong on this mountain.
Not anymore.
You know, you may all think
you're just having a great time,
but by the end of this week,
you're all going home losers.
Shit's going down
and you're gonna be gone.
You guys are way too serious.
And don't fuck with us.
Oh, no, I think it's Erich
that wants to fuck with you, Derek.
Real funny, huh?
Call it a warning.
Did... Did we win?
Oh, hi, guys. Did we win?
Day two is underway
here on the south course
for the second round of slalom qualifying.
The First Section's far out in front.
The remaining sections are struggling
to keep pace.
And with the way things are looking,
it's going to be more of the same
as First Section continues
to put its mark on the entire mountain.
Wow! All right!
Dave, you will never get me
because I have perfect hair.
Yes, we will
because we are wacky, offbeat types.
Oh, my God!
It's Godzilla!
Fitz, how could we let this happen?
Godzilla! He just came and...
No, I'm talking about the mountain.
It's in desperate trouble.
Do you have any ideas?
Subliminal hypnosis.
Suggestions to their subconscious mind
as they doze.
If you wanna be the best,
you must lose your mind.
If you want to be the best,
Johnny,
if you want to be the best,
you must lose your mind.
It's time
for the freestyle competition
and first up is Section 8's John Roland.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Most impressive is Section 8,
moving way up to fourth place
in the competition for the team cup.
I don't know what it was they did,
but they should do more of it
as they look towards tomorrow.
Ed, you have sex with too many women.
You will stop having sex
from this moment on.
If you understand, nod your head.
If I'm not mistaken...
And you rarely are.
...those are some of Reid's women
from the party.
Swimming semi-naked.
They leave us no alternative.
- Chocolate pudding!
- No, not so fast.
We don't wanna peak too early.
Look, guys, I'd love to stay,
but I have to get back to a dream.
I'll see you guys later.
- Hi.
- You're cute.
He is a phenomenon.
Back to the matter at hand.
Not so fast. I have a plan.
What is that?
It's not that I don't want to.
I mean, it's not that I'm not able
because I am.
It's just that I can't.
Not physically.
I mean, I'm not called Mr. Ed for nothing,
but it's just something in my head.
It's like this dream
that keeps reoccurring that...
You're not buying this.
I know you're not buying this
but it's true, I mean...
- Wait a minute!
- What are you guys doing here?
- Hello.
- Hi.
I know what you're thinking,
but worry not, my children,
because we are employed by...
What's his name?
- Master race.
- Master Reid.
- Master Reid?
- Sorry.
And he asked us to stop by
and make sure you were prepared
for tomorrow's activities.
And in order to be completely ready,
he made us promise him to teach you
how to lambada.
- The forbidden dance.
And how appropriate it is
that we find you here in a sauna.
No questions from you just yet.
Fitz here is going to brief you
on the historical perspective
of the lambada.
- Take it away, Fitz.
- Thank you, Dave.
You're welcome, Fitz.
Lambada.
The movements have been around
before time itself.
Criminy, that's a long time.
It started centuries ago with
the South Americans, who discovered fire.
Fire? That's hot.
- Hot, hot, hot.
- Lambada.
And that's how the lambada came to be.
Don't forget, ladies,
Reid wants a full demonstration,
bright and early in the morning.
Otherwise, why would we be here?
Ain't no reason.
Now, let's lambada, shall we?
Okay, grab your partners.
Everybody, come on, get up,
find a partner.
- You guys, get up, get a partner.
- Hello.
Come on now, let's get into it.
Now we're gonna lambada!
Now grab your partner
by the waist. Ready?
Gyrate, gyrate, gyrate motion.
Like a sack full of ax handles.
Right.
I could dance with you
till the cows come home.
Better still, I could dance with the cows
till you come home.
- Oh, Christ, I've come.
- Oh, Dave!
Fitz, Reid will be so pleased.
And how. Wink, wink.
Kumbaya, my Lord
Kumbaya
Reid, I don't understand
why Paulette came here
if she doesn't like to ski.
Don't you get it, Derek?
Because of who we are.
I mean, that's why people wanna
be around us. We're the best.
That's what makes us attractive.
It's not like I could have sex at any time.
Beer pump, magic foam...
Good book?
Anyone have a problem with that?
- No!
Not me, man.
- Well, I got a problem with that.
What the hell is this mountain coming to?
Half-naked girls walking around
at 9:30 in the morning?
Last year, they were completely naked
at 9:30 in the morning.
Do you think she's gonna walk around
like that all day?
Or will she be back
for a 5:30 hot tub?
I don't wanna have sex with her either.
I mean, it's not like I'm Dave.
Pumpkin?
She loves me.
These women, man,
they just don't understand, you know.
Sometimes I just wanna cuddle.
Well, ladies and gentlemen,
day four is over,
and it's First Section continuing to lead
the team cup race
behind its leader, Reid Janssen,
who remains in first place
in the individual competition.
Up to second place
in the individual standings, however,
is John Roland who proves
that his fast performance was no fluke.
That's Johnny Roland.
- Nice going, Johnny.
- Hey, we can do better.
Who is she?
- Where did she come from?
- Do you really care?
Oh, my fucking God.
This is shit. Let's get out of here.
Two nights ago, I was having
an out-of-body experience.
I was an Indian chief
and I was in the banquet room
of the lodge and your evil twin was there.
We were completely naked
and we were on top of the podium
and she was really getting
into my headdress.
And I was doing an obscure,
yet all-too-familiar rain dance,
and my feathers were having
a very, very ticklish effect on you.
She was saying something... What was it?
Was it something about your wigwam?
Yes. Yes, my wigwam.
And there was an adjective used
to describe my wigwam.
That's not important now.
Reid, what a surprise!
We were just talking
about Paulette's twin sister.
- What?
- Paulette. She has a twin.
Didn't you know?
What's he talking about?
My other half.
Your other half? Well, I'd love to meet her.
I bet you would. A rare pleasure.
She was here a couple nights ago.
Reid, good skiing on the mountain today.
Indeed. Your boys really seem
to be holding their own.
That is so witty. He kills me.
Dave, Dave, Dave.
When are you going to grow up, huh?
When you admit that you love me
and can't live another day
without me by your side.
Paulette, would you care to join me
at another table?
I'd love to hear about your twin sister.
It sounds so distinct.
Well, she's not at all like me.
So she's boring, stupid, and ugly.
Reid, you animal!
Shut up, Dave. I'd hate to have to make
an example out of you.
Will the director of ski school
please report to Sector 7?
Director of ski school, report to Sector 7.
Excuse me, that's me.
- Fitz, have you met Paulette?
- No! As a matter of fact I haven't, Dave.
- Well, do what you will.
- Hi, I'm Fitz.
- I'm Paulette.
- Paulette.
Can I just tell you that that dress
you were wearing the other night
looked very attractive?
- Thank you.
- No. No. No. No. Thank you.
Snowballs, get your snowballs.
Good, there, take a snowball.
Have a snowball!
Here you go. Good. Take two,
one for the little lady. Snowballs!
Hi, may I?
Sure.
- How did you do that?
- How did I do what?
Second place already.
I've been watching you ski.
- You're really good.
- Thanks.
- Do I know you?
- I'm Victoria.
- Johnny.
- I know.
Isn't that Johnny?
- Johnny? Yeah.
Man, she is totally hitting on him.
Hey, it's no big deal. I don't own him.
What am I gonna do with you, Johnny?
I don't know. What do you wanna do?
Here, this will explain everything.
- See you.
- Bye.
Fitz, that boy is definitely one of us.
Do you know
that wolves are monogamous
and are believed to mate for life?
Snowballs! Red-hot snowballs.
- Get your snowballs. Here you go, sir.
- Thank you.
Take one for the lady. Good. Good. Good.
Pretty lady like you
deserves two snowballs.
You little twerp, what the...
We didn't even make out.
Family fun. Fun for the whole family.
And now for another game of
"Who's underwear is it?"
with your host, it's Fitz!
Thank you very much,
ladies and gentlemen.
Let's have a nice, warm hello,
for today's guest underwear.
- Whose underwear is it?
- Whose underwear is that?
These underwear were worn
two weeks ago Saturday,
and the owner's name begins
with a consonant.
- Kim.
- Donna.
"D"! Good!
- "D".
- Denika.
If you'll notice the lacing,
the pretty trim, and the bow... Derek's.
- Derek!
- I knew that!
- "D"...
Guys, where are all the babes?
Ed, don't you think you talk about babes
a little too much?
No.
Well, well, well.
Anybody got a beer?
- Mr. Bryce, nice jacket.
- Shut up!
This time, Marshak,
you've gone way too far.
And I'm giving the board of directors
a full report of your conduct.
The skiing naked. The snowballs.
And you, your unspeakable behavior also.
You're all a bunch of animals.
And you're as good as out of here,
because it's just a simple matter
of filing the proper paperwork.
So put that in your pipe
and smoke it, mister.
- You got a problem, young man?
- No.
Fine. Have a nice night.
"Put that in your pipe
and smoke it, mister"?
Hey, wait a second, guys.
Maybe he's right.
Maybe we have gone too far.
Ed, it's not how far you go,
it's how go you far.
- We party here.
- We party big.
- We party now!
- Office party.
Ed, you get beer. Fitz, you get beer.
Johnny, you get laid.
Let me see Victoria's address again.
Guys.
Johnny! Johnny! Johnny! Johnny!
- Johnny! Johnny! Johnny! Johnny!
Lose your mind! Lose your mind!
Have a look around. I'll be right with you.
Okay.
Looks just like my place.
Hi.
So what exactly do you do?
Oh, I like to spend money.
Sounds like fun.
You're very perceptive.
Hey, some friends of mine
are having a party.
Do you wanna go to it?
Sure.
What shall I wear?
Okay, who's smoking?
Fitz! Pass 'em out, Fitz!
Yes.
Lights out!
- See anything?
- Yeah, I see lots of things.
- Johnny.
- Yeah.
Can't you find something?
God, you're cute.
What time did you say
the party starts?
If I was any closer,
I'd be in the other room.
Yes! Yes!
Reid will be so pleased.
Hi! Hello. Hello.
What the hell? Yeah, come on in.
Let's go.
Watch out!
Yes, I'd like to make
a long-distance phone call to Guam please.
Guam.
Now, there's something you can
do for me.
They're dead.
Three, two, one, go!
Come on. Come on.
Get off me, you pervert!
Come on, Dave!
Hey, Reid...
Three, two, one, go!
Reid, second to the pole!
Oh, my... Reid, let me tell you
about my sister.
Oh, God damn... Not feeling good.
Hi, Reid.
Oh, God.
Hi.
Hey, Karen, how's it going?
Hey, look, guys,
it's little Dave and his wienies.
Some nice skiing
on the mountain today, guys.
What, a one out of 15
in the qualifying round?
I got a better return on my savings bank.
Lori?
What happened to you?
I don't really know.
Can we talk for a minute?
Yeah, I guess so.
What's going on?
What happened yesterday?
What?
Hi, I'm having a party
after the competition.
I expect you all to be there.
Look, I gotta go.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
I don't understand.
- First you say no strings, then...
- Yeah, I said no strings. So what?
Well, which is it? I didn't say anything.
That's right, Johnny,
you didn't say anything.
I guess I'll see you.
Tough day.
Johnny may be the only one doing good
in the singles competition,
but we still have a chance
for the team cup.
Right.
Hey, you guys, maybe we should go
to bed earlier tonight, man.
We haven't even partied yet.
- Maybe partying will help.
- No, no.
Ed's right.
It's time to pull back and take it easy.
Now, I know a quiet little restaurant
where we can get a nice piece of fish.
Just relax.
You know, Johnny's becoming
a pretty good dancer.
I know. The plan is working perfectly.
There's just one more thing I must do.
Johnny loves you.
You love Johnny.
Johnny loves you. You love Johnny.
Show Johnny that you still love him
even though he's losing his mind.
What are you doing?
Left foot red.
I'll do anything for you now.
What the hey?
"Instructor and students of Section 8."
"You are called to appear before
"the general manager
of Sky High Properties Inc.
"for the purpose of disciplinary review. "
"The hearing will commence at 7:30 a. m.,
Saturday, March 12,
"in the office of the general manager. "
That's now!
As of this morning,
according to the determination
of the board of directors,
Dave Marshak is hereby placed
on disciplinary suspension,
and all of the students enrolled
in Section 8 are expelled.
Expelled?
This is ski school.
Well, shall we say disqualified, then?
- You guys are way too serious.
- You can't disqualify us.
Does this mean we can't ski
in the final competition?
Hold it, man.
These kids paid good money to come here
and buy me expensive, imported beers
just so they could go home knowing
that they have done something good
for their fellow man.
I am not going to send these kids back
to the great towns they came from
with the feeling that their rights
to be together, have a good time,
and yeah, do a little skiing,
have been usurped.
So put that in your pipe and smoke it,
Mr. Anton Bryce.
And Dave's a great instructor, bud.
Then why don't you tell me exactly
what it is you've all learned here then?
Well, Dave's taught me, like,
a lot of really neat moves.
What about you?
Well, I'm not exactly sure
what I've learned.
But how many of you
have seen Paulette buck-naked?
- I have, it's great.
- I know you have.
- Wow! Wow! Wow!
- Enough is...
Is enough. We don't have to take this.
I think it's Derek who's been taking it.
Shut up!
Marshak, you do have to take it.
You're not skiing in the final competition.
And that's final.
Okay, when you say final, do you mean
you are finally finished speaking?
Okay. Finals.
No one told me about a test.
Test? Does that mean
we have to cram, Derek?
Wait a minute. You have made
a mockery out of me and my mountain.
And I'm not going to have the future
of this facility go down in flames
because of you
and your juvenile hall antics.
There's a lot of important people
here today.
It kind of breaks my heart to know
that you won't be around to meet them.
Class dismissed.
Okay, you may be able to disqualify us
but you cannot stop us
from doing the lambada.
That's the forbidden dance.
- I think it's time we leave.
- I think it is time we leave.
It's getting really hot in here.
Boy. We must discuss the Paulette scene.
Now, was she wearing socks
when you saw her body?
You guys gotta quit your bellyaching,
you know what I mean?
"I can't ski... "
Guys, we gotta do something.
Maybe partying isn't the answer.
No.
You guys know
what I'm talking about, huh?
Skiing is partying. Partying is skiing.
Yeah. Yeah, that's it.
They can't stop us from partying,
so they can't stop us from skiing.
Johnny's right. And thank you, Fitz.
Wait a second.
I've lost, like, far too many brain cells
to understand that one.
What the boys are saying is, if you can't
bring the mountain to the party,
you bring the party to the mountain.
- Right!
- We crash the competition.
He's learning.
Lambada.
Qualifying rounds are over
and it's time for the annual
Spring Ski-fest Competition to begin.
The top ten qualifying skiers will compete
in the slalom,
giant slalom, freestyle and the downhill.
Mr. Bryce.
Seedings are completed.
Defending champion Reid Janssen
is top seed in every event.
Newcomer John Roland, who impressed
everybody with a second-place seeding,
has been disqualified
along with the entire Section 8 squad.
Well, Reid, looks like I'm gonna get
my piece of action after all.
You're gonna get yours too.
What the hell's that?
What the fuck is this?
Yeah!
Reid, just what the hell is going on?
Gentlemen, may I present to you
Section 8.
- Hi.
- What the hell do you think you're doing?
Well, we came here to ski.
- I came here to ski.
- You gotta be kidding, Marshak.
Your group is bottom of the barrel.
Even if they let you race, you...
What do you say?
Let them ski! Let them ski!
Let them ski!
Let them ski! Let them ski! Let them ski!
Yeah!
Ski! Ski! Ski! Ski! Ski! Ski! Ski!
Let them ski!
Reid, hold on a minute.
There are other things to consider here,
you know what I mean?
Marshak, why don't we say this?
You agree to calm down your antics,
we'll let you participate
in the competition.
It's a done deal.
- "Calm down our antics"?
- We're gonna embarrass you.
- Really?
Section 8
is back in the competition
and they're making the most of it,
quickly moving up to fourth place.
They're a bunch of pussies.
Section 8 is making
a run for the team cup,
but the downhill is
First Section's strongest event
and that's up next.
Man, this is bullshit.
We own this event.
Let's blow these geeks off the hill.
No kidding.
- Honorary dance for the girls?
- Definitely.
Millie. Millie. Millie. Millie. Millie.
Hi, Millie.
We own this race.
You don't stand a chance.
Helicopter.
Helicopter, yeah!
Well, all righty. Hi, how are you?
Yes! Helmet. Yellow, not my color.
In order to be the best,
you must lose your mind.
Get out of here, you slimes.
You've learned much, young Dave,
but you are not a skier yet.
Section 8 is still far behind,
so they're going to have to come up
with something really special
if they truly want to win.
Hey, are you all right?
Section 8's chance
has come down to John Roland.
He needs to beat the time
of two minutes, 22 seconds
for Section 8 to win the team competition.
The course record,
shown on the lower clock, is 2:24,
so it doesn't look good.
Come on!
Come on, Johnny!
2.2, a new course record,
but it's not enough for Section 8 to win.
It's a tie. Dave's section
and Reid's section are tied.
Johnny boy! Johnny! Johnny! Johnny!
- All right! All right!
- He's the man! That was really something!
Hey, Marshak.
You call what you did "skiing"?
Actually I call what we did
"kicking your ass. "
- Yeah, well, it's not over. You didn't win.
- Okay.
- Let's settle this once and for all.
- Right.
The best against the best.
What do you say?
Sure.
Only... Shall we make this
a little more interesting?
Say loser walks off the mountain
and never looks back?
Sure, and we ski the Dome.
Dave!
- The Dome?
- Of course.
Agreed.
Though I must say I'm a little surprised.
You and me on the Dome. That's great.
Oh, the decision was easy.
Johnny's gonna ski.
All right, Johnny.
Way to go, Johnny!
All right, John!
Way to go!
Yeah. Remember? Loser walks. No tears.
Sending the lamb
to the slaughter, Marshak.
First-timer on the Dome. Can't wait.
- I'll see you up there.
- You'll see the back of me.
Okay, Johnny, the only thing you
have to remember about skiing the Dome
is when you get to the Bald Rock there...
There, do not take the slope to the right.
It ends in a cliff.
It's a totally impossible jump.
No one has ever made it, so just...
You forget about it.
Take the slope to the left at Bald Rock.
Left at Bald Rock.
- You got it?
- Left at Bald Rock. Got it.
Left.
- Exactly.
- Right.
Hope he's okay.
The skiers will be dropped
at the summit.
Then it's a free-for-all to the bottom.
Where are they?
The first one past Bald Rock
will have the clear advantage.
- So whoever appears first should win.
- Come on, Johnny.
Come on!
- It's Reid. Where's Johnny?
- I don't know.
Wait a minute.
I don't believe it.
Roland's going towards the cliff.
He must be out of his mind.
Oh, no!
Check this out.
Come on, Johnny!
- Yeah!
Gentlemen, the mountain is ours!
He did it!
John Roland is the winner.
Section 8 wins the team competition.
Yeah! Victory!
Yeah!
I think you're about to be crushed.
Hey, I don't care, Reid.
They're still a bunch of dickheads.
Shut up.
Way to be, Johnny!
I wouldn't get too carried away
with your celebrating, Marshak.
You see, right now,
there's a new party in control.
I know. I know.
- Johnny! Johnny! Johnny! Johnny!
Hold on a minute.
The mountain has been sold.
I repeat, the mountain has been sold.
According to this press release,
the new management
promises radical restructuring.
"Radical restructuring"?
I didn't write that.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I give you radical restructuring.
How about the beers?
May I present your new owner.
The mountain is ours!
Yeah, okay, yeah!
- All right! Yeah, okay!
Yeah, all right, okay.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Anybody got a problem with that?
No! No! No!
- No! No! No!
Then let's get naked.
Oh, yeah!
Yeah.
This is radical restructuring!
It's simple. If you wanna be the best,
you've got to party with the best.
Know it, live it, love it.
Are you ready for a hot tub?
I love my life.
Welcome to my kingdom.