["Falling Out of Love" playing
by Ivan Neville]
♪ Don't know why it seems ♪
♪ Like a long, long time ♪
♪ Since I've been on the move ♪
♪ I'm just tryin' to find my way ♪
♪ Don't know my name ♪
♪ Livin' day to day ♪
♪ Just a little boy who wants to have
His way ♪
♪ I just can't keep still ♪
♪ And I'm falling out of love ♪
♪ Falling out of love ♪
♪ Sometimes it feels ♪
♪ Like I'm runnin' out of time ♪
♪ Sand slippin' through my fingers ♪
♪ Like rivers through my mind ♪
♪ On the corner hangin' with the boys ♪
♪ I always will be ♪
♪ Falling out of love ♪
♪ In and out of love ♪
♪ Out of love ♪
♪ Just foolin' around ♪
♪ Can't slow down ♪
♪ Should have listened
To what my daddy said ♪
♪ Just wanna be cool ♪
♪ Another fool I can't keep still ♪
♪ And I'm feelin' kind of blue ♪
♪ My eyes are red ♪
♪ But something keeps tellin' me ♪
♪ That I know ♪
♪ Just what is gonna become
Of this little boy ♪
♪ Inside this heart of mine ♪
♪ I keep on ♪
♪ Falling out of love ♪
-[Zachary] I don't know what to say.
-How about, "The Lord is my shepherd"?
[whimpers]
-Come on, Angie. Drop the gun.
-Is that it?
Zachary Hutton... Pulitzer Prize-winning
playwright,
internationally acclaimed author,
about to be shot to death by a jealous
female,
and all he can come up with is, "Come on,
Angie. Drop the gun."
-[woman] Zach!
-I'll be right with you.
-Who are you kidding?
-[gun loads]
You know as well as I do you're not
gonna shoot.
You couldn't kill a fly.
I could if I caught it fucking
my hairdresser.
[thuds]
Angie, come on now. Give me the gun.
Tell you what? I'll be fair about this.
Community property.
I keep the gun, you get the bullets.
[gun clicks]
[grunting]
-But I saw you load it.
-You weren't paying attention.
I always keep the first chamber empty.
-Oh, really?
-Yeah.
[gunshot]
[screaming]
-Son of a bitch!
-You're overreacting.
Get out of here, you bitch!
-[gunshot]
-Angie!
God damn it!
Hello?
Darling?
[woman sobbing]
Come on, Angie, for God's sake!
-Goodbye, Zach.
-Please, please, please.
-Hello.
-Alex?
I thought you were on a plane.
-Engine trouble.
-Oh. I'm sorry.
You have me at a disadvantage.
You obviously know who I am.
-I'm Angela Smith.
-And what do you do, Angela,
besides trying to kill my husband?
-Alex?
-[Alex and Angela] Shut up!
I'm an investment counselor.
-And Zach's mistress.
-Who was that in the sheet?
My hairdresser.
-I think I get the picture.
-Alex?
If you still wanna kill him,
do me a favor and take him outside.
Those are new sheets.
Go ahead and shoot.
No. That's too good for you.
[choking]
But I bet when that lady gets through
with you... you'll wish I had.
[breathes heavily]
Wait a minute! Wait a minute! Let's see
if I got this straight.
-Angie catches you in bed with--
-Tina.
In your house?
-She was cutting my hair.
-Bed?
I know it sounds turgid,
but I have a barber chair in my study.
Spurious perhaps, but not turgid.
She was finishing up with the blow-dryer.
A skittish instrument
if there ever was one.
-One thing led to another.
-Enter Angie with your 38.
Luckily, I always keep the first chamber
empty.
Oh, lucky, indeed.
That's the first empty chamber
you ever filled since I've known you.
-[Waitress] Scotch, rocks.
-Barney, do you really perceive me
as a major compulsive womanizer?
A 42-year-old shooting star
in a galactic harem.
Can I be cured?
Do you wanna be cured?
-I know it's ruining my life, and yet--
-And yet.
Two words that to one degree or another
plague us all.
-You see, I truly love women.
-Oh, I see.
I love everything about them, Barney.
I love the way they feel,
the way they smell, most of the time.
I-- I have to admit, I don't like women
with long, round toenails.
But that is the only abrogation so far.
And so far has been quite a while
and quite a few.
Oh, that's true.
-Out of soup.
-I long... for a meaningful,
monogamous, healthy relationship.
And I-- I was sure I had it with Alex,
but the truth is, Barney...
in the deep dark silence
of my considered conscience,
where there's just me and me...
the unmitigated truth
-is I want it all.
-Hey, wanting is okay.
I want a loving,
faithful, caring, care taking wife,
and I wanna make love
to everything else in long skirts,
with bare feet and ripe, juicy mouths.
Little boy-girls with small, firm breasts
and tight asses.
Rubenesque round women with big
Mother Earth breasts
and green eyes. God! I could go on and on.
Don't. I'm getting a hard-on.
-Me too. God.
-[both laugh]
The point is,
I'm bright enough to know
it's an impossible dream,
but I'm helpless to act otherwise.
[Alex] However, the ultimate fate
of the bill is still in question,
since those close to the president,
who were willing to guess,
believe he will veto the bill.
But proponents say such a program
is the only way to--
Zach, may I make a suggestion?
-Please do.
-Look.
Don't try to solve it tonight. Go home.
Sleep on it.
Alas, old friend, I have no home.
She chucked me out lock, stock
and typewriter.
[Zach] What have you got against
my typewriter?
[Alex] You used to write on it. Books
and plays and movies.
Once-- once you wrote a poem
on our second anniversary
and gave it to me. And you were happy.
You exorcised your demons with credible
thoughts and good words on that typewriter
and your talent turned me on.
I really thought we had a chance
"until death do us part."
And then one day you stopped. You gave up.
-I dried up. It happens to writers.
-Oh, so you bury yourself
with the first young female
that comes along,
in the hopes she's going to magically
restore your lost talent?
-Alex--
-No, don't say it.
This is a lecture, not a debate.
And since I don't intend to speak to you
for the rest of this lifetime,
you either get out now, or shut up
and let me finish.
I'm not saying that your condition
is unique.
In fact, quite a few older men
do the same thing.
How about quite a few older women?
If you're trying to redeem yourself
by implying that I might
have been unfaithful to you,
you're barking up the wrong older woman.
I could have, but regrettably didn't.
I threw out that typewriter
because it represents everything
that could have been loving and lasting,
and wonderful, and everything that wasn't.
-Can I say something? Please?
-No! No! No!
You have 20 minutes to get your things
and get out of this house forever,
or I will get a restraining order
and have you removed.
[Zach] It's over, but I still love
that woman, Jake.
You think you could patch it up?
[sighs] No, it's over. It's--
Hmm. That's a shame, because her divorce
lawyer called this morning.
She-- she's gonna be tough.
-How tough?
-Well, half of everything you've earned
since you've been married. A hundred
thousand a year
-for the next five years.
-What?
-The house, the farm, both cars.
-You've gotta be kidding.
-There's something I forgot.
-How about the shirt off my back?
That's it.
I'll tell you what I'll give her. I'll
give her exactly what she's entitled to.
The house... the farm... both cars.
A hundred thousand dollars a year
for five years.
I'm a desperate man, doctor. I need help.
I've gotta change my way of living.
And if that ain't enough,
I'm gonna change the way I strut my stuff.
♪ 'Cause nobody loves you when you're old
And gray ♪
♪ There'll be some changes made today ♪
♪ Yes, sir, there'll be
Some changes made ♪
♪ Duh-duh-da ♪
I couldn't resist it. You think I'm crazy?
No.
Then, what the hell is wrong with me?
Well, for one thing, you can't sing
worth shit.
[Zach] I can't go on like this, doctor.
If it's the last thing I do,
I'm gonna settle down,
start writing again,
and stop chasing after beautiful,
young women.
[horn honks]
[crash]
[man] Whoa!
[man] Camera two, get a tight shot
on Alex, will you?
We don't wanna miss this one.
-KRA-TV is proud to present...
-Ten seconds.
-Have you seen Adam White's piece?
-No. Is it good?
You-- you don't know about it?
[man] Five seconds.
Should I? What's so amazing
about gridlock?
[man 2] On one.
If you drive, you know about it.
It's called gridlock.
It happens when traffic gets so congested,
not even a green light means move.
In this continuing series on gridlock,
Adam White shows us how this bumper
to bumper disease
is spreading from town to town.
[Adam] Alex, it is now clear that gridlock
is an epidemic.
No one can escape it. You are looking
at the proof here in Brentwood,
a shopping center for the rich and famous.
This can be particularly dangerous,
because paramedics
can't even make their way
to help gridlock victims,
which in this case turned out to be.
Zachary Hutton, famous author
and playwright.
The victim was lucky. No serious injuries,
and a beautiful amateur nurse
who sells real estate in her spare time.
What do you bet she sells him a house?
[Zach] For a while there, I thought,
"This is it."
I was convinced it couldn't get
any better.
I should have known better.
[sighs]
-Don't worry about it... it happens.
-Not to me.
Not being able to screw is as bad
as not being able to write.
Maybe you should try writing again.
What the fuck does that mean?
I don't know.
I'm not the burning bush. I made
a suggestion, not a commandment.
[sobbing]
-Hi, Jasper.
-Welcome, Mr. Hutton.
There he is. Hey, Curt.
-I'm glad you could come.
-Curt Ames, Helena Walker.
-Hello, how are you?
-How's he been?
-Just adorable.
-That bad?
Mm-hm.
-Dear boy.
-Hi, Sparky.
Faulkner's one-time heir apparent,
and all he can say is "Hi, Sparky."
Never mind. It's nice to see you again.
Denise?
Helena. Helena Walker, Leon Sparks.
-So we've met.
-No.
Oh, shit.
-I foozled your redheads. Forgive me.
-Well, you know what they say.
Once you've seen one, you've seen
them all.
I'm sure Zach, as an expert
on the subject,
would be the first to denounce
that canard.
But for the moment, dear boy,
why don't you do whatever is necessary
to make yourself comfortable,
while I try to redeem myself with Helena
by introducing her to some clever people,
more her age.
-Excuse me.
-Double vodka tonic.
I decided not to drink to avoid arguments,
and to be alert to the narrative
possibilities of the evening.
[Zach] Then, Alex arrives with my stepson
Greg.
Alex!
Dear girl, how wonderful.
-[Sparky] You're almost as tall as I am.
-Excuse me.
You told me he wasn't going to be here.
He told me he wasn't going to be here.
-I don't believe you.
-Ask him.
You know that we're-- shit.
Ask me what? Hello, Greg.
Come to give your old failed stepfather
a big hug?
-Ask me what?
-Nothing.
-You said she wasn't coming.
-I said she wasn't coming if you came.
-Nice.
-And you said?
I said, "Oh, in that case,
I wasn't coming."
Then, I called him back, and said
I changed my mind.
Yes, a little addendum you neglected
to mention.
If you were under 18,
I would have considered it relevant.
Now, children, who is going
to leave first?
Come on, Greg. I'll buy you a drink.
You are such a prick.
Dear boy, some of my best friends
are pricks.
Some of your best pricks are friends.
There was a time when your wit
was incisive,
but that riposte was just a feeble jab
from a routed ex-champion.
If you think I'm such a failure,
why do you keep on representing me?
That's like asking a heroin addict
why he keeps shooting up.
It's because he keeps hoping
for that first-time rush,
that cherry high, even though
he knows he'll never get it again.
He's hooked... and he keeps hoping.
Watch out. I may surprise you.
You watch out. I'm beyond surprises.
[piano music playing]
Excuse me.
-[Curt] Leon!
-[Leon] No!
[Curt] Stop for a minute?
At least let me--
[Leon] Aw, stop it! It's over!
[Curt] You cruel, graceless
son of a bitch!
[Leon] I'm not going to argue with you.
I want you out of this house
by tomorrow morning!
-Sound familiar?
-[Leon] Now leave me alone!
For God's sake, stop sniveling.
Try to save yourself at least a lick
of self-respect!
Was I right? Adorable.
Snooping around for a 11:00 newsbreak?
[Zach] I take it back. You're too much
of a cunt to be a prick.
Don't say it, dear boy, write it.
Not being able to write is like not being
able to screw.
Well, maybe they sort of depend
on each other.
-What the fuck does that mean?
-How the fuck do I know?
I'm a bartender, not your psychiatrist.
♪ The most beautiful girl in the world ♪
♪ Picks my ties out ♪
♪ Eats my candy drinks my brandy ♪
♪ The most beautiful girl in the world ♪
♪ The most beautiful star in the world ♪
♪ Isn't Garbo isn't Dietrich ♪
♪ But the sweet trick ♪
♪ That will make me believe
It's a beautiful world ♪
I really hoped when Molly moved in
that we had a good chance
at a long-term relationship.
♪ My romance doesn't have to have a moon ♪
♪ In the sky ♪
♪ My romance doesn't need a blue lagoon ♪
♪ Standing by ♪
♪ No month of May ♪
♪ No twinkling star ♪
♪ No hideaway ♪
♪ No soft guitar ♪
♪ My romance doesn't need a castle ♪
-Any idea what started it?
-Spontaneous combustion.
-What's that?
-The inevitable consequence
of excessive vicissitude.
-What's that?
-Pressure.
Well, come on, explain.
Two people, who live an inharmonious
existence together
eventually arrive at a point
where the pressure is so great,
somebody has to give.
Unless you bleed off a certain amount
of steam
in a pressure cooker, it will explode.
Excessive vicissitude.
When wood is too dry and the sun
is too hot--
Spontaneous combustion.
-Exactly.
-You were the wood, Molly was the sun.
A felicitous analogy.
-And what's that?
-Showing off with big words.
Oh.
It's a condition that occurs when I mix
a lack of self-esteem
with an abundance of alcohol.
To be precise, a Banzai Sunset.
-All right, Zach. Car keys.
-Uh-uh.
Hey. Molly took my Jeep and my Mercedes
burned up with the fire.
Give her some credit, will you?
Most of the women I know
would have swung with the Mercedes.
-It had a flat.
-Oh, it had a flat.
When you pass out, where do I ship
the body?
I don't know. So far it's a toss-up
between your guest room
and the Ambassador Hotel.
-My guest room is occupied.
-By whom?
-By a guest.
-I don't believe you.
You're just timid about tidying
up after a drunk.
Tidying up is a cinch.
It's replacing furniture, buying
new carpet,
painting out the graffiti
is what makes me timid.
What are you looking for?
You hid the nuts. Didn't I reimburse you
for all that stuff?
-Some things are not reimbursable.
-For instance?
Like putting Krazy Glue on my dog's paws
and sticking him halfway up the wall.
-I see your point.
-Now look it's not that I don't empathize.
-What's that?
-Feel sorry for you.
-Good night, Barney.
-Hi, Barney.
-[Barney] Lonnie!
Hey, girls.
[woman] Hey, doll!
[woman 2] Hi, Lonnie!
-What's the soup?
-Lentil.
It was lentil last week.
When the lentil's all gone, it'll be
something else.
-I'd love a steak, but I shouldn't.
-Sure you should.
The kind of shape you're in you could eat
a whole cow.
-[Zach] Good evening.
-Hi.
-What's that you're playing?
-Something Cole Porter made up.
-You play very well.
-Are you a professional musician?
No. Are you?
No. I don't know anything about music.
That kind of music, anyway.
Can you play "Three Times A Lady"?
I'm sorry. I'm not quite drunk enough yet.
-Miss?
-Jones. Lonnie Jones.
I'm Zach. Hi.
If you're still here
when I finish my steak and lentil soup,
Zach,
we'll pick up this conversation
where it left off.
♪ Have you met Miss Jones? ♪
♪ Someone said as we shook hands ♪
♪ She was just Miss Jones to me ♪
♪ Then I said, "Miss Jones ♪
♪ "You're a girl who understands ♪
♪ I'm a man who must be free" ♪
♪ And all at once I lost my breath ♪
♪ And all at once was scared to death ♪
♪ And all at once I owned the earth
And sky ♪
♪ Now I met Miss Jones ♪
♪ And we'll keep on meeting till we die ♪
♪ Miss Jones and ♪
♪ And I ♪
[applause]
[Zach] It wasn't-- It wasn't a derby,
because it...
Hey, wait. Hey, wait, wait.
You promised to take me home.
-I have.
-This is home?
-This is where I work.
-This is where you...
this...
is where I live.
-This is--
-Hey. I like where you live.
It reflects a strong sense
of individuality and taste,
-yet it's still feminine.
-You sound surprised.
-Do I?
-Are you?
-About what?
-That a woman can be an individual
with taste and still be feminine?
Oh! If I admitted surprise,
would that mitigate against us
going to bed together?
-It might.
-Then, for the record,
I am the least surprised man
you have ever met in your entire life.
I'll take your word for it. I was hoping
you would.
-Wanna use the bathroom?
-Ladies first.
-No chauvinism intended.
-Make yourself at home.
[water dripping]
[grunts]
[toilet flushes]
[Lonnie] How do you feel about women
who are into bodybuilding?
I don't know. I've never known a woman
who builds bodies.
Look at it this way, Zach. I've worked
five years, 52 weeks a year,
five days a week, three hours a day...
to build this body. And for one night,
this night, it's all yours.
-How do you feel about that?
-Like Mrs. Arnold Schwarzenegger.
I love your sense of humor.
-And it loves you.
-Do you always try
-and joke your way out of a tight spot?
-Not always.
Occasionally, I'm too frightened to make
my lips move.
Hope you're not frightened now, Zach.
I'm not, but fortunately my cock
is scared stiff.
-Wonderful.
-I hope so.
-Now just relax.
-Right.
-And leave everything to Lonnie.
-You got it, Lonnie.
-Let's get these shorts off.
-Oh, that's a good idea.
[grunts]
Listen, while you're down there,
would you mind getting the sock?
Oh, shit!
[phone drops]
Oh, God! Thank you. Thank you, God!
[woman] Okay, ladies. Get it on!
[all screaming]
♪ Right across the room ♪
♪ Standing there ♪
-Morning!
-[All] Good morning.
[women laughing]
Sorry I'm late.
♪ Starin' a hole that cuts like a knife ♪
♪ Baby, it's burning burning ♪
♪ Skin deep ♪
♪ To the bone ♪
♪ Skin deep to the bone ♪
♪ Skin deep ♪
[dog barks]
How'd you get in?
Sorry everything's in such a mess.
It's the maid's day off.
I'm not going to argue with you anymore,
Zach.
You're dishonest and you're too good
with words.
Hey, when have I ever been dishonest
with you?
Oh, come on! You were dishonest with me
from the time you decided you wanted
to fuck me!
We were introduced. I said,
"How do you do?
I wanna fuck you." What's dishonest
about that?
Zach, in the six months
of living together,
-we had a hundred arguments.
-I only counted 99.
Okay. Out of those 99 arguments,
was there ever one time that you thought
that I was right?
-Honestly? No.
-What does that tell you?
That you were wrong 99 times out of 100.
Get out of my face, Zach, or I swear
to God I'm gonna kill you.
-Can I ask you something first?
-No.
What are you looking for?
My runes.
-I'm sorry. You're what?
-Runes.
I cast them for you once when we started
going together.
-Runes?
-Viking runes!
Little stones with runic symbols
that tell your fortune.
You said they were bullshit,
but the last time I consulted them,
I turned up Isa.
Isa? Oh, well, what does that mean?
Spiritual winter.
-Oh.
-I'm spiritually frozen, Zach.
So what? You thought a good fire
would help thaw you out?
There you go.
So where did you keep these runes?
I put them in my bedside drawer.
I thought because they were stone,
-They must have melted or something.
-You won't find them here.
The bedroom's over there.
You're in the toilet.
[laughs]
Yeah, the story of my life.
-Molly.
-Don't worry.
I'll bring back the Jeep as soon
as I find a job.
Shit!
[piano music playing]
-You don't look great.
-I can't imagine why not.
I spent the past 24 hours escaping
from a burning house,
getting shitfaced and shacking up
with a muscle-bound sex maniac
and doing three hours
of kamikaze aerobics.
Speaking of burning houses,
they haven't said so in so many words,
but... they're making noises
like they think
the fire has been deliberately set.
"They" being? The insurance company.
-Based on?
-Information from the fire department.
-What information?
-We'll know that when they tell us.
Uh, another screwdriver for Mr. Hutton,
and I'll have, uh, Jack Daniel's rocks.
Sorry about Sparky.
-What about Sparky?
-Oh, I thought you knew.
-Oh, shit.
-It was on the morning news.
I thought someone would have called you.
Nobody knows I'm here but you.
I'm sorry.
Well, what was it, a heart?
A suicide.
Oh, God.
Oh, God!
I talked to him just a month ago.
I told him. I wanted to apologize.
-Apologize?
-For what, for Christ's sake?
Oh, for letting him down, for the things
I said the last time I saw him.
But he said, "Well, that's very big
of you, Zach.
But I'm afraid it's too late.
You've cut me too deep."
Did he have any family?
No. Curt was the closest thing to family,
but...
God, I wonder how he's taking it.
I gotta get home
to the fucking loved ones.
Give Bernice my regards.
Uh, phone, please?
[sighs]
[indistinct chatter]
[piano music playing]
Thank you.
-[Operator] What city, please?
-Uh, West Los Angeles.
Alexandra Hutton on San Marino.
Sorry. I have no listing for a Hutton
on San Marino.
I show an A. Hutton on North Bristol.
Uh, there are no Huttons
in West Los Angeles?
-No, sir.
-Okay.
Give me the number on Bristol.
That number is 555-5657.
-5657?
-Yes, sir.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome, sir.
Do you see that very beautiful young woman
over there in the turquoise?
-The one in leather.
-Yeah. Find out what she's drinking
and I'd like to order her another, okay?
I approve.
[phone line ringing]
[woman] Hello. Hello? Hello.
Is anybody there?
-Hello?
-Alex.
-Who are you calling?
-Uh, Alexander Hutton.
We've got a whole bunch of Huttons here,
-but no Alexander.
-Sorry. Wrong number.
What man?
[woman] Operator, may I help you?
Operator, would you connect
me with the men's shop?
Thank you.
-[man] Men's Shop, may I help you?
-Yes, uh, this is Zachary Hutton.
-Yes, Mr. Hutton.
-Yes. Would you send me over
half a dozen jockey shorts, half a dozen
pairs of socks,
three pairs of pajamas and a robe?
-[man] Any particular color?
-Uh, usual colors.
-And a pair of slippers.
-[man] Where shall I send them?
-Yes, uh, Bungalow 11.
-[man] Bungalow 11?
-Uh-huh. And I'll--
-[man] Sir?
Yes. Look, um, I'll come by tomorrow,
and I'll pick up some, um, some pants.
[man] Yes, sir. Good to have you staying
at the hotel again.
Yeah, well, it's great to be here.
-[door slamming]
-[indistinct chatter]
[woman] Good-bye! You don't understand.
It's over!
-[man] Over?
-[woman] Yes!
-[man] You listen to me!
-[woman] I'm not gonna listen!
[man] You are gonna listen to me!
You are gonna talk to me,
and you are gonna talk to me now!
[woman screams]
-[woman] You son of a bitch! Ow!
-[water flowing]
-I've had it! Goodbye, Rick!
-[man] You get over here.
Indistinct chatter
-[man] Get out of there!
-Oh, shit.
[woman] No!
-Hey!
-[woman] Rick!
[man] I am sick and tired of you picking
up guys always behind my back!
[woman] Yeah? Let's talk about the
hot numbers that you pick up everywhere.
[man] I pay them! It's different!
-[woman] Oh, God!
-[man] I'm so sick of you!
-[woman screams]
-[man] You're like a bitch!
-[man] Come here! Come here!
-[woman] Stop it!
-[man] I'll tell you something.
-[woman] Tell me.
[man] I can't figure it right now,
but if I could, I'd tell you!
[woman] Your brain is the size of a pea!
-[man] Excuse me!
-[woman] That's it!
Start breaking up the furniture,
you creep!
[man] I'm not a creep. I'm a musician!
-Operator.
-Yes, operator.
This is Zach Hutton in Bungalow 11.
Would you please call the people
in the apartment directly above me,
and tell them to stop screaming
and yelling and breaking your furniture.
-Are you sure they're breaking furniture?
-Yes! Listen.
[objects crashing]
-Okay?
-[operator] I'll call right away.
[phone ringing]
[man] What? How?
Oh! Oh, the man down-fucking-stairs, eh?
Well, thank you very fucking much!
[phone slammed]
[indistinct chatter]
Downstairs to talk to this fucking man!
[doorbell buzzing]
[man] Shut up! Open the door!
I'm coming!
[man] Calling up, getting me in trouble!
-You!
-What's with you, man?
-Wait a goddamn minute!
Who the fuck are you?
-You hit on my old lady.
-I want you out!
-What are you blaming him for?
-You know fucking well why.
You said I'm always coming on to guys
the minute your back is turned.
Well, you're right.
I pick up guys all the time, whenever
I get the chance!
-And you wanna know why?
-Why?
Because you are a-- a boring--
-Arrogant.
-arrogant!
-Sanctimonious.
-Sanctimonious!
Cocksucker.
-Oh, you little--
-Ow! Jesus!
I picked him up, Rick!
Hey!
Hey, turns out great, don't it?
While you're screwing him, I'll move out.
Oh, I like that.
[clears throat]
[sighs]
Don't be stupid.
Hey, don't panic, you little wanker.
I'll pack real fast.
Ta.
Oh, God.
-Oh, God, I'm so sorry.
-It's okay.
Hey, wait, wait, wait a minute. Hang on.
Don't go back up there.
No, I'll just-- I'll just go take a walk.
No, no. You take a seat and relax.
Give him time to get out. Okay? Come on,
sit down.
-Don't be nice to me, please.
-Okay, I won't.
-Would you like a drink?
-No, thanks.
Look. I-- I've caused you enough trouble.
I really think I should leave--
No, you shouldn't. Now, come on.
It's not your fault.
Even if I did buy you a drink
because we had a kind of mutual exchange
across a crowded room,
that guy had no business beating
you up like that.
-Oh, he didn't exactly--
-Who is he? What does he do?
Uh, Rick Curry, he's the lead guitarist
for the Moon Rocks.
Naturally.
Why naturally?
Because rock groups like that,
and lead guitarists like Rick
are an unnatural phenomenon,
put on this earth, I suspect,
to test my reality.
I don't know how I could have missed it.
By the way, I'm Zach Hutton.
How do you do. Amy McKenna.
Amy.
Well, I'm sorry we had to meet like this,
but it's better than not meeting at all,
I hope.
-So, what do you do, Zach?
-I write and, um,
occasionally I wear orange and yellow
pajamas.
Usually under a robe. I'll be right back.
Don't go away.
[piano music playing]
[Rick] Amy, love, fuck you!
[door slamming]
-Amy?
-Yeah?
Where's your home?
My home? Um...
well, I was working in Seattle
when I met Rick.
He's got a house in New Jersey,
-but we travel a lot.
-Mm-hm.
Um, originally I'm from New Orleans.
New Orleans?
♪ Do you know what it means ♪
♪ To miss New Orleans ♪
Do you know that song?
Yeah. My father loves jazz.
How does he feel about the Moon Rock?
Um, he's never met him. I don't think
he'd like him.
-So where do you come from, Zach?
-Uh, geographically or emotionally?
Both.
Well, I was born in Philadelphia,
but I come from New Orleans.
-You like jazz?
-Oh, I love it.
-But you prefer heavy metal.
-No, I prefer good music.
Well, that eliminates heavy metal.
-I love good heavy metal.
-Oh, really? That's impossible.
That's like saying,
"I love good root canal."
[laughing]
You sound like my father.
Oh, no, I know. Sometimes that can be
a major handicap.
What times?
Well, sounding like a father
when I'm trying to impress a young
female under 22?
Twenty-five.
Oh, especially those times, yeah.
Well, you could lie.
Then I wouldn't know if it was me
or the lie.
And sooner or later I'd have to start
lying about my age.
Oh, come on. How old are you?
You couldn't be more than 35.
Close. I'm 33.
-Well, good night, Zach.
-Good night.
Thanks for everything. You were terrific.
[music playing]
[sighs]
[classical music playing]
[woman] Operator.
Yes, operator. This is Mr. Hutton
in Bungalow 11.
Would you please call the apartment
directly above me?
Do you know who's in that room?
Mm, I believe Miss Amy McKenna.
[phone rings]
-Hello.
-[Zach] Tchaikovsky?
-What?
-You're playing Tchaikovsky.
Oh. It's the TV.
I didn't realize it was that loud.
-Do you like the ballet?
-I like this ballet. I like the music.
I'm sorry if I woke you up.
You didn't.
Couldn't sleep?
No.
-Obviously you couldn't either.
-No.
-Would you like me to come up?
-Yes.
[door slams]
-Zach.
-Hm.
-Would you mind wearing something?
-I am wearing something.
-You are?
-Yeah.
Oh, you-- you mean-- oh, no--
Yes, do you--? Do you have a?
No, I-- see, there was a-- a fire.
And I lost everything. They were probably
the first to go.
It's just that, you know, these days
it's so--
I know you can't be too careful.
-I-- I really want you.
-Oh, God!
I really want you too.
-It's just we can't unless--
-I know, I know.
I could-- do you want me to go to--
I could maybe-- you don't--
Do you have any?
-Oh, you wouldn't mind?
-Are you kidding?
Oh, God, no!
-They're Rick's.
-They're Rick's?
Uh, that's all right. Um,
I'll reimburse him.
Yeah?
-Where in the--
-Ow!
-Sorry.
-That's all right.
We need to get-- are they in--
This drawer right here.
God! Are they in a box?
Yeah. They should be right on top.
That's not it.
Okay.
All right.
[Zach] Oh, my God!
I can't see what-- what I'm doing here.
-[Amy] I'll turn on the light.
-[Zach] No, no, no that's all right.
[Zach] Where's the bathroom?
may be that will be better.
-[Amy] It's right over there.
-[Zach] I'll be right back. Oh, God.
Ow! Goddamn thing!
[Amy] I-- I don't know about those,
but don't be surprised,
cause sometimes Rick's sexual taste
can get pretty kinky.
[Zach] It says in the instructions
that it's been treated with an ancient
Chinese herb,
guaranteed to prolong erection.
[Zach] Oh, my God!
[Amy] What's wrong?
[Zach] You're not gonna believe this.
[Amy] Oh, my God!
[thud]
Oh, my God!
[Zach] Truly amazing.
-[door opens]
-[Rick] Amy?
[Amy] Oh, my God. It's Rick!
[Zach] What was that?
[Zach] Rick?
[Amy] Quick! In the closet!
-Go! No, no, this way!
-[Zach] Where?
-[Amy] Right here.
-[Rick] Amy?
[door opens]
[Rick] Turn on the lights, Amy.
Amy. Amy.
Rick, you scared the hell out of me.
I'm sorry. I, uh-- I didn't mean to.
I, uh, came back to apologize.
-Too late.
-I--
-What's this?
-What?
-This.
This!
Rick, if you wanna talk,
we'll talk tomorrow.
-No, I, uh-- I don't wanna talk, love.
-No, Rick.
I thought maybe we could make a little
bit of love.
-No! No.
-Fine!
-Jesus!
-Where are you going?
I forgot my mousse.
-What the hell?
-What?
-[Rick] What's this?
-This.
-Oh, Rick!
Amy, it was gonna be a surprise.
They were in that-- that drawer!
Oh what, you think I took them out and--
No! No!
I think they got up all by themselves.
Rick, they're your stupid rubbers!
-Just take them and get out!
-All right!
All right! Fine!
Fine, but you know,
you don't know what you're missing.
Yeah!
[door closes]
Rick?
[door opens]
-[Amy] That's amazing.
-[Zach] I know.
I haven't had one that lasted
this long since I was 12.
[Amy] No wonder Rick wanted to invest.
[Zach] I feel like I'm in the porno
version of The Red Shoes.
[thud]
[Rick] Oh, my leg. Damn that hurts.
-[door closes]
-Oh, God, that hurt!
-Hey, honey!
-[Amy screams]
[Rick] No, no, it's me!
[Amy] I know it's you! Get out of here!
[Rick] Why, love?
How'd you know it was me?
It's dark in here.
[Amy] Oh, God, there's nobody else--
-[Rick] What?
-[Amy] No, Rick!
[indistinct chatter]
[Rick] Shut up!
[thuds]
-[Amy] Rick!
-[Rick] Shut up!
[door opens]
[screaming]
[grunting]
[Amy] No.
[Amy] Rick, get out!
No, stop it!
[Rick grunting]
[Amy] Stop it! Don't!
[Amy yells]
[Rick and Zach yelling]
[thud]
[Amy screams]
[phone ringing]
[sighs]
[ringing]
-Hello.
-Yeah.
-No.
What jail?
What did they arrest you for?
All right. I'll be right over.
-What's wrong?
-Zach's been arrested.
For what?
Cockfighting.
[groans]
[man] I never had the privilege
of meeting Leon Sparks.
Or Sparky,
as he was affectionately known throughout
the film community.
But his reputation for kindness,
friendship, creating excellence
was legend.
-Alex.
-Hello, Zach.
You changed your telephone number.
Look. I wanna talk to you,
for Christ's sake.
-Could we have dinner?
-No.
Alex.
I'm in trouble. I thought...
Could we just maybe go someplace
and talk?
No.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Sorry it wasn't nice seeing you again,
Zach.
-You ready?
-Anytime you are.
[horn honks]
If you feel like it, come by for dinner
tonight.
Eight o'clock.
Bye, Jake.
Bye.
[doorbell rings]
Hello, Danny.
Good evening, Mr. Hutton.
-You're looking well.
-Thank you.
They are in the living room.
They?
We thought we'd drive back through
Arizona, New Mexico.
See that part of the country, and then...
Hello.
Zach.
Zach, this is Rebecca Simms.
Zachary Hutton.
-[Zach] Rebecca.
-How do you do?
I'd do a lot better if I had a drink.
Danny?
[Danny] Banzai Sunrise.
-It pays to have roots.
-You remember Mama.
Sure do.
Hi, Marge, Harry.
Hello, Zachary.
Who gave you the black eye?
Why? Do you want to congratulate
him personally?
No. A telegram will do it.
[scoffs]
She hasn't lost her twinkle.
So, Becky, what? Are you Greg's main
squeeze?
-Squeeze.
-Yes.
Contemporary nomenclature, right, Greg?
I've heard the expression. Never used it.
Oh. Well, neither have I.
It was my first time.
So how come, uh...
I thought you were in school.
-[Marge] Summer vacation.
-[Zach] Oh, of course.
-How old are you now? Nineteen?
-Twenty.
Oh. It goes by so bloody fast.
Are you going to Brown?
[panting]
No, I quit Brown. I'm going to Juilliard.
Juilliard. Well, how about--
That's what I want. Bless you.
Greg is studying piano and composition.
I'll be damned. Mm.
I didn't know you were that interested
in music.
Probably because you never thought to ask.
That's not fair. But accurate.
Fair doesn't count? Come on, Greg.
You were only interested in rock 'n' roll,
like any kid your age.
He never gave me a clue--
he never went near a piano,
you know that. What, you want accurate?
You certainly never took the time
to tell me.
Uh, I hate to use the argument,
but I was just a kid, Zach.
Well, that's a kid's argument, Greg.
Dinner is served.
Let's see if we can get
through the salad course
without a 15-yard penalty, hmm?
[dogs barks]
[Alex] Zach would rather play
in a jazz band
than write the great American novel.
One does what one must.
But you've already written one
of the great American novels.
Hang Time is almost as great.
If you play the piano as well
as you write,
you're one hell of a musician.
Confidentially, these days.
I'm a lot better piano player
than I am a writer.
Mm-hmm.
I was only 15 and I saw
The Devil May Care six times.
-No, really?
-Rebecca's a drama major at Brown.
She just wrote and directed
her first play.
Terrific.
No, it wasn't.
But hopefully one profits
by one's mistakes.
Hopefully.
Did you? You must have made some mistakes.
A few.
[coughs]
-For instance?
-Coming here for dinner.
-I was being serious.
-So was Zach.
What were you saying about being fair,
Zach?
-Sorry, Becky.
-It's okay. Do me a favor, Zach?
-Name it, Becky.
-Don't call me Becky. I fucking hate it.
I'm truly sorry, Rebecca. It fucking
won't happen again.
Mm-hmm.
Either make more trips or get
me a bigger glass.
Yes, sir.
Mmm.
Oh, hold it.
-What is this?
-Brandy.
Brandy's good too.
Look, Marge, I know in the past
we've had our share of disagreements--
-[barks]
-Oh, sorry.
Almost sat on Harry.
Can I get you something?
A gun.
I'll see what I can do.
For what it's worth,
I didn't expect it to be this kind
of an evening.
I've had worse.
The day we broke up was worse.
Not much worse, but...
I don't think Greg has quite forgiven--
Greg has really grown up to be
quite a young pain in the ass.
Understandable when you consider that,
for about five years,
you were his only male pain-in-the-ass
role model.
How is Greg where I'm not concerned?
A little pompous. Sometimes arrogant.
Mostly... loving and pleasant
and talented.
How talented?
Greg, why don't you play something for us?
Yes, do that.
Okay.
-What'll it be, Zach?
-How about a little Buddy Holly?
How about a little Chopin?
How about a little Cole Porter?
[playing piano]
Either I'm drunker than I thought
or your son's better piano player
than I am.
-You're sweet. And you're drunk.
-Me too.
I know I've had too much to drink,
because I'm feeling sorry
for you tonight, Zach.
[exhales] Me too!
[piano playing]
I may regret this, but how can I help?
How can you...
I don't know.
I thought a lot about you.
And then when I heard about Sparky,
I just felt
I... had to talk to you, to see you.
Hmm. Scared, huh?
Scared?
Scares me getting older, friends dying.
He knew he had some terrible cancer.
Yeah, I think that's probably
why he threw Curt out.
Curt. I saw him a couple weeks ago.
He'll never get over it. He's...
Sparky probably thought
he was being noble.
Yeah, well, he was being selfish.
You don't share 20 years with someone,
then find out you're gonna die
and not share that too.
Well, I think it's pretty easy for us
to stand--
Well, it's easy to stand here in judgment
when the guy we're talking about,
by his own admission,
was an egotistical, unsympathetic,
uncharitable--
-I know.
-coldhearted, narcissistic scoundrel.
Nobody's perfect.
Right.
I'm glad you feel that way,
because I was about to suggest
that we give it another try.
We?
Are you completely off your nut?
Don't beg, Alex. It doesn't suit you.
-Oh, Zach.
-Oh, what?
There are a lot of things about you
that I would highly recommend.
But you're never gonna last with anyone.
You may settle down for a while,
but then something will happen.
You'll get scared and you'll start
to look for some thing, some place,
some... young girl to save you.
You're on a merry-go-round, Zach.
And the brass ring is just a brass ring.
It solves nothing.
I'm doomed?
You're Zach.
And you like merry-go-rounds.
Okay, troops. Time to fold the tents.
Mmm.
Barney, how about just one more itty-bitty
one for the road?
-You know what your problem is, Zach?
-Yep.
-Keys, Zach.
-Nope.
-You drink too much.
-Yep.
-Keys, Zach.
-You're probably an alcoholic.
-Yep.
-Keys!
But that's not my problem. You know
what my problem is?
I'm an addict.
-Drugs?
-Nope. Merry-go-rounds.
I am not gonna let you drive.
-You wanna go home with me, Zach?
-Yep.
All right. Let's go.
-Can't.
-Why not?
I'm just a kid.
-You're sweet.
-That too.
Give me a call if you change your mind.
I will give you a call even
if I don't change my mind, okay?
Okay.
-Good night, Barney.
-Sleep tight, sweetheart.
Good night, Miss Jones.
Oh, shit.
You drank me out of tequila.
It was a dirty job, Barney, but somebody
had to do it.
-Here.
-Thank you, Barney.
[coin clacking]
[melody music playing]
[phone rings]
-Hello?
-[Zach] Alex?
-Zach?
-I think so.
Oh, Zach, do you know what time it is?
Just a minute. Alex wants to know
what time it is--
Shh! Five after 2:00.
It's five after 2:00.
Besides being drunk, what else is wrong?
I forgot to ask you something
very important.
Yes?
What the hell was it?
-Oh, Zach, come on--
-No, no, no. I-- I-- I, re-- I remember.
Um, Alex...
Are you presently involved with anyone?
Yes.
Yes?
-Yes.
-Who?
His name is Jonas Mallard.
Sounds like a duck.
-Zach.
-Why wasn't he there tonight?
Because he's in New York on business.
Is it serious?
Yes.
Gonna get married?
We've talked about it.
I don't know whether you know it or not,
but it's bad luck to marry a duck.
Good night, Zach.
-Unless you're a duck.
-[thud]
Even then, it's no guarantee
it's gonna last. You know Barney?
Am I right? Are ducks monogamous?
-No. Swans are.
-This guy's a duck. That was Alex.
So I gathered.
Hey, Barney,
how about another one?
You know, of course, we're breaking
the law.
What "we"?
I got a mouse in my pocket.
We.
One thing's sure. Mice are not monogamous.
For sure.
-If they were, they'd be "monogomice."
-Yeah. I'll call a cab.
Okay.
I-- I don't go to hotels anymore.
I'm on their shit list.
So if your guest room is still occupied,
I'll just curl up on the bar right here.
All right.
Okay, but no throwing up in the fish tank.
I cross my heart.
-Let's go.
-Barney?
-What?
-Carry me.
Oh, shit.
[Zach screams]
I'm blind! I can't see!
All right, all right.
How did you do-- what is-- what is that?
-It's a B-12.
-Do I need it?
Did Custer need a bulletproof vest?
-[Zach grunts] Barney.
-All right. Easy. Easy.
[sobbing]
Okay, okay! God!
-Jeez!
-Okay.
-I gotta pee.
-Huh? Easy, easy. All right.
All right. Take it easy.
God!
Why did you wrap yourself in toilet paper?
[Zach] Because I was cold.
[Zach moans]
[moaning]
[panting]
I'm in a lot of trouble, doctor.
Frankly, I don't have the strength
or the courage to go on like this,
and even if I did, I wouldn't want to.
Every day, I get a little more depressed.
I get a little more desperate.
I feel like I'm worse off
than when I first started with you.
When you first started with me,
you were a mess.
[laughs]
I'm still a mess. I haven't changed.
Don't you know by now that changing
one's basic character
is next to impossible?
No. I don't know that.
Jesus, doctor if I thought
I couldn't change,
-I wouldn't come see you in first place.
-I didn't say--
-I didn't say you couldn't.
-You just said it was impossible!
-I said it was next to impossible.
-Well, shit, doctor.
"Next to" isn't that far removed.
If it were, there'd be no analysts.
Not an entirely unhappy prospect, doctor.
Did I ever tell you the story
about the frog and the scorpion?
No.
A scorpion who couldn't swim
asked the frog
to carry him across the river on his back.
The frog said, "Do you think I'm crazy?
Halfway across the river, you'll sting me
and I'll drown."
"That's not reasonable,"
said the scorpion.
"If I sting you and you drown,
I'll drown too."
Frog thought about it, said, "Climb on."
Halfway across the river,
the scorpion stung the frog.
And as the frog was drowning,
he said to the scorpion,
"But now you'll drown too."
The scorpion said, "Yes, I know."
"But that's not reasonable,"
said the frog.
And the scorpion replied,
"Reason has nothing to do with it.
I'm a scorpion. It's my character."
You know what I feel like telling you?
Yes. You feel like telling me
to go fuck myself.
And you probably will,
because that's your character.
See you next Tuesday.
[door slams]
[elevator bell dings]
[music playing]
[woman] The man was fabulous.
Absolutely fabulous.
I took one look at him,
and I just knew...
-Hi.
-Hi. You can go right in.
Thank you.
I got to go now. Okay.
-Can I help you?
-Uh, yeah.
I just happened to be in the building,
and I was intrigued
by the company name.
Is this the company name?
Yes, it is.
"Form 3, world's foremost fitness
and beauty program."
Mm-hmm
One of our clients lost 11 pounds
in three days
and was completely cured of his asthma.
-You take men?
-Mm-hmm.
Thirty-five percent of our clientele
are men.
-Really?
-Mm-hmm.
Uh, you know, the, um-- the girl who just
came in--
Emily?
Emily, yes. She certainly didn't look
to be
lacking in the fitness or beauty
department.
Well, you should have seen
her six months ago.
-Really?
-The first herbal wrap is on the house.
-Look--
-And if you give me your name,
Molly can set you up right away
for your complimentary treatment.
-Wait.
-Hello, Zach.
-Molly.
-Isn't that special?
-You two know each other.
-God!
-What are you doing?
-Working.
Molly's our number one therapist.
-Terrific. How've you been?
-Angry.
-Molly, this is silly.
-What's that?
I don't need a complimentary herbal wrap
and electro-stimulation.
-Okay.
-I just--
-I happened to be in the building.
-But it's not silly, Zach.
-It's what I do now.
-I-- I didn't mean--
[Molly] I mean, it's how I make my living.
You know, I could've sued your ass off,
Zach.
But instead I decided to get a job.
You may not approve, but it pays the rent.
I approve, okay?
If you think it's silly,
what are you doing here?
I guess, I'm getting a complimentary
herbal wrap--
-But if it's so silly--
-It's not, okay? Wrap me.
The silly little pads I've attached
to your problem areas
will make your muscles contract.
The more I increase the current...
the more your muscles will contract.
-Molly...
-For the first silly treatment,
it's not advisable to exceed plus-three.
God, I wish I didn't hate you so much,
Zach.
-M-- Molly?
-After ten silly treatments,
you should be able to handle plus-seven.
[machine buzzing]
[stuttering]
Why did you have to act like such a dick?
[Zach grunts]
Anything above plus-seven...
could be dangerous.
[Zach] Look, Molly.
[gasping]
Oh!
[screams]
Aah.
Oh!
[grunts]
Give me that!
Go fuck yourself!
[tires screeching]
[honks]
Hey! Jesus! Stop!
[indistinct chatter]
Here. Yeah.
-How much?
-Two and a quarter.
Hey!
[horn honking]
[tires screeching]
[siren wailing]
-[tires screeching]
-[crash]
[siren wailing]
[indistinct chatter on police radio]
[Zach] All you got to do is drive down
Sunset, look at the billboard.
She's representing something called Shape.
Yeah, it's a magazine. We-- we represent
it as well.
I'm telling you, you will not believe
this woman.
Yeah, well, you know that magazine is--
is throwing a big party tonight
at the Century Plaza.
You probably got an invitation.
-You think so?
-Yeah.
-Oh, God!
-You all right?
Maybe I should have something to eat.
-Coffee?
-No, that's bad.
I-- okay. All right.
-[Jake] Goddamn it!
-What's the matter?
[Jake] I can never tie these fucking ties.
Oh, God. Stop complaining.
How many times a year
do you have to put on your tux?
-You know something, Bern?
-Yeah.
One of us is wearing the wrong clothes.
Which one?
The Shape black-tie party...
is at the Century Plaza tonight.
-Uh-huh.
-The Share costume ball
is at the Century Plaza next Friday night.
[indistinct chatter]
Nice costume.
[costume bells jangling]
Is the Shape Party in here?
[indistinct chatter]
-Aladdin?
-That's what he told me.
[chuckles]
Bern, he's gonna kill me. Bernice,
it is not funny.
Okay.
[laughing]
[jazz music playing]
Get me the fuck out of here.
Jake! Jake!
-You told me it was a costume party--
-where did you get--
[laughs]
Bernice, stop it.
-Look at the lamp.
-Look at the shoes!
[both laughing]
I'm sorry. Zach, I'm really sorry.
I tried to call you several times--
-Jake.
-Howard. How are you?
Howard, this is Zach Hutton.
Zach, this is Howard Simon.
He's your host.
Howdy, Howard.
I told Zach that it was
a-- a costume party.
[all laughing]
-I tried to call you.
-You're fired.
[laughs]
Cheer up.
[All laughing]
Inside of about five minutes, I drank
14 glasses of champagne.
By the shank of the evening,
I was completely shit-faced.
[tooting]
Steamboat coming through. Excuse me.
And fearless.
[clears throat]
How do you do?
My name is Zachary Hutton, and my wish
is to fuck you.
[indistinct chatter]
I got to tell you guys. I just, I-- I must
[mumbling]
-So, what's the answer?
-[Barney] What's the question?
Can a man change his character
even if a scorpion can't?
Hmm, good question. What's the answer?
The answer is yes, providing you know
what your problem is.
I know what my problem is,
and I can't change it.
-Have you tried?
-No.
Don't you want to?
To be perfectly honest,
I haven't given it much thought.
Do you know why you don't want to?
I haven't the foggiest.
Because you don't know
what the alternative is.
-Oh, I see.
-I know my alternative.
No more young, healthy bodies
with beautiful, empty heads.
My salvation is a handsome,
experienced, healthy middle-aged woman
who's been married at least once
and who is a great deal smarter than I.
-How's Alex?
-I was just about to call her.
-Hey, Barney, do you have--
-Oh, yeah.
Thank you.
♪ I'll be dreaming ♪
[phone rings]
Hello?
-Hello, Greg?
-Who's this?
This is your stepfather. May I speak
to Alex?
Uh, no, she's gone for the weekend.
-Where?
-She asked me not to give out
that information, Zach.
Well, you're a fine young lad, aren't you?
Just please tell her I called.
Sure.
I wish he'd stay the hell out of her life.
[dog barking]
Oh.
[doorbell ringing]
-[Zach] Hi, Marge.
-Ah!
Can I come in?
Hi, Marge. I'm sorry to bother you,
but could we just talk for a minute?
[thud]
Shit!
Sorry. I didn't see the suitcase here.
-Are you going someplace?
-Yes.
-Where?
-Away.
Away where?
-Away... where you can't find me.
-Oh.
Ah! Harry!
[dog barking]
Sorry about that. Are you--
are you gonna see Alex?
What is it you exactly want, Zach?
Marge, I need to talk to your daughter.
It's very important.
Would you just... please tell me
where she is?
-No.
-Why won't you tell me?
Because if you knew where she was,
you'd screw up her life,
and then I'd have to kill you.
[clears throat] Oh, well,
that makes sense.
[clears throat]
Do you think I could have a drink?
I'm a little parched--
I'll get you some tap water.
That's fine. That would be great.
[clears throat]
Oh. Marge, thank you. Cheers.
It's good. Clear too.
Would you like a little?
[chuckles]
Ahem, look, Marge, um, I realize that
you and I over the years
haven't exactly hit it off and, you know,
you have just cause to really hate me.
But... I don't know why, I just feel that
somehow if you'd look
deep within yourself,
you might find that you have some good
feelings about me.
-Well, Marge, I-- I just think that--
-Harry.
-It's time now--
to bury the hatchet, you know?
-You left that door open--
-What.
If you let that dog run away, I'll rip
your beard off!
-Marge, I tripped. I--
-Harry? Harry!
[sighs]
[Marge] Harry? Harry? Here, Harry!
Holy Jesus. Harry. Harry.
Harry? Come on, Harry, snap out.
[Marge whistling]
Oh, God!
[Marge] Nice Harry.
[Marge] Come on, Harry!
Harry? Harry? Harry?
Marge, why don't you look out back,
okay? I'll-- I'll-- I'll go out front.
Harry!
Harry! Harry!
Harry?
-[Marge] Here, Harry!
-Harry?
-Here, Harry!
[whistling]
-[Marge] Harry.
-You find him?
[Marge] No!
-Keep looking.
-[Marge] Harry!
Harry! Here, boy.
Sorry, Harry. Stay.
Harry?
[door shuts]
[police siren wailing]
[Jake] Hi, you've reached the Fennermans.
Leave a message when you hear the beep.
[answering machine beeps]
[Zach] Jake this is Zach.
It's 2:00 in the morning.
I'm in Ventura County jail. Get me out
of here.
The arresting officer states
that you were clocked
at 134 miles an hour.
-Anything to say about that, Mr. Hutton?
-I was in a hurry, your Honor.
Me too. Five hundred dollars or 30 days.
[gavel bangs]
[indistinct chatter]
-Miss Alexander Hutton.
-What about her?
-I'm Zachary Hutton.
-Should that make a difference?
She's expecting me.
What's her room number?
-She's not in her room.
-Where is she?
She's in the arboretum.
[birds chirping]
[laughs]
[dog whimpers]
-Harry?
-[dog barks]
["here comes the bride"
playing on the organ]
Would you mind? Is this a bad time?
[priest] Dearly beloved,
we are gathered here to join
in holy matrimony
Alexandra and Jonas.
If there is anyone here who could show
just 'cause why this couple
should not be married,
let them speak now
or forever hold their peace.
Uh...
[grunts]
[people chattering]
[Zach grunts]
Come on, Zach.
Alex, you don't have to do this.
Yes, I do. Papa always said
if someone takes the trouble to ruin
your wedding,
the least you can do is walk
them to the car.
He sounds like a real old-world gentleman.
Oh, you'd have loved each other.
You could compare livers.
Do you know, your mother
missed her calling.
If she'd drop a few pounds,
I might get her a match with, uh,
Sugar Ray.
-I can't say as I really blame her.
-I always wondered what she saw in me.
Probably Papa. Could you get
Mr. Hutton's car, please?
[sighs]
-I guess I really screwed things up.
-You guess.
-You want to know why I came?
-No.
I feel like I'm drowning
and you're the only one that can save me.
-I can't save you, Zach.
-You can't?
That's not fair. I was counting on you.
You see, no matter how bad I am
or was or will be,
I keep thinking you're gonna save me.
In spite of everything,
you'll put your arms around me
and tell me it's all right,
and I'll be resurrected
because you love me and you've got
the magic.
No magic.
Yeah, but what a dream, huh?
-It's a selfish dream.
-That too,
but hey, these days I'm all I've got,
and that ain't much.
Zach, you know, I'm glad
I don't have the magic.
-How come?
-Because you'd count on it
and never look for the truth.
In spite of how it seems, I'm looking.
In the bottom of a cocktail glass?
[car door opens]
Good kill.
You know, Alex, I do love you
and I'm gonna make it.
Would it be too much to ask you to wait
until I do?
Yes.
Because you don't think I can?
Yeah, and if I do, what a guy.
Just think what you'll be missing.
[tires screeching]
Can we get married now?
We have to talk.
[music playing]
[Zach] I've never felt like this before.
I'm-- I'm seriously... unhappy.
This is not just the bush-league blues.
We're talking major-league
depression here.
I can't sleep.
[sighs]
I take pills, but they only last
a couple hours
and then I'm up at 4:00 in the morning,
pacing the fucking house or walking
on the cold
fucking beach, you know?
I'm so miserable,
I want to fucking shoot myself.
But I can't because I'm afraid to die.
How's that for fucked-up?
[crying]
So, what's the answer?
I forgot you don't have answers.
You're not the burning bush.
You just give suggestions.
Well, I need help.
I'm in the fucking dumper.
Give me a suggestion, because I know
you've got one.
I can see it in those beady little
Freudian eyes.
If an alcoholic wants me to cure him,
you know what I say?
[sighs]
That's a question.
That's not a suggestion.
-Okay. What do you say?
-First, stop drinking.
[music playing]
I don't get it.
Go home and think about it.
That's my suggestion.
["Falling Out of Love" played
by Ivan Neville]
[man on tv] We interrupt
our regular broadcast
to bring you an important announcement.
The western regional weather service
has just issued
an urgent tsunami wave warning,
due to a seismic disturbance
in the Pacific.
Waves could exceed heights
of 20 feet
and may crest at any time.
All residents in the coastal
area are urged
to be on the alert.
♪ Just trying to find my way ♪
♪ Don't know my name ♪
♪ Living day to day ♪
-Hi.
♪ Just a little boy who wants
To have his way ♪
♪ I just can't keep still ♪
♪ And I'm falling out of love ♪
♪ Falling out of love ♪
♪ Sometimes it feels ♪
♪ Like I'm running out of time ♪
♪ Sand slipping through my fingers ♪
♪ Like rivers through my mind ♪
[Zach] God, I rented this beach house
because I thought, if you're really there,
this is the best place to get in touch
with you.
I'm in pretty bad shape,
and I need some answers.
If an alcoholic wants me to cure him,
you know what I say?
First, stop drinking.
I got it!
Jake!
You won't believe it!
But there is a God! And he's a gag writer!
What the--
[all screaming]
[laughs]
What the--
Close the door, goddamn it, Jake!
Bernice will never forgive Jake
for renting me his other beach house.
But anyway, I figured it out, Barney.
You can't cure a problem until you know
what's causing the problem.
But before you can see what's causing
the problem,
you first have to remove the problem.
You gotta give up the vices to get
to the virtues.
-I could've told you that.
-Yeah? Why didn't you?
You want it to take, you got to figure
it out for yourself.
Okay, wise guy, what's my problem?
You're scared, like the rest of us.
You drink too much. You chase girls
much too much.
and you don't use your God-given talent
anymore.
-You've known that all along?
-I'm a good bartender.
Now all I have to do is figure out
how to stop being scared.
While you're at it, may I offer
a suggestion?
[Zach] Okay, open up,
I know you're in there.
I'm coming to get you!
[jazz music playing]
[saxophone playing]
The truth, was I research or recreation?
You were ravishing.
I switched you from tonic water to Slice.
-Think you can handle it?
-Yeah, that's fine.
Just keep me away from those honey-roasted
almonds.
Excuse me.
-Congratulations, Mr. Hutton.
-Oh, you read my book?
No, but since you stopped drinking,
you're a much better kisser.
[laughs]
-Hello, Miss Jones.
-Hi, stranger.
-You need any help--
-No, I'll get her. I got her.
Ow. Oh, God. Doesn't this hurt you?
Oh, God!
Rebecca, you look fetching.
-Merry Christmas, Greg.
-Merry Christmas.
-Marge!
-I'm really proud of you.
-You're kidding.
-Yes.
Hey, you guys. You're not mad, are you?
No, of course not. Congratulations, Zach.
Nice to see you both.
Watch out. He's dangerous.
-Molly.
-Zach.
-Hey, Molly--
-I'd like you to meet Steven.
-Nice to meet you. How are you?
-How are you, Steven?
-I read your book.
-Yeah?
-Mm-hmm.
-Great.
[clears throat] Thank you, uh,
-What do you do, Steven?
-I'm a fireman.
Nice move.
Curt. How are you?
I, uh-- I think you remember this lady.
How can I forget? She used to borrow
my socks.
Would you like me to get
you another drink?
Please. Good for you.
-Thanks. How's the duck?
-Oh.
Last time I heard, he was thinking
of moving to Washington
-and getting married.
-To you?
No.
Still got cold feet?
Only where you're concerned.
Alex, I've stopped drinking. I've written
a bestseller.
In my book, two out of three ain't bad.
No, but in my book, two out of three
just ain't good enough.
What would you do if I told you
that I've been celibate for six months?
Cross my legs.
[laughs]
Alex, we're made for each other.
And I'm gonna prove that to you.
One of these days, you're gonna be wearing
my socks again.
[crowd applauding]
[piano playing]
-Hey.
I think it's the best thing
you've ever written.
-Really?
-Your book set me on fire.
Rebecca, I think there's something
you should know.
Yes, Zach?
In order for me to write this book,
I had to...
change.
-Oh, Zach.
-Yes, Rebecca?
Have you ever heard the story of the frog
and the scorpion?
[man over radio] KBLA now concludes
its broadcast day.
["Star Spangled Banner" playing]
-When are you gonna grow up?
-What are you talking about?
I've stopped drinking,
I've written a bestseller,
refused to sleep with a beautiful,
lusty, aromatic young female.
In my book, that's pretty good growing up.
Oh, I suppose so.
But you're in a monogamous
relationship now.
So take it off.
[Zach] Okay, but you're not being
very patriotic.
["Falling Out of Love" playing
by Ivan Neville]