Choi Won ♬ Is it okay to laugh about it ♬
♬  Even on the hard days past ♬
♬ Because you were always there ♬
♬  Even my heart didn't know how I felt.  ♬
♬  Perhaps because you were always beside me  ♬
What are you doing?♬ From when it was ♬
You said you were coming but why didn't you come?
Won...♬ Or how it started ♬
Are you waiting for Cha Seo Hoo?♬ Or how it started ♬
♬  You and me, together ♬
You said you had gone through enough and gotten hurt enough so that you know better now.
I know Cha Seo Hoo is a bad person,
but he said he has something he needs to tell me.
So once again you're waiting here because of something that jerk said.
When Seo Hoo left me,
I wasn't able to hear anything.
I want to hear at least an apology or an explanation.
So what if you hear those words? What are you going to do with it?
I also want to hear why he sent me a rabbit doll.
There's definitely something dangerous in there, I'm telling you!
Let's go. I'm going to get rid of it completely for you.
Episode 6
Seo Hoo.
Was I very late?
I'm sorry I made you wait.
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Timeless Lovers @ Viki
What are you?
I'm in the middle of talking with Ha Na,
so don't you think it's something you shouldn't interfere with?
Go. You don't have anything to talk about with this punk.
Let's go inside.
Weren't you waiting for me?
"I'll come and pick you up in the evening."
Did you think I would wait for you because you said that?
Why? What are you, Seo Hoo?
What are you for me to wait for you?
Don't look for me again.
Did you wait a long time?
As usual, you only say what you want to say
and hear only what you want to hear.
What are you doing? Go inside.
You've become a lot stronger, Oh Ha Na.
Did you enjoy the movie?
I didn't get to watch it.
Thanks to you, I wasted the movie tickets.
No, today
the Sales team has made a big deal over nothing, that's why.
Hey. Brush your teeth first and then talk.
Why? What are you Seo Hoo?
What are you for me to wait for you?
Don't look for me again.
Won.
I wish I didn't have that rabbit doll.
Ha Na.
Should I throw that away too?
She's been like that, not moving at all.
It's the third day already.
♬ Although it was a tiring day ♬
♬ Your bright smile which I think of constantly ♬
♬  which makes me laugh for a moment ♬
♬ Just with that alone. ♬
I like the feeling. ♬ Love emerges,  ♬
Of course the best fist is the angry fist.  ♬  Although for some inexplicable reason. ♬
I'll give you one week, Oh Ha Na.♬  When like a habit the thought of you rises to the surface♬
Let's have best two out of three games on the punching machine game.
The loser has to pay for chicken feet for three years. Deal?
♬ That's precisely my song of love. ♬
Just letting you know, I got a score of 178 for it. Prepare for it.
♬  Although for some still unexeplainable reason ♬
♬ When like a habit the thought of you rises to the surface ♬
♬ That is precisely my song of love. ♬
Girl FighterUpper cut!!
Wow!
Yes!
That will be 5 dollars.
Why is it so exp- Hey! Hey! Eat a different thing!
What can I do when my mouth yearns for finer quality?
Finer quality, my butt.
There's no way you can get stronger fists as you get older.
Are you angry these days?
Shaking her is my decision. If she wavers, then isn't that her decision?
Hey! Anger or whatever is the past.
It's the age to control your emotional expression.
The machine must be out of order. No wonder, it's old.
It must be you that's old.
How do I not even get above 100?
Starting tomorrow, let's start exercising. At this age, we need to concentrate on building stamina, not strong fists.
They say you must have physical strength on your lower body.
That way, you will have a better body balance.
Hey hey. Your knee is out too far!
Watch. The knee can't go past this point
Oh it's so tiring.
I can't do it.
Let's start that tomorrow too. Together.
Tomorrow at 6. The late person has to pay for chicken feet.
Deal!
Sleep well.
The reason why you repeatedly look back on things that you've thrown away
is not because you don't know why you threw them away.
It's because you wonder maybe one day, you'll need them.
You can never know when that day will come.
- Gather you energy up! - Ugh, I'm dying.
Where did you put all the energy you got from diligently eating three meals a day for 34 years?
Hey! You keep going about my age...
Look at you! You are already huffing.
Go, go.
Ahh!
Don't push!
Hey, I'm going to fall.
Wow, how refreshing! Rest is really nice.
You really over exerted yourself from the first day, Oh Ha Na.
Are you going to fall asleep at the office?
At this age, for me to have my own room in the office,
it's not a song and a dance.
This is piece of cake.
I see, okay, okay.
I am starting a new project from today.
I've been working on it for a year on my own.
This time I am going to make the Crap Director eat it.
Crap Director.
Wow, I'd see your face on the Time Magazine soon.
Oh, hey~~
Ahh, so refreshing.
Hello, hello.
Good morning So Eun!
Sunbae, you seem to be in a good mood today.
Uhh? What is?
You seem happy about something.
Because the weather is great.
I'll put your shoes under the seat.
I'll put a cushion for you.
As a result of my research for a year,
the best suitable partner for our target
It is Jumei Global.
When did she prepare this?
That's what I am saying.
I get scared every time she does this.
-Shall we look at the slides?  -Yes.
They have 2 million customers visiting their website each day.
Not only foreign luxury products, but they also have Korean makeup products.
Through events, we are anticipating good results.
Starting tonight, we are going to work overtime.
If we can't get a contract with this company,
get ready to get your desks removed. So do it well.
That surprised me!
-Were you surprised?  -Yeah.
I don't like us taking long flights like this. We can't be alone.
What if people see?
Exactly. Outside we can't do this.
Let's stay here just a bit longer.
People don't listen to classical music these days because it's stuffy, do they?
Rather than new things I've always preferred old things.
Wow, I've also been like that recently.
I met a fan with the same preference.
Wow. I didn't know last time I saw you, but you really are a famous person.
You know me?
No, last time when you came to our company I saw you.
While you were coming out of Sunbae Won's office.
Ahh...
But, what is your relationship with Sunbae?
Our relationship is kind of deep.
Then, what kind of relationship does he have with you?
I'm a junior. A company junior.
A company junior.
-Just?  -Yeah.
Uhm...No, I am actually not sure.
I think Sunbae prefers friends over lovers.
Oh Ha Na.
- You know Unni Ha Na too?- I know, right?
Those two are a package where ever they go.
Can I ask for a favor?
Aren't you going home, Team leader?
You go home first.
I'll go once I finish this.
-Then I'll be going first.  -Good work today.
Sorry, no no to the early morning workout tomorrow.
I plan to work all night on presentation preparation.
Don't be sorry. The absentee will buy chicken feet twice.
What to do. I am so thankful.
You are genius when it comes to that kind of memory, you cold-hearted punk.
Won!
Would you bring me some cucumber from the fridge?
I think my face had gained some weight. I don't have enough cucumber.
My calves didn't used swell up even after long flight but they do now.
- You need a bottle of beer too.- Man of good sense.
You seem to be in good mood these days.
Tell me if you have something good happening.
Except about Ha Na.
Go ahead and tell me about Ha Na.
I am proud of Ha Na these days.
Why are you being cheesy out of the blue?
There was quite a worrisome issue.
But she overcame better than I thought she would.
And she seems to be living diligently as well.
- Is that all?  - Yeah.
When did she ever not live her life diligently and well?
She was, right?
Okay. You guys continue to be friends like you are playing house as kids.
Then get married when you get older.
Should I?
Huh? What's up with you?
You always beat around the bush.
What is this? What are you doing?
You are already going to work?
I have an important presentation to do today.
Oh, okay. I got it.
You leaving already? What about breakfast?
It's okay. I'll eat when I get to the office.
You should eat. If you lose weight as you get older, it makes you look older.
Ugh! I understand.
- Ha Na! Wait just a moment. Fruit, fruit, fruit!  - Geez.
So, you are wrapping it up today?
Uhh. Once I finish this presentation, I'll have some room to breathe.
Fighting, Oh Ha Na!
Shall we catch a movie tonight?
That would be nice.
How about a trilogy movie marathon from midnight to early morning?
I am sorry to keep bringing up your age.
But you would probably pass out before the first movie is over.  Let's not waste your physical energy.
How about just watch one movie cleanly and drink some beer?
Fine.
Yeah, yeah. In Ha's mother!
Yeah. Yeah.
Ah, I went out and just got back.
What?
Oh my world...
In-n Ha is getting married already?
Oh.
Honey! Do we have new tooth brush?
Uhh? Yeah, congratulations. Congrats ,congrats!
Where is the wedding venue?
Yeah.
Wow, must be nice.
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Timeless Lovers @ Viki
Tears, tears are coming out.
Will you talk to me now?
Come here. It's okay my son.
Please come out. I am in front of your house.
Oh, this song?  ♬ Now, the past things for us
For two, please!
- Alright. - Hello!
We'll get seated.
-It's nice visiting here again.  - Yeah.
-What would you like?  -We'll start with one kettle.
-I want cod pancake and fish cake soup.  -These too.
It's been a long time, hasn't it?
For Team Leader Oh Ha Na's new project!
For the day Oh Ha Na will adorn Time Magazine's page.
This is nice!
♬ Just looking at your gaze, there's no woman like you
♬ who would talk to me first It's the same for me, just like this!
Now that I think back, you were never once
close with any of my past boyfriends.
You never had a nice relationship with any of my past girlfriends either.
Why do you think that is?
Don't know.
Perhaps it's because we are seeing something for each other that both of us wasn't able to see at the time.
You are blinded when you are in love, so you can't see things clearly for yourself.
You can't see what the real problem is or what misfortune you are about to face.
But we each can see it from one step behind.
So we get upset and even think we are being wasted.
Right. All you past girlfriends were skanks.
Don't attack my past love.
Oh~ You are going to be loyal to your past women.
Right. All those women couldn't acknowledge you either.
Ahh.
Okay, okay. I won't date any woman you don't like.
-Really?  -If you take out loyalty from Choi Won, then I am only left with this face.
Nevermind! Uhh, seriously! Drink!
You really can't date,
unless I give you permission to.
Cheers!
I will see you tomorrow.
I think she'd have dumped me if I didn't have that ring.
Do you like a woman who might dump you over a measly ring?
She fits the bill for my ideal woman.
Slight dimples and white hands...
You've gone crazy.
I can say this for sure being the only married man here.
Once you are married,
they all are the same.
We'll see about that.
What is your ideal woman, Sunbae Won?
You have those when you are young.
Come on! Slim body? Small face?
You are playing again.
Oh by the way, about Unni Ha Na...
What is Unni Ha Na's ideal man?
Won, my ideal man...
That's because you don't know...
I will find my ideal man with a kiss.
Kiss?
Ideal man is usually described with details such as the height
and how his face looks. Aren't these the sort of thing?
I will think about on the first date whether I can kiss him or not.
If I can't then he will be scratched from my ideal man.
Give up on your romance novels. You're a serious case.
Within the pool of guys who passed the first round.
I will date with the guy who makes my heart pounds and make my head hazy.
That kind of love...
Do you even know it ruins peoples' lives?
It makes hard for the people around to watch the person being ruined too.
Even so, someday...
I want to experience that kind of love.
Crazy love.
Cha Seo Hoo
See you later.
Cha Seo Hoo Delete Conversation
Delete
So Eun
Yes, So Eun.
An arranged blind date?
Yes.
If I tell you it's an arranged blind date, I was worried you wouldn't come because you might be uncomfortable with it. That's why I didn't tell you.
So Eun, thank you but I don't do arranged blind dates.
I have no thoughts nor time for blind dates.
I'm sorry. I'm going first.
Unni, he said you two know each other.
I was also curious what kind of relationship you two have.
He knows me?
Oh, he's here. Over here!
I asked her.
I wanted to meet you, and I needed to meet you.
What relationship do they have?
You've built a strong wall that I can't even get close to you.
Did Choi Won make it that way?
Did So Eun plan this meeting?
I said I wanted to give this to you personally, so she said she's going to have us meet.
I think she really likes Choi Won.
What exactly do you want from me?
You suddenly show up after all these years. What do you want?
Is the wall finally having a crack?
You're still the same. You make judgments by yourself,
and digging around by yourself.
I realized something I didn't know.
That I am endlessly thinking of you.
Whenever I am walking by myself, driving,
whenever it's snowing like crazy or the sun is shining so brightly, I think of you.
Even if I just hear someone talk in Korean in the heart of New York,
because I wanted to hear your voice,
I think I'm going out of my mind.
I realized that reason.
You were the one that was dearest to me in my life.
The time we were together was too hot and profound,
that whoever I date couldn't compare to that.
I want to meet Oh Ha Na again. I need to meet her.
That's why I came back.
What? Who?
Cha Seo Hoo?
Ha Na is with Cha Seo Hoo right now?
Where is that place? Where is it?
I know it was hard on you.
But can you be so sure that you had worse than me?
Say something. Whether you curse or resent me, just say something, anything. In front of me.
I won't talk to you.
Why? Because you might waver?
What?
You're using all your strength to push me away.
I can see everything, Ha Na.
You... really...
Oh Ha Na! Where are you, Oh Ha Na?
Ha Na! Oh Ha Na!
Choi Won's here.
Ha Na! Ha Na! Where are you?
Oh Ha Na!
Whenever Oh Ha Na goes, Choi Won comes to find you anytime.
I'm going first.
Don't think you know everything.
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Timeless Lovers @ Viki
The phone you are calling cannot be reached.
Oh Ha Na
Cha Seo Hoo
It's me, Choi Won. Where are you?
What are you doing now?
I told you not to appear in front of Ha Na, didn't I?
Have you never thought that you acting like this is something you shouldn't do for Ha Na's sake?
What?
If not for you, Ha Na and I wouldn't turn out this way. Have you never thought of that?
If you didn't hurt Ha Na, things wouldn't turn out this way.
That's not right. You took away the chance for me to prevent Ha Na from getting hurt.
Don't make me laugh. You abandoned Ha Na!
No! I didn't abandon Ha Na!
And you're still the same, getting involved in our relationship.
I'm telling you this again, Choi Won.
You are someone who doesn't have the right to block me.
You're wrong.
You would never be able to go to Oh Ha Na.
I will definitely stop that from happening.
It's my first time seeing him that angry.
Unni, what should I do?
Ha Na dated Cha Seo Hoo.
Pardon me?
Cha Seo Hoo, to both Ha Na and Won,
could be the biggest wound.
Ah.
Ha Na! Hey, Oh Ha Na!
Why are you not still up at this time? Are you not going to work?
Work? What time is it, Mom?
It's almost 8 o'clock. How can you still be like this?
Are you really not going to work?
I need to get to work!
Hurry up!
52 missed calls 35 new messages
Oh, Assistant Hong. What's wrong?
Team Leader, why can't I reach you?
What's wrong?
Yesterday, there was a huge problem because Jumei Global has, all of a sudden, sent additional provisions.
Oh, really?
Fortunately, Team Leader Hwang and Director Byeon
have resolved it well, so I don't think it would pose a huge problem.
That's a relief.
Alright then. I'll see you at work.
You definitely can't go to Oh Ha Na.
Because I will stop you no matter what.
Manager Yoon, I'll drive.
Hmm? Ok.
I've grabbed the handle tightly.
Where should I take you?
I will accompany you wherever you want to go.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry, because I took care of it well.
You're in-charge of the marketing. Just hand it over.
Yes, I'm sorry.
You can go now.
Thank you.
Are you okay?
You're eating well, right?
Yeah. Still, thanks to you guys I'm fighting through this.
Chang Soo... never mind.
What does it matter if that person's not here?
I... only need you guys.
Yeah forget him! Forget!
What's the big deal about men?
To our 17 years of friendship,
- Cheers!  -Cheers!
Hey, Oh Ha Na!
What is Choi Won doing?
My first love, Choi Won!
Tell him to come out. It has been a while. I want to see his face.
He can come out and pay for the alcohol bill.
Even more grateful if buys an insurance policy.
Really?
Then... I'll ask him to buy an insurance policy for me.
Hey, mirror. I need to see a mirror for a second.
Why isn't he answering?
I'm sorry, because of me.
No, I'm sorry for yelling at you yesterday.
Is it okay for me to ask why you got so mad?
Who is Cha Seo Hoo?
I guess I can't know everything that goes on between you and Unni Ha Na.
But you look like you're worried.
Worried?
Although I don't know what it is,
in my eyes, it seems like my chance to get closer to you.
The most important thing for me is the way to get closer to you.
How is it that you always show all of your feelings?
Because if I hide my feelings, then the other person wouldn't know my heart.
Because then there's a chance that I might lose that person.
Oh, Won!
Hey, Won changed a lot.
Jeong Mi.
Chang Soo, Chang Soo, Chang Soo.
The extravagant guy is here!
Forgive me, Jeong Mi.
Why are you doing this?
I want to start over again with you.
So you changed you mind?
Rather than changing my mind
I realized what I didn't know.
I can't live without you!
You can't live without your mother!
But I realized my mom has my dad.
I needed you.
I'm sorry, Jeong Mi, because I'm so immature.
I gave you huge pain, Jeong Mi! I deserve to die!
You only know now?
Aigoo.
Chang Soo has matured. He has matured.
You did well, Chang Soo.
Yeah, what does it matter if you're late. You can just start over again.
I can't live without you either.
It turned out well for you guys!
Good for you!
Don't be like that in the future!
Why are you crying, too?
If you realized something you didn't know,
can love also be turned around?
Don't think that what you know is everything there is.
It's not that I changed my mind,
but I realized something I didn't know.
I realized something I didn't know.
This project to begin between us, Tandy, and Cha Seo Hoo,
is projected to be a three-month long project that will be of much profit to us.
It's a collaboration project between the country's hottest celebrity and Korea's representative shoe brand.
From Tandy, Team Leader Oh Ha Na will be in-charge of this project.
Cha Seo Hoo personally requested her.
I'm sorry?
- Do well. - Excuse me, Director Byeon.
Because I'm busy with the Chinese project, I don't think that I'll be able to oversee this project.
But why? Cha Seo Hoo specifically said that he wanted you, though.
Dae Bok!
What's the problem?
The thing is...there's something I need to ask you.
What is it? Tell me.
It's my parents' wedding anniversary next week.
Oh, yeah. It's around this time, isn't it.
I want to send them on vacation but,
you know how I'm a bit lacking.
Ok. I'll get you the plane ticket. Give it to them as a present.
I should prepare a present too.
Thank you, Hyung. I really hope my sister fixes her personality and dates you.
I love you.
Hey! It's gross. It's gross, you punk.
Okay. So I got Hyung, now Oh Ha Na.
Hey Noona, I'm going to your company.
There you go.
Okay. I'll give you gift certificates for the present, just think about what you want to buy.
I'm busy with office work right now, so I'll send it through one of my hoobaes.
Ok.
Team Leader, what should I do?
Director Byeon is going on a business trip to China tomorrow, but
no one from our team is going and he said he's just taking the design team.
What?
Team Leader Hwang?
Are you really going on a business trip to China tomorrow?
Yes. Director requested me to come.
Why are you making a move without even discussing it with the buyer, the marketing team?
We're in a meeting right now.
If you're going to raise your voice, lets talk somewhere else.
You're dating these days, right?
Why are you talking about that all of the sudden?
You are famous for blanking out at work whenever you have a problem with a guy.
What did you say?
Omo. It seems it's only you who doesn't know.
Your boyfriend made a ruckus at the wedding of your company junior, you had a scandal with a younger intern,
and your famous boyfriend keeps poking his nose into your office, company, and work.
Everyone at work knows that you can't maintain a clear line between official and private matters.
Since the last PPT,
did you not realize what is happening at work?
How would you know, when you are so preoccupied with other things?
This is work. You know that even if you endure with all your strength, it could end in an instant, right?
Stop exaggerating because of your dating matters and get your head together, Team Leader Oh Ha Na.
And at the company,
we will directly carry on the case with Director Byeon.
You worked hard till now.
It wasn't that I didn't know, but I forgot.
Even through cracks,
wind that can swallow up everything can come in.
What the thirty-four-year old Oh Ha Na has to handle
is not only a love full of scars.
Oh, Father! Where are you going at this hour?
Won! Good thing I met you here.
I went to a reunion few days ago snd came home at dawn.
She keeps nagging me about it for days.
Why? Did you drink a lot that night?
I'm going to drink from now. Do you have time?
Of course.
She says with words that she doesn't care, but when are even the smallest of something she can nag me with,
"So you felt sad? That's right.
Your first love is now alone after a divorce. Of course you should help her".
She keeps getting on my nerves.
Mother is being jealous. You should understand.
I find it nice to see that you're still fighting over love.
What do you mean fighting over love?
How can this be a melodrama? This is a thriller.
- Father.- What?
I'm jealous.
These kids are still like this even after turning thirty-four.
How did you two never change from when you still were in school?
That's right.
How did you two never change from when you were still in school?
Wow, Kang Na Yeong is so persistent.
Last time, she wanted to do a three-party meeting at the cathedral.
Now, she told the kids that we should play a truth game.
- Truth game?- Yeah.
I don't think you can get away from Na Yeong.
- You should continue on with what you were talking about. - What?
Truth game. So what did you do?
Na Yeong asked again. What kind of person is Choi Won to you?
So?
What are you expecting?
Do I have to?
I answered her honestly.
Until I die, Choi Won
will be a far important person than my boyfriend,
husband, or family.
I wished we will stay that way. I'm being sincere.
You bastard.
Let's go.
You bastards!
You bastard!
Why can't I like Oh Ha Na?
Why can't I?
Hey!
Why?
Stop getting beaten up. Who are the kids who hit you?
Tell me. I will avenge you.
It's your fault.
Why? Why is it because of me?
Why? Are there iljins (kids who do bad things such as drinking or smoking) who are after me?
Did they pick a fight because you are my friend?
So because it's troublesome, are you going to say
"I'm never going to love you" again?
I
won't love you either.
Don't worry, Choi Won.
If you knew back then about my secret I couldn't tell you,
would you have been happier?
Even the times when you got hurt because of love
and had difficult times,
would I have been able to stop that?
Even now, Oh Ha Na...
If you find out everything that you didn't know about,
will I be able to protect you?
Can I
love you
now?
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Timeless Lovers @ Viki
- Won.- Yeah.
Ha Na, I'm here.
I'll go to you. Stay still and don't move.
Okay.
♬  I'm standing right next to you  ♬
♬  But you always look far away ♬
♬  Somewhere in my heart,  ♬
♬  the word that I kept for a long time  ♬
♬  I love you, the countless days when I practiced  ♬
♬ You were always  ♬
♬  a spring-like person to me  ♬
Found you, Oh Ha Na.
My arm falls asleep. ♬  I know you better than anybody else in the world  ♬
♬ The time I've loved you  ♬
This, this!
Seo Hoo...
I missed you. A lot.
Where are you?
When I realize what I didn't know,
will I be able to turn love around?