(Roscoe Lee Browne)
This is the story
of how a person
got from point A
to point Z.
Some call it fate,
others, chance.
But whatever
you call it,
it sure is an interesting
thing to ponder, don't you think?
The twisted paths
our lives follow.
How did you get here?
The place where you are
right now at this very moment.
What series of events
Brought you to this place?
At this specific
point in time?
Where are you in life?
Are things turning out
the way you'd planned?
And By the way,
when was the last time
you spoke with
your parents?
Don't you think
you ought to give
them a call?
To thank them
for the set of circumstances
that Brought
them together,
at a certain place,
at a certain
moment in time,
when you
were created.
U hh,
what were we
talking about?
How you
got here.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ,
I can't believe
I'm still so...
uh,
Stoned?
Yeah!
A glass of orange juice
sure would hit the spot
aBout now, wouldn't it?
And some Tostitos.
That's it!
Oh, man!
That's exactly
what I'm thinking!
OJ and Tostitos!
Jesus!
It's like you're
reading my thoughts or something!
I am.
Whoa.
So go on.
What am I thinking about now?
Well, there are many
thoughts racing through
your head.
The first concerns
the orange juice and Tostitos.
Yeah.
And the second,
the second thought,
oh, how it vexes you.
Uh-huh.
What is it?
It is this.
Why are you having a conversation
with Roscoe Lee Browne?
Ha!
Roscoe Lee?
Holy shit!
You're famous!
Yes, I am.
I can't fucking
believe I'm having a conversation
with Roscoe
Lee Browne!
Okay. Ready
for numBer three?
You bet I
am, Roscoe.
Your third thought
is simply this. ;
[Both]
How in the hell
did I end up
on a ferris wheel?
How did
you know that?
Because, you
fucking pothead,
you're talking
to yourself.
[Gasp]
Shit. How the hell
did I get here?
[Video game music]
[Jane, stoned]
I guess mayBe it was
a little early in the morning to
Be getting stoned.
But whatever,
you know.
It's not like
I just sit around
collecting checks
from my parents or something.
I did that regional
soda ad a while Back,
Doctor Bjorn's Famous
Old-Fashioned Root Beer.
MayBe you saw
it? Anyhow, Between that
and unemployment I
get By. Bla-Bla-Bla.
All I know
is this game is
so fucking cool
when you're high.
They say a true pothead
stops getting the munchies
after a certain point.
I mean, a true pothead
wouldn't even say
the word "munchies." I don't know
what the true
pothead would say,
"Munchos" or "hungries"
or something.
[Chewing noises]
At any rate, I still
love to eat when I'm high.
So fuck you
if you're too cool
to get hungry
when you're stoned.
My free one year supply
of Doctor Bjorn's. Neat, huh?
I n the six months
I've lived with my roommate, Steve,
I've never seen
him get high.
[Bell rings]
Not once.
He even kind of looks down
on me for doing it.
God, you are
so pathetic.
Huh?
Here's the deal
with Steve.
He scares me.
Oh, hi, Steve.
See what I mean?
Steve's one of those
"Dress in costume
and wait in line
for Star Wars" types,
But angry.
Real anti-social.
I've always tried
to stay on Steve's good side,
who knows what can
happen with a weirdo like that?
[Gasping]
Mm!
[Cheerful music]
I know he made
that sign telling me not to,
But I had a counterplan.
A really good counterplan.
I would Bake
Steve some more cupcakes.
Some even
Better cupcakes.
[Monkey screeching]
And then,
I recognized
the true nature
of the cupcakes
I had consumed.
Oh, shit.
[Techno music]
[Steady Buzzing]
[Gong]
Oh, fuck.
Listen, Jane.
I really busted my ass
getting you this
audition so please, please, please
don't fuck it up.
It seems like you don't even give
a shit about
any of this.
Do you?
Do you even give a shit?
I give a shit.
Plan... need a plan.
My plan.
NumBer one.
Buy more pot.
You know, so I can make more
cupcakes for Steve.
NumBer two. ; use
the money Steve left
for the power Bill to
purchase said pot.
That way I
can Bake some fresh cupcakes
Before he gets Back.
Then I'll go
to my audition.
I mean, numBer three. ;
go to my audition.
I've never Been to an audition
this stoned Before.
But I'd Be willing to wager
that I'd Be damned good
Because I'll Be even
more in touch with my creative self
That's not really
a part of the plan. Scratch that.
Four. ; hit the cash machine,
zip on over to pay that power Bill,
pick up cupcake
supplies at the store
and head on Back
to home Base to Bake 'em up.
Not bad... for a person
who happens to be quite stoned.
[Doorbell]
You're baked.
No.
What makes
you think that?
J ust, you
know, the usual.
Actually, you
better make it a full ounce.
I 'm gonna
be making some cupcakes.
You got it.
(dealer)
What's going on over there?
Who's there?
Is someone in my apartment?
Man, you really
are stoned.
NumBer one. ;
Buy more pot.
You're like
40 short.
Can I just...
you know...
Goddamn it, Jane,
this is the last time.
You have to pay
me back today.
No problem-o.
I'm marking it down...
in the book.
I just gotta hit
the cash machine, my man.
(dealer)
It's all aBout capitalism
and shit like
that, you know?
Who creates the joBs?
Where do they come from?
The profits I make, for example,
trickle down through the economy
in ways I can't even comprehend.
It makes sense.
I'm totally vibing you, dude.
Yeah, simple Reaganomics
apply to the production of hemp.
Well, I don't think that really
qualifies as Reaganomics, but...
What are you
talking about?
Just because
weed isn't taxed
doesn't mean it exists in
some sort of,
you know, laissez faire paradigm
or whatever.
Did you just use "paradigm"
in a sentence?
Yeah, man.
I mean, what you do
is great and all,
God bless you
for it, but it sounds
like plain old market
capitalism to me.
It's Reaganomics.
Trust me.
What about it is Reaganomics?
The black market isn't taxed.
Listen, Jane,
you're fucking stoned
and I happen to be very knowledgeable
about this.
Whoopee! You own a UV lamp.
Let's start the revolution!
What the fuck do you know about
economics anyway?
Well... I majored in economics
in college
and graduated
fucking Summa.
I think I know a thing or two
about it.
I thought you
were an actress.
Economics didn't
really work out.
This is
where I'll be.
Meet me there with the money at
three o'clock.
Yeah.
Okay.
(Jane)
What is this?
I 've never even heard of half of
these movies.
(Jane)
Oh.
Actually, my
roommate's hosting this
science fiction nerd convention
this weekend
with his buddies flying in from
Toledo and...
Hey!
Three o'clock!
Meet me in Venice
with the money
at three.
Do not make me send
my associates over here
to collect
the hard way.
You mean,
like kill me?
No, Jesus.
Of course not.
So you'll probably just break my
arms, then?
Break your arms? Janey, what
the fuck?
I'm a dude
who sells weed,
I'm not Tony
fucking Soprano.
Well, what then?
[Sigh]
I don't know.
Take your furniture,
or something.
H mm.
So, Jane,
what's the deal
with your roommate?
Steve?
What about him?
He gives me
the creeps.
[Gasps]
I think he might be one of those
skull fuckers.
Know what
I'm saying?
I bet that dude
fucks skulls,
with candles
and shit.
[Gasps]
Oh my God!
You're right!
He's a fucking freak.
So, listen.
It would be a shame if you didn't pay
me back today,
and in addition to taking
your furniture,
I had to tell
your roommate
how you spent the cash for
the power bill.
[Mouths silently]
[Techno music]
[Cell phone rings]
[Cries out]
Hello?
(Kyle)
Jane?
Hey!
Is this...?
Who is this?
It's Kyle.
Oh, hey, baby,
what's up?
You asked me
to call you
to remind you to go
to that audition?
Are you stoned?
Stoned?
It's fucking 10.;45
in the morning.
Know what, Jane?
This isn't really working out.
I-I don't understand.
You're speaking in riddles.
Kyle, you need to
listen very carefully
to what I 'm saying and stop trying to
confuse the issue.
[Shrill siren]
What? Wait, Kyle!
I can't hear you!
Kyle! Hold on!
I just have to... Shut up!
Oh, shit.
[Grunts and groans]
[Alarm stops]
[Breathes heavily]
Kyle? You still there?
Now what am
I gonna do?
I can't.
I daren't.
I really shouldn't.
[Cries out]
The government weed.
I was saving the government
weed for a special occasion,
But the government weed will fetch
a fair price on the open market.
A very fair price.
[Cash register ring]
MayBe just enough
to Bail me out of this jam.
NumBer three. ;
Go to my audition.
[Engine starts]
[Car screeches]
[Motor running]
(groans)
[Cars honking]
[Cries out]
Whoa.
That was intense.
[Breathes heavily]
Getting on?
I've never ridden
a bus in L.A. Before.
This is gonna be fun.
Yeah, you're in
for a real treat.
[Shout and thud]
[Groan]
Hey I You squashed
BoBBy's car.
[Breathes heavily]
He spent weeks putting
that together.
[Crying]
Hey, right on.
Look what you've done.
(woman)
I saw her. She just
fell right over.
She didn't even try to stay up.
Hey! One
thirty-five!
Okay.
Hold on.
Get up.
I'm trying.
There's something
wrong with her.
There's nothing
wrong with me, lady.
What was it doing on the
floor anyway?
It wasn't on the floor,
fucking pothead.
You knocked it out of his hands.
I saw it.
I'm sorry.
That's not gonna bring his car back.
I think she's
on drugs.
He built that for
his grandfather,
in the hospital.
Hey, lady!
One thirty five!
I'm getting it!
[Shout and thud]
[Yells indistinctly]
Hey!
[Breathes heavily]
That was a close one.
(Jane)
"Come on, Frank.
"You know
I love surprises.
That's a fact. I'm always willing
to make exceptions."
What a piece of shit.
"Come on, Frank.
"You know
I love surprises.
That's a fact. I 'm always willing
to make exceptions?"
"I'm always willing
to make exceptions!"
[Laughs and applause]
(shouts)
"I'm always willing
to make exceptions!
[Laughs and applause]
(shouts)
"I'm always willing
to make exceptions!!"
[Loud laughs, cheers and applause]
[Breathes heavily]
[Alarm goes off]
(Jane)
Four. Hit the cash machine.
Wha...? I had over a thousand dollars
in this account!
Oh, yeah.
Oh, no!
(distorted)
Take your furniture or something like that.
No! Not my bed!
Not my Sleep Number bed!
(security guard)
Hey I
[distorted gasp]
You forgot
to sign in.
[Breathes heavily
and wheezes]
"Come on, Frank. You know I
love surprises."
[Loud slam]
[Gasps]
Have a seat.
[Sigh]
Hi.
[Music]
Do you have
any gum?
Uhm,
I, uh,
wait.
[Chuckles]
[Gasps]
Holy shit! Where'd this come from?
Do you want some?
No, thank you!
No, no, no.
Seriously. I could really use the cash.
[Quietly]
No, I don't.
200 bucks.
No, I don't want any.
No. I don't want it.
[Chuckles awkwardly]
[Clears throat]
[Loud]
I 'm really
stoned. Sorry.
(male voice, echoing)
Janel Janel
Yeah!
Yes, here!
Are you ready?
You betcha!
Hello.
Hi! I'm Jane.
It's nice to meet you.
I, um, heard
a lot about you.
Excuse me?
[Chuckles]
Nothing.
Whee!
Are you alright?
I'm fantastic!
How are you?
[Dryly]
I'm fine.
Great!
[Meow]
Hang on a second.
What?
Huh?
Did you just
say something?
Who, me?
Yes.
I'm sorry. I didn't realize
I had spoken.
Are you ready?
I sure am.
Okay.
[Clears throat]
(yelling)
"Come on, Frank!
You know
I love surprises!"
I'm gonna stop
you right there.
I want you to do it again,
but this time,
pull it
way back.
Okay. Sure.
Sure. You got it.
[Clears throat]
(robotic voice)
"Come on, Frank. You
know I love surprises."
What are
you doing?
I'm pulling it back.
Not that much. Can't you find
some middle ground?
You better believe
I can find a middle ground!
Middle ground
is my middle name!
[Crash, glass smashing]
Thank you.
So how'd I do?
You did some very interesting work.
Really?
Yes!
[Chuckles]
Well, thanks.
You have a wonderful day.
Hey, let me
ask you something.
Do you want to
buy some pot?
Are you trying
to sell me drugs?
Well...
Young lady, have
a seat outside!
Gee, you don't
have to yell.
Sit!
Here?
In the
waiting area!!
BoB I Get
in herel
[softly]
Tried to sell me marijuana.
Hey! Guys, I
was just kidding.
[Soft and indistinct]
She tried to
sell you what?!
[Heavy rock music,
male voice sings]
# Do you rememBer
Anyone here #
# No, you don't rememBer
Anything at all #
[door thud]
# Never woke up #
# There's a party
In my mind #
# I'm hoping
Never stops #
# There's a party
Up there #
[music stops]
I'm taking
a shit!
Hold on!
I'm shitting!
I 'm just
taking a shit!
Still shitting!
Nothing to worry about.
I 'm just taking
a big old dump.
That's it.
All done.
I'm finished.
You got nothing on me!
Nada! Zilcho!
Go ahead and frisk me!
Give it your best shot!
Hello there, Smiley.
(male voice)
H i, Jane.
[Gasps]
[Terrifying roar]
(dealer)
Meet me in Venice at three.
You better
get going.
I'm way ahead of
you, Smiley. Way ahead of you.
Shelly!
[Phone rings]
(recording)
This is Shelly.
Please leave a message.
[Beep]
(Jane)
Hey, Shelly I Guess whol
So, listen. I'm
looking for a ride
out to Venice for this Hemp
Festival thing.
And it sounds
cool, right?
Anyway, I thought
you might dig it.
But I guess
you're not there.
U m,
Jesus, Shelly, I'm so fucking stoned
you wouldn't believe it!
Call me.
(Angela, recorded)
Hi, please leave a message
for me or Tony
after the Beep.
[Beep]
U h,
who is
this again?
[Phone rings]
(M uriel)
Hello?
Mrs. Green?
Yes.
It's Jane!
Who?
Jane! I studied
clarinet with you!
It doesn't really ring a...
Hmm, I, I don't...
Brevin Ericson.
[Scream]
[Sigh]
Oh, boy.
(Roscoe)
Shall we say a few words
aBout Brevin Ericson?
Shall we say a few words about love?
[Phone rings]
For Brevin Ericson
is completely,
100% head over heels in love.
[Phone rings]
Perhaps it's difficult
for you to comprehend
how anyBody could Be
so passionately inclined toward
someone like this.
But do not judge
her too harshly.
After all, how was she to know they
were pot cupcakes?
And ask yourselves,
who amongst you
might not have
done the same?
Who are we to judge heartBeats in a
young man's heart?
(Steve)
Do you want Lightning Strikes Thrice?
(Brevin)
Yeah.
Do you want Secret Secret Agents?
I already have...
Exactly.
Dude, your roommate
is kind of hot.
You're kidding,
right?
[Soft snoring]
[Jane chuckles]
You're so good.
Nol
[laughs]
Oh, Brevin I
You're Beating me.
Damn it I
[shout]
Oh, Brevin,
right in there.
Oh I
[laughs]
Oh, yeah.
But...
[clears throat]
I thought you
had a boyfriend.
We're kinda taking a break right now.
Mm-hmm.
What's that got
to do with anything?
I 'm talking about something bigger
than our petty yearnings.
Of course.
[Clears throat]
So are we doing
this or what?
Well...
Come on, man. It's going to be
fucking transformative.
It sounds great.
I just...
What?
[Pke]
I, uh...
So, you are sure you want to come to
the dentist with me?
Absolutely, man.
Absolutely.
Let me just drop you off at a coffee
shop or something.
No, not necessary,
my good man.
I'm really looking
forward to it.
So last week they worked on
my left side.
Today they're gonna
finish on my right.
And I tell you, Jane, they really get
in there deep with the scraping.
A deep scraping?
Yeah.
That sounds
fucking awesome.
Maybe I
should get one.
I think you need
an appointment.
Oh, yeah.
An appointment.
Yep, that's pretty
funny I guess.
I don't even know
what I'm laughing at.
So, how much do you think you'd need?
I don't know.
Like five...
Dollars?
Yeah, I need
to borrow $5.
Well, what then?
Like $500?
Yeah, that
should do it.
Really?
Hey, if you can't,
it's no biggie.
No, I can swing that.
Really?
You're gonna pay
me back, right?
Absolutely.
Of course.
My wallet's in the glove box.
Get it for me?
I may have five C notes right here.
That would be
so fucking great.
Nope. I don't
have it.
We're gonna have to stop at a machine.
Why do you need
500 dollars again?
Well...
I don't think Steve
would fuck a skull.
Why do you keep it in the glove box?
What?
Your wallet.
It's too thick.
It hurts my butt when I 'm driving.
That makes
total sense.
Hey!
What?
Oh I I've Been
to that housel
Which house?
That one back there!
An old college
professor of mine lives there.
Really?
[Gasp]
Yeah.
He was a pretty
good dude.
What'd he teach?
Marxist studies.
Yup.
He introduced me to some pretty
out there concepts.
Some pretty
radical ideas.
So, [clears throat]
Were you, like, seeing him?
What do you mean,
"seeing him?"
Were you
seeing him?
Do you mean
like dating him?
Yeah.
Ew! He was a fucking
Marxist, man!
Marxist?
Why would you even ask something
like that?
Oh.
There's a space.
Where?
Right there, man!
[Tires screech]
Come on, dude!
We don't want to be late
for that dentist
appointment of yours!
Uh, right, right.
Right.
[Thud]
You comin' or what?
Yeah.
So are you scared?
About what, the dentist?
No, I've never really been bothered
by going to the dentist.
It would freak the shit out of me
right now if I had to go in there.
I don't think
I could handle it.
I kind of like it.
I mean, it's not like I'm a masochist
or anything, it's just,
well, in a way, it
makes me feel like,
yeah,
my teeth are being taken care of,
you know?
It make me feel...
prosperous.
I'm sorry, were you talking
about something?
Um,
Oh, yeah. Great.
It makes you feel prosperous
or something.
[Sigh]
I'm bored.
Ericson?
That's me.
Okay, I guess I will see you
in a little bit.
[Singing]
Till we meet again
Okay.
He's not my boyfriend
or anything.
Just a friend.
In case you were wondering what
my relationship to him was.
Or not.
[Slurping]
How's it going?
[Functional music, drill,
and baby crying loud]
Thanks, Gina.
Oh! Thank
fucking God!
This has been
the longest, dullest...
most uncomfortable thing I can remember
ever doing.
I really thought I was gonna die
of boredom.
I gotta pay still.
Oh, come on.
Can't we go already?
(Brevin)
Hey, Jane. What time
do you think it was
that I picked you?
[Mumbles indistinctly]
What was that?
Hey.
Why don't you come over here while
your friend's talking to you?
Young lady, come here.
Come here!
Look at me.
I'm not playing games here.
It's really bright out, officer.
Would you mind removing your hand
from your forehead?
It's really bright out.
What's your name?
Uh...
Christy?
You don't sound too sure of that.
No, it's Christy.
Well, Christy,
how come your friend just called you
Jane a second ago?
Jane's, uh, my...
religious name?
Your religious name?
Am I under arrest?
Why would you be
under arrest?
Have you done something I should
know about?
No, l... shit.
I mean, shoot!
Sir, do you mind opening your
trunk for me?
My trunk?
No. Wait, excuse me. We called you
because... my car...
Now, Christy,
am I gonna find whatever kind of drugs
you're on in here?
Christy.
Chris-ty.
Oh, Jesus
Christ, Jane!
Yeah?
Her name's not Christy,
it's Jane.
I don't even know why you're
doing that.
What do you have in here, son?
I don't know.
Just some stuff.
Folders that
I was supposed
to Bring to my dad's office
But didn't Because he's an ass.
What's that?
A tennis racket.
And that is a tennis Ball. I wish I
had more, But my dog eats them.
Jack head, paper clips,
shoes,
Hello.
Hi.
You're a little early.
Well, are you coming in or what?
Huh.
(Shirley)
Peter's not Back from the airport yet.
So why don't you just have a seat and
I 'll go get it for you?
Okay.
Would you like something to drink?
Uh, do you have any lemonade?
Oh, no. I 'm sorry.
How about some orange juice?
Yeah, that sounds good actually.
All right.
Are you hungry?
Well... now that
you mention it,
I wouldn't mind something to
munch on.
You know, like chips or whatever.
Well, let me see what I can find.
[Sigh]
Here we go.
Thanks.
What's with the corn?
Excuse me?
Oh, that's a photo of Peter's.
I suppose that's his idea of avant
garde or something.
How long have you been Peter's T.A.?
Who?
Peter.
Oh, you mean
Professor Harwood.
Yes.
Well, for quite a while now.
I guess it didn't work out with
that other girl.
I guess not.
Well, it's very nice to meet you, uh...
Jane.
Jane. I 'm Shirley,
Peter's mother.
Shirley, of course.
Peter talks about you all the time.
He does?
Oh, yeah.
Constantly.
[Gulping]
[Sigh]
I 'll just go and
get what you came for,
so that you can
be on your way.
That is where corn chips come from.
Hmm, maybe old Professor Harwood
is onto something.
He probably really loves corn,
and all corn related products.
I mean, isn't that what
you're supposed to put in a frame?
Things you love?
I'm gonna do that.
When I get home,
I'm gonna frame
a Bunch of stuff I love.
Like lasagna.
I love lasagna.
It's so good, and cheesy.
You know who else loves lasagna?
Garfield.
Man, that cat really
loves lasagna.
MayBe I should put
a picture of Garfield in a frame.
As a kind of shorthand way of saying
I love lasagna.
That would Be
so fucking inside.
Or how aBout a photo
of President Garfield?
Oh, shit. That'd
Be totally meta.
People would Be all like,
"Jane, why do you have a photo
of President Garfield
on your mantle?"
And I'd Be like
"Because I like lasagna, of course."
[Siren]
Oh, my,
what happened?
Did you fall?
Yes, that's exactly
what happened.
I was reaching for something and
I kind of rolled off.
Well, are you
all right?
Oh yeah,
I 'm fine.
Are you hiding
from someone?
Of course not.
Why would you ask that?
It seems like you're hiding
from somebody.
I don't know what you're talking
about, Shirley.
Well,
here you go.
Great. Thanks
a lot.
Now I 'm sure Peter's told
you this already,
but he wanted me to be sure to tell
you to take this
straight to his office
and put it in the safe.
Oh, of course.
Well, I guess
that's it then.
Okay.
See yah.
Holy fucking shit.
[Door opens]
Oh!
Hi.
I'm just waiting for my clothes
to dry.
Those are my clothes.
Right. I'm waiting for your clothes
to dry, so that I can...
dry my clothes.
Where are
your clothes?
In my bathtub.
[Buzz]
Excuse me.
Hey,
let me ask
you something.
Suppose you had
a very rare...
Let go of my arm.
Sorry.
We're cool.
We're just talking here, right?
Laundry buddies.
Do you even live
in this building?
That's not relevant right now,
laundry buddy.
Let's suppose a person had in
their possession,
a very old...
very rare...
book.
What kind
of book?
A very influential book.
A book that has changed history.
I have no idea what the fuck
you're talking about.
Hey, dude. What's with
the hostility?
You give me
the creeps.
The creeps?
Take it
somewhere else
before I call
the cops?
Whoa! Hold
on there!
If you want me to leave,
I can go.
Thank you.
I'm going, dude.
Goodbye, dude.
[Door thud]
It's always me.
[Gasp]
[Breathes heavily]
Sweet mother of Christ.
[Shout]
What 're
you doing?
I'm just,
I was trying...
I'm calling
the cops.
Hey, don't do that.
I 'm gonna give it back.
I swear!
What use could I possibly
have for a musty 200-year old book?
(laundry guy)
Don't put me on hold I
Hey!
She's getting away I will find
you I am a Marine Reservist I
[pop music]
[Indistinct yell]
Phew.
No.
Wow, do you
look fucked up.
Come on, Hercules.
Aw, cute pig.
The truck bed's open.
It's headed west.
To Venice.
I don't see
the connection.
Wait a minute.
It's coming to me.
Buzz.
It smells like
sausage in here.
Time for a
revised plan.
NumBer one. ;
Get to that Hemp Festival.
NumBer two. ; Try to convince Steve
not to steal my furniture.
Especially not
my Bed. Oh God.
Anything But that.
[Indistinct shout]
NumBer three. ; Once I've convinced
Steve not to steal my Bed,
try to figure out a way to return the
Communist Manifesto
without getting arrested. PossiBly via
the U.S. Postal Service.
No, GloBal Express
is much more reliaBle.
Now that sounds like an awesome
revised plan.
[Thud]
Next stop. ;
Venice, California.
(AIBert)
Holy shit I
What?
Dude.
[Gasp]
Are we in
Venice yet?
Venice?!
Lady, we, we're
in fucking
El Monte.
Where?
Do you guys
kill pigs here?
No, that happens way before
they get here.
We keep the pigs on ice though, until
we need them.
Shut the fuck up.
Albert, she asked.
Hey, fellas.
Now you
did it.
(Spencer)
What are you doing on the floor?
Who the hell are you?
You know the rules, Mikey.
No girlfriends allowed in the plant.
Oh no, Mr. Spencer,
this isn't my girl...
I 'm not his girlfriend, dude.
Believe me.
Mikey, Albert, would you mind
explaining to me
what's going
on here?
Uh...
I 'm here
to organize a union.
What?!
That's right.
I always make it a point
to get to know the
workers personally,
and these two gentlemen were kind
enough to give me a little tour.
Albert, I thought
we cleared up
all that union
nonsense last year.
We did, sir.
I was just showing her the way out.
Look, Mr. Spencer,
is it?
How much stake do you personally
have in this organization?
Well, not that
it's any of your business,
but I 've got
a very generous benefit package.
[Laughs]
A generous benefit package.
Listen to how quickly
the lackey adopts
the language of
his master.
Ma'am, I am going
to ask you one time nicely.
Tell your people
that we are not interested.
I 'll tell my
people all right.
But first, I have
a little message
for you to tell
your people.
You tell
your people
the slaughterers of pigs,
the profiteering cowards
who dishonestly hide
their dirty business
behind a sweet, happy
logo of a cute pig,
while they manufacture
misery and death.
Ma'am.
Please, sir, allow
me to finish.
J ust look around you.
Do you see it?
Can you hear it?
And you, sir,
stand here
in this warehouse
of death!
And you have
the audacity to tell me
that you have
a generous benefit package?
And them?
Do they have
a generous benefit package?
I think we all know
the answer to that. Don't we?
It is a tale
as old as man.
The history
of all hither to existing society,
is the history
of class struggle.
The free man and slave,
the lord and serf,
in a word, oppressor
and oppressed,
stood in constant
opposition to one another,
carrying on an
uninterrupted fight.
A fight that each
time ended
in either revolutionary
reconstitution of society at large,
or in a complete
and total ruin!
[Cheering]
You tell your
people that!
You think you're
so, um, uh...
Jesus! And then you go
on and on about this and that
and all this other
bullshit and all I have to say is
fuck, man! I mean,
this situation is totally fucked.
With a capital!
I mean, have you ever...
Do you like even...
Well, do you?
You tell your
people that.
Ohhh!
Ow.
(Steve the dealer)
Meet me in Venice at three.
(Shirley)
Take this straight to his
office and put it in the safe.
(Steve the dealer)
I'd proBaBly take your furniture.
(casting director)
Are you trying to sell me drugs?
(policeman)
Young lady, come here.
(Brevin)
Jane. Janel
(laundry room man)
You give me the creeps.
(Brevin)
Christy. Psst.
Chris-ty
Psst. Jesusl
Jane. Hey. Jane.
(Mikey)
Jane.
Hey.
What are
you doing?
I don't even know
where I am.
Do you
want a ride?
(Jane)
NumBer one. ; Get to
that Hemp Festival.
So you like
to smoke a lot of weed, huh?
Not really.
[Soft music]
[Many horns honking]
So are you like
a Communist or something?
No, man.
I 'm not
a Communist.
What's in Venice that you've got
to go all the way out there for?
[Sigh]
I 'm supposed to
be meeting someone.
H mm.
Can I ask
you something?
Sure.
If you could,
with a single act,
change the whole trajectory of your
life, would you do it?
The trajectory
of my life?
Yeah, the direction your
life is headed in. Where you're going.
Uh, I don't
know. Um,
I guess not. I 've got a good
job. Why?
I 'm thinking about changing the
trajectory of my life, that's all.
That's cool.
God. I get so horny
when I'm stoned.
What?
Pot makes me
so fucking horny.
Does it have
that affect on you?
I'm not stoned
right now. But...
Let's just fuck.
Right here, right now,
In the car. In the
middle of this fucking traffic jam.
I don't want to get in an accident.
Come on, Mikey.
Fuck me.
Fuck me right now.
You know you want to.
Come on, Mikey.
Fuck me!
Fuck mel Yeah I
Fuck mel
[moans]
Fuck me!
Oh, yeah!
Come on!
Fuck me, Mikey!
[Cars honking]
This traffic
sucks, huh?
Huh?
This traffic...
It sucks.
Oh, yeah.
Right.
H mm.
Oh, my God! No!
I got to go!
We're on the freeway.
What are you doing?
I have to stop
my dealer from stealing my bed!
What are you
talking about?
There's no time to...
I gotta... Bye!
Jane!
Where the hell
are you going?
Jane!
NumBer two. ; Try to convince Steve
not to steal my Bed.
You shouldn't be walking on the
freeway. It's dangerous.
I guess.
Where are
you headed?
Venice.
That's where
I'm going.
I'll give
you a lift.
[Chuckles]
Hold on.
Well, I hope you find
whatever it is you're looking for.
Thanks.
You too.
She was nice.
[Gasps]
Carrot Top!
[Laughs]
Excuse me, did you
just come from the Hemp Fest?
No, man. I'm
from Bethlehem.
Oh, sorry.
Dude, I'm just fucking with you.
But it's kind of over.
What?
You're a bong
hit late. It's done-ski.
No!
[Yells]
Hey, is this the
Thirty-third Annual Venice Hemp Fest?
Not any more.
Oh, you've got
to be kidding me!
I'm supposed to meet
my dealer here.
Do you know him?
His name's Steve.
Steve? Oh, yeah!
Is he a dude, he's
got like two arms, two legs,
And a head.
That's Steve.
Yeah.
Forget it.
Have a fun ride.
[Bell goes off]
[Gasp]
[Gasps]
(Roscoe)
In that moment,
perched high
aBove the earth,
high aBove those
who had come so far to find her,
Jane knew what
she had to do.
Jane was
no schemer, no conniver,
no thief.
Jane knew that
deep down she was pure of heart.
And that she
did not want to contriBute
to the toll of human
misery and suffering in the world.
[Phone rings]
She knew the time had come
to take responsiBility
for what she'd done,
and to return
the Book to its rightful owner.
That her intentions were honoraBle,
that there'd Be no doubt.
But what puzzled many on that day
was not the virtue of her intentions.
Hey!
What puzzled
many was why.
Hey!
By what Bizarre
and convoluted logic,
did she arrive
at the decision
to do
what you're
aBout to see?
In short,
what the fuck was she thinking?
Whoa!
[Breathes heavily]
Hey!
U p here!
Brevin!
I'm up here!
Oh no.
Heyyy!
Ohhh!
Help.
[Yells]
[Shirley whimpers]
[Crying]
Whoa.
So, my dad plays
golf with this guy,
who is a pretty good
criminal attorney.
I think he's
a criminal attorney.
He's definitely
a lawyer.
I could try to hook
you up with him if you want.
Yeah, that
sounds good.
Well, Brevin, it sure
has been a fucking day, huh?
Yeah, I guess.
[Moans]
What a weird
fucking dream.
Hey, stoner!
Back to work!
[Breathes heavily]
Sorry.
(Roscoe)
This has Been the story
of how a person started at A,
got to Z, and
somehow ended up
collecting garBage
By the side of the freeway.
And I think you'll all
agree that much like life itself,
it certainly has
Been... one hell of a crazy ride.
THE END
Subtitles by: Reklame