Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. Not for sale!
Get it for free @ d-addicts. com
Episode 2
A body's postmortem...
does not in any way signify
violating a person's dignity.
On the contrary, as such body
is bestowed upon the altar of noble learning,
the dead are vested with a most
honorable opportunity to achieve fame.
Today,
we shall ascertain
the location of the internal organs.
We shall cut down the
skin near the diaphragm.
Man's body is sacred, even after
the soul leaves its physical form.
Violating the essence of man
in such a degrading way...
feels like dishonoring
our own souls.
Hey. Hearing the scorn the Japanese
show for all the Joseon students...
who refuse to participate in
autopsy classes is no better.
Isn't one of the reasons why
we fell behind the Japanese...
our refusal to learn
practical science such as that?
Are you all right?
I don't know.
I don't know if this is
truly the path I must take.
Are you saying you'll stop
studying medicine?
I don't know.
I need to go, see you around.
I'm hearing strange rumors.
They say there will be a demonstration
against Japanese occupation,
looks like he's involved
in some way or form.
Our people appeal to Japan
and the world's powers for...
the opportunity to manifest
our own self-determination.
Should we encounter any obstacle in
our freedom-seeking activities,
for the sake of our survival and freedom,
we shall seek independence by force.
No matter what you think of us,
we are Joseon people, too.
Preparations for our
demonstration are going well.
You students of the
Gyeongseong Medical College will...
take care of writing our manifesto.
- Independence for our people, Hurrah!
- Hurrah!
[March 1919]
- Independence for our people, Hurrah!
- Hurrah!
Do you know what this
place is, to enter like that?
I know all too well,
so don't waste my time.
How have you been?
You little...
get out of here right now!
What is all this commotion?
What brings you here?
I came to show you
how grateful I am, Milady.
Thanks to your sending me to prison,
I even learned Japanese,
and I found a career
for myself, didn't I?
You brought me success,
so I should at least
show you my gratitude.
If that's what you're here for, I
don't need any gratitude, so leave.
Have you heard the
news from Gyeongseong?
In Gyeongseong, this "independence
movement" or something took place.
Those students refuse
to fulfill their duties,
and started infesting the streets,
participating in this demonstration.
They think a few fools on the
street will bring us independence.
They must have some
kind of death wish.
Ahhh... right!
I hear the Young Master is attending
a Medical College in Gyeongseong?
Then again, would a boy
from a rich and noble family...
waste his life on something like that?
Isn't that right, Milady?
So, until we meet again.
[*as in Mother-in-law*]
- Mother*.
- There is nothing to worry about.
He's not the kind of boy to
engage in such imprudent acts.
Indeed.
There is nothing to worry about.
- Independence for our people, Hurrah!
- Hurrah!
Lee Kwon was caught,
so we're in danger as well.
Let's part ways here,
and hide somewhere else.
Be careful.
Right.
You too!
- Here!
- Yes!
Where is he, your son?
In Gyeongseong.
I told you he
disappeared from Gyeongseong!
He came here, didn't he?
He's in Gyeongseong,
for all I know.
Fomenting impure ideological
slant towards the Great Japanese Empire...
is tantamount to high treason.
He's not here!
Anyone sheltering
such treacherous elements,
or even only helping them escape...
shall be convicted of
felony against the Empire.
- Let's move!
- Yes!
We shall meet again, Milady.
That...
that motherless scum!
How can you show
such behavior to her?
You still think of me as a servant?
If I can only capture
one of those fools,
then our days will be filled
with riches and fame.
I'll catch him,
and achieve success.
[*Orabeoni* = archaic form of Oppa (older brother/close friend]
You can't, Orabeoni*! I beg you,
please don't do that!
Let's wake up!
The world has changed,
and I'll use that for
my benefit any time.
The moment I saw him,
I brought him to a safe place.
You did well.
There is no other way.
He must cross the Amnok river.
Mother.
They even came here, so it
will be just a matter of time...
before they find him there.
He must cross the border.
Surveillance is so tight,
can he even make it safely?
Even if he does go, if they
find him crossing the border...
If that's what happens...
Milady.
Mudeon just came.
She said she must tell you
something regarding the Young Master.
What brings you here?
I came to beg for forgiveness.
Forgive my brother
for his despicable acts.
I have no desire
to hear you say that.
You must help him escape!
My brother is not
going to stop at this.
Help him escape...
How are you going to help escape
someone who never came here?
Milady!
Is there a way to help him escape?
Mi Reuk!
My son!
Mother.
Were you injured in any way?
Uh?
No.
Let's go.
You must run away.
We heard surveillance is
limited in the upper Amnok.
Cross the river, go to China and
then head for wherever you wish to go.
Mother.
Now.
What... who are you?
You!
What are you...
Did you lure me
here to help them?
Our father died because
of those damned Japanese!
How can you work for them?
Surviving made me like this!
I couldn't live, nor
die like a decent person,
so here I am!
I will catch him at all costs!
Orabeoni!!
Orabeoni!
Hurry up.
I am sorry.
Whenever I think of you,
I just feel sorry about everything.
I will ask you just this much.
What...
do I mean to you?
Whatever I mean to you,
just remember this.
That I will always be here for you.
Just that...
Never forget it.
Where did you hide him?
What are you talking about?
Where did you send your spouse?!
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
Get moving!
I caught him while
he tried to run away.
Speak.
Where is he?
Mi Reuk.
You are no coward.
You did lose you courage once,
but you still kept
walking your path.
I trust you.
Indeed! The Mi Reuk
I know is not a coward.
You will cross the river
and go past the border,
and you finally will reach Europe.
But, if I go...
What... what
will happen to you?
You needn't worry about me.
I will quietly wait
for your safe return.
Doesn't time fly?
Mother!
Should you not be able
to ever make it back here,
you shan't fall into despair.
Raising you as
my child all this time,
I have been blessed with happiness.
You gave me the kind of joy...
nothing else in the world
would be able to.
Now, walk on your path.
Don't think of your mother.
You must walk that path alone.
Hurry up!
Where is he?
"Korean Provisional Government"
Mother.
After safely reaching Shanghai,
I applied for a Chinese
passport to get to Europe.
While I was waiting,
[*Ahn Joong Geun = Korean independence activist
who killed Ito Hirobumi, Japan's PM]
I met the cousin of Ahn
Joong Geun*, Ahn Bong Geun,
and I'm helping him at
the Provisional Government.
So don't you worry about me.
They say this place is safe.
Mother. Finally,
I received my passport,
and I started
my trip towards Europe.
Bong Geun Hyungnim agreed to
join me, on his way to France,
and we are sharing
this experience together.
On this ship, not only Joseon students,
[*Annam was used by foreign states
up to the mid 19th Century for Vietnamese*]
but also people
from China and Annam*.
We talked about
our concerns and future projects,
and even discussed about
European politics and culture.
[*Swiss writer Gottfried Keller's
"Der grune Heinrich" - The Green Henry*]
It's a good book for learning German.
It's written with simplicity and candor.
You're too quiet.
You must be spending
too much time thinking.
In Asia, silence
is considered a virtue,
but it's different in the west.
They consider it
antisocial and haughty.
Try to spend time and socialize
with people, talk with them.
Just as you told me,
I safely reached Europe.
Thanks to Bong Geun Hyungnim,
[*Benedictine Abbey in Bavaria]
I found refuge at the
Munsterschwarzach Abbey* in Germany.
It was here that I started focusing
on my German language studies,
and I'm rapidly progressing.
My little boy!
Mi Reuk...
Mi Reuk!
Come in.
Brother,
I beg you pardon.
I don't understand this passage.
Is anything wrong?
I don't know what's
wrong with me either.
First I felt a strange
sensation in my chest,
and now even my stomach hurts.
Your hands are cold.
Do you feel nauseous?
Yes, it's been this way all morning.
May I help you out?
It will only be a slight sting,
you needn't worry.
I feel a little better.
Oriental medicine is
based on the five elements theory.
That is, wood, fire,
earth, metal and water.
These five elements regulate
all the organs' activity in the human body.
Fascinating.
You're well versed
in Oriental medicine,
and even studied western
medicine in your motherland.
I think studying medicine here
in Germany would suit you perfectly.
You will become a very
esteemed and talented doctor.
Do you wash your hands
that way at home, too?
Why?
Your face and
body as well, I suppose.
Yes. And?
So why is your skin still so dirty?
Hey, I brought someone
from your hometown.
From my hometown?!
Are you a compatriot of mine?
"C'est mon compatriote?"*
Why don't you talk to him?
Speak your mother tongue, that is.
Sadly, people from my hometown
and I speak a different dialect,
just like you can't easily understand
what professors from other regions say.
Isn't it?
Elizabeth!
Don't run!
Are you all right?
Nothing to be afraid of.
Because I come from another land,
the color of my skin is different.
Do you understand?
Thank you.
Do all men from your hometown
have the same skin?
Yes.
Is it because they
don't drink enough milk?
This land I come from
is a little country from the far east.
The people living there all
have dark hair and yellow skin.
Ahhh... it must be the sun
that makes your skin yellow.
It takes a such a long time to
reach us it doesn't have enough power,
so we're all white.
Yes, probably.
I'm Elizabeth.
And my name is Mirok.
Mirok?!
Mirok means being
foolish but of good heart!
When I was
this little just like you,
I must have looked like a fool,
but at least I looked kind,
so that's probably
why they called me that.
Uh?
Fool!
You can't pay the rent again?
I apologize,
I will pay as soon as I can.
You haven't paid for two months,
this can't go on anymore.
I'll only wait until
the end of this month,
otherwise you're out!
Mother.
Have you been well?
I'm wondering if the rest of
the family is healthy as well.
I'm doing fine.
We'll start practicing at the
hospital, beginning this month.
They're all very kind to me,
and the owner of this
boarding house dotes on me like a mother.
Throw everything out!
From now on, this place will
be used by the Imperial Police.
Erase any trace of the
traitors' shadows as well.
I'm glad you're doing well.
We're doing fine.
Our only concern is you,
living alone in such a far away land.
We recently moved.
Our house started
languishing in its old age,
so everything feels
fresh in this new house.
It's full of rooms and
with a very large yard,
it makes you feel elated.
So, you needn't worry about us,
and I wish you good health
and luck in your studies.
This is not worth much,
but that watch over
there would certainly be better.
Care to give me that?
Looks like it's the same
for Oriental philosophers,
worrying about the
time even for promenades.
That's what Immanuel Kant did,
every single day.
He took a walk at the
same exact time every day,
so people said he was
trying to match his clock.
Can I introduce myself?
My name is Rosa.
Mirok.
Mirok Li.
What does your name mean?
[*Mireuk = Maitreya]
Mirok* in Buddhism is a future Buddha
who's come to save all men,
creating a peaceful world to live in.
That's the kind of peaceful
world you'll make, one day.
You think I'm going to die?
Elizabeth!
That's what the doctor
told me, Aunt Rosa.
No.
That's not what I think.
Whatever happens to me,
will you stay by my side?
Of course I will.
I'm not going anywhere.
But you probably
will not be able to.
Why wouldn't I?
Because she likes
you more than I do.
Elizabeth.
I really care about you.
Stop!
A friend of mine was shot
to death by Japanese troops.
Another was arrested.
Before they could get me, I ran away,
and came all the
way here to Germany.
Without even realizing it,
everything came back to mind.
No one will harm you
here, it's a safe place.
Mother!
Are you all right?
Please.
You must save her.
The patient is already dead.
But her hands are still warm!
The machines don't lie.
She's still alive,
her hands are warm!
You're not suited to be a doctor.
People who can't be
objective with their patients...
are not qualified for this job.
Mother!
- Mother!
- Mister Li!
You're all burning.
I received a letter from home.
My mother passed away.
So you're leaving the hospital?
The human body is like
a small universe in itself,
a vessel embodying a man's soul,
but nobody seems
interested about that here.
I think the path I'm walking
could lead me elsewhere.
Spiritual enlightenment is
much more important to me.
That's a relief.
[*Munchen = Munich]
I'm leaving for Munchen*,
to study literature.
See those gates?
[*Frederick V = King of Bohemia and
Elector Palatine of the Holy Roman Empire, 1596~1632*]
It was commissioned
by Friedrich the Fifth*,
and built in a single night, to
make his consort Elizabeth happy.
They say when lovers
pass through these gates,
their love will
last a hundred years.
Mirok, should we
pass through as well?
Or maybe not.
If we go through, we could
be a hundred years together.
But if we don't...
it could be forever.
Mirok.
Will you come to Munchen with me?
There, you can find the inspiration
to live life as you wish,
to walk your own path.
Mi Reuk!
Jae Won.
The applications for
publication end this month,
but I already
mentioned them your name.
Thank you,
but I'll have to decline.
- Look.
- It's just that I wouldn't make it.
I was writing something,
but haven't finished yet.
Ahh... really, aren't you about
to be kicked out of that place?
What are you writing?
I'm trying to write
my first short story.
What is it about?
It's about a messenger from heaven.
Do you mean angels?
Two poets were walking
the streets of Seoul one night,
when they suddenly heard a woman's
voice coming from over the fence.
[*nyang = old Joseon monetary unit*]
She was praying to the
gods to give her 1 nyang* to free her son,
who had been
incarcerated because of her.
[*10 don = 1 nyang*]
The older poet only had 7 don,*
so he threw what
he had over the fence.
A few days later, the younger
poet passed there once again,
and he heard that woman again.
She was still praying to the gods,
asking for just another 3 don.
The young poet threw the 1
nyang he had over the fence.
He was waiting to get
the difference back,
but all he heard was this woman,
still praying to the gods,
saying she'd use the remaining
money to feed her son for a few days,
after all that time starving.
The young poet just
went home, smiling.
I love it.
That messenger of heaven,
I wish you had one by your side.
Will other people like it?
Will German people understand
and enjoy a story from the far east?
I love you.
See? I understood.
Just express your feelings,
with honesty and simplicity.
Then, other people will understand
and interpret your feelings.
Thank you, Rosa.
Of course.
You can love me, if you want.
Your Korean has
gotten a lot better?!
If I want to understand
what beats inside there,
I must do that.
I thought there was no path
past this labyrinth of mountains and rivers.
But I found a village of bright
flowers and the willows's shade.
It's a poem about finding hope in
a village where flowers bloom,
after enduring the despair
of losing one's path.
Hello.
My name is Seyler.
[*LMU = Ludwig-Maximilians-Universitat Munchen*]
I teach Art at the LMU*
here in Munchen.
I've heard you're an
expert in East-Asian culture.
I am grateful
for your inviting me here.
How long has it been since
you've left your homeland?
Over ten years.
You must be really missing
your friends and family.
Don't you feel lonely?
"Sa Hae Ji Nae"
"May you wise man whelm
thine life with heaven's order,"
"Gaehyeong...(je)"
"And all creation shall
be thine brethren."
Ohhh... that's a bone!
I think I'll have to call these Chinese
characters "bone scriptures," from now on.
"Sahaejinae
Gaehyeongje."
A pupil of the Oriental
philosoper Confucius...
worried that, while everyone
had brethren, he was alone.
Confucius then said that,
if you behave with decorum
and politeness to everyone,
all the world is your brethren.
So why are you losing yourself in anxiety,
saying you have no brethren?
You and I,
we are not of the same race,
and we don't speak the same language.
But I think what we all have in
common is that we're all people.
Because with affection
and understanding,
then all men can be friends,
and become family.
And I have faith in this...
So I feel no loneliness at all.
What are you going to do now?
I'll find a way.
Can you hand me those books?
- Where?
- There, on my bed.
What's wrong?
Come in.
Doctor Li.
Hello.
I must have
chosen the wrong time.
Ahh... no, no!
I've been forced
to move in a hurry.
Where are you going?
Welcome, Doctor Li.
I'm really grateful.
You can think of this as your house,
and should you need anything,
you can ask Lina here.
Hello.
Sahaejinae Gaehyeongje
This is wonderful.
Now there's nothing
you should worry about,
you can finally write in peace.
It's all thanks to those people.
I sent my final draft to the publisher.
Rosa!
I'm sorry, Mirok.
It slipped from my fingers.
Come in.
It's a package for you,
from Korea.
Thank you.
It's so beautiful.
These clothes,
and your wife,
who made them for you.
I'm just fine, Mirok.
You haven't betrayed
your wife even once.
And that's the reason I liked you.
It's soft and beautiful.
Do they make
these for women, too?
I am grateful for
the clothes you sent me.
I need a favor from you.
I'd like you to make me a skirt.
[*Famous work by female
poet Heo Nanseolheon]
The blue sky and white
clouds sing my prose.*
Altair and Vega bedeck
the deep, starry night.
Where art thou,
O my beloved?
The rain of tears my heart
sheds, as vast as the ocean.
Just remember this.
That...
I will always be here for you.
[*Nights in a Korean alleyway."
Mirok Li*]
I've been looking for you.
My short story was published.
I wanted you to be
the first I'd show it to.
Congratulations.
It's all thanks to you.
You've always encouraged me,
and gave me strength.
This is a small token
of my gratitude.
Open it for me.
It's really soft.
Mirok.
If that day...
we passed through those gates,
would our love have come true?
Mirok.
I can see you.
Multiple sclerosis.
I...
I don't have
much longer to live.
But... how did...
When I leave this world,
I will wear these
clothes you gave me.
I wish the path which led
you to leave your homeland...
and find refuge here will be
always as happy and peaceful as it is now,
Mirok
[*Don't buy from Jews!*]
- Don't buy from Jews!
Don't buy from Jews!
What is this?
It's an invitation to participate
at our book burning rally next week.
A book burning rally?!
Yes, we will burn all the blasphemous
and detrimental books harming our people.
This will include works by Thomas Mann,
Stefan Zweig, Karl Marx, other Jews...
and any other work
deriding nationalsocialism.
We would be glad
if you participated.
- Against un-German spirit!
Against un-German spirit!
In the ideological struggle,
books can become
a very fierce weapon.
From the flames of these
degenerate texts...
we shall rid our land
of this anti-German spirit
which besmears our pure Arian blood!
We shall all hail this
new spirit of change!
This new spirit led by our
beloved leader, Adolf Hitler!
[*the "Nazi salute"]
Heil Hitler*!
- Heil Hitler!
- Against un-German spirit!
They think...
burning these books will get
rid of the spirit they carry.
"The world is like a mysterious vessel,
impossible for man to control."
"Anyone trying to control
it will destroy it all,"
"those trying to grab it
with their hands will lose it."
This is what the great
Chinese philosopher Laozi said.
In Ancient China, Emperor Qin Shi Huang*
burned any scripture trying to criticize him,
[*Qin Shi Huang used Fenshu Kengru, a policy to
legitimize his "mandate," 213~206 BC*]
and buried one scholar opposing
his ideology after another.
But it took nothing more than two
decades for this mighty empire to crumble.
Twenty years is too long.
Even if our scholars end
up perishing to fight Hitler,
wouldn't our resistance against the
Fuhrer shorten that period?
Why should they die?
They will survive and fight instead.
[*Huber = famous member of the "White Rose,"
a Nazi resistance group*]
My name is Kurt Huber*.
I'm Mirok Li.
This is my way to help
my beloved Germany, Mirok.
But I hope you'll help
our country in other ways.
It's one of the biggest
publishing houses in Germany.
Would they publish something
from a nameless writer like me,
not to mention someone
from a far away land?
I'm sure they
will publish your work.
Just like your book, "Der Yalu Fliesst,"
will always remain in our memories,
you will always have
a place in our hearts.
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
Main Translator & Timer: MisterX
Timing QC: schizoar
Editor/QC: szhoang
Coordinators: mily2, ay_link
This is a FREE fansub. Not for sale!
Get it for free @ d-addicts.com