Warning: This Movie has profanity.
German Translation:
doubledutch
English Translation:
niyekine
Damn.
Fucking Shit!
Hey, bastard! I cannot have shower,
my ass is freezing!
Give me hot water!
Pay July, August and September
rent money fist!
Fuck off!
- Yes, your fish is ready.
- Thank you.
- How was it?
- Thanks. It was good.
- You paid that, right?
- Of course.
What about drinks?
Don't you finish them?
We need to drive.
Good night.
Lucia, beer is ready!
Give me a glass of wine
you stranger bastard.
I love you too, Sokrates.
Ya, ya, ya.
- Hi.
- Where have you been?
Nadine, I am on my way.
I am sitting in the car now.
I don't believe you. This is my last night
and you are missing it.
I was busy in restaurant.
You can start to eat.
All, all, all the time
Zinos, do you realize?
Happy for you. You will get
rid of me in the morning.
Bastard.
You decided to go,
Nadine! It was your idea!
Nadine.
- Place was full of idiots.
- Good evening.
Zinos?.. Zinos Kazantsakis.
- From training school in Billroth Road.
- Thomas Neumann! - Unbelievable!
Do you remember
what we do after school?
- This is my fiance Tanja.
- Hi. - Hello.
- Unbelievable.
- What do you do?
- Real Estate.
- I have a restaurant.
- Where?
- Wilhelmsburg.
Wilhelmsburg. Okay.
What is the name of it?
- Soul Kitchen. - Soul what?
- Soul Kitchen. Just like Soul music.
Will you cut the crap?
I am tired. - Okay.
Kazantsakis, I am very happy to see you, I will stop by.
I will wait... Thomas Neumann
wow, I don't believe.
- Hello Krüger Grandma.
- Here he is... Lady!
- Can you bring one more chair?
Everyone, slide a little bit please!
- Don't bother please.
- One more serving for young man.
- No need serving.
Food will be finished,
that's it.
- Mistress Krüger.
- Hello Zinos.
- Mister Krüger.
What does this mean? Can't you
sit straight?
- What can I do for you?
- I want to have a hot gazpacho.
- I need to ask chief first.
- Chief's opinion doesn't interest me.
Sure.
Chief... We have a problem.
It's taste is different
than your's, right?
- Asking Espresso?
- Yes.
Hmm... Super.
- She wants to go Shanghai and
eats dog meat - Mother please.
- Don't worry grandma, I never forget anyone.
- If so, come with me.
- We have argued about it for thousand times.
- We can have one more then.
You want to argue? Ok lets argue then.
First: It is your plan..
- It is my job. - Quiet
- What about my job?
Quiet!
Continue to eat.
I just want to have hot gazpacho
from the lady. That's all.
What's the big deal?
Gazpacho is a traditional spanish
food which is served cold.
Don't you have a microwave in the kitchen?
Do I come to your place of work,
and teach you how to do your job?
- I want to have a hot gazpacho!
- No!
- I can cum to your soup!
It will also get warm! - Shayn it is enough!
This is the last time. I don't want
you here anymore. Out!
Ya, ya! You sell everything you
can sell, don't you? Love, Sex, soul...
- Also Traditions!
- Get your traditions and fuck off!
Get out! You are fired!
It is enough!
I am sorry.
I am go out to smoke.
What will you do now?
Voyager...
...haven't reached his
destination yet. It is not over.
- Take care.
- Chief!..
...Hasta luego!
Good luck.
Hey Man!.. I like your foods!
Do you have a
job for me?
I fear.
Are you staring again
Nadine? It is enough.
Flight fear, Zinos.
Flight fear. You know.
Ha...
...sorry.
Very bad?
I don't know.
Yes.
You stink.
Look. It is very easy.
You call me from Skype.
Then, you click this
little webcam icon
...and we can see eachother.
- I don't want to just see you
I want to feel you, smell you.
If I want to smell you, I could smell fryer.
Smell this.
Mint.
- Do you understand now?
- Everything, everything.
- It is better, if you write.
- Later.
Zinos...
...there is no later.
Ah this legs, Ah.
What can be done with this foot?
These beautiful foot?
Ah, look at this ass!
Nadine?
Nadine!.. Shit.
Kazantsakis!
Lets go then.
- Hey Illias! Want to play?
- Okay.
Þnik, þnak, þnuk!
Suck this mate.
Your dept become 35 bucks.
- Need to pass from here?
- No need. Go on.
- Sign here.
- Okay.
You will be here at 6 o'clock, right?
But, I can be late for half hour...
Just kidding.
- Howdy malaka?
- Illias, what are you doing here?
- Did you escape from prison?
- Escape? What next. Everything is fine.
How are you? You seem good. Lost weight.
Sit. I need to talk to you.
sit, sit.
Now...
I need a favor.
What you want? You want me to hide you? What happened?
Everything is all right. The thing is:
They let me go out from prison for
a limited time. So I can go out weekends.
- It is really good.
- It is good but...
...the point is: If I would have a job,
I could go out everyday.
- But You have never work.
- I will pretend to work.
- I see. How long does it for?
- Half a year. Until the end of my prison time.
- Forget it. I have enough workers here.
- But Zinos, you are not listening to me.
I am saying that I will pretend to work here.
Listen.
All you need to do is
signing this paper.
Work starts 17:00, endss 02:00
But this is wrong.
I am closing at 12.
Doesn't matter. No matter
what is written there.
My hero. Aren't we brothers?
- How do I move motorcycle?
Good morning chief. - Morning.
Haa, one more thing, don't
mention about the prison to anybody.
- Why?
- there will be rumors.
I am leaving.
Ah... One more thing.
Can you give me twenty bucks?
Thank you very much.
Thanks.
Your welcome.
- Was it your Brother?
- You can say.
My brother will work
here for a while.
I don't understand... How is the
meaning of hiring one more waiter?
He is happy to work
just for unemployment money.
He needs job.
He is taking unemployment money
and wearing suits, isn't he?
Why this dishwashers are so heavy?
It was bought from Greece, that's why.
Okay.
One.. Two.. Go!
- We are really weak for this.
- You are!
Chief, is this a good idea?
I will beat you.
Zinos?
Chief, are you alright?
What happened? Lucia
can you come here?
Lucia!
- Who will cook the food?
- I will.
- You cannot. You should go to Doctor.
- I cannot go fucking doctor.
Wait a minute. Why can't
you go to doctor?
- I don't have insurance, that is because!
- Hey Zinos!
Stick a rod to your ass.
He, he. Pay your rent first, old man.
Zinos, will you pay our shifts?
I will take care of them.
Okay?
Nadine?
- Zinos?
- I can see you.
It is unbelievable.
It is like science fiction.
I can't see your face, sit please.
I can't sit. My back is fucked.
- Is it because of running at work?
- I don't know.
It hurts.
Ahh. poor thing.
- Can you see me now?
- Yes.
If your back is serious, you should go Anna
- Who is Anna?
- Physiotherapist.
- Wait, I will send you a link.
- Send it.
Eee?
You became an
oversea journalist now?
Yes.
This is stupid.
I am touching a plastic screen,
not your face.
Better then nothing.
I know what is better.
Come close.
I will move to Shanghay, to you.
What about your restaurant?
I will hire a manager.
We will see.
I am buying all of these.
Hello?
- Good morning captain.
- What's up?
- I am looking for Zinos Kazantsakis
- He is sick.
Sick? Ok then.
- Who is the owner of this place?
- Sick one.
Take care chief!
Do you have prescription?
- No.
- Did you see a doctor?
Not exactly.
I fear.
Lean forward.
- Ah. This is the end.
- Okay.
It can be hernia.
It is bad?
If it is, yes it is bad.
How can we know?
MR can show it, but doctor
need to write prescription.
Shit.
I can show you some
moves, can be relaxing.
- What is your job?
- Cook.
You can't work as
a cook in this situation.
Why?
Standing for a long time can be harmful.
Sitting too.
You need to walk a lot. Always in motion
Don't lift heavy things.
1 Kilo maximum.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Dancing can help to decrease your pain
- Dance?
- Hmm-m.
This is fantastic.
A real Roman coffeehouse.
They will destroy to come.
Tell me chief.
Do you want to hire this place?
I know everything about restaurants so that..
...I am aware of that
I don't want to manage a restaurant.
Hawaii steak.
Meatball.
Fish in oven.
Spaghetti with cream sauce.
Spinach with cream sauce.
Fried Potatoes
with cream sauce.
I won't cook this shit.
You were looking for a job.
Whore is who you are looking for.
I am a cook.
I see. Door is there.
Hey, wait a second.
I don't like these foods either,
but people like them.
They don't have a taste.
They have a hole in the stomach.
And they fill
this hole with shit
System's working like this.
Are you an opportunist?
No, but how can I pay my bills?
This place is not a gourmet temple.
It is what it is.
Sell out.
Things can't be sold, can be sold.
Fake Passions.
One illusion.
Optical illusion.
and filling.
Here:
45 Avro.
Great. Can we put this in menu?
There are 40 kind of food in the menu,
and everyone of them tastes same.
I will make 4 kind of food,
with same money.
Food for Soul.
Yea man.
Soul Kitchen.
Hello?
We are not open yet.
Good morning.
- Are you chief?
- Yes
Schuster, Hamburg internal revenue office.
Do you know that you have tax depth?
- Do you have cash?
- Do I look like a bank?
Can I see your wallet?
Do you want to sit down
and drink something first?
We are not thirsty.
Show me your wallet.
No.
Wait a second. You can't do it.
Don't take the music set.
Music is a food of soul.
We will come 3 weeks later.
We will be hungry next time.
This is a robbery.
I know my rights, alright?
You can't do this to me!
- Hey Zino!
At last,
your bumbum music is gone!
You bastard.
Hey Chief, what's up?
...Chief's soup.
What is the name of this?
Name...
... acupuncture chief's soup.
Let's do and eat hot-dog.
Taste very well though.
- No, not today.
- As you wish.
Why nobody orders food?
Ask them.
Ladies and Gentlemen,
Dear guests:
Could I ask
why don't you order food?
Cut the crap old fart.
I want my schnitzel
- Same here
- What about my meatball?
Where is my pizza??
You can find your pizza in next place.
Supermarket.
Peasant don't eat
what they don't know, right?
Taste fascist!
All of you are taste fascist
It is unbelievable.
Eat that shit yourself!
You are a yearly customer,
and what they have done to you!
Nadine, please
take off the towel.
Zinos, I need to leave in 10 minutes.
Doesn't matter, take off.
I am coming now.
Is it that fast?
Milli!.. Goat!... Me-e-e-e!
- Me-e-e-e.
- Hey mate.
- What's up? How are you?
- Fine.
Illia.
- So? How was it?
- Everything! Everything is done.
Darling, can you give me a beer?
Take yourself.
Would you like too?
I haven't finished mine.
Is is possible to flirt with you?
Don't mess with me.
- So, What happened?
- Nothing.
All listen me!
Go Home!
What is going on mate?
We've just arrived.
Illias, get out.
Stand up, let's go.
Are we going to Dollhouse?
Let's see some real woman.
What are you looking at?
I can't even pay your money.
Let's call it for today.
Just for today?
or forever?
I will call you.
Lucia, give me a break
and leave please.
Lutz, Lutz!
Are you deaf?
Take your violinist and get lost.
- Don't you like it?
- Not today!
Ok, ok.
Hey, close the door!
Soul Kitchen!
Neumann... What are you doing here?
It seems like your place rocks.
Poker is played here, right?
Sometimes.
What's up?
Don't you serve a drink?
Of course.
What you would like to drink?
- Break Beer.
- It is coming right now.
Is this the old view of this place?
It was, when I bought it.
- It was a bargain, right? ?
- Yes
Do you want to see what I bought?
Sure, Why not?
What is wrong man?
Want me to hand-job?
My back hurts when sitting.
Did you jerk off a lot?
- where are you taking me?
- You will see soon.
Take a look at these places.
Look, look.
All block is belong to me.
- So, Is it your place?
- Not exactly.
I rent it.
I rent it to girls and some boys.
Until building is collapsed.
Good.
We can fuck if you want.
Two for you, two for me.
It will be good for your back.
- Doctor Neumann ha?
- Doctor Neumann, exactly.
- What's up Tschako?
- Neumann. Do you have wave on you?
- Always.
- Hello.
Hello.
- So?
- What do you have?
Will you sell your place to me?
I can rent you,
just like this place.
I don't want to rent.
I want to buy it.
Tell me a price.
I really don't think to sell the place.
It is my place, you know?
I build it myself.
I installed the pipes.
Build the toilets..
I picked up the tables
and chairs from junkyard.
- It has intangible value for me.
- Okay Okay. Mine has intangible value for me too.
If you change your mind...
...my offer is always
available, Okay?
Okay.
Good afternoon.
Health Department?
Yes. How can I help you?
I have a complain.
Food poisoning.
From Soul Kitchen.
Where?
Soul Kitchen.
Soul... S-O-U-L
Kitchen
Just like Kitchen of soul, Soul kitchen.
Industrial area, Wilhelmsburg.
I ordered cheese bread.
It was stale.
It was Green mouldy
and hard like rock.
There was insects everywhere etc.
It was more like zoo, then restaurant!
We will take care of it.
Please. It is urgent.
This is illegal.
You should close this restaurant.
You need to search for another job.
What?
Are you nuts?
Do you know how hard was that
to get a job permission?
I am sorry.
Tell me another.
Why do you fire me?
I don't fire you.
I am going to Shanghai, to Nadine.
- What happens now?
- I am looking for a renter.
Or a manager.
- Why don't you ask me, prick?
- Management?
Do you know What this mean?
This means working.
You didn't want to work, did you?
You wanted to pretend to work? didn't you?
Good morning.
- Are you owner?
- Yes. What's up?
Meyer. Health Department.
- Oh shit...
- What?
Come in.
Off, off. This place stinks.
Where is exhauster?
Oh my dear!
This place needs to be a kitchen.
You need to floor tile, not carpet.
Also to the walls.
We don't buy kitchen tools from porcelain seller.
Stainless steel... Steel.
Remove the gas tubes. You need to have
orderly installed gas connection.
Else, your building will blow up.
Off, off... Look at this electrical connections.
My boy, my boy,
My boy, my boy!
I will come 1 month later.
Everything will be fixed. Chiko?
Chiko.
Else, I will close the restaurant.
I warn you.
Is Coffee machine ready?
Good morning Zinos.
- In the left.
- Okay.
- Who are they?
- We are kicked from studio.
- Will practice here?
- I thought that it will be Okay.
Lutz, lutz.
What about renting the restaurant?
You do what ever you want.
How much money for?
Forget it. Bad idea.
- Can we practice anyway?
- Be my guess.
Some fans will come too.
- I am hungry!
- What?
This, third food from up.
- Where are you showing?
- I want this food.
Problem is:
Chief is not here now.
I is not my problem! I am hungry.
Nadine. This thing will
be longer than I expected.
I know. Same everytime.
Nadine, you don't know it.
Place is fucking me.
Place, place
Yes, place, place
place, what did you expect?
Hey Zinos. They want food.
- Fix them something.
- They want from the menu.
- What?
- Zinos?
I will be back.
Nadine, I will call you.
No, talk now.
I will call you my love. Please.
Shayn. You should
really come. Come!
Don't mix the kitchen!
Out! Clear the place!
- This was the just the beginning.
- Yea man.
They will come as massive.
- See you tomorrow.
Fucking shit.
Illias! Your brother working with
hurted back in the kitchen,
and you enjoy yourself here.
- What should I do?
- Collect table number 6.
- Which one is number 6?
1, 2, 3, 4... 5, 6.
Can you do it?
- Give me a beer mate.
- He? - Beer.
- What are you? Ali Davidson?
- E of course.
Hey! Hey!
- No cheating!
- Fuck off!
Are you blind?
What are you looking at?
Lower the music!
Lutz bastard! Open the lights!
- It wasn't me!
- It is enough! We are close!
Time to go home!
Everyone! Everyone!
So? Do we go
to the party?
- Now?
- I will come too.
- Don't you need to return to the prison?
- I have two more hours.
- Have you told something to her? haven't you?
- No. - Are you sure?
- I haven't told anything.
- What are you talking about?
- Nothing!
Oh my god. This place was used
to be Karstadt, wasn't it?
- It was Karstadt.
- I know.
- Does it become a disco?
- It seems so.
- It is absolute that there is
no absolution, which is even not absolute.
- Is it a proverb?
It is my word.
Goethe said:
"Colors are light's
monument and misery."
That is because
Van Gogh get crazy and...
...cut himself ear.
Do you understand?
Of course, sure. I know.
Good then.
You like music, right?
What happens to us
if there was not a music?
Hey, dude. Dude!
All of these buttons.
How do these works, can you tell me?
Don't mess with me.
What did you say?
Fuck off, groin louse!
I need to go. I am leaving.
- Why? Do you have a date?
- I have things to do.
Milli, listen.
Call Goat now
and come here.
I will give you the address.
I need a favor from you.
Hey Zinos!
You asslickers!
What did you say?
Are you alright?
- Who are they?
- Some man.
They know your name, don't they?
I have a bad reputation.
Ah don't be ridiculous.
You can't have that much reputation.
Tell me what is going on?
I can't!
- Don't you trust me?
- This is not about trust!
What is this about?
Alright! Don't tell me!
- Wait couple seconds Lucia!
- Get out of my face!
Look...
Never Mind.
Heeey!
Okay.
But this is a secret.
Noone should know about this.
My brother is a prisoner.
Like the Count of Monte Cristo?
So so.
He is a thief, burglar.
king of the thief.
He climbs to roofs...
Hamburg's truss.
Hot plates
This is so romantic.
Hey, give two more!
Yes Lucia. Time to sleep!
Aloo!
Taxi!
Alo?
I am.
Do you remember?
Girl friend in Shanghai.
Nadine.
You promised to call me?
Something came up.
Rush, bustle.
- You forget me so.
- I definitely not.
- I miss you.
- Me too.
What happened to you?
Why are you moaning?
My back.. It got fucked.
What was that sound?
A boat.
Where are you?
In Speicherstadt.
I returned from
a party in Speicherstadt
What? Is that why
you don't call me?
You forget me because of
having fun with some girls?
- You told me that you are coming here?
- I will.
Come here then!
Nadine?
Zinos! I am falling in love man.
Love! To Waitress girl... Pam!
Okay, relax.
Didn't you tell her
about prison, did you?
Me? No.
Did you?
No. Never.
Malaka, I am so happy,
You can't believe.
I will call you later, Okay?
See you.
Okay. bye.
This is unbelievable.
Unbelievable.
How could you rent this place?
Are you rich or something?
No.
I live here illegally.
I even don't have a bathroom.
Where do you shower??
Swimming pool.
Like the old days?
Yes.
Tell me Lucia.
- Can I ask you something?
- Whatever you want.
What about managing my restaurant?
As manager of Soul Kitchen.
Where does it
come from now?
I need to go to Nadine.
What do I do with a restaurant?
I want to make my
own way and painting.
I want to be free.
I can't manage a restaurant.
I will sell it then.
No. Don't do it.
Ask your brother.
Alo?
Kazantsakis.
Neumann.
Yes it is. Tell me,
what's up?
What is what?
Don't you sell your place?
Ahhm..I can't talk
right now.
- Line is disconnecting.
- What line man?
- I don't understand what you saying.
- Call me. It is important.
It is tickling.
Can I face down?
This exercise is
important for you.
I am sorry.
I am so embarrassed.
You should be happy.
You are healthy.
What is happening here?
I don't want stolen equipments in here.
They are trouble.
What is wrong with you? She likes
the music, and I like her.
Take these back. You will
take these back today.
Goat, Milli! Take these back.
Immediately!
Who are these people Lucia
Where do they come from?
There is an opening of musical school
across the street. They are celebrating
Musical.
My prediction was true. They will even
eat your hairs in your head.
Start the music. Quick.
Girls should dance.
Girls should dance!
I don't know about these records.
What is these buttons.
What is these?
Can it be this?
Play this! Play this!
- Which song?
- three, three, three.
Which button?
33! 33!
This is better.
- Good, right?
- Yes.
Go on, semis up, semis up.
Stainless steel, stainless steel,
stainless steel.
Chiko?
Chiko.
One second, let me pass.
Thanks.
Can I pass?
Thank you very much.
Thanks,
Thanks.
I need to go to the
table at front. Thanks.
I am coming right now.
Hey! Who made this?
Get out!
Illias!
Hey! The Count of Monte Cristo!
We need help in the bar.
- What did you say?
- We need help in the bar.
No. Before that?
Count of Monte Cristo.
Illias! Illias!
Hey! Illias!
Stop! Illias!
Damn! I think
I pierce the bilis.
Fucking ass!
Take out your hands of it!
I don't believe. You
messy bastard! Ratty!
It is impossible!
You idiot!
Clean the place!
- Illias gone!
- What happened?
Prison thing,
got out of my mouth.
Sorry.
You will return.
Okay man.
Ali! Ali Davidson!
Run! Clean the kitchen!
Doesn't matter!
- Neumann! - Why don't you call?
- Did you see my brother?
- What on earth do I know.
We need to talk. - I will be right back.
I liked old
version of the place!
Illia!
Fuck!
I don't want to come here.
What are you saying?
Next week, I need to fly
to Lhasa, and report
every week for 6 months.
This means, I can't see you
even if you come here.
Don't worry,
I will handle it
Zinos, You don't know Chinese.
It is not easy.
What is wrong with you?
You wanted me to come there.
I did, but not now.
Listen. This project is
very important and
I can't get this chance again.
One second.
I need to close now.
Nadine!
Tell me a price.
Work is good at restaurant.
Really good.
Look. I don't care about work.
I will destroy the building anyway.
I am interesting for land.
Now... Okay, or not?
Kazantsakis, make
your decision.
Pop Shop
Come on man.
Fly!
Go! Go!
Ehhh fuck!
Idiots!
Greek!
What?
What is your problem?
What is my problem?
In fact, What is your problem?
Why did you tell
her about prison ha?
Come on man. This
was romantic for her.
romantic?
Do you know how romantic is it?
... 2.5 years with some bastards,
sitting in the same cage?
When you out, noone
will give a job to you...
...Do you know
how romantic is that?
Telling lie to your own mother,
working in a oil platform...
...do you know how
romantic is that?
It is not romantic
at all, mate!
I am ashamed, do you understand?
I feel ashamed!
- Brother!
- What?
I want you to be
manager of Soul Kitchen.
Man, could you give me
one more 20 bucks?
Sure.
Which permissions do you
want to give your brother?
Full permission.
Are you sure?
What kind of question
is that "are you sure?"?
Do I look like egg thief?
- No Mr...
- Kazantsakis.
Kazantsakis. You don't look
like egg thief at all.
But, why full permission?
Look.
I will fly to Shanghai tomorrow.
I don't want to fly for 15 hours
for every little problem.
Just for one sign, etc.
Do you understand?
When your criminal end,
you can move here.
- Great.
- There are everything needed here.
Television, music box....
...books... Everything.
Can I take your jacket too?
- Jacket?
- Hmm.
Leather, right?
It fits, does it?
Special Invitation
What the hell is it?
Tree Skin.
From Honduras.
I took from a native.
What is it for?
It shows Aphrodisiac effect.
Or lets say:
Makes horny, climbs you to walls.
So put some more.
Hey. I was kidding.
It is very sad, isn't it?
Look, what did you do..
I will miss you chief.
What is the problem ha?
Don't you like my foods?
- There's is no problem.
- Delicious.
Where is the party?
Po-ar-tiey!
Halli Galli!
Yes man!
Okay, alright?
Sorry, sorry!
Thomas... Neumann!
- Kazantsakis!
- Welcome, good to see you!
Thanks for invitation but,
I need to tell you something.
You give hope at first,
then take them away! Shame!
We are friends!
I didn't promise!
- When you gone, who will be manager?
- My brother!
- Your brother??
- I want my champagne!
- Okay!
Go to the bar!
Through to the bar!
Damn!
I am sorry!
- Miss Schuster!
- Do we take away the music box again?
No. I have better
thing for you!
Max! Write receipt
for Mr. Kazakstan!
Kazantsakis!
Do you want to eat something?
Do we hungry?
Ali! Ali Davidson!
Give me that! Give, give
There is just dessert left!
Thank you.
Enjoy.
Miss. Schuster.
I should better go.
Do you manage this place now?
Yes, I am the owner!
- Owner?
- Yes!
- Notary approved or something?
- Sure! All of them, everything!
Whores!
All of you! All of you!
Cut that shit!
It is enough!
Time to go home!
- Out!
- All of them!
Shut up!
Out! out!
You drink enough.
You are going home!
You with these whores...
Shut up!
I can't. Two children
waiting at home.
That bastard...
Wait, wait a minute!
- I saw you a minute ago.
- Ha?
I saw you a minute ago!
Pozitively!
I need to be in prison in an hour.
We will do a quickie.
Look that! Look at
these breasts!
Dut duuut! Dut duuut!
- This is a little flu.
- Flu but isn't it great?
- Great, great!
- You literally fuck revenue officer.
- I do that everytime.
Good for you!
- Good bye.
- Thanks. Thanks.
Miss. Schuster.
How was it's taste?
Can you tell me
this man's name please?
Thomas Neumann.
Neumann... Okay..
- Good luck young man.
- Thanks.
Nadine?
What are you doing here?
To Shanghai, I was coming for you.
My grandma died.
What?
Died.
My mother is waiting outside now.
I have to go.
Nadine wait. I will take my luggage
and come with you.
By the way, I am Han.
I changed my mind.
Take my luggage.
I will stay in Hamburg.
- Flying ticket?
- Here.
- Can I get them?
- One minute pls.
This is clearly
a hernia situation.
What now?
We open your back. Take the hernia,
and finish the surgery.
Do you have private insurance?
- I have no insurance.
- It will be very expensive.
I can tell this much.
What if I don't take the surgery?
If not, hernia will get bigger and..
...you will have to use wheelchair.
..This is Nadine's answermachine.
Your message...
Yes ladies. Beer was for you,
right? - Yes, thanks.
- Do you like it?
- Delicious.
- Ali Davidson. Dishes
- I'm going.
- How can I help you?
- Liquor for lady.
- Hard one?
- Yes
- Kazantsakis' brother!
- Aaa. - Neumann.
Neumann, right.
Do you want to drink something?
- Break beer.
- Sure. Coming.
Can I sit?
You should play than.
Sure, sure.
- How much money?
- 50 cent. We are coin people.
Here Shayn. Good work.
Thanks.
Let's play.
By the way, I am Thomas.
- Milli.
- Goat.
- Give money.
- Don't you have?
You owe me 10 bucks anyway.
You strip me.
Best one are these.
Once a day.
- Can I get glass of water?
- These are for chew.
I said one!
..Nadine's answer machine.
Your message...
- 15
- 15 right?
All in.
I am leaving chief!
I am in.
I see.
Lets open then.
So?
Damn.
Great man, great!
This is my night mates.
It was a good play...
wait, wait. Give me one more chance
Just you and me.
Thousand Avro.
- Are you crazy man? Fuck it.
- Fuck it man.
Stop, stop.
Fuck it man.
Hey! I am leaving.
Let's go man,
let's have fun at Dollhouse.
Let's go. Are you crazy?
That is enough.
Let's go.
Wait a second.
- Go on, thousand Avro.
- Wait, wait.
Lucia!
Hey Lucia!
Wait please.
Wait!
I don't want to wait.
You have to be in prison in two hours,
and instead of fucking me,
you are playing gamble.
Look. I am on my lucky day.
I need to use it today.
I don't like it.
Come here.
Listen.
I will enter inside and
play one more hand. I will win.
I will make rich both of us
and return to you. Okay?
- Okay. Don't wait me. Okay?
- Okay.
Thanks.
Guys, we are closed.
You can fly by your planes now.
- We are friends of Neumann.
- Neumann's?
- All of you?
- All of us.
...I am out. Please leave
message after sign...
Nadine?
I am in front of
your mother's home.
I am waiting you near ducks.
All in.
I see.
Yes.
Let's do.
- Take out trousers. Tak!
- Okay man.
Great Neumann!
Depth became 50.000.
Okay?
or continue?
Give me one more
50.000 credit!
No problem.
Nadine.
Hey Nadine!
Hey! Wait me!
When I was a child...
...speak like a child...
...think like a child...
...decide like a child.
After becoming a man,
I left my childhood behind.
Now, just like looking at the mirror,
we look at a dark word
But, we look face to face.
For now, I can just
recognize pieces of a whole
In due time, I will
recognize how I am recognized.
For now, I have
these 3 things remained:
Faith...
...hope...
...love.
This three thing.
But the biggest one is...
...love.
Nooooo!
Nadine!
Fucking pig!
Don't worry about
other things Mr. Neumann.
In couple of weeks,
contract will be legal.
What the hell
are you doing here?
I live here.
Watch out!
I will bring cloth.
Quickly.
Quick.
Damn.
Why aren't you in Shanghai?
Why aren't you in prison?
I will tell you later.
We need to leave here. Quick!
Who is watching the place!
I am not.
Where are you going?
Restaurant.
Wait. what will you do there?
Place is still mine,
isn't it?
Leave me boat,
you rats!
What are you doing,
bastards?
What you want
motherfucker?
I am the owner of this place!
Neumann is the owner of this place!
Corbie! you better
fuck out of my face!
Go on.
Situation was very difficult
and cost me very expensive.
I invest a lot of money.
Come to the point Mr. Neumann.
The point is:
You are not the only buyer.
As you know.
You need to increase your offer.
What is your offer?
- Where is that motherfucker?
- Right... Turn right.
Personally, I don't
want to talk about money.
Here.
What are you up to, Tommy?
What are you up again?
Talk, trickster!
"Good afternoon" should be said at first.
Good afternoon. What now?
A Psycho crowd claimed
that place is your's!
Your brother, didn't
tell you anything?
Sorry... I'm...
but I am sick, sick!
Understand me? I am sick!
I am not a thief or something!
I just paid my gambling depth!
You judah iscariot! Traitor!
Bastard traitor!
You are zero! Zero!
A huge zero!
Sorry.
Zinos! Forgive me!
Tell me something!
Tell me something.
Ahhh! It was good!
I am dying.
Tell me.
Notary told that...
Place ownership will become
legal after couple of weeks.
Will it?
Ye... Yes. I think
he did.
Did he or not?
He did. He did.
Neumaaaann!
We go to Neumann first.
Don't we go to the Notary first?
Doesn't matter where we go.
Why doesn't matter?
I need to know where to drive!
Stop! Which one is more important?
Notary or Neumann?
Neumann! Neumann!
to Neumann! to Neumann!
Right! Turn right!
- Next door!
- Here? - Yes!
Here it is!
Milli! Goat!
There! Let's go!
Hey! Put them back!
We didn't agree on that!
I found it! Found it!
Good! Let's get out!
Cops! Coops!
Damn!
Go run! Ruun,
Fuck!
- Come one man! Move!
- I can't! My back! You run!
- Don't move!
- I can't anyway. I have hernia!
Raise your hands, on head!
Do it!.. Do it!
We lifted some weight ha?
- Walk!
- Don't be hard on me please.
Hey! Hey!
I am on this robbery too!
Good evening!
Drive!
What will I say to
my mother and father now?
Tell the truth.
They are too old
to hear the truth.
I think I will tell them
that I extend my contract.
Which contract?
Oil Platform job contract.
Kazantsakis?
- Which one?
- Zinos.
- Him.
You can go.
prosecutor will let you know Mr. Kazantsakis.
Take care of my brother.
Take care of yourself.
Damn. Damned!
Everything is massed up!
Anna!
- Zinos.
- My leg is paralysed, Anna!
- All my leg is paralysed!
- Hey. What is going on here?
Excuse me please.
Get the fuck out!
I can't argue about it, Anna!
Come. Come with me.
I know what to do.
- Where are we going?
- Trust me.
I want to know where
are you taking me.
You will come with me to that man,
or you need a surgery immediately.
Which man?
A physiotherapist.
Alternative Medicine.
He learned this from his father.
His father from his father,
and his father from his father...
I got it, Okay.
What is the name of the man?
Turkish people called him
Bonebreaker Kemal.
What they call?
Thanks.
Don't you have a german newspaper?
Everything will be alright.
Next!
Anna.
Can you come with me?
I don't think I will like this.
Hosht!
Hoyt!
- How do I fall in this situation?
- Zinos, you need to relax.
If you make easy, you relax!
No talking.
When three.
One...
...Two...
...Three!
I made a mistake
Zinos. I am sorry.
At least, I should call you,
do you understand? But...
...I didn't have courage to tell you.
When my grandma died...
...I have been lockdown. I was in shock.
I didn't know what to do.
Do you understand?
But, still I shouldn't
behave you like that.
You don't deserve it.
Forgive me please.
What now?
I need to take care of heritage.
You became a rich woman, don't you?
What about that man?
He returned there.
so, you?
I will return, too.
Here. Eat.
Do you hear about Shayn?
He was talking about Honduras, wasn't he?
Is your salary good enough?
My children can sky for free,
what do I need else?
It is all right.
What about your band?
We don't have place to practice.
If I ever have a restaurant...
...You can practice in it.
- Okay!
- Okay?
Thank you Chief.
Thank you.
Zinos.
Do you hear about Shayn?
I heard that he is
throwing knifes in a mobile circus.
- He was a gypsy, right?
- I guess so.
What about Illias?
You should visit him.
No need.
- Visit him..
- What for? It is nonsense.
- Lucia. You know...
- Yes, I know. "Visit him".
Go visit yourself.
Two glass of champagne please.
Illias, want to play one hand?
I don't play anymore man.
- Fuck off.
- Fuck you.
- You still own me 35 bucks.
- You will get it, don't worry.
Hey man. What about this dude?
He fucked revenue office,
and revenue office fucked him now.
Mr Neumann.
Walk forward please.
- Say hello to your brother.
- I will.
"Voyager hasn't been reach his target.
It is not over."
Shayn, Shayn, Shayn.
Where are you bro?
Public Auction
13.12.2008 Tuesday, 16:00
Hamburg Courthouse, Hall 131
Can you lend me some money?
How much do you need?
Hundred thousand Avro.
Hundred thousand Avro?
Maybe two hundred thousand Avro.
No.
Can I tell you a story?
Come inside.
Hundred and ten on bid.
Anyone raise?
- Hundred and fifteen!
- Halleluya!
- Can I get your id please?
- Of course.
Kazantsakis.
Sit please.
115.000 is offered.
Anyone raise?
- 120.000.
- 125.000.
- 130.000
- 130.000.
- 135.000
- 135.000.
One minute, one minute!
- 2 hundred thousand.
- What? Asshole!
Bastard, capitalist pig!
Sit down!
You asshole! Farm rat!
Dirty capitalist!
We are in a german court!
Unbelievable!
Quiet!
Bastard! I will kill you!
- Where we were?
- Two hundred.
Two hundred thousand is offered.
Two hundred thousand, the first one...
Two hundred thousand, the second one...
Two hundred thousand and fifteen Avro!
Two hundred thousand and fifteen, first one...
Two hundred thousand and fifteen, second...
Two hundred thousand and fifteen, third...
Mr Kazantsakis gave the highest bid.
After third time of the announcement...
Object to!
Auction is end now.
- Hey Sokrates!
- Hey Zinos!
So... I have a problem.
I can't pay december's rent.
Doesn't matter.
Yes but...
.. January and February too.
I don't care.
We are in Christmas anyway.
Special Event
German Translation: doubledutch
English Translation: niyekine