At 2:50 a.m.
on November 11, 1918,
the Associated Press flashed the
announcement that an armistice
to end World War I had been
signed at 5:00 a.m. Paris time.
Overlooked in the excitement
was that hostilities
were not to cease
until 11:00 a.m. Paris time.
Factory whistles hooted.
People began pouring into the
streets, banging pots and pans.
The celebration was premature.
War still had six hours to run.
Even though it was certain that
it would end at 11:00, men were
being sent to fight and to die
in those final hours.
Why, when it was known
to the last minute
that the war would end
and end with Allied victory,
- were men still sent into battle?
- Edwin James,
correspondent
of the New York Times covering
the 26th Yankee Division,
was stunned by the scene.
He wrote, "Reaching the front
this morning, expecting
to find quiet reigning in view
of the imminence of the
cessation of hostilities,
I found the attack
in full swing."
Why did French
field marshal Ferdinand Foch
and American AEF commander
John Pershing order
their armies to fight
to the last minute,
the 11th hour of the 11th day
of the 11th month?
Why didn't they stop fighting
when the Germans signed
the ceasefire rather than
six death-filled hours later?
>> On that last day
of World War I,
the American forces alone
suffered casualties
of over 3,200 men.
The fact that more men
were casualties
on November 11, 1918,
than on D-Day, June 6, 1944,
is more than just a historical
curiosity.
That senseless sacrifice of men
in the last 24 hours is,
in microcosm, World War I.
So what happened on the last day
is emblematic of what happened
in the four years
- that preceded it.
- It was a war
with a senseless beginning.
In 1914,
Archduke Franz Ferdinand,
heir to the Austrian throne,
visited Sarajevo.
Young Bosnian Serb
nationalists,
including a 19-year-old
named Gavrilo Princip,
plotted his assassination.
The capture of the assassins
revealed no deep
international plotting.
But the murder set off a tumble
of diplomatic blunders that
plunged 20 countries into
a disaster that would slaughter
a whole generation of youth,
over 8 million soldiers,
and a great European
civilization.
The Great War began
on August 4, 1914.
Germany launched
the opening attack.
With its crack army and
superior war plans, it planned
to finish the war early with
a crushing flank attack on Paris
through neutral Belgium.
But a brave French
counterattack
on the River Marne
caused their plan to founder.
Soon both sides were locked
along trenches that stretched
some 600 miles.
The soldiers of previous
European wars had mostly fought
in short, vicious battles of
maneuver where mobility and
strategy were quickly decisive.
In 1914, the strategy
would shrivel to a matter
of who could kill fastest
and in the most massive numbers.
>> One of the aspects
of World War I
was in terms not of technology
but of demographics.
The last time that the major
European powers had fought was
actually 100 years before
in the Napoleonic war,
when the population of Europe
was 180 million.
By 1914, it was 390 million,
and it became quite possible
to run lines
from the Swiss Alps all the way
to the English Channel.
Two opposing lines.
No flanks to turn.
Stalemate was almost
a guarantee, and stalemate
meant attrition.
The aging military
leadership, all through
the war, failed to develop
new tactics and retained
the verities of bygone wars.
Typical was the man who would
be the British supreme
commander at the war's end,
Sir Douglas Haig.
>> Sir Douglas Haig was a man
who was still caught up in the
19th-century form of warfare.
In much ways, he was like
American officers
who had been trained
to fight the Native Americans
on the Western frontier--
quick sort of open warfare,
quick charges,
that sort of thing.
Neither Haig or some of
the American officers early on
recognized the fact
that the First World War
was a war of technology.
>> World War I was
a particular horror.
The use of gas, the use
of airplanes bombing cities,
the use of tanks, and most of
all the use of machine guns
mowing down people in rows
was particularly terrible,
particularly horrific.
Even deadlier was
the introduction of light,
accurate, fast-firing artillery.
A recoiling barrel meant that
the gun carriage stayed
in position after each shot and
the crew could remain in place.
Rates of fire and casualties
soared.
Repeatedly, artillery
was lined up, a gun
every 6 yards for 15 miles,
and the objective pounded
with perhaps 4 million shells.
Then infantrymen would advance
over open, featureless terrain,
perhaps 120,000 of them,
walking into a steel shredder.
French casualties in the first
two months of the war--
dead, wounded, prisoners,
and missing--came to 360,000.
Germany had suffered
241,000 casualties.
The British had lost 30,000 men
in the first month.
Every man who had survived to
these last few days of the war
was, for the moment, a victor
over stupendous odds and
misguided leadership.
No amount of futile deaths
in huge offensives that went
nowhere had ever dented the
assumption of the opposing
general staffs that only
a few hundred thousand more guns
and men would produce
a breakthrough and victory.
A junior officer wrote
nervously, "They decided that
all they needed was another and
more copious supply of men
and a larger quantity
of ammunition."
And he feared that the generals
would want just one more try
at, literally, the 11th hour
of the last day.
>> Since the war on the Western
Front was a war of attrition,
the generals had to harden
themselves to the losses of
these troops.
And apparently they did so
rather well, because they kept
pouring these young men
into untenuous situations.
>> So you had these generals
which seemed, to the average
solider in line, who were
coming up with just ideas of
offensives, of throwing them out
into no-man's-land
- with little territory gained.
- The generals began
using the word "attrition" more
and more openly in describing
their strategy--in short,
to see which side could bleed
the other to death first.
As the last day of the war
approached, it was as though
the months and years before
had never happened at the
slaughterhouses of the Somme,
at Verdun, at Ypres, at Arras,
and Passchendaele;
as if futile headlong charges,
fast-firing long-range
artillery, and the machine gun
had never been invented;
and as if troops had never
piled up on the wire.
The last day of the war was
about to be fought,
and it would look very much
like the first day.
By 1918, Britain,
France, and Germany were all
bled white by four years of
stupefying battles of attrition.
Russia had quit the war,
freeing German armies for the
Western Front.
But America was about to enter
the fight on the Allied side.
The German General Erich
Ludendorff launched an all-out
last-ditch offensive to end
the war before the fresh,
aggressive American troops
could arrive
in overwhelming force.
>> One of the reasons that
Germany sought an armistice was
the failure of the Ludendorff
offensive that began
in March of 1918.
Ludendorff and the German
general staff had put
a tremendous amount of changes
in effect in the German army--
using small 10- to 11-man
organizations with portable
weapons like flamethrowers
and light machine guns,
using infiltration tactics
to break into the rear
of the Allied forces
- and continue an offensive.
- Ludendorff's
tactics were initially
a stunning success, pushing the
Allies steadily backwards for
many miles with heavy losses.
But the Allies soon developed
a counterstrategy--to give
ground, to bend backwards
until the German offensive had
overstretched and outrun
its supply lines.
Only when the exhausted
attackers slowed and halted
did the Allies re-engage them
frontally and drive their
thrust back with uncountable
casualties.
And quickly the Germans saw
that they had used
their last strength to repeat
the last four futile years.
With this final draining
exercise, Germany came to the
decision to seek an armistice.
Germany was collapsing beyond
its battlefields.
At home, the starving people
were rioting in the streets.
The German navy
was in rebellion.
With the realization
that imperial Germany was
disappearing, the military
leadership had to stop fighting
as soon as possible in order to
get reliable troops back home
to restore order.
Their motivation for
an armistice was nothing less
than the salvation of Germany
as a nation.
>> The armistice--
November 11, 1918--
actually stemmed from an event
that happened in January
of 1918.
And that's when President
Woodrow Wilson offered
his Fourteen Points to conclude
the war.
Among those were that Germany
had to give back all the ground
that she had gained during
World War I, as well as
Alsace-Lorraine, a piece of
French territory that had been
taken by the Germans in the
Franco-Prussian war of 1870.
When Germany was running out
of steam in the fall of 1918,
they quickly grasped for
Wilson's Fourteen Points.
And it was on that document
that they made their appeal
for peace, because it was
- the best deal they could get.
- On November 8,
1918, German and French
negotiators met in a rail car
in Compiegne, France,
to begin armistice talks.
The Allies were fully aware
of the terms the Germans were
willing to accept, which took
away any need to fight
one additional day for territory
already conceded.
But, immediately, negotiations
took a grim turn.
>> Ferdinand Foch, who was the
Allied commander in chief,
led the delegation at Compiegne
in the railroad car
to discuss negotiations
for the armistice.
And by this time,
Foch was an angry man.
I think that best describes him.
He was willing to take little
concessions from the Germans.
And so, therefore,
to be able to sit down with
the German army that had caused
such devastation, caused such
financial loss, and to have
a peaceful negotiation with them
was something beyond him.
"Ask these
gentlemen what they want" was
his shockingly dismissive
opening statement.
When the Germans stammered
that they expected to discuss
armistice terms, Foch
stonewalled them again with,
"Tell these gentlemen I have
no proposals to make."
What Foch wanted was Germany's
admission that she alone had
sought armistice.
Obtaining that, he then
hammered her delegates with
a humiliating and merciless list
of 34 demands for territory
and reparations.
Unable to forge a cease-fire
on the spot, the Germans had
to make time-consuming
communications with Berlin
to present the harsh terms to
their homeland leadership.
>> Foch gave the Germans
72 hours in which to agree
to the armistice.
And during this time,
brave men were dying
when it was quite obvious
that the Germans were going
to sign up for an armistice
and there was no need
for any more dying.
So here's a 72-hour period of
time when people on both sides
were sacrificing their life
for no good reason.
>> The German chief Erzberger
pleaded, "For God's sake,
Marshal, let us stop the
fighting during those 72 hours.
Let's not have senseless
killing while we talk."
But Foch was adamant.
He'd lost his son in this war.
He'd lost his son-in-law
on the same day.
He had seen his country
devastated.
And, as he put it to his staff,
"We're going to hold the swords
to the back of the Hun
to the very last minute."
The Allies were
certain to demand that
Germany's despised leader,
Kaiser Wilhelm, step down
as part of negotiations,
and his staff asked him do so.
Wilhelm, ever raging to
continue the war
to the last soldier, refused.
>> Some of their leaders had
talked to him on November 8th,
brought up the fact that he was
going to have to abdicate
the throne.
He didn't accept it.
Finally, on the 9th,
he does accept it.
Then you have to move him out
of Germany.
So all during this time,
battle is still going on
in the Western Front.
An average of
2,250 troops on all sides were
dying on the Western Front
every day that the fighting
went on.
The Germans finally realized
that more time would buy them
nothing but more death
and returned
to the negotiating table.
>> The German and Allied
representatives who met to
arrange an armistice on the
morning of November 11th signed
at 5:00 that morning.
However, the ceasefire was not
to take effect until 11:00.
So we have six hours of
a decisional no-man's-land.
What's to happen between then?
The only order that was given
was to stop fighting at 11:00.
And so we had a situation where
commanders had to determine,
what were they going to do with
their divisions in the interim?
Essentially,
there were two groups.
There were the professional
career officers who saw
a fast-fading opportunity
for glory, for victory,
and perhaps promotion.
And you had a more sensible,
humane factor who reasoned,
"This war is going to be over.
Why should I send my men to
die today for territory that
they can walk into peacefully
tomorrow?"
At 5:00 a.m.
Paris time on November 11th,
on paper, the war was over.
It was a moment that should
have unleashed joy and
salvation for the soldiers.
But on the last day
of World War I, many officers
would decide to keep fighting
to the last awful second.
The armistice
ending the Great War
on November 11, 1918,
had been signed at 5:00 a.m.
But the fighting on the last
day of World War I was to
rage on until 11:00 a.m.
On the German side, a young
veteran, Herbert Sulzbach,
had been pondering
his personal good fortune
in these closing minutes.
"I do not believe," he confided
to his diary, "that there are
many soldiers who were
stationed at the front for
50 months and are coming home
as I am now, unwounded."
But suddenly he was looking
at a menacing advance
of enemy troops.
A brown mass was emerging
from the American line as if
the ground itself were moving.
What lunacy was this?
The war was over and lost.
The German officers had read
them the cease-fire order
earlier that morning.
They had no desire to kill more.
Yet they still had a mission.
>> Here was an army that had
a very definite mission, and
that is to cover the withdrawal
of their forces so that
organized units could go back
into Germany and create
stability and to eliminate
rioting in the streets and to
save the German government.
And these soldiers were
completely baffled by American
organizations that were
attacking at the last minute.
The advancing
Americans were soldiers
of the 26th Infantry Division.
They were one of the divisions
delivering an attack planned
before the armistice, then
cancelled, then reinstated
when there were no
confirming orders to stand down
from the assault.
A look at the mindset
that kept the fighting going
to the 11th hour
could be found in a letter sent
by a tough American
artillery captain
busy raining fire on his enemy
to the last second.
To his fiancée, he wrote,
"It is a shame we can't go in
and devastate Germany
and cut off a few of
the German kids' hands and feet
and scalp a few
of their old men."
The man
behind the shocking sentiment,
Captain Harry Truman,
would one day manifest
that hardness as president
of the United States
during World War II.
Elsewhere on the last day,
American lieutenant Harry
Rennagel had rushed back to his
unit from the hospital when he
heard the armistice rumors.
He found his comrades jubilant,
then suddenly plunged
into stunned silence when
the attack order was renewed.
At 10:35 a.m., bayonets fixed,
they went over the top.
At 10:55 a.m., a shell exploded
a dozen yards from Rennagel.
"I hurried over, and there lay
five of my best men,
one fatally injured
with a hole near his heart.
He said, 'You know, we all
expected things to cease today,
so I wrote my girl we were to
be married when I returned.'"
There would be no wedding.
Near the center of the American
front, Marine Elton Mackin had
survived 156 days at the front.
Whether he would survive the
last day depended heavily on
the actions of his commander,
General Charles P. Summerall.
>> Summerall was
a tough officer.
On the eve of the armistice,
he calls his subordinate
commanders together and says,
"I want you to cross the Meuse
River during the night."
And then he added rather
cryptically, "I don't expect
to see any of you again."
The orders passed
down from Summerall announced
the astonishing goal of their
final attack of the war.
It was to provide support
for an operation planned for
November 14th, three days
after the armistice.
Elton Mackin, tagged three
times for medical evacuation,
had torn up his ticket to
remain with his fellow Marines
as they went forward.
Enemy Maxims embedded
in the hills knocked down men
like target soldiers
in a shooting gallery.
Still, they kept coming.
By early morning,
the marines and the infantrymen
of the 89th Division
had crossed the Meuse River
and taken the town of Pouilly.
>> Elton Mackin survives,
gets across the Meuse River.
However, that crossing has
cost the American army
1,100 casualties
in the very last hours
of the war.
The very next morning,
when the fighting stops,
General Summerall goes down
to the riverbank
and takes a few steps out
onto one of these bridges,
turns around, and goes back
- to his chateau headquarters.
- General
Summerall's personal risk
in the operation had involved
nothing more than the danger of
getting his feet wet
in a photo opportunity.
Summerall, like all the
American officers, could claim
that on this last day of the
war, he was just interpreting
the orders of his American
commander, John Pershing.
>> John Pershing knew
that President Wilson wanted
to get this war over
as soon as possible.
But no one from Washington was
telling him precisely
what to do.
He took a very ambivalent
attitude towards whether or not
units should continue fighting
or not.
Pershing was of the opinion
that an armistice, simply
a ceasefire, would not be
sufficient to deter Germany
from again attacking in Europe
and being an aggressive nation.
So he was not enthusiastic
at all about the armistice.
Pershing was
content to issue no commands
that would prevent his
ambitious officers from going
on fighting and punishing
the hated enemy until the last
possible second of the war.
>> Among the divisions engaged
on that last day was
the 81st Infantry Division.
The 81st, in those final hours,
lost 365 men.
Why?
The men had been hoping that
their war was over, that within
hours they would go on
to lead full lives, go home,
marry, have children,
pamper grandchildren.
So why are they sent forward?
The general who commanded the
division had information that
there were bathing facilities
in the town of Stenay,
and so the town is taken.
It's the last city that the
Americans take in World War I.
And for this indefensible
reason, men have given
their lives.
By November 11,
1918, the war on the Western
Front had dragged on
over four horrible years.
But even as word finally
reached the front that
an armistice was coming
in a few hours,
soldiers continued to die.
The New Englanders of the 26th
Yankee Division were taking
casualties from German Maxim
machine guns at the very moment
their neighbors back in Boston,
Providence, and New Haven began
spilling into the streets to
celebrate the end of fighting.
A tragic 192 of these men whose
return was already being
cheered were doomed to fall
in these last senseless hours.
>> The amazing thing about
the motivation of soldiers
on November 11th, some who
even knew that in a few hours
the armistice would go into
effect, was they would attack
simply because their comrades
were attacking.
And so they went with them.
Why the doomed
soldiers went forward with
their units could only be
explained by the superhuman
bond they had formed
with one another.
A soldier wrote in his war log,
"We give away anything we have
if we think the other fellow
needs it more than we do.
I like the unselfish attitude
up here so much that, in many
ways, I wish I could live
on the front forever."
On the last day, this human
caring was the only visible
good to have come out
of all the killing.
As the clock ticked down,
there was an unspoken question
in the casual spending
of American life
with nothing left to gain.
Why were African-American
soldiers, almost unused
by Pershing through so much of
the war, committed to a frontal
assault in the last hours?
Were some lives worth less
than others?
>> At the front on the last day
of the war is the 92nd Division.
This is an all-black division
run by white officers.
They rallied around the flag in
the hope that what they could
not earn in the cotton patch or
in the cornfield, they could
earn on the battlefield--
that is, full American
citizenship.
Still, in this war,
they received
second-class treatment,
second-class training,
second-class equipment,
- and second-class duties.
- These troops had
excelled in battle when
assigned to French units.
But under poor American
leadership, a few had faltered
in battle and were stigmatized.
Lieutenant General Robert Lee
Bullard wrote of them,
"Our government seemed
to expect the same of them
as of white men.
Poor Negroes.
They are hopelessly inferior."
>> The 92nd assumes on the eve
of the armistice that their war
is over.
They're going to survive.
They're going to go back home.
However, the next morning,
there remains in force
an operational plan involving
the blacks in the 92nd.
John Sherburne, a general,
questions the corps commander,
the army commander.
"Are we really sending the men
into battle at this late hour?"
He's informed, "Yes."
And he describes his reaction
- as one of absolute horror.
- On that last
morning of the war, the men of
the 92nd came out of their
position in a wooded area
to a hail of German machine gun
and artillery fire.
Some 190 of these
African-American soldiers died
within hours of the end
of the war.
Major Warren Ross was
an officer with the 92nd.
When the war ended,
a heartbroken Major Ross
wrote sadly
of their brave performance.
"My heroic battalion.
The battalion has earned
undying fame for itself,
its regiment, its brigade,
its division, and for
the American colored race."
Hundreds of miles up the front,
the town of Mons, where the
British Expedition Force had
suffered their first major
defeat in the first days of
the war, had powerful symbolic
significance.
The battle's survivors had been
given a treasured special
decoration, the Mons Star.
Now, four years later, when
the British could have marched
unopposed into Mons
on November 12th,
they chose to attack
and retake it on the 11th.
Sergeant Will Bird was one
of the first men
into the outskirts.
>> They find
three dead soldiers.
Bird notices that they are
wearing the Mons Star.
That means that these are men
who were engaged the very
first day of the war.
They have survived to the very
last day only to die
in the last hours.
And so the British high command
has achieved its symbolic wish;
the first defeat of the British
has been vindicated by their
recapture of the city of Mons.
They are back
where they started the war
700,000 British lives later.
On November 11th,
the cannoneers that had created
the artillery hell that had
characterized the war were not
only unwilling to end their
barrages; they eagerly
redoubled their fire.
>> In the very last hours of
the war, there was a terrific
bombardment.
Every side is firing off
every round of ammunition
they have left.
It's as though at a country
fair, they want to shoot off
all the fireworks
before the festivities end.
This ammunition is being
fired off randomly to get rid
of it and in expectation of
the arrival of peace.
But these rounds don't make
that distinction,
and in the very last moments,
men are dying from this random
artillery fire.
Death stayed to
the very last moment of the war
and was about to provide
Private Henry Gunther of the
American 313th a tragic place
in American history.
>> On this last morning of
the war, Henry is positioned
along a hillside in a place
called Ville-devant-Chaumont.
Just hours left in the war,
but the 313th doesn't know it.
No word has yet reached
this regiment.
With 16 minutes left
in the war, a runner catches up
to the 313th and says,
"Ceasefire at 11:00."
Nothing is said about what is
to happen in these last
16 minutes.
Up ahead are German machine gun
emplacements.
Henry Gunther
starts approaching
these machine guns.
His men alongside and his
comrades urge him to stay back.
The Germans are appalled
by this.
They're waving him back.
He moves on.
He's shot through the head.
Henry Gunther dies at 10:59
that morning with a minute left
in the war and becomes
officially the last American
casualty of World War I.
According to the
most conservative estimates,
during the last day of the war,
principally in the six hours
after the armistice was signed,
all sides on the Western Front
suffered 10,944 casualties,
with 2,738 deaths.
Eventually, people were going
to ask why.
Taking the daily
rate of death and wounding in
the Great War as a standard,
had Marshal Foch accepted
Mattias Erzberger's plea
to stop the fighting
on November 8th while
negotiations were underway,
it is likely that 6,624 lives
would have been spared
and 14,895 maimed, burned,
gassed, and blinded men would
instead have gone home whole.
A parent supplied
a heartbreaking epitaph:
"To all the world,
he was a soldier.
To me, he was all the world."
>> Soon after the war ended in
1918, members of Congress began
receiving rather poignant
letters.
People wanted to know why did
a son, a husband, a brother die
in the last hours of a war
when it was clearly known that
the war was about to end.
On that last day
of World War I,
the American forces alone
suffered casualties
of over 3,200 men.
Subsequently, when these
letters became numerous enough,
Congress created
a subcommittee to investigate
- this matter.
- On November 5,
1919, almost a year after
Armistice Day, General Pershing
was called to testify before
the House of Representatives'
Committee On Military Affairs.
He was questioned by
congressman Alvan Fuller.
Fuller probed directly at why
American troops were ordered
over the top on the morning
of the last day.
Under the terms of the
armistice, these same troops
could have marched peacefully
into Germany at 11:00.
Pershing cited that the leader
of the Allied armies, Ferdinand
Foch, had not commanded
a cessation of hostilities
and that he, Pershing,
as the American commander,
had properly informed
his subordinate officers
of the fact of the armistice.
But he had said nothing about
what they should do
until 11:00 a.m.
His order thus created a limbo
in which these commanders were
free to decide whether
to keep sending men
into the meat grinder
or to cease fighting at once.
Different decisions ended lives
or preserved them.
Subcommittee member Oscar Bland
stepped in and knifed to the
heart of the matter as he
questioned the reluctant key
witness, General Fox Conner,
Pershing's chief of operations.
Bland demanded, "Would it have
been best under the
circumstances to have included
in that order that hostilities
should cease as soon as
practicable before 11:00?"
Conner stonewalled.
"No, sir, I do not."
Bland pursued
with icy determination.
"How many generals did you lose
that day?"
"None," said Conner.
"How many colonels did you lose
that day?"
"I do not know how many were
lost," replied Connor.
Bland said coldly,
"I am convinced
that on November 11th,
there was not any officer
of very high rank taking any
chance of losing his own life."
He then spoke for all the
unnecessarily bereaved families.
"I resent that these lives were
lost, and the American people
resent the fact that these
lives were lost."
General John Sherburne,
a decorated officer, pulled no
punches in his denunciation of
the events of November 11th.
He testified, "They did not
look upon human life
as the important thing.
They had set up what, in my
opinion, was a false standard
of excellence of divisions
according the amount of ground
gained by each division.
It was much like a child who
had been given a toy that he is
very much interested in and
that he knows within a day
or two it is going to be taken
away from him, and he wants to
use that toy up to the handle
while he has it."
By the end of January,
the hearing concluded.
The committee arrived
at the verdict that needless
slaughter had occurred on the
last day of World War I.
The full Select Committee on
expenditures in the war adopted
the report.
Justice and the placement of
responsibility were primed
for arrival.
But then the politicians
stepped in, wrapping themselves
alternately in the flag
and raw partisan maneuvering.
The report was preparing to
defame America's victorious
leadership in a war that had
brought the nation
onto the world stage.
The names of the generals
Liggett, Pershing, and Bullard
were going on monuments.
Some in Congress saw
a Republican plot to criticize
the army and the conduct of the
war by a Democrat president.
The report was recalled.
The recall set off three hours
of acrimonious debate
that changed nothing.
On March 3rd, any imputation
that American lives had been
needlessly sacrificed on the
last day of World War I had
been struck away.
Nothing remained of the tragedy
except thousands
of broken hearts.
>> But on all sides,
there were men who would not be
returning home to wives, to
careers, to becoming parents,
to becoming pampering
grandparents.
They would not be returning home
because of the decisions made
out of vainglory and pride
by other men whose lives were
- not risked that last morning.
- The madness of
fighting to the last moment
of the 11th month, 11th day,
11th hour soon would be
forgotten in the long euphoria
of armistice celebrations
and victory parades.
Nobody yet realized that
victory would have its costs.
The vengeful armistice
had paved the way
for an even bloodier conflict.
The war to end all wars
would be refought
by the same enemies
barely 20 years later.
It turned out that the dying
from the first day onward
had been as senseless
as it had been on the last.
Captioning by CaptionMax
www.captionmax.com