%%
[GRINDING NOISE]
[CLICK]
I HAVE
A PRIORITY PACKAGE
FROM THE NAT-SAT
PRINTING ROOM.
WHY DON'T YOU
SAY IT A LITTLE LOUDER?
WE COULD OPEN
THE WINDOW.
YOU COULD SHOUT IT
TOWARDS MOSCOW.
SORRY. I--
IT'S NOT YOUR FAULT
YOU'RE STUPID.
JUST OPEN THE CASE
AND GET OUT OF HERE.
THE CASE IS CHAINED
TO MY WRIST.
SECURITY DISPATCH
HAS THE KEY.
LEAVE THE MATERIAL,
TAKE THE CASE,
AND WAIT OUTSIDE.
NO CAN DO.
THE MATERIAL'S
LOCKED INSIDE.
ALL RIGHT.
JUST GIVE IT TO ME.
GET IN THE CLOSET.
HI-WEATHER IV
TRANSMITTED THIS STUFF
AN HOUR AGO.
BEAUTIFUL CLOSE-UPS!
MIEGS AND SLINE
WILL DROOL.
THEY'RE LATE AGAIN.
UNUSUAL FOR SOLDIERS.
THEY KNOW
WHAT THEY'RE DOING.
GENTLEMEN.
HERE THEY ARE.
ARE THOSE THE SHOTS
FROM THE LATEST FLY-BY?
OVER HERE, GENERAL.
WAIT.
IS SOMEONE
IN THIS CLOSET?
IGNORE HIM.
HE'S JUST ONE
OF OUR COURIERS.
WELL...OK.
NICE CLOSE-UPS.
DEFINITELY APPROACHING
FULL-GO HOUR.
I GREASED THE HOUSE COMMITTEE
FOR COVERT APPROPRIATIONS.
THEY THINK THE FUNDS ARE
FOR MORE STEALTH BOMBERS.
WE'VE SELECTED
2 GLG-20s--
THEY'RE THE BEST MEN
WE HAVE.
THE LAST 2
WERE THE BEST MEN WE HAD.
NOW THEY'RE OUR
2 BEST DEAD MEN.
I'M CONVINCED
THERE'S A SECURITY LEAK
IN YOUR TRAINING PROGRAM.
WELL, WE COULD
BYPASS TRAINING.
NO. THEY'LL TRAIN WITH
2 OTHER GLG-20s--
2 WHO ARE RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE PROJECT
AND 2 WHO ARE...
DISPOSABLE.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING
WE ASSIGN THIS JOB
TO INFERIOR PERSONNEL?
NO, I UNDERSTAND.
2 TEAMS.
ONE TO DO THE JOB,
THE OTHER
TO BE A DIVERSION.
YOU MEAN DECOYS? TARGETS?
EXACTLY.
GLG-20s DON'T
EXACTLY GROW ON TREES.
I'D HATE TO WASTE
2 OF THEM AS TARGETS.
I'M SURE YOU CAN FIND
A COUPLE OF MEN
YOU WON'T MIND WASTING.
%% I'LL BE %% WHEN? %%
LOVIN' YOU %%
%% CLOUDY DAYS OR SUNNY %%
%% LOVIN' YOU %%
%% ARE YOU SURE? %%
?
%% THAT'S A PROMISE, HONEY ?
%% WHEN YOUR KISS CAN
NO LONGER PACK A THRILL %%
[SMACK]
NOTHIN'.
%% I'LL STILL
BE LOVIN' YOU %%
%% I'LL BE HUGGIN' YOU %%
%% HOW? %%
%% LIKE A BABY PANDA,
KISSIN' YOU %%
%% WHERE? %%
%% ON YOUR
OLD VERANDA %%
%% WHEN YOUR CHARM, DEAR,
IS ABSOLUTELY NIL %%
YEAH, I KNOW. YOU'LL
STILL BE LOVIN' ME.
%% BILLIN', COOIN' %%
%% YOU I'LL KEEP
PURSUIN' %%
%% ALWAYS LOVIN' %%
%% HOTTER THAN
A BAKER'S OVEN %%
%% WE DO SMART WORK %%
WHAT?
%% YOU'LL JUST LOVE
OUR ARTWORK %%
%% DON'T BLAME ME... %%
WHAT?
AREN'T YOU TAKING
THIS TEST TOMORROW?
THE FOREIGN
SERVICE BOARD? YEAH.
DON'T YOU
HAVE TO STUDY?
I KNOW THE FSB EXAM
GLASS-BACKWARDS.
I'VE TAKEN IT
3 TIMES ALREADY.
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE
DIFFERENT THIS YEAR--
500 QUESTIONS
IN 2 HOURS.
LET ME SEE
THE BOOKLET.
LOOK AT THESE SAMPLES.
ALL MULTIPLE CHOICE.
IT'S EASY.
HERE.
"IF DISCOVERED APPROPRIATING
CLASSIFIED DOCUMENTS
"AT A FOREIGN
CONSULATE RECEPTION,
"YOU SHOULD...
A--EXPRESS CONCERN,
"B--ACT SURPRISED,
"C--DENY EVERYTHING,
AND D--ALL 3."
THE ANSWER IS "D," ALL 3.
COMMON-SENSE STUFF.
I GUESS YOU JUST DON'T WANT
ADVANCEMENT BAD ENOUGH.
MY GRANDDAD
WAS AN ENVOY.
MY DAD WAS AN ENVOY.
I WAS BORN
INTO THE TRADE.
BESIDES, I'VE ARRANGED
FOR AN INTIMATE LUNCH
WITH OUR SUPERVISOR.
YOU HAVE TO TAKE
THAT TEST.
I'M VERY HURT THAT'S WHY
YOU INVITED ME OVER.
DON'T DO THAT, ALICE.
I'M SORRY.
I'M NOT MYSELF TODAY.
I SAW MY NEUROLOGIST
THIS MORNING.
DON'T GIVE ME SOME
BULLSHIT YOU'RE DYING.
NO...
NOT NOW.
Radio:  %% 'CAUSE THERE'S
ONE THING WE FORGOT TO SAY %%
%% WE'RE GONNA
ROCK THE HOUSE DOWN %%
MILLBARGE.
%% WE'RE GONNA
SHAKE UP THE PLACE-- %%
WHERE'S THE BRAIN
FOR THE SCRAMJAM 7000?
PROCUREMENT PICKED IT UP
OVER AN HOUR AGO.
WAS IT FIXED?
YEAH, WITH NEW
VOICE-SCRAMBLERS.
OH. WHAT ABOUT THAT
RED-CHINESE RADIO CHATTER?
IT'S DONE.
HERE YOU GO.
DONE?
THAT WAS A STATIC-FILLED,
TRIPLE-SCRAMBLED
MICROWAVE TRANSMISSION
BETWEEN 2 SOLDIERS
TALKING IN MANDARIN CHINESE.
THEY WERE ONLY USING
A SIMPLE POLYPHONETICALLY
GROUPED 20-DIGIT KEY
TRANSPOSED
IN BOUSTROPHENDONIC FORM
WITH MULTIPLE NULLS.
I BROKE IT WITH THIS.
A DROGAN'S
DECODER WHEEL?
THEY PUT THESE INTO
CEREAL BOXES FOR KIDS.
YEAH, I FOUND IT IN
A BOX OF LUCKY CHARMS.
BREAK IT DOWN AGAIN
WITH THE MACHINES!
I ALREADY DID.
WELL, THEN...
CLEAN UP THE DESK!
GOOD.
THAT'S MUCH BETTER.
BY THE WAY, GOOD LUCK
ON THE TEST TOMORROW.
WHAT TEST?
THE FOREIGN SERVICE
BOARD EXAMS. GOOD LUCK.
FOREIGN SERVICE
BOARDS TOMORROW?
I CAN'T TAKE IT.
I HAVEN'T STUDIED.
I'M NOT PREPARED.
YOU WERE BUMPED UP
ON THE LIST.
YOU'RE SCHEDULED
FOR TOMORROW MORNING.
I'M SURE I TOLD YOU.
THIS IS DATED
2 WEEKS AGO.
YOU PLANNED THIS.
YOU WANT ME
TO FAIL THAT TEST
SO YOU CAN KEEP ME IN
THE CENTER OF THE EARTH
DOING YOUR WORK FOR YOU.
YOU JUST WATCH
YOUR MOUTH, MISTER.
THIS DEPARTMENT'S LAYING OFF
CIVILIANS LEFT AND RIGHT.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
HOME. TO STUDY.
ONE NIGHT STUDYING
FOR A GRADE-19 FSB EXAM?
GOOD LUCK.
LISTEN, CAPTAIN, I'M
GOING TO PASS THAT EXAM,
AND I'M GOING TO GET
OUT OF THIS HOLE
AND DO SOME REALLY IMPORTANT
WORK FOR NATIONAL SECURITY.
YEAH, SURE.
I WAS GOING TO DO
YOUR FAMILY A FAVOR
AND HOOK UP
THE DISNEY CHANNEL FOR FREE.
WELL, FORGET IT.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
AS OF THIS AFTERNOON,
THE UNDERSECRETARY
FOR SOUTH AMERICAN AFFAIRS
EMPHATICALLY DENIES
ANY AND ALL INTERVENTION
IN THE CURRENT REALIGNMENT
OF TOP POSITIONS
IN THE PARAGUAYAN AIR FORCE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WHAT ABOUT
THE ARMY'S REQUEST
FOR SPRAYING
SUBSIDIES?
ARE THERE
ANY PARAGUAYANS HERE?
NO?
THEIR REQUEST FOR SUBSIDIES
WAS NOT PARAGUAYAN,
AS IT WERE.
THE UNITED STATES WOULD NEVER--
IF THE PRESIDENT--
THAT'S HOW IT WILL ALWAYS BE.
IS THAT CLEAR?
HOW CAN YOU SAY
WE AREN'T SPENDING
MILLIONS ON SPRAYING
WHEN THE INTERNATIONAL
WHEAT BOARD REPORTED
"EXTENSIVE CONTAMINATION
IN THE GRAIN FIELDS
OF SOUTHERN ARGENTINA"?
THE STATE DE...EBER...
UH...THE STATE...
MICROPHONES...
CUTTING OUT ON US.
I'M SORRY.
HOWEVER,
THE QU...WO...SI...
...UNCH DATE,
SO I MUST GO.
THESE EXAMINATIONS
ARE QUALIFIERS FOR POSITIONS
IN THE INTELLIGENCE SECTIONS
OF OUR EMBASSIES OVERSEAS.
THE NATURE OF YOUR POSTINGS
WILL BE SECRET.
NOW, SECRET WORK
CAN BE VERY RISKY.
I CITE WHAT HAPPENED TO ONE
OF OUR GREATEST AMERICANS--
NOT YET!
OOP!
EXCUSE ME.
I'M SORRY.
MY FAULT.
I'M SORRY I'M LATE.
I HAD TO ATTEND
THE READING OF A WILL.
I HAD TO STAY
TILL THE VERY END.
I FOUND OUT
I RECEIVED NOTHING.
BROKE MY ARM.
[CLEARS THROAT]
WOULD YOU HOLD MY WALLET
WHILE I TAKE THE TEST?
THERE'S $1,000 IN THERE...
OR MAYBE THERE ISN'T.
KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
ARE YOU SAYING
I CAN TAKE THIS MONEY
IF I HELP YOU PASS?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
THANK YOU.
SO, WHERE DO I--
SIT DOWN!
YOU MAY BEGIN...
NOW.
[BREAKS WIND]
EXCUSE ME.
AHEM.
AHEM! AHEM!
AHEM! AHEM! AHEM!
AHEM!
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
OH, GOD, THE PRESSURE!
I CAN'T TAKE IT!
I CAN'T!
I CAN'T DO IT!
[SOBS]
I CAN'T...WHAT PAGE?
THIS IS
EMMETT FITZ-HUME.
HE'S AN INFORMATION
OFFICER AT STATE.
HE STARTED THERE IN '74
AS A MAIL BOY.
HIS FATHER
GOT HIM HIS JOB.
THIS IS AUSTIN MILLBARGE.
HE'S A REPAIR SUPERVISOR
IN DIA'S CODE-BREAKING ARM
AT THE PENTAGON.
WIGGLED INTO SUPERVISOR'S PAY
THROUGH AN F-SECTION.
HIS LAST JOB
BEFORE JOINING DEFENSE
WAS FIXING OFFICE COPIERS.
HE'S GOOD WITH HARDWARE,
GOT SOME RUSSIAN.
WANT TO SEE
THEIR TEST SCORES?
WHAT THE HELL FOR?
THEY'RE A COUPLE OF ABSOLUTELY
SELF-INVOLVED BULLSHIT ARTISTS
WHO GOT CAUGHT CHEATING
ON A DEPARTMENTAL EXAM.
THEY'LL DO ANYTHING
TO SAVE THEIR JOBS.
ONE'S GOT
BASIC DIPLOMACY SKILLS.
THE OTHER'S A CODE-BREAKER
WITH LANGUAGE ABILITY.
I BELIEVE
WE'VE FOUND OUR DECOYS.
AHHH!
HEART ATTACK!
CAN I BORROW YOUR PEN?
EVERYBODY,
PLEASE, STAND BACK!
I AM A TRAINED
CARDIOVASCULAR
RESPIRATORY EMERGENCY
ASSIST TECHNICIAN.
I WANT ALL OF YOU TO STAND BACK!
THIS MAN NEEDS AIR!
IN FACT, ALL OF YOU
SHOULD LEAVE THE ROOM--
WELL?
SO, WHAT ARE WE GONNA GET?
DISMISSAL? SUSPENSION?
CENSURE? DEPARTMENTAL
PROSECUTION? WHAT?
PROMOTION.
WHAT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE LIKE WHAT WE'VE
SEEN OF YOU TWO.
WE'RE BUCKING YOU
RIGHT UP FRONT
TO GATHERING,
LEVEL 20.
GATHERING,
LEVEL 20?
THAT'S QUITE A STEP UP
IN BASE PAY.
WE'RE NOT
IN TROUBLE?
WE'RE NOT RECRUITING
FOR THE BOY SCOUTS.
WE WANT PEOPLE
WHO ARE AGGRESSIVE,
WHO KNOW HOW
TO GO AFTER THAT EDGE
YOU NEED TO SURVIVE.
WE ESPECIALLY LIKED
THE WAY YOU TWO GUYS
WERE WORKING AS A TEAM
IN THERE.
NOW...
IF YOU FEEL
YOU CAN WORK TOGETHER,
YOU'RE ON YOUR WAY UP.
WE'VE GOT A VERY
SPECIAL ASSIGNMENT.
FOREIGN SERVICE?
YES.
UNDERCOVER WORK?
EMMETT FITZ-HUME.
AUSTIN MILLBARGE.
WHEN DO WE BEGIN
OUR TRAINING?
RIGHT AWAY.
BOY!
WE'RE JUST
HITCHING A RIDE.
THEY WON'T
MAKE US JUMP.
JUMP? NO CHANCE.
WE WON'T HAVE TO JUMP.
[BELL RINGS]
ALL RIGHT,
SKY-TROOPERS!
LET'S GO!
GO?
WHAT DOES HE MEAN?
YOU CAN'T DO THIS!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
AAAH!
FITZ-HUME!
HELP! HELP! HELP! HELP!
OH! OH, NO! OH, NO!
WHOA!
AAAH!
WOOOAAAHHH!
OOOH!
WHERE ARE WE?
I DON'T KNOW.
I WASN'T WATCHING.
I LOST EVERYTHING
AT 7,000 FEET.
[HOO]
YOU HEAR THAT?
YEAH.
IT'S A DICKFER.
WHAT'S A DICKFER?
TO PEE WITH.
Man: AAH!
WAS THAT ME?
EIIAAWW! HAIII!
WE NEED A PLAN.
LET'S PLAY DEAD.
EIIAAWW!
HAIII!
COME ON, SUPERSPY,
THINK OF SOMETHING.
YOU'RE THE DIPLOMAT.
TALK TO THEM.
ALL RIGHT.
STOP RIGHT THERE,
AND I'LL BRING
BACK THE SUN.
OK?
THIS IS MY SISTER.
YOU CAN
ALL HAVE HER.
I HEAR
SHE'S VERY GOOD.
ONE MORE STEP,
I START SWINGING!
HE'S THREATENING YOU!
LET'S GET HIM!
SHOW SOME BALLS!
IT'S TOO LATE TO TRY
TO IMPRESS THEM.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
AUSTIN MILLBARGE?
HERE, SIR.
EMMETT FITZ-HUME.
HELLO.
SIR.
COLONEL RHOMBUS,
SPECIAL PROJECTS TRAINING.
WE'VE BEEN EXPECTING YOU.
EXCUSE ME, BUT WHAT
WAS ALL THIS, UH...
THAT'S HOW
I WELCOME NEW TRAINEES.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH
COFFEE AND A HANDSHAKE?
IT'S MY JOB TO GET YOU READY
FOR FIELD COMBAT.
I MUST KNOW RIGHT AWAY
WHAT I'VE GOT TO WORK WITH.
I'VE MADE MY DECISION.
WHAT'S IT SAY?
"PUSSY."
THAT'S NOT FAIR.
THEY HAD SWORDS.
WHAT COULD WE DO?
IT DEPENDS ON YOUR
PARTICULAR ARENA OF COMBAT.
MAYBE THIS.
I'LL TAKE YOU
BACK TO THE BASE.
THIS IS
THE OBSTACLE COURSE.
IT IS ESSENTIALLY THE COURSE
FAMILIAR TO
ARMED SERVICE RECRUITS,
EXCEPT HERE IN INTELLIGENCE
OPERATIVE TRAINING,
WE DO IT A BIT DIFFERENTLY.
WE ADD THE ELEMENT
OF SCORCHED EARTH.
THIS IS YOUR STANDARD
BOG NEGOTIATION TRIAL.
YOU'LL BE JUDGED
ON SURVIVABILITY AND TIME.
ENTER...
NOW!
HEADS DOWN!
THIS WILL
VERIFY YOUR ABILITY
TO STAY AFLOAT
AT HIGH SPEEDS.
WE'LL NOW
BEGIN WITH AFPSR--
AIR FORCE
PASSIVE STRAIN RESPONSE.
YOU'LL NOT BE REQUIRED
TO EXERT YOURSELF AT ALL,
ONLY TO SURVIVE AGGRAVATED
BODY TEMPERATURE MEASUREMENT.
WHOA!
OOOH!
OWWW!
HOT! HOT! HOT!
WE WILL NOW DETERMINE
YOUR G-FORCE THRESHOLD.
JUST RELAX, GENTLEMEN.
I GUESS
WE JUST SIT HERE?
PIECE OF CAKE.
YOU WANT SOME COFFEE?
THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
COLONEL,
WE WERE JUST TALKING,
AND, UH, WE'VE HAD
LOADS OF FUN HERE.
MET NEW FRIENDS,
HAD A GREAT LUNCH.
WASN'T THAT
A GREAT LUNCH?
THE TUNA AND CREAM
CASSEROLE WAS BEAUTIFUL.
ANYWAY, WE WERE TALKING,
AND WE'D LIKE TO GO HOME NOW.
THANKS FOR THE BRUISES.
KEEP THE STOOL SAMPLES.
BOYS, IT WOULD BE A SHAME
TO HAVE TO KILL YOU NOW.
WHAT DID HE
MEAN BY THAT?
IT MEANS WE'RE O.I.O.
WHAT'S THAT?
OBLIGATED
INVOLUNTARY OFFICERS.
GENTLEMEN,
BEGIN RADICAL VERTICAL
IMPACT SIMULATION...
NOW.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
COME IN.
YOU WANTED
TO SEE US, SIR?
SIT.
CONGRATULATIONS, MEN.
YOU'RE ABOUT TO ENTER
THE OPERATIONAL PHASE
OF YOUR ASSIGNMENT.
I'M NOT AUTHORIZED TO GIVE YOU
THE FULL OPERATIONAL PACKET,
BUT I'LL TELL YOU THE LOCATION
OF YOUR INITIAL DROP
WILL BE WELL INSIDE
THE BORDERS OF PAKISTAN.
PAKISTAN?
IS ONE OF THESE PEOPLE
OUR CONTACT?
OK...
WHO LED THE AMERICAN LEAGUE
IN HOME RUNS IN 1953?
I'LL HANDLE THIS.
[SPEAKING PASHTU]
WHAT'S HE DOING?
IT'S JUST THEIR WAY
OF SAYING HELLO.
HELLO.
I'M AUSTIN.
[SPEAKING PASHTU]
HI. BUD SCHNELKER,
LIAISON OFFICE.
U.S. CONSULATE,
KARACHI.
ROB HODGES.
DIA, WEST ASIAN SECTION.
WELCOME TO PAKISTAN.
BOY, WE'RE GLAD
TO SEE YOU GUYS.
WHEN'S LUNCH?
COME ON, GUYS.
JEEP'S OVER HERE.
Emmett: I'M STARVING.
WHAT TIME YOU GOT?
LISTEN, COULD WE STOP?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
I GOT TO TAKE A LEAK.
YOU SHOULD GO, TOO.
WHAT ARE YOU,
MY MOTHER?
DON'T YOU THINK I'M
CAPABLE OF DETERMINING
MY OWN TIME TO GO
TO THE BATHROOM?
SO, ISN'T NOW
ONE OF THOSE TIMES?
NO.
YOU DON'T FEEL A CERTAIN
DEGREE OF URGENT PRESSURE
ON THE INNER WALL
OF YOUR BLADDER
NOW RIGHT AT
THIS MOMENT?
NO. I'M FINE.
WELL, WOULDN'T YOU FEEL
MORE COMFORTABLE
BEING FULLY RELIEVED
OF EXCESS FLUID SNOW?
I GOT TO TAKE A WHIZ?
DON'T GO AWAY.
OH, WE'LL BE HERE.
THESE GUYS ARE NOT
OUR LEGITIMATE CONTACTS.
THEY'RE KGB SPECIAL BRANCH.
OH, COME ON.
THAT WAS
A RUSSIAN WRISTWATCH.
I KNOW THE COUNTRY OF ORIGIN OF
EVERY TIMEPIECE IN THE WORLD.
THAT WAS A RUSSIAN COPY
OF A 1969 TIMEX DIGITAL.
IS THIS YOUR HOBBY?
BASIC. MOST COMMON
SLIP-UP IN ESPIONAGE.
WE WALKED RIGHT
INTO ENEMY HANDS.
HI.
IF YOU DO KNOW YOUR
FINAL OBJECTIVE,
YOU'D BE SMART
TO TELL US.
WE'LL WORK THINGS
OUT A LOT QUICKER.
WE STILL
DON'T KNOW.
YOU KNOW WHAT THEY SAY
ABOUT THIS TYPE OF OPERATION...
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
DA! DA!
DA!
FEET.
HAT.
COME ON!
LOOK OUT!
THEY SURE HAD ME FOOLED.
THE SOVIETS OBVIOUSLY
KNOW WE'RE HERE NOW.
WHERE TO, BOSS?
FIRST WE CHECK
OUR GASOLINE SUPPLY.
HOW'S OUR
GASOLINE SUPPLY?
8 5-GALLON CANS.
ENOUGH TO GET US
TO AN AIRPORT?
I HOPE SO.
WE'LL DRIVE IN SHIFTS.
ONE GUY'LL DRIVE,
THE OTHER'LL SLEEP.
OK. I'LL DRIVE,
YOU SLEEP.
WAKE ME UP
WHEN YOU GET TIRED.
OK.
GOOD NIGHT.
SLEEP TIGHT.
THANKS.
DON'T LET
THE BEDBUGS BITE.
OK.
NIGHT.
[WHISTLING]
GOOD MORNING.
IS THERE
AN AIRPORT NEAR HERE?
[SPEAKING PASHTU]
AUSTIN.
YOUR TURN TO DRIVE.
THESE ARE
THE YUSUFZAI.
THEY'RE AFGHANI
FREEDOM-FIGHTERS.
THEY'RE OUR ALLIES.
OH!
WE'RE AMERICANS!
[SPEAKING PASHTU]
DR. HADLEY!
OH, MY GOD!
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
[SPEAKING PASHTU]
SORRY ABOUT THIS.
THEY'RE VERY DISTRUSTFUL
OF OUTSIDERS.
NO PROBLEM.
GET YOUR MEN
TO CUT THEM DOWN.
[SPEAKING PASHTU]
WHO ARE YOU?
OH, SORRY. HADLEY.
LONDON COLLEGE OF MEDICINE.
THEY ONLY ALLOW US HERE BECAUSE
WE'RE HELPING WITH THE WOUNDED.
THEY DIDN'T REALIZE
YOU WERE WITH THE EFFORT.
WITH WHO?
THE UNITED NATIONS
MEDICAL EFFORT, OF COURSE.
AREN'T YOU DOCTORS
TROWBRIDGE AND GREENBERG?
DOCTORS?
YEAH, SURE,
THAT'S US.
I'M DR. TROWBRIDGE.
THIS IS DR.--
GREENBERG.
GREENBAUM.
GREENBAUMBERG.
WE'RE DOCTORS.
EVERYBODY LOOKS
FINE HERE, RIGHT?
YES, DOCTOR.
STICK YOUR
TONGUE OUT, PLEASE.
EVERYTHING'S FINE.
WE'LL HEAD BACK
TO THE OLD U.N.
AND LET THEM KNOW WHAT
A GOOD JOB YOU'RE DOING.
AH, THE AMERICAN
SENSE OF HUMOR.
COME ON. THE OTHERS ARE
ANXIOUS TO MEET YOU.
HAVE WE RECEIVED THE LAST
SHIPMENT OF PENICILLIN YET?
NOT YET. NO.
POSSIBLY
TOMORROW.
2 ENVOYS
ARE COMING.
HERE WE ARE.
I'M HADLEY,
INTERNAL MEDICINE.
DR. LA FONG,
COMMUNICABLE DISEASES.
DR. BOYER,
BACTERIOLOGY.
DOCTORS STINSON,
MARSTON, AND GILL
OF THE NORTHAMPTON
TRAUMA INSTITUTE.
AND DR. IMHAUS
OF THE ZURICH RELIEF FUND.
OUR NEW SURGEONS,
TROWBRIDGE AND GREENBAUM.
DOCTOR.
AND DOCTOR.
DID WE MISS ANYONE?
YOU GENTLEMEN RELAX.
THE TRIBE'S RAIDING A SOVIET
TANK DIVISION TOMORROW.
THERE WILL BE PLENTY
FOR US TO DO THEN.
DOCTORS.
DOCTOR.
WE'RE NOT DOCTORS.
WE'VE GOT TO LEAVE
HERE IMMEDIATELY!
NO. NOT UNTIL I'VE HAD--
EXCUSE ME.
HER.
AM I INTERRUPTING?
NO! HE WAS JUST
ON HIS WAY OUT.
What happens when
the real doctors come?
HI.
DR. TROWBRIDGE.
WHERE?
OH! RIGHT!
MAKE YOURSELF
COMFORTABLE. SIT DOWN.
THANK YOU.
[CRASH]
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
DR. TROWBRIDGE--
MAY I CALL YOU HOMER?
WHY?
WELL, THAT'S YOUR NAME.
OH! RIGHT!
HOMER. OF COURSE.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
KAREN.
DR. TROWBRIDGE...
HOMER...
WHEN YOU WALKED
INTO THIS TENT,
IT WAS THE MOST EXCITING
MOMENT OF MY LIFE.
WELL, YOU JUST WAIT.
YOU'RE MY HERO. I'VE
READ ALL YOUR PAPERS.
HOW'D YOU GET
MY PAPERS?
OH, YOU MEAN
MY MEDICAL PAPERS!
ARE YOU
MAKING FUN OF ME?
OH, KAREN,
OUR FIRST FIGHT.
YOU MIGHT THINK I'M SILLY
TO WORSHIP YOU THE WAY I DO,
BUT IN MY ESTIMATION,
YOU'RE A GENIUS.
WELL, I THINK GENIUS
IS A PRETTY STRONG WORD,
BUT IF YOU INSIST ON USING IT,
I CAN HANDLE IT.
IN FACT, I HESITATE
TO MENTION MY PROBLEM.
IT'S A TASK HARDLY WORTHY
OF YOUR ABILITIES.
GO AHEAD. MENTION IT.
THERE'S NOTHING
I WOULDN'T DO FOR YOU.
THE KHAN'S BROTHER,
HE'S BEEN SUFFERING
FROM PAIN IN
THE RIGHT LOWER ABDOMEN,
OBVIOUSLY
AN INFLAMED APPENDIX.
OBVIOUSLY.
DR. HADLEY WAS
GOING TO REMOVE IT,
BUT NOW THAT
YOU'RE HERE,
JUST TO SEE YOU PERFORM
EVEN A SIMPLE SURGERY
WOULD BE A GREAT THRILL
IN MY LIFE.
I'D REALLY RATHER NOT.
I DON'T HAVE
MY INSTRUMENTS WITH ME.
USE DR. HADLEY'S.
THE KHAN'S BROTHER
IS BEING PREPPED NOW.
IF YOU REFUSE
TO DO THIS,
THE KHAN WILL LOSE
FAITH IN YOU AND US.
THE CONSEQUENCES
COULD BE SEVERE.
I SEE.
WELL, THE TRUTH IS
I AM A GREAT SURGEON,
BUT ALAS, I RECENTLY SUFFERED
SEVERE NERVE DAMAGE
IN MY LEFT HAND.
OH, MY GOD!
YEAH. LOOK AT THAT.
NO FEELING AT ALL.
DEAD.
HOW DID THAT HAPPEN?
I WAS LIFTING
A CAR OFF A CHILD.
IT WAS A BIG CADILLAC.
I'M SO DISAPPOINTED.
THE KHAN WILL BE
VERY SUSPICIOUS.
MY GOD.
OH, THERE, THERE, THERE.
ACTUALLY, I COULD
OPERATE WITHOUT MY HANDS.
DR. GREENBAUM
COULD BE MY HANDS.
I COULD TELL HIM
WHAT TO DO.
YOU WOULD GET A CHANCE
SEE ME IN ACTION.
THAT WOULD BE
WONDERFUL.
AFTER I GUIDE DR. GREENBAUM
THROUGH AN OPERATION,
I GET VERY DEPRESSED.
I COULDN'T
DO IT MYSELF.
IT'S A VERY BAD TIME
FOR ME.
DON'T YOU WORRY.
I'LL BE WITH YOU.
GIVE ME A BREAK.
ABOUT AN HOUR?
FINE. AN HOUR.
THANK YOU.
BYE.
YOU'RE GOOD WITH TOOLS,
AREN'T YOU? INSTRUMENTS?
YOU KIDDING? YOU'RE
TALKING TO MILLBARGE.
WANT SOMETHING CONVERTED,
BUILT, REPAIRED, MODIFIED?
YOU'RE TALKING
TO MR. HANDS.
AHH. MIND IF
I PLAY THROUGH?
DOCTOR. DOCTOR.
GLAD I'M NOT SICK.
IF ANYTHING HAPPENS TO HIM,
MY PEOPLE WILL BE ANGRY.
TO DIE IN BATTLE
IS GLORIOUS.
TO DIE IN A TENT
IS DISGRACE.
AND WITH THAT, I GIVE YOU
DR. JULIUS GREENBAUM.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
I'LL JUST STEP OUT
FOR A SMOKE.
PERHAPS
I'LL STAY HERE.
TODAY WE'LL BE REMOVING
THE PATIENT'S APPENDIX.
THE FIRST STEP IN AN OPERATION
OF THIS PARTICULAR TYPE IS...
TO SHAVE THE PATIENT.
NAH, FORGET IT,
FORGET IT.
WE'LL SKIP THE SHAVE
AND GO TO THE OPERATION.
THE SECOND STEP
IN THIS OPERATION IS...
ANESTHETIC.
BUT CAN'T YOU TELL
HE'S ALREADY BEEN GIVEN
THE REQUIRED INJECTION
OF PENTOTHAL?
OF COURSE.
HE'S ALREADY BEEN GIVEN
THE REQUIRED...INJECTIONS.
ALL RIGHT. LET US BEGIN
THE OPERATION.
[CRASH]
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
AND NOW,
THE FIRST INCISION.
DOCTOR.
ISN'T THAT INCISION
A BIT HIGH
FOR AN APPENDIX?
DO YOU WANT TO DO
THE OPERATION?
FINE! YOU COME ON UP HERE,
AND YOU DO IT!
IMHAUS.
HE WAS CUTTING
INTO HIS CHEST!
DID I CUT HIS CHEST?
I WAS PROBING TO DETERMINING
MUSCLE TONE AND SKELETAL GIRTH.
IT'S A NEW TECHNIQUE!
WE MOCK WHAT
WE DON'T UNDERSTAND.
GO AHEAD, WILL YOU?
I'M GETTING HUNGRY.
AND NOW,
THE FIRST INCISION.
I WILL INCISE.
CUT THE SUCKER.
AHHHHH...
THIS MAN IS DEAD.
[WHISTLING]
[SPEAKING PASHTU]
EXCUSE US.
THANK YOU.
LET ME DO IT!
EMMETT!
HELP ME!
LET GO!
THE DRIVE-IN
IS CLOSED.
WE'RE WITH
THE ACE TOMATO COMPANY.
ALL THIS
CLOAK-AND-DAGGER STUFF.
THE MILITARY LOVE IT.
CHRIST, WILL YOU
LOOK AT THIS PLACE?
MR. RUBY.
SIR.
MR. KEYES.
YES, SIR.
WON'T YOU GENTLEMEN
HAVE A PEPSI?
2 PEPSIS TO GO.
NOW WHAT?
"WHY DON'T YOU
GENTLEMEN HAVE A PEPSI?"
YOU DO IT.
AAAH!
THIS WAY,
GENTLEMEN.
WELCOME TO W.A.M.P.
GENERAL SLINE, SIR.
YES, SERGEANT?
IT'S A COLLECT CALL FROM
PAKISTAN FOR MR. RUBY
FROM MR. FITZ-HUME.
WHAT?
WE'LL JUST BE
ANOTHER MINUTE.
THANK YOU
FOR YOUR PATIENCE.
IT'S COLLECT. THEIR
CONTACTS TRIED TO KILL THEM.
THEY DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
AND THEY TOLD YOU THIS
OVER A PUBLIC PHONE?
NO, SIR. AT&T's OPERATOR
TOLD OUR OPERATOR.
THEY'RE INSANE!
AND APPARENTLY
ROAMING FREE.
HE'S ON LINE 7, SIR.
GET US THE HELL OUT!
EVERYTHING'S UNDER
CONTROL, MR. FITZ-HUME.
HOLD ON ONE MOMENT.
LOOK, THE LONGER THEY'RE
OUT IN THE FIELD,
THE MORE HEAT WE CAN DRAW
AWAY FROM THE REAL TEAM.
I AGREE. LET'S SEND THEM
OVER THE BORDER.
HOW WILL
THEY GET THERE?
THAT'S THEIR PROBLEM.
HELLO, GENTLEMEN.
WE'RE ORGANIZING
A RESCUE OPERATION FOR YOU.
FOR AFTER YOU'VE REACHED
YOUR FINAL OBJECTIVE.
WHAT IS
OUR FINAL OBJECTIVE?
THAT INFORMATION IS ON
A NEED-TO-KNOW BASIS.
AT THIS PARTICULAR TIME,
YOU DO NOT NEED TO KNOW.
HOWEVER, WE CAN TELL YOU
TO MAKE IMMEDIATELY
FOR THE SOVIET PAMIR DISTRICT.
WAIT FOR YOUR NEXT CONTACT
ON THE ROAD TO DUSHANBE.
THE ROAD TO DUSHANBE?
YOU PRACTICALLY TOLD THEM
THE STRIKE ZONE.
LISTEN, IF THEY
MAKE IT THERE AT ALL,
THEY'LL BE PLUCKED BY
SOVIET MOTORIZED INFANTRY.
THE ROAD TO DUSHANBE
IS A HEAVILY TRAVELED
MILITARY ARTERY.
I GUESS THAT
TAKES CARE OF THAT.
WE MUST MAKE
NO MISTAKES THIS TIME.
OUR WHOLE WAY OF LIFE
HANGS IN THE BALANCE.
PAMIR? DUSHANBE?
YOU'RE SURE
THAT'S WHAT HE SAID?
RIGHT. AREN'T THEY
IN RUSSIA?
AND HOW!
[SPEAKING
PASHTU]
NO, THANKS.
I'VE ALREADY EATEN.
HOW CAN WE GET THERE?
IT'S THOUSANDS OF MILES.
IF THIS IS
THE LOWER KOHISTAN,
WE'RE ABOUT 150 MILES
FROM THE SOVIET BORDER.
YOU WOULD HAVE TO
KNOW THAT.
WAIT A MINUTE!
HOW DO WE CROSS
THE SOVIET BORDER?
WE DON'T SHAVE,
SELL THE AMBULANCE,
SELL OUR CLOTHES,
AND GO NATIVE.
HOW FAR DO WE HAVE
TO GO ON THIS BUS?
AS FAR AS IT
TAKES US.
HEY, LOOK!
IT'S DR. BOYER!
SHE'S THE LAST PERSON
WE WANT TO SEE.
NO! SHE'S NICE.
WHAT'S THIS, THE BORDER?
NO. TOLL STOP.
HOPEFULLY, THERE WON'T BE
GUARDPOSTS WHERE WE CROSS.
LOOK.
DR. BOYER.
LEAVE IT ALONE.
I LEFT WITHOUT
SAYING GOOD-BYE.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
YOU CAN'T DENY WHAT
HAPPENED BETWEEN US.
DON'T TOUCH ME.
COME ON.
"DON'T TOUCH ME."
LOOK AT THIS.
IT'S REALLY NEAT.
HOW CAN SHE LET A LITTLE DEATH
INTERFERE WITH ROMANCE?
THEY COULDN'T
HAVE DONE BETTER.
THEY AREN'T DOCTORS.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
THAT METAL CASE SHE WAS
PACKING ON HER HORSE.
WHAT ABOUT IT?
IT'S A SAT SCRAMBLER
TERMINAL.
SOPHISTICATED EQUIPMENT
FOR SENDING, SCRAMBLING,
AND RECEIVING
SATELLITE MESSAGES.
SO SHE'S
A SOPHISTICATED WOMAN.
IT'S A HIGHLY
CLASSIFIED PIECE
OF INTELLIGENCE
HARDWARE.
SHE'S A HIGH-CLASS
INTELLIGENT PIECE.
KNOCK IT OFF.
YOU'RE SAYING THAT
THEY'RE SPIES LIKE US?
THEY'RE SPIES, BUT NOT
NECESSARILY ON OUR SIDE.
I THINK IT'S OUR DUTY
AS AMERICAN OPERATIVES
TO FOLLOW HER AND
FIND OUT WHAT SHE'S UP TO.
YOU JUST WANT
TO FOLLOW HER.
NO.
YOU'RE THINKING
WITH YOUR DICK.
THEY LEFT THEIR
LAND ROVER HERE.
THEY'RE PROBABLY
HEADED FOR THE BORDER.
IT WOULD SAVE US
A LOT OF TROUBLE.
THEY SEEM TO BE HEADED
IN THAT DIRECTION.
MAYBE YOUR DICK'S
NOT SO DUMB.
GOT ME THROUGH
HIGH SCHOOL.
DO YOU THINK THOSE MEN
ARE FOLLOWING US?
THEY'RE MOST LIKELY
CHITRALI NOMADS.
NOT TO WORRY.
DID YOU SAY SIT?
I DIDN'T SAY SIT.
NO, I DIDN'T SAY SIT.
WHAT--
NOW WHAT?
I GUESS WE WALK.
[GROWLING]
WHY DO WE HAVE TO CARRY
ALL THIS STUFF?
THE DUSHANBE ROAD RUNS ACROSS
THE TOP OF THE MOUNTAINS.
IT'LL BE SUB-ARCTIC
TEMPERATURES UP THERE.
YOU'LL THANK ME.
"YOU'LL THANK ME."
THAT'S IT.
THE DUSHANBE ROAD...
WHERE WE'RE SUPPOSED
TO MEET OUR CONTACTS...
I HOPE.
ONLY INSOFAR AS IT
SERVES TO CONFIRM
THE PRESIDENT'S
OWN BELIEFS.
THIS IS QUITE
AN EXCITING PROJECT.
WHAT WAS THE COST OF
THIS STAR WARS SYSTEM?
JUST UNDER
$60 BILLION.
QUITE A BARGAIN.
SIR, PRINTOUT
FROM GRAVSAT.
A TRANSMISSION
FROM THE FIELD,
YOUR GLG-20s.
WELL, WONDERFUL.
THEY CONFIRM
ESTIMATED ARRIVAL
AT THE STRIKE SITE
BY 6 P.M.
THEIR TIME TOMORROW.
THAT'S 9 A.M. HERE.
RIGHT ON SCHEDULE.
YOU CAN ALWAYS
COUNT ON OUR PEOPLE.
WELL, THIS IS IT.
WHERE ARE THOSE CONTACTS
WE HEARD SO MUCH ABOUT?
DID THEY SAY WHERE
ON THE ROAD?
NO.
MAYBE WE SHOULD
START HITCHHIKING.
WE'RE INSIDE
THE SOVIET UNION.
I WISH WE HADN'T
LOST BOYER.
THEY HAD HORSES.
WE WERE ON FOOT!
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
It's the Tadzhik
Highway Patrol.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
They were just
sitting there.
They heard our
entire conversation.
[SPEAKING
RUSSIAN]
WHAT ARE THEY SAYING?
HE SAYS WE NEEDN'T
BOTHER WHISPERING.
LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
THEY'LL CUT US DOWN.
WE CAN'T JUST
GO WITH THEM.
WHAT OTHER CHOICE
DO WE HAVE?
IF WE GIVE OURSELVES UP,
THE STATE DEPARTMENT
WILL GET US HOME.
NOT ME!
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
HI! JUST ME.
I WAS JUST LOOKING FOR
THE BURT REYNOLDS THEATER.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
DON'T I GET
A PHONE CALL?
AND WHO DO YOU
INTEND TO CALL?
GODDAMN IT!
HE GIVES HIMSELF UP!
WHAT IS
YOUR OBJECTIVE?
MY OBJECTIVE?
WELL, I OBJECT TO
BUYING A GIRL DINNER,
THEN SHE WON'T
PUT OUT FOR YOU.
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
WHY AM I HERE?
WHY IS ANYBODY HERE?
I THINK SARTRE SAID--
HOW DO YOU SPELL SARTRE?
OW! AND LET THAT
BE A LESSON TO YOU!
EVERY MINUTE YOU DON'T
TELL US WHY YOU'RE HERE,
I CUT OFF A FINGER.
MINE OR YOURS?
YOURS.
DAMN!
WHY ARE YOU
STILL HITTING ME?
HE'S GOING TO CUT
MY FINGERS OFF!
YOU HAVE 30 SECONDS.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA HUM
THE JEOPARDY THEME?
WE START WITH
THE LITTLE ONE.
ALL RIGHT!
I'M AN AMERICAN AGENT.
AND?
AND, UH...
THEY SENT ME HERE
TO ASSASSINATE YOUR PREMIER.
I KNEW IT!
PAY UP, COMRADE.
LET'S CUT HIS
FINGERS OFF ANYWAY.
NO.
LET'S TAKE HIM TO
HEADQUARTERS IN MOSCOW.
GOOD MOVE.
HEADQUARTERS.
IT SHOULDN'T BE MUCH FURTHER.
WE'VE MADE GOOD TIME.
WE'LL GO ON FOOT
FROM HERE.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
OW! OHH!
WHOA!
GODDAMN IT!
AH--AHH--AHHH!
WHOA! WHOA!
HI!
HOW YOU DOING?
REMEMBER ME?
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
THEY SURPRISED US.
BORDER TROOPS.
THEY GOT MY PARTNER.
DID THEY
GET YOU, TOO?
I'M FINE!
NO WONDER NEITHER
OF YOU COULD OPERATE.
YOU'RE SPIES LIKE US!
YOU MEAN, YOU'RE--
AUSTIN MILLBARGE.
I'M A GLG-20.
SO...
YOU TWO ARE
THE OTHER GLG-20s.
THE DECOYS.
DECOYS!
LOWER YOUR VOICE.
THAT'S WHY THEY RUSHED
US THROUGH TRAINING,
WHY WE WERE MET
BY THE KGB,
WHY THEY SENT US
INTO ENEMY HANDS.
RIGHT.
I AM--extremely
pissed off!
MY PARTNER AND I
WERE SET UP!
FORGET IT!
THAT'S BEHIND US!
OUR FIRST PRIORITY
IS TO COVER THOSE BODIES,
ESTABLISH
A NEW BASE CAMP,
AND COMPLETE
THIS PROJECT.
FITZ-HUME'S
IN THE CUSTODY
OF THE TADZHIK
HIGHWAY PATROL
BECAUSE OF YOU.
THE ONLY PROJECT
I HAVE TO COMPLETE
IS TO GET
MY PARTNER OUT.
FITZ-HUME!
COME ON!
LOOK! DID YOU DO THAT?
YEAH. I DID THAT
FOR YOU.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
YOU KNOW, I MUST
REALLY LIKE YOU,
BECAUSE I DON'T
LIKE HORSES,
AND I HATE GUNS.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
WHAT'S THIS?
YOU DON'T WANT IT!
AAH!
DUCK!
I'LL GET THE HORSE.
LET'S GO!
HI-HO, SILVER!
AWAY!
[MUSIC PLAYS]
ITS SOUL FINGER
BY THE BAR-KAYS.
THEY MUST BE HAVING
TROUBLE GETTING GIGS.
WOW!
THIS IS A SOVIET
ICBM SITE.
Austin: THAT'S
AN SS-50 LONG-RANGE ROCKET
AND MOBILE LAUNCHER.
THEY JUST MOVED IT
IN HERE.
HAVEN'T EVEN PUT UP
THEIR LOCATOR BEACON.
MEANS THEY'RE NOT HOOKED
INTO SOVIET DEFENSE.
THEY ARE RADIO-ISOLATED.
ONLY 3 MEN.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
AND THEIR MOTHER.
OH!
LET ME SEE THAT.
HEY!
COME ON!
HONESTLY!
YOU TWO
ARE UNBELIEVABLE!
WAIT A MINUTE.
WHAT ARE WE DOING HERE?
THIS IS OUR FINAL OBJECTIVE.
OUR PROJECT ORDERS
ARE TO SUBDUE THE CREW
AND SEIZE CONTROL
OF THIS EMPLACEMENT.
HOLD IT, SISTER. WE'RE
NOT GOING NEAR THAT THING.
THAT MISSILE HAS
A 40-MEGATON NUCLEAR WARHEAD.
GOOD NIGHT,
EVERYBODY.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
HOME.
FOR ONCE, I'M IN
COMPLETE AGREEMENT.
WE SHOULD GET UP AND
LEAVE IMMEDIATELY.
THOSE THINGS CAN SUCK
THE PAINT OFF YOUR HOUSE
AND GIVE YOUR FAMILY
A PERMANENT ORANGE AFRO.
I DON'T WHAT YOU TWO DO,
BUT I'M FULFILLING
MY OBLIGATION.
I INTEND TO GO DOWN THERE
AND SEIZE CONTROL
OF THAT EMPLACEMENT,
ALONE IF I HAVE TO.
YOU KNOW WE'D DO
ANYTHING FOR YOU,
BUT WE CAN'T
SEIZE THAT ROCKET.
WE'D HAVE TO KILL
EVERYBODY DOWN THERE.
I'M NOT
KILLING ANYBODY.
I'M NOT, EITHER.
GENTLEMEN, I THINK
YOU BOTH SHOULD REALIZE
THE GRAVITY
OF THIS MOMENT.
I'VE SPENT THE LAST
2 1/2 YEARS OF MY LIFE
PREPARING FOR
THIS PENETRATION.
THIS AFTERNOON, I BURIED
MY PARTNER JERRY HADLEY,
PERHAPS THE FINEST,
MOST DEDICATED GLG-20
IN THE HISTORY
OF THE SERVICE.
HE IS NOW ENTOMBED
IN A SNOWY GRAVE,
AND IT'S NOT GONNA BE
FOR NOTHING.
WE ARE HERE TODAY
TO GUARANTEE
THE PERSONAL FREEDOM
OF EVERY AMERICAN.
AND WE SHOULD NEVER FORGET
THE WORDS OF PRESIDENT
JOHN F. KENNEDY
WHO SAID, "ASK NOT WHAT
YOUR COUNTRY CAN DO FOR YOU,
BUT WHAT YOU CAN DO
FOR YOUR COUNTRY."
WILL YOU MARRY ME?
NOW...
THESE ARE HIGH-COMPRESSION
TRANQUILIZER PISTOLS.
WE'RE NOT GOING
TO KILL ANYBODY,
BUT YOU'VE GOT TO GET
IN CLOSE TO USE THEM.
HOURS--T-MINUS 2 UNTIL
DESIGNATED TARGET APOGEE.
SIR, ALL AIR TRAFFIC
HAS BEEN DIVERTED
FROM OUR
RESPONSE CORRIDOR.
WHAT'S OUR PRESENT
ON-LINE POWER READING?
MICHIGAN REACTOR
AND WASHINGTON STATE
ATOMIC PLANTS
ON-LINE, GENERAL.
LOCK US IN, SERGEANT.
W.A.M.P. SECURE, SIR.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GO TO
RESPONSE LEVEL YELLOW.
INITIATING LEVEL YELLOW.
[ALARM SOUNDS]
RUN YOUR FULL SERVO
AND ARMING.
[ALARM SOUNDS]
SERVO ON AND ARMED.
[ALARM]
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
AH...
SOUL FINGER!
[MUSIC PLAYS]
SOUL FINGER.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
WHAT'S SHE SAYING?
HAIR...HAIRBRUSH...
HEADREST...
WHERE DID YOU LEARN YOUR
RUSSIAN, J.C. PENNEY?
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
WHEN SHE WAS A CHILD
IN LITHUANIA,
HER UNCLE USED TO TELL A STORY
ABOUT STRANGE BEINGS
THAT CAME DOWN FROM
A DISC AND STOLE AN OX
WHICH THE VILLAGE HAD
PUT ASIDE FOR ROASTING.
I TOLD YOU
IT WOULD WORK.
EVERYBODY KNOWS
ABOUT UFOs.
APPARENTLY, THE ALIENS
DISSECTED THE OX
AND KEPT THE BEST PIECES
OF MEAT FOR THEMSELVES.
SO WE OWE THEM
A COW.
WHERE DO WE GET ONE?
NEE NEE NEE!
DE DE DE!
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
DO WHAT I DO.
AAH! AAH! AAH!
AAH!
SAT SCRAM SIGNAL
FROM THE STRIKE SITE.
YOUR GLG-20s HAVE
PENETRATED SUCCESSFULLY
AND ARE AWAITING
THE GO-CODE.
OPEN AND LOCK DOWN
GROUND DEFLECTORS.
GROUND DEFLECTORS
OPENED AND LOCKED.
[ALARM SOUNDS]
OK, DOSTOEVSKY,
WHAT DOES IT SAY?
IT SAYS...
"APPROACH SS-50...
SOURCE PROGRAMMABLE
ROCKET."
EASY.
"FIND CONTROL BOX
AT FRONT OF TRANSPORTER."
THIS IS A SNAP.
"FOR ERECTOR PANEL,
PUSH RED BUTTON."
"DEPRESS RED KEY SWITCH.
ENTER FIRST
NUMBERED SEQUENCE."
GO.
"3-3-9...
"DASH 2-5-9...
DASH 6."
"ACKNOWLEDGE COMPLIANCE
ON SAT SCRAM NOW."
GLG-20s ACKNOWLEDGE
PROGRAMMING AND COMPLIANCE.
BRING ALL BIRDS
INTO FINAL BOUNCE MODE.
BOUNCE MODE ENGAGED.
SEND THEM THE GO-CODE.
"GO WITH NUMBERED
SEQUENCE 7-4...
"DASH 7-4...
"DASH 8-8-3...
DASH 5, DASH 3."
[HONKING]
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SAC-COM CONFIRMS
AN OUTBOUND BLIP
FROM SOVIET CENTRAL ASIA.
IT'S ON ITS WAY.
OVERRIDE ALL SAC ALERTS
WITH ERROR STAND DOWN ORDERS
FOR 10 MINUTES.
SAC OVERRIDE CODE
ENTERED.
ERROR. STAND DOWN.
I THINK WE JUST STARTED
WORLD WAR III.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SHE WANTS TO KNOW WHY
WE WOULD DO SUCH A THING.
TELL HER
SO DO WE.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
WHAT ARE THEY
SAYING?
IT'S 4:47 A.M.
THEY'RE SAYING IT'LL BE
28 MINUTES
BEFORE THE ROCKET DETONATES
ABOVE ITS TARGET
SOMEWHERE INSIDE
THE CONTINENTAL UNITED STATES.
LET'S SEE--28 MINUTES.
THAT'S 18 UNTIL IT'S
INSIDE THE U.S. RADAR CUP.
FIGURE 2
FOR OUR RESPONSE,
SAY, 20 UNTIL
TOTAL COMMITMENT.
FIGURE 20, 22
UNTIL THE FIRST IMPACT
OF OUR RETALIATORY STRIKE.
I FIGURE
WE HAVE 42 MINUTES
UNTIL THE END OF CIVILIZATION
AS WE KNOW IT.
YOU WANT TO GO OUT
WITH A BANG?
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
IT WAS JUST AN IDEA.
YOU KNOW, IF WE WERE
SITTING IN A BAR,
I'D THROW A DRINK
RIGHT IN YOUR FACE...
BUT UNDER
THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
IT'S NOT SUCH
A BAD IDEA.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
RELEASE FULL PULSE.
3...
2...
1.
FIRE!
BOUNCE PULSE FAILED TO
CONNECT WITH TARGET, SIR.
JUST WHAT ARE YOU
SAYING, SOLDIER?
WE MISSED IT, SIR.
WHAT?
WE MISSED THE ROCKET.
IT DIDN'T WORK.
DIDN'T WORK?
WHERE DID THE PULSE GO?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR, BUT
IT DEFINITELY DIDN'T CONNECT
WITH THE INBOUND TRAFFIC.
[MTV THEME PLAYS]
WOW!
EXCELLENT!
WE'D BETTER
CALL THE PRESIDENT.
WE'RE NOT CALLING ANYONE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
WE'RE NOT CALLING ANYONE?
THE PRESIDENT MUST KNOW
THAT THIS ATTACK
WAS NOT INITIATED
BY THE SOVIET UNION.
WE ARE PREPARED
FOR THIS CONTINGENCY.
WHAT IN HELL DO YOU
INTEND TO DO?
YOU UNDERSTAND, SIR,
THAT WE ARE RESPONSIBLE
FOR LAUNCHING A NUCLEAR WEAPON
AGAINST OUR OWN COUNTRY?
NO ONE OUTSIDE
THIS COMMAND CENTER
HAS THAT INFORMATION,
GENTLEMEN.
WHEN WE COMMISSIONED
THE SCHMECTEL CORPORATION
TO RESEARCH THIS PRECISE
EVENT SEQUENCE SCENARIO,
IT WAS DETERMINED THAT
THE CONTINUAL STOCKPILING
AND DEVELOPMENT
OF OUR NUCLEAR ARSENAL
WAS BECOMING
SELF-DEFEATING.
A WEAPON UNUSED
IS A USELESS WEAPON.
SAC-COM CONFIRMS
ALL DEFENSE SYSTEMS
COMMITMENT READY.
WE HAVE VERIFICATION.
THE PRESIDENT IS ABOARD
THE AIRBORNE COMMAND CENTER.
I'M SURE IT WILL ONLY BE
A MATTER OF MINUTES
BEFORE THE PRESIDENT
COMMITS TO TOTAL RELEASE.
JESUS CHRIST!
YOU SEE, WE HAD TO SHOW
THAT WE HAD
THE TECHNICAL CAPABILITY
AND WERE DETERMINED.
HISTORY DEMONSTRATES
CONCLUSIVELY
THAT NAIVE
WISHING FOR PEACE
IS THE SUREST
POSSIBLE WAY
TO ENCOURAGE
AN AGGRESSOR.
I DEMAND YOU PLACE ME
IN IMMEDIATE COMMUNICATION
WITH THE PRESIDENT!
RELAX, MR. RUBY.
THIS FACILITY IS MORE THAN
ADEQUATELY STOCKED
FOR A COMFORTABLE 17 MONTHS
OF BELOW-GROUND EXISTENCE.
WE'LL BE FINE.
BY YOUR ACTIONS, SIR,
YOU ARE RISKING THE FUTURE
OF THE HUMAN RACE!
TO GUARANTEE
THE AMERICAN WAY OF LIFE...
I'M WILLING
TO TAKE THAT RISK.
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE
IT'S BEEN ONLY 15 MINUTES
SINCE I DESTROYED
THE WORLD.
IN ANOTHER 15 MINUTES,
IT WILL ALL BE OVER.
IT'S SUCH A SHORT TIME
TO DESTROY A WORLD.
AND TO THINK MY HIGH SCHOOL
GUIDANCE COUNSELOR
SAID I'D NEVER
AMOUNT TO ANYTHING.
IT JUST GOES TO SHOW--
GUIDANCE! SOURCE
PROGRAMMABLE GUIDANCE!
FITZ-HUME! BOYER!
GET UP! GET UP!
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
COME ON! COME ON!
COME ON!
FITZ-HUME!
BOYER!
UM...
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
WAIT A MINUTE!
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
YOU HAVE A TENT?
BRING ME
THE SAT SCRAM DISH.
I THINK WE CAN
RECALL IT.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
RECALL IT?
YOU MEAN LIKE
A DEFECTIVE PINTO?
[SPEAKING
RUSSIAN]
TAKE THIS UP.
UP. CLIMB.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
GRAB A ROCK.
GRAB A HAMMER.
WE CAN DIVERT IT.
IT'S MADE TO RESPOND
TO IN-FLIGHT COMMANDS.
HERE'S A ROCK.
GO TO THE SAT SCRAM
TERMINAL.
NOW WHAT?
SMASH THAT THING!
IT'S BROKEN.
BRING IT HERE.
NOT THE ROCK.
WHAT'S THE USE? IT'S
PROBABLY ALL OVER ANYWAY.
NO, NO, NO.
ALL WE HAVE TO DO IS
SWITCH SENDING BOARDS.
OK.
START SENDING THE LAUNCH
SEQUENCE IN REVERSE ORDER.
YES, SIR.
[BEEPING]
FITZ-HUME...
HOLD THESE TOGETHER.
I'VE GOT
TO MAKE THE SPLICE.
HOLD IT TOGETHER.
OW! I GOT A SHOCK.
AND YOU WILL.
I DON'T CARE
HOW PAINFUL IT IS,
YOU'VE GOT
TO HOLD THEM TOGETHER.
YOU ARE THE CIRCUIT BRIDGE.
B-B-BUT...
I NEED, UH...
BIGGER
THAN A BREAD BOX?
I NEED, UH, UH...
THE TITLE
OF A MOVIE?
ANIMALS AND
THEIR NATURAL HABITATS?
THE TITLE OF A BOOK?
THINGS THAT ARE BEING
ELECTROCUTED?
I GOT IT!
MILES--
5.
ZERO.
WE DID IT!
WE DID?
CAN I BORROW YOUR TENT?
SAC-COM CONFIRMS
DESTRUCTION OF THE INBOUND.
WHAT ABOUT THE REST
OF THEIR INBOUNDS?
THERE ARE NONE, SIR.
BOTH THE U.S. AND SOVIET
RESPONSE CHAIN ON FULL RECALL.
DAMN.
RECALLED.
PLACE THEM UNDER ARREST--
ALL OF THEM.
WAIT! WE DON'T KNOW
THESE MEN.
WE WERE KIDNAPPED.
THAT'S RIGHT!
KIDNAPPED!
YES! WE WERE. WE WERE
AT THE DRIVE-IN.
AS THE DISARMAMENT
TALKS HERE
CONTINUE THROUGH
CLOSED SESSIONS
LAST NIGHT AND
ON INTO THIS AFTERNOON,
A FEELING
OF POSITIVE ANTICIPATION
IS SHARED BY EVERYONE
IN THE PRESS CORPS.
THE DOORS
TO THE CONFERENCE ROOM
ARE OPENING.
I SEE THE CHIEF
UNITED STATES DELEGATE
MR. EMMETT FITZ-HUME.
MR. FITZ-HUME.
HI, ED.
EVERYBODY AT HOME IS
MOST ANXIOUS TO KNOW
HOW THINGS ARE GOING
IN THERE.
WELL, ED, RIGHT NOW
WE'RE AT AN EXTREMELY
SENSITIVE JUNCTURE.
AND, OF COURSE,
THE SLIGHTEST MISPERCEIVED
PHRASE OR GESTURE
COULD UPSET EVERYTHING
WE'VE ACHIEVED TODAY.
NOW IF YOU'LL
EXCUSE ME, ED...
THANK YOU,
MR. FITZ-HUME.
THANK YOU, ED.
MR. EMMETT FITZ-HUME,
CHIEF STATE DEPARTMENT
NEGOTIATOR
HERE AT
THE DISARMAMENT TALKS
RE-ENTERING
WHAT HE HAS CALLED
"THE DELICATELY
BALANCED NEGOTIATIONS."
COMRADE!
OK.
"WHAT LITTLE RICHARD SONG
"WAS THE TITLE
OF A 1950s MOVIE
STARRING JAYNE MANSFIELD?"
GOOD GOLLY,
MISS MOLLY?
GREAT BALLS OF FIRE?
WRONG! IT WAS
THE GIRL CAN'T HELP IT.
SORRY. YOU LOSE.
EASTERN EUROPE.
%% SPIES LIKE US %%
%% WHOA WHOA WHOA %%
%% THEY DON'T HAVE TO
GET THEIR POINT ACROSS %%
%% SPIES LIKE US %%
%% OH, SEE ME THROUGH THE HALL
AND LIFT ME THROUGH THE WALL %%
%% SPIES LIKE US %%
%% OOH OOH OOH EEE
YEAH YEAH YEAH %%
%% SPIES LIKE US %%
%% OOH, SEE THE MAN
WORKING %%
%% SPIES LIKE US %%
%% AAAHHH %%
%% YEAH, YEAH %%
%% SPIES LIKE US %%
%% OOH OOH OOH
OOH OOH OOH %%
%% OOH OOH OOH OOH
OOH OOH %%
%% SPIES LIKE US %%
%% YEAH %%
%% WHOA %%
%% SPIES LIKE US %%
%% AIN'T NO HURRY,
NO PLACE TO RUN NO-HOW %%
%% SPIES LIKE US %%
%% WHOA %%
%% WHEE-EE %%
%% YEAH %%
%% SPIES LIKE US %%
%% FIRE, FIRE, FIRE %%
%% DON'T PAY NO COST %%
%% SPIES LIKE US %%
%% OOH OOH %%
%% WHAT DO YOU DO? %%
%% NO ONE ELSE
CAN DANCE LIKE YOU %%
%% SO WHAT'S ALL THE FUSS %%
%% THERE AIN'T NOBODY
THAT SPIES LIKE US %%
%% HEY, HEY,
WHAT DO YOU SAY? %%
%% SOMEONE TOOK
YOUR PLANS AWAY %%
%% SO WHAT'S
ALL THE FUSS %%
%% THERE AIN'T NOBODY
THAT SPIES LIKE US %%
%% HEY, DON'T FEEL AFRAID %%
%% OF AN UNDERCOVER AIDE %%
%% THERE'S NO NEED TO FUSS %%
%% THERE AIN'T NOBODY
THAT SPIES LIKE US %%
%% SPIES LIKE US %%
%% OOH %%
%% WE DON'T KNOW
THE MEANING OF FEAR %%
%% WE PLAY EVERY MINUTE
BY EAR %%
%% ONE FOR ALL
AND ALL FOR ONE %%
%% EVERYBODY'S ON THE RUN %%
%% ESPECIALLY
AT THIS TIME OF THE YEAR %%
%% OOH, OOH,
WHAT DO YOU DO? %%
%% NO ONE ELSE
CAN DANCE LIKE YOU %%
%% SO WHAT'S
ALL THE FUSS? %%
%% AIN'T NOBODY
THAT SPIES LIKE US %%
%% HEY, HEY,
WHAT DO YOU SAY? %%
%% NO ONE ELSE
CAN LOOK THAT WAY %%
%% SO WHAT'S
ALL THE FUSS? %%
%% THERE AIN'T NOBODY
THAT SPIES LIKE US %%
%% SNEAKY %%
.
%% OOH %%
%% WE GET IN THERE
BY HOOK OR BY CROOK %%
%% WE DON'T DO A THING
BY THE BOOK %%
%% NEVER NEEDED
SPECIAL CLOTHES %%
%% HOW WE DID IT,
NO ONE KNOWS %%
%% GUESS WE MUST HAVE
HAD WHAT IT TOOK %%
%% OOH, OOH, OOH %%
%% OOH, OOH, OOH, OOH,
OOH, OOH %%
%% OH, WHEN THINGS
GET TOUGH %%
%% GUYS LIKE US ACT ROUGH %%
%% HEY, HEY,
WHAT DO YOU SAY? %%
%% SOMEONE TOOK
THE PLANS AWAY %%
%% SO WHAT'S
ALL THE FUSS? %%
%% THERE AIN'T NOBODY
THAT SPIES LIKE US %%
%% SPIES LIKE US %%
}}