Well, you gotta get away,
gotta go and play
Gotta find a day that's
full of nothing but sun
Cruising down the street,
moving to the beat
Everyone you meet is
having nothing but fun
Leave it all behind you
Feel those palm trees blow
The folks up north
can't find you
They're outside
shoveling snow
The time to move
but don't be slow
On your mark,
get ready to go
Lovin'
with the Lauderdale ladies
Playin'
in the Lauderdale sun
Lovin' with
the Lauderdale ladies
And you won't be going home
till you find...
Nelson,
wherever you look...
skin skin skin.
Spring break
in Fort Lauderdale.
250,000 kids
here for the sole purpose
of partying.
Lookin' for the best,
better than the rest
Put her to the test
and see that she's number one...
- Hi.
- Special kind of smile
Special kind of style,
it's gonna be a while
Before you know
how it's done
Always on the run
when you're lovin'
With the Lauderdale
ladies
Playing in the Lauderdale sun
Lovin'
With the Lauderdale ladies
And you won't be going home
till you find the one...
- So this is it?
- Ahh, nothing but the best, buddy!
Whoo!
- Humma humma humma!
- Easy, big fella. Easy.
Ohh!
Come on, guys!
- Nice, huh?
Yeah.
So I'm...
So where'd you hear
about this place anyway,
Guinness Book of World Records?
"Hotel most resembling
a refugee camp."
Excuse me, pardon me.
Sorry. He he!
All right, who's next? Hey!
Lovin'
with the Lauderdale ladies
And you won't be going home
- Till you find the one.
- Do you have a reservation?
About what?
I mean yes.
I mean I do.
- Uh, Stern.
- Stern? Okay.
Stern, uh, yes.
Right.
Here you go.
- Do you want to sign in?
- Why not?
I think he'd like to sign up.
Well, there's nothing
wrong with having a good time.
Bing bing! Bing bing!
- That's Eesh. Ask him.
- Hi there.
Hi.
Holy sh...
Viola!
Gentlemen, home!
I think somebody's using
this room.
Oh, no no!
Don't worry about it.
No! This...
this is lickety-split.
See?
Very clean.
Over here? No problem.
Two seconds... one, two,
three.
Good like brand new!
Bingo, huh?
Look... sanitized
for your protection.
And over here, please.
Over here...
see? The wonderful view!
Oh, this.
Well.
Nice!
So?
Now you tip.
Oh.
- All I have is a five.
- No problem.
Anything you need, you call Eesh.
Anything you want, you call Eesh.
You get in troubles...
they work themselves out.
Enjoy!
Okay.
Well, I'm gonna go
down to the pool,
get a beer and a hard-on.
First we take off our shoes.
Do you want help
with your laces?
I'm... I'm sorry.
I just still feel... funny.
Nelson, relax.
You're not funny.
So what if you took off? So what if
your stepfather's mad that you took off?
Nelson, you gotta stop letting this guy
push you around so much.
You weren't even there
when he decided
you're supposed to
work during spring break.
You had no choice!
Nelson, he was gonna make you
stay there at home in the snow,
where every kit's covered up
by a shirt and two sweaters.
We're talking cruel and unusual
punishment here
just to work on
his goddamn campaign.
Campaign?
It's not even off the ground yet.
Shit.
Nelson, we're college students.
College students don't work
during spring break. It's unnatural.
We're supposed to
go fucking crazy.
College students are supposed to go
fucking crazy during spring break
because after college is over,
they're never expected to ever again.
This is your chance.
Don't blow it.
If you don't go
crazy down here,
then you are crazy!
All right, all right, all right!
Oh, buddy buddy buddy,
this is gonna be great!
Come here! Hurry up, will ya?
Hey, man, do you mind? I've been
sweating my ass off since Gainesville.
Go ahead.
Beer is like...
fucking great, you know?
Welcome to Florida.
Whoa!
Stand up and cheer.
Aww, sheesh.
Isn't your air conditioning
working right?
It's you that's not
working right, Eddie.
I can see why
my brother died young.
What I can't see is why he
married you in the first place.
Why did he?
I'm busy.
What do you want?
Guess what? I still got
a hot buyer for this dump.
You can turn around and
march your ass out of here.
I'm not selling this hotel.
You sure?
Heh heh heh!
You may not have to sell.
Maybe it'll just be
taken away from you.
Will you get out of here?
I was talking to Philly Kaufman down
at the bank today.
I bet you didn't know
that Philly Kaufman and I
are old poker buddies, did you?
Well, Philly says you're
way behind in your mortgage payments.
I'm always behind
before spring break
and I'm always paid up
when it's over.
Well, God forbid something should
happen to close you down
- before you could pay it up.
- Will you get out of here?
My sister-in-law Geri Potmore;
my friend Mr. Ames.
- Pleasure.
- Charmed.
- Another poker buddy?
- Close enough.
I thought Ames would take
an interest in going over the place.
He takes a professional interest.
He's got a professional right.
He belongs to
the Unsafe Buildings Commission.
My ID.
Okay.
Go inspect.
Heh heh heh. Thanks, Ger.
- What an asshole.
- Really.
- Oh, sorry.
- Why?
You hit the nail
right on the head.
What can I do for you fellas?
Nothing too tough though, okay?
Nah, we have reservations.
Oh, hi.
Suitcase.
Catch you later.
- Hey hey!
- Pleasure.
- Excuse me, excuse me.
- Pardon me.
- Popular room.
- Too popular.
It's a nice one, huh?
Swell.
- Yeah, hi, this is room 21.
Oh yeah, right... Stern.
No, see, we got a problem.
This is Stu Molinera
- and you gave the room to me.
- But Stern's in there.
- That's the problem.
- Just a sec. Let me check.
I really need this.
Oh, honey, I'm sorry.
I've got a lot on my mind.
I don't know what to say.
Every room in town is booked.
- So what are you gonna do?
- Send up some extra towels?
I can't fucking believe this.
- Yo, OT!
- Everything settled?
I haven't even sat my ass down yet
and bang! A hassle.
That's bullshit.
This is my vacation.
Isn't it funny how well
hassles travel?
You know what my vacation
was last year?
Working one job instead of three.
I mean, I've been saving money for
two years to come down here.
You know what it's like saving
money in New York?
It's like making it with your sister...
it's just not done.
Whoa, is that one hot
sun out there.
So what's the story?
The story is
we got "el shafto grande."
We have nowhere to go.
- Fuck it.
- Man, what do you mean, "Fuck it"?
We're here.
You're right.
When you're right you're right,
and you are right, brother.
Wait a minute. I think it's great
that you guys are so right,
- but what are you talking about?
- Stayin'.
- I know, but where?
- Here.
- What?
- What are we supposed to do?
Sleep in the fucking car?
I mean, come on.
What are you gonna do, throw us out?
You won't even know we're here.
Don't worry about us.
You guys go swim,
- get laid, whatever.
- Now wait a minute.
Stu. OT.
I'm Nelson. This is Adam.
No, thanks.
we already paid for this room.
- Why is that a problem?
- Really. That's a big help.
Oh, come on!
Listen, let's just play it
by ear, okay?
- Okay, OT?
- Ready.
See you guys later.
Have fun.
All right then, Mr. Dalby
will see you tomorrow at...
- Take care of it.
- Yes, sir.
God damn it.
It's all I need is a cold.
Ernest, you're not getting a cold.
Calm down.
I find it very disturbing that
one lousy night
can be so damned important.
It's a testimonial for you,
not a court martial.
Don't be too sure.
You have no idea
how fast so-called friends
can turn on you.
One little slip up and they go
from following you to chasing you.
- I have to be perfect.
- That's not very realistic.
Politics has nothing
to do with being realistic.
I tell you, one juicy rumor
and forget it.
You could put every penny
you had into my campaign
and it wouldn't help.
Nearly every penny
is in it already.
Can you spare me
the commentary?
All I am saying
is that this dinner
is either going to make
or break my political career.
Nothing can go wrong...
not one thing.
Yes?
Mmm.
It's DiFozio.
What is it, Nick?
What?
He's gone?
Nelson's gone!
He's supposed to be
organizing the canvassers,
putting out the mailing lists,
doing at least six other things.
God damn it,
he'll cripple me.
What? No no!
Don't call the police.
That's the last thing I need,
God damn it.
No, just... just...
Never mind, Nick. Never mind.
I'll take care of it myself.
You see? Didn't I always say
Nelson was irresponsible?
Well, now he has
finally proven it.
Maybe he's doing
some sort of research.
Whoo! This is great.
Go go go go go go!
All the way from the Big Apple,
OT Blastin!
It's O as in "out there"
and T as in "totally."
Hey, OT!
That's my roommate!
Let's hear it for
OT Blastin from New York
where nothing's normal!
OT! OT! All right!
Now that concludes
the semi-finals of today's competition.
And in just a couple of minutes
we'll move on to the finals.
All right?
Now don't forget
that The Candy Store
is the home of a special drink.
It's called
The Spring Break Screamer.
One part vodka, two parts rum,
three parts gin...
Toto, I don't think
we're in Kansas anymore.
Two beers, please!
Oh, I'm sorry.
- Fuckin' asshole!
- Ahh!
I'm gonna kick your ass,
fug-face!
- It was an accident. It was.
- Excuse me.
- Sir?
- What?
I don't think he's that much
of a fug-face.
That's my roommate.
You wanna leave him alone?
All right?
You too, shit for brains!
Get out of the fuckin'...
- Thank you.
- He hurt you?
- No no, I'm fine.
- Thank you.
Uh, I don't think Nelson would have been
too much fun with his head torn off.
Really?
Head torn off.
Okay, everybody,
it's time for the finals!
- Come on.
- The final round of competition
here at The Candy Store...
the belly-flop contest.
- Let's go.
- Look what I found over here.
All right,
here's our first finalist.
Let's hear it
for Mr. Universe!
Mr. Universe!
He's a real crowd-pleaser.
Isn't he, ladies and gentlemen?
What a guy.
- Jump! Go!
- Come on.
Go!
All right,
that's Mr. Universe!
What's he train on,
antifreeze?
Wait a minute, you guys.
Here you go, here you go.
Give 'em hell, buddy.
All right, here we go!
Our next contestant
making his final jump of the day,
from the University of Massachusetts,
crazy gut guy!
Crazy gut guy!
Ahhhh!
That man makes
a big splash, ladies and gentlemen.
Let's hear it for
crazy gut guy!
He's gonna be
tough to beat.
Oh shit.
Go go go go go!
Okay, man, go for it.
Blow 'em away.
OT Blastin! We can't keep score.
A belly-flop record!
OT Blastin from New York!
Beers!
Beers, everybody! Beers!
Go go go go go go!
I live in the city
And I love the lights
Ooh, we're from the city
We're going out tonight
My girl's so pretty
She's out of sight
Ooh, we're from the city
We're getting down tonight.
Come on, buddy.
Come on, come on.
- Wait, Stu.
- Take it easy, man.
Just a bunch of guys
getting in the car
No matter who's
driving up or how far
Feels so good,
feels so alive
Know that the driver stays,
I don't drive
Me and the boys
Just me and the boys
Me and the boys...
Hey, how many miles
to the gallon do you get?
Hey hey!
Me and my buds
just like to go
We're having fun,
everybody knows
We don't fuss
and we never grab
We just dig
taking in the sights
Me and the boys...
Just me and the boys...
Sure.
- Yo, OT?
- What?
OT, come here.
- Hi.
Beer?
- Well, all right.
- Come on, let's go party.
- Mm-hmm.
- Come on.
Yo, Nelson.
We got the car.
Just a bunch of guys
getting in the car
No matter who's
driving up or how far
Feels so good,
feels so alive
Know that the driver stays,
I don't drive...
This is great!
Let's go find a saloon!
I've never seen so many people
in all my life!
They're all over the place.
And they're all having fun!
More fun than I've
ever had.
Got no sex issues, know what I mean?
This is great.
What? Hi!
How are you? Oh boy!
Me and my buds
just like to go
We have fun,
everybody knows
We don't fuss
and we never grab
We just groove
taking in the sights
Me and the boys
- Just me and the boys...
- Want a ride somewhere?
Should we give her a ride?
Go back.
- Me and the boys.
- Give her a ride!
She likes me!
I'm sure of it!
I keep wondering what
Stu said to those girls.
Oh, probably something like...
"Nice night, isn't it?
Be nicer if
you spent it with us."
He probably made it
sound good too.
Sure. Stu is what you call
professionally cool.
Yeah, really.
Hey, that last bar
was pretty good.
I think that girl in
the white pants liked you.
What was her name, Serena?
Yeah, she was drunk.
I thought you were
buying her the drinks.
Those guys sure know
how to have a good time.
We're doing all right.
What do you want?
Shit.
- No.
- Come on.
- There they are!
Want us to tuck you in?
It's too bright in here.
Whoa!
I'm sorry. Here.
This plant's leaking on me.
Ohh.
Oh, just a minute.
Wait. I'll be right back.
Hey, how you doin'?
I'm okay.
Did you see those chicks?
They're like... whoa, you know?
Jeez.
Hey, um...
Well, do you think you could
get out of the bed?
You know what I mean?
It's just... you know...
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Of course. Sure.
- Thanks.
Yeah, thanks a lot.
I don't believe this.
Okay.
I can't stand it.
Don't listen.
Jesus.
This is making me crazy.
Where are you going?
Jesus Christ.
Nelson, those are
"Playboy" tits.
I've never seen "Playboy" tits anywhere
except "Playboy."
Come on, man,
where's your manners?
Sorry.
What?
I'm just figuring out what
you're trying to shave off here.
Stu, how come you always
talk like that?
Like what?
You always move your head
when you say something.
What the hell are you talking...
Get the hell outta here,
will you, please?
So you guys know
where you're gonna go?
No, not really.
Well, Nelson and I
talked about this.
I don't know how
you guys feel, but...
we were thinking maybe you'd
like to stay here.
- Are you serious?
- Really?
- No, not really, but...
Yeah!
All right, all right!
Hey, I feel like I should kiss you.
Anybody got a ring?
You can kiss that, man.
There it is! Hup hup hup!
May, get in here.
What in the...
what is he doing?
Look at this.
Look!
- Well, it's Nelson.
- Well, of course it's Nelson.
- That's why I showed it to you.
- What's he doing?
He is killing me.
Doing this in Fort Lauderdale?
I mean, think who's going to see this.
Imagine what they're
going to think of me.
It's not a very
good picture of him.
Well, it's good enough.
Get the boat ready.
- We're going up there.
- Today?
Now. He is running around
making an ass of himself and me,
and it's got to be stopped.
I mean, this is the kind of thing
that can blow a political campaign
right out of the water!
- Forget it. I'm not doing it.
- No, Nelson.
Eesh said this guy will
only deal with one of us.
- It's your money. Do it.
- Okay.
- What if it was your money?
- Get out of here.
It's only gonna take
a couple minutes, Nelson.
Man, what's your problem?
Too much caffeine?
Hello?
Buenos dias.
Uh, por favor.
You must excuse
my tardiness.
I had to kill a man.
No problem.
Eesh sent you, huh?
- What is it you want?
- Um...
well, see, my friends and I
were sort of wondering
where we could find some p...
stuff, you know,
to sort of have around, right?
- And Eesh said that maybe you...
- You want pot, huh?
- Isn't that it?
- Yeah. Yeah, that's it. Yeah.
Amigo, if there is something
going on,
you will go home in the trunks
of 10 different cars.
No no. No, nothing's wrong.
Mmm. No.
Ahem.
- So is good, huh?
- Mmm!
Mmm, yeah.
- 250!
- Dollars?
You think is too much?
No no, that's not... no.
No, that's fine.
Here's some paper.
Matches.
Here you go.
No no no no!
Please, no.
Es bueno, huh?
Uh, muy.
100!
- 100 watts? That's very good.
- No, $100.
- 15 watts.
- Ahh.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Something else?
- No, that ought to do it.
- Have a nice day.
You too.
Hey, buddy.
Look at...
Oh my God.
Hey, you got any left for me?
Later.
Winter is my enemy
The beach is where
I'd rather be
Lots of sand
and lots of swimming
One long beach
just filled with women
Let's hit the beach
Take the beach
by sneak attack
Grab the women,
drag 'em back
Torture prisoners
till they talk
Plenty of babes,
the old boardwalk
Let's hit the beach
Let's hit
the beach
Let's hit the beach
Let's hit
the beach
Let's hit the beach
beach beach
Let's hit
the beach beach beach
Let's hit the beach
beach beach
Let's hit
the beach beach beach
Let's hit the beach.
Hi, Mr. Dalby. Hi!
Welcome welcome!
How are you?
You look like a million bucks.
Or maybe I should say
a million votes.
Oh, thank you.
You remember Thomas and Lloyd?
Yeah, sure.
But they aren't used to the heat
down here, are they?
Could we get on to the business
at hand?
Um, you gotta believe me
when I tell you
that I've done everything I can
with my sister-in-law.
But when it gets
to that hotel,
she's as tough to move
as a concrete mattress.
- Potmore...
- But I got a guy who can do the job.
His name's Ames. The only trouble
is he's gonna cost us five grand.
- But he says...
- Would you please listen to me?
- Yeah.
- The business at hand
is not the hotel,
it's my stepson.
- There's nothing wrong with him?
- There's plenty wrong with him.
He's in Fort Lauderdale.
I want him found.
No sooner said than done.
Potmore?
Do you know what
he looks like?
Jesus.
Here.
- Ahh. Good-looking boy.
- Hmm.
Find him and
you'll have your $5,000.
And Potmore?
Not a word to my wife.
Let's get some beer.
- Beer!
- Can we have four beers?
Make it eight... eight beers.
Ladies and gentlemen, party!
Yeah!
Everybody's got an ambition
Doin' things that
they want to do
Trying every kind
of position
Hoping that their dream
will come true
Open up your eyes
and see I'm not disguised
What I want to
say to you
I want to do it, do it
I want to do it
to you
I want to do it,
do it
I want to do it
to you
You don't need
your ma's permission
You're thinking about
a rendezvous
I see that I arouse
your suspicion
And you're wondering if
it's gonna come true
It's really not surprising,
your temperature is rising
Listen while I
give you a clue
I want to do it, do it
I want to do it to you
- I want to do it
- Do it
I want to do it
to you
Do it, do it, do it, do it
I want to do it to you
- Do it, do it
- I want to do it
- Do it
I want to do it to you
- I want to do it
- Do it
I want to do it to you
- I want to do it
- Do it
I want to do it to you
- I want to do it
- Do it
I want to do it to you
- I want to do it
- Do it
I want to do it to you.
- I feel great.
- You're supposed to!
- Not this great.
- He's loaded. He's loaded.
I'm drunker than you are.
- I'm so wasted.
- You look it.
Hey hey,
I found something to drink!
Ahhh!
Get him, get him get him!
Stop it, stop it, stop it!
No no no!
Stop it, stop it!
What? Hey!
- What happened to him?
- Where you runnin'?
What happened?
He's here.
Your stepfather?
Yeah, my stepfather.
Oh, shit.
His stepfather.
That's his boat down there
in the water.
Well, where's it supposed to be,
in valet parking?
Stu, you don't understand.
- His stepfather's an asshole.
- Why? My father's an asshole.
We're talking king
of the assholes here.
This is a drag.
Shit. Does your stepfather
know you're down here?
- I don't know.
- So why the rabbit routine?
- You're bringing everybody down.
- I'm sorry.
It's cool. There's only one way
we can get it going again.
What's that?
Drink!
Has anyone ever died
of a hangover?
I can't move my eyes.
It was those last
four or five beers.
Ahhh.
I'm... I'm going upstairs.
You really feel that bad?
No, I'm okay. I just have to
throw up for a while.
Operator.
- Um, hi... Uh...
- Hello?
Ernest Dalby, please.
Hello?
Hello!
- Who is this?
- It's Nelson.
Don't you dare hang up!
Wha... I called you.
What in the hell
have you been doing?
I know you're in Fort Lauderdale
and so am I.
Now you get your fanny down to
the marina pronto. Do you hear me?
Nelson!
Nelson, do you hear me?
Nelson, are you listening?
Nelson!
God, Nels...
It's a wonderful day,
let the music play
You keep wishing that
it's never gonna end...
Look out!
Playing by the sea,
all the people you meet
Thinkin' how it's
good to have friends
Taking a leave
is the only thing to do
Things are just as fine
as they can be
Everybody's insane
and they're feeling no pain...
Ahhh!
Can you handle
everything you see?
And we're singing
songs of love
We're wishing on
the stars above
It's happening
every single day
As long as it's good
we'll take it any old way
It's a wonderful day,
let the music play
Here's to wishing
that it's never gonna end
Playing by the sea,
all the people you meet
Thinking how
it's good to have friends
And we're singing
The songs of love,
we're wishing
On the stars above
And laughing
every single day
So long as it's good,
we'll take it any old way
It's a wonderful day,
let the music play
Here's to wishing that
it's never gonna end
Playing by the sea,
all the people you meet
Thinking how
it's good to have friends
Look at that dude
working on a scheme
Looking for the one
he thinks is best
Taking it easy,
just a little bit sleazy
Knowing that you're
different from the rest
And we're singing
songs of love
We're wishing
on the stars above
It's happening
every single day
So long as it's good
we'll take it any old way
It's a wonderful day,
let the music play
Here's to wishing that
it's never gonna end
Playing by the sea...
One.
You guys want a chili dog?
Thinking how it's good
to have friends.
Don't wipe your nose on it!
Jeez.
The Button,
home of the annual
Fort Lauderdale!
- Whoo!
- Spring games!
Hey, you guys ready for
some serious competition or what?
Whooo!
The lady from Pennsylvania
is going wild!
The lady from Pennsylvania is doing
a job on Kid Austin.
It's hard to believe that
this lady is so quick!
Now Kid Austin is holding her
with his right hand.
She hits him in the jaw
and hits him down!
And the referee goes down too.
She's on top of him!
- The people are going crazy!
- One, two...
He's counting them out.
- One of the referees is down too.
- Five, six...
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's amazing.
It looks like Lucy from Pennsylvania
has done a fantastic job!
Oh my God!
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have awarded three points
to the winning team...
Pennsylvania!
This is the most incredible decision
that has ever taken place
in our championship ring!
Hey, you want to go for a ride
on the back of my hog?
What's wrong?
Don't you like to go fast?
Or are you the kind that
likes to go slow?
- Get lost, hmm?
- What's wrong?
I'll do you great,
sweet cheeks.
Get lost.
I'm not...
Hey.
Hey, man,
don't you have someplace to be?
You fuckin'...
- Ahhh!
- Ohhh!
Come on, let's hear some cheers!
Excuse me, have you seen
this kid anywhere?
I see people all day long.
l...
Okay, man, you sure?
You seen anybody?
l...
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's time for the one and only
world-famous
Button wet-T-shirt
extravaganza!
And here come the ladies
from Pennsylvania!
And their opponents
this evening
are from Ohio!
Oh, I gotta see this.
I gotta see this.
Well, it was Saturday night
and I was feeling all right...
Ahhh!
- Hi, cutie.
- What? Are you talking to me?
Yeah. Don't you
think you're sexy?
Oh my God!
All the time!
- What you doing later?
- Ah, hopefully something with you.
Sounds good.
Stay right there.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'll be right here.
Wet 'em down, boys!
- Wet 'em down!
Ahhhh!
We now have wet T-shirts.
And who's going to be the first lady
to win this evening?
Which lady is going to
help win it...
Wait, over here. Over here!
Ladies and gentlemen,
they're going crazy.
Excuse me, lady!
I've always heard good things
about Ohio!
- Aha!
- They'll all take it off!
Let's hear it for
the amazing ladies.
They're doing
a fantastic job this evening.
Let's hear it for them! What an amazing
job from these ladies.
They're taking it off!
Let's hear it for these ladies.
They're doing an amazing job!
Let's hear it for 'em!
They're gonna go all the way!
And some of the young ladies in
the audience are getting into it!
Ooh!
They're going out.
Everything is off!
Ladies and gentlemen,
they're leaving nothing to chance.
This is the kind of
competitive spirit
that has made America great.
This is what it's all about!
Pee! Come on! Go!
Hi.
Shh!
Temperamental machine.
- Ahh!
- Too much thruster.
Yeah.
You know,
I saw you the other day.
You were at...
- Use the shield more.
- Like this?
Yeah, a little.
Yeah.
- Look out. There's a pulsar.
- Where?
- In the zone.
- What do you mean?
- The photon blast.
- I don't see it.
Don't hyper... here.
God, you're really good.
Actually, I'm better than that.
I just... you know.
- Oop, that pointy thing.
- Gamma dart.
It's one of my more useful skills.
- You wanna play doubles?
- Sure.
Okay.
Guys, don't you worry,
because coming up is
the wet he-shirt open!
And ladies,
I do mean open!
- Let's sign up.
- Are you crazy? What do we gotta do?
- Who the fuck cares?
- Go go go!
Innkeeper!
Two beers.
Thank you.
Here we go, ladies.
Wet 'em down!
- Hey, I'm Carla.
- I'm Diane.
Hi, I'm wet.
Ahhh!
Oh my God!
Is everybody ready?
Then let's do it.
'Cause you're horny all day
and you stay up all night...
Ladies and gentlemen,
the boys are getting wild and wooly
at The Button!
They're rocking and rolling.
The girls are measuring
for the competition!
The ladies are all
gonna go crazy!
And what's this?
A player's down.
He's going down.
It's the great American rip off!
You're all the witnesses.
It's a rip off, ladies and gentlemen.
That's my roommate.
- Which one?
- The tall one.
- What's his name?
- He's from Brooklyn.
His name's Brooklyn?
No.
Look at him.
These men are smoking.
They're steaming.
Women in their presence can't
contain themselves any longer.
Oh my God.
He's ripping his shirt on back.
This is one cocky competitor.
And it looks like he's going to
bring up reinforcements.
- Go go go!
- Go, Brooklyn!
Hey, come on, man!
You got nothing to lose.
Show 'em that famous
Molinera muscle!
Here he goes!
It's all coming off!
Oh, fuck the picture.
You wanna go inside or not?
Two bucks. Let's go.
Give me the money.
Thank you. Inside.
Hi. Nice to see you.
Now comes the one
and only
banana-eating extravaganza!
Do we have any contestants?
Yo, OT.
Come on, big man.
Go go go go go!
Go go go go!
- This is gonna be great.
- This is already great.
There are no points to score
in the banana-eating extravaganza.
The reason is people know
who's scoring.
The rules are simple
because there are none.
All these couples have to do
is eat these bananas
as erotically and as
outrageously as possible.
So go for it!
Yeah yeah, hang on.
Wait here, okay? Don't move.
I won't move.
Dude, you know that girl that
I saw before? She's back here.
She asked me if I'd
go home with her.
Go have a good time!
Get out of here.
How are we gonna
find anybody in here?
I don't know.
Give me a break!
Look at this!
A bodice pipe.
A double whammy
with the sliding sit-downs.
- Take the button off.
- What?
Take the button off.
- Are you all set?
- Yeah.
Look at this! These two have
only tongue in between 'em!
And here is a one-handed
car boost!
Ladies and gentlemen,
they have gone absolutely crazy.
They're going nuts. And everybody
wants a piece of the action.
It's all happening during spring break
right here in Fort Lauderdale.
Come on, let's scream.
Come on!
Let's scream louder!
Louder!
Good evening.
Maybe I should give him
a call, I don't know.
Oh, shit.
Well... good night.
Aren't you coming in?
Sure.
Come on.
Don't mind my mess.
You okay?
Yeah yeah.
I wish you weren't
leaving tomorrow.
It's a whole night away.
What's wrong?
I'm, uh, thirsty.
How about a Coke?
Sure, great.
You get me one too?
Go on, hurry up.
Okay.
- I never knew...
- Hey.
- You got a Coke machine?
- Yeah, right over there.
Thanks.
When I'd be saying to you
Don't let this good love
slip away
Now that we know
that it's true
Don't... don't you know
the kind of man I am?
No, said I'd never
fall in love again
But it's real and
the feeling comes shining through
I'm so caught up in you
Little girl
And I never did
suspect a thing
So caught up in you
- Little girl...
- Um...
That I never want to
get myself free
And baby, it's true
you're the one
Who caught me,
baby, you taught me
How good it could be
It took so long to
change my mind
I thought that love
was a game
I played around
enough to find
No two are ever the same
You made me realize
the love I'd missed
So hot,
love I couldn't quite resist
When it's right,
the light just comes shining through
I'm so caught up in you...
- It's me.
- Little girl
- You're the one that...
- Well, come right in.
I'm so caught up in you,
little girl
That I never want to
get myself free
And baby, it's true
you're the one
Who caught me, baby, you taught me
how could it could be...
Down?
Look, I just don't know her name
or room number, that's all.
Come on, guy.
Hey, listen, you know that
really pretty girl I came in with?
Who was she?
She's waiting for me!
Whenever you want me...
Thank you.
Thank... thanks a lot.
Nice. Nice guy.
When you should turn
and walk away
- Oh no...
- Where are you?
I can't live without you...
- I'm so caught up in you.
No wonder it looks like
you slept in a Cuisinart.
Thank you.
So what happened to you?
Ahh, Carla and Diane.
I think I'm gonna start
writing my memoirs.
Oh, yeah,
what was was it like?
Which time?
How'd you even know
what to do?
They told me! They said,
"Slide your hand under here.
Arch your back
a little more."
Ahh, they were
very patient.
They kept it up all night.
I still don't know where
my underpants are.
Why?
What happened to 'em?
I think they ate 'em.
- I made a decision.
- What?
I'm leaving.
What?
That's stupid.
Where are you gonna go?
I don't know.
Home probably.
I mean, I can't have
any fun down here
with my stepfather chasing me
all over the place.
I got a sister in Hoboken.
Your stepfather would
never find you there.
Adam, I'm not an animal.
My mind's made up
and nothing's gonna change it.
You don't have to quote me
on that or anything.
From the University of Connecticut,
let's hear it for Tammy!
You can't leave, man.
Your stepfather's not going to find you.
- That was just luck yesterday.
- That's what I told him.
You're gonna drive yourself
apeshit worrying about it.
I said exactly the same thing.
You gotta go on with it.
You know what I mean? Right, OT?
- Fuck 'im.
- I said that too.
Let me see if I got this:
I gotta stay cool,
gotta go with it
and I gotta fuck 'im.
You got it, pal.
Really.
Number 10,
must be a friend of Brenda's...
What?
That's her.
- That's her on the stage.
- Which one?
Which one do you think it is?
Let's see who's gonna
win this contest.
What we're gonna do now is allow
the girls to walk around the pool.
- Hey, yo!
- Let's hear it for Kim.
Hey! Hey, it's me! Hey!
What's your name?
Let's hear it
for all the beautiful ladies up here!
How about Kim from
the University of Alabama? Come on!
What's your name?
Come on, let's hear it for 'em!
Make some noise.
Hey, it's me!
What's your name?
Number two,
from Ohio State,
Susie!
All right! How about Susie?
Come on.
Hey, Susie!
Susie! Susie!
Excuse me. Hey!
Hi. Hi.
Look!
Hey, guys, this is her!
- Right here!
- Hey, buddy! Yay!
- What happened to you?
- I got lost.
- It's okay.
- I got lost. I didn't know your name.
- What's yours?
- It's Nelson.
- Nelson.
- I thought you left.
I was going to
but I wanted to see you.
- Really?
- Yes.
We're having a party at the Breeze n'
Seas Motel tonight. Can you make it?
I'd love to.
But promise me one thing.
- What?
- You won't get thirsty.
Sure.
The man of the hour!
Hey!
- Did you see her?
- Yeah, she's beautiful.
Yeah, I know.
She stayed to see me.
I found him!
- I said I would.
- Where is he?
Now Mr. Dalby,
with all due respect,
I don't want to tell you that
just yet.
I want to just make sure that
our little deal is still on.
You know what I mean?
The bribe money.
Of course I know.
I'm not an idiot.
You'll get your money when
I get my stepson.
Right. Listen, you mind if
I borrow your two boys?
They might come in handy.
Besides, I think it would be
a good idea
- if they see how I work.
- All right, all right.
I bet you think
I'm pretty amazing, huh?
Hey, baby,
looking for some action
Come on,
get some satisfaction
Anyplace
is all right
Anything you plan
Any way we want to
So come on,
go with me and we can
Whoa ho ho ho ho ho ho
Have some fun tonight
Make you feel all right
Whoa ho ho ho ho ho ho
Have some fun tonight
Whoa ho ho ho ho ho ho...
- Hi.
Make you feel all right
Whoa ho ho ho ho ho ho
Have some fun tonight
Make you feel all right
When we wake tomorrow
If you think you can
We can start all over
So come on and
come with me and we can
Whoa ho ho ho ho ho ho
Have some fun tonight
Make you feel all right
Whoa ho ho ho ho ho ho
Have some fun tonight
Make you feel all right
Whoa ho ho ho ho ho ho
Have some fun tonight.
Hey, who are those turkeys
with your brother-in-law?
I don't know, but I'll lay you odds
they're not Boy Scouts.
Um, those are the guys... the ones
that work for my stepfather.
- What are they doing with that creep?
- Let's go ask 'em.
- Shit.
- We can deal with this.
- Wow.
- Eesh.
Don't make waves
Gotta be cool, junior
Stay away...
- What's the rush, Eddie?
- I was just looking for a friend.
You're gonna be looking
for a long time.
Come on, come on.
Here!
Go go go go! Fast!
Gentlemen,
you can't leave now.
Have you heard of
a boom-boom cocktail
with rum, vodka,
fruit and juices?
You haven't tried it?
You have to try it before you go.
It's our claim to fame!
Haa!
Come on!
Son of a bitch!
Son of a...
Oh, I just love the ocean.
Nelson, come on.
Sit down.
You'll feel better.
Hey, what's the matter?
Nothing. Um...
I just wanted this
to be perfect.
And I'm sorry
all this happened.
Hey, it's not your fault.
You couldn't help it.
Um...
I got... could you wait here?
I'll be right back.
Really, um...
- Where are you going?
- Right... just over... hang on.
Waah!
Hey, whoa.
Susie!
Susie! Susie!
Oh, Nelson!
Nelson.
Here he is in
all his glory.
The honor student!
The future lawyer!
- The candidate's son!
- Stepson.
Don't you talk back to me,
you little wimp.
You could have ruined me.
You didn't even know
that the testimonial was here
and not in Miami, did you?
No.
- Dad, l...
- Shut up!
To think that it has
come down
to the complete and
outright disregard
for everything that
I stand for.
I was just trying to
have some fun.
Fun?
Fun!
Reeling around like
a drunken cretin,
chasing after every
teenybopper in sight,
indulging every whim...
you call that fun?
Yes.
I will not have you running around
in public acting like a fool
and dressing like
a hermaphrodite.
You are a shame
and a disgrace.
Your mother is sick
to death about this.
- Where is she?
- Out shopping.
- Look, Dad...
- I don't want to hear it.
Why not?
From the way you're acting, you'd think
I was killing baby seals or...
Nelson!
Look, nothing is
wrong with this.
Nobody's having a bad time. I mean,
nobody's gotten hurt.
I'm having about the best time
I've had in my whole life.
Just let me go back
to the hotel, all right? Please?
You're staying right here.
There's nothing to go back to anyway.
Believe me.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Never mind.
You are trying to buy
the hotel, aren't you?
Yes.
And if a circus college went up
in its place,
it would be a big improvement.
I've heard the stories.
You can't do that.
Hey!
Real fair. Real fair.
Two against one, right?
I'm wearing a towel!
You'd better control yourself,
young man.
It's being done for me,
thank you.
Why don't you really throw out
the welcome mat and just lock me up?
I've just got
this funny feeling.
All you got is funny feelings,
Adam.
- Let me see your tongue.
- Will you guys get serious?
He should have
called in by now.
Hey, with that chick
in that car
with that backseat,
we may never see him again.
Really, man, I don't see any reason
to get so crazy about it...
- Oh Adam!
- What happened?
- Where's Nelson?
- They took him.
Who?
The guys from last night?
They just shoved him in the car
and drove away. It was terrible.
Okay, now can I worry?
You guys think you know everything.
That's him!
- You fat jerk!
- Hey, wait!
- Hey hey hey hey!
- Back back back!
Hey,
we want to talk to you!
You again?
What's the matter?
You want some more?
- All right, take it easy.
- What's this, the color guard?
Mr. Ames has something here that
he'd like to read to you.
Take it away, Mr. Ames.
"In violation of its safety code,
the Unsafe Buildings Commission
hereby orders the Breeze n' Seas Motel
closed until further notice,
effective immediately."
What crock is this of?
You can appeal.
She can get a hearing in, what?
Say six to eight weeks?
Perhaps.
You know damn well if you close me
down now, I'll have to sell the place.
Yes, I know. I know.
- Uh, may I?
- Oh, all right.
"All guests are instructed to
remove their personal effects
and vacate the premises
as of sunset."
- Dated today.
- Get him out of here!
Son of a bitch got me.
No, it's not over yet.
- That's bullshit.
- No way this is over.
This is gonna change
our plans this evening.
Really?
- You see anything?
- No.
Why does OT have
a knife in his mouth?
Does he really expect trouble?
Nah, he always wanted to swim with one.
He saw it once on television.
"...your consideration,
and yes, your trust.
I will not disappoint you.
Thank you all."
Nelson?
- Nice to see you too.
- Sorry.
- What was that?
- Probably just a fish jumping.
Hyah!
Go for it, Nelson!
- What was that?
- More fish.
Ahhh!
Go go go!
Come on, get up there!
- Ahhh!
Nelson, you come back here!
Ahhh!
Oh, go go go go go!
Nelson, come back here!
Ernest!
Ernest, what's going on?
Never mind!
I'll tell you later!
Never mind "never mind."
You tell me now.
Susie walked into the room, you'd
think she was the only one there...
Ooh!
When she walked into the world
and dropped the drinks in the dirt
And they'd stare,
but who cares...
Go go go go go!
Susie used to go out...
'Cause Susie dated all the guys
They'd go for her,
she only had to choose
Or you lose
Here comes trouble,
here comes trouble
Susie means trouble
Oh yeah
Oh yeah, oh yeah
Here comes trouble
Here comes
trouble
Here comes trouble
Oh yeah, oh yeah.
Holy shit.
Ahhh!
Get them!
What in hell is this?
Let them go... now.
God damn it, did you hear me?
Untie them.
Or I'll see to it that the police
throw you all in jail
- and that you rot there for a week.
No!
Nelson.
- Get out of my way.
- No.
You are asking for
very big trouble.
- Now step aside.
- Damn it, I said no.
I'm through stepping
aside for you.
And that goes for getting pushed aside,
held back and screwed over too.
You have gone too far
this time.
No, I think it's you
that's gone too far.
Mr. Ames?
Where'd you say you got that
$5,000 from?
- Eddie Potmore.
- Mmm!
And where did he get it?
F-from Mr. Dalby.
And what did you say it was?
- A bribe to close the motel.
- That's a lie!
Mm-hmm!
- Is that a lie?
- No.
No no no.
I'm sorry,
I forgot to introduce you.
- These are my friends, the witnesses.
Hi.
Well, I guess you'd better go
call the police now.
And tell 'em we'd like to
talk to 'em too, okay?
Ernest, is this true?
Nelson, let's be reasonable.
Oh my God.
- Does anybody want to be reasonable?
No.
Nelson, for God's sake!
If this ever gets out...
Well, okay.
If you agree to keep
the hotel open
and guarantee that it'll stay open
with Geri as the owner,
I guess we don't have to
talk about any bribe.
It's a deal.
I want to talk to you.
It's finally time now
I've been waiting all year...
You plotted.
You bribed people.
You kept my only son
a prisoner.
You are nothing but a sneaky
disgusting liar,
and I have had it. I'm taking back
every cent I put into your campaign.
Stop talking nonsense.
There are 300 guests
and a six-piece console waiting
for us across town.
And we are damned well going...
together.
- No!
- What?
You go alone.
And get used to it,
because not only am
I leaving you with nothing,
- I am leaving you, period.
- Fine! Fine!
Have your little tantrum.
I don't need you.
I don't need anybody
to reach the Senate.
My real friends are waiting.
To hell with all of you.
Hey, what are you doing?
Don't get me wet!
You're ruining my jacket.
Please.
Stop, damn it. Oh!
Thanks for sticking up
for me, fellas.
No problem!
- Get out of the car, please, sir.
- Yes, Officer.
Let's see your license
and registration, sir.
All right here.
You must understand,
I am on my way to
a very important political dinner.
- License please, sir.
- Right there.
Yes.
Sir, have you been drinking?
Drinking? No no no.
It was poured all over me.
Sheriff, pour him
into the backseat.
I am already very late,
as I've stated.
I think I should...
I think I should warn you,
the mayor is a very close
friend of mine.
He always speaks well
of you, sir.
What are you doing?
Where are you taking me?
- Damn it, do you know who I am?
- No, sir, I've got it right here.
- Oh shit!
- You have a real way with words, sir.
Lovin'
with the Lauderdale ladies
Playin'
in the Lauderdale sun
Lovin' with
the Lauderdale ladies...
- Oh!
- For the garden.
And you won't be going home
till you find the one...
Bye.
Well, everybody... here.
- Ashtrays.
- Thank you.
They steal them anyway.
Oh.
Oh, here's your car.
Hey.
They miss you.
Jeez.
Lovin'
with the Lauderdale ladies...
Will you move already?
Come on.
All right, get over there.
I've got this great idea.
Okay, I know how tough it is
for you guys,
but please try to act like
you're having some fun.
Just a second!
Whoo hoo hoo hoo
Whoo hoo
hoo hoo
Whoo hoo hoo hoo
Well, I work so hard
From September to December
But that was so long ago
I hardly remember
Now I need the old crazy sun
Better than ever
Now I know hard ways but
Still things'll get better
Well
Do you think I need a break?
I need a spring break
It's how I still believe
it's what I really need
I need a spring break
It's been so long
since I've been gone
And I can't go on till
I get down
To the action, honey
Into the sand
Well, it's last stop, honey
And I got a plan
Well, do you think
I need a break?
I need a spring break
And I still believe
that's what I really need
I need a spring break
I'm longing to find
Lots of fun in the sun, oh
Spend my life having fun fun fun
I need a spring break
Give me a break
Ooh, I need a break
Yeah
I'm longing to find
Lots of fun in the sun, oh
Spend my life having
fun fun fun fun fun fun fun
I need a spring break
Oh, give me a break
I need a break,
I need a spring break
I need a break
Give me a break
I need a spring break
I need a break
Give me a break
Whoo, I need a break
Yeah
I'm longing to find
Lots of fun in the sun, oh
Spend my life having
fun fun fun fun fun fun
I need a spring break
Oh, give me a break
I need a break,
I need a spring break
Give me a break
I need a break
It's time for spring break
It's time for spring break,
spring break
It's time for
spring break, spring break
Spring break, spring break,
Spring break, whoo
It's time for spring break.