My Love From The Star
First love?
I almost got into a big
accident when I was young.
There was someone who saved me.
Twelve years ago.
The person who saved you was me.
Do Min Joon!
What did you do to me?
You did something to me, didn't you?
You did!
Why else would I be acting like this?
The reason I saved you was...
because you looked like
the girl from 400 years ago.
The owner of this hair pin.
Then you lived 400 years or what?
That's right.
I came here from an outside world
400 years ago.
I could not return to my planet.
I had to live here for 400 years.
[My Love From Another Star
The Beginning]
[Gangreung, August 25th, 1609]
[Gangwon Provincial Office]
You want me to report
this to the King?
Your Excellency! This is a bad omen.
People are concerned.
Scandals cover scandals.
Speaking of which...
Do we have anything?
There's an interesting story
within my jurisdiction.
Why does Mother want me to
read books about Chaste Widows?
Does she want me to die after
my husband or what?
Why should I?
I'm only fifteen!
Being a widow already
is unfair enough.
The daughter of Seo family
who became a widow at fifteen
recently committed suicide. And her
in-laws applied for the Chastity Widow Award.
We will have the cremation tonight.
Find her and get rid of her.
We have already applied for
the Chastity Widow Award.
We can't let anyone see her alive.
Yes, My Lady.
Leave with me.
I will protect you.
Come with me.
My Lord!
Miss is back.
She's back alive!
You've saved my daughter's life.
I'm indebted to you.
I can't express my gratitude enough.
Go somewhere.
And live as if you're dead.
Mother!
So why bring a man we can't even identify?
What about him?
What happened to him?
Is he still not dead?
What happened?
He ate the arsenic-laced food.
It should've been potent
enough to kill an ox.
But I don't know how he's still alive.
Officer Choi!
Search Seo's family and capture
that fake chaste widow!
Honey, did she run away all right?
She went to the man she came with.
She said that she couldn't let her
life saver die like that.
Sir! Your face is becoming more pale.
Get them!
Come here.
My late grandmother told me
that I should always say the
farewell before the time comes.
Because when the time really comes...
I won't have time to say good bye.
Thank you, and thank you again.
I will not forget.
I will not be able to forget.
Even after death, no matter where I'll be,
I will not forget your death.
I will not forget you, sir.
Get them!
Over there!
Surround them!
Arrest them alive.
He's using dark arts!
Shoot them!
Kill them!
There are moments I want to stop forever...
Such as the moment of death
of my loved one.
I didn't want to see it or believe it.
I couldn't do anything.
A moment where
I felt completely helpless...
That was the first death
I had witnessed on Earth.
Do you know why people fear death?
Because they will be forgotten.
It's because the world will not
change after they are gone.
And they will eventually be forgotten.
I was not afraid.
Even if I left this world and
went to a different world...
Even if no one remembered me...
I did not care.
But right now
I am afraid a little.
There is someone whom I don't
want to be forgotten by.
Cheon Song Yi!
Hello!
That kid!
What's he doing there?
Do you know him?
Yeah, I do.
He lives next door.
Really? That's good.
This isn't a drama class.
It's really hard for you.
You already received an F
and you needed to re-take it.
What?
You didn't do anything
to offend him, did you?
You couldn't have had time.
You moved in yesterday.
I had time.
No! I'm going home alone!
Can we let her go home alone?
She met a pervert the last time
she got into an elevator alone.
It got really messy.
Don't you remember that the pervert
was hospitalized for eight weeks?
She beat the hell out of him with
the metal studs on her bag.
He was messed up.
Yeah I'm Cheon Song Yi.
How long have you been following me?
I see that you're young
and full of energy.
I see that.
Go study.
Or exercise and release that energy.
If you followed me here to
do something perverted...
Then you picked the wrong person!
This isn't the first time this
happened to me.
That pervert!
Hey!
Are you going to my place?
Where do you think you're...
You're going to the apartment next door.
You live there?
Don't you know me?
Don't you?
Me?
Do I have to?
No, you don't have to.
I've waited 15 years.
Isn't that long enough?
Sorry.
What's the reason?
Why not me?
Do you remember his face?
Who?
Song Yi!
[12 years ago]
Cheon Song Yi!
Stop following me! Leave me alone.
She had the same face as
the girl from 400 years ago?
Yes.
He's Song Yi's first love.
I wouldn't go that far.
But I want to see him again.
To thank him for saving me.
And ask him why he saved me.
Ms. Cheon Song Yi?
Perhaps you haven't read the syllabus
because you didn't come.
You can't plagiarize or cut-and-paste
for the papers in my class.
But it seems you did all of that.
So you will receive a zero for this paper.
Can you be eating ramen?
Don't you have to shoot tomorrow?
Asshole.
Wrong pass code.
Why?
- You have been blocked.
- Blocked?
You'd dare?
Open sesame!
Hul! It really opened!
Of course it did,
because I opened it.
Did you like giving me a zero
and embarrassing me?
Did you?
I bet that you will bleed, blue blood.
You wouldn't even spit
gum in a beggar's hand.
Excuse me, Cheon Song Yi.
Shut up!
Where are you going?
What's wrong with her?
Why sleep at her neighbor's?
Cheon Song Yi!
Do you know that you're sleeping
in a stranger's place?
Wake up!
Watch out.
Hi Yoo Ra.
Hey!
Where is Cheon Song Yi?
Why are you asking?
Where is she?
You little!
What?
How did you come here?
Let's go out.
Where do you think you're going?
Look! Can't you see that
I'm talking to her?
Don't get in the way
and get lost!
Who is she?
Why look at someone else's
picture without asking?
Who is she?
Do I have to answer that?
What are you doing?
Are you out of your mind?
Who are you?
My belly...
Aww my belly...
Excuse me.
I'm sorry, but where are you going?
Me?
Just... Songin University Hospital.
At two in the morning?
I have business to attend to.
She seems to have nausea and vomiting.
Also fever.
Sharp pain when probing
in the lower abdomen.
And the pain worsens when
the probing hand leaves.
I suspect appendicitis.
By the way, who are you?
Pardon?
How are you two related?
He's my manager.
My manager.
Me?
No way.
How am I your manager?
I'm an actress.
If people hear about me coming to
the ER with a man...
There will be scandals of me being pregnant
or that I tried to commit suicide.
And you made me your manager?
You said that you would be my manager.
- Since when?
- Cheon Song Yi's Manager?
Yes?
- So what are you going to do?
- About what?
Her shoes.
You said that you saw them in your vision.
If you had foreseen like you did
twelve years ago...
Then the owner of the shoes may die.
Hey! What are you looking at?
Those shoes.
Are they yours?
Of course they are.
You thought they were sponsored?
Look here please.
Look here.
Smile!
Hi!
Oh!
Congratulations Seo Young!
You even copy my shoes now?
I didn't copy you.
I was the first to get them in Korea...
Why do you have to always fight?
Just stand by my side.
Let's take a picture.
Okay that's good.
What are you doing?
Take it, now.
Damn it, I blinked.
Take one more, please.
Oh yeah, where's your best friend?
She went to drink.
Again?
Song Yi! It's dangerous.
Careful.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Where did Song Yi go?
You said that she went to get a drink.
She was there just now.
Crazy.
Cheon Song Yi, I...
Shhh...
It's rude to talk in
someone else's dream.
I'm cold.
The body found in the river was
identified as Han Yoo Ra.
It's a shocking story.
The sudden death of a movie star
has shocked many.
Some find the reason of her death
as due to a fight with her colleague.
Han Yoo Ra was found.
Dead?
Yes.
How?
An accident?
What happened?
I don't know about that.
But we're dying.
Why?
You have to leave now. The reporters
are going upstairs. You have to hurry.
Get on the elevator!
I'm on my way!
No! Not the elevator.
No? Why not?
The reporters got on the elevator.
- Emergency stairs!
- Emergency stairs?
No!
No? No?
Why not?
Some walked up that way.
Wait! Wait, wait!
Over here.
Cheon Song Yi!
Just a few questions.
Can you step out for a sec?
Have you heard?
Han Yoo Ra suffered from depression
because of Cheon Song Yi.
That's why she committed suicide.
I heard that she gave her a hard time.
Really?
Oh yeah.
Your last drama ended with
a 4% tune in rate.
That's the one I turned down.
Look at her talking.
She's so mean.
Her family doesn't want an autopsy.
The police are assuming that it's a suicide.
That's how the media portrays it too.
It's likely that the case
is going to be closed.
You're not drunk.
It's paralysis.
You will just be another celebrity
who has committed suicide.
However...
We found videos and recordings of her
phone calls with you on her laptop.
We took care of the laptop.
But there was a trace of her making a copy.
Where's the copy?
I checked the black box on her car.
She left her USB in her clutch bag.
It was Cheon Song Yi.
Good morning!
It was just...
having a person sleeping here.
And yet you've managed to change my place.
Right?
Having a girl makes a
difference in the air right?
It even looks brighter in a sense right?
I'll kill you!
Huh? Bring it on.
There seems to be a misunderstanding.
It's not what you think.
I just wanted to make sure.
To see if there's really a connection
between Yi Hwa and her.
Or if they just look alike.
It's nothing more or less.
Fake eyelashes.
[Happy birthday! Cheer up.
Your fan.]
Do Min Joon!
Do Min Joon! Are you in there?
He's not there when I really need him.
Where did you go?
Get a cell phone.
I couldn't call you when I needed you.
Final exam at four.
Mandatory.
F for no shows.
Vroongy!
Let's go for a ride.
Ouch! Who the heck?
Oh no! Oh my God.
I'm at Cheon Song Yi's place.
I'm sorry! I rear-ended you.
Can you come out?
It's fine! Just leave!
You need to check your car.
Cheon Song Yi!
Can I have an interview?
Cheon Song Yi! Your face please.
Show us!
This was not a car accident.
It was on purpose.
You knew that a person was in there.
You also knew that she could get hurt.
And you purposely made the collision.
Hence, it falls under willful
negligence destruction.
Who are you?
I'm her legal representative.
I'm also the witness.
If the person in the car is hurt...
I could also charge you with
assault battery.
If you yell at someone to get out of
the car, when she doesn't want to...
Or do any threatening gesture...
It falls under Section 283 of
Criminal Law under threatening.
For cases like this, you will
be arrested as a flagrant offender.
Should I call the police?
You may take pictures.
But if you distribute them
without consent
you will be subject to a lawsuit.
Come out.
It's okay.
Only hide when you have something to hide.
Don't just hide.
Where have you been, Manager Do?
Let's go.
Manager Do.
Hey! Take it.
Huh?
It's not working.
Is it broken?
Is it out of batteries? What's wrong?
What's wrong with it?
[Hurry]
Yeah, it's Cheon Song Yi.
What kind of manager leaves
without telling me?
Where did you go?
Call me.
You wanted to have a meeting.
What's our business?
What do you want to eat for dinner tonight?
For your information,
I like sea cucumbers.
I want to eat them before winter passes.
What kind of a manager
leaves so frequently?
You should've told me.
Is something wrong?
Of course!
Aren't we going to have a
meeting about our lunch?
I want some pot udon.
Gosh, bye!
But I'm hungry.
Song Yi!
What? Why aren't you with Se Mi?
This.
You left it in your car last time.
Oh yeah.
You can have it all after I'm gone.
So clumsy.
I can't just throw it away.
But I can't keep it either.
What is this?
We found videos and recordings of her
phone calls with you on her laptop.
I took care of the laptop.
But there was a trace of her making a copy.
Get me out of here.
I'm not crazy.
I think I'm really going to go crazy.
Tell me.
Why did you end up here?
- You need to get away from him.
- Who is that other girl?
He could kill you too.
Where did you get it? It's good.
Hello?
Oh! It's out already?
Today?
Manager Do! We have a schedule!
- What is it?
- My tailoring is done!
What am I going to wear?
What's that?
Oh that?
A present from an anonymous fan.
Isn't it cute?
What are you doing?
What's that?
Things have gotten inconvenient.
Start.
Who was watching me?
Does he hate me so much to
invest his own time and money?
I'm Do Min Joon.
Oh yes. You reported him right?
Is he the culprit?
I'm administering your shot.
Okay.
I admitted to everything.
Why wouldn't I admit to this one then?
That wasn't me!
Then is there someone else?
[Manager Do]
Do Min Joon!
Help!
Who's that?
What was that?
The master cylinder was taken out.
It couldn't have stopped.
Finish her.
Yes sir.
What?
When we woke up...
We were both on a highway
far away from that place.
When we got back there,
Cheon Song Yi was already gone.
Who was the man who came out of nowhere?
I don't know.
I can't even make a guess.
Is this what you want?
If I hand this over to you,
will you stop then?
Yes, of course.
I will pay you back in return then.
Do you know what this is?
It's a tranquilizer for animals.
It will put you to sleep.
Your suicide will look more
natural than anything I've ever done.
You killed Han Yoo Ra and assaulted
the prosecutor on the case.
Then you couldn't handle the pressure.
You chose your death.
I need to take care of you first.
To get rid of Cheon Song Yi.
Bye.
Listen well.
Stop right here. Don't do anything.
Come out! Come out!
Yeah Yoon Jae.
It's me.
Where?
I'm next door.
Unit 2302.
Yeah, I'm at the front door.
I just opened the door...
What happened?
I just called you.
Are you okay?
Wake up!
Are you awake?
Where am I?
My room.
You slept for more than ten hours.
What happened last night?
What if someone's in there?
I will take care of it.
You just worry about yourself.
You said that it wasn't
unrequited love.
It's not!
I didn't know that the
prosecutor was your brother.
How is he?
He received surgery for
traumatic subdural hemorrhage.
Do Min Joon could hear me sing.
He could even hear me screaming.
The wall is perfectly sound-proof.
How did he do it?
Leaving now?
Yeah.
See you later.
Where are you going Do Min Joon?
- Supermarket.
- Supermarket?
Good I need to go too.
Like that?
Oops.
I'll just put a coat on.
Wait just a sec.
Don't go.
I told you to wait for me!
Let's shop together
and split it in half.
I don't buy more than I need.
- Potato?
- I don't like potatoes.
Do you dip salt or sugar in potatoes?
Why would I want to dip?
What about chicken?
Do you like the legs or the breasts?
Breasts.
We like the opposite stuff.
We won't fight over food
our whole lives then.
I won't eat anything with you
for my whole life.
Where are you going?
Is it far?
Can I come along?
No.
I have something to tell you.
Did you come all the way here because
you wanted to hear my answer?
What do you think about me?
Wait!
Don't answer that! I will kill you!
I'm not normally like this.
Yeah, I admit that you were good to me.
But am I someone who can't
distinguish gratefulness and love?
No.
But why do I have to think about you?
I'm normally someone to be thought about.
My airport fashion, my lipstick, my hair...
I'm always thought about by people.
Should I think about you?
Your kiss...
Have I lost my mind?
What do you think of me?
Wait don't answer that! I will kill you!
I don't like you.
And now I dislike you even more.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to get out of my sight.
But...
Why do I feel like...
you're lying?
One-person management?
Yes, Mrs. Yang.
I feel bad about Song Yi's scandal.
I want to manage her career from now.
You were protecting
Cheon Song Yi too well.
So I found a different way.
So what will you do?
Choose.
You always said...
on the night you almost
died twelve years ago...
The person who saved you.
If he came to you again,
you said that you'd recognize him.
And?
He's right next you.
So why can't you recognize him?
Next to me?
Where?
Blood?
Do Min Joon?
Do Min Joon? Wake up!
Do Min Joon? What about me?
You shouldn't have gotten involved.
Then you wouldn't have gotten hurt.
Min Joon is leaving soon.
In less than two months now.
If you have feelings for him, I think
it's best that you stop for both your sakes.
Think of it as it never happened
in the first place.
I...
like her.
Two months are good.
One month is enough.
I just want to be with her.
Is it really not going to work?
Will it not work?
This was unexpected.
I didn't think that you'd call me first.
I came to make a proposition.
I will do what you want me to do.
You want me to take the
blame and disappear right?
I will do that.
Then... will you stop here?
You said that you wanted
to ask something.
It doesn't matter.
Who you are...
Or what happened...
If there's something
you can't tell me now...
It really doesn't matter.
I'm going to tell you what secret
lies behind the man
you foolishly trust.
That's why I wanted to see you.
Didn't you want to know who
saved you twelve years ago?
The person that saved you was me.
The reason I saved you was...
because you looked like
a girl from 400 years ago.
The owner of this hair pin.
Do Min Joon, let's go home.
You're not well yet.
I came here from an outside
world 400 years ago.
I could not return to my planet.
I lived here on Earth for 400 years.
Don't you get it?
I can hurt you right now if I want to.
So...
Leave while I let you.
Leave!
Then why did you do it?
Why did you save me so many times?
And do the things I wanted to do.
Doing everything for me.
Why did you protect me?
Why?
Because you looked like her.
I wanted to see if you
two were connected.
But that doesn't seem to be the case.
If you are just Cheon Song Yi.
Then I'm not interested.
You never liked me for one second?
Your heart never fluttered for me?
You never worried about me sincerely?
You never liked me without having
to do anything with her?
No, never.
I will give up then.
Good idea.
- Are you shooting that today?
- Yeah.
You should watch if you have time.
I'm going to make history in action films.
Hee Kyung!
Prosecutor!
Look!
Cheon Song Yi got into
an accident while filming.
How did that happen?
I was talking!
Do Min Joon!
What do you think I'm going to do?
Die!
I will show you what
total destruction is.
- You dare.
- You dare!
I will show you who exactly
you dared to infuriate.
Wow! Did you see this?
A man caught Song Yi from her fall.
He's an heir to a corporation.
Dang!
He's got money and height?
She's so lucky.
We know each other personally.
Three times is too much!
My daughter is Cheon Song Yi.
You dared to reject her?
Who do you think you are?
We're not sorry at all.
Song Yi got a contract with S&C.
She's going to get engaged with Hee Kyung.
Is it because you heard
that she's getting engaged?
Cheon Song Yi doesn't like him.
He saved her life.
She could change her mind.
Haven't I saved her?
I've saved her more than once!
Why are you getting angry?
I'm not angry! You're
just not making any sense!
Wake up.
Stop.
Stop it. Stop.
She says it tickles!
She says to stop!
Fried chicken and beer!
Get in.
I said no!
I will count to three.
One, two, three, three and a half.
Come here when you're done.
I will wait.
No, Do Min Joon.
Don't wait.
Leave.
- Cheon Song Yi, I...
- Do Min Joon.
We're nobodies to each other.
You said that you didn't like me.
Then act like it.
Cut!
Thank you! Thank you!
Did everyone just leave me?
I'm Cheon Song Yi!
It's unbelievable.
I said leave.
I said I'll wait.
Why wait for me?
Because I...
I need to protect you.
I want you to know how selfish you are.
What are you doing?
This is the most selfish thing
I can do to you.
Subtitles by DramaFever
[My Love From Another Star
The Beginning]