David Wozniak, room 4.
You have tissues, towels,
a pitcher of water and a sink.
You can settle in here.
Here's all the reading material
you might need.
Your cup.
When you're done, come see me.
PAST DUE
David.
I brought you your breakfast.
OK! OK!
Hey.
Dad's looking for you.
You're 45 minutes late.
Can you move it this morning?
Sure. Morning, Mom.
- You took the truck home again?
- Yup.
I asked you not to use
the delivery truck
for personal reasons.
- Did you?
- But you do it anyway.
- Yeah.
- Did you at least get the jerseys?
- Yes.
No, for real.
Do you have the jerseys
for tonight?
Yes!
Yes.
Yes, yes!
Yes, dear.
Yes.
I should never have
knocked that woman up.
Reproduction is a mistake.
Never reproduce.
I've got a customer.
- I gotta talk to you.
- Mr. Dubé.
- Hang up! Hang up!
- Yeah. Bye.
I gotta talk to you.
To help pay off my debts...
I set up a small hydroponic garden
in my apartment.
You're growing pot?
Yeah, but I'm having trouble,
and you're the only one I know
with a green thumb.
You want me to help you grow pot.
You've got a green thumb.
Sure! Of course! Absolutely!
That's the one thing I'm missing:
being part of a drug ring.
Calls every three minutes
from my pregnant wife
aren't stressful enough.
I wanna live a double life
so I can get called in
to testify at a major drug trial.
So, what do you say?
No, David.
My answer is no.
How much do you owe?
Eighty.
Eighty?
Thousand.
$80,000?
When you say it with a face
like that, it sounds like a lot.
David!
You know I love you like a son.
I am your son.
Which is why I love you
like a son.
But if you don't have ourjerseys
for the game tonight...
I've got the jerseys.
It's the first game of the season.
They're taking the team picture.
We need the jerseys.
I have the jerseys.
You ask him about the jerseys?
You were supposed to get them
three weeks ago.
I have the jerseys!
He obviously
doesn't have the jerseys.
No.
I was here first!
My blinkers were on.
I was backing up.
I'm gonna have to ask you
to move your car, please.
I'm already parked.
I'm here!
He came in from behind.
If I don't get those jerseys,
I'm a dead man.
Thank you!
HYDROPONICS
HYDROPONIC GARDENING
No rolling papers with this?
Your loan has been declined.
If I don't find $80,000,
men are gonna come to my house
and drown me.
Did you write that down,
that I'll be drowned?
You don't have
the required collateral.
That's why we can't
give you the money.
If you have no assets
for us to seize,
what guarantee do we have
that we won't lose our money?
So, basically,
you're a big goddamn pawn shop.
We're not a pawn shop.
You're a big goddamn pawn shop
with fancier furniture.
So, I'm forced to decline
your application.
I'm sorry.
Fine, I understand.
This is a hold-up.
Pardon me?
I said: "Fine, I understand."
This is a hold-up, asshole.
I've got the jerseys.
I swear on our mother's grave!
Yeah, Mom's!
The jerseys are in the truck
as we speak.
The whole point of a relationship
is to share the good moments,
and the bad moments.
But when you leave someone,
you lose those privileges.
I never left you!
You never call or email.
- You're always trying to con me.
- No, I'm not!
- Why can't I come over?
- You can!
What are you hiding
in your apartment?
You're imagining things!
I never said that!
You can come whenever you want!
I'm pregnant.
I'll raise it on my own.
What do you mean by that?
I don't want a father who disappears
because he's too busy.
I don't want a father
who doesn't have a life.
- I do have a life.
- No, you don't.
You don't wake a pregnant woman up
at 2:00 a.m.!
I didn't know!
If you called more often,
you would have.
One day, this kid will ask
what you were like.
I'd rather be honest.
I'll say you weren't there
because you really had no interest
in being there.
But I am here.
I'm here!
Valérie, I'm right here!
Sure, it came as
a bit of a shock at first.
A real big shock, actually.
But the fear wore off right away
and I thought:
It's the best thing
that's ever happened to me.
No!
Etienne, get back to bed.
It's 3:00 in the morning.
Back to bed!
It's time to sleep. Go to bed!
Where are you going?
Not in the sandbox!
Talk her into an abortion.
What?
You can't say things like that
in front of your kids.
My kids know they're too old
to be aborted.
I'm telling you that I think
I might want to have a child.
David...
you're free.
You're a free man.
Believe me,
you don't want children.
They're like...
black holes that suck up
all your energy,
all your time, all your money,
all your hair.
Do you remember
when I had hair, David?
I can't get it up anymore.
It's as simple as that.
How can you say that
in front of your kids?
I can say whatever I want.
They don't listen to me.
They don't pick up
the frequency of my voice.
I can't get a decent hard-on.
At my age, it isn't normal
not to have a full erection.
I should wake up with
a raging boner every morning.
That's what my life should be.
No, sweetie pie, back to bed.
It's 3:00 in the morning.
Not in the sandbox. You too?
No!
Go to sleep!
I want a child.
David, as your friend
and your lawyer, can I -
Daddy!
Can I be brutally honest with you?
Yes.
You are in no way capable
of raising a child.
I want order in my life.
You think this is order?
Yeah.
This is beautiful.
Valérie!
I've decided to make some changes.
I'm working right now.
I'm gonna show you I'm worthy
of being the father of that child.
David Wozniak.
The name's Chamberlan.
The kitchen door was kicked in.
I'm a lawyer.
I've been trying to reach you.
I don't have a lot of time.
I'll be brief.
Between 1988 and 1990,
you donated sperm,
under the alias of "Starbuck"
at the Lafrance Clinic,
which I represent.
You made 693 donations
over a 23-month period,
in exchange for which you received
$24,255 in compensation.
You have high-quality sperm.
I'm sure yours isn't so bad either.
Due to certain complications
during a given period,
Mr. Lafrance ended up giving
your sperm to all his clients.
As a result,
you have fathered 533 children,
142 of whom
wish to know your identity.
You have fathered 533 children.
At each of your donation sessions,
you signed a confidentiality clause.
The clinic is thus legally bound
to protect your identity.
Some of the children plan to contest
the legality of these documents.
They want to know who Starbuck is.
So, you say each of the 693 times
you donated sperm,
you signed a confidentiality clause.
I signed one every single time.
Did you sign before or after
you choked the chicken?
- Before.
- You always beat your meat alone?
Yeah.
And you deposited your man juice
in little plastic cups.
Did the little plastic cups
consent every time?
Should I get another lawyer?
Honestly, I'm a bit hurt
you never mentioned it at the time.
You call your friend after
sleeping with a hot girl,
not after jerking off.
But from now on,
every time I masturbate,
I'll call you up
and fill you in on all the details.
No need. Listen up.
They claim your right to privacy
should take a back seat
to the basic human rights
they say have been violated.
It's complex.
Very complex.
Extremely complex.
Every lawyer dreams of defending
a case this significant!
It'll go down in the history books.
It'll set a legal precedent.
My mother always told me
I'd never amount to anything.
I'm gonna show the old bitch.
I don't feel very good.
Postpartum depression.
533 times over.
You might feel a little down.
What do I do?
For now, I advise you to stop
whacking off in fertility clinics.
Should I get a real lawyer?
You can't afford a real lawyer.
I'll call the Bar this afternoon
and get my licence back.
- You're not licensed?
- A formality.
It's just a matter of a few dates
and some paperwork.
And a bribe or two.
Here.
What's that?
The 142 children in the class action
want you to know who they are.
Those are their profiles.
They're not my children.
These are the months
of the year...
Do you have a babysitter?
Like right here, right now?
To baby-sit your envelope?
- I opened the envelope.
- Crap.
I shouldn't have. I know.
I looked at one profile. Just one.
I picked it out at random.
One. Wanna know who it is?
Ricardo Donatelli.
There he is. There!
That's him, number 14.
You see him?
Sit down!
Let go of me!
Move it! Move it!
My genes were on
a professional-soccer pitch!
It's crazy.
It's like an extension of me
scored the game-winner.
So, do your kids play
on a professional soccer team?
Not that I know of.
But I'll ask.
They don't tell me everything.
I was thinking we should consider
an insanity plea.
What?
You can't be held responsible
for your actions if you were...
mentally unstable.
We'll play up your mental problems.
But I don't have mental problems.
I don't have mental problems!
That's exactly how
I want you to say it in court.
Let's go, Reds!
We're starting!
Come on, David!
Give it to me!
Go! Go!
What position is he playing,
for Christ's sake?
Hello.
Yeah, it's me.
What are you doing?
You should've been here
15 minutes ago.
Are you messing with me?
Yes, it's this afternoon!
I wrote it down on the schedule
three days ago!
Yeah, it's there.
So, what am I supposed to do?
Finish up what you're doing.
I'll call and tell them
I'll be an hour late.
OK, hold on a sec.
A large coffee to go, please.
Come on, man,
give me a break!
Forget it, I'll work it out.
Thanks, you're a pal!
It was to go.
Thanks.
That's $2.25.
You could be more polite.
I'm sorry?
I'm the customer.
You're the waiter.
A "please" and "thank you"...
What is this?
If you wanna be a waiter -
That's the problem.
I don't wanna be a waiter.
I'm an actor.
Who's missing a huge audition.
And you want me to smile for $2.25?
While the opportunity of a lifetime
is passing me by?
Doesn't have to be a big smile.
OK.
Have a nice day.
Yes?
You go. I'll fill in for you here.
Who'd know the difference?
We do get customers
in here sometimes.
Isn't this your big chance?
How do I know
you won't run away with the cash?
Take my delivery truck.
It's full of meat.
What's in it for you?
The satisfaction of making
a difference in someone's life.
Bring it back without a scratch.
People might come in.
I can figure out
how to make a cup of coffee.
Fly!
Go, go, go!
You know you have the easiest job
in the whole shop?
And just so I'm being clear,
by that, I mean you're a moron.
And yet despite how
mind-blowingly simple yourjob is,
you always manage
to mess it up somehow.
It's like every day,
you find a new way
to push the limits of stupidity.
Essentially, you've only got
two things to do.
Two!
Get meat.
Deliver meat.
The phone's ringing off the hook.
Apparently, today,
you forgot to do
one of those two things.
You forgot the delivery part!
No, I'm doing the deliveries now.
I'm delivering my ass off
as we speak.
You're more of a meat watchman.
Today, all you're doing
is watching the meat.
I'll have a "tell-me-who-you-are-
before-I-call-the police".
The waiter.
I'm the owner.
I do all the hiring.
I'm filling in for Etienne.
He had an important audition.
He can find himself anotherjob.
Sir...
It's the role of a lifetime.
Cut him some slack.
Slack really isn't the problem here.
- What is it then?
- He's no good.
He can't act.
He never gets a role. Ever.
He sucks.
I'll let you tell him
he's not a waiter anymore.
Let him know it's your fault
if he can't make his rent.
I lost my job?
Yeah.
I got the part.
You did?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Where were you yesterday?
You were supposed to be here at noon.
I started, but I can't
do it all by myself!
No.
I'll be two seconds!
Hold on. Don't go anywhere.
- Hello. That'll be $1 1 .50.
- I'm $4 short.
I knew you were gonna
fucking bail on me!
How the hell am I supposed
to pay the rent?
And you owe me money, too!
Am I gonna see any ofthat?
Fuck off and die!
You said May!
Shut up! Shut up!
You're a goddamn liar.
You're a goddamn liar!
How am I gonna pay for this?
I don't have a fucking cent!
You owe me money!
I want it back! Stop it!
Stop it!
Miss?
Don't worry about the $4.
I don't know who you are,
but this isn't a good time, OK?
Get out of my apartment.
Sure, sure. Absolutely.
But I...
I'm gonna call the cops!
No, no need for that!
But you sound really upset.
And we have a very strict policy
about the state of mind
in which we leave our customers.
My boss is a real stickler.
He always says: "At...
"At Rigoletto Pizzeria,
we care about our customers.
"We believe in
a more human approach to pizza."
Are you all right?
No. Fuck, no!
Let go!
Julie.
- Let go! I want out of here!
- Julie!
I wanna get out of here!
Let go of me!
Who are you, exactly?
Are you ashamed to admit
you're my father?
No.
You have to sign my release.
Can I have a word with you?
The good news is,
a spotjust opened up
in our methadone program.
The bad news is,
your daughter has no interest
in the program.
She's still a minor,
so it's up to you.
I...
We get excellent results.
I'll talk to her.
Can we...
Hi...
Dad.
Sign the release.
I don't know who you are,
but I'm begging you.
- They have a good program.
- I can quit on my own.
I just had the scare of my life.
I think the program -
I'd be surrounded by junkies
24 hours a day here.
I'll have a relapse for sure.
They'll help you.
They'll lock me up,
and I'll lose my job.
I just started. It's my dream job.
It's all I've got.
Thank you.
I'm signing the release.
You're making a huge mistake.
She'd be unhappy here.
Right now,
she doesn't need to be happy.
She needs to get clean.
She's gonna quit.
Do you love your daughter?
- Yes.
- Tell her that.
Then tell her
you won't sign her release.
Where do you work?
At Ogilvy, on Sainte-Catherine.
I never finished school.
A friend got me the job.
- You have my phone number?
- Yeah.
- Tomorrow, you start work at...
- 8:00.
- And you'll be there at...
I tend to make some very,
very bad decisions.
I'd like you to prove to me
that this isn't one of them.
You made the right choice.
Thanks, Dad.
...but it's the first time
I really injured myself.
It's rare to welcome outsiders
to our colony,
especially since
the Iroquois resumed
their attacks on our settlers.
That's very nice of you. Thanks.
It's rare to welcome outsiders
to our colony,
especially since
the Iroquois resumed
their attacks on our settlers.
Push!
Cheapskate!
It's rare to welcome outsiders
to our colony,
especially since the Iroquois
resumed their attacks
on our settlers.
Watch where you're going.
I think he's an inspector.
We need a hand!
Did you say "yum-yum"?
I'm not sure I heard you right.
- Did you say "yum-yum"?
- Yeah.
Don't say "yum-yum"!
I had a revelation.
I realized it's impossible
to be a father to 533 children.
It's impossible.
It can't be done.
It can't be done with four.
Exactly, it's impossible.
But I can be their guardian angel.
- Their guardian angel?
- Yeah.
I realized these kids
need someone in their lives...
someone to watch over them.
I'm the donor.
They're my responsibility.
And I accept that responsibility.
So, you're telling me,
your mission here on Earth
is to watch over 533 children
like some sort of superhero.
I didn't say superhero.
When you're watching over them,
are you wearing Lycra?
I didn't say superhero.
I said guardian angel.
So, no Lycra,
but you have wings
and you play the harp.
You know what?
I'm feeling more and more comfortable
with an insanity plea.
I don't have mental problems.
Perfect.
Say it just like that
to the judge.
I haven't slept in four days.
I've never been happier
in all my life.
I never thought
I could love anyone this much.
He poops eight times a day,
and I think I've lost my mind,
because I swear,
I worship every single one
of his diapers.
Your brother wants to go
on parental leave
so he can have more time
to worship his son's dirty diapers.
I'm entitled by law
to parental leave.
I have three kids.
Two hours after each was born,
I was here.
Which is why your 1 1-year-old son
hardly recognizes you.
When he comes by, he asks me:
"Which one is my dad?"
You gotta have kids, too, David.
Thanks.
Hey there.
Today's my first ultrasound.
Is it?
- I need a friend, not a father.
- I'm your friend.
- I want to be clear.
- It's clear.
Hurry up. I drank a litre of water
and I'm not allowed to pee.
Are you going to ask the sex?
I want a girl.
- That's not how it works.
- I want a girl.
It'll be a girl.
Here you can see
your baby's profile.
There's a little hand
coming into the frame.
There's the profile,
with a little hand just above it.
And the little face.
There's the heart beating,
which you can see clearly.
See?
Let's look at the circumference
of the head.
I'm not so sure about this.
About what?
Whether this baby
will be a source of happiness.
Look at them. Look!
Look at that one!
I've watched him for 10 seconds,
and already I wanna smack him.
I swear, it's all I can do
to keep from kicking him in the ass.
It'll be fine, Valérie.
Sure, you can be
a bit anal-retentive...
Remember that woman
who drowned her two kids?
I think I'm the only person
on the planet
who thought she made
a convincing argument.
I'm not saying
the kids deserved to die,
but they could've listened,
for Christ's sake!
I think it's the best thing
that could've happened to us.
Who made you the Dalai Lama?
What the hell does that mean?
Look at that one!
He's eating his boogers!
They're full of protein.
Valérie, did you know
we all have...
tremendous untapped resources
inside of us?
Resources? What do you mean,
"untapped resources"?
Here's what I know about my resources:
My kid looks at me like that,
he gets a smack upside the head.
You're gonna be a good mother.
OK.
Because I don't trust you at all,
what I'm gonna do is...
I'll name you... No.
I'll declare you as the father...
Yes!
- Yes!
- No, wait.
I'll declare you
father-on-a-trial-basis.
- Father-on-a-trial-basis!
- Zero screw-ups allowed.
- For how long?
- Forever.
OK.
Will the kid have to call me
Trial Basis Dad?
No.
Will I have any kind of costume
or sign to wear...
that'll set me apart
from the regular dads?
No.
Then I accept.
Your name?
Léopold Duval.
And you are...
A friend.
He's over there.
OK, I'll be back.
You're not staying for a visit?
I wanted to see him. I saw him.
I'll come back later.
It would make him really happy.
Yeah.
But I...
Just talk to him.
Hey, Raphaël.
Hi.
I was in the neighbourhood.
So I stopped by to see you.
I wanted to talk to you.
You did a good job.
I didn't say anything.
You did a great job.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Bye, man. See you later.
I know, I'm late.
I'm really sorry.
Come on. We'll be late.
We approached Starbuck
before filing the suit
to see if he was willing
to change his mind,
but he categorically refused.
Yes?
Thank you.
I just wanted to tell you...
well, I don't know
all of you, but...
I love you.
I love you all very much.
You're all focusing a lot
on Starbuck.
But you can't forget that
whatever happens,
you're all brothers and sisters.
You've found one another.
Hey, man! Thanks!
You're right.
Yeah, well, thanks.
I always see him in the subway.
What are you doing here?
I'm Raphaël's adoptive father.
Raphaël?
Raphaël's disabled.
He's in an institution.
That's why he can't be here tonight.
Julie, this is Marco.
It is Marco, right?
Marco saved my life
at the public pool.
He's a lifeguard.
I'm Raphaël's adoptive father.
He's disabled
and can't be here tonight.
- One of these kids is yours?
- By adoption.
Hey!
What are you...
It's Etienne!
Etienne works at a café
in my neighbourhood,
but he's an actor, too.
This is Marco, a lifeguard.
Julie, an ex-addict.
I adopted Raphaël,
a disabled young man
who couldn't be here tonight...
adopted.
David.
David!
What are you doing here?
I spoke to the psychologist.
He said he met you
and you're perfectly normal.
- I told you so.
- You're not normal!
As of tonight,
you're party to a class-action suit
against yourself!
- What are you doing here?
- Spying.
The only chance we have
is to show that you're not normal.
It's our only chance.
But I am normal.
I've known you 20 years.
You're not normal.
It's time to tell the psychologist
about Mariouka.
Mariouka?
You married a Russian woman
you didn't even know!
She said she'd be my maid
for a year.
And she took off after three days.
How much did you lose in
that scheme to import Cuban cigars?
The guy seemed like
a legit businessman!
He walked around in a swimsuit!
Who does business
with a guy in a swimsuit?
Make sure you mention
you once paid $500 for one of
Hall and Oates's guitar picks.
When they die,
it'll be worth a fortune!
That won't be for another 30 years!
Besides, it's Hall and Oates!
They'd do a gig
at a kids' party for $500!
For once, I'm doing the right thing.
You're not doing the right thing.
Stop going to see your children!
Hello, David Wozniak.
My name is Antoine.
I'm your biological son.
I don't like being lied to.
Are you going to out me?
Yeah.
Can't this be our little secret?
- What do you do?
- I work in a butcher shop.
I'm a vegetarian.
So, you murder animals.
No, no! I'm just a delivery guy.
I don't kill them.
I just cart them around.
You cart around the carcasses
of murdered animals.
Yeah.
I imagined you as a musician.
Are you into music?
I'm more of a jock.
Like the guys who beat me up
in high school.
You got beat up?
As you can see,
I'm a little different.
Different how?
Most people come into this world
out of an act of love.
Most people are conceived in love.
But me...
I came into this world
out of an act of self-abuse.
I was conceived in a little cup.
Can I stay here for a while?
Yeah.
Cool.
He's excruciating.
He's excruciating!
He's already called me
three times this morning!
Three times in one morning!
Do whatever he says.
He can't turn you in.
The conversations are endless,
like a police interrogation.
Don't upset him.
Go along with anything he wants.
No.
- Answer.
- No!
- Answer it now.
- No.
No!
Antoine!
Go along with anything he wants.
Yes.
- You look way too relaxed.
- This is a special moment for me.
It's a big step
in our relationship.
Nothing they say about me is true,
not a word of it!
They enjoy humiliating me.
They're monsters.
Seriously. They're monsters!
David! Valérie.
Hello. Thank you.
Hello! Welcome!
Thank you. Hi. Valérie.
- Our kids.
- Hi!
- Hello, Valérie.
- Hello.
- He's beautiful.
- David!
Dad! Dad, Valérie.
Nice to meet you.
OK, everyone, no stories tonight.
The photo albums
are in the living room.
No, not the photo albums.
No pictures!
No pictures right off the bat!
Come, let's look at the albums.
Sorry to interrupt.
I want to propose a toast
to Valérie,
because it's important
you know that this...
Rite of passage.
This rite of passage
isn't just about humiliating David.
Although that's a highlight.
That's most definitely a highlight,
but it's not the only one.
We showed you everything
about David's past
because it's important you know
what you're getting into.
Now that you know all that...
I have more pictures.
We'll see them after dessert.
What pictures?
We've seen them all.
There are no more.
Sniper.
Not Sniper!
- What's Sniper?
- David's band.
- No way!
- Yeah, with makeup and everything.
It was the '80s.
Everybody wore makeup!
I didn't wear makeup in the '80s.
I had to explain to Dad
you weren't gay.
What?
You wore tights.
Now that you know all that
and realize the humiliation
isn't over,
you should also know that...
the Wozniaks have had
some wonderful times,
as well as some difficult ones.
- Don't go there.
- Why not?
You know it makes me uncomfortable.
It's embarrassing.
What?
Come on. Dad...
When my wife and I got married,
we were very young.
Our dream was to go to Italy
for our honeymoon.
But we didn't have much money.
Then came the kids, the business.
We thought: "One day,
when we're old and grey."
But time passed.
You have to make
the most of the present.
Are you all making the most
of the present?
Yes, Dad, we are.
Good.
My wife got sick.
David showed up
with two tickets to Venice.
He arranged everything:
a hotel near the Doge's Palace,
gondola rides...
And then our three sons
came to join us.
We had supper together...
near the Piazza San Marco.
David paid for everything.
He does things like that.
If you can live
with his countless shortcomings...
you're in for plenty
of beautiful surprises as well.
Let's pray.
Just a little prayer!
Let's drink!
How did you pay for
your entire family to go to Venice?
I had the money.
When you were 20?
Yes.
OK, but where'd you get it?
Can't I have a secret or two?
Sure.
As long as you're not growing pot
or anything.
Very cute.
I wasn't trying to be cute.
It was a threat.
- Have a good game, David.
- Thanks!
You OK?
Yeah.
You wanna play soccer?
Yeah!
Let go.
Now straighten up.
Now that one has to...
Both have to be straight.
I can't do it.
Not bad.
Switch.
Straight. Make an L.
Yeah! All right!
Switch.
Oh, I'm sorry!
I'm sorry, guys!
You won't believe me,
but you were good.
Once you realized
you can't touch the ball with your hand,
you were...
By then, the game
was almost over, but...
I thought for sure your brother
wanted to break my neck.
He wants to break everybody's neck.
You have to come
to the lake this weekend.
I have plans with Valérie.
Everyone's gonna be there!
You're the reason
we thought about doing it.
I understand,
but I have plans with Valérie.
And we've already spent
a lot of time together.
I've got a real family, too.
A real family?
I mean... my family.
OK.
So, the rest of us don't exist?
Maybe you put
that part of your life behind you,
but it doesn't mean
the rest of us just vanished.
We exist.
We're here.
And we're also your real family.
I hope you're happy.
I hope you're very happy.
I hope you really,
truly appreciate this.
Because thanks to you,
I had to lie to Valérie.
Thanks to you,
I had to lie to the woman
who's carrying my baby.
And as far as lying goes...
I'm done.
Did you bring me here
to tell everyone who I am?
No.
I want to keep you for myself.
All right!
Cheese?
This one's a bit heavier.
Right!
How many for tofu?
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven.
I just want to say...
I think it's disgusting,
people who murder tofu for food.
I don't know if you've ever seen
a tofu slaughterhouse,
but it's horrible.
What they do to the tofu
is shocking.
But I'll cook some up
for you anyway.
See what happens
when I put it on the grill?
Exactly what it tastes like...
nothing!
I love my adoptive family.
I adore them.
I'm sure you all feel the same way.
We all love our adoptive families.
There's no doubt.
But this has been
the best weekend of my life.
It would be really unfair
for anyone to miss out
on having a family like this.
I don't know.
Don't you think so?
David! Hey, David!
That was a lot offun.
See you soon.
Raphaël!
I just want you to know...
I'm your father.
Go ahead.
Have a great day!
Have a great day, ma'am.
Have a great day, big guy.
Careful, your hat.
Have a great day.
Coffee? Toast? Eggs?
No, I'm fine.
- Busy weekend?
- Nothing special.
I stayed home and read
The Lord ofthe Rings.
Lie to your girlfriend all you want.
Lying is the basis
of a solid relationship.
But I'm not your girlfriend.
So before you tell me you spent
the weekend with Frodo and Gandalf,
have a good look at this.
THE CHILDREN OF STARBUCK
It's not cutting-edge
investigative journalism,
but The Times and Paris Match
are interested in the story,
which means, by bedtime tonight,
somewhere between
4 and 5 billion people
will be wondering:
"Who the fuck is Starbuck?"
Is this good news?
Is this good for the trial?
Is this a situation
we can turn to our advantage?
- Yes.
- Yes?
Time to get aggressive.
A countersuit.
We're suing the clinic, too.
For what?
Libel. You should hear
what they're saying about Starbuck.
- Like what?
- Awful stuff.
But it's fine!
With the countersuit,
we'll settle your debts.
We'll even make money.
We'll get...
a crapload of money!
You want me to sell my children
to pay off my debts.
They're not your children!
I want to come clean.
You can't tell them who you are.
They're my children.
OK.
But first I want you to hear
what people are saying.
I'm telling you this
as your friend.
How can one man be so
devoid of humanity that he...
so devoid of humanity
that he can bring
so many children into this world?
You gotta be oblivious.
Yeah, you have to be stupid
or mentally unstable.
I'd like to meet that guy
and ask him a few questions.
WHO IS STARBUCK?
What do you think
about this whole Starbuck thing?
It's horrible.
Why's that?
Because it's horrible.
Don't you think so?
I don't know.
What was he thinking?
I'm sure he didn't think his sperm
would be used as much as it was
or that his profile
would become so public.
He's a pervert,
plain and simple.
He's not a pervert!
- Yes, he is!
- No, he's not!
After 655 times,
what's the difference
between that and prostitution?
It's not prostitution!
- It's all the same.
- No, it's not!
When somebody
pays you to masturbate,
it's prostitution!
- Can I help you?
- Do you have a 533-seat stroller?
- No.
- No!
Because it's not normal
to have 533 children, is it?
Imagine how mortified
those children must be.
It's a national disgrace!
How does this make us look?
For an air-conditioned room
to beat off in,
I'd pay $35 any day.
But them paying me $35?
That's a sweet deal!
Why not? You're gonna do it anyway.
It's like taking money to breathe.
I'm sure that guy
will never come forward.
Imagine being known
as Sergeant Pecker
the rest of your life?
How could you work?
No matter what you'd say
in a meeting,
you'd still be Starbuck to everyone.
You could make an awesome pitch,
but they'd still think:
"Hey, it's El Masturbator!"
Anyone ever donate?
David, you must have donated sperm
at one time or another.
No.
What about when you lived
next to the Lafrance Clinic.
No.
When you were a kid,
you were always jerking off.
Cut it out, dammit!
I said cut it out!
Can't you shut your mouth for once?
Take it easy.
David...
your brothers want a word with you
in the office.
Some thugs showed up at Dad's.
They threw him in the bathtub.
They want their $80,000.
- I went to all the banks.
- Find the money.
We're filing the countersuit.
Excellent.
I've got everything.
It's all ready.
GOOD LUCK, DAD
A SPOKESMAN
FOR THE CHILDREN OF STARBUCK
David.
All rise.
We shall take the matter
under advisement.
Court is adjourned.
Why are they taking so long?
I don't know, David.
- What don't you know?
- Nothing, OK?
I don't know anything!
Absolutely nothing!
My mother was right.
I'm worthless.
I'm out of my league, David!
You should've hired a real lawyer!
Yes!
Yes.
Yes, all right.
The ruling's in.
Please be seated.
Both parties will receive
a detailed written account
in which you will be able to read
that Starbuck...
is wholly and unequivocally
entitled to his anonymity.
He is also entitled to receive
the compensation claimed
from the Lafrance Clinic
for damages and interest.
Starbuck will be entitled
to keep his identity secret,
and will receive $200,000
in damages and interest,
a verdict that will shock many
and disappoint many more.
I feel for all the children
in the class-action suit,
but I am extremely proud to have
defended my client's rights.
I'd like to say hello
to my own children and...
my mother.
I won, Mom.
I won.
I got an A+!
I also wanna say...
well... we did it, David!
No...
We did it!
No! Shut up! No!
Who's David?
David is my lover.
He supported me.
Thank you, my darling David.
I love you.
I love you, David.
Are you disappointed,
or did you expect this verdict?
Obviously, we're disappointed.
But it's not all bad.
What we found out today...
is that the law does not require
Starbuck to come forward.
But there's more to this
than the law.
There's us. And there's him.
Beyond the law,
there are human beings.
Ultimately, the choice is his.
He can stay in hiding.
But now that he's seen us,
he could decide to reveal his identity
on his own.
There's been a massive
anti-Starbuck backlash in the media.
We want our father to know...
we don't see him as a pervert.
We see him as someone
who gave happiness and life...
to people who really needed it.
Thank you.
Congratulations...
darling.
I had it.
For the first time ever,
I got it all right,
and I had to go and fuck it up.
My mother caught it all
on television.
Was she surprised to find out
you have a male lover?
No, she said
she always suspected it.
She thinks we make a cute couple.
What about your kids?
They think it's cool.
I wanted to ask you...
incidentally...
theoretically...
if I reveal my identity now,
do I lose the money
from the countersuit?
Theoretically...
do I lose the money
from the countersuit?
Yes, I think so.
I was officially trying
to turn my life around.
It's harder than I thought.
Dad...
I'm Starbuck.
You're "El Masturbator"?
For once in my life,
I'd like to make
the right decision.
I'd like to be a normal person.
What would a normal person do
in this situation?
A normal person wouldn't be
in this situation.
I know, but let's just say
they were, OK?
You know what?
You're probably
one of the few people
who can cope in a situation
as screwed up as this one.
Why don't you tell them?
Because, as you know,
I've got money problems.
Your debts.
You know I grew up
in unspeakable poverty.
I know, Dad.
When I left Warsaw
to come to Canada,
my father gave me $10.
It's all he had.
I couldn't refuse his help,
but I promised I'd pay him back
a thousand times over
when I made my fortune.
My father died
while your mother and I
were still penniless.
I always wondered...
what was more difficult for him:
not having given enough
to his children
or not having been beside them
during the hard times.
My greatest achievement in life...
has been to have you all beside me
every single day.
That's my greatest achievement.
So, like my father before me...
I want to help you.
Here.
Here's $10.
Dad...
It brought me luck.
So take the $10.
And take your share
of the butcher shop.
It's your inheritance.
In small bills.
I'm scared I'll be
a disappointment to them.
Why would you be?
Because I'm just
a meat-delivery guy.
And a terrible one at that.
True, you're terrible
at delivering meat.
It takes you four times longer
than it takes anyone else.
But wherever you go...
people love you.
They'll love you.
Everyone loves you.
That doesn't worry me one bit.
MY NAME IS DAVID WOZNIAK.
I AM STARBUCK.
Heads up!
We're live in eight, seven, six...
We'll be right there, sir!
Valérie!
Mr. Wozniak?
There are some people here for you.
Is he healthy?
Yes.
So, can you come in
to work tomorrow?
This is a bit weird, huh?
Sorry.
My name is David.
David Wozniak.
And I'm your biological father.
And you all have
a new little brother.
He showed up a bit early,
but he's doing very well.
Can we see him?
Sure.
I'll see what I can arrange.
Valérie.
He's so small.
Will you marry me?
Don't you wanna see
whether my figure comes back?
If you stay flabby,
I'll get flabby, too.
Is this the first time
"flabby" has been used
in a marriage proposal?
I'm Starbuck.
Why?
Why are you always trying to con me?
How could you think a proposal
would make it easier to swallow
the fact you have 533 children?
Well, you can forget
about this child.
Let me be clear on two things.
First, you asked me to change
as quickly as possible,
and that's exactly what I'm doing.
I've thought about this a lot.
I've concluded that nobody
can make that decision for me.
Not a judge, not my family,
not Paul Arcand, not even you.
I'll decide whether or not
I'm that child's father.
My name is David Wozniak,
and I am the father of that child.
Me.
You can say or do whatever you want.
It won't change the fact
that I am that child's father.
The other fact that won't change
is that I'm Starbuck.
I know it's freaky.
Nobody's gone through this before.
We're like the first astronauts
on the moon.
But I see...
infinite possibilities
for happiness...
and an incredible amount
of free babysitting.
Second...
That was a very long point.
I admit the first point
was a bit on the long side.
Second...
the proposal...
was for real.
The second point was shorter.
I think I managed
to be more succinct with that one.
I've already revealed my identity.
You did?
Promise me you'll take me
to Venice someday.
On behalf of all of your real family,
thank you.
Translation: Shonda Secord