Doogie!
Douglas, i can't
understand why
you're so angry.
We caught the fish.
Ha ha.
A good-sized
critter,
I might add.
You just
don't get it, dad.
I don't care.
I never wanted
to come here.
What?
I could be
in palm springs
with wanda right now.
Instead,
i'm stuck out here--
Needs more butter.
...Talking to the fish!
Butter.
More.
[doorbell rings]
Murray, get the door!
I've grown out
of these trips.
Butter.
[muttering]
I don't want to be
the great white
hunter.
Sorry to disturb you
at this hour,
mr. Seidenbaum,
But you have been
personally selected
To receive a most...
Irresistible offer.
Giving me instructions
Like i was still
a little boy.
I didn't realize
you felt like this.
I'm surprised you
didn't say anything
before this.
Murray, what are you
doing back there?
Murray!
[electronic noise]
Aah!
[burp]
My name is darryl knable.
I'm a normal kid
who led a pretty normal life...
Until that night.
[announcer]
it looks and feels natural,
Whether you're
skimming the surf
Or racing the wind
on a cruiser for two.
And remember,
we stand behind it.
I'm not only
the hair club
president,
But also a client.
[darryl]
in describing my dad,
several names come to mind--
Bill cosby, alan thicke,
The brady bunch father.
My dad watched
all of them.
In fact, he watched
anything on tv all the time.
They say
the average american
Watches 7 1/2 hours
of tv a day.
If that's true,
there are two guys
who never watch,
And my dad
took their times.
Perhaps i shall
one day.
You have some
dispatches for me,
captain?
I have some dispatches
for the queen.
Prepare to taste
corsican steel.
Uhh!
Hi.
It's late.
Yeah, i know.
I'll be up
in a minute, honey.
[swords cross]
I'm thinking
of renting out
Your side of the bed.
Huh?
Don't get me wrong.
I like tv just as much
as the next person.
It's just there are
more things you can
do with it
Than only watch it.
For instance, you can
also make money with it.
We interrupt
this broadcast
for a special report.
Young electronics
genius darryl knable
Has just won
the nobel prize.
Oh, you dipstick.
For secretly videotaping
his sister diane
French-kissing with
her boyfriend chris.
We're talking
tongues here!
For copies of this tape,
send $3.00 to...
Darryl knable,
1532 blue jay court--
Hey, knable,
your kid's messing up
my tv reception again.
And your dog's
messing up my dichondra.
Rivets didn't do that.
Then there's
a brontosaurus loose
in the neighborhood.
Bad dog. Bad, bad doggie.
I'm going to call
the fcc!
The fcc!
[snort]
My mom was a big-deal
advertising executive
With a vitamin company.
My dad had this
real suck job selling
plumbing supplies.
I heard them
arguing one night,
And she said
he was suffering from
Something called
a mid-life crisis,
Whatever that is.
He said he wasn't.
She said he was jealous
of her success.
He said he wasn't.
They argued a lot.
Aah!
So that's my dad,
Going to his
pretty normal home
After his pretty normal day
at his suck job,
Ready to watch his tv.
That brings us to that night
i was talking about.
That's when
everything changed.
[woof woof]
I love you.
I don't care
who loves who--
I won't play
the sap for you.
You killed miles, and
you're going over for it.
Wait, wait, wait.
Where are you two going?
Mom, remember?
Oh, right. You're
spending the night
with friends.
Diane...
No boys.
Mother,
i am not a child.
Mm-hmm. You go
directly to tracy's,
you understand?
Right.
Mom, you know my friend
billy stephan?
Mm-hmm.
Well, his dad
moved out for a while.
Then his parents
went away and sat
in a hot tub all weekend.
When they got back,
billy's dad moved back in
And things were all better.
Did you plan this
so your dad and i
could be alone?
We don't know how much
that hip bruise he got--
Roy?
Hi, helen.
I have an idea.
You know how proud
i am of you--
pass it!
Let's go away.
Go ahead. I'll be
there in 4 minutes
and 16 seconds.
Roy. Roy, listen.
Let's go away
like we used to,
To the mountains.
O.K.
Just the two of us.
No phones, no kids,
no tv.
No tv?
They don't have tv
there.
Is there a plug?
This is abnormal.
Honey, you're just
shutting yourself off
From everything
and everybody.
Are you having problems?
Is--is it me?
Yes! No.
Is--is it work?
Are you having trouble
at work?
Of course not.
What makes you say
something like that?
Shoot, you idiot.
Shoot.
The one thing we always
promised each other
Is that we would
remain honest.
We are honest
with each other.
Look...
You say
that i'm shut off,
That--that i can't
open up to you,
That i'm closed down.
O.K., well,
i'm going to
tell you something
That's--that's
very important to me.
I'm going to be
completely honest.
I just don't want you
to take this
the wrong way.
Oh, roy, talk to me.
I can take anything.
We're in double overtime
here.
Fine!
Watch tv.
Thanks, sweetheart.
Could you move
just to--
This is unbelievable!
You couldn't listen to me
for two minutes
Without that
stupid television
being on!
When i married you,
you were a doer.
Now all you are
is a watcher!
[announcer]
he gave it away
to drexler.
Drexler fouled
at mid-court.
Oh, roy?
Huh?
Hyah--aah!
The tv!
[paul henreid]
i was afraid
You were keeping tina
out of pity,
But that wasn't pity
just now.
Now i know
you still love me.
It won't die,
what's between us.
Do what you will--
Never happen.
Ignore it,
neglect it--
No further developments
in the disappearance
Of murray and sarah
seidenbaum of oakview.
Police are still baffled
and report they
have no clues.
Ahhhh...
Roy...
Your boring little life
Is about to become
Much more exciting.
[doorbell chimes]
Mr. Knable?
Sorry to disturb you
at this hour,
But you've been
personally selected
To receive a most
irresistible offer.
I'm busy.
Wait, mr. Knable.
I have something
you want--
Escape...
From all your
failures and woes,
At the touch
of your thumb...
On this.
[beeping]
Go ahead.
Your new controller.
Your passport
to the ultimate
television adventure.
Cute place.
You fence!
Oh, i used to.
Did you ever, uh,
kill anyone?
Of course not.
Look, mr., uh...
Spike.
At your service.
What exactly is it
that you're selling?
Mmm! Attractive.
The little woman.
You two
having difficulties?
Well, i don't see how--
I know all about you, roy.
Success, it's
like a fly buzzing
around your head.
You reach for it,
you grab it,
And all you get is...
Nothing!
You're tired
of nothing, roy,
So you want to hide
from everything,
But she gives you heat,
right?
Roy, wait till she
gets a load of this--
600 and 66 channels
of heart-pounding,
Skull-blasting
entertainment.
Comedy! Drama!
Hot-oil aerobics
Like nothing
you've ever seen,
brother.
Unlimited entertainment,
snatched from the ether
And slammed into
your brand-new
44-inch,
900-line resolution,
3-way expanded-matrix,
Dolby stereo tv,
right here, roy.
A new tv?
Straight from
the temple of high-tech.
Make this thing
look like a philco.
Some people would give
Their souls
for a system like this.
Just sign here.
We're in business.
I--i can't.
All right.
Good night, mr. Knable.
Did i mention, uh...
Free trial?
Free?
Well, roy,
all set for the tv
adventure of a lifetime?
Now remember...
You'll have to
adjust the dish
To fine-tune reception.
Like this.
Enjoy your new system,
roy.
We'll be in touch.
Ha ha ha!
That was a dead end!
[thunder]
[spike]
ha ha ha ha!
Hi.
Ho ho ho ho ho!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Aah!
Now, honey, just
keep an open mind.
There's no obligation.
I got it on a free trial.
It's a whole
satellite system,
over 600 channels.
¶ i hate to leave you ¶
¶ but i really must say ¶
¶ oh, good night,
sweetheart ¶
Wednesdays at 9:00...
The salesman said
we'd get a lot
of shows
You can't get
on regular tv.
Helen?
I don't want this anymore!
[announcer]
we thought
it would be funny,
If our bob, dressed
as a policeman,
Would tell
a perfect stranger
Her husband is dead.
Mrs. Cecily barth?
Yes.
Your husband's name
was steven barth?
Was?
What do you
mean, was?
Did your husband drive
a 1978 chevrolet impala?
What are you saying?
Has something happened
to my steven?
[announcer]
watch her reaction
to the bad news.
I'm afraid so.
Ah! Aah!
[weeping]
It's all right.
[announcer]
i think it's time
for mrs. Barth
To be let in on the fun.
Mrs. Barth, look
across the street
At that van behind me.
Look really carefully.
Is that, uh...
It's a camera, yes.
Then...You mean...
Yes, mrs. Barth.
You're on...
Sadistic hidden videos?
And you're...Bob.
Ha ha ha ha!
I'm on tv?
Uhh! Oh, you guys!
Oh!
The dish needs adjusting.
Ohh!
That'll improve
the reception!
Yeah?
Oh, yeah, roy?
Well,
how's this?
[banging]
You receiving this?
Are you getting this?
Will you stop it?
I am leaving you, roy.
[beeping]
I want a man who'll
touch me rather than
his remote control.
Please hang on
a second.
We have to talk!
It's too late
to talk!
Whoa!
Fasten your seat belts,
folks.
It's going to be
a bumpy ride!
Ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha.
And welcome back to...
You can't win!
Now let's welcome
our new contestants
Roy and helen knable!
Do you know
the rules of our game?
What game?
The game with these
great prizes.
Jay?
Feast your eyes on this--
The all-new nappa-crapper
9000.
You'll never have to
get off your fat butt again.
It has every amenity--
A built-in color tv.
It adjusts to you
so you don't have to move.
No more trips to the kitchen
during commercials.
Better yet, no more annoying
trips to the bathroom.
Your television viewing
never has to be interrupted,
And of course,
win or lose,
Every contestant takes home
a set of encyclopedia satanica!
And now it's time to play...
You can't win.
Back to you, guy.
Roy, the first question's
for you.
On your last
wedding anniversary,
You missed
the romantic dinner
your wife had planned.
The reason,
a--car trouble.
B--you were
running a marathon.
C--you were in a bar
Swilling a beer,
watching...World series.
Car trouble,
just like i said!
No! Can you take it?
You were watching
baseball?
That's right!
Trust me, babe.
You walked into
the right place.
Very cushy down here.
You can cool your heels
in here for the rest
of eternity
If you
kiss the right ass.
These lips
ain't calloused
for nothing!
Ha ha ha ha!
Are you some kind
of comedian?
I once opened
for liberace in vegas.
Great.
This is
the jumbotron.
It's got all the bells
and whistles.
It's our
official scoreboard.
Keeps
track of the sbis.
Souls batted in.
Ha ha ha.
Kind of a sports thing.
[cough]
Time for the
seidenbaums, sir.
Punch 'em up.
Mmm...
The seidenbaums.
Yearning for
exotic locales.
This episode
takes them to tokyo.
They're having
a wonderful time
Starring in
their own movie.
It's the seidenbaums
versus...
The gigantic
stinking-footed lizard!
Aah!
Ooh!
Sayonara, mrs. Seidenbaum.
That's entertainment.
Oh, he's good.
He's so good.
Ha ha ha!
Shocking.
Sir, this is pierce,
our new, uh, intern.
If you can't stomach
the sight of blood--
It's not the blood
i find distressing.
It's your lack
of subtext.
Film school graduate.
Yes, sir.
Usc.
I did my thesis
on kurosawa
and spike lee.
Mr. Pierce,
let me educate you
about our organization.
Here at hellvision,
We've turned the process
of soul acquisition
Into an entertainment
extravaganza,
And all for the benefit
of one very demanding
viewer below.
The boss himself,
And i don't mean
springsteen.
He has an enormous
appetite for misfortune.
It is our job
to supply him with
an eclectic offering
Of light amusements,
not subtext!
Don't go away, knables!
It's time for...
The final question.
What's that mean?
The pit!
Yes, the pit!
And what's down there
today, jay?
Lots of slimy, crawly
bad things, guy.
Eeeuw!
Now you have
10 seconds
To answer the question
correctly, or be...
Eliminated.
Aah!
So the object's
to get to the end--
The object's to kill them
before the end.
Take the knables,
for instance.
They just
checked in.
If they
survive 24 hours,
they go back.
Part of our treaty
with the other side.
Kind of
a geneva convention
In the war
for souls.
Ha ha ha ha!
Name the person
who's recently
been seeing
A former lover.
Is it,
a--roy?
No.
B--helen?
Or c--roy and helen?
I know, i know.
The former lovers
we've been seeing
are each other!
You're...
Right!
Aah!
We'll be back
with the knables'
vacation round
Right after this!
How long do they
usually last?
Whether they go
quickly or not,
In the end,
they always join us.
You're forgetting
that wiry little
peruvian chap.
A mistake, mr. Crowley,
that won't be repeated.
Hey, it wasn't me
that loused up. Jeez.
Are you implying
that if was my fault?
I'm kidding!
You know me.
Always joking.
I think, mr. Crowley,
it's time for
a little...Field work.
Uh...
Spike.
Sir.
Uh...
Why don't i
take you to lunch?
We can sit down.
We can--
Oh, boy.
Hey, spike,
come on.
You know me.
Heh heh heh.
Chronic
foot-in-the-mouth
disease.
I don't want to
do field work.
I'm
executive material.
I belong
here with you.
Aaahhh!
Screw up in here,
and you're dead meat...
Dead meat.
Mr. And mrs. Knable,
It's time to find out
Where you go on
your fantasy vacation.
Door number 1
it is!
What is going on?
You're going on
the trip of a lifetime!
Aah!
[bell dings]
Ladies and gentlemen,
The main event--
Mixed pairs wrestling.
No holds barred.
No transfusions allowed.
A battle to the death!
This has got to be
a dream.
It's a bad dream.
In this corner, roy
"the couch potato" knable
And his wife
helen the harridan!
I gotta wake up.
And the challengers...
The vilest and evilest duo
Ever to disgrace
a wrestling ring...
That ogre and ogress...
The gorgons!
Rraahhhrr!
Oh, my god.
Rraahhr!
Calm down. Stay calm.
Couch potato, come on.
I--i think
he means us.
Excuse me. We're
not suppose to
be here.
Rrraahhhr!
O.K. Everything goes--
Maim, murder each other,
i don't care,
But keep it clean.
When the bell rings,
kill or be killed.
Do we look
like wrestlers?
We have no idea
why we're here.
I'm a senior product
manager for
a vitamin company.
Senior product manager?
I got a promotion.
Why didn't you tell me?
Roy, you know why.
Why?
Because my success
threatens you.
Your success
does not threaten me.
It does, too!
[bell dings]
Uh-oh.
I've watched enough
wrestling to know
It's all fake.
No one
ever gets hurt--
Aaaahhhh!
Rrraahhrr!
Rrraahhhr!
Roy!
Not fake.
It's not fake.
Run for your life,
helen--quickly.
Helen, hold me...
Aah!
Watch, mr. Pierce.
See how it's done.
The exhilarating end
of a tedious life.
Grrr!
Get up. Get up!
Here comes that gorgon girl
to finish the job.
Leave him alone,
you bitch!
Grrr!
I apologize.
You're probably really
not a bitch.
Roy, get up!
The gorgon's
in the seats!
He's history!
Roy!
You know, for
a full-figured woman,
You really wear
that outfit well.
Help! Ow!
Whoa, nellie! Cat fight!
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
This could be the end.
Grrr!
My hair!
Looks like
that pathetic loser
Isn't going to be
as easy as we thought.
Roy.
What happened?
We won.
Or rather, i won.
Knables!
All right,
you won, too.
Damn right.
And your success
does not threaten me.
It does, too.
Totally wicked.
Excellent.
[door opens]
Where's mom and d--
oh, my god.
Dad must have
gotten it
last night.
How did james dean
really die?
Find out tonight
on autopsies of
the rich and famous.
The usual, sir?
Please.
[ride of the valkyries
plays]
Bizarre.
Welcome to
northern overexposure,
The story of a young doctor
from new york
Who comes to alaska,
complains about everything,
And freezes to death.
Hello! Yoo-hoo, mister!
Stay away!
These are my holes!
Back off!
Oh, knable,
it's only you.
How does he know
our name?
Trying to find
a conduit out of here.
Conduit?
Yeah. A window
to the next channel.
If you think i'm spending
the rest of eternity here,
You're crazy!
[wolf howls]
Here it is!
This is it!
[growling]
The shack!
Aah!
Helen! Helen!
Hey, mom and dad
left us a note.
Give me that.
"dear kids,
had to leave
for a while.
"will call tomorrow
to explain.
Love, mom."
Killer!
The house to myself!
They did it.
They went away,
just like billy's
mom and dad did.
And now it's your turn
to go away, dweebnik.
Shelley, it's me.
Guess what?
[beeping]
What are you doing?
Did you see that?
That dish,
it ate my bmx.
Is this some kind
of male puberty thing?
[barking]
Let me get
this straight.
We've been sucked into
some kind of tv world?
Are you saying
that that salesman was--
Mr. Spike--
Mephistopheles
of the cathode ray,
Big brother
to the ungrateful dead.
If we ever cross
channels again--ho ho ho!
Roy, how could you?
I thought
i was buying a tv.
Oh! This is
just great.
This is great.
You wanted to live
in a tv fantasy?
You got your wish.
At least we're not dead.
Not yet.
Stay alive
another 15 hours--
Bingo. Free pass
back to reality.
The odds
of making it are--
[crack]
Oh, my.
The cold's no place
for a stiff.
Oh, my god.
Don't panic.
I got us into this,
i'll get us out.
Your leadership skills
couldn't get us out
of a t-shirt!
[doorbell chimes]
I'll get it!
Hi!
Hi. Come in.
I don't believe in
out-of-body experiences.
That's because you hold
your emotions back.
Do not.
What do you think
of this color?
That's all right.
I don't think
it really goes
in here.
Clashes
with the bars.
You can't really say
you're an expressive person.
What do you think
of this color here?
Clashes
with the bars.
See? I told you.
Coming this fall...
¶ row, row,
row your boat ¶
¶ gently down the stream ¶
¶ merrily,
merrily, merrily... ¶
These kids are
driving me crazy!
Wish there was some way
to shut them up!
[announcer]
for those long, tedious
car trips, you need...
The silencer of the lambs.
Driving will never
be the same.
Silencer of the pets
sold separately.
It's...
My bike.
That's my bike.
You saw a bike
like yours on tv.
So what?
Not a bike
like my bike.
My bike! Come on.
Stop it!
Leave me alone.
Look, there's
something else.
I found this
on the ground
near the dish.
Mom's watch.
It stopped at 10:30.
This is going to sound
totally crazy,
But i don't think
Mom and dad went
to the mountains
for the weekend.
Come on, diane!
Look, i'm sure it's nothing
to worry about, o.K.?
Now leave us alone!
Diane, whatever you do,
Don't go
in the back yard, o.K.?
in the back yard!
If you'll excuse me,
I'm off
to warmer megahertz.
Going to find a channel
with sun,
Funny drinks with
those little umbrellas,
And maybe a dog track.
All clear.
[grrr]
Hey! Aah!
I'm already dead!
Save her!
We got to get
to that conduit!
Roy, it's getting worse!
Wait, wait, wait.
I got an idea.
Push! Come on, now.
There it is.
There it is!
Come on.
[grrr]
Jump.
Jump?
Wherever it leads can't
be any worse than this.
Yeow!
Umph!
Couldn't be any worse,
huh, roy?
Helen?
Oh, my god!
We're cartoons.
Boy, this is strange.
Strange? I'm
an animated rodent
Wearing high-heeled
running shoes.
The word "strange"
is somehow lacking.
At least we're safe here.
No one ever dies
in cartoons, right?
Ralph, i left
some food out.
I hope it doesn't
attract any mice.
Don't worry.
That new device
is guaranteed.
No rodent stands
a chance in there.
Stay tuned.
How can you even think
of eating doughnuts
At a time like this?
Should i look
for some oat bran?
I'm starved.
If you don't come down,
i'm leaving.
Where you going to go,
your cartoon mother's house?
I am warning you, roy.
Roy?
Wow! These things are
as big as buicks.
I'm gone.
That's it.
I said we're through,
and we are through.
I can do better
on my own.
I am not a mouse.
I'm helen knable.
I have an mba.
I live at 1532
blue jay court.
I have two
beautiful children--
Who i may never
see again.
Mom?
Roy?
Warning--you are trespassing
in a human habitation.
The penalty is death.
My doctor was right.
Doughnuts will be
the death of me.
[whistle blows]
Aah!
Would you let go
of me?
You have to see this.
There.
This will work.
It worked on macgyver.
What are you
talking about?
Can't you see?
It's mom and dad
in the cartoon.
Very funny, pus-head.
Diane, you've got to
believe me.
Kids, don't try
this at home.
I think we lost them.
What?
For a mouse,
you, um, look pretty sexy.
Too bad you didn't like
the way i looked
When i was human.
I always did.
News to me.
I'm sorry.
Surrender.
Come out with...
Look!
Roy, turn! Turn!
Helen, wait!
This is one clever
pussy.
I've watched
enough cartoons.
How would
an animated character
Handle this?
This will put a permanent
crease in his shorts.
[doorbell chimes]
Identify yourself.
Catnip-gram.
[barking]
[meow]
I'll never get out
of here.
Deeb-a-deeb-a-deeb--
that's all, folks.
I've lost the feeling
in my arm.
All of a sudden,
i can't see anything.
Uhh!
Oh!
Sundays at 8:00...
It's...
Where did he go?
Duane's underworld.
It's partytime! Excellent!
[guitar riff]
Welcome
to duane's underworld,
o father of lies.
I'm your
excrement host duane,
And with me as always
is my slightly decaying
cohost garf.
Wifto! Wifto!
Party eternally, garf.
Party eternally,
duane.
All right.
Today we have
a special guest,
A man who can't even
sell plumping supplies.
Shhyeah! Like no one
uses a toilet.
Mr. Roy knable.
Salutations,
o mighty failure.
Mr. Knable,
before we get started,
Tell me what you see
on this card.
I...War ship...Satin?
Excrement.
Now, i understand
You're searching for
your lovely wife helen...
Who i truly believe
you will find,
Because good always
conquers over evil...
Not!
In order to assist you
in your efforts,
We have located
a photograph of your wife
To show our viewers.
Where did that
come from?
She's a vixen,
mr. K.
Beezle-babe! Tent pole!
Lady knable,
we salute you.
Schwing!
And your daughter's
pompoms,
They're delectable,
too, man.
You creeps!
Uh-oh. Extreme close-up
on mr. Knable.
Oh!
Excellent.
One more time!
Man,
i'm getting dizzy.
I could hurl.
No. Chew it back, man.
Now the red-hot-poker-
in-the-eye cam.
Bogus.
I'm black and white.
Hello. Testing, testing.
"roy knable,
private dick."
Well, better than being
a public dick.
O.K., i'm in some old movie.
Must be on cable.
I've been watching
these things my whole life.
I should know
what to do.
Be like bogart,
like in the maltese falcon.
I'm on a case.
I got to find helen.
Got to find the clues.
Got to find out
how to use this thing.
[intercom buzzes]
Mr. Knable,
you've dropped
your gun again.
I know!
[knock on door]
Roy, is that you?
Sir...Great news.
Your new class
of recruits--
We've taken possession
of all of them,
Except two, sir.
Oh! I know that,
you postulating putz!
They've just been lucky,
that's all.
Have they?
You know, the strain
of your job
Must be tremendous.
Ever considered
taking a vacation,
Letting someone else
take the burden
off your shoulders?
Someone else?
You?
I'm flattered
you'd even think
I could fill
your shoes.
But i'm ready
to try, sir.
[announcer]
and now...Get in shape
with the exorcisist.
Come on, people,
let's get in shape.
Come on.
Make it burn.
Feel it burn.
[explosion]
Good, doreen.
O.K., everybody,
head spins.
With me.
Ready, go.
Very good.
Very nice.
I like it.
O.K., that's good.
Cool down.
Shake it out.
O.K., now vomit.
[announcer]
kids, now there's
a new beer just for you.
It's got no alcohol,
But it'll make you
act just like dad.
[burp] give me
another one,
babe.
That's my boy.
Yogi beer. You'll be
just like your dad.
[channel changer beeps]
Dad?
[voices]
Get away
from the dish.
Darryl, what
is with you?
Get lost.
[beep]
5, 6, 7, 8.
Aah!
Darryl,
what are you doing?
Darryl!
Oh, my god!
Guys, wait!
It's not my fault
my brother's a creep!
[door slams]
Darryl!
You're pizza topping!
Wait. Mom and dad
are here.
They're home?
Well, not exactly.
Look.
See? That's dad.
That is not dad.
Mom?
That looks like mom.
It is mom.
That's what i've been
trying to tell you.
Our parents are trapped
in television.
Oh, wow.
"classy dame vanishes.
Last seen
at club seidenbaum."
Helen.
Seidenbaum.
That name is
famil--
Oh, my god.
Murray seidenbaum.
He lives
right near me.
He borrowed
my lawn mower.
[beep beep beep]
Obviously,
we're dealing
with something
Of a supernatural
nature here, diane.
I mean, this thing,
it did not come
from radio shack.
Yeah, so you're
the smart one.
Think of something.
O.K., um...
What goes in a dish
and winds up on tv?
My bike...
Our parents...
Follow me.
Hey, not my stereo.
I need the parts.
Go downstairs
and watch them.
Keep track of them.
Ho ho.
Nice work, boys.
Glad you could
join me, mrs. Knable.
Didn't have
much choice.
Lobster?
Drink.
Where's my husband?
Why worry about him?
I ditched my wife
five channels ago.
She happened to meet
the business end
of a 50-ton reptile.
And i can tell you,
I don't exactly miss
dried meat loaf.
This is great here.
Great.
I don't ever want
to get out.
Outside, i was
murray the doormat.
In here...
Boss seidenbaum.
Brought my remote
in with me.
Gets too hot--bam,
i'm on another channel.
Wait a minute.
Aah!
Oh!
You're not coming
in here!
Euh! Euh!
Ahhh!
Well, look
who showed up.
Where's my--
Hello, roy.
Helen,
you're all right.
You--
you look terrific!
Oh, really?
Hey, seidenbaum!
I'm taking over
your business!
Aah!
Seidenbaum.
Knables.
All i wanted was to be
the big shot for once.
Take my remote.
Get out of here.
You two
still got a chance
of making it together.
There it is!
No, no, stay down.
This is my job.
Piece of cake.
O.K., ready?
[channel changer
beeps]
[neigh]
Oh, my god.
I lost them.
The next item we have
for you on the...
Dad, where are you?
And now the all-new miniseries
about the french revolution...
The story of
the marquis de knable,
An enemy of the people,
Who wears a disguise
to escape the guillotine.
It's an epic drama of love,
danger, and cross-dressing.
Roy.
You have boobs.
Oh, they're not mine.
[shouting in french]
Psst! Hey, knables.
Nice disguise.
Crowley?
Interesting concept,
diagonal boobs.
Could you fix
that thing?
Thought the wolves
got you.
Tell you something
about wolves--
Vicious?
Goes without saying.
But not that bright.
While those dumb bunnies
were fighting
over my appendages,
I managed to escape.
Liberte, citizen.
Vive la france!
Power
to the people!
Ha ha ha ha!
Come on.
Personally,
i think
he's losing it.
What a pathetic
thing to watch.
Only 2 hours left,
and your 24 hours
are up.
All you
got to do
is lie low.
[speaking french]
Les cops.
Inside.
I'll find a conduit
out of here.
Bonjour. Nice day
for an execution,
non?
[the marseillaise plays]
Stay tuned for
the final chapter of
off with his head,
When the marquis de knable
finally loses his.
Uh-oh.
Darryl!
We got to jam.
[beep beep]
Merci.
Well, we've always
wanted to go to paris.
In the 20th century.
Since we're here,
we might as well make
the best of it.
Make the best of it?
This is the french
revolution.
People are trying
to kill you.
If we get out of this,
things will be different.
I won't just be
a watcher.
I'll be the man i was
when we first met.
You weren't blond then,
and you wore
a lot less make-up.
[darryl]
aim it at the center
of the dish!
You are both
under arrest!
For what?
For being
too beautiful
And without
proper escort.
Ha ha ha!
Garcon,
more wine!
[beep beep]
O.K. Tv's connected
to the dish.
Now we go
for contact.
There's no interference.
Nothing's getting through.
We need more power.
I'm going to cop
some juice.
Be careful.
This woman is not
who you think.
She is wanted.
Of course she's wanted,
you fool!
By me!
My cherie...
You inflame me.
I never kiss
on the first date.
Oh?
Ooh!
Naughty boy.
This has been a kick,
fellas, but we've got to go.
No, no!
Come back here,
sweetheart!
Keep your hands
off her!
Your hair's so beautiful.
May i have a lock of it?
I--
Oh!
Why don't you keep
the whole thing?
I tried
to tell you!
It's the marquis
de knable!
Enemy of the people!
I knew that!
Marquis de knable...
The guillotine awaits!
I would have
given you chocolates.
[beep beep]
Kill the marquis!
I'm telling you,
i'm not a marquis!
I sell plumbing supplies
in seattle...
Washington!
[grrr]
Roy!
Roy! Roy!
I love you.
You guys are making
a big mistake.
I'm not even a member
of this country!
Darryl, you'd
better hurry up!
[grrr]
Kill the marquis!
Hi, fellas,
i loved you
in star wars.
Can we just talk
for a second?
Oh, my god. Holy--
Oh! Could we--
[grrr]
[woof]
[shouting]
Any last requests?
Yeah. How about
the long version of
stairway to heaven?
I'm afraid that
is not where
you are going.
Darryl!
[grrr]
[woof]
Here, catch!
Wait! An innocent man's
blood is being spilled!
Good point.
Better back away.
This one, he could
be a gusher.
By order of the court...
Looks like spike's
going to make his quota
after all.
I deliver the marquis
de knable's soul
To its rightful owner!
Finally, he's mine.
How come he dresses
like a woman?
I do that sometimes.
Kill the marquis!
Dad, can you hear me?
Darryl? My god!
God?
Yes!
It's...
God!
Right, god?
Tell the infidels
to release him.
What's an infidel?
I don't know.
Tell them
to release him!
Tell them!
Um...Um...Release
the marquis.
You heard him.
Get me out of this.
What's happening?
[beep beep]
Who's messing
with my programming?
[beep beep beep]
You--the weenie
in black--
You, dork--
At the wheel--
Yeah, you!
Release him!
I am the voice of--
Ohhh...
Oh, roy!
We beat spike!
We did it!
I would have given
an arm and a leg
to see this!
In fact,
i already did!
Ha ha ha!
No, it's...
Not possible.
[beep beep beep]
[alarm warbling]
Sir. Speaking
for the staff...
We'll all miss
your kind words
and inspiring leadership.
Ducker, contracts--
What?
There was a protest
Filed on the knable case.
A verbal contract binds
only those parties personally
making the agreement.
Therefore,
the contract can
only be for one person.
You took two.
Yes.
Yes! Yes! Oh!
Mmm!
Oh, you're
the ugliest bitch
in perdition,
But you gave me
a beautiful idea.
Discharge
mr. Knable.
But, sir...
The contract
was for him only.
Masterful stroke, sir.
I don't get it.
They should've zapped
you two home by now.
You heard me...
Discharge mr. Knable.
Roy?
Roy!
Oh!
[darryl]
dad!
[diane]
Where's your mother?
My obligation is
limited to those
i have a contract with.
I fulfilled my end
by discharging mr. Knable.
His wife is still--
Those who trespass
into the system
are on their own.
We'll sort out
the bodies later
After i kill them both.
How can we be sure
he'll come back?
Because he loves her.
He's a puss.
Oh, and i'll be back,
In case anyone's
feeling ambitious.
Well, time
to rock 'n' roll.
Oh!
Crowley.
Quite a radical
weight-loss plan
you've been on.
Yes. Ha ha ha.
Ha ha ha.
But, uh...Feeling
a lot, uh, better.
Ha ha ha!
Aah!
Hello, mrs. Knable.
Mr. Spike,
at your service.
Where's my husband?
I'll take you to him.
Rahrr.
Oh!
Howdy, ma'am.
Reckon the 3:10 to yuma
will be along any minute.
Funny thing, though...
It don't exactly stop here.
You're going to hit me
with a train?
What can i say?
I'm a sucker
for a big ending.
You sadistic bastard.
Runs in the family.
My father was
an oil company
president.
Well...Have
a good day,
mrs. Knable.
[beep]
This just in...
Helen knable
has been kidnapped
And taken to channel 1.
We take you there live.
Roy, wherever you are,
get your butt back here!
Unfortunately,
her gutless failure
of a husband
Won't lift a finger
to save her.
Right, roy?
No.
Dynamite. He's going
to hit me with a train
and blow me up?
Roy!
I want you both
to stay inside.
Make sure
those doughnuts
are ready.
I'll be
very hungry
when i get back.
O.K.?
[darryl]
careful, dad.
[theme from the good,
the bad, and the ugly plays]
[cough]
[cough cough]
Help!
Helen?
Roy!
Back to play
the hero, huh?
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Not exactly
typecasting.
Be about 6...6'1".
Yeah.
Make your move,
tinhorn.
Today, roy!
No!
Dad!
[beep beep]
You missed me,
partner.
Captain,
the ship
has found itself
In an orbit
around hell.
The underworld
is hailing us.
I know you.
Greetings,
captain roy.
Our remotes
are synchronized,
So wherever
you go, i go.
Enjoy the attack.
[alarm warbling]
Lieutenant?
Captain?
G-g...Get us
out of here!
No!
Phasers on, uh...
Torture.
Holy shatner!
And just to show you
how effective
Our passenger
restraint system really is,
Watch this demonstration
at 110 miles an hour,
Where our driver dummy
has the benefit
Of seat belt
and air bag,
The other dummy
having neither one.
Neither one?
I can't watch.
Switch to mom.
Switch to mom!
[train whistle blows]
Dad'll save her.
[beep beep]
Aah!
Ooh. Rrr!
No! No, wait!
Aaaaaahhhhh!
Hey, lady, watch out!
Ooh.
Whoop.
Aah!
Yaaahhhh!
Whoa!
Unh! Ahh!
¶ come and knock
on our door ¶
Where have you been?
¶ we've been waitin'
for you... ¶
Aaaaaahhhh!
[cough cough]
My, my.
Now you'll never
get back to kansas.
En garde.
Oh, no sword.
Have to talk
to that prop man.
Right about now,
your wife is probably
Catching that train...
Right between the eyes.
And you let it happen.
Here it comes, dad!
I've taken
loads of souls...
And none more pathetic
Than yours, roy.
Say good night, gracie.
Not yet.
You see, i was captain
of my junior college
fencing team.
All right. Co-captain.
I gave you escape
from your pitiful life.
I want it back.
All sales are final.
Not this one.
¶ you got to start me ¶
¶ up ¶
¶ start me up ¶
¶ you got to start me up ¶
¶ come down ¶
¶ the "s" to the a-l-t ¶
¶ the love
to the b-u-g ¶
¶ come down ¶
¶ the spin
to the d-a-rella ¶
¶ come down ¶
¶ s-t-double e-v-e
in the "p" ¶
¶ come down ¶
The "p" to the e-p-a ¶
¶ the idolmaker's
in the house, how ya know? ¶
¶ come down ¶
¶ to the record lord ¶
¶ wait a minute,
wait a minute, y'all ¶
¶ let's get serious
for a minute ¶
¶ y'all havin' fun? ¶
¶ i'm havin' fun,
everybody havin' fun ¶
¶ but you know
those times ¶
¶ when you
get stressed out ¶
¶ and you wanna
give up? ¶
¶ everybody has a time
in their life ¶
¶ when things doesn't
always go right ¶
¶ it just gets harder
every day ¶
¶ and it makes you
wanna run away ¶
¶ then i wonder
when it will end ¶
¶ can i ever
be myself again? ¶
¶ yo, i got hopes,
and i got trust ¶
¶ and i got you here
to start me up ¶
¶ i'm fed up, fed up ¶
¶ word up, dead up ¶
¶ gotta keep my head up ¶
¶ don't stop or let up ¶
¶ you're sleepin',
laid up ¶
¶ time to get
your bed made up ¶
¶ always gonna lose it ¶
¶ till your dues
get paid up ¶
¶ straight up, wait up ¶
¶ i'm not gamin'
or bluffin' ¶
¶ watch television
all day doin' nothing ¶
¶ poisoning your liver ¶
¶ looks like
you're ready to deliver ¶
¶ yo, salt, i think
he gets the scissors ¶
¶ start me up ¶
¶ you got to start me up ¶
¶ start me up-- ¶
¶ start me up ¶
¶ you got to start me up ¶
¶ on the dial,
the people gonna fall off ¶
¶ the eeby deeby jam
coming at me, big mama ¶
¶ stoppin' at the period ¶
¶ and pause
upon the comma ¶
¶ the bis boom bit did
a drama for your fodda ¶
¶ tell me, rough ¶
¶ coach man workin'
i'm stuck ¶
¶ de-man-a man-a
lek-o lek-o ¶
¶ fix the collar
on a world, rah ¶
¶ the microchips
never fail me ¶
¶ start me up ¶
¶ you got to start me up ¶
¶ you got to start me ¶
¶ up ¶
¶ well, uh, well, uh ¶
¶ we-heh-heh-hell uh ¶
¶ you're caught
in the rain ¶
¶ but you forgot
your umbrella ¶
¶ what could you do ¶
¶ punch-a-nella,
punch-a-nella? ¶
¶ you're trapped
in a cage like an ape
called magilla ¶
¶ and now you're ready
to throw in the towel ¶
¶ that's kinda foul ¶
¶ you don't give a hoot ¶
¶ like a mute owl ¶
¶ that's not the way
i know you to be ¶
¶ you used to be
true to me ¶
¶ oo-ee, what you
used to do to me ¶
¶ start me up ¶
¶ you got to start me up ¶
¶ start me up... ¶
Wait.
O.K. You got
the remote. You win.
But how about--
just pitching here--
You and me
working together?
We could come up with
dynamite programming.
Chairman'd love it.
Knock him
off his hooves.
We'd be number one.
Of course, we are
the only one, but--
You don't get it,
do you?
Without me, you
don't get out of here.
Sorry, spike.
You're cancelled.
¶ you got to start me up ¶
¶ start me up ¶
¶ you got to start me ¶
¶ up ¶
Roy!
Deactivate
escape frequencies.
What are you doing?
I've trapped them.
It's not working!
Turn it off.
What do you do
when you want the tv
to go away?
You turn it
Off!
We've lost them.
Helen...
We're home!
Kids!
Oh!             Dad!
Oh! Oh!
[dog growls]
Whoever left
the gate open
is grounded for a week.
[woof]
Check that.
Whoever left
the gate open
gets double their allowance.
Look at that.
Wetzel!
Don't get me angry,
you worm!
Get me out of here!
Put a lid on it, fido.
O.K., pierce,
what do you want?
Corner office?
Name on the door?
Hello, spike.
Heh heh.
Crowley.
You know,
you're a gentleman
and a scholar...
A fine
corporate asset...
A man who i, personally,
like very much.
Oh, incidentally, spike,
nice of you to drop in.
Ha ha ha ha...
Ah...That's funny.
Ah!
Aah!
[woof woof]
I get his parking space.
So what can i tell you?
My parents
got back together.
The only tv my dad
watches is 60 minutes,
And he started
a new job.
I guess you could call us
a pretty normal family.
That's if anything
is ever normal.
Who on earth
taught you that?
Uh, i saw it
on tv somewhere.
Some old movie.
Take my advice, kiddo.
Don't watch too much tv.
It can get you
into trouble.
O.K., fencers.
Class dismissed.
¶ me and that dude
is talkin' ¶
¶ baby, i just love
your body ¶
¶ can't believe the feeling
when you walk your walk ¶
¶ baby, we don't need
no party ¶
¶ you can taste it
if you don't like to talk ¶
¶ i used to have a woman
who was so shy ¶
¶ never spoke about
what she desired ¶
¶ now the door is open,
it's open wide ¶
¶ take a little peek
and find what's inside ¶
¶ baby, i just
love your body ¶
¶ can't believe the feeling
when you walk your walk ¶
¶ hey there, we don't
need no party ¶
¶ you can taste it,
if you want ¶
¶ baby, i just
love your body ¶
¶ can't believe the feeling
when you walk your walk ¶
¶ baby, we don't
need no party ¶
¶ you can taste it
if you don't like to talk ¶
¶ used to have a woman
who was so shy ¶
¶ never spoke about
what she desired ¶
¶ now the door is open,
it's open wide ¶
¶ take a little peek
and find what's inside ¶
¶ baby, i just
love your body ¶
¶ can't believe the feeling
when you walk your walk ¶
¶ baby, we don't
need no party ¶
¶ you can taste that,
if you want ¶
Captioning made possible by
warner bros. Inc.
Captioning performed by
the national captioning
institute, inc.
Captions copyright 1992
morgan creek productions, inc.
Public performance of captions
prohibited without permission of
national captioning institute
¶ do you want it? ¶
¶ do you--do
you want it? ¶
¶ do you want it? ¶
¶ moon's out tonight ¶
¶ the doctor's
takin' a walk ¶
¶ awoo ¶
¶ the mic stalker ¶
¶ some dame did me wrong,
and i admit it ¶
¶ my temper was a fuse,
and you just lit it ¶
¶ and made me right
that on a saturday night ¶
¶ that i bit it,
the price is death ¶
¶ this is a row,
the fight for right ¶
¶ don't get hyped
this is my knife strike ¶
¶ no nob, no gun ¶
¶ took my vocals
through the mic ¶
¶ it's cold so i pack it
in my jacket at night ¶
¶ hey, i live by my mic
and die by my mic ¶
¶ no, i live to exist ¶
¶ and i never bid
on the great ride to hitch ¶
¶ and while you're dying ¶
¶ your son is cryin',
beggin' and yellin' ¶
¶ will i give you
pity? Hah! ¶
¶ never would i with all
the trouble i'm in ¶
¶ until the devil eat heart out
cause i'm hotter than him ¶
¶ the other day kid was rockin'
on the corner alone ¶
¶ and i was stroking
my microphone ¶
¶ i heard him reciting
somebody's record
that was sold ¶
¶ though he was five years old
i had to adjust some more ¶
¶ teach him a lesson
no matter what the age ¶
¶ i'm on a rampage
on and off the stage ¶
¶ you wanna copy
of my record? ¶
¶ this is what you do ¶
¶ go to the precinct,
and they'll give you a few ¶
¶ the mic stalker,
stalker, stalker ¶
¶ i got a natural gift,
i don't sniff ¶
¶ for a little lift, boy,
my mother woulda whipped ¶
¶ i got accused
when my mother gave me,
never gave me dope ¶
¶ to coke, she say,
just say no ¶
¶ it's criminal
or premature ¶
¶ it's premeditated
literature ¶
¶ the mic stalker,
stalker, stalker ¶