Sun Sin.
Mom.
Have you eaten dinner?
Mom, I'm sorry.
Why are you sorry?
Mom, I didn't change.
I am still... still Lee Sun Sin.
I'm your youngest daughter,
Hye Sin eonni's and Yu Sin eonni's sister,
Granny's youngest grandchild,
U Ju's aunt, right?
It will stay forever like this.
Right?
So, treat me the same way.
Treat me exactly like
you treated me before.
If you don't do that,
I'll get really mad.
Let's go, Nunim.
Let's go.
Nunim, the press conference concluded successfully.
Since it ended well,
how about keeping your distance from her?
Aren't you scared?
With what happened to her father and all.
If you keep seeing her,
you'll always be on your toes.
Once the reporters have settled down,
let's carry on like before.
This...
- Zero
- Zero.
Here.
Zero.
Your mother isn't back yet?
Yes, I hope the reporters outside have left.
Mom cannot meet them.
You haven't heard from Sun Sin yet?
Yes.
I don't even know if she has money.
She just left like that.
She probably went to see her real mom.
What?
She has a wealthy mother.
What's there to worry about?
She'll just give her money
if she doesn't have it.
Yu Sin.
Are you going to keep bitching like that?
Sun Sin is this family's flesh and blood.
Your sister.
What the heck are you saying?
She's our flesh and blood?
How could you say that?
You like her now that
she's dad's daughter.
When you used to bully her before.
What did she say?
Why are you saying that?
Are you really fine with it?
Can you treat her like before?
What can we do?
It's not Sun Sin's fault.
I know.
I know, but...
Whenever I see her, I can't help but
recall how Dad has betrayed our family.
I feel uncomfortable.
U Ju, do your homework upstairs.
Aunt.
Sun Sin.
Where have you been?
Do you know how worried I was?
A girl can't spend the night outside.
It will be a big problem
if this becomes a habit.
I'm sorry, Granny.
Wash your hands.
I'll prepare the food.
You haven't even eaten dinner yet?
Here, I made the soup you like.
You must be hungry.
There's plenty of delicious food.
Mom made a lot of side-dishes
while waiting for you.
You'll choke.
Eat slowly.
Did you meet any reporters outside
when you came home?
No, I think they left.
What's the use?
They'll come back tomorrow.
Yu Sin.
Did I say anything?
I'm going up.
Oh, my. Look at her.
She's probably stressed out
because of the reporters.
Just understand her.
Eonni.
Did you guys know about this?
That I'm not Mom's daughter.
You're Dad's daughter anyway, aren't you?
I feel very uncomfortable with you.
I'm also disappointed with our late father.
I'm also disappointed with
how foolish mom is.
It must be difficult for you but...
it's also difficult for me.
I hope you understand.
You're not sleeping yet?
It's been a while since I slept beside you.
Shall we do that now?
That...
Jun Ho.
Mi Ryeong's daughter...
What does her father do?
I don't know, either.
Tell me.
I'm dying to know.
I tried to get some info from Mi Ryeong
but she just snobbed me.
It will come out anyway,
why must she still keep that a secret?
Seriously, you...
You asked her that?
Why can't I ask?
We're close friends,
so she should tell me.
I don't know why she won't tell me.
What is he like?
Is he married?
I don't know, either.
You obviously know.
That's enough.
What did I do?
Oppa. Is Teacher Song's daughter
an aspiring actress?
Who said that?
Aspiring actress, Miss A.
Do you know her too?
Really?
It runs in the blood.
Oh my, oh my, oh my.
This is amazing.
Let me see that.
Isn't that your agency's press release?
You don't know?
I have to go.
Hey! How about breakfast?
Nevermind.
You don't need to do that.
No, let me.
Go and wake Yu Sin up.
Tell her breakfast's ready.
I'm not eating breakfast.
I'm late.
What should we do with her?
You go and talk to Yu Sin.
Yes.
How annoying!
The reporters are back again.
Really?
Do you think we should move house?
Why should we hide?
We didn't do anything wrong.
It will be fine after a couple of days.
You kept saying that every morning.
How long will this continue?
This is really embarrassing.
Stop it, Yu Sin.
I'll go and have a look.
- Sun Sin.
- Hey, wait.
Sun Sin, don't go out.
It will make things worse.
It's okay, Eonni.
Well... Perhaps...
Go home!
I have nothing to do with Song Mi Ryeong.
Will you still continue your
debut as an actress?
I heard you were once a trainee in
Song Mi Ryeong's agency, is that true?
When did you start dreaming
of becoming an actress?
I heard you studied acting under Song Mi Ryeong,
is that true?
Please say something.
Stop it!
Put those cameras down.
Put them down, I said.
I am Gabi Entertainment's CEO, Sin Jun Ho.
From now on, all interviews must
have our company's consent.
We will issue a statement soon.
If one of those photos you
took gets publicized,
I will sue you for invasion of privacy.
Got it? Get out of here.
Get out of here!
Hello.
How could you foolishly head out like that?
How did they find out about me?
How did they find out I was a trainee?
Did you tell them?
No, I didn't.
Stop lying.
You should also know about
that press conference too.
That...
Go and tell Teacher Song to leave me alone.
Stop hurting me already!
Sun Sin, why did you blow up like that?
He's really worried about you.
He called you many times yesterday.
He even came today.
Did you tell them?
What?
Everything about Sun Sin.
Was the press conference not enough?
What's going to happen to her in the future?
How could you act so irresponsibly?
Have you ever considered her feelings?
President, please don't blame her.
I did that.
What?
Everyone will find out anyway.
And also...
Don't underestimate the reporters.
You might not know since
you've never been a reporter.
If they smell something, they'll keep
digging until things get worse
and make things more difficult.
Does that even make sense?
That's enough. It already happened.
What's the use of arguing about it?
Teacher, please...
think about Sun Sin.
Don't use Sun Sin to shield you
from your current predicament.
What?
What did you just say to me?
I used Sun Sin?
Didn't you use her?
All interviews from now on must
go through the agency.
You must seek the agency's approval
if you want to meet her.
Don't tackle this amongst yourselves.
President Sin, this is between me and my daughter.
This wouldn't happen at all
if you treated her like a daughter.
What did you say?
Are you lecturing me?
Who are you working for?
Me or Sun Sin?
I'm doing this for myself.
I'll remind you once again.
You've crossed the line this time.
Hello.
You haven't left yet?
Yes. Just in case you encounter some difficulties.
We'll be fine today.
Don't worry. You saw what I did, right?
I chased them away yesterday.
I can't say about other things,
but my charisma... "What!",
I have confidence in my charisma.
And my expression...
This expression of mine is very perky.
No, there's no need to do that today.
Don't worry about it.
We're just helping each other.
Let's head out first.
Come on, U Ju.
Let's go.
No one's here.
Perhaps what I did yesterday
was very effective.
I scared the reporters away
so they're afraid to come back.
Right?
My aunt's boss came by and
chased them away.
Idiot.
U Ju...
U Ju, wait for me.
Hey, U Ju!
No word from Song Mi Ryeong yet?
Yes.
She created such a huge mess.
Shouldn't she come and find you?
She should come and beg for forgiveness.
It's all over the news.
Even attracting a lot of reporters here.
But how could she pretend
like nothing happened?
She should compensate you, at least.
Compensate?
Yes, compensate.
I heard she's filthy rich.
A successful actress like that,
don't tell me she doesn't even have assets?
Hey! Since things have already become like this,
might as well ask for some compensation.
If she has any conscience,
she has to do something for you, at least.
Furthermore, how long did you raise her daughter?
How much should she pay you for that?
How could you say such a thing?
'Her daughter'?
Why is Sun Sin her daughter?
What I mean is...
Anyway, things are already like this,
better meet and settle this.
After raising her daughter up,
you even got hurt.
What are you saying?
Did I raise Sun Sin for that woman's sake?
How frustrating.
That's not what I meant.
Try and bring this up again.
Hang on.
My son. What's the matter? I got it.
I'll go and find it right away.
Jeong Ae, Chan U left an
important document at home.
Can you look after the shop for me?
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Don't misunderstand.
I'm here for my treatment.
I won't say anything.
Please don't worry.
Let's go in.
I'm sorry but I'm done for the day.
This early?
Yes, I have an afternoon surgery.
Then...
Hello.
Is this your first time here?
I'm here to see Dr. Pak Chan U.
Do you have an appointment?
No. He's my son.
What? Oh, my.
So, you're Dr. Pak Chan U's mother.
Yes.
Chan U left this important document at home.
I'm here to give this to him.
Is that so? Come with me.
I'll take you to Dr. Pak.
Thank you.
This way, please.
Hello, Mother.
Mother?
It's nice to meet you.
I am Sin I Jeong.
Who... ?
I like Dr. Pak Chan U very much.
No, I'm a patient who
respects him very much.
What?
She's the Chairman's daughter.
She's a patient of Dr. Pak.
Is that so?
Mother, you're really beautiful.
What?
Not really.
I was wondering why Dr. Pak
is so handsome.
He took after you.
What are you saying?
You really, really leave a good impression.
Thank you.
Yes?
Chan U!
Mom, why are you here?
Here. You should have called a courier.
That's expensive.
It's faster this way.
Still...
You should have told me you were coming.
I want to check out the hospital
where my son works.
By the way, Chan U...
What's your relationship with
the Chairman's daughter?
What?
I just met her.
She's so pretty.
Is she your girlfriend?
I think she likes you a lot.
What girlfriend?
No, she's not.
I can sense these things.
How can I not know?
It's really nothing.
There's really nothing going on?
Fine. I'll just take your word for it.
This room is really huge.
I like it.
My son is amazing.
What happened?
Did you meet Song Mi Ryeong?
Come on.
I'm dying to know, I can't do anything else.
Did you meet?
We did.
Really? What did you talk about?
Hey. What will happen to you from now on?
What can happen?
Nothing will change.
How is that possible? Is this common?
You're an absolute Cinderella.
Cinderella?
Yes.
The codis are all wondering who
her daughter is.
Everyone's so envious.
To be honest, isn't this like hitting the lottery?
What did you say?
You know...
Think carefully about it.
Your life will totally change for the better.
It's just a matter of time.
Your mother will support you all the way.
You can continue to act.
Pak Chan Mi!
Stop it.
What?
How could you say that?
How could she be my mother?
Why is she my mother?
Don't talk to me about Song Mi Ryeong again.
Nothing will change.
Try and say it one more time...
Who's that?
=The number you have dialed is unavailable...=
Mom!
Oh, you're here.
Where are you going?
I bought some iced desserts--
Think carefully about it.
Your life will totally change for the better.
It's just a matter of time.
To be honest, isn't this like hitting the lottery?
Sun Sin.
Let's talk for a moment.
I have nothing to say.
I've already said everything
at the hospital.
Just for a moment.
Let me go!
Sun Sin.
I thought I told you not
to appear before me again.
Stop being too emotional.
Let's have a serious chat.
There's a lot of things to clear up
between us.
I'm really sorry about the reporters.
I really didn't know.
I'm so sorry about that.
Anyway... Anyway, can we move to a quiet place?
Listen to what I have to say.
No, thanks.
I don't want to hear anything.
After you said what you wanted,
you're not even going to listen to me?
Aren't you even curious about me?
How you and I separated...
What your father is like,
don't you want to know?
Yes, I don't want to hear them.
I'm not curious about them.
They're not important to me.
Why isn't that important?
Don't suddenly appear before me
and act like a mother.
I only have one mother.
Sun Sin.
Let me say it again.
I don't want to see you.
So, please don't disturb me anymore.
I beg you!
Please.
Please go.
Boss, have you heard?
What?
Anything can happen in this world.
What do you mean?
Sun Sin is...
She's Song Mi Ryeong's daughter.
Then my father is Obama.
Isn't it funny, Boss?
Who said that?
I overheard the trainees
talking about it over there.
It's hilarious, right?
It's the best joke I've heard these days.
Take care of this.
Yes.
Boss.
Have you been well, Sun Sin?
Yes.
Have you been well?
Can you come by for a moment?
There are still some things to settle.
What?
Mom!
You are still here?
Where have you been?
Is something wrong?
Nothing.
Did you meet Sun Sin?
She didn't want to listen to me.
I just wanted to explain my side.
But she brushed me off.
How could she do that?
Calm down, Mom.
Come and have dinner with me.
Let's take a walk too.
You'll feel better afterwards.
Nevermind.
Carry on with your work.
Don't be like this, Mom.
I can't.  I'm tired.
I need to rest.
Here.
You said I need to settle some things.
What's this?
This is the settlement.
Eat what you need to eat,
fix what needs to be fixed,
then leave.
How is it staying at home?
Happy that you're not working?
Yes, I am.
I'm hurt.
We're the only ones who miss you.
Is that true?
I'm really hurt.
What's wrong with you?
What's that?
A gift.
I wanted to give this to you on your birthday.
I guess I'm quite impatient.
Thank you.
Is it very hard?
You heard?
Sun Sin, it's much better to confront things
rather than hide and leave it unresolved.
This way, you and your family
will feel better.
If things get tough, it's better to vent
your anger  from time to time.
Get furious.
Then, shall I vent it on you?
Hurry, eat.
The food's getting cold.
When you're stressed,
eating is the best.
Thank you.
Sir, how could such a thing happen?
It's jackpot.
Sun Sin's really lucky.
She's a Cinderella.
Goodness.
This should have happened earlier.
There's just too many offers.
There are even requests to act with Song Mi Ryeong.
She's really popular.
What should we do?
Shall I schedule it?
Schedule.
What schedule?
Absolutely not.
Decline them.
What's wrong with you?
Where can you find
such a nice turn of events?
This is the perfect chance.
Sun Sin is famous,
Miss Song is famous.
This is such an opportunity for Sun Sin.
She can be famous.
Why must we miss this?
No!
You should never tell Sun Sin about this.
Understand?
Jun Ho.
You are getting off work now?
Come and drink with me, will you?
I'm going to see Miss Song.
I was just there.
She's not feeling well.
Jun Ho.
Can you comfort me today?
I'm a little depressed today.
Teacher Song is suffering a lot
because of someone.
You must be too.
I feel really sensitive.
Do you understand how I feel?
Let's go in.
Have a drink with me.
I'll take a rain check.
I'm quite busy today.
Yeon A.
Who's this?
We meet again here.
Oppa, I have a sister now.
Yeon A.
You're drunk.
No, I'm not drunk.
Sun Sin...
Forgive Mom already.
Do you know how worried she is now?
Sorry, I'll go ahead.
See you again, Boss.
Aren't you going to answer that?
Yes.
It's a spam.
Isn't that from a man?
No, it's not.
Yes, do you have time for this now?
Your family must be in such
a turmoil these days.
Yes.
What are we going to do about your mother?
Take better care of her.
Yes.
Oh.
Did Chan U mention anything
about having a girlfriend?
Pardon?
It looks like Chan U's dating
the Chairman's daughter.
Although I thought nothing of it when
the Chairman invited him to his home,
looks like it's not like that at all.
Come to think of it,
I think he invited him over
to set him up with his daughter.
Chan U didn't even say anything.
I even thought there was
a problem with the girl.
I saw her. She's so pretty and cute.
You saw her?
I met her by chance at the hospital this morning.
She keeps coming to the hospital.
Looks like they're really dating.
Hey, Yu Sin.
Find yourself a man
and get married too.
Your mother's pretty down lately.
With what happened to Hye Sin and Sun Sin...
Wouldn't it be nice if you could
lift her spirits up a bit?
Stop dating around.
Find a reliable guy and get married.
Get married immediately.
Don't be too picky.
Everything's so expensive these days.
Oh, my.
It's heavy, Gil Ja.
Let me.
Thanks.
Why are you here?
Ah, really...
You're done, right?
Let's go, Mom.
What's wrong with you? Go home.
I still have to salt the kimchi.
Why do you have to salt the kimchi?
Let's go, Mom.
I told you to go ahead.
Yu Sin.
I heard. Congrats.
You nabbed the Chairman's daughter.
Don't let go.
I should start dating too.
I just broke up with my boyfriend too.
What's wrong with you?
What did I do?
How could you raise your voice
in front of ajumma?
What did Chan U do?
Apologize to them.
Ajumma, I'm fine.
Okay. I'm sorry.
I'l go ahead.
Mom, you can live here forever.
Yu Sin.
Why did she stalk out?
Gil Ja, I have to go home.
Yes, yes.
Go home.
She's even shouting at her mom.
It must be serious.
Go home.
Give this to me.
Okay, go.
Oh, gosh.
What did you say to Yu Sin?
What did I do?
How could she get more and more annoying?
You...
Imagine how she bad feels these days.
What's wrong with you?
Are you deliberately giving me a hard time?
What did I do?
You made a scene back there.
What does that make me?
Just stop working there.
Yu Sin.
Why? Are you going to hit me again?
I'm sorry about that.
However...
However what?
Have you ever considered my feelings?
It's always Sun Sin, Sun Sin.
When did I do that?
You do!
After knowing she was dad's daughter,
you still worry about her.
Imagine how she's feeling.
How confused and helpless she must be.
You are her big sister.
Can't you understand her for a moment?
Don't you know how pitiful she is?
How is she pitiful?
Don't you hate her too?
I know you hate her so please don't
pretend otherwise and act all mighty.
All mighty?
That's right!
She's the product of dad's affair.
How can you pretend to feel sorry for her?
Don't you hate her?
Go and have your own child too.
Do you think you can hate
just because you want to?
That's what a parent is.
That's what a child is.
Be honest, Mom.
Child? What child?
She's now grown up.
Can't you see how awesome her mother is?
But you said you don't hate her.
I don't hate her.
Why should I?
I know!
I know how great you are.
I know you're great but not like this.
Fine, I lose!
But, Mom...
Don't forget this...
I'm also your daughter.
I'm your daughter who worries
about you more than anyone.
Oh, my.
Why is it so noisy?
What happened?
What did she do again?
Nothing, Granny.
Eonni.
Don't claim to know
how I'm feeling right now.
Do you know how much
I've hated you since I was little?
They said you almost died on the side-road.
Dad and Mom were always worried about you.
As their real daughter,
I had to keep giving in to you.
I never had their love to myself.
But you're actually dad's daughter.
Does that make any sense?
You're dad's daughter.
Then, what about me?
What's the use of yielding
to you all those times?
Yes. Just as Mom said, it's not your fault.
I know that.
But I'm really having a hard time
whenever I see you.
I can't accept it no matter how hard I try.
What can I do?
I can't help it even if they call me selfish.
Do you have a reservation?
Ah, well...
Hyeongnim.
He's over there.
- Hello.
- Yes.
I thought we're just meeting for a while.
Why are we in such a nice place?
I wanted to do this all along.
I just didn't get the chance.
I see.
Thanks, then.
Have you been busy lately?
Just the same.
Hey. How did things turn out like this?
Couldn't you just have kept that a secret?
Must you really do that?
Hyeongnim...
Anyway, there are no secrets in this world.
Tell her this.
She can't live like that.
She used her daughter to elicit compassion.
She'll get punished.
What are you saying?
That's too much.
Don't you agree?
She held the press conference
precisely because of that.
Please leave her family alone.
Do you know how much they've suffered
after Chang Hun hyeong passed away?
Then this happened.
Sister-in-law is close to collapsing.
Hyeongnim, are they suffering a lot
since Chang Hun hyeong died?
Isn't that obvious?
The head of the family suddenly died.
Goodness.
There were no witnesses.
They can't even get compensation.
They are barely getting by.
By the way, Il Do.
I'm curious about one thing.
Is Sun Sin really Chang Hun hyeong's daughter?
I don't understand what you mean.
Come on...
Tell me the truth.
Then, whose child could she be?
It has always been Chang Hun for Nunim.
Is that so?
Stop talking nonsense.
Let's just drink.
- Come.
- Yes.
Don't suddenly appear before me
and act like a mother.
I only have one mother.
Sun Sin...
Let me tell you this again.
I don't want to see you.
So, please don't appear before me again.
I beg you.
Please.
Nunim, are you drinking again?
You'll become an alcoholic like this.
Are you that worried about her?
In that case, just give them some money
to make you feel better.
I heard her family's suffering a lot
after Chang Hun hyeong died.
If you go and help them,
I reckon this will be best
for everyone concerned.
This way, they won't say anything bad against us.
You will also feel better.
If you don't want to get her back,
give them what's appropriate.
Then continue living like this.
This is the best solution for everyone.
You were also very upset because
of Chang Hun, weren't you?
This is the only way to alleviate your guilt.
Guilt?
What guilt?
Did I do anything wrong?
Did I kill Chang Hun oppa?
What are you talking about?
Furthermore,
did I leave my child to them?
Did I beg them to raise her?
Why should I feel guilty?
I didn't do anything wrong.
No.
What I meant was...
I... want to bring her back and live with her.
Nunim.
Why? I want to live with my daughter.
Is that wrong?
That old lady who disregarded me.
I bet she's abusing my daughter.
The daughters of that family,
will they treat her the same way after
finding out that she's my daughter?
It's a different story if I didn't know.
Now that I know, how can I stay still
and do nothing?
Nunim.
I will take her back and give her everything.
People will envy her.
Anyway, everyone knows now.
My daughter...
Song Mi Ryeong's daughter...
can't stay in that wretched house any longer.
My pride won't allow that.
Are you going somewhere?
Prepare the car.
I'm going to Sun Sin's house.
What?
What are you doing?
Writing my CV.
I have to find a job soon.
Don't be in such a hurry.
Take your time to think about it.
Don't worry, Eonni.
I'll get employed right away,
then buy U Ju some delicious food
and give you pocket money.
All right, then.
Good luck.
Thanks, Eonni.
What are you doing, Granny?
Where are you going?
I'm going to submit my resume
to different companies.
Have you met your real mother?
Didn't she contact you?
Oh... No, she didn't.
If she wants to meet you,
tell me, okay?
I'll go with you.
Yes.
Okay. Go on.
Then, I'm going.
Hang on.
This...
Buy your lunch with this.
No, Granny.
It's okay.
Take it.
Why isn't there a comfortable day?
Granny, do you want to go out with me?
Where are we going?
Let's have lunch together.
There is no need.
There's a really nice cold noodles restaurant nearby.
When you're feeling blue,
eating that will surely lift your spirits up.
Let's go, Granny.
Don't worry, it's okay.
I can't chew.
I'll cut the noodles for you.
Come on, Granny.
My goodness.
My granny's waist is so small.
You can join the Miss Korea contest.
Come on, let's go.
Wait here.
What are you doing here?
I was in a hurry last time.
I didn't make a proper greeting.
I'm here to do that now.
Are you the eldest daughter?
Yes, I am.
Is your mother here?
I heard from Chan U.
It's already in the newspapers.
They call her aspiring actress, Miss A.
The reporters are quick.
They even know what Sun Sin is doing.
They are even saying,
"Like mother, like daughter."
I really don't know why everyone's saying that.
Yes, Hye Sin.
Mom. You have a guest at home.
Song Mi Ryeong.
Who? Song Mi Ryeong?
Song Mi Ryeong's there?
Why is she there?
I don't know, either.
Come home first, Mom.
Please have some tea.
Thank you.
But, where is your mother?
She went to work.
What kind of work?
She's helping out at a friend's shop.
Shop?
What kind of shop?
Chicken shop.
I'm curious about something.
Who picked Sun Sin's name?
Why do you want to know?
There are plenty of nice names.
Why must it be...
Oh, yeah.
Where is Sun Sin's room?
What?
She shares a room with her sister?
Yes.
Can I open that?
Excuse me.
I'm curious.
What my daughter wears,
what her room looks like.
I want to know all that.
Does she share a wardrobe with her sister too?
What are you doing right now?
No, forget it.
Let's go down.
Is there a problem?
How have you been?
For all those times you've raised my child,
you've worked really hard.
I've gotten over those negative feelings.
Let's get along well from now on.
I've already prepared to do everything for Sun Sin.
Those times I ignored my motherly duties,
I'm now ready to assume it.
What are you saying?
She's going to continue studying
and pursue her acting career.
I will do everything I can for her.
That way, I can pay back everything
I owed my daughter.
Isn't that a mother's duty?
What?
What's that?
Thank you for raising my daughter.
It's a token of my appreciation.
Please take it.
I'm going to take her
because she's my daughter.
-=Next Episode Preview.=-
You abandoned her back then.
Now you want to come back as a mother?
Abandon her?
It was Chang Hun oppa who took her away.
She said she wants to take you.
She said she'll take you and raise you.
Let Sun Sin go, Mom.
We absolutely can't Sun Sin sent away.
Let's tell the families.
What are you doing?
I want to marry you.
Let's get married.
I know your heart.
Try to be honest to yourself.
Promise me.
You won't go find my mother anymore.
Can't you open your heart a bit for me?
No matter what you say,
I'm still your mother.
Mother.
What mother?
= Teacher Song Mi Ryeong =
= Boss Gim Yeong Hun =
= Pak Chan U =
= Job Application Form =