The movements of my heart
are ruled by sweet suggestion
of a glance, of a vibration,
and not by the words from your mouth
You get it if you think that it's so easy
to make me a suit
without measuring the curves that draw
the contours of my being
To go up stairs and to know to stop
to measure the exact time to start kissing
To take the right path and to take care of me
Only a gentleman passes here
To make it through requires its system
so that, in this matter
it's words of affection that open the secret formulas,
zippers and so on...
What do they put in love
that it climbs upward, higher and higher,
growing to the tempo of the movement
marked by two
There are sages who will think here,
"mystical that this be in the world"
but it's the body that's the condensation
of drives, nurture and passion.
It's your actions that form a presence
and it's in your absence
that I'm without the strength that's in
a person whole and real
What do they put in love
that it climbs upward, higher and higher,
growing to the tempo of the movement
marked by two
What do they put in love
that it climbs upward, higher and higher,
growing to the tempo of the movement
marked by two
What do they put in love
that it climbs upward, higher and higher,
to the tempo of the movement marked by two