MK Pictures &
Rascal Entertainment Present
Supported by Koflc
Seoul, 1953
Hello, Mister.
LEE Wan, SoNG chang-Ui
Everyone off.
- You're here.
- Yeah.
- How many?
- 6
Move it.
Make a Iine.
- What's your name?
- HAN Chul-Ho.
Get over there!
Name.
What?
Seunq-woo?
Come here.
Producers LEE Eun, KANG ln-Ki
Associate Producers
Yl chi-Yun, PARK Hong-Geun
Line Producers
SoN Sung-Moon, LEE Seung-Yeon
co-producers
LlM Byeong- Woo, JANG Mi-Hee
- Bring it next time.
- It's okay.
No one saw, right?
Screenplay
HAN Ji-Hun, KlM Sang-Don
Yep.
Move it carefuIly.
So, It wiIl cost
always Iike this?
Director
BAE Hyung-Joon
Boss! Boss!
Who's there!
- It's Tae-Ho.
- What?
I think Jonq-Du took off.
I thought he came over here.
What?
Who's here?
Jong-Du.
You're sure he's here?
I didn't hear a thing.
I'm sure.
I followed him here.
Son of a bitch.
- Maybe he's dead.
- Dead, my ass.
I knew it.
Wait.
Let's do one more round.
This is enouqh.
This is a one
in a million chance.
No way.
Hurry.
Shit, what the heck.
Just take only cigarettes
and liquor.
They sell at high prices.
Fuck, it's heavy.
Let go of me!
Hey, come out here!
You son of bitch!
You fuck, let go of me.
Come on out.
- Here's your cards.
- Got something good?
- Huh?
- I win, I win.
I win!
Who the hell is it?
Laugh, you fucker.
Laugh. Go on!
What's that noise?
Check it out.
Don't move!
Move if your want
your head blown off.
Fucker.
That's enough.
I saw some unauthorized stuff
on the market.
You sons of bitches.
You steal from
right under my nose.
Sung-Jae!
Now that it's summer and all,
let's round a few mutts.
Yes, boss.
Come here, you fuck.
I said come here, you fuck.
once upon a Time in Seoul
There are 50 boxes of liquor
and over 100 boxes of cigarettes.
The reason they mess with our stuff
is they're not getting it on time.
So I was thinking of finding
some new deals.
Take care of that with Myung-Soo.
Good job, yesterday.
I'll tell Sooyangro to expect you.
Take the boys for a drink.
Good day, sir.
Hello.
How are you sir?
It should be easy to find out
who supplied them.
You beat them for half a day
and still haven't find out?
That black guy
they were talking about,
I can't find him
anywhere.
Forget it.
I'll take care of that.
What about the stuff?
Why does it take half a day
to calculate how much it is?
Well...
How much is just the Luckies?
The Luckies?
Well, there's 50 boxes of Luckies.
And I got 5 more boxes.
That's 55 boxes.
So how much is that,
you dickhead?
Calculating that
is no big deal but...
I spent all morning looking for
that black master sergeant.
Get it done
by tonight.
Okay.
That's reward for yesterday.
I'd like something else, sir.
Something else?
Let us work the market, sir.
Look, boy, you need brains
to work the market.
1,760,000 huan.
What's 1,760,000?
One pack of Luckies is 40 huan.
One carton of 20 pack is 800 huan.
One box is 40 cartons,
8x4=32,
32,000 huan.
50 boxes x 32,
1,600,000 huan.
Plus 5 boxes equals
1,760,000 huan.
You can do that in your head?
Boss, he's really good.
Forget it.
Take that
and get out of here.
- I can do well, sir.
- You little prick...
Why not?
Give them Kyung-Soo's store.
They're only boys, boss.
What if someone robs them?
The market's unstable now.
You know that, boss.
So what if stolen goods
get stolen.
- Good day, boss.
- Let'em try.
Good day, sir.
Fuck, why do we have to
work for them?
We got U.S. goods, too.
So how are we gonna
get rid of them?
If we move too early,
we become targets.
Keep your enemies close.
I got an idea.
So you decided
for both of us!
Just take your share
if you want to leave.
That's for running out on me.
If I had stayed there,
we'd have both died.
All that for nothing.
Fuck.
That's all our stuff.
Forget about it.
We'll get another chance.
- Don't eat this.
- Okay.
If you' re told to stop,
then pack up and come back in.
There's lots of days
you can't work.
Wait, where is it?
Then find other work
or something.
Here, Johnnie Walker!
- Johnnie Walker!
- Hey...
You get into trouble,
mention our boss.
Then the market will
take care of things.
Mister Do-Chul?
Whatcha talking about?
I mean Boss Myung-Soo of course.
There's a fight.
Fuck off.
He grabbed his throat
and just threw him.
Never seen nobody
so strong.
He was like someone else.
They're all still thugs.
No, they said he was
even better during the war.
I don't think
he's just a thug.
I'm warning you now,
stay away from any fight.
They attacked first.
You're working here but
you take off at a time like that?
Shut up.
We got nothing to do
with them.
Whoever messes with me
is dead meat.
Make sure you don't mix it up
with our stuff.
This is really good.
Y eah, it's sweet.
- Give me that.
- No.
I heard about this place.
Is this real?
Of course.
We got them
straight from the Yankees.
Then l'll take one
for 1,000 huan.
No way.
That was the price yesterday.
From today,
it's 1,300 huan.
We can't do that.
It went up again?
This is getting crazy.
Then l'll take it for 1,200 huan.
But give me 3 bottles.
- I shouldn't.
- Then forget it.
All right then.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Do come again.
Give me chocolate.
This month's pay.
Go on.
- All done?
- One more to go.
Have a heart, bro.
- Please!
- Next time.
No way.
That doesn't make sense.
I' m telling you.
Look at the office.
There's stacks of stuff
that aren't being sold.
Why do you think?
Maybe other areas
don't sell well.
That's not it.
Mister Do-Chul isn't
interested in business.
We close shop a lot too.
I was wondering why
and now I get it.
When stuff sells,
you buy more stuff.
When it doesn't sell,
you hold onto it.
It's because
prices keep going up.
It might be better
to keep our stuff.
What?
Then you really won't sell it?
No, we could get
caught anytime.
We should get rid of
what we can.
Just as long as we don't
keep it in cash.
Then what do you suggest?
I don't know about
after that.
Pick it up.
Grab it.
Let go, you fuck.
- T ae-Hwan.
- Fucker.
Thief! Thief!
Help us!
Help!
Please!
Thief!
Come on!
Let go, you fuck.
People are coming!
Come on, guick!
What's this?
What the hell
were you thinking?
Things like this always happen
on collection day.
You should have been careful.
Where the fuck are they?
Boss.
That's over 8,000 huan,
you fuck.
You send it
with these two babies?
- Are you insane or what?
- They took 2 cans of Spam.
- l'll repay it somehow.
- What?
They held onto the money.
- You checked it?
- Yes. It's 8,060 huan.
A good meal's the best cure
for a mugging, you know.
- They haven't had dinner yet.
- We don't need dinner.
Give 'em some money to eat.
Boss!
We rounded up the kids.
- You boys come too!
- Boss!
Please stop.
Please stop!
Please...
This is what we call
hanging up a mutt.
A mutt is a dog that keeps
biting you every time you let it go.
Then you have to take out
all its teeth.
Otherwise,
it'll try to bite you again.
So you have to take them all out
when you grab them.
Come on, you shithead.
You got something to say
to me?
Please don't.
Wait, wait, hold on!
Hey! Hey!
He's dead.
You' re so rough.
Why'd you do that?
Clean up.
You didn't kill him.
It was just bad luck.
We get screwed all the time.
So just forget about it.
But I never killed nobody.
What's with you, Jong-Du?
Stupid fuckers.
They should have left town
right away, not get caught.
They were dumb to begin with.
You can't get anywhere
with that kind of brains.
We' re different from
those idiots.
But we need to stay on
our toes.
See how he left it to you
at the end.
The more I see that bastard,
the less I like him.
- If we get unlucky...
- Just let them try.
I' m not afraid one bit.
Shit.
You' re right, Jong-Du.
We' re not that easy
to deal with.
Don't worry.
As long as I have you,
I got nothing to worry about.
I'll find a way somehow.
You made it?
Yes.
Do it like you're flicking it.
Where's the whiz kid?
Don't know.
He went to find out something.
The first time's
always the toughest.
- Goodbye, sir.
- Go on then.
No RlcE
- Sell rice?
- Y eah.
There's a lot of flour
coming in,
but you think Koreans can live
without rice?
Harvest has been bad for years.
I'll bet when it gets cold,
there'll be a huge fuss.
Fuss?
Cuz of rice?
I know this rice guy
from way back.
He says he'll give me more than
the market price for any amount.
How much more money
do we need?
I don't know.
But a box of cigarettes went up to
2,000 huan.
If the value of money keeps falling,
it'll get harder to get out.
But what choice do we have?
And we have to run
the store too.
Nope.
We could do better than that.
We might need kids
younger than us.
Get her!
Catch that thief!
- Got ya!
- Let me go!
What are you doing here?
Mister.
- She's my little sister, sir.
- So what?
She forgot to take money
with her.
Mom told me to go after her.
Here.
I'm really sorry
about that day.
But we were forced
to go there.
Maybe you were, but your pal
killed someone.
No. That's not it.
That was an accident.
He's still agonizing over it.
So what good does that
do now?
Is that gonna bring
a dead guy back?
I don't know what to say
when it comes to your chief.
But you guys would have ended up
like that one way or another.
What's that mean?
You would have kept stealing
and gotten caught someday.
I'm sorry
if I offended you.
That wasn't
why I came to see you.
I've been looking for
you guys all day.
That's Sang-Gook
and his brother Jae-Gook.
Woo-Shik, Young-Nam,
and Duk-Bae.
So what you got up
your sleeve?
Why are we listening to the guy
who killed out chief?
You keep guiet.
The reason
I asked to see you is
to suggest selling stuff with us
from now on.
I thought
it was a pickpocket j'ob.
Sell what?
Dirt from the street?
Selling ain't
for the likes of us.
Yeah, they don't even treat us
like people.
This is just a taste.
If business goes well,
you'll get fed 3 times a day
and we'll give you a cut.
I guarantee it.
You're google-eyed
over a few pennies?
- More soup please.
- Me too.
You already forgot
how our chief died?
So?
They're in?
Well...
Guys should just say yes or no.
What's so complicated?
All I need to do is pay you back
for what I did to you.
That's all you need, right?
Okay. I'll do it.
It won't get any worse
than this.
And like someone said,
we need to get paid back for
our chief's life, right?
Okay, l'm in.
- Me too.
- And me.
What about us?
Well, if everybody's doing it,
then...
Wow, it's an organ.
No one's been living here
since it got bombed.
- You sure?
- Y eah.
It's far from anybody
and perfect for storing the rice.
And it's close to the stream.
Hey, what's that?
- Come here.
- What is it?
Over there.
- Look at that.
- At what?
I mean over there.
There.
It's done.
I miss Mommy.
I wanna go with her.
I wanna go to Mommy.
Stupid fuck.
You want to be buried
here too?
Shut your trap and bow.
You don't know
how to bow?
Do what I do.
Go on out.
They said
they'd take care of it.
- Look here.
- Shut up.
Ask!
When are we startin
the rice business?
Well, we work in the store
tomorrow
and you guys need
to get your stuff,
so the day after tomorrow
maybe?
We don't really have anything
to bring.
But you' re gonna have to live here
from now on.
Tell me what you need
and we'll try to get it for you.
Thanks anyway.
It's all thanks to you.
Don't worry too much.
They know the market
so they think fast.
And they follow orders well.
What's he say?
When do we start the rice thing?
What?
find the biggest landowner
in the village.
All the rice will be there
anyway.
And then...
Hello, sir.
Huh?
Who are you kids?
Well, um.
We were...
What our big brother means is
we're on our way to SeouI to find
our parents we split up with.
And we ran out of rice.
What's going on?
- Good day, sir.
- Yes.
Our uncle who works
on the U.S. base gave us this
to give to our parents
when we meet them.
But seeing
as we're in need now...
Fuck.
They wouldn't give us any rice.
They said
a girl was bad luck.
Shut up. I told you the place
we went to was stingy.
Don't worry. We can do
that much tomorrow.
I heard rice prices were good
in Kimpo.
How about we go there
next time?
I think I heard that too.
Okay.
We go to Kimpo next.
You did well for your first day.
We'll make it in no time.
We'll get more and more
from now on
and l'm worried about leaving
such a little boy here alone.
I think someone should
stay with him.
Then Soon-Nam should stay.
You got the least.
Why me?
I just had a run of bad luck.
You have no choice.
You guys did get the least.
Hey, it's the traveling doctor.
This medicine happens to work for
asthma, nervousness breakdown,
strengthening stamina.
The results will blow you away.
You gotta try it.
Mister, try this.
- Just try!
- It can heal every disease!
Look at that guy's belly.
- Shall we steal that?
- No.
Where are you from?
You' re not from around here,
are you?
Hey, what's that on your back?
- It's nothing, sir.
- Hand it over.
- You little...
- Run!
Stop right there!
Get up.
I said stop!
Come on!
Quick!
Bro!
Throw it!
Come on!
Bro!
I told him it was nothing.
But the cop just charged at me.
Then big bro Jong-Du swerved
and took out his whip...
Yummy?
- You're supposed to fall.
- Huh?
Ha, ha, ha!
You're pathetic.
I'm PARK Jong-Du, the fighter
from Jong-ro.
That's bullshit.
He didn't say that.
Sure he did. I heard him.
Yeah, right.
Just shut up and eat.
I just got it
at the market.
- This is good.
- What is it?
This is porridge
straight from America.
- lvory.
- 1 dollar.
Bro!
Good to see you.
Welcome.
Wow, that's heavy.
Wow!
Hey!
Stop that!
Attack!
Guys!
- And this.
- Ok.
So you want to
come with us too?
No, staying with Soon-Nam
is fun too.
What's fun?
Dunno. She only talks about
the rice and T ae-Ho.
- What about me?
- Let's go.
Wow.
Jong-Du, look at this.
Gi-Dong, let's go.
Why? What's up?
Who's that little shrimp
with Jong-Du?
Never seen him before.
Why those little fuckers.
I went by the office earlier.
They were all looking for you.
The market seems weird.
Is something up?
How long are you gonna
stay here?
What?
You miss your timing and
you'll never get out.
Like you?
No.
I don't care what happens.
It's time you stopped.
This place isn't that easy,
you know.
Watch your back.
Tae-Ho!
I walked over 10 kms.
Now my legs are stiff.
I don't think
l'm cut out for this.
It wasn't like that at first.
But now I can't even out-talk
country bumpkins.
But you' re good at
stealing money?
Why'd you do it?
We promised each other
from the start
we eat, sleep together
until we're done.
But why did you do it?
Eat together
and starve together?
Rice rations are 200 huan.
Rice we buy
from the country is 300.
Isn't that strange?
You ever been to the market?
No one's selling rice
in stores.
But rice on the black market is
600 huan.
Why are we working
our asses off?
We don't know shit.
And somebody's making money.
- You wanna die?
- Stop it.
We have to show that fucker.
A bastard who doesn't trust his
pack needs to learn a lesson.
We'll j'ust kick him out.
How does that make us
different from Do-Chul?
Fuck.
Yeah, l'm an ignorant pig.
You' re happy?
Bastard!
So you'll beat him to death too?
Shut up and butt out.
All right.
Do what you gotta do.
It was because of my mom.
I dropped by my house
just in case.
My family's come back.
My younger brothers
are starving
and my mom has a lung disease.
What was I supposed to do?
I feel really bad
about you guys.
But I had no choice.
Shut your trap, you fuck!
You go and betray us?
Don't hit him.
He said it was for his mom.
Shit!
Get lost.
You're letting me live?
Go back to your family, you fuck!
Thanks, Jong-Du.
They're depressed because
of Duk-Bae.
They're not talking
but they envy him.
You too?
I got no one to go back to.
My dad...
used to make western biscuits.
After the store got bombed,
I went after the U.S. soldiers.
I became a refugee
on my own.
I kept going to school.
But I dropped out
when I came to Seoul.
Then if this works out,
you go back to school?
I gave that up long ago.
I got a much better plan.
Wait and see.
I'll make money like crazy.
I'll build a market bigger than
Mangi Market.
Then nobody will look down
on us.
No. They' ll be
bowing to us instead.
That sounds good.
There used to be a stream
outside our house too.
I went with my sisters
at night.
We washed our hair
and took baths.
After I became alone,
I cut my hair like a boy.
Some girls who worked
on the U.S. base
said I looked real bad
for a girl.
They tried to keep me there.
But I took off.
It was suffocating.
But,
I won't have to do that now.
Give me a drink.
What do I have to do
to be tough like you?
What?
I saw you fight.
I want to be strong like you.
So you want to be a thug.
Anything's fine.
I don't want to rely on anyone.
I want to be strong by myself.
Like you.
You know why this is great?
It looks like it'll go out,
but it never goes out.
That's what being strong is.
I don't live like this
'cuz l'm strong.
I'm just hanging on
because I got no choice.
I thought you were the toughest man
I ever saw.
Toughest man.
Kid!
You listen to me.
You think
there's such a thing?
No way.
The tough, the weak, the cowards
all end up dying.
That's why
this world is fucked up.
You get it?
You don't know either.
You don't know,
do you?
Run.
Check our goods.
You're not practicing
the whip today?
Nope.
The market's unstable and
Do-Chul smells something's up.
I think we should pack up.
If you say so.
Don't worry.
We're almost there.
Just hang on a bit longer.
And then?
Huh?
What happens
after we sell off the rice?
I'll split the money with the kids
like I promised.
You round them up
when you need them
and spit them out
when you' re done?
How can you say that?
Who says l'll do that?
- l'll make sure they get paid...
- Money, money, money!
Fuck it.
All you think about is money?
That's all?
You listen.
Jobs and a full stomach
is a lot in these times.
We're in no position
to look after anyone else.
They have to find
their own way.
Soon-Nam's gonna go with you?
Kids
Wrap it up
and come to the office.
Let's go.
- Is it weird?
- Wow.
I j'ust tried it on because
the laundry's still wet.
You' re so pretty
like an angel!
You're such a sweet-talker.
T ake this.
- Pass it back.
- Take whatever you fancy.
Take one each.
Jong-Du...
- Anyone not get one?
- Line up.
Who are we?
We went out on the battlefield,
crushed the commie bastards
and came back alive.
We' re mighty warriors.
- Yeah!
- That's right!
Commie bastards
who attacked us
couldn't get anywhere
near killing us.
- That's right.
- Yeah.
That's how tough we are.
If we lose our lives now,
if we lose our livelihood,
then that's worse than dying
at their guns.
- Yeah!
- Let's fight!
- Go on.
- Sis.
- Go on!
- What's wrong?
The heads of those running away
Iook much bigger than
commie bastards coming at you.
One shot for one bastard.
Fight like hell if you don't want
a hole in your head.
- Got that?
- Yes!
- Let's fight!
- Fight!
Hello, Boss.
You bring kids
to a territory fight?
Since when were you so low?
I called them.
If we have more people...
Are you okay?
Off!
Go home.
You shouldn't be here.
- I can fight.
- I said go home!
Don't make me tell you twice.
Send them home.
Go on.
- What is it?
- Soon-Nam...
- Soon-Nam.
- Stay back.
What's wrong?
I have a guestion.
Where's the rice?
What?
I was supposed to watch it.
Why isn't it there?
I moved it next door
after Duk-Bae left.
What is it?
Don't!
Who was it?
Who did this?
What bastard did it?
Duk-Bae.
I'm sure of it.
But he went home...
Who else knows
about the rice here?
He used to hang out
with some tramps.
It must have been them.
Let's go.
There was no rice
like he said
but at least
I got me some pussy.
She was so wild she bit me.
She hurt me.
You bastards!
Bastards!
Duk-Bae!
Fuckers!
Bastards!
Tae-Ho, no!
Tae-Ho!
Don't come closer!
Forget about it.
Duk-Bae started it.
Let's go see Mister JANG
and tell him
we'll sell all the rice.
We have so much
and that's the best thing.
- What about the market?
- We guit.
If we disappear suddenly,
they'll get suspicious.
We'll say
we're going to see relatives.
Listen up.
Just hold up for a few days.
Don't think of going anywhere.
Bring the rice.
He's just having a hard time.
He'll be all right soon.
He's a smart one.
We haven't slept outside
in a while.
Let's feed them well.
What happened?
What's the use of having
a strong fist and fast feet?
You can't fight a bullet.
He killed our boss.
He deserves to die.
How could he do this?
Some party last night.
I thought the tramps were
talking nonsense.
I' ll make this short.
Bring all the money you made
on the side and the rice.
Now that Myung-Soo's gone,
no ones got your back.
Like I said before...
Run!
The bastards!
What the hell?
Get some woods.
Everything will be fine
if we sell off all the rice.
That's a lot of money,
even for adults.
With that money
they can all go live anywhere.
You think they can go anywhere
just 'cuz they have money?
What if Do-Chul finds them?
It's the same
if they're with us.
It might be more dangerous
to be with us.
No way l'm sending them off
like this.
Jong-Du! Tae-Ho!
It's ready!
Okay!
So warm.
Chicken! Chicken!
I' ll eat noodles every day.
Me too.
I'm gonna buy shiny boots
like the American MPs wear.
Wow! Me too!
- Copy cat.
- What!
Then are we splitting up?
Idiot!
Why would we split up?
Stop talking nonsense.
Jae-Gook!
There's liguor in my backpack.
Go get it.
Liguor? Liguor?
- Gi-Dong, pour me some.
- Okay!
Here.
Yeah!
Let's see.
17kg, 15kg, 14kg...
Are you gonna take all day?
I' m calculating.
I forgot where I was.
Little prick.
Let's count this.
Hey, it's a puppy!
48, 49, 50
51, 52, 53
54, 55...
- 57, 58
- 52, 53
58 Damn! 58.
Where's Gi-Dong?
He was here j'ust now.
Gi-Dong's disappeared!
I can't find him anywhere.
Split up and look.
- Gi-Dong!
- Be careful!
Gi-Dong!
The lowlifes in the market.
You shouldn't have taken him
around with you.
It's a good thing
we got all the money.
I was worried about it
so I got it all at once.
Give me all of it.
What do you mean?
You don't get it?
We' ll use it
to get Gi-Dong back.
Isn't it obvious?
What are you gonna do?
You think Do-Chul will let him go
if he gets the money?
So you' re giving up Gi-Dong?
Shut up!
Gi-Dong's got nothing
to do with us.
You really wanna die?
You can beat me to death
but I can't do that!
You son of bitch!
Gi-Dong is one of us!
Bastard,
Gi-Dong isn't the only one.
We do what you say
and we all die.
I know!
Jong-Du
I know where Gi-Dong is.
We get our family even if
we get beat up trying.
Don't go.
Let's go.
I hope you get your wish.
Gi-Dong!
- Be on the lookout.
- Okay.
Gi-Dong! Gi-Dong!
Hey, they wanted to know
where you were.
Didn't tell them.
Gi-Dong, you' re a real man.
It's okay now.
Let's go home now.
Bro!
You came?
I didn't think
you'd really come.
Stop!
I' m the one you want dead.
Do what you want with me
but let them go.
Why are you so upset?
After I saved your life and all.
We have a history, right?
Fuck that.
I know you' re a coward!
You shot Myung-Soo in the back
because you couldn't beat him!
Don't play dumb.
The whole world knows.
You got some balls.
Bring it on, you fuck.
If that's what you want,
I'll skin you alive.
Don't. You' ll lose.
He won't let you go
even if you win.
So don't.
Look kid,
the world's a tough place.
Jong-Du!
Come here.
You want to fight, you fuck?
Get up!
Get up, you fuck.
Get up, you bastard.
You piece of shit.
Damn it.
Who's this?
I thought you'd split
since you' re smarter.
What's wrong with all of you?
This is everything we earned.
I brought all of it
like you said.
This is what you wanted.
Take it and let my family go.
You got brains
and you don't get it?
You're not getting out of here.
Try it.
I'm not dying alone.
I'm disappointed.
I thought you were different.
Your brains shouldn't
go to waste.
It's still not too late.
How about working for me?
Fuck you!
Fuckers!
Stop!
Stop it!
That's enough.
You kids.
Never show your face here again!
Ever!
- Let's go.
- Boss!
What?
Tae-Ho.
Stupid fuck.
Why'd you come?
Why'd you come, you fuck!
If I hadn't,
you'd have all died.
Tae-Ho.
Tae-Ho!
Open your eyes, you fuck!
Tae-Ho! Don't die!
It's weird
sleeping outdoors again.
Yeah.
Doesn't this remind you of
when we were in the camps?
Shit! Don't talk like that.
Just thinking about it sucks.
Me too.
I'm sure I can pull it off.
But what if it goes wrong?
Then our efforts are for nothing.
Then we do another raid...
But this time,
I'm taking off first.
You stay behind
and get beat up.