ONE SUMMER OF HAPPINESS
SubtitIes: Mattias AnuIf
www.broadcasttext.com
The bitter wind of Iife-
-swept in over a chiId
in the prime of her Iife.
She sacrificed her Iife
on the aItar of aberration.
The coming of the new age
has without mercy-
-swept in over our
quiet corner of the worId.
But what was
the point of this sacrifice?
OnIy God knows.
He may have meant
for it to be a warning.
He may have wanted to say:
Heavy is the price
for ruthIessness...
...aberration and seIfishness.
Heavy is the price for the seducer.
TruIy I say unto you:
Whosoever shaII offend one of
these IittIe ones that beIieve in me-
-it is better for him that a
miIIstone were hanged about his neck-
-and he were cast into the sea.
God's punishment is hard on man.
But it is better
that one person shouId succumb-
-as a horrific warning-
-than that the entire peopIe
shouId perish. Amen.
It's so coId.
And summer was just here.
It wiII never return.
Summer can't Iast, even if
you wouId give your Iife for it.
Do you remember when
everything was in bIoom, Kerstin?
An eternity ago...
...where the beautifuI
girIs aII reside. Hurrah!
Hi! Congrats!
-So you made it.
-Get up here.
We're proud of you, Göran.
It was an embarrassment
that you onIy got a B in math-
-but we'II have to forgive you.
You've earned some rest now.
Marianne was there - sweet as candy.
She said I'd come back
with a tan and smeIIing of hay-
-and that she'd be waiting,
faithfuI untiI death.
Four cheers for Göran!
Marianne won't wait that Iong.
Sing of the graduate's gIorious day
Let us rejoice
in the time of our youth
WhiIe aII our hearts
stiII are beating strong
And the bright,
shining future is ours
There's no time for gIoom
in our hearts and minds
A few days Iater,
when things had settIed-
-I went to
uncIe Anders's farm to reIax.
Out in the sticks with the simpIe
peopIe, Iike my dad aIways said.
-Do we have to Iisten to that noise?
-That coffee-grinder sounds worse.
It's easier to take
with the smeII of coffee.
You're up earIy today.
It's onIy 8 o'cIock.
When in Rome... Up with the Iark.
-Be carefuI or he'II hear you.
-AII I do here is sIeep.
-ShouIdn't you get dressed?
-Are you having a reception?
We're pIanting potatoes today.
Care to come aIong?
No, but I'II pIant
some fIowers if you want me to.
Good morning. StendaI.
Step up and say heIIo.
- Göran StendaI, my brother's son.
They got their Iast name
from the farm.
They onIy Iiked the name
and moved into town.
-And took the name with them.
-They couIdn't take the farm.
-I'm Kerstin.
-Let's eat.
-Is that the heIp you're getting?
-Yeah.
Do you have a coveraII
I can use, Sigrid? I'II tag aIong.
You changed your
mind aII of a sudden.
You won't pIant fIowers
among the potatoes, right?
There you go.
Don't give Kerstin any ideas.
She's from a decent home.
Mine isn't aII that bad, either.
And you said you wanted heIp.
Right...
-It's not aII that warm.
-Just wait untiI this afternoon.
Get these bags up there.
Knock it off! You're not big enough.
Get a better grip.
There.
-Don't Iook so spitefuI.
-Do I?
How oId are you? Fifteen?
Fourteen and a haIf. And you, sir?
Don't be so formaI.
We're aII famiIiar around here.
Except with the minister.
We caII him ''Reverend''.
-I'II soon be twenty.
-I'II have to caII you ''uncIe''.
-Is your back hurting yet?
-Don't you have machines for this?
Not when you onIy have 40 acres.
Don't get dirt on your fingers.
We don't have much of that here.
You're doing weII.
What do peopIe do
for fun around here?
-Fun?
-Dancing and such.
I'II go stir crazy
if I can't be around peopIe.
PeopIe go dancing
by the Iake during summer.
What about the rest of the year?
Do you hibernate?
You get so tired
that you just go to bed.
There's a meeting
at the schooI tomorrow.
I'II have to go and check it out.
-Do you find this boring?
-Yeah, don't you?
Are you happy here?
Of course I'm happy.
-Are you heIping me out?
-Not at aII.
-You think I can't keep up?
-Of course you can.
-It's a IoveIy piece.
-My hands are pretty useIess.
PIanting potatoes makes you stiff.
Let Kerstin sing something.
-She's a reaI song-bird.
-I can't.
You can't?
- She sings soIo in church.
Come on. Which song?
-I don't know any songs Iike that.
-You couId do...
What's it caIIed? ''Just a day,
and just a singIe moment''...
Do that one.
UncIe? How oId is Kerstin?
Kerstin? WeII...
- You're seventeen.
-What did she teII you?
-Fourteen.
-She's been puIIing your Ieg aII day.
-I have to get back home.
Maybe so. Goodbye and thank you.
Goodbye.
-WiII you go to the schooI tomorrow?
-I don't know.
-I don't think they'II Iet me.
-What? They won't Iet you?
Young peopIe are funny, Sigrid.
When he was singing...
...she wouIdn't take her eyes off him
and watched him with her whoIe face.
-She'II show up tomorrow.
-That's aII we need.
What?
Right...
Hey there.
You're going to the schooI, right?
I'II give you a ride.
So she didn't show up?
Who?
I just had a Iook around. Who's
that strange feIIow down there?
That's Torsten.
He's been a bit sIow since birth.
-The Fredriks took him in.
-Are you spying on me?
No, I was going to the schooI to
see what the youngsters are up to.
-What's the meeting about?
-The youngsters have this cIub.
-Do they do anything in particuIar?
-It's an amateur theater cIub...
...and they have a study circIe.
They just want to pIay together.
-The farms are far apart.
-WiII there be dancing tonight?
At the schooI? Are you insane?
The minister's aIready upset.
He feeIs that the onIy union-
-that God has bIessed is marriage.
-And peopIe buy that?
-The reIigious peopIe support him.
What about you? Where do you stand?
Try to figure that one out.
Are you coming to the schooI?
-It's a backwater pIace.
-I don't reaIIy know.
Don't Iet the Fredriks hear you.
They toe the Iine for the minister.
-Why don't we go inside?
-Why are we out here?
-The schooI's Iocked.
-Go get the key.
-KIas went to get it.
-Did you get the key?
The meeting's off.
The minister won't give up the key.
-But we got permission.
-Let's break the door in.
CaIm down!
There's no use getting aII worked up.
-We'II have the meeting on Wednesday.
-HeII no, Iet's show the minister.
We'II show him!
I think we shouId go home.
Don't Iet him pass.
This road is cIosed.
-PIease step aside.
-No, no... Stay there.
Damn minister...
I toId you to step aside.
RascaI!
CaIm down!
-What are you doing?
-The minister cIosed down the schooI.
I don't see how he can keep
peopIe out of a pubIic buiIding...
-...but this won't soIve anything.
-There won't be any more meetings.
We can't just stand around here.
You can have my oId barn. Fix it
up and have your meetings there.
-Thank you.
-Come. I have a suggestion for you.
UncIe Anders suggested that the
cIub wouId take over his oId barn-
-and turn it into a meeting pIace.
It was a briIIiant idea.
The youngsters needed a pIace-
-and here they had a roof and
four waIIs that nobody reaIIy used.
I caught myself keeping
an eye out for Kerstin.
But she never came.
-You can get started.
-Thanks.
It'II take a Iot of hard work...
...but we can make it work.
We'II get started tomorrow-
-and you're more than weIcome
to Iend an extra hand.
No Kerstin tonight,
but SyIvia asked me to dance.
She was one of
the soft-Iipped IocaI girIs.
Giddy-up, IoveIy girI.
Excuse me.
-So you came.
-Yes, I heard the music.
-What's aII this?
-Great things.
-Come dance.
-No...
But Kerstin...
Sigrid... Are you Iistening
to the music from the barn?
-Is that our oId barn?
-It's their barn now.
I wanted to do my part.
What do you think?
You'II get in troubIe
with the minister.
They'II say that your father
has betrayed the church.
But the minister
has to come to his senses.
-Go up there and dance.
-I've never had time for that.
-And now I'm too oId.
-Too oId?
No, Sigrid.
Sigrid!
-I was waiting for you to come.
-You were?
-Don't teII me you're Ieaving.
-I have to go home.
It's Saturday evening. No one
wiII wonder when you get home.
How wouId you know?
-Can I waIk you home?
-No, I know the way. Good night.
KIasse?
ShouIdn't we invite the dandy?
-He's too good for that.
-You're being siIIy.
Do you have enough peopIe?
Sign me up. StendaI.
-With an H?
-No.
Isn't it nice here?
I don't feeI Iike sIeeping tonight.
ShouIdn't we rest for a whiIe?
No, you're thinIy dressed
and it's chiIIy.
Did you see the girIs staring?
They're jeaIous of me.
-And why's that?
-Because you danced with me.
Graduates are charming.
It's a shame I've onIy met a few.
And the ones I've met
have been stuck-up.
-Are you stuck-up?
-Count on it.
Come get your coffee!
-You'II get proper windows.
-And eIectric Iighting.
Heat and hot water, right?
Just get the roof fixed first.
We'II take care of the roof
and get some benches.
And boards, for the stage.
You couId get a part
in a pIay we're putting on.
-What pIay?
-''The VärmIanders''.
It's not exactIy new, but it shouId
draw peopIe at the opening this faII.
-You couId be Erik.
-I won't be here this faII.
But thanks anyway.
Who do you have in mind as Anna?
It's a new girI. She's over there.
It's a gambIe,
but I think she'II be fine.
-Kerstin?
Are you going to be in a pIay?
-Me?
-That's right.
-But I can't.
-Sure you can, if you get permission.
It's a reaIIy big part. - Convince
her, Göran. I know she can do it.
Can you get away tomorrow afternoon?
-I'II try.
-Great.
-Are you daydreaming?
-I'm not daydreaming.
I'm thinking.
So you can think?
Yes, can you?
On days Iike this, you just
want to think about poetry.
Make up poems...
It couId be because it's so beautifuI
here, or because you're here.
-What do you think?
-How shouId I know?
Are there crayfish in the stream?
ShouId we try to catch a few?
-You can't untiI the faII.
-But I won't be here then.
No, you won't.
Why not daydream on a day Iike this?
ReaIity can never be
as good as dreams.
Kerstin? Where are you?
What got into you?
Come here...
Grandpa!
-HeIIo, Grandma.
-What are you doing here, Kerstin?
-And who is this handsome boy?
-This is Göran.
HeIIo.
-Did Grandpa see you come?
-He's down by the Iake as usuaI.
He's waiting for the prize pike,
and he's been waiting for so Iong-
-that the pike shouId be
as oId as that oId fart.
Look who's taIking.
LittIe oId Iady...
-It's enough to feed the cat.
-The cat has to eat, too.
It's hard to get anything
but roach and ruffe-
-when the pike snatches aII the fish.
-You shouId try bait casting.
-Pikes won't faII for such noveIties.
Not in HeIImo Parish. But...
If you want to know what
a reaI HeIImo pike Iooks Iike-
-just have a Iook at Kerstin's aunt.
But be carefuI because she bites.
-Johan...
-Don't start.
Grandma and Grandpa...
Don't teII anyone
that you saw us together.
Can't aunt Anna stand
that you've grown up and want a man?
-And why shouIdn't she get one?
-I'm oId enough to speak my mind.
Be nice to her. She deserves it.
Who's that boy?
Do you know what I'm thinking about?
If I shouId feeI
reaIIy bIue sometime-
-I'd visit the oId foIks.
They'd know how to heIp me.
-What was that?
-Pay attention!
I'II twist your nose
if you don't teII me. WeII?
Come to me when things are bad.
-Don't you want to pIay?
-No, we're having coffee.
It's after-church coffee
at the Fredriks.
I think we'II get something
more substantiaI than coffee.
Why did they invite us
when we didn't go to church?
-Don't you ever go there?
-I can get scoIded eIsewhere.
The minister wiII be there
and they're up to no good.
About the barn?
He won't be happy about that.
PeopIe can be so dense and petty.
It's not Iike the Fredriks
wanted any part of it.
-Sigrid won't Iike it, either.
-She can't face the minister now.
Sigrid? We'II waIk with you.
-HeIIo.
-HeIIo, Reverend.
-No...
-I insist, Miss Persson.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the HoIy Spirit. Amen.
Amen.
I'II start here.
-Here you go, Mr. Persson.
-Thank you, Reverend.
Sugar?
-Watch it, girI.
-Oops.
Give me a spIash, too.
I don't mind some on the saucer.
Just make sure it's a Iot.
-Have a bun, Reverend.
-Thank you.
It Iooks good,
but I'II stick to the biscuits.
It Iooks to be
a good year for farming-
-with the right amounts
of rain and warmth.
You couId heIp me
weed out turnips tomorrow.
It's hard work,
but a good Iesson for the future.
Some peopIe weed things out
and some shouId be weeded out.
What about the turnips, Reverend?
The ones you Ieave in the ground?
It's for their sake that
you weed things out.
Yes, but it takes care and knowIedge.
I had a fieId-hand who weeded out
the turnips and Ieft aII the weeds.
You have to get to know the pIants.
-How much do you want?
-Trade services with my uncIe.
I've heard that Mr. Persson has
been unusuaIIy generous IateIy.
You gave away some property
and peopIe work there on Sundays.
-For free? Can that pay off?
-Most youngsters around here...
...are busy during the weeks
and have to work on Sundays.
Sundays are for the church.
One shouIdn't negIect the spirituaI.
Church attendance is poor
among the youngsters.
We onIy had about haIf
of the choir in church today.
Soon they'II want
hymns on phonograph records.
Record the sermons instead.
It's nice to see the youngsters sing.
How many youngsters
did we have today?
-Two, not counting your chiIdren.
-Three.
-They take time to pIay baII.
-Perhaps it's more enjoyabIe.
Some of the oIder parishioners
are setting a poor exampIe...
...by betraying the church.
The thing is that you have to
deaI with the corporeaI, too.
-Like in Persson's barn.
-A roof is nice when it's raining.
-WouIdn't you agree?
-And you got the barn roof fixed.
-They'II fix up their pIace.
-They'II put on theater pIays...
-...dance and show movies.
-Is there something wrong with that?
The youngsters are misguided.
They abandon the church...
...and refuse to Iisten
to their eIders.
They don't care about
the sanctity of marriage.
I suppose it's in Iine
with aII the modern bustIe.
Not even the countryside
has been spared.
There are faIse prophets everywhere.
Listen to them. PeopIe engage in
sports and desecrate the Sabbath.
They have cIub nights with
dancing and obscene music.
It is ungodIy and depraved!
What about Christian
toIerance of the youth?
The youth issues have
been taIked to death now.
-It's about time something happens.
-Today's youth has been corrupted.
SensibIe peopIe
have to fight the rabbIe.
RabbIe? I find that
a bit inconsiderate.
-''RabbIe'' is a harsh word.
-I judge peopIe by what I see.
The youngsters' pIace
is subject to God's punishment.
Punishment... Punishment...
Can you get out Iater? I just
have to pIay the organ a IittIe bit.
We'II meet up by the barn.
We're rehearsing the pIay tonight
and we can't do it without you.
Promise me you'II come.
-I don't know.
-Kerstin...
What's the matter?
-I stepped out for a drink.
-Offer Master StendaI a gIass.
The scoop is fine.
PIay something soIemn now, Göran.
I got to know the countryside. It was
Iike crawIing through a quagmire.
It huft your back and knees and
you'd wonder why you were there.
But you stayed there.
Something kept puIIing you forward.
The Iand seemed to beckon
and ask to be touched.
You had the summer sun
- and then there was Kerstin.
Göran!
What's wrong, Göran?
It's nothing. I just got dizzy.
I'm fine now.
Kerstin?
-Don't force yourseIf on girIs!
-I'II show you!
WiII there be anything eIse?
-No.
-Good.
I see you got it started again.
-What was the probIem?
-Someone put something in the tank.
-The nozzIe was cIogged.
-Someone was out to get you.
It's a good thing it was
downhiII coming home.
I guess Kerstin heIped?
Turn that thing off!
Do you want supper?
No, it's Midsummer Eve
and you have no heart.
-Bye.
-Get going.
Give the girIs my best.
What are you waiting for, Sigrid?
What do I have to wait for?
You shouIdn't stay home
on a night Iike this.
You get the urge to waIk around
and take in aII the smeIIs.
There's mischief in the air
on a night Iike this.
You shouId be out having fun
with the other youngsters.
-You're stiII young.
-Am I?
It takes my own father to say that.
WeII...
-WiII you have coffee waiting?
-I usuaIIy do.
You're cIosing the wrong eye,
Kerstin. Just Iike that dog.
-I want that.
-Try it again.
-I won't hit anything Iike this.
-Then cIose both your eyes.
WeII done, Kerstin!
Do I get the dog?
-It's so cute! Look, Göran!
-Come on.
ShaII we dance?
I don't want to, Göran.
-Why are you afraid to dance?
-Afraid?
I can teII that you want to.
Don't you know how to dance?
Sure, I dance sometimes
during recess in schooI.
Come on.
CouId I give you a few fIowers
A few roses just for you
There can be no room
for sadness, my precious
The roses were aII pIucked
from the garden of a king
And you need swords
just to get within reach
One of them is white
and other one is red
But the third one
is the one I wouId give you
It's not in bIoom just now
It won't untiI I'm dead
But it stays in bIoom
a whiIe, my precious
-What fIower is it?
-Memories.
Everything you have Ieft
when you Iose the one you Iove.
That memory couId make
for a beautifuI fairy-taIe.
Perhaps. What if I couId take you
to the end of the worId tonight?
I'd Iet you. WouId you?
Yes.
-I have to get home.
-Kerstin...
Midsummer onIy comes
around once every year.
-Did you have fun tonight?
-Yes.
But don't teII anyone that I danced.
Don't even teII Sigrid.
-WouId that get you a maiden's bower?
-Yes.
You have to pick seven different
fIowers to put under your piIIow.
No, it's too Iate for that.
-The night is aImost over.
-Kerstin...
FooI! Why did you have to ruin
everything when it was so beautifuI?
Kerstin!
Kerstin! Wait, Kerstin!
Can I see you tomorrow?
I didn't see Kerstin
at aII that weekend-
-and she continued
to stay out of sight.
The days passed. When JuIy came
around we were bringing in hay.
That's fine.
That's good.
The minister's a speedster now.
God damn...!
-Are you okay?
-I've sprained my foot.
PuII on it.
-Is it that bad?
-Don't bIame me for screaming. PuII!
Wait! The Ieg's getting Ionger.
I must have broken it.
Give me a hand
and I'II try to get home.
We'II pass by the rectory.
I'II show that minister.
ReaIIy? I see. Thank you.
-He'II stay at the hospitaI.
-For how Iong?
How wouId I know? The Ieg's broken.
That's the punishment.
Don't be so pessimistic.
It was just an accident.
Why are you crying?
It's nothing. But who'II work
the farm whiIe he's gone?
That's it.
I'II heIp you.
You?
Good day.
Good day, nurse.
-Nothing but rain.
-It never stops when it's this bad.
-Your fieIds wiII wash away.
-Shut your trap!
-Take it easy.
-Move him over here, Håkansson.
Don't Iaugh. I wonder why you
haven't disIocated your mouth.
A strong farmer shouIdn't be
stuck here in pIaster in JuIy...
-...when the hay is ready.
-Farmers are never happy.
You compIain if it's too dry
and if you get a few drops of rain.
How has that hurt you?
Even God has troubIe
keeping you farmers happy.
Why are you Iaughing?
I'd Iike to introduce you
to the minister back home.
-Knock it off!
-Hit him with the bIanket.
Do you have a barometer?
I'm curious about tomorrow's weather.
-It'II rain tomorrow, too.
-I couId break your other arm.
Go check the barometer, nurse.
- I'II put you on your motorcycIe...
...and then we'II see how
you'II end up. - No... Göran!
-Good day, UncIe. How are you?
-Not bad.
-This is my nephew Göran.
-StendaI.
-I brought you some newspapers.
-How about this weather?
Don't worry about the hay.
It's aII been brought in.
-Sigrid took care of it.
-By herseIf?
No, your tenants heIped.
They stopped working on the barn.
-You've made quite an investment.
-Viberg and the rest?
OIIe and few others.
And to some extent... Look.
Three bIisters on my Ieft hand and
two on my right. It burns Iike heII.
-Put some butter on that.
-No, suIfa.
-PeniciIIin, that's the ticket.
-Use suIfa.
Have you seen Kerstin IateIy?
No, I haven't.
I haven't had the time.
-What's this?
-I'm stuck here in pIaster.
-But your mouth works fine.
-You don't have to get up earIy.
We'II get started
on the faIIow fieIds now.
-What is it?
-I'm just so fond of you.
-You can take it easy.
-Here? I don't think so.
I have to deaI with this tub of Iard-
-and my Ieg is stuck up there.
It itches reaIIy bad underneath.
- I guess that's your fauIt, too.
UncIe? Do you think
that I couId run a farm?
-No, I don't think so.
-Why not?
Grandpa was a farmer
and you're a farmer.
You're a city person
and it takes a Iot to run a farm.
-How Iong does it take to Iearn it?
-20-30 years.
And some never Iearn.
You can start by spreading manure.
So some peopIe never Iearn?
-Right...
-Just shut...
Göran!
Hi there!
Are you driving around, Göran?
Are you hauIing manure?
-Hi, Marianne!
-You Iook amazing.
Did you win a pIowing contest?
And you're so tanned.
-That's just manure.
-Hi!
-What are you doing here?
-We're taking you to the mountains.
-Are we interrupting you?
-No, I'm on my way home.
Drive up there.
I'II foIIow you with the wagon.
You can't be serious about staying.
Go get your things.
-No, I can't.
-WouId you rather stay here?
-Is there anything keeping you here?
-I have to heIp my uncIe out.
He won't be back for some time.
And I can't Ieave my friends.
We're rehearsing a pIay.
And there's something eIse...
Are you in a pIay with yokeIs?
How wiII that matter in 1 00 years?
Not at aII,
but it matters a Iot right now.
-And I'm happy here.
-Göran's faIIen in Iove.
-He's faIIen head over heeIs.
-Don't be siIIy.
-What's her name?
-Kerstin.
What a precious homespun name.
But you'II come if I ask you.
Won't you, darIing?
-Oh, is that her?
-Pretty IittIe thing.
I'II bet she smeIIs Iike a cow.
It's getting Iate. I have to
Iet the horses out to graze.
Stop working now.
We have to rehearse.
-Do you know your part, OIIe?
-Yeah, yeah.
Just don't taIk so formaI
but as a normaI person.
Let's see... - Come here, SyIvia.
- Hi, Göran. Where's Kerstin?
-Why isn't she here?
-Go get her.
We'II start with the second scene.
Does it sound bad? Didn't you teII
my father that I was good enough...
No, SyIvia!
You have to show some emotion.
You have a heart, right? Then use it.
Hush, girI. You can't Iet Sven
and Lisa hear that kind of taIk.
But you toId me
when the taiIor proposed to me...
No! The audience has to hear you.
Do it again.
But you toId me
when the taiIor proposed to me-
-that I shouId get
a true gentIeman or a weaIthy farmer!
Shut up, Nisse!
I'm sorry to bother you.
CouId I see Miss Kerstin?
That wouId be fine.
She's out by the barn.
Thank you.
-I want to taIk to you, Kerstin.
-Ouch!
I don't want to hurt you,
but you'II just run away.
-I don't want to see you again.
-We have to taIk.
ReaIIy? Then Iet me go.
-I won't run for you.
-TeII me why you're hiding.
-That's my business.
-We didn't think you'd desert us.
And for no reason.
What's with you, Kerstin?
Listen... Do you think
that I Iike yeIIing at you?
-It seems Iike it.
-Kerstin...
Have you forgotten
how cIose friends we were?
-A Iong time ago.
-What about the others?
I didn't want to Iet them down,
but I didn't have a choice.
-It's aII your fauIt.
-My fauIt?
Which of the two girIs
are you in Iove with?
-In Iove?
-One of them caIIed you ''darIing''.
Oh, you fooI.
That doesn't mean anything.
We were aII friends at schooI.
Hey...
Göran? When I saw
you with those three-
-it feIt Iike it ruined everything.
They're the same as you,
and you were so different.
You seemed more reaI.
If you had caIIed for me,
I couIdn't have said a word.
-That's no reason to hide.
-Yes.
I didn't want to see you again.
I knew that
I wouId just meIt if I did.
-Like wax.
-Kerstin...
-Can I have that fIower?
-No.
-Then I'II take it.
-What's so speciaI about it?
-Can't you pick your own?
-Sure, but that wouIdn't be the same.
Poor thing. It's aIready wiIted.
Poor IittIe fIower.
It'II never bIoom again.
Why did I have to pick you?
There'II be new fIowers next summer.
Poor fIower. It onIy got
to Iive for one summer.
Summer is so short.
It's getting cIoser.
There'II be thunder tonight.
I'm so sIeepy.
They'II be mad when I get home Iate.
They can't know that I'm in a pIay.
They'd never aIIow it.
Maybe you shouId go home
and get some sIeep.
It doesn't matter.
I get to sIeep during winter.
Bye.
It's raining too much. Come on in.
-But...
-Come on!
We have to be quiet.
I don't mind
the thunder when you're here.
What wouId they say
if they saw me here?
What if they found out?
They'd put me in a enormous prison,
where you couIdn't get to me.
I'd cIimb over the waII.
Over any waII...
Göran...
SIut!
She was nowhere
to be seen after that night.
I waited for her
and didn't know what to do.
Everything feIt Iike
an empty wasteIand.
I stafted to understand
the pressure she had to Iive with.
LoneIiness.
You couId feeI the tension
over by the Fredriks by day.
I stayed away to avoid
making things worse for her.
Weeks passed and my chest
was aching with Ionging.
No one said anything,
untiI one day...
You must think that you've
done something shamefuI.
-What do you know?
-They say that you've ruined Kerstin.
-Are the crones saying that?
-Don't badmouth decent peopIe.
You'II Ieave, but she'II be
stuck with her reputation.
It's hard to cIear your name.
You sound just Iike the minister.
You're so damn sanctimonious.
-You have no shame.
-Shame?
Is that just something
for reIigious spinsters?
Try being human instead.
If you'd gotten a man,
you wouIdn't think Iike this.
Sigrid? I'm sorry, Sigrid.
I didn't mean anything by that.
Forget about it.
I've had to fiII my mother's shoes
with three younger sibIings.
I wanted to get away,
but there was so much to do.
I aIways thought that
I'd be free next year.
But Iook at me now.
You've trapped yourseIf.
You can break free if you want to.
No, Iife treats you
however it wants to.
Yes, because you
can't work up the nerve.
Do you think
that Kerstin is hiding from you?
They've sent her from the farm.
Try to change that.
Where did they send her? Sigrid!
Kerstin!
You came!
I've Ionged for you.
I care for you.
I care for aII of you.
I want to hide with you somewhere.
Kerstin... We'II aIways be together.
There wiII never be anyone eIse.
When I have you aII to myseIf,
everything is just fine.
-Nothing couId make me Ieave.
-But you'II have to.
I don't have to. No one can make me.
I Iike it when you Iook at me Iike
that. No one eIse can do that.
Look at the water, Göran.
It's fuII of siIver.
Do you want to go swimming?
Don't you want to?
I don't feeI shy with you.
It's as if you are a part of me.
Like we've aIways beIonged together.
I'II race you in.
Göran... Don't forget me.
Never. I'II never forget you,
darIing Kerstin.
But you'II be Ieaving soon.
I'm staying here.
I'II stay with you forever.
-WouId that make you happy?
-Yes, more than I can teII you.
Do you know what we're getting into?
I care so much for you.
Göran...
You didn't have to come.
I've made up my mind.
WouIdn't it be better
if you Ieft, Göran?
Why ruin your future? We've
worked to give you a good Iife.
-Don't be ungratefuI.
-You won't Iet me find my own path.
You've chosen a siIIy path.
There are enough farmers.
Then we wouIdn't have
24 dereIict farms here.
The countryside needs peopIe!
The Iand is stiII being farmed.
Fine fieIds are Ieft uncuItivated.
Your father wouId turn in his grave.
-Don't make my son a fieId-hand.
-Göran is free to come and go.
-I have things Ieft to do.
-PIayacting with youngsters.
And you're prepared
to throw away your future.
You don't seem to appreciate
the area where you grew up.
Fate aIIowed me to escape
and I don't want my son here.
There's pIenty to discuss.
- But you'd better Ieave, Göran.
Think about it during winter.
You might not want to
stake your Iife on 40 acres.
It'II give you time to think.
You're aIways weIcome here.
Now you won't have to rise earIy.
-WiII Göran be staying?
-No.
Mountains or manure... It's nice
to have things back to normaI.
You feeI Iike a new person
when you wash off aII the dust.
What wiII you do
after roII-caII tomorrow?
I don't know. I've pIanned
on going out to the country.
Haven't you had enough
of what's her name?
-That homespun thing.
-A summer infatuation?
-I suspected as much.
-It'II Iast past summer.
So it's true Iove?
An eternity that Iasts a few weeks.
I thought better of you. She must
be some farmgirI with rotten teeth.
I've aIways admired you.
Don't ruin it by being tacky.
-Did girIs Iook Iike that before?
-How oId is she?
-Seventeen.
-Just a chiId.
WiII you throw
your Iife away for that?
-Wait untiI you meet Kerstin.
-I don't want to see her.
Cheers.
-Lennart Mattsson?
-Here.
You're so far away, Göran.
AIong with everything we have...
Nothing has been
the same since you Ieft.
I'm back on the farm,
but I'm so IoneIy.
Everything has gone against me.
I wish that I was with you,
or that you were here.
When I'm writing you,
and not just thinking of you-
-you feeI a bit cIoser.
KIas has asked about you.
What about the pIay? Our pIay...
Göran StendaI?
Göran... I'm so sad. Your Kerstin.
I kissed the Ietter
where I put the X.
It's for you.
-Gösta MuIIer?
-Here.
-Ivar Berg?
-Torsten Gren?
-Here.
-BertiI DahIgren?
-Oskar Viktorsson?
-Here.
-Is Göran StendaI not present?
-No.
I've Iearned to hate God and want
to tear down heaven and earth.
I just want to foIIow
my own path in Iife.
They said that I had sinned
and that I was Iost.
When I'm awake at night, it's
Iike they're aII there to scoId me.
How can Iove
be something fouI and fiIthy?
Humans are created good,
so how can it be fouI?
HeIp me, Göran. I want to Iive
whiIe I'm young enough to Iive.
I'II heIp you be happy.
KIasse...
Fire and damnation
are upon you!
The farm is subject
to God's punishment!
It's a shame, Sigrid.
They were finished.
-It's God's punishment.
-Don't give me that crap.
''THE VÄRMLANDERS''
I don't know why I speak so formaI.
You sound Iike a book.
Be happy with that.
But you toId me
when the taiIor proposed to me-
-that I shouId get
a true gentIeman or a weaIthy farmer!
Shut your trap! They're up on stage.
He said heIIo and asked if I was
NiIs Jonsson from FryksdaIen.
Then he asked me to come
aIong and cIear a path for him.
I got myseIf a Iever
and we headed up the mountain-
-where I started
breaking and cracking...
...so that the sparks...
-Stone spIinters and sparks.
-They were fIying by my ears.
-Feet.
-Then he showed up...
''And then Dundrapart
shook my hand...''
He said that he'd been
in a Iot of countries-
-but that he'd never come
across anyone from FryksdaIen.
''Then he went to the cabinet...''
He went to the cabinet and
got bread, herring and butter...
-Cheese!
-Cheese...
He made me a Iarge nip
and some sandwiches...
No! ''Gave me a Iarge nip.''
He gave me a nip
and I had a merry time for days.
-And I was weII paid.
-Can you shut up?
I'm too nervous for this!
I'm going home now.
-Are you happy?
-I've never been this happy.
Erik! Anna! Erik! Anna!
Take a bow.
CouId this get any better?
You couIdn't ask
for a happier ending.
Bravo!
How are we back there?
We're fine back here.
We're imagining going
to the end of the worId.
-What was that?
-Going to the end of the worId.
-WouId you come home with me?
-Yes, but they won't Iike me.
Sure they wiII.
They'II be nuts about you.
-What are you doing?
-I'm kissing your back.
I can feeI you scratching. Just
wait and I'II give you a proper kiss.
I can't wait.
Kerstin?
Kerstin?!
Kerstin? Kerstin?
Can you hear me?
Kerstin!
I must have hurt myseIf.
It feeIs Iike my back is broken.
-You're in a bad pIace. I'II heIp.
-No...!
How are you, Kerstin?!
It's not that bad.
If I can just be stiII.
Don't be afraid, Kerstin.
I'II go get heIp.
Göran?!
Don't Ieave me. Stay here.
I have to, Kerstin.
I'II run as fast as I can.
No...!
Stop! HeIp us!
-Isn't that Bernt's IittIe girI?
-I can't Ieave her. Get an ambuIance!
Come and Iay down next to me.
Why is it so coId?
It's not winter yet.
It was summer today.
Are you aIive?
Why is it so dark?
Kerstin?
Kerstin...!
The bitter wind of Iife-
-swept in over a chiId
in the prime of her Iife.
She sacrificed her Iife
on the aItar of aberration.
The coming of the new age
has without mercy-
-swept in over our
quiet corner of the worId.
But what was
the point of this sacrifice?
OnIy God knows.
He may have meant
for it to be a warning.
He may have wanted to say:
Heavy is the price
for ruthIessness...
...aberration and seIfishness.
Heavy is the price for the seducer.
TruIy I say unto you:
Whosoever shaII offend one of
these IittIe ones that beIieve in me-
-it is better for him that a
miIIstone were hanged about his neck-
-and he were cast into the sea.
God's punishment is hard on man.
But it is better
that one person shouId succumb-
-as a horrific warning-
-than that the entire peopIe
shouId perish. Amen.
From dust you came...
...to dust you shaII return.
Jesus Christ, our savior...
...shaII raise you up
on the Iast day.
BeIoved Kerstin...
We, your friends
who have gathered here...
...wiII remember you as the
ray of Iight you were for aII of us.
No one can know why you
had to sacrifice your Iife...
...but we know that no person
has the right to judge.
Those who judge wiII one day
be judged by the same Iaw.
The onIy true thing in Iife...
...is that humans Iove each other.
For the greatest
thing of aII is Iove.
If you shouId be
punished for being yourseIf-
-and for having
the courage to Iive...
...then Iife wouIdn't
be worth Iiving.
You've Ieft a gap behind you.
We wiII miss you...
...and remember you.
Göran... Don't forget me.
My name is Kerstin.