WOMAN OF THE DUNES
What a terrible place to live
Are you inspecting?
lnspecting?
ls there an inspection?
Well, if you're not inspecting...
l'm collecting insects
My speciality is these sand insects
Then you're not from the government
The government? No, l'm
a schoolteacher
A teacher... l see
One needs so many corroborating
certificates
ldentity card, usage permit,
contract...
...union card, letters of
recommendation...
...income and custody certificates,
even a pedigree certificate
Aren't there anymore certificates?
Have l overlooked any?
No more to certify?
Who knows the last certificate?
Certificates are limitless, it seems
There's no end to them
You criticised me, you said
I argued too much
But these are facts, not theories
What now, Professor?
Well, l'll come back again tomorrow
But the last bus has gone
Well, can't l stay somewhere?
ln this village?
Maybe along the main road somewhere
-You're walking?
-l'm in no hurry
You needn't go so far; l'll be glad
to help if l can
This is a poor village, but
if you're not fussy...
Really? That would give me more time
tomorrow
And l'd very much like to stay in
a house in such a village
Careful, there are deep holes
Aunt, here's a guest for you,
hurry up
l'm just coming
-Are you sure?
-lt's no trouble at all
-A rope ladder?
-lt must seem strange to you
lt's really quite an adventure
Mind how you go, don't look up
You'll get sand in your eyes
This way, please
Welcome, guest
Pleased to meet you
Dinner will be ready soon
Could l have a bath first?
Yes, but...
Never mind, then
The day after tomorrow
That's hopeless, l've only got
three days leave
l'm sorry
-Only one lamp?
-l'll soon be finished here
You miss electricity
Shellfish broth and bream -
local food is best
-Why the umbrella?
-To keep the sand off
-ls the roof damaged?
-No, it's the same with a new roof
Why, then?
lt's more pesky than a gribble
Gribble?
lt makes holes in wood
A termite
No, it's this big and scaly
That's pri'conus insularis
lsn't it red, with long antennae?
No, bronze, like a grain of rice
chalcophora japonica, perhaps
lf it gets a hold, it will rot away
a huge beam
-chalcophora japonica?
-No, the sand
How can sand...
Well, it draws water
lmpossible. Sand is a naturally dry
substance
Still, it rots things
Don't talk rubbish.
Use your common sense
A desert is a desert because it's dry
Have you ever heard of a damp desert?
Some tea, please
Still, it does rot things
lf you leave sand on clogs,
they rot within a month
What nonsense
Wood rots, and so does sand
The roof of a buried house became
soil rich enough to grow cucumbers
Well, never mind
-Enough?
-Yes, thank you
That was good
lt is serious
When the wind blows, one or two feet
of sand drift in a night
Even the bedding is damp
No others?
-No family?
-No, l'm alone
There was a storm. The sand
swallowed my husband and daughter
Swallowed?
lt roared down like a waterfall.
So they went out
To rescue the chicken house and...
They were buried?
Such a wind
That's terrible... really terrible
lt's the sand
Doing research?
Have you seen this insect here?
lt's called the blister-beetle
l'm collecting the genus on this trip;
it has many species
My name will be in the encyclopaedia
if l find a new one
My only talent is to hold
insects' tails
The tools for the helper
-So there is someone else
-You do say nice things
Didn't he talk about a helper?
He meant you
-Me? Why me?
-lt's all right, take no notice
Some misunderstanding?
-Do you need the lamp?
-Well, l'd rather have it
,
Never mind, l'm used to the work
anyway
This is filthy
No
-Can l help?
-lt's not right on the first day
What do you mean, ''first day''?
l'm only staying tonight
You always clear sand at night?
lt's easier when the sand is damp
The basket
What a job they have
ln our village, the Native Place
spirit is strong
What spirit?
Love of One's Native Place
l see. That's fine
-When do you stop?
-At dawn
The sand doesn't wait for us
What a ruin
That's funny, the ladder's gone
Madam... please get up
Excuse me, but where's the ladder?
It's disappeared
l must leave now; l've only
three days leave
lt was a rope ladder
lt can't be put up from here
You were in league with them
l'm sorry
What do you mean, ''sorry''?
What do you mean?
l'm sorry
That means nothing. l have to make
the most of my time
Don't you understand yet?
What is there to understand?
But, really, life here is too hard
for a woman alone
What's that to do with me?
The winds are coming;
there'll be sandstorms
l'm your prisoner?
l'm sorry
Listen, l'm not a tramp, you know
l've got a respectable job,
a registered address
When the police find me, you'll be
charged with illegal confinement
The sand will bury the house,
if we don't clear it
Then let it. Why involve me?
The next house will be in danger
if this is buried
So it's buried. You, too
Why do you slave to cling to such
a place? Are you insane?
Why be faithful to the villagers?
l've no sympathy for such
old, ''noble'' legends
lf the village is afraid of
sand erosion, plant trees
They proved it's much cheaper this way
Call someone who's in authority here.
l can tell him a few things
Come on. How do you contact
people outside?
Bang on a tin can?
Say something
At least l'm not going against nature...
...l'm not trying to make
a gentle slope steep
Guest, are you awake?
How do you feel?
Not too bad
l'll wipe your back
That hurts, l tell you
Shall l rub it?
lt's no joke. My spine may be broken
lf you're so kind, why not call
a doctor?
ls my underwear dry?
lt's better not to wear underwear
when you're asleep
You'll get sand rash
Sand draws water
Don't make a sound
You'll have to put up with it.
Now l've trapped you
lt's your own fault
A human being is not a dog
lt's not the same as chaining up
a dog
What are you doing?
Still in bed, you two?
l won't let go until you pull this up
She's roped up indoors. Pull this up
if you want to save her
No. They haven't won yet
The battle has just begun. It's them
who are going to be in trouble
Why should I be nervous?
lt's me who's pinning them down,
after all
This is real/y a good e Kperi'ence
When I get home I might write
a story about all this
Only cheap sake
So they want me to drink to my
success; how considerate
There's been a coup d'état.
It seems no one can stand still
A cigarette?
No, they make your throat dry
-Water?
-Not yet
Just ask
l'm not doing this out of
personal spite
Are you in pain?
You must be careful. That ration
comes only once a week
Ration?
Only where there are men.
The village council pays for it
Have other men been trapped like this?
l'm only curious
We're very short of hands, you see
What men?
Well, about last autumn there was
the picture postcard man
They say he was a salesman for
people who make them
Any others?
Since the beginning of the year...
...a student on some sort of survey
l hear he's with a neighbour
l suppose he hasn't a ladder, either
Our young people won't stay here
They get more money in the cities
After all, they've got cinemas
and restaurants there
This is ridiculous
What's the matter?
Sorry, but will you please scratch
my right ear?
Like this?
l'm sorry, but will you give me
some water
Some water. l beg you
Not much left; when's the ration?
That's enough
lt's all your own fault
The cords
Want them off?
l don't pity you, but l just can't
stand your misery
But there's one condition. you won't
shovel the sand, do you promise?
l promise. l'll promise anything
lf l suffer, you'll suffer,
just remember that
Where to?
What can we do?
We haven't moved the sand;
we've left it for two nights
What can we do about water?
Why don't you help a little?
l was kind enough to untie you
Well, then, we must work
Stop joking
Who's got the right to force us
into a deal like that?
There's such a thing as the
right man for the right job
l'm a teacher and something of
a scholar
Surely they can think of a
better way to put me to use
For example, we could...
...think of some way to exploit
the sand's appeal
After all, that's what brought me
all the way here
l'm serious
That's probably why that postcard
salesman came, too
You advertise it and develop it...
...as a new tourist area
But for a tourist area you need
a hot spring
Well, that was just an idea, of course
The sand might be good for
some kind of crop
The Young People's Association
grows a few things
Things like peanuts and tulips
They said the tulip bulbs...
...were so big they showed them at
an agricultural fair in Tokyo
That's enough!
A monkey could learn such work
A monkey? Could it?
lt's bad for you
My breath's on fire
lt's useless
This sand
lt could swallow up a city,
a country even
Did you know that?
A Roman town called Sabrata...
and a town in The Rubiyat...
...were buried by tiny particles
one-eighth of a millimetre across
You can't fight it. It's hopeless
Don't!
l'll make a ladder
Shall l brush off the sand?
But the women in Tokyo,
aren't they prettier?
Ridiculous!
l'll do it
Goddam it!
My blood will rot
What a dirty trick
What must l do? Please do something!
My blood will rot!
Well, if we begin to work...
All right, l'm beaten.
l'll let them win!
Guest, there's water.
They're sending water
Guest, it's easier if you hold
the shovel lower down
Use your left hand; keep a balance
l'm tired
Rest, you're not used to this yet
All my muscles are aching.
l'm exhausted
You can't help it, with new work
Will l get used to it?
Oh, yes
l don't understand. Don't you
find this pointless?
Are you living to clear sand,
or clearing sand to live?
Of course, this place isn't as
interesting as Tokyo...
l'm not talking about Tokyo
How can you stand being shut in
like this?
But it's my home
Then assert your rights
l'm just going to wait for help
Help?
Of course. Someone will go to my room
before long
They'll find a book with
the pages left open
Money in my suit pockets
They'll become suspicious
But l suppose this is your life
But, you see, the bones
are buried here, too
My husband and daughter
We'll find them
Then you can leave. l'll help you
You know how to make them
drop the ladder down
What is there special for me
to do outside?
You can walk
Walk?
That's right. It's wonderful
to walk where you like
lsn't it tiring to walk
without doing anything?
Shut up! Even a chained dog
goes mad
Are you human?
lf there were no sand
no one would bother about me
That's true. For you, too
-Look, here's one
-Stop it!
This is what l came out here
Iooking for
A kind of tiger-beetle
-Got any scissors?
-Scissors?
l just want to cut my whiskers
l have some somewhere
They're not very sharp
-They're pretty rusty
-The sand does it
They don't work.
They won't close properly
We'll ask for a razor when
they bring the ration
See? The sand in my beard
makes it all scratchy
That sand just makes a mess
of everything
-Go ahead!
-Thank you
-What's your man doing?
-He's got stomach-ache
Have you been at it too much?
-A bath?
-No, l'm very tired today
-l'd like one
-Not when you're ill
l'm very sweaty. l just can't
get to sleep at all
l'll boil water, then
-l'll help
-No, l'll do it
-What are you thinking about?
-Nothing much
Let's take a photograph of you
l've never...
Don't fuss
-You want to go home
-Why?
l think you'd like a radio
-You could hear about the world
-Nonsense!
But you could hear about everything,
about Tokyo
l only collected insects because of
useless things
One's name in an encyclopaedia, that's
worth more than everyday stupidities
But a radio would take your mind
off things
l know, let's drink the sake
But you're ill
-To help sleep
-l'm sleepy enough without it
Oh, come on
Really, l can't
Come on, it's all right
-lt's boiling...
-First a drink
You're a terrible man
Right down
That's better
You are cruel, when l'm so tired
Help! Someone help me!
Grab this
l'm sorry. Please pull me out
No, it's not like pulling up a carrot
We'll save you. Just hold that board
lt's a good thing we came along
This is ''Salty Bean Paste''.
Even dogs won't come near it
l wonder how many have fallen in
Sometimes strangers hike here
We might dig up lots of
valuable things
Two or three cameras, at least
-Be quiet
-l'm sorry
Shall l make some tea?
What's the time?
l don't know... about 8.30...
l failed
Yes
Complete and utter failure
Have you...
...a wife?
ln Tokyo
That's none of your business
But it's too bad
lf l'd succeeded, l was going to buy
a radio and send it to you
-A radio?
-You wanted one...
No. You don't have to do that
l can do piecework and buy one here
l failed
Shall l dry you?
l should have known the geography
But they'll be looking for me
There will be my friends,
the co-operative...
...the Board of Education
and the PTA
They won't leave me to my fate
l'll wash you
What's that?
Hope. A crow trap
l put bait here...
...and then the crow gets sucked down
with the sand
But crows are crafty
Not when they're hungry
But why is it hope?
Hope because...
l'll tie a message to the crow's leg,
asking for help
lt hasn't come yet. It's almost
three months now
-What hasn't?
-Help
Maybe they thought you ran away
Ran away?
That you hated your job
lmpossible
l left my bank book. l left
a book open on my desk
My whole room is shouting for help
What's there?
-Where?
-ln Tokyo
Why not go and see?
lt's too much
Here's the ration
Wait a moment
Will you let me out a little,
just half an hour a day?
l want to see the sea.
l won't run away
Twenty minutes... ten minutes...
l've been good. It's three months
now... l'll go mad
l'll discuss it with the village
council
l don't mind if there's a guard
You're diligent
l'll soon earn 1,000 yen
That's enough
l don't want to die in a ditch
What's a radio worth in this place?
They're not your friends.
It's everyone for himself
You're being exploited
You wag your tail, but just you wait
We'll be deserted, left to ourselves
No, because of the sand
Sand? What use is it?
Nothing but trouble
We sell it. To builders
lt's against the law to use
such salt sand
lt's a secret. We sell it half price
But the buildings would soon collapse
That's not my business
Well, that's not your business.
Yes, that's true
But somebody must profit by it.
Why help them?
lt's a co-operative
People like me are treated very well
l'll sieve them
lt's like building a house on water,
ignoring the existence of boats
You can't get the idea of a house
out of your head
Haven't you been wanting to go home,
too?
Even if it's false...
...as long as there's hope...
...something different may happen
tomorrow
l'm always afraid
ln the morning, when l go to sleep...
...l'm afraid of being alone again
when l wake up
l'm afraid, really afraid...
Here, put them in this
What now? The basket already?
l hear you want to see the sea
Will you let me?
lt's not out of the question
l beg you. Just half an hour a day,
l won't escape
Then let us see you doing ''it''.
The two of you
Outdoors, where we can all watch you
''lt''?
What men and women do together. ''it''
We all discussed your request.
We all agreed what you must do
What now?
lt's ridiculous
But it's a chance, at least
lgnore them
We could, that's one way, but
we needn't take it seriously
What? Are you a sex maniac?
You live like a sow, anyway
Pretending will do
But how?
Funny...
There hasn't been a drop of rain
for three weeks
Capillary action
That's it
Maybe l can develop a water supply
Surface evaporation probably
draws up water
The sand is a pump
l'm living on a suction pump
Perhaps I can make a really
ecient reservoir
lt's awful. l'm choking
lt's nearly December
Still trying?
l'll catch a crow easily
when food is scarce
Really, men are...
l want to be the trapper for once
We can hear the weather forecast
when we get the radio
l'm afraid
l'll go and bury this
Until tomorrow
ls anyone there?
l don't want to
-What's wrong?
-A pain
A child?
-Since when?
-Since October
lt hurts? Do you feel sick?
That's it, it's probably a miscarriage
You know?
He used to shoe horses for a vet
Get a doctor
He'll be too late
Doctors today...
Go and get the van
l'm afraid. Has the wind dropped?
Almost died down
-What now?
-Wrap her up
A radio
Only now...
Want to hear it?
Want it?
Tuck it in the bedding
Have you got another board?
Take one from the bench outside
The one underneath
What did you say?
Nothing... Iater
l don't want to...
l needn't run off yet
My return ticket's open. I can
use it whenever i like
Anyway, there's my reservoir
experiment, it's very exciting
The villagers must be the first
to know of it
l'll tell them today or tomorrow
As for escaping...
...l'll think about that afterwards
Judgement : Court of Family Affairs
Concerning the disappearance of
Junpei Niki, born 7th March, 1926
The Court acknowledges his absence
for seven years, since August, 1956
The verdict of the Court
is as follows.
Junpei Niki is adjudged to be
a missing person
Certined 5th October, 1963.
Judge of Domestic Relations