He's a civil servant.
He works for the Government.
You're not taking my kids.
Hope never dies!
We go get Al and the others,
we head for the coast.
I close my eyes and I see...
What?
.. what might happen.
I wish that...
What?
Who we were before,
all the things we did...
All that matters...
is who we are now.
Do you think they're OK in the back?
Yeah.
What do you think they're doing?
They're... probably talking.
Hmm. We could've stopped.
Speak for yourself.
I meant the truck.
Well, they'd get a big surprise.
Not that big.
Excuse me?
They've guessed.
No way.
Trust me.
Our secret is safe.
Come on.
Is she OK?
Yeah. We stopped to help.
What about the driver?
He's all right. He's alive.
We'll look after him.
You OK?
Let her go.
Poke your nose in?
Yeah? Yeah?
Get down! On your knees!
On your knees!
Hands on your head!
What have you got?
Keep hold of her.
Let me check it out.
What are you looking at?
Hey, come and see this!
What is it?
Argh!
Len? Lenny?!
Get in there.
What's in there? Huh?
Give me your knife.
What's going on?
Argh!
Are you all right?
Are you OK?
They drove us off the road.
We were going back home.
Home? The valley...
That's where we live now.
There are 16 of us
and we're working the land.
How far is it?
About 20 miles.
OK. We'll take you home.
Come on.
Come on, let's go.
Do all four tyres.
Stop 'em going anywhere.
It's just about two miles
down the road.
Well, we said we'd take you.
You've got an injured man. We
should leave the lorry here, though.
We don't want to mark the turning.
It's OK. I'll drive it on a bit. There's
barely a mile of fuel in there, anyway.
Come on.
We, er... We don't have
vehicles in the valley.
I'll go back for the others.
Hmm.
This is where we live.
Pinch me.
Did we have an accident? Cos I think
I have died and gone to heaven.
Come on.
It's so beautiful.
Judy!
Hey, Clare.
You go for seeds
and come back with eight people.
You all right, Mark? I'm fine.
I had to put in a couple of
stitches. You should take it easy.
We were attacked.
We weren't followed.
These people,
they've saved our lives.
Thank you.
Do you keep any weapons here?
What for?
To defend yourselves.
We don't need to.
No-one's going to invade.
No-one can find us.
We did. Oh, don't worry.
We're not invading you.
You must stay a bit, though, eh?
Stay the night.
Yeah, there's plenty of room
and we're having a party later.
Really? Six months together.
That'll be great, thanks.
Please celebrate with us. It's
the least we can do. Follow me.
She sews. Can she cook, too?
The perfect woman.
We're heading for the coast.
Some wine?
No, thanks... Yeah, settle down.
Like you've done here.
Make a new start.
Thank you.
I hope you're not going to
run out of wine.
How much are you going to drink?
I didn't mean tonight.
No. We will run out of this stuff,
but we're making our own now.
We don't want to have to forage.
Well, you saw what happened
out there today.
Hey, there's a girl here
that's about your age. Where's Izzy?
Oh, Izzy? That sounds nice.
Oh, they've got a cold up there,
early night.
Just cos you're in love doesn't mean
everyone else has to be!
Do you want to say something?
No, you can.
Er, I...
Me and, um... Sarah are...
We know, we know.
We're very, very happy for you.
Al and Sarah.
Cheers.
It's the closest we're going to get
to a wedding.
Listen, I was thinking,
before we make this new start,
I'd like to go home... one more time.
Well, you can.
It would take a day.
Well, what's a day?
Everyone seems very happy here.
Yeah.
So, yeah, it'd be good.
Good. I'll go with you.
In case I get lost, yeah? Yeah.
Come on!
# All those people
# Gathered round
# Flocked to view that lovely sight
# All the maidens came to town
# They waved her out into the night
# Her lonely heart setting free... #
Are you sure you're
a fully qualified doctor?
You seem too young...
.. and glamorous.
You can talk. Me?
Yeah. You're running
this community...
No, I'm not, it's a co-operative.
You calling me glamorous?
Yeah.
I'm glad you came.
You should get back to your friends.
Yeah.
Night. Goodnight.
What are you doing?
What do you mean?
What are you doing? Nothing.
Don't lie to me.
I was saying goodnight.
What are you doing? Stalking me?
Don't do that. Do what?
Walk off when I'm talking to you.
SHE SIGHS
Come 'ere!
Ow!
You like her, don't you?
Yeah, I like her.
Like that.
Like what?
You know what I'm talking about.
No, I don't know!
You're hardly Mr Articulate, are you?
What are you talking about?
I meet someone, I get on with them,
and you go ballistic.
You think this is ballistic?
Oh, you can go further, can you?
Are you threatening me?
Night, Tom.
The happy couple.
You should get some sleep, Tom.
It's been a long day.
She'll dump you, pal,
soon as she gets a better offer.
No. You're wrong.
You can't change.
Goodnight. Goodnight.
I'm going with Greg in the morning.
There's something he needs to do.
Sure.
And you are wrong, you know.
You can change.
You are what you are.
Oh. So it's hopeless?
Well done.
And you'll die alone?
A killer and a thief.
Put it on my gravestone. No.
Feels blessed, this place.
Hi. You going for a walk?
Yeah, it's a beautiful day.
Yeah. Do you want a bike?
Great! Thanks.
If you head up the valley, will you look
in at the farm where the chickens are,
see if they need anything? Sure.
And bring us back a few eggs.
So this was your life?
Mmm.
Frozen...
Mind you, it froze
months before the virus hit.
When she left?
Mmm.
With them.
I just need to go upstairs
for a second.
OK, I'll wait here.
You OK?
Yeah.
Just one more thing.
It's been playing on my mind.
Have a look at this.
"Hope never dies. "
Yeah, and what are these numbers?
Who's it from?
I don't know. It was weird. It came
by courier just before the virus hit.
They're co-ordinates.
I don't know
why I didn't see that before.
Greg, does this,
um, really matter now?
I don't know. It might.
Yeah. South... It's here!
It's an airfield.
It's only an hour or so away.
You want to go there? Mmm.
It's probably just some marketing
thing. Yeah? Selling what?
I don't know.
I need to find out.
OK.
Hello?
Anyone here?
Oh, my God.
You shouldn't be here!
You're ill...
Keep away from me.
The chickens died yesterday.
Izzy always looked after 'em.
She died in the night.
Virus.
Took her so fast.
Now you'll get it.
Oh, no, don't worry.
I've been exposed
loads of times before.
I'm immune.
So were we.
And our families all died.
We survived, like you.
This is different.
Our immunity... no longer applies.
I'll go and get your friends.
You can't!
You might infect them.
This has to be contained.
What's your name?
Sarah.
Sarah...
.. was my daughter's name.
It's... It's going to be OK.
I'll stay
and we'll get through this together.
We'll help each other.
Do you have water here?
Kitchen.
I'll get some.
Where are we going?
Good question.
Sorry. I said, good question.
I know. I said, sorry.
Watching you with her last night...
you looked so...
I don't know.
Very beautiful.
And I was thinking...
"Why does she look so beautiful?"
It's because you looked happy.
It made me want to... Kill me?
I love you.
Tom...
I'm...
really... flattered...
Flattered?
You mean a lot to me.
A lot...
And I owe you so much.
I'd be dead if you hadn't...
But last night,
with Judy...
You're right.
I was attracted to her.
I felt that spark.
But there is something
between you and me,
I'm not denying that,
and, yeah, we could have sex,
but that would make it worse,
for both of us,
because we are so different.
Yeah.
Men and women.
You and me.
I can change, if you can.
Ohh.
You're an angel.
Hi. Hi.
You OK?
Man trouble.
Ah.
Morning! You seen Sarah?
Yeah. She went for a bike ride.
To the end farm.
Right.
Go up there, it's a nice walk.
It's only a mile or so.
Cheers.
I... I think I'll go with them.
Sure.
Stay where you are!
Stop!
OK. Anya, the people here,
they're sick.
That girl, Izzy, she died last night
but the chickens, they died first.
The man and the woman here,
they're really sick...
OK, Sarah. It's OK. It's all right,
don't worry about it. Al, wait.
Sarah, what are the symptoms?
Well, like the virus, lumps
under the arm, nausea, fever...
But they were exposed to it before,
in the beginning, like the rest of us?
Yeah.
And you've been in the house?
In the same room?
How close?
Close.
Right. They say I have to stay.
No. No way!
It's possible the virus has mutated.
Whatever it is,
it has to be contained.
You have to wait it out,
in quarantine.
You understand?
How are you feeling?
I don't know. OK.
Temperature?
I don't think so.
Good.
Good, good.
So let's go now, while we still can.
Don't worry, it'll be all right.
Yeah. Um... keep your fluids up.
Do you need any food or water?
No, there's enough here.
Well, um,
I'm going to go back with Naj.
Let everyone know what's happening.
OK?
Let's go.
Come on, together. That way.
Tempting...
But I think I better stay.
And, you know,
I'm going to be all right.
In a few days, well,
you'll be fighting me off.
Can't get rid of me that easily.
Better late than never.
This the right place?
Abby...
Give us a hand.
What are you looking for?
I don't know.
Greg, more postcards.
What does it mean?
It could just have been
a corporate day out, or something.
It'll be OK, Naj.
How do you know?
You don't know that!
What are we going to do?
We're going to keep calm.
Izzy died!
We know that, Mark,
just give us a second, OK?
Did she have any
underlying conditions?
Possibly.
But none that you are aware of?
No.
OK. Everyone, listen.
Anya, do you want to...?
Did anyone have any contact
with them yesterday?
Don't be shy.
No-one went to the end farm?
The day before?
I spoke to Ted outside for a minute.
But he said not to come close because
they were coming down with a cold.
OK.
Well, hopefully,
it's been contained.
They just have to stay
in quarantine.
We can't just leave them there.
We're not leaving them, Clare.
But listen, we cannot go in there.
We have to just wait
and just pray that they'll survive.
It's the second wave.
It's come to kill off everyone
who survived the first.
We're all going to die.
Hey, did you listen?
We're containing it.
We need to keep calm
and carry on as normally as possible.
All right?
Let's eat.
Anything I can do?
Um...
No, I don't think so.
You got it all under control?
What is your problem? What?
Don't.
Don't?! You telling her, don't?
Don't what? Provoke him?
I'm not scared of you.
Are you scared of me?
There's nothing else here.
Oh!
I'm ready.
Mr Stevens.
You've come to take me away.
You're the pilot.
You're the pilot?
Um...
Well, it's one of you.
It isn't me. I can't fly.
Listen, it's OK...
If I could fly, I'd have flown.
Sorry...
Where are we going? We're...
No, no, don't tell me. You can't tell
me, can you? No, of course you can't.
Classified.
Mr Stevens?
Been waiting long?
Um...
My fault. I missed the flight.
Or flights.
Lot of people.
Were there two?
Or one?
Or three?
Um...
Pretends he doesn't know.
He's very good, isn't he?
You're very good. Better than me.
Misread the email.
What email?
The time! The departure time.
So I was late.
Missed the flight.
Yeah, the... the flight.
So did they. Missed their flight.
The unlucky eleven.
So they didn't hang around?
They died.
I buried them.
OK, so you're immune. That's good.
Do you know who else was
on the flight?
The chosen few. The saved.
Is this a religious thing?
Who needs religion?
We've got science.
What's...? What connects the people?
Who chose them? Who chose you?
Greg... Tell us. We'll take you.
I don't know.
It's OK, it's OK. Come on.
Oh, come on. It's OK, Mr Stevens.
Please...
Look... Look, you need to sit down.
OK. And we'll get you
something to eat, OK?
Has she come out again?
I brought you some food.
Thanks.
You don't want it?
No, I'm not that hungry.
The thing is... you have to
keep your strength up.
Good point.
Thanks.
You eaten?
A bit.
Good.
You want a drink?
No, it's OK.
Thank you for the food.
You're welcome.
We're going to sleep here.
And take me in the morning.
Cos you don't want to
fly in the dark, do you?
No.
The lucky ones...
that caught their flights.
There are hundreds.
We'll meet them.
On the other side.
OK, I think we should all get some rest.
See you in the morning, Mr Stevens.
My last night.
Time to wake up.
Morning.
You know who I am?
Yeah.
I'm Mr Stevens.
And you haven't come for me,
have you?
Hang on. I've hung on.
Too long.
He didn't send you, did he?
Who?
Who didn't send us?
I wish you knew.
No!
She's gone.
Sorry.
How are you feeling?
Fine.
Me too.
Laura was, um...
She had asthma.
You're made of sterner stuff.
Do you believe him?
That people got away?
Natalie's new partner
worked with the Government.
Maybe she got me on the list
to get a postcard, to get away.
But no email?
Maybe something
went wrong with that.
So she could've escaped with...
with your kids?
They might be alive somewhere.
I'm kidding myself.
Hope never dies...
until it kills you.
Let's get back to reality.
Morning.
Morning. Hi.
How are you?
Well, thanks.
How are the others?
Laura died. Sorry.
She had other things wrong with her,
you know?
Fight it, Sarah!
I will, Naj, I will. Don't worry.
Come on, let's go back to the barn
and get some breakfast.
Give them some privacy.
See you soon, Sarah.
I'm going to get off, mate,
if that's OK with you.
You're not going to do
anything stupid, are you?
I won't let him.
We should make some plans.
Er...?
For the future.
Right. Unless you don't want
to be pinned down?
No, no, no.
Yes... Yes, pin me down.
OK.
House or flat?
A flat, definitely.
Cool new apartment building.
Wrong. House. Older the better.
Older the better? You're joking?
With a garden.
With a pool? No pool...
With wildflowers and a plum tree.
You'll get wasps.
Don't be negative.
I'm not being negative.
You're the one who keeps saying no
to everything I suggest.
Only the bad ideas.
Yeah, try crying.
Good strategy.
I still won't give in.
If I knew you were so, um...
So what?
You'd have gone with someone else?
Too late. You're stuck with me now.
To the bitter end.
So, kids. How many?
Two?
Three.
Boys?
First.
Um... we've made a good start, but...
.. I need to go inside now.
I was dreaming about Peter.
I'm sorry.
That was me, talking about kids.
It was nice to see him.
It's so peaceful.
Maybe we should stay here for ever.
Where is everyone?
Hi. Hi, there.
Hey.
What's going on?
Sit down, Abby.
Where's Al?
He's all right. But...
Where's Sarah?
They're all dead?
Yeah.
Cos they're not as tough as you.
You think I'm tough?
I think you're perfect.
Thank you.
For making me glad to be alive.
I have to go and lie down now.
I need you
to do two things for me.
I need you to look after Najid.
And leave me... alone.
Al!
Just stay out of it!
It's none of your business!
Didn't you hear what she was saying?
She doesn't want you to die.
You could have saved her!
There's no cure!
No cure...
Tom.
Are you OK?
Yeah.
The virus is spreading
through the birds.
We'll all get it, won't we,
sooner or later?
There's so little time.
It was his own fault,
for going soft on her.
Your face is cut.
It's all right.
Let me look at it.
Why now?
Now is all there is.
Want an apple?
No, thanks.
You've been sitting there all day.
You should eat something.
Why?
All right.
I'll just...
I wish I'd gone in instead of Sarah.
I might have got it and survived.
Hi, Tom.
You all right?
Yeah.
I was just thinking.
We need a plan.
Abby?
I think we should wait one more day.
Let the virus burn itself out.
Al.
I'm going to go in there now.
It's less of a risk for me.
She looked... at peace.
Beautiful.
To every thing there is a season
and a time
To every purpose under the heaven
A time to be born and a time to die
A time to kill and a time to heal
A time to mourn and a time to dance
A time to embrace and a time
to refrain from embracing
A time to get and a time to lose.
Thanks to Sarah and her courage
and self-sacrifice,
this outbreak's been contained.
But it's only a matter of time
before it surfaces again
and kills more of us...
unless we can find a way to
fight it.
So, I'm going back to the lab,
but this time on my own terms.
They'll have to release all the
people that they've locked up.
Then I'll co-operate and let them do
whatever's necessary
to find the vaccine
they've been looking for.
When do you want to do it?
Now. There's no time to lose.
And I'll go alone.
No, you won't.
You're outvoted, Abby.
Al?
Let's stick together.
The lorry's parked up on the road,
about a mile from the turning.
Just take what you want from it.
Good luck.
See you.
Look after her. Bye. Bye.
See you soon. Good luck.
Whitaker, is that his name?
Yeah.
If he doesn't agree to your terms,
what's to stop him and his guards
taking you by force?
Do you regret it?
No.
Do you?
Is that it?
Yeah.
It's open.
Something's happened.
Power's still on.
Don't.
What's in there?
The people they experimented on.
Come on.
The scientists.
The virus finally
broke through their defences.
Let's get out of here.
Peter!
Abby?!
Where did they go?
Are you sure it was Peter?
I know my own son.
Where's her kid?
Abby...
We're not animals.
Why are you doing all this to me?
I was a friend of your mother's.
I don't care what you do to him,
just get me my son.
Like I said,
you're going to tell me.
We have to test it again.
I'll do it.
.. I'll see you on the other side.
I have the boy.
Well, then, we must get you out.
I'll prepare an evacuation team.
Do it! Do it!
Stop!
Uploaded by Lauta