[ Tires Screeching,
Horn Honking ]
[ Man ] Hey, what the hell you doin'?
Get off the road!
- [ Thunder Continues ]
- [ Horn Honking ]
[ Honking Continues ]
Move!
[ Laughing ]
What's so funny?
It's like pettin' a gorilla.
Well--
Was your father this hairy?
No, l, uh, I got it
from my mother.
I mean, I mean,
from my mother's side of the family.
That's where you, um,
inherit hair patterns.
- My uncle's bald.
- On your mother's side?
Mm-hmm.
Well, um, I guess I'm talking
about usual patterns.
- Hmm.
- There's always exceptions.
- That's--
- [ Sighs ]
- That's the way these things... work.
- [ Sighing ]
Shouldn't you go
to the hospital?
No, I'm fine.
You don't look fine.
You worry about me, don't you?
You think this is normal?
- What?
- What we do.
What do we do?
[ Sighs ]
That's just it.
We don't speak about it.
You know that feeling
you get sometimes, Tracey...
that you didn't ask to be
brought into the world?
Yeah.
Well, then who did?
What?
If you think that
you didn't ask...
to be brought
into the world...
then who did?
[ Sighs ]
[ Men Talking,
Thunder Rumbling ]
All I'm saying is nobody asked you if
you wanted to be brought into the world.
You just ended up getting here.
[ Sighs ]
So the question is,
now that you're here...
who's asking you to stay?
[ Sighs ]
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
Look, are you sure
you're gonna be okay?
Yes.
Good night.
[ Footsteps Departing ]
- He touched you?
- He didn't want to.
- What do you mean?
- I know him.
- We all know him.
He's crazy about you.
- Not like that.
Why didn't you get one of the boys
to handle this, Eric?
Because I didn't think of it.
I just saw him touch her, and--
Why didn't you
ask him to leave?
- Because he wouldn't have listened.
- How do you know that?
Because he's in his own world,
the ass-wipe.
[ Zoe ] I don't know
where you're both coming from.
You are telling me that he touched you,
but he really didn't.
And you're saying that you overreacted,
but you didn't have a choice?
- I didn't.
- Why not?
Why not?
Because he touched you.
[ Sighs ]
Okay.
All I'm concerned about
is if he makes a case...
I have to know
what happened.
We told you
what happened, Zoe.
And that is
what happened?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Is that it?
[ Phone Rings ]
[ Answering Machine ]
Hi. This is Thomas.
I am not in at the present time,
but I am in town.
Please leave a message
following the beep.
[ Machine Beeps ]
[ Opera Date ]
Good morning.
You're probably not up yet,
so you haven't seen what I've done.
I'm a customs officer
at the airport.
Actually, I-I saw you the other day when
you were having your bags inspected.
I know-- I know how you probably
smuggled those eggs in.
There's a special unit at work.
I-I think they give them
to the zoo or something.
They asked me where I got them.
I had to lie.
Where are they?
- I took them.
- Where?
- I'd like to see you again.
- Oh, no.
[ Thomas ] Uh, no, they're in
the country now. Uh, they're
definitely in the country.
It's just I don't have them,
uh, with me presently, but it
doesn't mean I can't get them.
- And if you can give me, like,
uh, just, uh, um, a couple--
- [ Bird Squawking ]
- Good morning.
- Hi. Uh, and, uh, I'm here. Okay.
So I'll call--
I'll talk to you later. Bye.
You look like you're
in worse shape than I am.
- [ Bird Squawks ]
- Uh... what happened to you?
Oh, I fell down
some stairs and--
- Are you okay?
- Well, do I look okay?
- Uh, no, not really.
- Well, I'm-I'm better than I look.
Here, I got you a coffee.
I didn't, uh--
I didn't know how you took it.
- Oh, black's fine.
- Oh.
- Uh, I added cream.
- Oh, that's okay.
- No, here, have mine. No, I insist.
- No, really--
[ Bird Squawking ]
- [ Laughs ]
- What is it?
Well, it's just that
this has cream in it too.
It's milk.
Oh. Oh, good.
[ Sighs ]
Okay, well, I'll, uh--
- I'll get to work.
- [ Bird Squawks ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Eric ]
Mmm, what?
What is it?
What is it that gives a schoolgirl
her special innocence?
Is it the way they smell?
The sweet smell
of their perfume, of their hair?
The aroma
of fresh flowers...
and all that other stuff
that hasn't been fucked up...
by late nights
and a lot of bad food.
[ Microphone Feedback ]
Is it their gestures...
and the way they move?
The way their body still holds on
to some semblance of self-respect and...
- and dignity?
- [ Bird Chirping ]
When they wrap
their beautiful legs around you...
tight and holding on,
looking at you...
you looking at them.
It's just--
[ Sighs ]
Or is it whatever comes out
of their cute little mouths?
All those questions,
all that wondering that--
[ Sighs ]
It's just, you know, you--
They got their whole lives
ahead of them, you know?
And you've wasted
half of yours away.
Damn.
What is it?
[ Birds Chirping ]
There's this feeling
I get sometimes, you know?
What sort of feeling?
That I wasn't ever meant
to be satisfied.
Satisfied with what?
A lot of things.
I mean, it seems to me
that every time I'm about to...
you know, get a hold
of something or someone...
it's just bound
to slip away.
Maybe you want it
Maybe I want what
to slip away?
The things that you think
you're about to have.
What would you
think about that?
As a general philosophy...
or how it pertains to you?
You think you could talk
about how it pertains to me?
What do you mean?
Well, I feel
like I want you.
Do you think that means
you'll slip away?
[ Sighs ]
[ Bird Squawks ]
[ Tracey ]
Dad?
I'm not going to baby-sit
for Uncle Francis anymore.
Baby-sit?
You go there to practice.
That's absurd.
Why?
Dad, he pretends
I'm still baby-sitting for him.
Why would you think that?
Because he's paying me.
To house-sit.
[ Sighs ]
Twenty dollars an hour?
When did it go up?
He wants to believe
that Lisa's still there.
I make it easier for him
to convince himself.
Francis always had strange ways
to convince himself...
of many things.
Things that never happened,
things that might happen.
People who did things
for reasons, but they didn't.
What has any of this
got to do with me, Dad?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
So why do I have
to keep going there?
You don't.
And you'll tell him?
[ Thomas ] I was in here the other night
when that guy was thrown out.
Why did that happen?
Has he ever been thrown out before?
- Why do you think he would touch you?
Why do you think
he would touch you?
Well, what do you think
was going through his mind when he--
- Or-Or what was he thinking?
- [ Laughs ]
- Well--
- What's so funny?
Well, this is a joke, right?
Not at all.
If you do this favor for me,
I'll do that favor for you.
But I'm not hiding anything.
Thomas, you're hiding
a smuggling operation...
that brings in over $200,000 a year,
probably a lot more.
We've suspected you
for a long time.
I was just brought in to confirm
what was already known.
So how do you want me
to report back?
[ Sighs ]
All I'm asking
for is a bit of help.
That's all.
It's very important
for me to know these things.
Just ask her these questions.
Do this for me,
and you have a clean slate.
[ Groans ]
This really hasn't been my day.
So change things.
Make it your day.
* Exotica **
[ Eric ] And all you men sitting
near that stage, I can see you.
I know what you're thinking.
You're thinking that "because I'm
sitting next to that stage...
I'm getting the same feeling
as all those guys...
shoveling out that cash
for their own private dancer."
Well, you know, you guys want
to watch, go to the movies.
We're in the live-action
business here, gents.
And, okay, granted--
Granted, that beautiful creature
writhing before you on stage...
she maybe, you know,
smiles at you.
She winks her eyes at you
occasionally...
and you may feel
like the man.
Is that all you guys
are looking for?
Is that all you want?
Come on, come on.
Invite one of our lovely ladies over
to your table where the real action is.
- [ Eric Growls ] Yeah!
- Hi.
I'm really sorry that took so long,
or I took so long.
- Hi.
- It's such a busy night.
Hi. I'm Chrissy.
Hi. I'm Thomas.
It's nice to meet you, Thomas.
I like the name Thomas a lot.
Oh, thanks.
Are you from out of town?
Yes.
Where are you from?
Um... San Francisco.
Oh, you're kidding.
I love San Francisco.
Oh, you've--
You've been there?
Yeah, I was there a couple of years ago
with my debating team.
- Debating team?
- Mm-hmm.
[ Thomas Over Speaker ]
Um, that's-- I admire
someone who can debate well.
I mean, who can debate
i-instead of just argue.
Well, anyone can argue, but i-it's
a good skill, uh, discipline...
to be able to debate
and stand back.
Um, and that's something
you can apply in your life...
- outside of school.
- [ Christina ] Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
And, and when you're meeting
someone or negotiating.
- Negotiating?
- Well, I mean, if you have--
If you have to--
Um, it's a good skill to learn,
as opposed to cheerleading or--
Well, that's what I say.
Don't be nervous
about this, Thomas.
- We're gonna have some fun, okay?
- Sure.
Sure.
Um... um...
I was here
the other night, um--
What night was that?
The night th-that guy
was thrown out.
You were dancing for him.
His name is Francis.
Um... what happened?
[ Sighing ]
He was a bad boy.
- Wh-What do you mean by that?
- What do I mean?
I mean, have you danced
for him before a lot?
Mm-hmm.
-And has he ever been thrown out before?
-No.
So what do you
think happened?
He touched me.
And when you're dancing
for the customer...
they can't touch.
Yes, but why do you think
he touched you last night?
Has he ever touched you before?
Is this what you really want to talk
about for five bucks a dance, Thomas?
Well, I just want to know
what you think was going on in his mind.
Are you here for some kind
of psychology conference?
[ Laughs ]
Uh, well, uh, yes.
Uh, I am, actually.
He's, uh--
He's a very particular case.
Particular in what way?
Um...
you want the full story?
Sure.
His daughter was murdered
a couple of years ago...
and then he was implicated.
- [ Thomas ] For th-the murder?
- Yeah.
- But why?
- I-I don't know. I don't
really remember the details.
I mean, he was cleared, and then
they caught the guy who did it.
But... it obviously had,
like, this...
- this incredible effect on him.
- [ Sniffles ]
I mean, he is--
He's just so fucked up about it.
Oh.
You know...
Thomas...
Francis and I have
a very special type of relationship.
And I-I've never--
I've never minded.
But then he chose
to violate it.
S-Special in what way?
Well, we've, we've always
had this understanding.
I mean, I need him
for certain things...
and... he needs me
for certain things.
I mean, that's the way it's been.
Uh, and how did he
violate that?
He-He violated that in his-his,
in his role and what he was
supposed to do for me.
Wh-What's he su-- Why?
What's he supposed to do
for you? I mean, he comes
to this club. He pays you.
Because I was
doing things for him...
and he's done things
for me.
[ Static, Christina Crying
Over Speaker ]
[ Thomas ]
What has he done for you?
- [ Siren Wailing ]
- [ Christina Sniffling ] I'm--
[ Crying ]
I'm sorry.
[ Continues Crying ]
Okay, this is really stupid.
And then I'm getting so emotional
over the fact that he touched me...
because, I mean, he was,
he was always paying me...
to do him this favor and--
[ Sighs ]
- What favor?
- I don't know, Thomas.
- Why do you want to know all this?
- Well, I'm sorry, but l, uh--
What is it about a schoolgirl that gives
her that special innocence, gentlemen?
Such a thing that you have
absolutely no control over.
You never have.
And you never will.
- After this break, we'll be right
back with sweet Chrissy...
- He-He's not supposed to do that.
- who'll help us answer that question.
- Do what?
He's not supposed to--
He's not suppose--
He can obviously see from his booth that
I'm sitting here talking with a client.
He's not supposed to call me
when I'm talking with a client.
- Why? Do you have to go now?
- [ Sighing ]
Uh, yeah.
But I-I-I want to come back,
and I want to, you know, talk.
But I want to move downstairs.
I don't like it here.
Sure, sure, sure.
Okay. I'll see you soon.
Uh, I'm going to move
to the washroom.
[ Woman Murmuring ]
[ Woman Laughing, Murmuring ]
[ Urinating ]
Hey, I've noticed you've been spending
a lot of time with that lady.
[ Thomas ]
Are you-- Are you talking to me?
Yeah.
You seem, uh, to, to both
hit it off together.
- Well, I guess.
- Yeah.
Um, I guess
that can happen.
[ Eric Over Speaker ]
So what do you guys talk about?
[ Thomas ]
Oh, just things.
What sort of things?
Oh, this and that.
"This and that," eh?
You know, it's amazing how...
you can hit it off with someone
like that, isn't it?
[ Eric ] Have you ever noticed that
some people just drift into your life...
like you've
known them forever?
I mean, there are some people
that you can remember...
the moment that you met them
really clearly.
And other people that...
it seems like you've known them forever,
even though you haven't.
And they all become part of this
continuous memory you have of yourself.
This ongoing--
Are you with me?
[ Thomas ]
Uh, yeah, I-I think so.
I mean, here you are,
y-you know...
you're having this beautiful
conversation with her.
You're getting to know
each other, and--
I mean, there's other guys
that come in here. [ Laughs ]
There's this one guy who comes in here
every other night or something...
and he spends
a few hours with her.
But he never really
gets to know her, you know?
Not the way you have.
Not the way you two--
She really seems
to be herself with you.
Well, how do you know?
What? That she's being herself?
Yeah.
Because I used to be her lover.
I'm, uh, sorry, sir.
I can't let you in.
Look, why not?
Look, can I-- Can I at least
just talk to the manager?
- You want to talk to the manager?
- Yeah.
You have to understand that
we have very strict rules...
regarding
this sort of behavior here.
- And I have always respected them.
- And this one time you didn't.
Now, the problem, Mr. Brown,
is that this one time...
happened in a room full
of other men who were watching.
Now, if I let you
back into the club...
- what's to stop them from trying
to do the same thing?
- I told you.
Someone told me to do it.
I was set up.
And you believed that someone?
- [ Radio Transmission ]
This is, uh, Security.
- Please, sit down.
Thank you.
[ Zoe ]
Why did you touch her?
- Well, I needed to make sure.
- Why?
What if she let you?
What would you have done?
I'd have been disappointed.
I'm not sure...
I understand you.
That's not the way
she was raised.
You know her?
Personally?
There is another club
I can recommend.
I need to come here.
- I understand that very well.
- No, I-I d-don't think you understand.
Exotica is a special place.
My mother was dedicated to creating
a very particular type of atmosphere...
and I would like
to maintain that.
You don't understand.
[ Inhales Deeply ]
Mr. Brown, we're all aware
of what you've gone through.
You've suffered a lot.
But you have to understand
that Exotica is here for your amusement.
We're here to entertain,
not to heal.
There are other places for that.
[ Francis ]
Other places?
[ Zoe ]
I can give you a list.
Mr. Brown?
Are you listening to me,
Um...
um, I-I just met this man
in the washroom.
What man?
Well, I'm not sure.
I-I was in a booth.
I didn't really have
a chance to see him.
- So how did you meet him?
- He just started talking to me.
And what did he say?
Well, um, he said
he used to be your lover.
Well, it's always
a sad moment, gentlemen...
when that clock
strikes that magic hour...
and we have to send you out
into the long and dark and lonely night.
[ Sighs ]
But just remember...
we're only ever
just a dream away...
wherever that is.
* You say that
you don't love him *
* But he's right there
by your side *
* He's just there you say *
* To take away the loneliness
you feel inside *
- I guess--
- I have to go.
- Oh, o-okay.
- ** [ Music Continues ]
Um, wait a minute.
- Oh, no. Thomas, don't.
- No, no, no.
- Thomas, please, don't.
- Uh... no, no. Uh, I insist.
Please.
Thank you.
[ Thomas Clears Throat ]
Your dad told me about, um...
you not wanting
to baby-sit anymore.
There's no baby to sit.
Well, I just want you
to know, I understand.
Understand what?
That this might all seem
a little weird.
A little?
- I just want to thank you, Tracey.
- For what?
You've been very patient.
And, uh...
if you think the time has come
for this to end, then I understand.
[ Unfolding Money ]
Thank you.
Good night, Francis.
[ Unlatching Seat Belt ]
[ Opening, Closing Door ]
[ Footsteps Departing ]
He-He-He calls me from
a table to dance. Of course
I expect you to do something.
- Christina--
- And then-- And then he follows
this guy to the washroom...
- and he tells this guy
that, that he was my lover.
- Well, he was.
- [ Door Closing ]
- It's going too far, Zoe.
Actually, baby, you have
no idea how far it's gone.
You know, I told him to touch you.
I said you were into it. Yeah.
It used to be wonderful
watching you dance for him,
seeing how you could soothe him.
I mean, it soothed me.
You know, you soothed me.
Do you understand that?
- Hey, hey.
- Don't, don't, don't!
- Stop. Stop that!
- Don't fucking touch me, you fucker!
- Stop!
- Just fuck off, Zoe!
- Stop it when I say! Eric!
- Stop it! Ow!
- Chill out! Chill out!
- [ Screaming ]
- Chill out! Relax!
- [ Hysterical Crying ]
- All right? Relax!
- Eric, come here!
- John! Get out. What's the matter?
- [ Crying ] No!
Fuck off, Zoe! No!
[ Water Sloshing ]
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
[ Sighs ]
Morning, Thomas.
- What happened?
- I had to leave.
Did you, uh, hear everything?
Yeah.
Did you know?
Did I know what?
That she knew...
about your daughter.
[ Sighs ]
You know, when the,
when the police came to question me...
they told me
a lot of things.
They told me that my wife
was having an affair with my brother;
had been for years.
They told me that I thought
Lisa wasn't my daughter.
They told me
I thought she was Harold's.
Wh-Why would they say that?
Because they thought
I could harm her...
that I would harm her.
And then they found the man
that, uh, that did it.
Let me go.
And I went home.
And then my wife was killed
in a car accident a couple months later.
[ Sighs ]
And, uh, Harold was in the car.
He lived.
[ Sighs ]
What do you think
it would have taken...
for your father
to kill someone?
I'm-I'm asking because there's
someone that I want to kill now.
I felt it last night
as I listened to him in the washroom.
I don't understand.
He set me up...
to touch her.
Why would he do that?
He took something
very special from me.
I've had too many
special things taken away.
- That's why we have to go back tonight.
- To kill him?
- What would you do, Thomas?
What would you do?
- Well--
- Well, I would talk to him.
- I can't even get in there.
What would you do?
You go back tonight...
and you have her
dance for you...
and then you touch her.
And he'll throw you out
just like he threw me out.
But I'll be waiting outside
with the gun.
I'm not gonna
help you kill somebody.
Not even to save
a few years in prison?
No.
Well, to help me then?
And that was Mirella, gentlemen.
Mirella.
You can have her at your own table
for only five dollars.
Thank you, Mirella.
And now, it's always a pleasure
to announce to you our next dancer.
Gentlemen, please, let's give
a big round of applause...
- for Christina.
- [ Man Hooting, Applause ]
[ Applause Continues ]
[ Man Chuckling ]
* Everybody knows
that the dice are loaded *
* Everybody rolls
with their fingers crossed *
* Everybody knows
the war is over *
the good guys lost *
* Everybody knows
the fight was fixed *
* The poor stay poor
The rich get rich *
* That's how it goes *
* Everybody knows *
* Everybody knows
that the boat is leaking *
the captain lied *
* Everybody got
this broken feeling *
* Like their father
or their dog just died *
* Everybody talking
to their pockets *
* Everybody wants
a box of chocolates *
* And a long-stemmed rose *
* Everybody knows *
* Everybody knows
that you love me, baby *
that you really do *
* Everybody knows
that you've been faithful *
* Ah, give or take
a night or two *
* Everybody knows
you'd been discreet *
* But there were so many people
you just had to meet *
* Without your clothes *
* And everybody knows *
* Everybody knows *
* That's how it goes *
* Everybody knows **
[ Clattering ]
Don't be afraid.
I know everything about you.
What do you know about me?
- [ Siren Wailing ]
- I found her.
You found who?
Your little girl.
Oh. Oh.
[ Eric ]
I found her, man.
I found her.
[ Echoing Laughter ]
[ Francis ] Yeah, play something happy.
Play something happy.
Yeah. Hello.
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Knocking ]
Okay, I'll get it,
I'll get it, I'll get it.
** [ Piano ]
- Hi, Christina.
- Hi.
- I'm a little bit early.
- Yeah, th-that's okay. Come on in.
** [ Piano Continues ]
[ Francis ] Yeah, I mean,
it's difficult for me to tell...
'cause I never had much
of a musical education myself...
but her teacher thinks
she's really talented.
And, um, actually, we were thinking
of buying her a better piano.
An exotic baby grand,
you know?
And when I mentioned "baby grand,"
do you know what she said to me?
[ Laughing ] She said, "Dad,
isn't that a contradiction in terms?"
I mean, she just never
ceases to amaze me.
I mean, she's eight years old.
Can you imagine?
She can already identify--
Wh-What do you call that when...
it's two words,
kind of cancel each other out?
Oh, she just amazes me.
[ Turns Off Engine ]
- [ Sighs ]
- Where's your mind?
I was just thinking.
About what?
About the way
you talk about Lisa.
You get so excited.
It's nice.
Well, I'm sure your parents
talk about you that way too.
I don't think so.
Oh, I do.
Why?
Because you're a very
responsible young woman.
[ Sighs ]
Responsible to what?
Well, to whatever it is
you believe you have to do.
Like what?
Well, Lisa loves it when you
come over to baby-sit, for example.
[ Laughs ]
She says you really
listen to her.
That's nice.
She really listens
to me too.
- [ Sniffs ]
- She thinks you're not very happy.
- Listen, Christina,
- [ Sighs ]
if there's, if there's ever anything
you want to talk about...
about what might be going on
at home or whatever...
- you know that I'm here, okay?
- [ Sniffles ]
- Okay.
- Okay?
Okay.
[ Sniffs ]
Oh, no.
I-It's okay.
Thank you.
You know, I really enjoy
these drives home, Mr. Brown.
Good, good.
So do I.
- Bye, Mr. Brown.
- Good-bye.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Sighs ]