Tales From
The Golden Age
Urban legends from the Ceausescu era,
also called "The Golden Age",
in communist propaganda.
The legend of the air sellers
All her classmates are going.
Your soup's on the table, dear.
So when are you going
to this holiday camp?
It's not a camp.
May 1st is a Thursday this year
and we've no school on Friday.
You're going on your own?
Teachers are coming,
but we've organized it.
And where will you stay?
At the Forum, in Costinesti.
The Forum costs 300 lei?
It's 300 lei all included:
Transport, meals, everything.
Listen, we'd like you to go,
but this Monday
we have to pay an advance
on the Dacia and we're a bit short.
So, can I go or not?
Yes, but stay at aunt Didina's
in Constanta.
It takes half an hour
to go to Costinesti by bus.
You've been saving money
for this crappy car for years.
It'll be yours one day.
Better to take the bus
than eat yoghurt all your life.
Crina!
Coming to the party?
No. I've just had a fight
with Dad.
Come on, they have a video player.
Shall I ring at your door?
No, don't bother.
Shall I wait for you?
I'm coming down.
I'm going down to talk to Roxana.
Don't you have
a French test tomorrow?
I've studied all week.
Be back by 10.
- Is he a student?
- I think so.
He's lent our block
his video player.
What's his name?
Bughi, I think.
I was trembling so much
I forgot my own name.
- He's damn gorgeous!
- Shut up!
Hi, what's your name?
Crina.
Crina, what a nice name.
Shall we dance?
No.
Why?
I don't want to.
Later, maybe?
Maybe.
Make room for my friend.
This is Bughi.
- Crina.
- Bughi.
What film is it?
Bonnie and Clyde.
Didn't you ask me
for a bottle today?
You said you were from
the People's Council.
Give me a smoke.
I'm going.
Stay...
Wait, where are you going?
Where's Roxana?
- Who's Roxana?
- Your date!
She's a nice girl
but she's not my date.
Listen, I'm not hitting on you
or anything,
I just wanted to say sorry
for today.
I don't usually do that
in my neighborhood, but...
Do what?
You know,
knocking on doors and...
So, what's the trick?
You want to know?
You've made me curious.
It's a long story.
Make it short.
It's a trick to make money.
I've got that much.
But what's the scheme?
You want to know too much.
Afraid I'll steal your trick?
You never know...
Come on,
I need to earn some money, fast!
Then work for it like honest folk.
Is that what you do?
Never mind me.
So, you won't tell me.
You have the time?
I've got to be home by 10.
You smoke?
Afraid your dad will smell it?
How did you guess?
I've got to go.
You can come with me if you want.
Can I?
You got the nerve?
Depends. What do I have to do?
You'll see.
Ok.
You free tomorrow?
I've got school in the morning.
School...
- After school, then!
- Ok.
- Bye.
What are you doing with that book?
Book?
The biology book
under your desk.
I wanted some more paper.
You haven't even started yet.
He has no inspiration, Miss.
Quiet!
Give me that book
so you're not distracted.
Yes?
Good afternoon.
Sorry to interrupt. Crina's father
from the factory sent me...
And?
The boiler in their block blew
and flooded the apartment.
She has to go home
and unlock the door.
We're in the middle of a test.
I've finished.
Alright.
You can go, then.
Is that your car?
It's the first one
I found unlocked.
Any particular block?
Don't say a word.
Just watch.
- Right?
- Yes.
Wait there, on the stairs.
Be quiet, Tarzan!
Good afternoon.
I'm from
the Ministry of Chemistry.
Yes?
I need to know
if your tap water's fine, Madam?
I mean, does it taste alright?
Citizens have complained about
the water, so we're doing a study.
Yes, it's cloudy.
Can we take a sample
from your apartment,
to test it?
Come after two o'clock
when my husband's home.
I have to give the samples
to the Ministry by two o'clock.
I don't know...
My husband did lodge a complaint,
but I know nothing about it.
It's very simple, you just have to
give me a bottle of tap water.
A bottle of tap water?
Yes.
From the kitchen or the bathroom?
Either will do.
It's dirtier in the kitchen.
From the kitchen, then.
Ok. One moment please.
- Is a litre enough?
- A litre is perfect.
All this nonsense
just for a lousy bottle?
Listen...
What's your father do?
What's his job?
He's a technician.
What does he earn?
A bit more than a couple of grand.
Let's say he earns 2400 lei, ok?
Divided by 26 days...
That works out at...
10 lei an hour.
If I want, I can earn 20 an hour.
And I don't have a boss,
I don't stand around all day.
I work as much as I want...
But you can't afford to buy a car.
A car? Take it slowly.
You can buy a video player.
- No, you can't.
- Sure you can.
Is that how you bought yours?
A guy bought a scooter
just selling bottles.
I don't believe it.
I'm telling you!
Shall we go in?
How long will it take
to make 300 lei?
Depends how hard you work.
- If you collect 100 bottles a day...
- Impossible.
- Why not?
- Not enough hours in the day.
I'd like to give it a go.
You'd like to give it a go.
Good afternoon!
Ministry of Chemistry.
We're testing the tap water.
Go to the 9th floor,
talk to the administrator.
The 9th floor.
We spoke to him, he said
your tap water has sand in.
It looks like coffee!
The Ministry doesn't believe it.
Could you give us a sample?
Let them come and see
for themselves.
We'll sort it out quicker
if you give us some.
- A jar's ok?
- A bottle's better.
Come and take one yourself
so I don't make a mistake.
- Is this one ok?
- Excellent.
Would you like some jam?
No, thank you.
It's rose jam.
Thanks,
but I'm allergic to flowers.
Look at that!
You should see the laundry!
The sheets come out of the wash
with rust on.
- It's the same in the bathroom?
- It is!
Give us a bathroom sample too.
- In the same bottle?
- No, another one.
Let me look for one...
Why shouldn't we go in?
There could be someone else
in the house.
The husband, the son,
anybody...
You're afraid?
No, but a bottle
isn't worth the risk.
It's not for the bottle.
You know what I'm talking about.
Listen, I have an idea.
Ministry of Chemistry,
about pollution from the factory.
Have you any ID?
Yes, sure.
I left it in the car.
I'll go and get it.
No, here it is!
What's it about?
The quality of the air.
It stinks awfully.
Indeed, we've received
a complaint and...
A complaint?
I've lodged three myself!
We've received several...
May we take some samples
from your apartment?
Why? You don't believe me?
We do, but...
a chemical analysis of the air
is required...
And what should I do?
We'll take some air samples.
It'll take 2 minutes.
Come in, then.
Where does it smell worst?
The whole house stinks
but the living room's the worst.
Please!
Yes, you can smell it.
You have a cat?
A tomcat, but it's not his smell.
I know his smell,
this is from the plant.
I can smell ammonia.
Listen, I hang my socks out
to dry on the balcony
and in the morning
they're yellow.
You know what we need to do?
I'll take a sample
from the living room.
Please do!
Do you have a jar?
You mean a sterile jar?
Any jar will do.
Coming right up.
Will this do?
No, it smells of mustard.
We need a glass one.
A glass one?
Can you choose one?
Look up there!
- It's 75 cl.
- It's perfect.
But it still smells.
It had pickles in it.
It's fine, that won't alter it.
- And a lid!
- A lid.
It does smell in here.
The entire house stinks!
Please, take it!
Sorry...
I'll take a sample.
Please!
And from the living room too.
Please do!
Do you have
another bottle or jar?
- What about these?
- They're perfect.
They're clean.
My wife washed them to sell.
In the bathroom?
No point,
there's no window in there.
In the bedroom, then.
The smell goes up.
Of course,
air is light and rises!
Ok.
That's it?
We're finished.
Thank you.
It's great you're doing this.
I hope you don't mind me asking...
How come you don't get
the samples mixed up?
- How come?
- Yes.
Well...
Why do you think we asked you
for a jar for the kitchen,
a beer bottle for the bedroom,
and a ketchup jar
for the hall?
And what do you do
in three-room apartments?
We ask for champagne bottles.
They can afford to drink champagne.
Well done, kids.
You've thought of everything.
We're in a hurry.
Goodbye, then.
My ID, please.
Listen, do you think
we can make 300 lei by tonight?
I'll give you 300.
I don't want you to.
You can't earn that by tonight.
You bet?
- How much?
- 50 lei.
Deal!
- Any more?
- These here.
I'm not taking this one.
- Why not?
- It's not clean.
They were all washed!
Don't argue! I don't have to take
80 bottles from you.
You have to take them all.
I'll take as many as I can pay for,
alright?
194 lei and 50 bani.
Together or separate?
- Together.
- Separate.
I'll give it to you together
and you sort it out.
Don't come again
with so many bottles!
Thank you!
What if he remembers me?
It's not good.
The lower your profile, the better.
How often do you think
somebody comes with 100 bottles?
- Here.
- Forget it.
No, I lost.
How long would this take
to buy a car?
Years.
How many bottles?
For a Dacia?
Not a Dacia, say a Lastun.
You'd need 5 or 6000 bottles
for a Lastun, maybe more...
If you collect 500 bottles a month,
you can buy it in a year.
You can't.
For example, today, two people,
three blocks, 200 lei.
- We need to be more efficient.
- Yeah, we rob a bank.
Want to watch a video tonight?
I have to be home by 10.
- I'll talk to your father.
- Right, thanks.
I've got it!
Excuse me.
Could you explain it again?
What didn't you understand?
Why do we need samples
from every apartment?
Like I said,
we measure the degree of pollution
on each floor
on both sides of the block
to determine the cause
of the pollution.
It's from the chemical plant.
Why do we need to test it?
Can you detect
the chemicals by smell?
No, I can't.
So, we have to carry out tests
to determine the cause,
to find solutions.
When will you come
to collect it?
Whenever you're ready.
I don't know...
I can put a note up
on the bulletin board,
because calling at every apartment
would take a week!
We need them on Thursday.
That's in two days time!
- I don't know...
- Comrade Administrator!
Workers' Day is coming up.
We'll celebrate it properly. Agreed?
Agreed. But you'll have to
pick the bottles up
and take them back yourselves.
There's no way I can do it.
We'll come and pick them up.
On Thursday at 11.
Yes, Comrade. Thursday at 11.
Goodbye.
I don't know
if this is going to work.
Why?
We fooled him today,
but if he checks...
That's why I said Thursday.
One phone call and we're done for.
It was your idea!
I didn't really think we'd do it.
If you want,
we'll just forget about it.
If they call the police,
we're in deep trouble.
I'd get at least five years.
You're fine, you're underage.
They'd get me for corrupting you.
If they send me to jail,
will you wait for me?
Will you?
Listen, I have to go.
You and your school!
Is it raining?
It's just started.
- What are you making?
- French toast.
What's this for?
Your holiday camp.
It's not a holiday camp.
Aren't you glad?
Of course I am.
What about the Dacia?
We'll manage.
Thanks.
I'm looking for Bughi.
Who's Bughi?
The boy with the video player.
Is Bughi the guy with the video?
No idea.
I won't come in.
Can you please get him?
What's up?
I want us to go tomorrow.
Where?
To collect those bottles.
Are you sure?
Well, I'm going.
You coming with me?
Sure.
Thanks.
I'm going home now.
See you at the block at 11.
- At 11.
- Bye.
Will we have room for them all?
We can make a second trip.
I asked them to put them all
together in one apartment.
Good day, Mr. Albu.
We've come for the bottles.
Please, come in.
We can't. They're in a hurry.
How come? I've made some coffee.
Really, you needn't bother.
It's no bother, come in please.
You take that down
and I'll wait for you here.
I'll go check the next block.
Go on, we'll wait for you.
Where's Bughi?
- Where's Bughi?
- Who's Bughi?
- What?
- They called the police.
They're downstairs.
What's this about the police?
Nothing.
It'll be cleared up immediately.
Don't play games with me!
We're not playing games.
- Hold still!
- Let him go!
You damn thieves!
Catch them!
They're thieves!
Catch those thieves!
It's not far, we can jump!
Let's jump!
They're coming.
Calm down, will you?
- They'll catch us.
- They already have.
We can jump!
You think if you jump,
there's somewhere to run?
You're scared.
Yes, I'm scared. So what?
The police will take you to jail.
Nobody's going to put me in jail.
My uncle's a Party Secretary.
One call and I'm out.
- He's a Party Secretary?
- Yes.
Stay calm, I'll talk to them.
There's nothing to see.
Gentlemen, move along.
Go home now, folks.
Legend has it that
with the end of communism,
Romanians bought Dacia cars
with empty bottles
The legend of
the chicken driver
Fane!
Do you have any more to do?
This one and I'm done.
- Grigore!
- What?
You want some fish? My nephew's
coming from Babadag today.
My wife's fasting for Lent.
It's Annunciation on Sunday.
We can eat fish.
I'll get back to you.
What?
Fane asked if we want fish.
What kind?
Fresh fish. His nephew's
bringing it from Babadag.
How much is it?
- He didn't say.
- Ask him.
Hold this.
You're losing a button.
How many eggs can you get me?
Last year, they gave each employee
two boxes, but you never know.
I'll see if I can have
my nephew's as well.
Has he got used to his job?
A job's a job.
Listen...
I met this guy
from the printing house.
I can get you some red paint
for Easter eggs.
We have some left
from last year.
If I've no eggs for Easter,
my wife will kill me.
Vladut! It's Daktari!
Come on, Daktari's starting!
Good morning, Grigore.
Ionut!
Normally you have
no business in here.
But before you leave, come
and get the stuff for the road.
What stuff?
For the police, if they stop you.
- Even if it's all in order?
- Yes.
When they see the chicken truck,
they'll stop you.
What's in there?
Gizzards and a chicken.
This is Sebi, the new driver.
- Sebi.
- Ionut.
What are you doing for Easter?
I'm going to my Grandma's.
Can I take your eggs, then?
I'll have to ask Grandma.
Can you get me a lamb for Easter?
Folks don't keep sheep any more
but I'll ask around.
- You've already driven livestock?
- No.
Rule number one:
You can't stop for the night.
Whether you're going 100 km or 800,
you don't stop.
Not even to give them water?
No food, no water, nothing.
You just get to where
you're going.
Rule number two:
The chickens stay locked up.
The truck stays sealed.
Understood?
Yes.
If you have time,
you can stop and have some soup.
But it's better
to take your own food.
When you can,
ask for gizzards or livers.
Nobody will notice if you
take half for yourself.
It's harder with a whole chicken.
You've been doing this long?
I've been driving poultry
to Constanta since '84.
You never sleep?
I nap in the cabin,
if I really have to.
I've always made it
to the destination by night fall.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
Listen...
Why must we arrive
at the destination the same day?
That's the rule!
Is the boss in?
She's busy.
I'd like a word with her.
Sit down, she'll come over.
- What's today's soup?
- Beef.
Cheers!
How are you, Grigore?
How's the road over here?
Fine.
I got stuck in the blizzard
on Saturday.
By the time I found a tractor,
my side mirrors had gone.
At 3 o'clock in the afternoon.
Gelu got stuck too.
Three sheep died in his truck.
Listen, do you think Gelu
can get me a lamb?
He's in hospital.
He collapsed and an ambulance
took him to hospital.
What's wrong with him?
Something with his liver.
I'm surprised, he rarely drinks,
and then only plum brandy.
At least I'll die knowing
I drank and fucked all I wanted.
Where's the boss?
She's with the guy
from the county offices.
Easter is coming up,
they're getting supplies in.
Come on, we're starving!
I'm by myself.
Leave the soup. Fetch more bread.
The boss is busy.
You can give me the things.
Get a move on!
And some sugar,
20 kilos...
For you, Miss...
And a few hundred eggs?
Why do you need so many eggs?
We paint some
and bake Easter cakes.
I'll try and get
a couple of crates.
It's not easy to get eggs before Easter.
And Turkish delight?
- Excuse me, Camelia.
- I'm busy.
I've brought you some gizzards.
Can I give you some sugar?
We'll settle up another time.
You sell them separately now?
Ask Mariana for whatever you need.
I'll be back before Easter,
we'll see then.
You think you can get me
some eggs?
I said I would.
You said two crates.
I need more.
Sure, I'll get you some eggs.
Will 100 do?
If you can.
- Name?
- Radu Marian.
Radu Marian. Two.
- Hello, Grigore.
- Hello.
I'll take Ionut's eggs too.
Does he know about it?
Sure. I've talked to him.
And his second crate?
New employees only get one.
Hey, some people get extra?
Mind your own business.
They're for his nephew, Ionut.
No hot water?
No.
The food is on the table.
They gave us our eggs
for Easter tonight.
A crate each.
Maybe Ionut will give us his eggs.
You don't think they need them?
Bring me the pot of hot water
on the stove.
You stopped fasting?
The fish roe salad is for you.
Shall I pour it for you?
I'll do it.
The boss?
In the kitchen.
Yes.
May I?
Please.
I've brought the eggs.
I could only bring 60.
60 is fine. We can't find
any eggs at all round here.
Sit down.
Are you in a hurry?
No, you carry on.
Do you want some peas?
No, thanks.
Why? You're in a hurry?
I have to be at the port by 11 pm.
Why?
Just wondering.
Drivers usually stop here
for the night.
With poultry, you have to arrive
before nightfall.
They're very strict about it.
Isn't it hard?
Always on the road?
You get used to everything.
But I'd like to retire
to a place like this.
Really? You like it here?
Fresh air, peace and quiet...
It isn't easy here, you know.
Isn't it hard,
doing everything by yourself?
Of course.
And with the food shortages,
it's a struggle.
And it's harder for a woman.
Doesn't the guy from the centre
keep you supplied?
With what he gives me...
Selling to the public
brings in more money.
By the way,
can you get hold of some chicken?
It's not easy.
Why? Does somebody count
the chickens in your truck?
It's sealed and can't be opened
until delivery.
You've some flour...
I got you some sugar and flour,
for Easter.
Thanks.
I understand.
They've been told I'll be late?
Should I call them?
Fine.
If Sebi brings the tyres
in the morning
I'll be at the port by noon.
Yes, I understand.
Bye.
So, you're spending the night?
It's open.
- A clean towel.
- Thank you.
The bathroom's in the hall.
A blanket's in the wardrobe.
Right.
Anything else?
No, you can go. Thanks.
Goodnight.
Leave that.
I'll clear it up later.
No problem.
- You need anything else?
- No.
Is the yeast good?
Yes.
With bad yeast,
you can knead away, it won't rise.
You know how to cook?
A little.
Men who can cook
are few and far between.
In a household, it's good to know
how to do everything.
If you want,
there's some wine left.
Thank you.
- Shall I pour you a glass?
- No.
I can't drink alone.
Ok, just a drop.
Cheers.
You can take the bottle
to your room.
I've had enough.
Goodnight.
Camelia? Come here.
What is it?
I've brought you more eggs.
Where from?
The chickens in the truck.
You opened it!
They told me to give them water
before I leave.
And what happens
to all those eggs?
I don't know.
I never opened the truck before.
Are you taking the chickens
to another farm?
I don't know.
They're for export.
And how many chickens
do you have in your truck?
Well, there are 400 cages...
So there must be
2000 or 3000 chickens.
Why?
Just thinking...
You have a 1000 lei's worth of eggs.
Possibly.
Know what?
I could sell them like that,
with Easter coming.
But they're not mine.
Whose are they, then?
You think anybody's
going to ask for them?
I don't know. Why risk it?
You could earn a few thousand lei.
I'm not desperate for money.
Besides, I have to deliver
by noon.
Gathering all those eggs
takes time.
It's up to you.
But it's a shame to waste them
before Easter.
Coming to bed?
No.
You're driving tomorrow?
Yes.
To Constanta?
Hello.
How are you?
Very busy.
How's business?
Could be better
but I'm not complaining.
- Did you manage...
- What?
To sell those eggs?
Like hotcakes.
I could've sold twice as many.
- Are you busy?
- Yes, but go on in.
I've brought a cake I made
and a bottle of wine.
There's people waiting outside.
I won't be free for a while.
How long?
You're in a hurry?
I have to be at the port by 7.
You're not staying tonight?
I can't.
Pity. Tomorrow's Saturday,
people come from town to buy.
Yes, I know, but...
- Where are the blankets?
- Over there.
There's no way you can stay?
Really, I can't.
- Madam?
- Eggs.
- You have any change?
- No, sorry.
Take these.
I'll get your change.
First he was kept
at the police station
and now he's in jail.
Why did it take so long?
He didn't want to sign
the statement.
- And now he's signed it?
- Yes.
The trial begins next week.
What will he get?
Who knows?
At least he's allowed visitors now.
Four kebabs with mustard, please.
Are the kebabs fresh?
Yes.
Four kebabs with mustard.
Got used to the route?
- Surugiu.
- Present.
A visitor.
To the right.
Legend has it that many Romanians
were forced to steal
in order to survive during the '80s