Dear, love is a burning fire, stay
cause then the flames grow higher, babe
Don't let him steel your heart
It's easy, easy
Girl, this game can't last forever, why?
We can not live together, try
Don't let him take your love from me
You're not good, can't you see, brother Louie, Louie, Louie
I'm in love set you free
Oh, she's only looking to me
Only love, breaks her heart
brother Louie, Louie, Louie
Only love's paradise
Oh, she's only looking to me
Brother Louie, Louie, Louie, oh, she's only looking to me
Oh, let it Louie, she's undercover
Brother Louie, Louie, Louie, oh doing what he's doing
So, leave it Louie, cause I'm a lover
Stay, cause this boy wants to gamble, stay
love is more than he can handle, girl
Oh, come on stay by me, forever, ever
Why, does he go on pretending that, his love is never ending fate
Don't let him steel your love from me
You're not good, can't you see, brother Louie, Louie, Louie
I'm in love, set you free, oh she's only looking to me
Only love breaks her heart, brother Louie, Louie, Louie
Only love's paradise, oh she's only looking to me
Brother Louie, Louie, Louie, oh, she's only looking to me
Oh, let it Louie, she's undercover
Brother Louie, Louie, Louie, oh doing what he's doing
So, leave it Louie, cause I'm a lover
Brother Louie, Louie, Louie, oh she's only looking to me
Oh, let it Louie, she's undercover
Brother Louie, Louie, Louie, oh doing what he's doing
So, leave it Louie, cause I'm a lover