The story is based on real people, the true modifications.
Chung Xuan Dao, ie direct, Dai Son origin.
The poor little house, not born
people often been adopted.
Adoptive father was killed during the Japanese invasion,
adoptive parents can not afford to take care of her training.
Concern forever, she finally arranged training
to do to assist them to evaluate.
From thirteen onwards after serving her previous training through
fourth generation evaluation, a total of over sixty years.
Finished subtitles: TGHD ?? ?
trans: Toptabi
When I was born.
Ms. Dao was at my house ten years.
I was 20 to aesthetics.
In 30 years, then to Hong Kong.
Also around this time out,
Ms. Dao has always lived with me.
Until two years ago ...
Sold as any here?
Twelve copper per pound.
Twelve East Asia?
What does, the view goes.
Sell ??... sell it cheap.
Know choose not there?
Two results to be good results there.
As these results .... results are here.
Get this place going.
Enough?
In, that's enough.
Sixteen copper.
Everyone goes to her selection as this,
What else was doing, really ...
Hey, hey, come, come.
Ms. Dao.
- Hello.
- Welcome direction.
- Hello, hello.
Oh, come and game direction.
Trafficking good?
Still passable only.
Today you buy?
Choose less garlic.
Selection, natural selection.
Choose carefully into one bulb.
Mac Ti, Ti Mac.
Why ignore the world we go, Mac Ti.
Today ignoring me?
Wife and then it runs it.
I wear the shirt was light.
Go ahead.
Wearing the glasses slightly.
Wear away, feel free to take home.
How did this cold?
Clear out any place.
This time how long it take?
Two days.
Long not eaten beef tongue.
Ha?
Long not eaten cow tongue.
He also wants surgery
blood vessels connecting the heart at all?
Not long ago, do not eat that food again.
Today I also
Then you eat crab.
Tongue can not eat this stuff, do not eat anymore.
I want to eat ... archive type.
What are you doing?
Insert the map.
No, not,
're talking about, now is talking about.
Well on the go.
This scene must to the half again.
Because it is not enough to, but not high enough.
If the ...
He explained to listen to him.
I also have similar problems.
These he halved,
I have to display a table.
The top three people to stand still.
I also have to hold the position
Vinh lighting him.
He said will you?
I said what I said ... what?
They want to spend money,
certain of his reason.
, We fall into two groups AB filming there.
In the center of attention, but have to go back.
Piled the corridor, go do?
He had not filming? This movie is here.
À The two directors.
Department rendering of the
he was going to spending all the money.
Each movie has that estimate.
They had not filming?
When I filmed
you are in the U.S. west flirting here.
So depending.
Hey!
From Director, director Tsui.
I recommend him to help him walk.
- I also like, any advice?
- Do not be angry, do what.
Sit down, sit down.
Do not make noise anymore, do not make noise anymore.
The two great directors, sit, sit.
Sit down.
I see now that ...
now that people arguing.
I see the results of the work,
does not help anything.
Now it has exceeded estimates.
I saw a later stage
consider measures.
Two large director
How that experience.
Otherwise, the
a little more so.
His film or too.
À filming me?
Benefits harm, harm beneficial.
Speaking of film,
His new film.
He's not an actor
a waste then.
He said if there is not it?
My movies or not, how
boss fooled again increased by 5%.
Where I'm not acting.
Actually he did not know,
directed and very miserable.
Filming such as giving birth.
Most importantly, keep
is his inborn.
Otherwise it will create
localize there.
Okay, I clearly then.
Generally pick up materials sauce rice.
La Kiet, you do not say
confusing is not?
- Will pick up rice sauce.
- He really is tricky, you know you?
I'm hungry, food call away.
- Serve.
- Oh.
That, where service!
Oh.
Please wait a moment.
What call do?
Give me a plate of food ... the rolls.
Add half the weight ... goat ribs.
Be.
Add half pound of meat goats.
For another ten the cake.
Missed it, break it.
I do not eat goat meat.
No problem, I do not eat goat meat.
Ty again, after he finished eating together.
We eat fish hot pot.
So go away now.
- Yes.
- No.
I also do not eat fish hot pot where.
Really?
Come on ... hurry up, hurry up, go do it.
Think not? What you eat this evening?
- Eat what does?
- Eat vegetables only.
As this star can
meal is called?
Fine.
I think this scene should still
for to a little more.
Also want to again?
Want to add little is
just to add some fruit juice.
He promised there and then.
Ca ca.
Do you go?
Where to go there?
Bureau baby, you want to go?
Ms. Dao!
Ms. Dao! I forget to take the key!
Ms. Dao! I forgot to bring his key!
For the first ...
Water before or
Children's clothes before?
Hello La masterpiece.
Hello Wilson.
Sit, sit, sit down.
He did not sleep good game?
I'm alright.
Insights on how he rolls out at all.
Today not much time,
we say go to main content.
Ok.
The interest him wrong,
lacks a few thousand dollars.
We have discussed previously done.
And clearly written on the contract again.
Bank of our revenue is
LIBOR, not the base rate.
Do not try again, he sees this.
I then marked out, are the same at all.
Look away, wrong.
Fixed now, fix right here.
Thank you.
Also, I know the U.S. holiday today.
If the afternoon working at the
Beijing does not get our ...
Fifty thousand dollars
the second time he moved.
Then the film we
would require a strike.
Losses will be
bank of his subject.
Michael ...
Account his salary,
taken for comparison bother you again.
Terms and income ...
must see clearly.
Bothered him too.
No stars, no stars.
His work goes, I go here.
Not eight to him, the evening meeting.
Hey!
I waited for him all morning and then.
Regulate water flow every sales meeting.
Come on, come this way.
This side.
This is my business card.
I change the air conditioning repair job,
I'll tell slightly.
Sorry ... sorry you very much.
Edit this regulation, any damage that machine?
Air conditioning repairman game ...
Going this way, sorry you very much.
Com this site delicious?
Be, be.
The game you do not eat?
No then.
Go eat an orange.
You eat it.
I do not care where ...
I still do not eat rice.
Going ... going for a meal, eat the rice.
Color, color, color.
Mau go, quickly went away.
Just talk over with your doctor.
He told her two days ...
I was able to discharge.
Song still need patience
return to physical therapy.
Seven of the eight recovery
No problem.
He told me, she later
little food to be careful
So wrong.
Each winner will win back room and then going on.
Do not worry.
I thought then.
I will find her temporary replacement ...
Chinese ... and know.
Such communication will be easier.
San Francisco what time is it now?
Afternoon.
Helped me a phone call to his mother.
What for?
Tell her, I do not do anymore.
Do not stand anymore.
Why?
I want to go to a nursing home.
Not you?
In nursing home
How much should children?
She likes to star nursing home?
Yes, all nursing homes in the purse?
You do not need to know, I will help you with that.
No, I have money to pay me.
I have money.
Single room is five thousand,
double rooms, four thousand.
If the room from three
to five people, then ...
Three thousand five hundred ... is the same.
But if the properties of
that his elderly ...
Three thousand is not enough ... the case ...
We can help her
apply for government subsidies.
Song I do not think we
commission, he has here.
What commission?
He never heard back?
Outside of things are bizarre.
If you take buy
a bed in that they mind.
They will help you do all procedures.
Then go for government subsidies.
Then each month to pay five hundred
commissions for him.
Actually both are deceptive,
This place is beneficial to him.
Another thinks his way regained.
We do not like it,
we do business properly.
Each are very clear terms.
Also Check the settlement month
of customers?
Money off diapers a month
five hundred eighty-East Asia?
And to see him
any of its users.
Then how much use ...
calculated one by one by one.
Like this kind of attention,
there are water-proof edge.
So little more expensive.
This uncle rather hard, a lot, very quickly.
Charges by Chan is what?
By Chan à charge?
Right.
It is the old manual examination periodically ...
Agree ... doctor, do physical therapy ...
... Massage, acupuncture, something also.
Song of different body parts
will charge differently.
If the Southeast Asian migrants
collection of one hundred and fifty copper.
There shall return, earning two hundred.
The Hong Kong shall be collected
the two hundred and fifty.
The most expensive is a foreigner,
collection of three hundred.
I know this is the land that Hong Kong.
Foreigners in line
which is also a priority.
Collect fees in that she really is ...
Actually there are enough categories.
He asked enough?
No, I just want to know ...
This place has a certificate of
nurses, nurses, pharmacists ...
.. Nutritionists, doctors and rehabilitation
physician or physical therapist does not?
Be, be, be.
I went looking for a
superior to his answer.
I wonder if the unit
do not seconded.
It is likely to disrupt.
This is my boss.
Meng Thao?
He Inv?
In the talk.
Long time no see, how you like it?
Yes, long time no see, how you like it?
The lady who ... what ...
Girlfriend of me?
Sorry.
You do not necessarily
she's despised.
Tell you know, the
Her career there very long.
Can be compared to the Great Wall there.
How are product managers, Huh?
Recently the big movie about?
Where available, dial Three Kingdoms.
Three Kingdoms game again, then turn so much.
Yes, that hour or so.
Why do not you find me?
How dare find him,
films that are fighting.
- A fight then?
- Old as he ...
- Thanks
- Is hard enough to sleep late
- Strenuous how you?
- The realization missed injuries, how?
He is not insurance,
no pension, right?
Speaking also, as it advanced age.
Personal injury, medical
nine months is not out.
Do not say that anymore, do not talk anymore.
This place ...?
Is six or seven years ago, my girlfriend ...
Investment ... tell me a nursing home,
so I try to do.
It's really easy to find,
each month are in hospital charges.
He said Hong Kong now
that population aging.
The market was very good,
This library open to all institutions.
First is the delta,
New Territories of Hong Kong.
Next is open in the islets.
I see coming soon
supermarket and a whole lot more.
He loves any institute
told me that was that.
I think this is the time.
The area is well used and then some.
Strictly speaking much, was used to it
do not move anymore.
No sooner promoted Gil.
Do same with my same age,
no nursing home in that.
He did not do what?
Not me.
My favorite game?
Not considered to be relatives,
is an old maid.
How at home I almost sixty years.
Now as any age?
Over seventy.
Man he is good.
Help that is treated as such.
Medium weight of gratitude,
just being built, good job there.
This goes in my place ...
Get you 80% of hospital charges only.
Regulate money, things are heating long before.
Also will appoint a
a foreign doctor.
I just like cash income households usually only reason.
For in the particular ease, right.
Say a little hard of hearing,
caring and concern only material here.
Have not any idea?
I really did not expect, she did
so long in my house then.
Up to now?
Arrived.
Is where this stuff?
Wait lightly.
Dear Ms. Chung Xuan Dao,
I was her Thai leader of this place.
Please welcome her!
- Thank you.
- Beware ...
Okay, okay, my self down ...
Little careful.
Slowly.
Look at, look on.
Do.
- Ok, fine.
- Okay, bye bye.
- Thank you very much.
- At only slightly.
Later, she will be in place there.
Find a place to sit down, sit there, and there sat out.
We go this way.
Would you like to do a wheelchair?
No need ... no need.
She considered very lucky.
We do not have
Where some single rooms.
This room is mind, the best.
Sit down.
Slowly.
She kept looking at me forever doing?
There is nothing personal,
she took all away.
We will paste up to her name.
Including clothing, shoes all mild.
As this will not take each others'.
Names are in place, OK.
Precious belongings, she must preserve themselves lightly.
Otherwise, given our
preservation also helped her.
But if you lose, we
no responsibility to light.
I .. I ... no ... no.
So be it.
So she takes his map laid out all away.
What can press
bell to call for the other.
Should I help?
No need.
Are few people like her
how this good.
She went to rest.
Eating.
Eat something, does the same meal.
Meal!
Hey, Grandma, what Ha to mouth.
Good.
Dear, to him then.
Come on, eat rice.
His chin hole game? Fall while eating.
So might there.
He know what, dear,
to eat do not know.
He looked at him behold, he looked at him here ...
Teaching as always do not know!
Release the left hand dean.
Release the left hand.
So he does something?
She looked at him, watching him ...
- At the end I pain, pain and ...
- How so inadequate?
Full dinner table drops,
how are you?
I eat my, he ate his ...
Pick tha sloppy.
Okay Okay, okay then.
She is new to the game?
I saw her go into.
Looks like no one home
to join her, right?
All in the U.S. then, they mind.
This is not my teeth.
Who then wear my dentures?
What type meal here?
His dentures, this payment.
Knitting fabrics.
Referring to her as are you?
Chung Xuan Dao is my name.
Spring Training?
Just hearing the name of the maid.
What I have sinned him back?
A Training call me.
Ms. Dao.
Yes, this call to hear a little easier.
I do not need him to call.
Do not mind him anymore, eaten away.
Food has no taste of her?
I want to go home ...
Home ... I want ...
She, her game.
Be, be, okay.
I led her home lightly.
About any of that ...
Go slowly, I helped her hold luggage.
I led her home lightly.
Go slowly.
Ms. Dao.
Sister you doing?
She do not scan anymore.
This place is not
Star janitor?
Living conditions here ok?
Very good.
- Have not used?
- Get used to it.
Direction and do not need anymore.
Well, is that ...
She do not do it, to me.
To me, to me.
Do not scan again, you do not scan anymore.
See what you lack
then she told me.
Wait I will bring salvation to her.
Where no shortage.
Not you?
Things like soap,
toilet paper idea, even pajamas anymore ...
There are two sets may be substituted for each other.
Be, be.
The next time I fell for her.
You're so busy, the next is always so?
After two weeks away.
Do not scan anymore.
Put another away, put the other away.
He was later to buy me
two vials tofu like, kind of tear gas.
Why is not good food à?
I have not eaten that long ago.
Not long ago, do not eat that food again.
Grilled containing nothing.
Be.
So like this, I get to her
mobile phone.
Do you have what they call me,
possible?
No thank you, do not waste money.
I do not know how to use.
- I taught her that.
- No need.
I would have told her the Thai
found his calling is.
Also.
No need to worry about me.
Do you remember, he won that year grandma style ...
Yes remember?
He did not remember right, you go to study that.
She's winning style attention, and then off.
From then winning, then off.
Repeated.
I am very good in this place, someone take care of that.
Her son game?
Not.
I say that, looking at their general appearance
are not the same.
Adoption game?
Right.
Direction and it was good being there.
A foster child is visiting her, good enough.
One, Two, Cha Cha Cha.
One, two, three or four years.
One, two, shake shake shake.
Who, he shakes this side.
One, two, three ... one, two, three ... one, two, three ...
Who, he shook wrong.
He went off a little.
Aunt Kim, what do do, do you jump my sister.
- We dance together.
- No, no ...
She was so shy?
She is definitely the newcomers,
any way ... I took her dancing.
Away from me a little!
My legs are not good, go away, go away.
Not good, but just go back as well.
High age and then, still afraid or what?
I'm just learning this,
little more interest on.
Morning swim out a little,
English language learning and the Rat ...
Dance dance to shrink.
People that do not love will die there.
The grandparents say is not it?
Pregnant, she said if there is not it?
Do not "flirting" anymore, ant.
Where available, links that you only.
Go sit over here.
A Mai His name, they called me that she Mai.
This is the mother of the child.
Welcome her.
- A Training Call me okay.
- Welcome direction.
Go drink sugar.
Do customers flute, I do not eat sweets.
I'm so good, she visited the game.
Not where, as I visited it.
I-term dialysis.
This place has a dialysis machine, the relative convenience.
I am old, well it does not care anymore.
I was hit style.
I told her it soon.
Sure not to name her apartment for her son
so quickly, she did not listen.
Now or then, he left her here,
to have no shadow.
Mother is not
the child is alone.
Discussed before, the cost per month of the mother.
Two people each half of that.
Part of me, I took it.
Part of him, I do not care.
Thai mother told her to let him get away home.
Her son, as of valuables.
As children, they look like trash mother.
So leave a message lightly.
No, the money paid later
okay a few days.
Sure, you go first.
No, no, I'm waiting for you.
- Have you tired?
- Not tired.
Not tired and had little rest.
So little rest.
Do.
I've said many times before.
I told him not to talk
with people like that.
You talk to these people
how can we consent to you?
Dispatch to where it finished?
You ... what?
The complete text now?
Dispatch finished ... really?
Ok ... Ok ... Ok ...
Sorry, my hot temper, easily angry.
I check the timetable.
If I'm going to add soon.
Ok, bye bye.
There is place?
Self-looking.
She waited a little.
Grandma, this place.
Thank you, thank you.
Thank you.
Nhe Thanks!
Thank you, thank you.
Brother moved out.
What call do?
What fish?
Que Hoa Fish, fish birds and fishes.
There are no cobia?
What call do?
U.S. Fish go Que.
A plate of boiled vegetables.
No oil, no salt, no oyster sauce.
All are not, right?
Right.
- Hey.
- What?
A bowl of rice only.
Two person game ... a bowl of rice?
Why not?
Be.
U.S. Fish Que.
She eat.
À Do not eat?
I do not eat, I'm not hungry.
I later in the meeting.
They like meeting food festivals so.
Come on, take it.
Thank you.
Let me make.
Likely possibility is that Ms. Chen,
I do not know as what?
It sure is good, better than me at that.
I do not own but to look well.
This.
Thank you.
How are you?
Delicious fish there.
Then what?
Soy sauce is not salty.
The next time we bring order.
Do not use them anymore.
She seriously like eating,
do people in the house ...
Both are picky eaters ... then, you know?
Eat a little more.
Taxi ticket at the gate was then recorded.
I like the taxi driver why?
He was not the taxi driver game?
I am a mechanic regulation.
She Thai well, very sweet American grape.
- Best of Van.
- Sweet you?
Sweet.
Van Best, Best of Van.
(Name cards)
Van à most?
I also added here.
I have not won any games here.
Just wait to go.
Consultants.
- Then turn him away.
- She took this.
Note cable, pay cable ...
Do not sleep.
Wake up, see any military type.
Right there.
Do not play anymore, I'm tired.
I go to sleep.
Note Cap ...
As do now?
Do not fight again?
My wife said, after leading his son on holiday in London.
Would drive ... travel the UK.
How come with me?
Do not count me in,
my daughter says she wanted to go to Japan.
Little to change that schedule.
Does anyone get more rock?
I get, I get.
Ok.
There is good food?
What's that?
What is black so black?
As her tongue before training as instructor.
So now ... now I can eat?
Eat.
Do not forget, this is cold food there.
Shareholders can not leave?
Microwave turns slightly away.
No, not, not
where we have no ...
What it is ... no.
No, boiling heat, stay calm.
I am also on I did go to.
Britain finished this game
I do not have?
Stay away, stay away.
Relativity and know, cut, cut ...
Always cut away.
Surely this is delicious.
- You look, you look here ...
- There are no known cut here?
He cut and crushed, you know?
Are cut into.
Do not limp limp ...
Do not hurry, do not ..
He scoundrel that ...
Do not touch again, his hand now.
Capo, this piece for me.
Real good.
Delicious ...
- Speech
- Just do not salt.
Give me a piece.
Cut some thin is beautiful.
People happily gambling game that ...?
Ants, paying out dancing game again?
To Shenzhen.
I heard people say the Phuc Dien mind ...
The shop ... have old marriage.
But not, ant?
Why is the standard one hundred
buy a hope that.
Aunt Kim, accompanied me.
Go, go away.
Direction and the stars?
Same goes away.
Go out.
Best of Van.
He eat, eat, you eat ...
Enjoy him, enjoy him here ...
As this goes, so see who is faster?
Alright.
- Come on.
- One, two, three.
Not that count to three.
Deliberately to give you that.
If not you study with him.
We'd have no luck
How delicious to eat.
Forgot your hands? Music team practice at the time ...
What time is the most well liked here.
Ms. Dao are making a big table like this.
Every time that it also
holding belly, nor floating away.
He said watch and direct the stars like to wear a kind of ...
Service ... old-style clothing that so?
Black pants, white shirt.
She wore a very beautiful song.
Which is kind of clothing
poor quality here.
At that time he was watching
people there all day.
That's right.
Not want
for Shenzhen Star?
Do not go anymore.
Go or no go that's okay.
To direct phone,
her adopted son.
Snacks.
Alo?
One, two, three.
There's a fat girl is the timid.
Buy a piece of pork to worship god.
On top is a bowl team.
Careful not to accidentally hit the door.
One hundred more, two percent less.
Three wine you drink too much.
Four pea eat too much.
In valedictorian, six apples.
Seven big horse running on the table.
Boy eight or nine playing like demons.
Intersection to purchase cotton.
Hong Kong girl threatened to run away shoes.
Guess who we are what?
Is your primary school of La masterpiece game.
Not playing bad, definitely
to say the new name there.
Broke my bowl,
well not to me.
He said look who it is?
Wow, she is still so stingy?
The day he peeled chestnuts help me ...
Hang Tu is not it?
She still remembers it.
A Week One? A week not to game?
What to say instead.
Ms. Dao Well, I miss ..
Told her to do ... duck dishes.
There, there dish ...
Taro cakes, crab eggs certificate, soy sauce chicken stew.
There are dishes I enjoy eating the most beef tendon.
Ms. Dao game, a few days ...
We agreed to meet together to
even, is not it?
No where to go.
Me eating the clean-up done for me.
Relax, have me here, no matter where.
To direct me to the mainland at night,
only marginally at the visit.
No, do not have time to.
Alo? Alo ...
Hung up already?
Uh.
First inhale.
Good, then push forward.
Slowly.
Slowly ... right.
Well, little higher up ...
Well done.
Slowly lower down.
Slowly.
Well done.
Ok not? Do it again.
Yes, the code on the stand,
straighten your back, breathe deeply.
Ms. Dao well, she improved a lot here.
Today we note this file lightly.
Fighting mild.
Good.
Yes, hold handrails.
Good, standing there already.
Balance goes.
Ten fingers knit together, knit tightly.
To reach the chest, then stretch.
Yes, open the little hand.
Yes, good.
Try laughing three hours away, a little fun.
Good, good, drop your hands down.
I'm so much better then.
We can then take the bus.
Taxi.
Ride the bus!
Taxi ... taxi ...
Taxi!
Ms. Dao Dao ... she helped me sewing buttons.
Help ... me ... sewing ... buttons.
Daisy now?
Thank you.
Wait a minute.
Wait stage to help her.
A Pepper, sitting down wearing.
He sat down wear off.
Sit down any.
Thai greet her.
Welcome.
She is where?
Sitting here and waiting for you all morning.
I'm going to look.
Ms. Dao!
Adopted son arrived.
Sewing buttons for her already.
- She helps me sewing buttons.
- Okay, okay.
To me.
Got it.
- I'm finished.
- Come on.
She Thai game.
I do not eat rice in mild pain.
Dao said she did not take
go back to eating light.
- Hello, good morning.
I do not remember who she was there?
- Direct, Long time no see.
- Hello.
Who is that?
The eighth floor.
Ability to.
Why do back here?
Why do so again in this world?
It said she returned.
In the morning I give it the key,
it opened in order here.
You're so good at Giang, said opening game?
Where's my slippers?
This is our slippers, right?
There are recognized?
You ... you want to go .... You want to game?
He had to find someone to do it.
Ms. Dao game, come here.
She do not clean anymore, no, sit here goes.
See if any.
What is it?
Of course life ripe Italian, Italian course West, chlorophyll protein structure, post workshop center.
Four colors to two bowl water bowl.
Her mind, before a bowl to drink.
Eight other left, taken billions more.
Good same?
Of course life ripe soup mixture mind game?
Features like this like porridge too.
She was very thing.
You need two boxes or one?
Two.
- Here, two.
- Put ... put down.
Not enough parts then.
So like any now?
Throw go.
No, no, no ...
Retain retained ... for the ...
Give in, give in, that this antique.
You ... you help that.
Open the cabinet above I see.
- Sister to me, to me.
- The ...
Buy at Toys Jason was born there.
Keeping game?
Keep! Of course keep it.
Hold, hold.
These others?
Equally to all.
This ... is necessary?
No. What is it?
This, this.
Just keep going.
This place is junk too, she kept many items too.
Right.
You see the view.
What?
In that contract.
Remuneration for the first time I domains.
Remuneration for the first time?
- In the same game?
- Yes.
At least that?
That time is very much there.
In copper can buy a floor there.
I do not believe in her way.
How many magazines that hold
"South Korea cinema" that?
Do you know that, then do not let me watch announced.
I know that, but this is my purchase.
I also answer very
oral games.
Won numerous awards.
Something that Lux soap ...
- There are Zebra pen more ...
- Look at this ...
... Lux soap.
How many women hold back?
There where only one wheel only.
Still scented like baby.
It is quite aromatic.
This belt is a piece of the bridge there.
At that time he has stomach problem born crying.
Every day he carried their ...
City ... walking, you would take from crying.
He is like living in this street.
Protection really.
Photos do not stick flat again.
You see this on the penis.
He looked at the view.
He looked at his eyes to not see this.
This is me?
How old was she then?
At that time I ...
Okay, do not ask again, do not ask again.
To obey, do not stir.
Do you mind, not good.
At home we have to maintain propriety here.
Listen to see?
Come, come.
I declare before the light.
The danger, disgust, I do not do.
I do not clean windows, do not wash the toilet.
Nor cleaning kitchen hood.
My mind, this ancient man did not wash his underwear.
Said a person taking a look.
If the invited guests about the meal that
do in such a messy
I ignored here.
I previously called intellectuals,
They completed the work in there.
Two years ago, if not insolvent companies.
Not find a job forever.
I'm also not urgent
Where do the assisting.
So what she uses pot to cook it?
If the rice of course use
Then she à rice cooker.
She was well, cook attention.
Certain iron pot used to cook a new fragrance.
Do you know where can buy
Fresh red snapper is not?
Prime Fish live well
can be purchased here.
He is my only eat steamed fresh fish only.
If he's in Hong Kong at attention.
She had chicken soup for him to eat.
The idea is to do two days of fishing little bubble ...
... Abalone, sea cucumber, for example.
Just as simple as that time.
He's all like she was special.
I find it very difficult to find
servant he has done.
She also do not waste
everyone's time again!
Choose à daughter?
Ms. Dao, and her son spend much money?
Or as I hymn and then the
make him more room to go.
She will not come this time
new desires you?
Mother told me, when she was young
Many people pursue.
There was a man ... sell vegetables.
A person who sells precious metals,
a fish seller.
Very good, are the boss.
- Not good.
- Why?
Not interested.
So what?
They are evil.
- He also metal ugly?
- Bad.
Bad.
She definitely liked my father.
I added!
He said falsely!
How about you?
why he was not married?
There was a man I loved.
The people from the age of two
Ph.D. graduates.
Two stars are not married?
Not good.
Good that that this pretext.
He did not like because she double eyelids?
Very bad.
Speaking falsely.
As a girl there.
Tall, very pretty, so thick.
The model just like her mind.
Take it as a model.
Kwok also take the body.
- Really?
- Yes.
- In harrow!
- Do not cheat her way.
You mind.
I said, you know, people
he asks too high.
So you do not like it.
Right?
Listen to their pursuit of her ants, have you?
Said harrow!
I have no say harrow.
Actually looks him get there.
Not good!
Ask her high so people do not like.
Not.
Try it out.
Nausea do.
No problem, no where ...
I walked in and saw Tart cake ...
... Just got out of the oven.
No thank you, I eat, do customers and gas.
Throughout the day you are invited to eat that.
Give me a chance to take that.
Now, what, come here, really delicious, no ...
Hot, very fragrant too.
He also eat.
I have diabetes, you can not eat.
I need money for urgent examination.
Lend me two or three hundred
doctor is not?
I saw her adopted son or her money.
Three hundred game?
Five hundred little for its abundance, five hundred to go.
I do not have as much.
Then come three hundred.
Three hundred.
Tart cake right there to light.
Hong Kong's atmosphere far from perfect.
If A Dig in the mind that knows her dry throat.
Will definitely cook a large pot of water Arhat fruit
for us to drink, right?
Daily work of the busy enough then.
There have traveled since A Dao itself is not enough rest?
The only nod only game?
This ... this medium.
This is here.
Now, to me.
Do not be.
I find I ... more ...
A Dao, she sat away.
La Kiet, I find.
- Where?
- Inside.
This is ...
I stew for her oats.
Small cylinders, I have given sugar water.
To her food now.
But this attention to the pot.
I have for seasoning.
She was so into the fridge,
always want to eat it ...
Sweet ... or salty foods to eat are whole.
She expensive as I do?
to which she is enough.
What to do but to spend it?
A Dao.
She really is.
I and her own age.
That year I was ill in hospital.
She almost turned the kitchen
in the house to here.
That's not to do so.
Now, when people are hot, and eat.
Bring to the bowl game, where I have that bowl.
How?
There is not ginger?
Ginger à longer need?
Should not be fishy here ginger.
I sampled it, there is no
Where do little fishy.
No game?
I try to watch.
Blades.
Mother said not to tell her the good news the other training game?
I forgot to tell her.
Jason's wife in June next year will be born here.
Provide supply joy joy ...
She is about to be clutching boyfriend!
- Yes.
- It is good too then.
Other people like that?
They are very healthy.
Sharon's husband, preparing to retire next year.
My health, first is fine.
She really well here.
The Sunday still brought some tools to go to church.
Yes she is here to pray?
Yes, yes, I pray, read.
Yes, she keeps taking place.
No, no ... I do not need.
A Dao, I gave her money to keep it.
No, not ...
A Dao!
Kiet was spent not less money.
No, this is absolutely not.
It's like for her,
but also the right thing to do.
She takes the new effort include raising it big.
This money is different, is to buy food for her.
No, do not be.
A training game ...
Not really, really not.
She put away, she put away.
She bought me flowers
Description The modern young master.
She is not like this,
she is not like this.
Yes, this will definitely love her.
When I boarded the plane was deliberately
bought two pairs of people.
She previously was not always sure
cold cold soles so afraid?
Thank you, thank you, this good, this good here.
Do.
So beautiful that for me?
She went for her,
she went for her ...
Nhe Thank you, thank mild.
Still to spend her money.
How that should be.
What bothered her too, makes me
this much food.
I will visit her.
She did not, do not come free.
La Kiet spare much on the mother side.
Will that.
Softly, to the oats in the fridge.
Go here.
Do.
Bye bye.
Open is not,
opening is not ...
Looks like is the oats, which ... see.
Avoid the little, avoiding the bit.
- Do not sure I see ...
- And pretend what the?
Everyone to eat.
Be, be, A Sa took the bowl back, took the bowl back here.
La Kiet, the TV bit smaller.
No need for newspapers to like that.
La masterpiece.
Mother is thinking.
You should recover quickly
apartment in the Shenzhen Water Ministry.
Remodel a bit.
Initially, A Training can
take care of itself.
They can say no in a few years.
Before we migrated to America,
father has not said already?
We moved to the U.S..
This will leave the apartment for a Training
in after the holiday.
Until her centuries-old hidden mountain.
La masterpiece!
I have heard parents say is not there?
Or is there just nodded that?
He is ...
La Kiet, I hear parents say no?
I hear it.
Now the remaining rent a guest house,
make money for him and would not go away.
I think you can measure it.
Not hot?
What is this?
Honey chrysanthemum tea.
No Arhat fruit.
Mother temporarily taking away.
How are you?
Get up, get up!
Told him to get up, he heard not?
Looking for something that looked
see something that looks!
We have to record it as a martial arts shop.
His term for three days
moved, have heard yet!
Done it.
So good enough.
This count is over.
Count something that counts?
What is required of him
recording time consuming.
Also no one yelling at all.
Where to use cable suspension, much less
do stunt jumping death.
Tell your big brother watch
Elementary age at death that move?
Three days.
Bother you then.
Nothing, bye bye.
- Thank you, thank you ...
- Take your time.
Finished subtitles: TGHD ?? ?
Trans: Toptabi
- Go drink tea.
- Go.
I told mom, mother to son
mainland and have fun.
Parents do not care anymore.
Now the new year then,
mother did not go with you.
Then here every New Year's Eve
alone by yourself.
Does not he call me
power to protect his mother.
It said it came to pick her,
it would definitely be that.
The mother called to help a
calls for it.
Take off.
Her mind, according to her daughter to return to
grandchildren to welcome the new year.
My son does not have that time.
She was happy than me, went away quickly.
Well, hey.
Any home.
Ms. Kim game.
This is a gift for her.
Wish her a new year, the bridge is evaluated.
Lucid, healthy.
The two also so lightly.
Ms. Dao, nonetheless adopted son
she's not in Hong Kong.
30 New Year evening or home
New Year's Eve we went.
I welcome the new year with
is that people in hospital.
No thank you.
This two-person ... wait a minute.
I went to pack her a red envelopes.
- Do not ...
- No thank you.
Wait for me, wait for me.
Note the water on the ground,
Do not wet the luggage there.
Yes sir.
Selling as does that?
This.
Eighteen contract.
What about this?
This oh, twenty-eight co.
This two eight-East Asia?
Right.
Place the excitement that he do it?
We just finished eating all annual,
everyone is playing.
Accommodation is the tomorrow you
st a festival right?
Right.
Remember me play lucky money lightly.
No, her own over here.
Sitting through this development aircraft.
Do not like that.
Red packets can be delayed but
can not play that.
At the site you like?
Very good to me.
There are sausages, chicken stew this food.
The best is, he too is good here.
Could lead to quite satisfactory with me.
Two of us were very happy there.
I said you know, right before lunch to
thank the nursing home.
They imitate the new guideline.
St four Tet I will bring it about, you know this?
Ms. Dao, I Jason here, also found light trucks joy.
Provide financial joy found! Also found financial joy!
Her guidance, I'm Sharon.
Wish you abundant health, pay attention Take care of yourself.
People also care of,
Take care of yourself everyone.
Her guidance, I am La masterpiece.
She can really get
the voice of Jason back?
But not irreparable.
She was the oldest tools here.
This place is mind, also changing boss
to times in the past.
But nor do
affect her.
Song have traditionally not
one had ever visited her.
Heard as a
the early 90s.
We all immigrants, then
there is no news anymore.
And who's responsible for her expenses?
Government there.
Do not make noise anymore.
Actually I can also ask for assistance.
Is that.
She returned to do?
I am the owner of that.
Must be subordinate to the home but food festival.
The family where she?
Beautiful British period.
Beauty.
Be careful.
Slowly.
The people behind us
crystal does not intelligent?
Probably so.
TV actress there.
She sit here slightly.
She let me go first & greet little.
Wait for me, do runs wild.
Kiet was quick to come!
I see this one came.
Buffalo boss, thank him lightly.
- Congratulations, congratulations.
- I am so there is blood present.
Everyone congratulated both.
Director of production, congratulations congratulations.
Boys.
Do not smoke, smoking, cancer will be there.
Please ... sorry, I have not heard.
You're mind, you should not smoke.
Smoking also has cancer!
Clear and well ..
I rubbed my drugs gone.
How so?
What is this?
He told her what?
Not, not ... he ...
Ninh Hao? You doing here?
You are not outside the star?
No ... no ...
You're hiding in here?
Few people ... do ...
This is a very directed
Mainland famous us.
Let me introduce, this is my mother.
I told him, she is my mother.
Hi, La masterpiece!
- Ms. Roland.
- Congratulations you.
Movies look very good.
Thank you, thank you ...
My mother.
There is no drive to?
My car is here, a segment driver you okay?
No, no thank you.
In recent years, a few steps away to that.
So okay, I went before.
Another time his dinner appointment.
Thank you to light.
Do customers flute.
She is very polite.
Also no channel style.
No doubt her life so skinny.
Crystal is now proving really strange.
Thin as a toothpick
also said to reduce fat.
Fortunately, he is not
is proving fine, no need to lose weight.
Earlier when it first started airing mind.
I saw his name, the name to do.
She recognized?
Get out.
If his father can see here.
Will die happy, if seen.
He's going nowhere.
There there!
There is.
She has.
Thank you led me to see
premiere soon, Thank you.
Take this party.
- That this King ...
- How?
I observe, observe, see
so many people out.
I also think they take the WC.
The dates that they come back.
Movie or not, not by
a little early.
It must be watching
when he saw us.
Make us ashamed.
Or not u?
Or here!
Who says no or you?
Actual or game?
Or!
I saw that she slept.
My eyes were so dry that or closed.
How dry?
Who in the world? Is it?
What is this?
Someone then fell.
Ms. Dao is not the game?
Signed.
Do not be sad.
Hold on.
Do not be sad, to pay attention to health.
Her situation is not very good.
I find your device
nursing home in which she ...
... Is incomplete.
She is best to find the same family
make social work a little negotiation.
See capable of transmitting a
nursing equipment better.
Mary, dentures photo taken here.
She well, she dragon teeth out then,
no longer hold all the way.
Make a set of dentures to
that it can eat.
Doing so what?
Hey, no, no ...
Okay, do not where.
She do not have teeth to eat this?
The machine can make a contract that
false, but used for how long?
Okay, do not do.
Doctor, I do not need to notice her,
I help her do it.
Do not do it again!
Fans do not wind torn, old people
useless, no.
With what? You rush about?
I do not do anymore!
She deposits what the?
Back then she steer.
She's gone?
Ms. Mai game?
Ms. Mai said she was sorry.
Nursing next car coming soon.
So she does not wait
be returned to her, was gone.
She said to tell her to keep
in good health.
There are times she will call
phone to talk to her.
I know, thanks.
Overheating.
Ant game.
I'm as old ambiguous.
Stroll through the city for losing money.
Lend me three hundred bucks to ... two.
How much?
Three hundred.
Aida home .... thank you.
He mind, there must often come home.
Thank you lead me out.
He then very horny.
Aida, do not be impatient like that.
She was sick the day before,
then abdominal pain.
New hospital known to cholecystitis.
Surgery immediately.
I am not afraid, half the
already in the ground and then.
Face to the sun.
God will arrange that for us.
In the "Bible" told you,
lower natural things are at it.
Sometimes crying, sometimes laughing.
At birth, at death.
There was blood vessel surgery.
Sometimes gallbladder surgery.
Pain game?
Laughter is even better to abdominal pain
is the pitiful cry.
There was latching on.
Sometimes invisible coffin.
The sweetest joy of life.
Are from the left with the tragic.
Thursday purest life.
Are found from the hardships.
We must personally
experiencing hardship.
Then you know the
how to comfort others.
Oh God, please bless the
Training for her peace.
During surgery to remove all
unnecessary suffering of her.
I invite people to apply for mercy.
Complete a wish
her small child.
She always look forward to seeing members
Thursday life of our families.
Jason's children will soon lead me wife
primary protection and security of Hong Kong.
If god is not
Training would like to meet her yet.
Dig in, let her next
us a bit more time.
I would thank people, amen.
Now, Dear guests.
In this moment, we will hold ...
Ceremony where the team ... only Ninh.
Dear Customers.
We're about to organize
routines then birthplace of The Ninh.
As such, the Korean children.
At one year old must be
only place to hold a ceremony.
By then, the table will
display means a lot of items.
View your baby will eventually
select the type of articles.
Then from that predicted
This way after the baby.
This idea ...
Grandmother ... she was there for us.
Now, for me.
What about this ... the small stuff is mine.
For me there.
Now, out here, just right, he over here ...
two people standing on the little ...
Ms. Dao ... her guidance here ...
No, not ...
Be careful little bit backward ...
She do not stress Nhe, looking straight
forward, looking toward the other is.
What a laugh ... two or three yeahhh!
- Now, to the mother.
- Take your time.
- You two go ahead, I'll finish up parking.
- The ... peace of mind away.
Not long back then children.
- Take it?
- Yes.
La Kiet told after record
Her apartment will go through.
Laughter on?
What is, back to a small.
Ms. Dao pampering you,
Pets are always terrible.
Mami said I did not drink soft drinks.
But she always secretly sneaking
cocacola on average.
It came into my room to drink.
She wanted to drink, she is not.
She à envy?
Uh, envy.
Over the years then,
she is still jealous of you game?
Her jealousy, she really jealous.
Song pampering her children,
as well as rewarding.
I see you now care
she knows how thoughtful.
She also considered to have good retribution.
Sometimes I feel and
Training you are lucky.
Several years ago I have
heart surgery.
At that time she cared for her training healthy.
If not her,
I will not recover so quickly.
Now mind, her winning style.
You can also have time
her health care.
Time is just smart.
If reversed,
do not know how.
Right?
I feel god has
a super computer crisis.
Has arranged the fate of several billion
our people worldwide.
Children's right?
Children per month, spending
Training for her as much.
OK or not?
OK, I have no problem.
Her son are also
raised that direction.
I have undertaken the
caring for her.
After making this funeral expenses of her ...
Not fair to all concerned for her.
To express her heart.
Buy her a bottle of fresh water for refreshment.
No thank you.
Go drink some water.
She ... she was taken away.
- She was drinking.
- Do you want to go.
Here, at her home, I'm a guest.
Next time back, she must buy
feed into the kitchen.
Make us an
delicious meal there.
Be, be.
Do.
Thank you, thank you.
She looked at the refrigerator, then children are also very old.
Remember we first bought
refrigerator, and eat watermelon together.
Right.
Great young master told me to the Bac Ha
buy a melon to about that.
Then chilled in the refrigerator.
At night, each one a piece to use.
The old lady can not eat cold,
also a piece to eat.
Yes, yes.
I tell her lightly.
The old lady that evening before going to bed.
I also get a bottle of high tiger.
Fear of diarrhea was midnight there.
Dear men and women, good people!
Today the doctor's pet
our grandchildren come here, very happy ...
With everyone ... can pick mid-autumn festival.
This is like, today I bring
ten pet doctor.
Look me in his arms
grandchildren, it's name is quite satisfactory.
This year four, people see ...
Do not see it very good now, but mistaken,
normally it's the most mischief here.
Besides this puppy out,
there are other pets other doctors.
I recommend to every word.
There is a poodle dog.
It's name is Phi Phi.
Yes, we play with it at all.
As a further note, named QQ.
There's also an uncle named Lang Lang.
There is this uncle, Nhi Thuc Cong.
We're out to visit a nursing home.
We're also here to visit the hospital.
We have the most popular jokes,
He embraced them like that here.
During his lifetime he only.
That made me edgy as well.
The world changes but
my heart forever yours.
I willing to devote the praises ..
... Sincere.
Okay, stop!
No where to go play.
Abundant health.
- Mid-Autumn Festival Day fun.
- Thank you, thank you.
It is awarded for I ate there.
Health abundant light.
Mid-Autumn Festival Day fun.
La Kiet, why is he like?
British Dam.
Why you here?
No, I ...
I live with foster parents.
- Really?
- Uh, uh ...
Long time no see, how health?
This for me?
You want to game.
Where no part of him.
Is it time for tea light.
Mid-Autumn Festival fun!
What to do but want to regain it?
Props that, we also have
to another nursing home.
At mid-autumn festival, there will be cake
medium and put back for her.
On the sister any money?
take two or three hundred for me.
Note à Note back to?
Notes and loans into addiction.
Note doctor?
Notice I visited some shampoo!
A Kien, A Kien.
What?
For him to go, but can go much longer than.
I have loose change ...
I have loose change, no ... take her away.
How much?
Three ... three hundred.
The three hundred game?
Go on.
Mother Mother giants game.
Ms. Dao!
Here we go.
Mid-Autumn Festival fun, bye bye ...
Do not go, do not go.
Sit back, sit back away.
Coming soon a group of people to visit here.
Try a bit of that.
The same mother dancing
Latin Nhe, prepare yourself.
You like it? Be afraid?
Do not be afraid.
Do you want a little faster?
Hurry up, hurry up a little.
Shame on you, shame on you.
Can not, they must stay little.
Quick, quick ...
Shame on you.
So let's put up this slope.
We back up the more ...
Any interest, of a play.
This fat mom walk out?
Unexpectedly mother pushing a ty
I was breathlessly.
Hot too ...
I want to eat banh bot loc ...
Mother waited a bit, wait a bit ... any good.
I want to eat banh bot loc ... ...
Mother waited a ty.
Do not move ... all right ... all right ...
Flour ... filter ...
She was bronchiectasis, plus
twice before winning style.
Body condition had deteriorated.
The functions are then degraded.
We have nothing
can help her be.
Let her spend with
go natural, okay?
He finished thinking told me.
Do not say anymore.
Little to say.
Alo ... Carmen ... right.
Just follow the original plan, tonight's flight.
Be.
He decided yet?
The decision then.
Also want to meet relatives
not face one last time?
No.
So we will start
reduce the amount of drugs.
Later in my work on the mainland.
About a week back.
If ... if she's suddenly gone.
Troubles he directed her to the cold.
Procedures to wait for my return.
Lend me a hundred is not?
Fifty?
Thirty-so.
Also a special word puff cups Nan.
Wind spring brutal stop to take hundreds of flowers.
New silkworm silk make love to death.
Love the new rate becomes dry.
Change the color of hair in the mirror afraid.
Solitary moonlight night welding.
Bong mountain crossing thousands of miles.
Sacred bird Message sex free man.
There may be directed at home
we serve that long.
As a gift.
Thanks everyone for coming.
trans: JoE - Google Translate