Follow me.
- Hi.
- Hey.
I am so sorry.
I don't speak any Japanese.
The interpreter couldn't make it,
but I'm sure you're going to love it.
Getting a table on the last night
is almost impossible.
Yes, doctor, I understand.
It's just all so unexpected that--
Yes, of course.
Fine. She's fine.
Sure. Does that mean
that she can go to this dinner?
That is if she wants to, obviously.
Very well then. Thank you, doctor.
Goodbye then.
Goodbye.
- That's it. I'm going.
I see, madam.
Shall I prepare the car?
Yes, but first fetch the ladder.
We're taking him along.
Yes, madam.
Well, do get a move on, Burton.
I mean, you've got
to get me ready too
and do my hair and all that.
Honestly, I don't know
why I pay you.
Yes, madam.
- Mmm!
Good evening.
Hello.
Yoshio Takamura,
- Isao Kamikama--
- Kamiyama.
Kamiyama, sorry...
are both very excited
to come here to dinner tonight.
Thank you so much for coming.
We're so pleased to have you
here and we're so honored
that you've come all the way
from Tokyo to enjoy our meal.
Ah.
The presents.
Um... and now we'll start you off
with a cocktail.
- Matilda.
- Darling.
I can't believe it. You came.
No, now don't go all mushy on me
or I'm leaving.
- Max.
- Countess.
Are you okay?
What happened?
Oh, this?
Oh, no, no, it's nothing.
Well, they went crazy doing tests.
So I'm a little anemic.
What do they expect?
- Doctors.
- Is that what I think it is?
He wouldn't want to miss this.
You know, he never changed his plans.
Stubborn as a mule.
Matilda, thanks so much for coming.
You don't know what it means to me
to have you here tonight.
They should've closed
this place down years ago,
- seeing how you cook.
- Sure, sure.
Anyhow, what was I to do?
Stay home?
Frankly, I'd rather
make a fool of myself,
come here alone and dine alone.
At least that way it gives them all
something to gossip about.
- Matilda, I have to go.
- It's paid for, yes?
Yes, of course.
Oh, good.
The first to arrive,
the last to be greeted.
My apologies.
Max Barney, director of Chakula.
- Walter Reilly.
- Of course. Mr. Reilly.
Well, welcome.
I hope you have a wonderful evening.
Thank you.
I've been looking forward
to this moment for a very long time.
Well, we're very glad
to have you with us.
Please, if you need anything, don't
hesitate to ask a member of our staff.
Don't worry about me.
If I get bored, I'll let you know.
Ah!
- Do you need help?
- No, no, no. No, thank you.
Well, yes. Would you mind
holding this for a moment?
Sure, of course.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
Ah, careful now.
That's my husband.
Oh. Lovely.
Not to worry, dear.
He's already dead.
- I hope so.
Alive, he would've given you
something to worry about.
Thank you. I'll...
I'll take that as a compliment.
- Are you married?
- Um... was.
- Oh, he died too?
- No. No, we're, um... divorced.
Oh, divorced.
Well... make the most of it, dear.
Life is short.
Mmm!
Hello.
It's beautiful.
It's ringing,
but nobody's picking up.
- You're killing me.
- Man: Listen, they're not picking up.
Should I just get
in the car and we leave?
Oh, I don't know. Yes!
All right, let's go. Come on.
- Diane, come on.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
for the last time,
welcome and enjoy.
Please.
Hold on now.
I... I don't need this huge table.
It looks like I'm expecting someone.
- Orders from up top.
- This is where you park the old lady
so she doesn't cause any trouble.
And now we will follow up the
cocktail by serving our tasting menu,
what we like to call the second act.
Afterwards,
we will return to the terrace
for desserts and liquors.
And finally, tonight's surprise dish.
Sayonara.
Please. Enjoy your meal.
Yeah.
- Um...
Go for it, young man.
She's available.
Divorced.
I managed to reach
the restaurant and told them
we're running a little late,
so quit your pouting, Daniel.
Actually, do you want me to text her
and tell her we landed safely?
No. Thank you. You know
what I'd like you to do?
Keep your eyes on the road,
drive a little faster,
So we don't have
to be so damn late.
He's just jealous.
Can't you tell he's dying
to be with a literary star
ten years younger than him?
No, she's 20 years younger than me.
Twenty years. Now can we
get off this now, please?
We've been on it since New York.
So... a toast.
We need to toast.
To a wonderful evening
and to the success
of your business,
your new business.
Chin-chin.
Oh, in Japanese,
we don't use that word
at the dinner table.
- What word?
- Chin-chin.
- Why?
- In Japanese,
it's something we have
but you don't.
What?
Oh, I get it.
You mean a penis.
Chin-chin means penis
in Japanese.
I love it. Penis-penis.
Mr. Reilly, the wine list.
Oh, please.
Finca Garbet, 2005.
- Finca Garbet.
- I assume you have it.
Absolutely.
Excellent choice.
I know what I like.
Um, is everything all right?
Are you enjoying your food?
Delicious, thank you.
- Would you like to try one?
- Oh, no, no, no.
Thank you very much.
Those are for you.
Um...
The maître d' has been telling me
that you've been discussing the menu.
He's very impressed
with your knowledge of gastronomy.
I know very little.
I have a passion for fine cuisine,
that's all.
I'm intrigued by the process.
Well, perhaps you'd like to come
and visit our kitchen later.
That won't be necessary.
Of course.
- Mr. Barney?
- Yes?
Excuse me.
Um...
I knew you'd end up
being demoted to waitress.
- Serves you right.
- Mind if I sit down?
Oh, if you insist.
Thank you.
- Okay.
Don't you like
the table I chose for you?
When you get to my
age you'll know what it feels like.
There's nothing worse
than being pitied.
How's the count doing?
Well, you know, so far
he hasn't sent anything back.
Please don't spread
the ashes around here.
You could use them as an ingredient.
That'd be something new for you.
Don't you have some work to do?
I don't need a babysitter.
Matilda, there is nothing
wrong in missing him.
- I miss him too.
- Go to work.
Go boil an egg
or do something useful.
Go on.
Bon appétit.
Yes, yes, yes.
Yes.
Yeah, yeah.
Hidalgo, hey, it's Max.
Look,
it's really very busy right now.
I have to go.
I'm liking where this is going.
What are you doing here?
Are you crazy?
This is a surprise.
Do you like my surprise?
- What are you talking about?
- We just sat in a table
in New York and said it was a bummer
we couldn't be here
together at this thing.
Well, here we are,
we're together.
We're not exactly together,
because you gotta deal with him,
- but still--
- I don't understand, okay?
How long have
you had this planned?
I didn't plan this.
Diane had a friend who got
pregnant and she couldn't fly,
so I just took her spot.
I mean...
That was a week ago,
but it wasn't a plan.
You're happy to see me, right?
Dan, you can't just show up here
without checking with me.
Wait, so you're saying
you're not happy to see me?
It's true.
It's called "Costa Brava lifestyle."
It's about the sea,
the landscape, the light,
and with the food. Yeah.
Eating out in the sunshine
with a nice wine.
- Mmm. Do you understand?
- Yes.
It's for that that you
need a calm sea.
Here we don't have
earthquakes or tsunamis.
We... we are relaxed people.
Yes.
Um, please.
Why don't you have another glass?
And then you can tell me
what the food tastes like.
Anyway, we don't have to pay.
'Cause we don't have to pay.
- Who is she with?
- Who?
Oh, uh... Nobody.
Just her ex.
They have some...
Just... I don't know.
- Things to wrap up.
Yes, sir?
Give that to the woman
over there in the red dress.
- Thank you.
Daniel's very mysterious
tonight, don't you agree?
He is, isn't he?
And he seems so much younger
since he started dating Rachel.
And it even looks
like he's grown more hair.
I have hair plugs.
"My love, I haven't told you
that you look glorious tonight.
Why don't we swim naked
under the moonlight?"
Hey, uh, forgive the interruption.
- It's Marc. You're Marc, right?
- Yeah.
- How are you?
- Good.
I just wanted to come by
and take a minute
- to talk man to man if you don't mind.
- No, no, not at all.
Yeah, Raquel told me you are working
hard on the new book.
She didn't tell you, did she?
No. What hasn't she told me?
Rachel and I are together, Marc.
You mean working together.
I mean we're getting married.
It's a tough way to find out, huh?
- Yes?
- I want you to take this
to Rachel Grossman
with her dessert.
- I'm sorry--
- Ah!
Save the small talk for
your boyfriend. This is important.
You're still here.
Yes, sir.
It's good.
But it's good or bad?
Oh. Oh, I'm sorry.
I'll bring you another
carrot tangle straight away.
No, that's fine,
Eduardo. Thank you.
- They were tangled up to begin with.
- My apologies.
You're sure you don't
want a new one?
No no, it's fine, really.
Thank you.
Tell me...
...do people usually
fight like that in here?
No. No, not really.
But here...
...there's a surprise every minute.
- Of course. Thank you.
- Hey.
It's a nice spot, huh?
I was thinking maybe
we should buy the place,
open a restaurant or something.
What do you think?
- What, they didn't like the food?
- Mmm...
No, really, I love to sing.
It's my hobby.
Never professionally,
only in the karaoke bar.
But you've got a lot of karaoke bars
in Japan, right?
Yes, we do.
And have you ever sung in a
karaoke bar?
Yes, I love singing.
Who's your favorite singer?
Lady Gaga.
Mmm.
- Eduardo.
- Yes?
I am very flattered,
but you are far too young.
And I think you know
where this ring belongs.
- Yes, I do.
- Mmm.
I will take care of that.
Thank you.
Gentlemen, how is everything?
Is everything all right?
Oh, everything is great.
Thank you very much.
- Well, you're really welcome.
- Thank you.
Um, well, if there's anything
you need, just ask, okay?
- Max.
- Yeah?
Ladies and gentlemen.
Ladies and gentlemen,
if I can have your attention please.
The night's not over,
but we're gonna change the venue.
If you've got a drink,
bring it with you.
If not, please come and join us
for a cocktail en el chiringuito.
My husband and I
came here quite often. Mm-hm.
He was really very fond of Mar.
I suppose she's, well,
the daughter we never had.
Your husband sounds like an
amazing man.
Oh, you cannot imagine,
Miss...
- Rachel, please.
- Oh, Rachel.
Pretty name.
My husband was a businessman.
Uh, not a very good one, I'm afraid.
He was... an adventurer.
One of those men for whom
the world is just too small.
I seem to come across men
for whom the world is too big.
Fernando ate more than anyone,
drank more than anyone,
shouted more than anyone and--
- Don't say it. I can already imagine.
No no, that is not what I was going
to say, you cheeky young lady.
I was going to say that everyone
knew him everywhere,
and when he spoke,
nobody dared open his mouth.
Except for me.
You know, I had never
really understood his tastes.
But I really rather miss his...
walks on the wild side.
I wanted to crawl into a hole and die
at every fresh encounter, but...
...truth be told, that's when
he made me laugh the most.
Excuse me.
- Oh, will you excuse me?
Yeah.
Hello. Thank you.
Yes, I'm still here.
Yes, no news.
Everything's still the same.
What can I tell you?
If there's no news, there's no news.
I'm sorry. Can't talk now.
I'll call you back.
- Sorry about that.
- No problem. Um...
This is really kinda silly,
now that dinner's over,
it's not gonna matter
one way or another, but--
I'm sorry, I just have to ask.
You wouldn't--
- Excuse me.
What?!
Yeah, yeah.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Mar?
Uh-huh.
- Can we talk?
- Daniel, what are you doing here?
I just think we should talk
given what's happened, privately.
- What are you talking about?
- What do you mean--
- Listen--
- Am I talking to you, Marc?
'Cause I don't think I am.
- Oh!
Are you okay?
Let me see. Let me see.
Water. A glass of water, please.
What, me?
Lou, get her a glass of water.
It's just my blood pressure.
- Can I sit down somewhere?
- Sure.
Well, the pulse is fine and I don't
really see anything wrong.
I'm fine, really,
I told you.
- Please leave.
- Well, are you sure that's a good idea?
Go, please.
- Okay.
- Shoo!
Uh, she can stay...
- ...if she wants to.
- Okay, okay, okay.
- Thank you, doctor.
- You're welcome.
There's nothing wrong
with you, is there?
Do you know what a fright
you gave everyone?
Don't you start complaining,
young lady.
I saved you from a doozy.
Do you realize what was
about to happen out there?
Both your men
in the same restaurant?
- And they say women are the smart ones.
- You're a real piece of work.
So Fernando told me. Many times.
Actually, I'm afraid
you can't smoke in here.
Actually, I'm afraid I can.
I, uh...
- I have something of yours.
- Mine?
One of your men is expecting
a little something extra tonight.
Who... Who gave you this?
I don't know.
- What did she say?
- I'm not sure.
Um...
The thing is the musicians
that came to play for you tonight
and the captain of the ship are--
Well, they're in a life raft
somewhere out there
and they haven't been found yet.
But we're sure that they're close by.
Um...
Look, why don't you just...
...take your drinks and
enjoy the beach?
Max. Max!
Hey! Hey. Who are you?
Because a food critic you are not.
- What are you talking about?
Show me your passport.
- Excuse me?
- Ramon: Max.
No, no, no. I would like you
very much to show me your passport.
- Is there some kind of problem?
- Just show it to me.
All right, fine. Walter Reilly,
who were you talking to?
Max. Hey.
All right. Do not let him leave.
I swear, I don't know
what the problem is.
I'm so sorry, sir.
Actually, it's a wonderful plan.
I think the beauty of it
is it's really simple.
- Folks, please.
- Matilda: Why not?
- You know, and I--
- Hey!
Perhaps one person
at a time please.
Okay, look, all we're saying, right?
We wanna help, okay?
We don't think it's right
to be here sitting on our asses,
drinking cocktails,
while there are people lost at sea.
The coast guard is doing
what the coast guard does, okay?
It might take them a while,
but they're gonna find them.
Now look, you've all paid to be here.
You have the right to enjoy
the evening.
Don't you tell me how
to enjoy my evening, Max Barney.
Look, here's the situation.
There are five people
out there who need help.
There are 30 people here
who want to help.
- Exactly.
- Um...
All right, what would the plan be?
Okay, the plan is
we form two groups.
Okay? So the first group...
- is gonna go up the cliff...
- Mm.
...and build a fire
so they can see us, right?
And then the second group
takes that boat
- and go look for them.
- That boat?
- Yeah, that boat.
- That boat hasn't been used in years
and the engine isn't gonna start.
And even if it does,
the last thing we need is another
boatload of people lost at sea.
And you can't build a fire
on the cliff, because, well,
if the police catch you,
they'll shut us down.
I thought you were
shutting down anyway.
What the hell. All right, fine.
- Okay. Okay, everyone.
- Okay.
So... So let's go.
Follow me and bring flashlights.
- And what else do you think we need?
- And firewood.
- Firewood, firewood.
- Come on, people. Come along.
Emergency communication are
always on the same frequency.
So we should get something
if there's a patrol
using the radio within
a seven-kilometers radius.
Okay.
No, no, no, please,
do not... do not put...
- Max.
- Yeah?
That's good news?
An hour ago you were
in a wheelchair,
and now you're climbing a mountain.
I know!
- But whatever.
I haven't felt so alive in...
for years.
If you're sitting down, so am I.
No, put the light right over here.
No, it's not the battery.
I don't know what to tell you.
The motor looks fine. It's got gas.
- It just doesn't wanna start.
- Mind if I take a look?
The oil looks fine.
Ah.
This is not gas. This is rainwater.
Stagnant rainwater.
- So you're a mechanic?
- No, I'm a watchmaker.
A watchmaker?
What's the matter? You've never
seen a watchmaker before?
No, as a matter of fact, I haven't.
Not that you knew of at the time.
- Can you fix this?
- Yes, if you get me some gas.
Gas?
One of you must know how
to siphon gas from the tank of a car.
- I'll do it myself.
- I'll come with you.
You are in a pickle, aren't you?
You wanna hear something funny?
Mm-hm.
When I was doing research
for my book...
...I lived with the Lakota Sioux
for a long time.
You know, I practically
became one of them.
They taught me...
They taught me
about their cooking and their...
...rituals and ceremonies.
It was incredible.
I have never felt so connected
in my life.
It's... It's like
I learned nothing from it.
- Hmm.
- I mean...
...I'm alone now.
I'm alone and I still...
I still don't feel in control
of my life.
Well, you could always go back
and settle on the reservation.
Yeah, that's actually not a bad idea,
because, you know,
right now I'd love to be
a million miles away
from Dan and Marc.
Although it's not like
I do so good on my own.
I'm a disaster.
How did you do it?
- Oh, well...
- I mean really.
Welcome to the human race.
We're all contradictory.
There's no way around it.
You know, there's nothing
more precious than freedom.
Mmm.
But you can be free
with somebody by your side.
I learned that from Fernando.
You're just fearful.
That's normal.
Just follow your heart.
- It's okay?
- Not yet.
Okay, this is great. Let's go!
Arriba! Cut us loose!
Wait, wait, wait, um...
- We can't all fit.
- You need me out there.
Maximum of four.
We gotta leave room for the others
when we come back.
- I'm going too.
- Yeah, big surprise.
- Is that because I'm going?
- I'm a doctor, you moron.
All right, look, I'll go.
You know how
to steer this thing, right?
Yes, of course.
We'll use the flame as a beacon.
- You should go.
- All right.
Here we go.
- All right. Here we go, push!
- Let's go.
Good luck.
At least you got the fire going.
- We could have toast.
- Yes!
Ooh, yes.
- Mina: Is... Is that a...
- What? What do you see?
- What is that?
- Matilda: It's a flare.
They must've lit it
when they saw our bonfire.
It's them! It's the lifeboat!
- Hello!
- Yoo-hoo!
- Yoo-hoo! Over here!
- Over here!
Is that the coast guard?
No, it's a friend who's got
a friend at the coast guard.
Max. Max, Max!
- Yeah?
- We saw a flare.
- Where?
- Yes, quite distinctly. Out there.
Okay. Please,
just one second. Look, Gerard...
- Great.
- Okay. Excuse me.
Look what the sand has
done to my stocking.
- It's them. Look!
- It's the boat!
- Yoo-hoo!
Sorry, sorry.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
- Are you recording?
- Man: Yeah.
You are the man
who saved these people?
- Yes. Yes, I am.
- Right? Yeah.
And what's your name?
- My name's Daniel.
- Daniel.
You know,
it was a decision point.
It was, "I'm gonna risk
my life and save others."
- Yeah. Okay.
- And that's what I did.
Here's your ring.
♪
Thank you.
I owe you an apology.
Really, there's no need.
No, no,no, I mean it. I'm sorry.
I just wanna thank you
for all your help.
You're welcome.
It was a cinch fixing it.
The motor, I mean.
Can I ask you a question?
Why'd you come here tonight?
I'm an admirer of your restaurant.
I've visited restaurants
all over the world,
and I've never experienced
anything like this.
It's unbearable to think
that you're closing.
So who were you talking to all night?
My mother.
She thinks I'm in the shop.
She's a dreadful cook.
Okay.
Whatever he's offered,
our offer will be better.
Shall we go to my office
and discuss details?
No. After the party.
Enjoy.
"Thank you very much for everything.
It was a night I will never forget.
I'm sorry to leave you this way,
but I feel it's the most
honest thing to do.
Money corrupts art."
Son of a bitch.
- Max.
- Matilda.
Do you mind if
I borrow her for a minute?
We did it.
- Thank you.