He honestly doesn't seem
to like you, Finstock.
He loves me. Do you know why?
He loves me because I'm his master.
He knows I will protect him...
...like the students at Hamilton University.
Sit!
They know why I'm here.
Finstock, do you know why you're here?
Yes, sir. $32,500 a year and summers off.
You're here because it's time
to bring the glory back to this institution.
The regional boxing finals
are in three months.
Now, you and I have a sacred oath...
...to provide these young people
with an opportunity...
...to develop not only their minds,
but their spirit as well.
Their fighting spirit.
Am I right?
I promised the alumni
I'd give them a winning boxing team...
...and all you've given me
is this Todd Howard.
The only thing he ever did on an athletic
field was to play in the school band.
Clarinet, looks like.
Can I make a sudden move?
Yeah, that's the kid. I know him.
His cousin played basketball
for me at Beacontown High.
- And?
- And what?
And what?
What?
I don't think Scott knew the first thing
about playing the clarinet.
I gave that kid a full scholarship
based on your recommendation!
On my recommendation? That's great!
- Finstock!
- What?
Your job is riding on this boxing team!
My reputation as an educator
is riding on this boxing team!
And all you've brought me
is a clarinet player?
- I think it's that way.
- Okay, three blocks?
Todd!
- All right. Thanks a lot.
- Bye.
Come on, Todd! Let's go.
- Excuse me!
- Watch out!
Okay, she said the dorm
was past the quad...
...and left after the administration building.
- Or was it right?
- That's okay. We'll keep going straight.
I know how you feel.
College is a stressful time,
especially on your first day.
What I mean is, it's stressful for anyone...
...even for people without
your particular worry.
What worry?
You know.
I don't believe it!
Absolutely.
I hate it when you do that.
I'm not ashamed of who or what I am,
and you shouldn't be, either.
I'm not, because it skipped my family.
No, look, I've got enough problems, okay?
I'm at a new school,
it's my first time away from home...
...I gotta make new friends, and try
to fit in without this hanging over me.
It is true that
sometimes it skips family members.
Your mother and father aren't werewolves.
But if I were you,
I'd keep my possibilities open.
Uncle Harold, can you please change back
before we get to the dorm?
Thanks.
I think the dorm
is just a little north from here.
Watch out!
Excuse me, I think that this was our space.
- Are you talking to me?
- No, but...
...I’d like to maybe give you a call.
Gus, he says this is his space.
A freshman.
Did you think I said that this is my space?
I didn't say that, no.
This is your space. My space has got
a couple of yellow lines on it.
I brought my uncle by to see your space,
'cause it was such a nice one.
And now, since you're in your space,
we'll go get in ours.
They seem like nice kids.
Yeah, I think I saw
another space up the street.
Todd? Buddy, how are you? Come on in.
Drop your stuff off.
Make yourself at home.
Do I know you?
Stiles. We're roommates.
- Okay.
- Stiles?
Mr. H?
- How's the Prince of Paint?
- What are you doing here?
Took some doing, but I've got connections.
You know, daughter of somebody.
Let me just tidy up a bit.
It's a great room, I decorated it myself.
What do you think?
You're in the big time, kid: college.
No one telling you what to do. No more
picking up your stuff if you don't want to.
No parents. No offense, Mr. H.
Let me help you with that.
- Todd?
- Yeah?
I gotta get back to Beacontown.
- Could you walk me to the van?
- Sure.
Everything's kosher.
I've taken care of everything.
I've got Todd's year
at college all mapped out.
For the drive home.
- Thanks. You got any fries?
- See you in a bit.
Yeah, I'll see you.
We are going to have a great year.
I think so.
I got them vibes happening.
In a big way.
Listen, Uncle Harold,
everything's going to be fine.
I'm sure once I start those science classes,
I'll really like it here.
But what about
that sports scholarship they gave you?
The closest you ever came to a field,
was playing clarinet in the marching band.
I'm sure once they take a look at me, they
won't want me to try out for any team.
They're not going to give
you something for nothing.
I guess that's their problem.
- Listen, don't forget your groceries.
- Yeah, thanks.
It's just that your mom and dad...
I promised them to look after you, and...
...the last thing I expected
was to find Stiles as your roommate.
He seems okay.
Stiles was Scott's
best friend in high school.
He knows all about us.
I figure since I'm not a...
Since I don't have the family problem...
...there's nothing really to worry
about Stiles, is there?
- I'm sure you'll be okay. Listen...
- What are you doing?
- Come on, take this. You never know.
- Thanks.
- Take care.
- Yeah.
What?
If you need anything,
you call me, you hear me?
I will.
Okay.
- Thanks again, Uncle Harold.
- Take it easy.
Call me!
En garde!
No mercy!
- Take that!
- Take it easy, man!
Die!
He's nuts!
Sorry.
Chocolate milk.
- Grab the door for me?
- Todd, Chubby. Chub, Todd.
Hi.
Chub played basketball
at Beacontown, Todd.
- Yeah? You know my cousin?
- Scott.
We just love the Howard family.
Stiles, where's all my stuff?
Some of my t-shirts are in there, but
go ahead and help yourself, I don't mind.
What did you mean when you told
Uncle Harold you took care of everything?
All your classes. I registered for you.
You what?
Stiles, I've already pre-registered.
I know, I saw what you picked.
I made the necessary changes.
Trust me.
This is all wrong.
- "Girls' volleyball"?
- Good class.
"Candle-making."
"French for chefs"?
C'est très magnifique.
I took it twice. I'm taking it again.
- There's not one science class on here.
- Science?
You don't understand.
That boy's got werewolf
written all over him.
If everything goes as planned, he and I
are going to take this school by storm.
I love college. I love it.
- I gotta get these changed.
- Don't make me laugh, kid.
Rules are rules. Policy is policy.
You don't understand.
This must be changed.
- You've got a lot of nerve.
- Excuse me.
Nobody ever changes their classes.
What do you want?
- I...
- Well?
Come on. I haven't got all day.
I'd like to change some classes.
Have your professor sign this
and bring it back here...
...but not to me.
- Thank you.
- You're very welcome.
It's not as tough as it looks.
I'm looking for Professor Brooks.
She's not in there.
I was wondering
if you could tell me where she might be?
Professor Brooks
is both omnivorous and bipedal.
She's also a Homo sapiens femininus.
And a brilliant one at that.
I'm Tanya Brooks. Can I help you?
Yeah, I'm Todd Howard.
Howard, yes. I know all about you.
You do?
I'm your faculty advisor.
I read your application.
Your talent for science is very impressive.
That's why I was surprised
that you're here on an athletic scholarship.
That surprised me, too.
Listen, Professor Brooks,
I have a little favor to ask you.
You see, I want to be a veterinarian,
and I need your class.
I realize registration is over,
but I wonder if you could see it my way?
Yes.
You're in my class. It's not full yet.
As your advisor,
I'll make an exception for you.
Really? Thank you.
Thank you very much.
What are you looking at?
I'm looking for Lubrus protozoa.
Let's see.
Here it is, right here.
There's nothing on this.
It helps if you turn it on.
See you.
Are you a coach?
I need to speak to a coach.
There's nothing to talk about.
You're Todd Howard.
We're all depending on you.
Depending on me for what?
You missed a spot!
I know just how you feel.
I had this kid once,
he had an athletic scholarship just like you.
A gifted athlete...
...but he had this crazy dream
about wanting to become a chiropractor.
But he had to work all night
as a short-order cook at this diner...
...because he was supporting his sister
and she had three kids.
And, wait, his name was Phillip.
- No, wait...
- Doesn't matter.
Okay, but it sort of does.
No, his name was George...
...and her three kids were really nice...
...but one of them
had two thumbs on his right hand.
Did he become a chiropractor?
Not with two thumbs
on his right hand, he didn't.
Wait a minute.
- You're from Beacontown, aren't you?
- Yeah.
Now I get it.
You think that I'm...
You can forget it,
because you see, I'm not Scott.
I can't do what Scott did. I'm not like him.
What's a five-letter word
for Italian sausage?
So that's why they gave me
a sports scholarship.
What's the worst that can happen?
You jump in the ring, you go a few rounds,
you get your head knocked off, maybe.
Then you get your scholarship
and everybody's happy.
Wait. Jump into what ring?
Just show up for practice
this Thursday, okay?
- Practice for what?
- Boxing.
"Frank!" That's perfect!
Would you take it easy?
I'm trying to make it look good.
I want to keep this scholarship,
but I don't know what to do.
Fat kid's a great dancer.
- All right.
- Go, Chub.
Okay. You want to play rough?
I'm going to throw two jabs.
You come back with a right.
- Which one's the Howard kid?
- Hey, Todd.
I guess he's a little rusty, you know.
If this is some kind of joke...
...you'll notice I'm not laughing.
- I had dibs on this.
- Possession is nine-tenths of the law.
Now you're a lawyer?
I thought you were a biologist.
What do you want with it, anyway?
It's probably over your head.
- Over my head?
- Over any jock's head.
Jock?
Listen, all I want to do
is go to this school...
...but I'm here on some
stupid sports scholarship...
...with a coach who wants me
to have two right thumbs.
My roommate sunbathes
with a 40-watt light bulb...
...a fat kid's eating me
out of house and home...
...I’ve got Dean Dunn's dog
trying to bite my leg off...
...and you want the only book
that I want in this entire library?
I'll tell you what:
You can have this book
and this book and this book and this book.
And you can keep that book as well.
You too, buddy.
You okay?
Yeah.
Here.
I think you want this
a little more than I do.
Thanks.
I guess I got a little carried away in there.
I guess you did.
Wait up.
Phylum and Genus Classes
of North American Crustaceans?
A little light reading for you?
I guess I should have known
that I'd find you in the science section.
You know, I probably
won't be needing this book anyway.
I was a science fair champion
in the Tri-County area.
Yeah.
My research is in crustacean reproduction.
How exciting.
- So, how's your schedule?
- It's better.
Listen, Nicki.
I was wondering if...
Would you like to...
I'd love to.
- You would?
- Sure.
Great.
I'm busy Friday, but Saturday I'm free.
Do lab partners usually work on
the weekends this early in the semester?
I thought you were asking me if...
Really?
Then, you mean you'd like to?
I mean, maybe...
Maybe we can.
Hi.
- Bye.
- Bye-bye.
- About earlier...
- Don't worry about it.
It's nothing.
- Thanks. You look nice.
- Thank you.
- You want to dance?
- Sure.
How's that left hook?
It's great.
Todd Howard,
I'd like you to meet Mrs. St. Claire...
...one of our principal benefactors.
New physics lab, athletic field
and other endowments.
- It's a pleasure to meet you.
- Thank you.
I'd like you also to meet Lisa Goldfluss
and Emily Lord.
They are co-hostesses
of our reception committee.
We've met.
This fine young man carries
our hopes and dreams...
...into the ring, eh?
Lisa, dance with Todd.
- Dean Dunn, I...
- Do it.
Why are you smiling? You're next.
How's your boyfriend?
I may have to dance with you,
but I don't have to talk to you.
- You sure do sweat a lot.
- Shut up and dance.
Oh, no.
Oh, my god.
Oh, my...
You're a dog.
I've been dancing with a dog.
Yeah, I knew you had it in you!
Look out!
Mrs. Woodbury, be careful.
I can't believe they're doing this.
Let me give you a hand with that.
This has gone much too far.
Miss Goldfluss,
do you have an explanation for this?
What are you so upset about?
Upset, Stiles?
Me, upset?
I just had a beard all over my body, okay?
- I had fingernails the size of French fries.
- So?
Teeth from here to Texas,
and she called me a dog.
- A dog, Stiles!
- Okay.
I might be able to cut you a deal.
If they'll let you keep the scholarship,
you'll promise to be the school mascot.
- Yeah?
- This is just the tip of the iceberg, buddy!
The whole school will be talking about you.
All you got to do is be the wolf, Todd.
- I'll take care of the rest.
- Wonderful.
Wonderful!
She called me a dog.
The bed they laid him in
was only six feet long.
His feet hung over the end.
Mary, his wife, clung to his side.
Her tears mingled with his blood.
Her prayers echoed the grief
of an entire nation.
The small projectile from the derringer...
...that John Wilkes Booth used...
...was still lodged in his left temple.
- I got fleas. You distract him.
- And all night long...
- Hi.
...the vigil waited in that small boarding
house across from Ford's theatre...
...until the wee hours in the morning...
...when fate dealt that final blow.
A crowd of mourners gathered.
White, black, rich and poor.
And so, 10 hours after that fatal shot...
...President Abraham Lincoln...
Mr. Howard, where are you going?
I've been wanting
to speak with you, young man.
Your disruptive behavior
at yesterday's reception...
...warrants my personal
attention, don't you think?
I don't like practical jokes.
I am not a funny man.
Frankly, I fail to see the humor
of dressing up in a dog costume...
...and trying to frighten our alumni.
- But, Dean Dunn...
- Don't give me any of that back talk.
If you're trying to push me...
...you have no idea
who you're dealing with.
Your first fight is coming up.
So far, I'm unimpressed.
You'd better not fail me...
...because if you do...
...I’ll call every dean at every school...
...and you'll never go to college,
anywhere, ever.
Do I make myself crystal clear?
Strange boy.
Excuse me.
It's that guy.
You know, the guy who turned into a dog?
He's really weird.
Everybody's scratching around here.
Todd, we're all looking forward
to your presentation. Are you ready?
Yeah. I think so.
Todd, I want to see you.
All right, everyone.
That's all for today. Thank you.
Do you want to go to lunch?
You don't want to be seen with me.
I'm a dog.
Do you want to go to lunch, or not?
Nicki, I've got to go see the professor.
They're giving you a hard time, aren't they?
I'm your faculty advisor.
Maybe there's something I can do.
- I don't think so.
- I would like to try.
You have a talent for science.
Let's start with that.
No matter what anybody
says or does to you...
...don't lose sight of your goals.
All I wanted was to study hard
and become a veterinarian.
I can help you with that.
You're a very bright young man, Todd.
You'll find a way to deal
with your other problems.
If you only knew, Professor Brooks.
I'll do my very best to try and understand.
In any case,
I'm always here if you need me.
Okay.
I hope you're hungry.
I got a ton of stuff here.
You like chicken, don't you?
- Why are you doing this?
- Because I'm hungry.
Drumstick?
You know what I mean.
Listen.
Biologically speaking,
it's absolutely fascinating...
...what's happened to you.
If you think I'm going to feel sorry for you,
you can forget it.
But I'm a dog.
You'll be okay.
You will.
One, two, three. Come on.
You're outta here.
Bring the doctor in here.
- How many does that make?
- Three for them. None for us.
Okay, you're up next, big guy.
Coach, it isn't my weight class.
That'll be my problem, okay? Go on.
What do I... What if I...
You got to be kidding. That guy's a tub.
He outweighs my guy by 50 pounds.
It's all water weight. Look at him.
All right, Chubby, look tough.
Let's box.
- What are you doing?
- Put him down.
- Put me down!
- I'm warning you.
All right. Let's box.
- You pig!
- I'm warning you. Come on.
Come on.
Use your weight, Chub.
Break loose!
All right. Come on, get over there.
That's the last fight you win.
All right, Chubby.
All right, Gus. Take him, babe.
Get out there, babe. All right.
Get in there.
Let's box!
You're next.
Next!
Don't worry,
there's a good hospital on campus.
Let's get this over with,
I got a date in a half hour.
Let's go, Big Blue, let's go!
This makes or breaks your career.
We want a knock out!
Let's go, Pug!
You're going to die.
I know.
Move!
Knock him out!
Great move!
I'll break your kneecaps
if you don't keep still and let me hit you.
Come on, Pug!
All right.
Yeah! All right, get back over there.
Come on.
You're history.
I knew Pug would win that fight.
You okay, kid?
- One, two.
- Todd, get up. Come on!
Get up! Don't lay there like a fish.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Holy shit!
What is this?
It's that dog you were dancing with.
You want to stop the fight?
Hell, no. Go on.
All right. Box!
Stay away from him.
Nail him.
What are you doing?
Get in there and kill him.
He's got a right hook. He can fight.
Murder him!
You're out.
Have no fear, Stiles is here.
We're going to rock 'n' roll.
The brewskis are coming, everybody.
We're going to have a party.
We're going to have so much fun.
We need music!
Is this thing on? Can you hear me?
Ladies and gentlemen...
... we have a very special guest
with us this evening.
Not only does our teen wolf
throw a punch like lightning...
... but he sings, too.
"You broke my heart
"'Cause I couldn't dance
"You didn't even want me around
"But now I'm back
"To let you know
"I can really shake 'em down
"Do you love me?
"Now do you love me?
"Now that I can dance
"Watch me now
"Work it out, baby
"You're drivin' me crazy
"With just a little bit of soul now
"Yeah
"And I can mash potatoes
"I can do the twist
"Tell me, baby
"Do you like it like this?
"Tell me
"Do you love me?
"Now do you love me?
"Now that I can dance
"Watch me now
"Work it out, baby
"You're drivin' me crazy
"Don't get lazy
"I can mash potatoes
"I can do the twist
"Tell me, baby
"Do you like it like this?
"Tell me
"Do you love me?
"Now that I can dance
"Crazy"
We've arrived!
Look what I got.
Boys and girls of all ages...
...come and see Stiles, the man.
I've got the stuff for you.
Break!
The championship,
it's just two weeks away.
It's down to just you and that wolf.
Any predictions?
Every dog has his day, and his is mine.
Hello?
- Emily.
- Stiles.
- Yeah?
- Go away.
What?
You don't mind, do you, buddy?
Lisa!
- Todd!
- Stiles, beat it.
Chubby?
What?
I've created a monster.
Okay, so I was absent
the day you guys did this.
Are you mad at me?
- You're jealous.
- What?
Of those two leeches
you've been hanging around with?
You can't even see it, can you?
They don't like you, only the wolf.
Just because everything's
going great for me...
...doesn't give you
the right to go off and start judging...
You just hit me with a dead frog.
Jerk.
Frog fight!
Incoming!
What is going on here?
Frog fighting in my lab?
Put those things away.
That's the end of class for today.
Except for you.
I want to talk to you.
I've been talking
with your other professors.
I know about the car,
about the grades you're getting...
...and how you're coasting through.
It's like anything else in life.
When you have a gift,
you have a responsibility to use it wisely.
You're not.
And you're only letting yourself down.
Are you in a hurry?
Yeah, actually, I have to get to practice.
Team's nothing without the wolf.
You can't face life as a wolf
and expect it to solve all your problems.
You do realize you have finals coming up,
don't you?
Yeah. Regional finals.
No. Course finals.
Listen, I don't think I need this class.
You told me to choose the right path.
And with the road that I've chosen...
...I don't think I need biology at all.
I'm very sorry to hear that.
You waited for me?
I don't know why.
You know, I never thought I'd say it,
but I miss the old Todd.
What happened?
He turned into a werewolf.
But that's not the real you.
The wolf lets me do what I want to do.
Okay? It's a gift.
I've a responsibility to myself...
Responsibility?
What about school?
What about wanting to be a veterinarian?
What about you and me?
My feelings for you are real.
They have nothing to do with the wolf.
Those others could care less
about the real you.
Look, I'm late, and you're wrong.
That's the way it's done, girls.
Watch this.
We'll play through.
How can you take him seriously?
He's a freshman...
...with an awful lot of hair.
Why don't you shut your mouth?
Why don't we settle this man to man?
- I don't fight chipmunks.
- Not here, Gus.
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
You die in the ring, pal.
Fore!
It's in the hole.
You guys studying?
Yes. Some of us
actually have to take finals.
Mr. Stilinsky...
...what say you, me, and the wolf...
...take the wheels for a little...
...spin?
Nope.
No?
How about you, big guy?
I might even let you drive.
What do you say?
I'm busy. Okay?
See you, Stiles.
See you, Chub.
Shot a 46.
You know, it's funny.
I wanted you to become the wolf
more than anybody else.
So I guess I'm partly to blame
for what you've become.
What have I become?
A jerk, Todd.
Thank you for coming.
I really need to talk to you.
You're in a tough spot?
Yeah.
I just let it get out of hand.
I mean, I know you warned me.
And I guess I should
have listened because...
I got a little crazy, Uncle Harold.
I ended up hurting a lot of people
that I really care about.
What are you going to do about it?
I don't know.
I really don't know.
Don't be too tough on yourself.
After all, you're only human, too.
So?
So, you made a mistake.
You admitted it. It's over.
Maybe it's time
you were Todd Howard again.
I'm scared.
Really scared.
I mean, if I'm myself in this ring tomorrow,
I'll get killed.
I don't think you're going to get killed.
This guy's really big.
- He's huge.
- Never mind him...
...because what I'm interested in is you
and what you've got right there.
What's that got to do with boxing
when the guy's twice your size?
- Uncle Harold, I wouldn't stand a chance.
- Maybe not.
Sometimes, you have to make a stand...
...even if it's the last thing you want to do.
- What's that?
These are boxing gloves.
They used to belong to me.
It may surprise you,
but when I was in college...
...I did a fair bit of boxing myself.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Maybe I can show you a couple of moves
nobody's seen in the last 30 years.
- When's this big match?
- Tomorrow.
Plenty of time.
- What are you doing?
- Studying.
I still have two more finals.
I guess you wouldn't know about that.
I'm real sorry...
...for everything.
I guess the wolf makes you a jerk.
No.
I'm a jerk.
I just hope that...
...there's still time to make up for it all.
There's still time to try.
I want to try.
You can start by saying
you're really sorry...
...for mistreating someone you like.
I'm sorry for mistreating someone...
...I really love.
You missed your final.
What?
Your final.
I'm sure Professor Brooks flunked you.
Maybe we could talk to her.
Yeah.
We were just coming to see you.
I know I probably don't deserve it...
...but if you're willing
to give me a second chance...
...I’d really like to earn my grade.
You can take a make-up exam
tomorrow at 12:00 noon.
That's the latest I can give it.
I have to turn the grades in
by the end of the day.
I have a fight at 3:00, see?
The test takes three hours.
You ought to just make it.
That's my final offer. Take it or leave it.
- We'll take it!
- Yeah, thank you very much!
It's time.
Good luck on your test.
Thanks.
And at the match.
Will you come see me box?
Yeah.
- Good luck.
- Bye.
That's the best I could do.
I missed a few classes.
It looks like
you did well enough to pass the course.
Great.
I really want to thank you
for trying to help...
...when things got a little crazy.
Welcome back.
Where've you been?
Taking a final.
Where's the wolf?
What are you doing? You got to go fight
in the 145-pound class now.
That's Peter's weight class.
Yeah, so what?
Look, coach, we are a team.
We're going to fight as a team.
By the way, I am going up against Gus.
That's great.
All of you, go out there
and get your brains knocked out.
That'll be attractive.
"Hamilton
"Thou art highest of them all
"We, your loyal subjects
"Are listening for your call
"Proud are we of your emblem
"Of your columns straight and...
White!
"White
"So let's get in the ring, boys
"And fight, fight, fight"
This is only the beginning.
From here, we go to the state finals,
then the nationals, the Olympics!
Remember, this is only your first year.
What you've got to do is fight and win...
...I’ll take care of the rest.
Grades, cars...
...money, women!
It'll be our little secret.
I hope you don't have any funny ideas
about not fighting as the wolf.
Oh, no.
Remember, I still run this school!
I hold your scholarship.
Give 'em hell, kid.
"Way to go, Hamilton,
way to go, fight, fight!"
Ready, and...
"Hamilton says, for all to see
"We're gonna float like a butterfly
"And sting like a bee
"We know how to punch
"We know how to fight
"We're gonna hit 'em with the left
"Then we'll hit 'em with the right"
Okay, Peter!
You're next! Go on up!
I'm sorry. I'm busy right now.
I know what you're doing.
I know about the car, the grades...
...and the promises.
I want you to lay off.
Todd Howard has a future at this school,
but it's not in the ring.
Who do you think you're talking to?
He'll do exactly as I say.
You don't own him.
Is this your idea of a threat?
No.
This is.
You don't know who you're dealing with.
All right, Chubby! Come on!
Box!
Let's go.
Come on.
He's out. Let him go.
Come on. Put him down.
Put him down so I can count.
- Let's go. Come on.
- Good night.
He's out!
Chubby!
Come on out, dude.
Ladies and gentlemen!
Welcome to the Hamilton University...
... Memorial Arena!
Now entering the arena,
three-time state champion...
... from the Nimitz Academy...
... weighing in at 200 pounds...
... Steve "Gus" Gustavson!
All right!
Steve "Gus" Gustavson!
Number one!
Come on!
Now entering the arena...
... weighing in at 195
wild and wooly pounds...
... Hamilton's own Todd "The Wolf" Howard!
Wolf!
Todd "The Wolf" Howard!
Where's the wolf?
- What are you doing?
- Come on!
Are you crazy?
Come on!
Man!
What is the meaning of this?
Tactics.
I'll have him kicked out of this college!
Bring out the wolf!
Dean Dunn.
I won't be needing these anymore.
It's my last fight.
Good. I hope he kills you.
He probably will.
- You sure you know what you're doing?
- Are you kidding?
It pays to be positive, big guy.
Come on!
Box!
He made such a great wolf.
Kill him, Todd!
Come on. Hit me.
Come on. Hit me. Right here.
My grandmother hits harder than that.
Take that!
Come on!
Good round!
- Try that with me!
- What are you? Come on.
- Let go.
- Calm down.
- Round's over.
- Good round.
Back up! Look, I'm warning you.
- Are you listening to me?
- Yeah.
Cut the ring off on him.
- How you doing?
- All right.
You feeling okay?
Keep them in, keep them tight,
keep them up. How's the ribs?
Chubby, give me some.
How's the jaw?
- Listen, I'm sorry I called the wolf a jerk.
- Don't worry, I was a jerk.
If you don't turn back into the jerk,
you'll get us both killed.
It's got to be this way.
Coach, got anything to say to me?
No.
- Go out and kick some butt, Todd!
- Take him now!
Break!
- Step back.
- He's a baby!
Let's box.
Come on. Get up.
Break!
- Let go, you sissy.
- Break! Come on, let's go.
Break, I say. Box!
Come on. Sit down.
- That's an early bell!
- I said, "Sit down!"
God.
Come on ref,
keep your eyes open over there.
Listen, unless you're planning on
wolfing out on this guy...
...I suggest we throw in
the proverbial towel.
I'm not quitting.
Teen Wolf Too!
Don't worry. It's not as bad as it looks.
You're way ahead on points, okay?
You got both rounds.
Keep fighting the same fight.
Look at his face over there.
That guy's in trouble. You got it? Go!
Touch gloves.
Last round. Box!
Go, Todd, go!
Do it!
- I'm gonna make you howl with pain.
- It's gonna be a long night.
Come on. Back in the ring. Let's go!
He's going to kill him.
Somebody do something!
Don't worry. He'll be all right.
Are you all right?
Get back in there.
- Where are you going?
- Home.
Okay. Let's box.
One.
Two, three.
Four.
Get up!
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight, nine.
Come on, dog. Fight like a man.
Give me your best shot.
Break.
Step back. Box!
He's out!
The new regional champion
from Hamilton University...
... Todd Howard!