Sub resynced by: PEEAN91
credits to original uploader
Behold.
Before you are the most
popular students
At ashley high school.
In a world governed by
the laws of teenage physics,
These girls are
the gravitational force
All else revolves-
around which
Royalty, if you will.
With an iron fashion sense.
And they rule their kingdom
But if you think the royal
treatment is all they seek,
Don't be fooled.
A queen isn't really a queen
until she gets...
Her crown.
It's prom. Prom.
You need a date, or
it's a reflection on me.
Not just anybody.
A-list. A-list.
Two varsity letters are better. Two.
Okay, okay.
A-list, two letters.
Got it.
Good.
And these poor dears
Are ashley high school's
least popular students.
Isolated from
the mainstream,
Our outcasts retreat
each afternoon
To a dank garage,
Making little piggy movies
That other outcasts
will watch
From their own dreary rooms.
The pig still
looks tense.
It can't be tense
for this shot.
Relax, pig.
Clear.
Cut, cut, cut,.
I'm not feeling
the drama.
We gotta go bigger,
much bigger.
Rarely do these two groups
And that's really
for the best.
I don't want any ninth- or
tenth-grade votes screwing this up.
Absolutely.
We'll round them up.
Round them up.
You're going
to be prom queen.
God, amber,
what do you want?
Every vote
in the whole school?
Yes.
Remember that sad sickly
boy who died last year?
I want his vote.
Is anybody unclear?
Because I think
it's pretty simple.
So clear.
Like crystal.
Good.
oink, oink. Snore.
And go.
And music.
Crazy pig turns up
the volume.
Crazy pig goes overboard.
Pigs are exploding,
and I'm getting nothing.
It's just empty noise.
Maybe lisa should
speed it up a little bit.
I have an idea.
Yes! Finally!
Another artist to help carry the load.
Great, lisa.
Oh, good.
No one's in here.
Uh, excuse me.
Oh, forgive us-
Amber pollock
needs this room
Important
strategy meeting.
Now, get out.
Hey. You don't
own this school.
Watch out, girls.
The elf bites.
Yeah, she's right.
You can't do this.
It-it's not-
Well, it's just not-
What's the matter?
Piggy got your tongue?
No, carlita. More like
having no life got her tongue.
Go.
As you can see,
When populars
and unpopulars collide,
It's not pretty.
Nevertheless,
it's sometimes inevitable-
Fate, as it were.
But I'm getting
ahead of myself.
Easy to do when
you're omniscient.
So, I'll just let
our tale unfold
And say no more.
Not another word.
Absolutely finished now.
Mom?
Can you come up here?
Mom's on the phone.
Tell her I want her
to see my dress.
Mom, she wants you
to see her dress!
I'm working!
For god's sake.
I think you look
pretty, amber.
Whatever.
Look, we can't
represent these people
If they're just gonna
second-guess me
What is so important?
Do you like it?
What, the dress?
It's fine.
I was thinking maybe I could
wear your diamond hoops?
You know,
for good luck,
Since you wore them
when you won prom queen.
Amber, please don't tell me you're
relying on luck to win you a crown.
You have to reach out and
take the things you want.
I know. I just wanted
to show you my-
Oh, I had
another thought.
Yes. Right.
I think we should
delay...
It's just darling.
Ha ha ha!
Oh, no one will know
it was mine.
Yeah, it's been so long,
all the witnesses are dead.
Stop it.
Tonight can be fun
If you just let it be.
Are you gonna help me out
at all with this?
Honey, I know you're feeling
awkward going without a date,
But the school website said
there'll be lots of solo kids.
There's no stigma
to it.
No stigma at all.
Welcome, losers.
Hush. That is not the
attitude to walk in there with.
I said I'd go.
That's all you get.
Hey, you know what? I think
that's the dress I was wearing
When we made you.
Right, henry?
Stop.
Oh, he was such a tiger
back then.
Mom... Stop.
I know, I know.
"if accepted at juilliard...
I would be... "
So freakin' grateful
to have an actual life.
"if accepted...
"I would bring
my great enthusiasm
"for all musical forms...
Including voice
and composition. "
Hey!
I didn't think
I'd see you here! Ha!
Hey, nick,
how's it going?
What's up, man?
You ready for this?
Sure, nick.
I'd love to dance.
Just let me get rid of
my imaginary date first.
Here you go.
Heh. Seriously?
Paisley, we're here. Great.
Voting just ended.
Perfect timing.
What are you doing?
Dropping you off. There
aren't any close spots.
You don't really expect the queen
to walk in there alone, do you?
I need to make
an entrance.
Yeah, but I'm
not gonna-
Make a spot. Now.
oh, man.
Don't worry
about it, really.
Come on! Move it!
Hey, amber!
Hey, girl!
What's up, amber?
Yes, indeed.
Let's give it up
for mixmaster ashley eagle!
And, as our hard-working
vote committee
Is tallying up the results,
I'd like to welcome
all of the students tonight
Feel better, barry?
Awesome. Ah.
I've just been handed
an envelope.
I wonder what's inside.
What do you think,
mixmaster?
All right.
Now, this year's
ashley high school
Holy toledo! For the first time
in school history,
A unanimous decision...
Amber pollock!
Yes!
Amber, no!
It's too dangerous!
That crown is mine.
It's okay, it's okay.
I'm all right.
Stand back,
don't touch her.
People, hey...
I'm over here.
No, not moving at all.
Oh, yeah.
As a doornail.
No! I can't be dead!
This is so unfair!
I had it in my hands.
Are you kidding me?
I always knew heaven
wouldn't allow nasty cuticles.
Do you have
an appointment?
But no one's even here.
That's because they all
have their own place to wait.
Oh, so...
This isn't heaven?
Let's just say it's
kind of halfway-
Like limbo-
made just for you.
Ah. Amber pollock.
Date of death-
right now.
Can you believe how
speedy these gadgets are?
I really think
they're the future.
Oh. Oh, well...
Weren't you a nasty
piece of business.
What's that supposed
to mean?
Ashley high
consensus says...
"queen bitch".
Pretty hellish,
I'd say.
Hellish? That doesn't
mean I'm going to-
Not as yet.
Your life arc
was interrupted
Before reaching
its full formation,
So you're getting an
opportunity to raise your scores.
Putting it
in high school terms,
You're, like,
getting an extension.
Oh. So, I'm, like,
repeating a grade?
I have to go back?
Not in corporeal form.
You'll be more like
a spirit.
And you'll have a specific
task to accomplish.
If you succeed,
it's wings and a harp,
Never a bad hair day, and
you'll always be model-thin.
If you fail, well...
How do you look
in asbestos?
oh, lookie here.
The task they've given
you is rather ironic,
Since you were very nearly
crowned prom queen.
Oh, it was unanimous,
you know.
Lucky you.
You must take
the least popular student
And get this individual
elected queen
What?
And here she is-
The misshapen
lump of clay
That you must mold.
She doesn't go
to my school.
Lisa sommers.
Been in your class
for eight years.
She was your lab partner
in freshman biology.
No. I've never
seen her in my life.
Maybe this will help.
That girl?
Prom queen?
That's a joke.
Listen, sister,
you have one week.
Is best expressed
by those closest
To the one we have lost.
Thank you to those
who showed up today.
Well, this seems to be it,
so we might as well start.
Is this all for me?
So, I'd like to invite those
who were closest to amber
To come up and share
your love for her.
A memory, an anecdote,
A short story of what
she meant to you.
Let me just say thank you.
Thank you all.
Hello?
We have microphones on
either side of the stage,
So please take
as much time as needed
All right, then.
Hey.
Let's have a moment
of silence for amber.
Oh, honey.
On prom night, of all
nights, she's gotta die.
She promised me
- promised that when she got that crown,
She was finally
gonna let me do her.
I dented my car
because of her.
And what do I get?
Nothing.
This is worse than dying!
Where is my group?
Where are my girls?
That was beautiful.
I will now unveil
the memorial portrait
That will hang
on the wall
Where we
hang pictures
Oh! You like the photo I picked?
Stop laughing, all of you!
I demand you
to stop laughing now!
Amber?
Do you see
what I see?
I see justice.
Why, what do you see?
no! No!
Lisa?
Okie-dokie.
That was so moving.
Well, the Saturday
committees
For make-up prom
Will meet after lunch.
And let's make it a
safe one, okay, people?
Where are you all going?
This is so wrong.
You all love me.
Somebody say something now.
I'm popular!
I'm tmost popular!
You! You can see me.
Mm-mm. No.
No, I can't.
You can see me,
and you can hear me.
Mm-mm! Wait, come back!
I need to talk to you!
There you are.
Stay right there.
Whoa.
That was kind of cool.
Hey.
Oh. Hello.
That's 20 minutes of my
life I'm never getting back.
Hey, the girl died.
It's genuinely sad.
Show a little respect.
Aw, bless you,
nameless nerd boy.
And everyone wonders
why I never date.
Chicks are just crazy.
It's just stress, lisa.
That's all.
Music school applications,
senior anxiety.
It's a natural reaction.
You know, this whole
"you run, I chase" thing
Is getting
boring fast.
Why are you here?
What did I do?
Nothing,
from what I can tell.
It's whi'm
gonna do for you.
Get out of here. Now.
Hey,
it's a public bathroom.
Yes, of course.
Okay, I'll give you
five minutes.
Just not in here.
Prom queen-
Me?
Yep, by Saturday.
Okay. Joke's over.
Lisa sommers officially
looks like a fool.
Hooray to whoever's
doing this.
Do you really think I
could make all this up?
I have to admit,
you're not that smart.
Excuse me!
It just doesn't
make sense.
Why would I
want to help you?
Because... I'm the only
one that can help you.
Don't you see? I can make you popular.
I don't want
to be popular.
Oh. Poor thing.
Everyone wants
to be popular.
In five days
with me in charge,
You'll be the talk
of the school.
Everyone
will be wondering,
"what's liza wearing
today? What's liza thinking?
Where's liza going
tonight?"
It's lisa.
Well, if you're popular,
people would know that.
My friends
know my name.
All two of them?
Three!
Okay, mousy bits, if you
don't want to be popular,
What exactly
do you want?
I want to get
out of here.
I want to go
to music school.
I want to live in a world
where they don't judge you
By how many people want
to sit with you at lunch.
Instead...
They appreciate
the fact
That your playlist not only
has the newest gaga,
But all of
haydn's symphonies,
Charles ives'
concord sonata,
And the ella fitzgerald
songbooks,
Because they're
all magic works of genius,
And they transport me.
You done yet?
You're deader
than I am.
And you're
a vacuous shrew.
Come on! You have
to do this for me,
Otherwise they're sending me
to hell, and I don't want to go.
Why? There'll be so many
people just like you.
I can't believe you
don't want to help me.
You know what?
I don't think I'm gonna get
another chance to say this
And really
make it happen,
But, for all I care,
you can go to hell.
She's stubborn,
doesn't listen to reason,
And she only cares about
what she wants. I hate her!
Why? Too much
like yourself?
I offered her the greatest
gift of high school-
Complete popularity.
And she tells me
to go to hell.
Amber,
dear, sweet child,
Sometimes we can't
accomplish a task
Simply by browbeating
the weak.
Why not?
Often-
And I know this is a
radical notion for you-
We must actually think
of the other person.
But that sounds
really hard.
Very well, then. We won't put
you through any more of this.
hello, this is j-3
in arbitration.
I have
a miss amber pollock.
She's given up and is
ready for processing.
Uh-huh.
I'll ask.
Would you prefer being
slowly skinned by demons,
Or having your pretty nails
pulled out, one by one?
I know. Hard to imagine clawing
your way past the little people
Without ten little talons of
sinful ruby rouge number 17.
Tacky, by the way.
I guess I can give lisa
one more shot.
You'd do that for her?
How sweet.
Uhh!
You have ghostly powers.
Use them.
Lise, I've been
waiting for you.
I didn't want to
come up behind you
'cause I noticed
you were kind of jumpy.
What? Wha-wha-
what makes you say that?
The fact that you're...
Kind of jumpy.
Are you okay?
What happened
this morning?
Can I ask you
something?
But you have to promise
to keep it between us.
Come on,
we're best friends.
What if I told you amber
pollock visited me today?
You mean, like,
as a ghost,
Or some kind of spirit?
Ohh. Just hearing
the words out loud
Makes it seem
even more crazy.
Forget I said
anything.
Lise, you're
freaking me out.
Are you really
seeing amber?
I don't know, selena.
Maybe this is just some
kind of freakish dream.
Or maybe I'm actually unconscious
from a dangerously high fever
That's causing me
to hallucinate,
And hopefully sweat off that
donut I ate this morning.
Or maybe I'm just
going completely insane.
Okay, not true. A lot
of people see ghosts.
My aunt marielle
- she sees them all the time.
Of course,
there was that one week
When she only bathed
in ketchup.
But she's not insane.
And she says that ghosts
are nothing to mess with.
So, you better
be careful here.
You know what?
I don't even have time
To think about this
right now.
Whatever it was
is gone, thank god,
And I have to concentrate on
the real things in my life.
You mean you're gonna
go out to the field
And pretend to do your homework
while you stare at nick ramsey?
Okay, so, it's more
of a delusion,
But, uh, I'm
comfortable with it.
As long as you're sure
you're okay.
Yeah. Thanks.
Hey, nick!
This one's to you!
Oh. Nick ramsey.
Uhh. Please get out
of my life.
Whoo! Yay, nick!
Nice butt!
Good choice.
Choice? He doesn't
even know I'm alive.
I could get him
for you.
What if I told you
I could have you
in his arms like that?
Yeah, right.
Blue 42! Hut! Hike!
Heads up! Look out!
Are you okay?
Oh-
You're lisa sommers,
right?
You and your friends make
those clay pig movies?
I watch them online.
They're funny.
Lisa. I'm-
I'm lisa.
Nick! You done
over there, man?
I gotta go.
A lot more where
that came from.
He has strong hands.
And he's just
between girlfriends.
Perfect time
to make your move.
No, no, I can't.
I'm just-I'm not-
No, no, no.
I'm not. I'm not.
Well said.
We were almost friends
in the seventh grade.
A bunch of us
went over to his house
To watch him feed
his pet snake.
Then everything changed
over the summer.
Some girls got breasts. I
got braces and piano lessons.
And he got tall
and athletic.
And we all know
how that turned out.
I always wondered
what might've happened
If I just had
the courage to say,
"hey, nick, cool snake,"
you know?
You're like a human
sleeping pill.
Please don't ever talk
like that on a date.
But he knows my name.
And he's seen
pig tales.
Maybe I should leave him
a cool little message
In the next movie.
Look, I only have
five days.
You don't have to like me,
but I know how to hook a boy.
Are you really willing to pass that up?
Okay, it all starts
with how you look.
I know, I know. It's what's
on the inside that counts-
Blah, blah-which only ugly
people say, by the way.
But we're talking about
hardball high school popularity,
Which is based on looks
by about...
Hmm, 170%.
And the good news is,
you're not ugly...
Exactly.
You just gotta work
on your presentation.
And that's what
my life is all about.
Was.
Okay, fine. Was.
That's why we're
doing this together.
You're gonna help me
get into heaven,
And I'm gonna help
get nick into you.
Emotionally.
Wait.
That's my sister.
That's clementine.
God,
she looks so sad.
I wonder
what happened.
You died on Saturday.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, listen,
I gotta go.
I'll catch you
later.
In the meantime,
wax.
Everything.
Hey, mom.
Did you go to the office at all today?
Your sister got into
washington college.
I didn't even know
she applied.
Why didn't she tell me?
I did tell you.
Sdid tell you.
But you said
I wasn't good enough
To get into the school
where you went.
Now what do I do
with this?
I'm gonna
start dinner,
'cause people get
hungry, you know?
You did it, honey...
With no help from me.
You went out and got it.
I'll be damned.
Hmm.
You-lisa sommers-
Actually spoke
to nick ramsey?
Mm-hmm. I did.
Clear.
Perfecto.
Click me off
two frames, raj.
It's speaking to me,
people.
Let's pick it up.
Today you finally
talked to him
After five years
of slack-jawed gawking.
Mm-hmm. I don't know,
things just-
Things just happen.
It was weird.
No, they don't.
Not with you.
Clear.
Wait, wait, cut. I want to
shoot this next one from above.
Let's go outside
and grab the ladder.
Are you sure
you're okay?
Because earlier, things
got a little, well...
You know.
Of course.
I'm better than okay.
I'm thinking of running
for prom queen.
What?
Okay.
Who was the first boy
that ever tried to kiss me,
And when did it happen?
What are you-
just answer the question.
It was
your cousin leo...
At your grandma's house
when you were ten.
What the hell
is wrong with you?
I had to make sure
it was still you in there.
Seriously? Prom queen?
Who are you?
Prom queen.
Hmm.
♪ no, I don't care ♪
♪ don't want to be
typical ♪
♪ you could say
everything to me... ♪
Mom? Hello?
♪ no, I don't care ♪
♪ don't want
to be typical- ♪
Excuse me.
Nice voice
in there, girl.
And the sweet tune
- is that something you wrote?
Have you ever heard
of a thing called privacy?
I knew I had my work
cut out for me, but this-
Please! I mean, nothing
goes with anything.
The salvation army would
reject this entire closet.
You're not going
to school today.
What? Why?
You're calling in
unattractive.
We're gonna go
to the mall
And get you some outfits
from this time period.
Are you all right?
Did you see your sister?
Yeah, I saw her.
Is she okay?
Let's just focus
on the job at hand,
Which is making you
look better.
I could use a little
of your help.
Lise, were you talking to somebody?
No.
Not really.
Mom, I was thinking of
skipping school today
So maybe I could go
buy a new outfit
For Saturday's
make-up prom.
Are you crazy?
You can't tell your mom you're cutting.
You want to buy
a new outfit?
Oh, honey!
That's wonderful!
Do you need money? I'll just take
some out of your dad's wallet.
So, do you always tell
your parents the truth?
I mean, like, what do
you do when you sneak out?
I don't sneak out.
Come on. Even amish
girls sneak out to...
Raise a barn
or something.
Did you have to
make it this hard?
Try on
that blue outfit.
How do you like it?
This is not me.
That's the point.
If they sold you here,
they'd go out of business.
I cannot wear
something like this.
Why? Someone might
find out you're cute?
I am not cute.
I hate to be the one
to deliver the bad news,
But you are.
You've got boobs,
Which you seem to be in
denial about, and actual legs,
Which you could
show off on occasion.
And...
A perfectly nice little
butt, I have to say.
Are you coming on to me?
Honey...
I'm telling you
what guys like.
And it's not
that complicated.
Now, zip it down.
Hike it up.
The dress.
Now do this.
No, I refuse.
Do it.
Think of nick.
You're not ready
for that.
Let's stick to the
clothes. Hold that one up.
No, you couldn't pull it off. Could.
Oh, I would so kill
in that dress.
How'd you do that?
I don't know.
I thought I was gonna be stuck
in that prom dress forever.
Oh, my god.
I have fashion powers!
Ha ha!
You told her we're meeting
for lunch, right?
You were standing
right there, colin.
Then she must be
sick or something.
Well, she'd better not
be blowing us off.
Who said we were
being blown off?
She-she wouldn't do that.
Hmm. How about a shorter
cut with some highlights?
No.
Okay. What about
a swoop bang
And some lowlights?
I don't think so.
Maybe we should just
turn the lights off.
Hey.
We can dye it blond.
Bad idea.
I know what'll
fix this mess.
Let's add
some length.
Oh, that's nice.
Now, every girl needs
her signature scents
That their boy
can find in the dark.
Great. So, it's like
being sniffed out by a dog.
look at that.
What? Zac efron boy over there.
He's not
looking at me.
Well, he's sure not
This is perfect-
a starter boy.
Call him over.
I don't know his name.
Hi.
Um... I never know what
to say to a pretty girl.
Well, that's not
a bad start.
Say it. That's not a bad start.
Damn cute, isn't he?
Just say hi.
Hi.
Hi, my name's aiden.
Now tell him your name.
Back off.
I'm sorry, I was just-
No, no, no, no.
You're fine.
Oh.
I'm lisa.
And I have to go.
What?
Right now?
Yep. I was just here
buying things for my prom,
And now I'm done.
What are you doing?
He's great.
If I come by tomorrow,
will I see you?
I don't know.
Probably not.
Bye.
You just discarded
a perfect good boy.
Congrats.
What if it led
to something?
What if he
asked me out?
This is about nick, not
some cute guy in a store.
These moral convictions
of yours
Are only getting
in the way.
Everybody's gonna
laugh at me.
They're gonna say, "who
are you trying to fool?"
I'm going home.
No, you're not.
Do you want to be
an unpopular nonentity
For the rest
of your life?
Yes. I'm good at it.
This is about confidence.
Nobody actually has it.
You just
have to project it.
I'm out.
No, you're not.
That was so weird. What
the hell just happened?
I don't know.
But I love that
I can do that.
Would you stop fighting me?
What am I supposed to do?
Nothing. Let me drive.
No. Yes. No! Yes!
Go!
This is amazing.
Quiet!
Morning, boys.
Could you do me
the hugest favor?
I need your signature for
my prom queen petition?
Would you mind?
Thank you.
Luke, that's a great shirt.
Looks so good on you.
Kyle, did you get
a haircut? 'cause it works.
This is fun.
What the hell
happened to her?
She's obviously
not sick.
She looks great-
like a different person.
Yeah, a person
crying for help.
Oh, my god, what a rush!
Is this what popularity
feels like?
Yes. And that's
just a taste.
You want to fly solo?
Can I?
Let's see it.
No, no, no.
Not them.
They have no heat. You
need to seek the heat.
Yes. Nice.
That's some heat.
Hi, adam.
Lisa, is that you?
Would you do me the
giant-est favor in the world?
Have you been
working out?
Like, at the gym
and stuff?
Yeah. See you.
Well, look at you, all
talking to the boys.
I'm gonna walk down this
hallway for the rest of my life.
Hey, has anybody here not signed
carlita's prom queen petition?
carlita's running
against me?
I mean, against you?
Is that bad?
It's terrible.
I taught her everything.
She'll annihilate us.
Come on.
You're amber pollock.
What does she have
that we don't?
Nick.
I thought you said he
was between girlfriends.
That's not between.
That's on.
Did you see
that kiss?
How could carlita
do this to me?
That crown was mine to
give, and I didn't pick her.
That wannabe is not
sending me to hell.
He's never gonna put his big
strong hand on my butt again.
We can still
get him for you...
As soon as we stop
carlita.
We just have to figure
out what her next move is.
How?
Gee, I don't know.
It's not like
one of us is invisible
And can walk through walls
or anything.
Here he comes.
Looks like he's
getting over amber.
So, how come you didn't
go for brandon?
And look like I'm
picking up amber's scraps?
No. That's a loser move.
I wanted somebody
on the way up-nick.
Smart move.
Way up. Nick.
She's in my seat.
All right, guys,
Friday night,
Everybody who's cool...
Will be at my house.
Next day...
Everybody's buzzing
about it,
Which carries right into the
prom voting Saturday night.
So, it has to be
a great party.
Uh... Mm.
Paisley, can you get
your stoner brother
To stop playing video games
long enough to buy us beer?
Good. And, dakota...
"dakota... "
Your friend's band-
panda house- get them.
But they don't do
parties anymore.
Tell them you'll
sleep with them.
Okay.
All right, these are
all the important people.
Oh, um, why not invite
everybody to the party?
Paisley, you still need
a ruling class
For the pathetic people
to look up to.
If I invite the masses, I
come off as... Approachable.
And that's dead.
Not stupid
amber electrocution dead,
But pretty close.
You... Look thirsty.
Let's roll, girls.
Oh.
The world has people
for that.
Heh.
Uhh!
Thanks, aunt marielle.
You're the only one
who can help me.
Give me the photos.
Something is
definitely going on.
I don't if she's trying
to take over lisa's body,
Or steal her soul,
or god knows what.
But I'm not giving up my
best friend without a fight.
We must break her grip
and deliver this amber
To her ultimate
destination.
But how? We can't
even see her.
You don't see spirits
with your eyes.
You see them with...
Inner vision.
Like eyes...
Inside your body.
And you wonder why people
think you're a whack-job?
do you want
to see the ghost?
Yes.
I will attempt
to conjure her
From these photos.
She was very powerful
in life, wasn't she?
Think medusa with blond
snakes and killer pumps.
Now, this amber-
Her soul is in peril, and
your friend is the key.
Does that mean
lisa's in danger?
It does.
Their bond is strong.
There's only one way
to stop her.
Tell me.
What's the last thing
amber touched
Before she left
this plane?
I know.
And I'm gonna get it.
I'm gonna get ya,
ghost bitch.
Carlita's
throwing a party?
Yes, and that's why you're
gonna throw one, too.
Won't hers be better?
Let's just say hers
is gonna run into...
A little trouble.
This one's
still logged on.
Great. That way, they
can't trace it back to you.
This is so wrong.
What's your point?
Write the email?
Right.
Oh, wait. You got
carlita's address wrong.
It's fairview place,
nlane.
Come on.
Ready to send?
I feel almost...
Criminal.
Do you want to feel
almost nick?
Sending.
Oh! It's out there.
Blackberries are jingling,
iphones are shaking,
People are buzzing.
I feel it, too.
Being bad is exciting.
Welcome to life.
Now let's go.
Party time!
What are you doing here?
Party!
The party's tomorrow.
The message.
What message?
I didn't send that.
Say cheese!
No, don't!
What the hell is this?
Get in the car!
Come on, you punk!
I'm calling the police.
Hey, there's
another party!
Lisa, when did you
plan this party?
You know, I just kind of
threw it together.
And my parents got
a free spa weekend,
So you could put
those drinks anywhere.
Lisa, the band's here.
Thank you for doing this
on such short notice.
No problem.
We're gonna go set up.
It was fantastic.
Carlita never knew
what hit her.
Awesome party, lisa.
Have a nice time.
People are really
showing up.
Go ahead and mix. Don't
stay here in the corner,
Talking
to yourself, girl.
Right. That was
the old me.
Actually, the old you
never went to parties.
Right again.
I'd love to stay
and chat, but...
I've got a party
to host.
How do people leave the
house without my help?
Ech.
I'm a little confused.
Why would carlita send us
to a party that isn't hers?
We're checking up on the
competition. It's intelligence.
Oh, cool.
I love being
intelligence.
God, this is such a great
party. Totally great.
It's like something
amber would've done.
You think?
Nick is here. I don't know what to say.
You're not gonna
sanything.
I called carlita,
and she was crying,
And she started
yelling.
I asked her
what happened,
But she just
hung up on me.
I'll tell you
what happened.
Somebody
burned her good.
Huh. Should I
call her again?
No. She'll just
hang up.
Best party
of the year.
So, whose house
is this, anyway?
Lisa sommers-
that music weirdo
Who suddenly turned,
like, red-hot in two days.
So red-hot.
Hmm.
Are you kidding me?
I only do that
in the shower.
That's it, I'm coming in. You cannot-
You cannot make me.
Stop it. Stop it!
Get out of me!
Can you guys do me the
hugest favor in the world?
Just keep it simple
and follow me. Thanks.
♪ so, you think you see
the truth ♪
♪ but you don't have a clue ♪
♪ I'm not someone
who's here to lose ♪
I can't do this.
You already are.
♪ hey, I'm something
new today ♪
♪ so, stay the hell away ♪
♪ unless you got
something to say ♪
♪ you can be anything
you want ♪
♪ give me a reason
why you won't ♪
♪ no, I don't care ♪
♪ don't want to be typical ♪
♪ you can say everything
to me ♪
♪ I know who I am,
and you will see ♪
♪ so, stop and stare ♪
♪ I'm not invisible ♪
♪ not gonna be typical ♪
I'm doing this.
I know.
This is amazing.
Lisa, it's your voice.
I just got you up here. Now,
can I get out so I can watch you?
No, no, no-
♪ someone who's lost ♪
♪ looking for the answer ♪
♪ someone who's scared ♪
♪ I know I can do this ♪
♪ yeah ♪
♪ I can be anything
I want ♪
♪ give me a reason
why I won't ♪
♪ no, I don't care ♪
♪ don't want to be typical ♪
♪ you can say anything to me ♪
♪ I know who I am,
and you will see ♪
♪ so, stop and stare ♪
♪ I'm not invisible ♪
♪ not gonna be typical ♪
♪ oh, not gonna be typical ♪
♪ I'm not gonna be ♪
Thanks for coming.
That-
that was amazing.
The things I have to do
to get your attention.
Nice.
Thank you.
No, thank you.
You really surprised
people tonight.
Did I surprise you?
Yes, you did.
You know, I've kind of
been going out with carlita,
But it's not
really serious.
It's just been
a few days.
Do you remember back in
the seventh grade
When I had
a bunch of people over
To watch me feed jimbo?
You know, my pet snake.
I was thinking about that the other day.
You were there,
right?
Wow.
Seventh grade-
um, maybe.
Who even remembers
that far back?
I'm gonna go tell carlita
things aren't working out.
I would like that.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, my god.
She looks horrible.
So horrible.
I know. I got sent, like,
15 different pictures.
It's just too awful.
So awful.
Do you need me
for this?
I've got it from here.
So, lisa, what are
you doing for lunch?
This is some strange...
I know you're
in there, amber.
Leave my friend alone.
You're messing
with the wrong girl.
Selena, are you okay?
I wiget you.
Isn't it pathetic
How some people can't handle
other people's success?
Hey, lise, how was the big
party we weren't invited to?
As awesome as everyone
who was invited says?
Colin, come on.
She's still our friend.
Is she, now?
Excuse me, boys,
But doesn't the virgin's
club meet during lunch
To polish their
purity rings?
Ohh, golly,
that is so rich.
I'm gonna process that
and laugh at it later-
You know, while you're out
getting your s. T.D. Shots.
Guys, guys, guys.
The party was
a last-minute thing.
I meant to call.
I just-
Only invited
the cool people.
'cause that's how
it works these days.
Colin, would you
give her a chance?
Yeah, it was-
I was-
It was a-
I just-
Got it. Thanks for
clearing that up.
So, listen, we've got to
finish this pig movie tonight.
So, are you there?
Or is being cool your new
full-time gig these days?
Uh-
Sorry I missed
our lunch plans,
But I was too busy
getting this.
For me?
I had no other
creative way to, uh,
Ask you to prom
tomorrow night.
Ahem.
Oh. Yeah. Right.
Guys, uh...
Things have gotten really crazy
in the last couple of days,
And I just-
I don't have time
for the movie right now.
Maybe on
the next one, okay?
I know that was
probably hard.
Skinny and runt boy liked
you when you were nothing.
And, believe me,
you were nothing.
But that was
a bold move.
You know, I think you're
finally getting this.
I'll make it up
to them after prom.
Maybe I'll to rub some of my
new popularity off on them,
And then they'll
understand.
Lisa, hey.
Hey.
I know you got a lot of
new stuff going on,
And that's great.
And colin is-
is colin.
But we need you
on the movie.
We count on you.
I count on you.
I know, raj.
Maybe sometime
next week.
Mr. Kurkuri...
You were logged onto
computer terminal 14
Yesterday after school,
right?
You were also logged on
to that computer
Until this morning.
I guess I forgot
to log off.
Oh, did you, now?
Did you know there
was a bogus email
Sent from that computer
About a social event held by
another student at this school?
That action is
a suspendable offense.
And it also
created damage
Which happened to
another student's house,
Which is something you'll have
to take up with the police.
But I was just
trying to buy a-
Do you know anything
about this?
No, nothing.
But I'm sure
it was just a goof.
A rather serious goof.
Come with me. We're gonna
talk to your parents.
Wow. Well...
That didn't work out
as I expected.
Uh, maybe we should try
to do something about it.
Raj will be fine.
I can't risk getting nailed for
this one day before the prom.
I'm doing this for
both of us, amber.
I need to be
elected queen,
And you need to get
into heaven...
Which we wouldn't have to
worry about if you'd been nicer.
I can be nice.
Sometimes.
Maybe when
you were five,
But that girl's
long gone.
Ooh,
I like your jeans.
I was five.
I miss you.
Are you gonna
do this every day?
I don't know.
I need this form for
my science field trip.
You still haven't
signed it.
I didn't?
You didn't.
You're not looking
at her, mom.
Look at her.
Mom, I'm trying to hold
this house together.
But I could use
a little help.
Do you even hear me?
Amber:
She's crying out for you.
This is it, mom.
You want to
make it up to me,
Do something for her.
For clementine.
Mom!
I'm going to
be there for you.
I haven't been.
I'm gonna do better.
Better.
We'll all be bet-
Mom? Clem?
What's going on?
We're-
we're putting an end
To all your evil ghost
plans, amber pollock.
Excuse me, do we
know each other?
We've only been in the
same class for nine years.
Jeez. Really?
Did you change your
hair or something? No.
Listen, evil one...
We have you now, and you are never
gonna bother lisa sommers again.
You've totally
corrupted her!
I know, I know.
Everything that was
bad about me-
The way I treated people
- it's her now,
And it's
all my fault.
What are you doing?
Is this a trick?
Please let me go.
I have to talk to lisa.
You think that after
what you've done,
We're just gonna
let you free to do more?
Ha!
Selena...
I sense remorse.
And only a spirit can undo
what a spirit has done.
Thank you...
Weird lady.
Well said.
Okay. Okay.
But you have to promise
To turn lisa back into the
nice girl she was before.
I really want to, but
it's not gonna be easy.
I mean, she's hot and
sexy and popular now,
And it's hard
to give up.
You wouldn't know.
Obviously.
Sorry. That slipped.
Oh, my gosh!
Of course!
You're that
mousy brainiac
Who skipped
a grade.
That's me. Smart...
And mousy.
Well, let me just say
you look a lot better now.
But that purple eye shadow
- not helping.
She's right about
the eye shadow.
Go! Save lisa.
Boy, it is great
in here.
You've got the
candles over there.
We've got you and me
right here.
We've got my parents still
out of town till Sunday.
Lisa, we need to talk.
Not now.
Okay.
No, no, you're fine.
Oh.
Seriously.
It's very important.
Now is not a time
for talking.
Oh, yeah.
Wow, that was nice.
I'm not leaving,
you know.
Is something wrong?
No, no, it's perfect.
You're perfect.
I can't stand what
I've done to you.
I've ruined
your life.
My life is fine,
thank you.
Mine, too.
You're self-centered
and shallow.
And it's all
because of me.
And you'll continue to keep
getting more self-centered
And more shallow
unless you stop right now.
I'm not stopping.
Me, neither.
You need to stop. I can't
let you become another me.
So, that's what this is?
You're jealous.
I've become a better you
than you were,
And you can't stand it.
Huh?
Not you.
You thought,
"let me work my magic
On the pathetic ugly duckling
and make her almost presentable. "
But I've surpassed you.
I'm better, hotter,
Smarter... Alive.
You know...
Lise...
You're acting
kind of crazy.
It's hot.
Yeah.
This is important.
If you become prom queen,
It will ruin you.
I need to be crazy
for just one more second.
Okay.
I'm going to become
prom queen,
And you're gonna go
to heaven.
It's a win-win.
Now get out of here.
That's it.
Okay.
This is not hot
anymore.
Uh...
Don't worry about lisa.
I mean... I'm fine.
Nick, honey, we can't
have sex tonight.
Why don't you
just go home?
Whoa. Okay.
Um...
But can we do it
tomorrow night?
Sure. Whatever.
Right after prom.
Just go home.
Okay.
But I'll be
warming up.
Mmm.
Okay.
I'm so sorry I did this
to you, lisa.
Where are we?
No place.
And too far
out of town
To get back
for the prom.
What? Why?
I'm doing this
for you, lisa.
Wait, you're doing this
for you, too.
Don't you want
to go to heaven?
Not that much.
No! No! No!
Don't leave me here!
She's not stopping me.
I'm getting to that prom.
I have lots of friends.
I'm popular.
All I have to do
is call one of them,
And they'll be crawling all over
each other to come rescue me.
Does that phone work?
it does if you
got change.
Nick, it's lisa.
Hey, crazy lady.
Hi, sweetie.
No time to explain, but I need you
to drive out oak springs, highway 7
And pick me up.
I'm surrounded
by dead things.
Oak springs. Damn,
that's a long way.
I know. And it's getting
late, so you have to start now.
Oh, yeah, babe, jeez...
If only I could.
But I don't want to die. Die?
Yeah, I just entered
the nova star,
And if you quit
before you make overlord,
They cut off your head and you
have to start all over again.
What the hell
are you talking about?
The nova star.
Babe, this is big.
We have to be at prom
in six hours.
Okay, can we just
meet there?
You know what?
Never mind.
Wait, we're still having
sex afterwards, right?
Of course.
No! No, my head! Ohh!
Oh, thank god.
Paisley, it's lisa.
I need you to come
and get me in oak springs.
You're getting
your hair colored.
Of course.
Curls before girls.
Who doesn't live by that?
No, I'll just call dakota.
Oh, they're with you.
No, of course her curls
are important, too.
Far more important
than me being stranded
In the middle of nowhere.
Hi. It's lisa sommers.
Emily. It's lisa sommers.
Listen, thank you for that invite
to go shopping and grab a latte.
But if you really
want to bond,
Don't you think spending four
or five hours in a car would be-
Hello?
Hola, isabelle.
Really?
Doesn't word
travel fast?
Yeah, it's very funny.
Ha ha.
Listen, I don't suppose
you'd be up for-
Please stop laughing.
You're so damn slow.
Look, tarantino, we're a
little shorthanded today.
Give me a second.
No personal
phone calls.
Bite me.
Hello?
Oh, thank god.
Lisa?
Okay, calm down.
It's okay.
We'll be there.
Oh!
Thank you guys so much
for coming to get me.
I thought I was popular,
but nobody would come.
They were all getting
their hair done.
I can't believe
how stupid I was.
I can't believe the way
I treated you guys.
I'm so sorry.
Especially you, raj.
You should be.
He got suspended,
And he has to perform
community service
Fixing carlita's yard.
You're worse than amber.
You went from zero to
satan in, like, two days.
That's what I've been telling
you. She was possessed.
Oh, right. The great
ghost bimbo from beyond.
I wasn't possessed.
This was all me.
See? No ghost.
No, there's a ghost.
There was. Or-
oh, my god. Amber.
I've got to save her.
You're about
a week late, remember?
"give me that crown!"
zzzzzt! "aaaah!"
Colin, I need you to get
me to the prom right now.
Come on!
Hello?
Mr. Purgatory man?
Miss pollock.
The prom isn't
till this evening.
We can't send you upstairs
until it's official.
I'm not gonna be
going upstairs.
Really? I was getting
such positive reports.
It didn't work out.
I failed.
So, send me,
I guess... Down?
Are you sure
about this?
I think you could
pull this off.
I'm sure.
Okie-dokie.
Your ride is here.
I thought all the fun
people were going to hell.
A knife fight?
Two dead?
That's kindergarten
stuff.
I sold high-risk mortgages
to homeless people,
Only so I could repo
their new abodes
And make them
homeless again.
What did you do,
blondie?
I was...
Mean to everyone.
Hmm.
Rookie.
Exquisite. Fabulous.
No drinking.
Arrive alive.
Miss sommers... What
happened to your shoes?
Oh. Oh.
Nothing. It-
it's a thing I'm trying.
Well, you're certainly
cutting it close.
They're about to start
voting. Go check it.
Thank god. Wait,
I need to talk to you.
Raj is innocent. I was the
one who sent out the emails
About carlita's party.
Okay, bye.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
little missy.
If that's the case, you're
suspended immediately,
And ineligible
from prom queen.
No, you have
to let me run.
Please,
it's so important.
Hey, hey, hey.
No underwear showing!
Where'd she-
What's up?
Did you guys get dressed
in the dark?
Whatever happened
to tuxedos?
Woman over speaker:
Attention life losers-
Please keep your hands
and feet inside the shuttle
At all times.
In a moment, we'll be entering
the outer reaches of hell.
As the temperature rises,
Please refrain from
screaming and pleading.
Trust us-
We've heard it all.
Can I get your attention,
everybody?
Can I get your attention
real quick?
Hello. All right.
Let me just remind everyone
That lisa sommers is no longer
eligible as a candidate.
So, that leaves...
Well, just carlita cache.
All right, well, good luck...
Everybody!
I hate my life.
God, carlita...
Everyone is voting
for you.
They sure are.
Thanks, girls.
Would you get me
some punch?
Yes.
No, me!
Everybody, could I-
Excuse me, everybody?
Can I-
Can I get your
attention, please?
Please let me do this.
What is she doing? She
said she had an idea.
Something that's going
to fix everything.
First of all...
I was the one who sabotaged
carlita's party.
I knew it.
Totally knew it.
I was the one who
sent those emails,
Not my
good friend raj.
I was trying to
take carlita down.
You see...
I was so tired
Of not being seen,
That when I finally
got the chance,
I was willing to do
anything to be noticed,
To feel special.
I thought being popular
would make everything better,
But it didn't.
You know what else
I found out?
Being popular does not
mean everybody likes you.
This is dangerous.
She's tampering with
the fundamental dynamics
Of the high school
universe.
Be honest.
How many of you have ever
felt the way I did?
How many of you walk
into this school every day
And wonder if anyone
really cares?
How many of you have worried
About whether your clothes
are cool enough,
Or if you're listening
to the right music?
Or how many of you
have been hurt
When you find out about a party
you were never invited to?
And how many of you have done
something really stupid and insensitive
Just to be part of
the cool crowd?
What about this?
What if the cool crowd
was all of us?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
What if going to school
wasn't a competition?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
What if we all just said,
"screw this!"
Screw having a contest
That draws attention
to someone
Who clearly
doesn't need it.
Screw the idea that
you can't look around
At everybody in this room
And believe that you couldn't
be friends with any of them.
This year, let's make
tonight mean something.
Let's shower that attention on
somebody who's just a good person,
Who's a real friend,
Somebody who believes
the best of everybody.
Yeah!
Let's vote for raj kurkuri.
who?!
Raj!
"who?" right.
Exactly my point.
After tonight,
let's make sure
We never ask that again.
Who is it?
Sure.
Raj! Raj!
Raj! Raj! Raj!
You know what?
Forget about counting ballots.
Let's vote right now.
Everybody who's for raj,
raise your hand.
The white-hot plasma
outside the window
Indicates we are nearing
our final destination,
So please fasten
your seat belts.
Just joking.
You're already dead.
In order to make your arrival
even more unpleasant,
The man downstairs would like you
to please deposit your teeth and hair
Into the small bin
provided at the exit.
Then please move on
to the next line,
Where a hot metal tube
Will drop you into an
endless lake of molten lava.
Amber, dear.
The oddest thing
just happened.
The least popular person
in your high school
Was just elected
prom king.
King?
What can I say?
It's a modern world.
You know
what this means?
Heaven?
Eventually.
But right now, scads
and scads more paperwork.
So, you're
coming with me.
And, to the rest
of you...
Bye-bye.
Hey!
Just you in there?
Just me.
Hey, this is
great and all,
But we've got a lot of work to
do on the movie, starting tonight.
Or tomorrow.
Tomorrow's good.
Give me a sec.
The sweet dweeb
got the crown.
Not bad.
I like your gown.
They told me
it comes with wings.
But I'm not ready
to accessorize.
So...
Hey, give me a minute,
would you?
Thank you.
Listen...
I think you're
a great person,
And I want you
to have a great life.
And I was telling you
the truth.
A little confidence
doesn't hurt.
Now, don't become an amber,
but, you know...
Somewhere
in the middle.
Yeah.
Hey, you're gonna be
a huge hit in college.
I know it.
Actually, I peaked.
I'd hug you, but I'd
go right through-
Thank you... For her.
Oh, my god.
Come on, turn around.
Slowly.
Zac efron mall boy-
he found you.
Oh, my god.
What do I do?
You know what to do.
I do.
Now go.
I'll be looking
over you.
I have been to seven proms
tonight looking for you.
Heh.
Man, you are...
So much hotter
than what I remember.
Oh, I'm sorry. Um...
I don't want to
scare you again.
That scared girl is...
Gone.
Since you came
all this way,
You want to dance
or something?
Oh, god, yes.
So, um... Should I
say anything
About the really hot
prom outfit you've got on,
Or do I just continue
to ignore it?
Ignore it.
you got it.
All right, ashley high,
let's kick it up!
And so, for
one brief, shining moment,
The high school universe
was upended,
And the least of them
became the best of them.
And for the rest of
the evening,
The walls came down.
Oh!
Whoa!
This is wrong!
This mixing-
It's completely wrong!
It's against nature!
Stop playing now!
Uhh! I'm shutting
this whole thing down!
Oh, lucky me.
Here we go again.
Sub resynced by: PEEAN91
credits to original uploader