Subtitles by CJ Entertainment
[4 years ago]
- Where are you?
I just passed Young Wol.
Honey...
What now?
You heading over there is making me nervous for no reason.
Then, should I just quit and go home?
Do I need to chop off my fingers for you to believe me?
Don't say things like that.
Hang on.
Daddy!
Minji!
I'll be home early tomorrow after work so listen to Mom...
Okay?
Daddy!
Addict
You must want some ice cream.
Minji...
My name is Hyo Jung.
We don't need this!
What?
Hey... go bet for someone.
I told you I'm resting today.
Shut up and hurry.
I'm in a rush.
I think they'll give us some.
Fine, I can get someone else.
What time?
You little... trying to play hard to get.
I'll give you the address, write it down.
What address.
They told us to go to their house.
Who is it?
Did you call for someone?
Mrs. Kwon!
Did she forget about morning prayer?
Why is it open?
Mrs. Kwon! Are you home?
Detective Baek.
Come back.
I'm tired of it...
I'm tired of the smell of blood.
I'm tired of feeling sorry for myself in Seoul.
This matches me anyway.
You're a girl?
You can't tell?
You're a student here?
Junior Class, Room 3.
Oh, sorry...
Sorry, sorry...
What?
An entire family has been murdered.
So what?
Call Flounder.
Senior, you remember Kang Jong Yoon, right?
An entire family was found murdered at Kang Won Do...
...Jung Sun Goon, Shin Won Ri this afternoon.
Mr. Lim, who was murdered the night before, had called Mr. Kang...
...to help place a bet, based on the statements.
Kang killed the family and robbed their house.
The police are currently looking for the fleeing suspect.
Meanwhile, Kang, who stole 2 billion dollars at a casino 4 years ago...
...was last seen wandering around the venues-
- Hey!
- Senior!
Are you sure it's Kang Jong Yoon?
Yes.
Mr. Park had called him into this house the night before the crime.
And we confirmed his face with the witness.
Nothing's changed.
This way.
What's wrong with her teeth?
Did she get hit?
You can't break teeth without injuring the mouth.
I think the victim bit something.
He escaped this way.
Victim's identity?
He was a loan shark by the name of Im Do Sool.
It looks like he took all the cash that was in the house.
But, they're looking into the exact amount.
What's our radius search?
20 km.
Make it 40.
Why?
You were in the Army Reserves.
You wouldn't know...
This bastard was in the Marines Special Forces.
Did you send someone over to his house?
H-house?
How long have you been doing this?
Gwang Pal!
Let me ask a favor!
He took his cash, jewels, everything and split.
Bank account?
Clean.
He must have been in a rush,
even leaving the dish soap!
Okay. Thank you.
That means he was on the same page.
Everything is set, right?
Who do you think I am?
I told them to call as soon as they see a suspicious guy.
I already told all the merchant ships.
But, is he really coming here?
The thing about gambling addicts...
Instead of killing people...
They care more about gambling.
That's the scary thing.
Their heads go crazy if they think they can't gamble again.
Sooner or later, his wife will be here to bring him money.
This is the only place he can keep gambling.
Is this the bastard I'm thinking of?
The one who screwed you over!
No wonder you're so into it!
If I hear that he smuggled out...
You know what'll happen, right?
What?
Senior! We found Kang Jong Yoon's cellphone!
Where?
Young Wol Terminal.
Young Wol?
Young Wol is in the opposite direction!
Is this another mess up?
What?
Senior!
Kang Jong Yoon is inside a bus right now.
He'll be arriving in Won Ju at 1:30.
Won Ju?
Sorry! Sorry!
Hey Baldie! You wanna die?!
Baldie?
Okay! Sorry!
Sorry. Sorry.
This is the police.
Wait! Wait!
Senior! Now!
He turned his phone on!
What are you doing?!
Stay still.
I'll break your arm.
Save me!
Who are you?
I only took $30!
I just needed to make a call once I got here.
What?
We sighted Kang Jong Yoon not too long ago.
What? Where?
He was in... Jung Sun.
Jung Sun?
I really thought that was him.
What kind of crazy man would do that so close to the police station?
What's that?
Im Min Sub, the victim's brother.
Send him off.
Yes.
Excuse me.
You can go back now.
You can't stay here.
We'll contact you later.
Bye.
That's a great photo.
Did you forget that we have a hearing next week?
The Boss decided he wants to be involved.
Regional Unit.
What have you been doing not taking the lead?
I'm sorry.
If you give us a week-
Give us 3 days.
Because he was caught red-handed...
They're wondering how fast we can catch him...
This case is hard as hell but there'll be no reward for catching him.
Is it because of Detective Baek?
The way he murdered the family members still doesn't make sense.
Anyway...
When his kid grows up, this crime will be the most painful for her.
What could be more painful than watching the person you love kill someone?
I shouldn't have said that.
It's fine.
It's more painful to have forgotten the pain.
I can't believe that he was over Jung Sun and didn't run farther away.
What in the world could've gotten into him?
Did Kang Jong Yoon show up?
No!
Then why did you call?
Somebody else came looking for him...
Who was it?
A rough looking guy.
I thought maybe just in case.
Go ahead and write this down.
Silver Grandeur, license number 9881.
Okay.
Search for a Silver Grandeur, license number 9881.
Fine.
Wait.
Go back a little.
Stop.
That's Bong Yang, right?
Yes.
He went inside at 1:22...
...and came out at 1:45.
2 minutes, 57 seconds.
If that took 3 minutes, then that means he was here for 20.
What did that bastard do here?
Where could he have gone?
Have you seen this man?
I've never seen him.
Mrs.!
Have you seen this person by any chance?
I'm not a Mrs.
Sorry to bother you but have you seen this person?
I've never seen him.
I'm not sure...
I thought I told you that I've never seen him.
You little...
Found it!
I was hesitant at first.
What can you do for me for $500?
In this economy, the question is what can't I do for you.
If...
I wanted to look for someone.
I'm not sure...
I have to renew my contract next month...
I can even look for a stray dog that ran away 10 years ago for you.
Let's see... who are you looking for?
A guy who wants to kill Im Do Sool.
A guy that wants to kill Im Do Sool?
I took the money.
But isn't it funny?
Why was he looking when he's the one who killed him?
What was the suspect's specialty?
Marine.
Do you see something strange?
He stabbed him in the chest 8 times...
But, he completely avoided the body's pressure points.
Could it be a coincidence?
It could be... but there's very little chance of that.
The deepest wound was on the left side of the neck.
This is the only time he stabbed at a pressure point.
He must be a pro.
We found a fiber sample on his neck that matched the daughter's outfit.
He must've killed the daughter first and then the father.
When do you think the wife was killed?
The autopsy isn't complete yet but looking at the muscle contraction,
she was killed 1-2 hours before the other two.
Wife, daughter, victim.
What?
The order that he killed them.
Did I ever thank you for coming?
You did.
Nam Yeh Ri will stay in Seoul and talk to the suspect's family members.
Is anyone there?
Ah... yes...
Hello.
I'm from the police.
You're Kim Eun Joo's nephew, right?
I've broken ties with those people a long time ago.
But! Wait-
I'm here to ask about Kim Eun Joo.
I'm so tired of this!
I have some questions about Kim Eun Joo-
What?
Who the hell is that?
Hey punk!
Senior.
It's been a year.
What are you doing here?
Well...
This case was given to us.
You know...
From above...
And so...
You came here trying to take on the case?
Yes.
Where's Director Yeo?
Encounter
There are blood stains on the wall but not on the frame.
That means the frame wasn't there during the crime.
You're still the same.
Director Yeo.
For a culprit who left his fingerprints everywhere...
Why would he dare to take the frame off and put it back on?
It probably fell during a fight.
Then, what's the motive?
The only thing missing from the scene is a couple of checks and some cash.
For that, he stabbed three people?
For some reason...
That doesn't fit with this kind of complicated crime scene.
What are you saying?
Sounds like you're saying the culprit might have been framed...
The culprit left Im Do Sool in a not so fatal state...
...and stabbed the wife and daughter first.
Why would he do that?
Pain...
The culprit wanted the victim to watch his family get murdered.
This murder was for revenge.
Director Yeo.
What do you know about Kang Jong Yoon?
I know about the attempted murder case from 3 years ago.
I heard you were in charge back then.
Then, I'm sure you know that it's the same technique.
Kang Jong Yoon is claiming his innocence until the end.
Saying that he only went in because he thought he knew someone...
That it's unfair...
To not let him go to jail...
That he couldn't let his daughter become the daughter of a murderer...
He begged on his hands and knees, that bastard.
Do you know the first thing he did after receiving probation?
Right when I saw those eyes, I knew.
Ah... So this is it.
Gambling addicts will do anything to keep gambling.
Putting on a show to get what they want is nothing to them.
I won't make the same mistake twice.
You're the one who helped him get out of jail on probation.
Don't tell me they're blaming you for this family's death.
Mixing personal feelings into an investigation...
...is the deadliest thing.
Personal feelings?
Look who's talking, Director Yeo.
You said this was for revenge, didn't you?
Ah...
Because revenge is your specialty.
Isn't that why you're known for?
In this territory, there are a lot of things you won't understand.
These Detectives are mean and nasty.
They don't like outsiders poking their head in their case.
So leave quietly.
Come in.
2nd floor.
Did she have any close friends?
No! Only debt collectors.
What are these numbers?
She's so strange.
Her daughter is old enough to know her numbers.
I don't know why she wrote these numbers on the stairs.
No usage of the transportation card or call history after the crime...
She didn't meet anyone either...
Where could she have gone with her child?
These are all new.
A man?
This is Yeo Ji Hoon from the Special Affairs Team.
Where is the wine bottle that was at the crime scene?
It's in custody at the NFS for fingerprint verification.
Would you be able to call them and send me a photo?
We have a photo.
But Kang Jong Yoon's fingerprints are very subtle.
I don't need the fingerprints.
I need the label.
Can we at least eat?
I'm starving.
After giving him the orders,
we should be hearing from him soon.
Would he actually be that stupid to act up when the police is around?
He's coming.
You little punk.
How many years has it been and you don't even know anything here.
Let's go.
Cheval Blanc.
Keep watch here.
Yes, Senior.
The account book?
Of course, I brought it.
The rest is in here.
Forget the money.
Min Sub.
All done, right?
I'm leaving first.
What are you still doing here and not running away?
Why... are you doing this?
Stay right there.
Where is Kang Jong Yoon?
I said where is Kang Jong Yoon, you bastard.
There.
Who the hell is this?
Assault, robbery, threat.
Your records are impressive.
I played around when I was a kid.
Is there something wrong with that?
So...
You wanted to catch Kang Jong Yoon yourself?
He murdered my brother's entire family.
If you were me, would you let him get away?
License plate 9881, Silver Grandeur.
Was that you?
Yes.
What did you give him?
If you lie again,
I'll rip your mouth off.
The account book.
Account book...
What account book?
Who else would want to kill a loan shark except people who are in debt?
That's why I made the private-
Whenever you open your mouth,
it's always a lie!
Why would a killer look for someone that could kill him?!
It's true. I just gave him the account book, that's it!
Was Im Do Sool ever threatened before in his life?
Threatened?
Think carefully.
If he ran a pawn shop for gamblers,
I'm sure there were a few people.
What are you saying?
Even though his job was shady,
he lived an honest life!
You motherfuc-
Motherfucker?
Motherfuc-
I can have you rot in jail for disrupting an interrogation.
Watch your language.
Should I feed you prison food?
Director Yeo.
What are you doing?
This is the wine that the criminal drank.
Looking at Im Do Sool's wine collection...
Most of the labels were ridiculously expensive.
Should I say he had vulgar taste?
If he had to choose one wine out of his entire collection...
It would be this one.
1982 Cheval Blanc.
Is it a coincidence that the culprit chose to drink this specific wine?
You can fool one's eyes.
But you can't fool one's taste.
Taste?
We've been doing this the wrong way.
Kang Jong Yoon isn't the criminal.
He was framed.
And he's looking for the real killer right now.
The one wanting revenge against Im Do Sool...
The one who likes Cheval Blanc...
Wait.
So...
So you're saying it wasn't that gambler but someone else?
Kang Jong Yoon is finding the real killer?
Whether it's Cheval or bullshit or whatever-
My taste is soju so I'll go my own way.
While you write your novel, I'll be investigating the medical facilities.
Kang Jong Yoon is calling!
He wants to talk to the Detective in charge.
This is Yeo Ji Hoon from the Special Affairs Team.
It's him!
The bastard who called me!
I thought that bastard was dead.
The man I met that night wasn't Im Do Sool!
Kang Jong Yoon.
Right now, you're wanted as the prime suspect.
If you want to prove your innocence, come to the station-
You don't think I know that you'll just arrest me?
I'm telling you that the bastard framed me!
I'll record this conversation so tell me in detail.
Okay.
Start.
I went to the house...
That bastard let me in...
I thought it was his house.
Good work today.
Have a seat.
Have a drink.
Thank you.
Did you bring what I asked for?
Ah, yes.
I couldn't find the brand you were looking for.
The frame fell.
My daughter likes to play around.
I'm sure you know how 4 year olds can get.
Tell me about your family.
Do I really need to say?
You don't have to if you don't want to.
Can I have another drink?
Today is my daughter's birthday.
The last time I saw her was when she was two.
She should be 6 now.
You should at least call.
I've given up on seeing her in real life.
When I think about her and my wife...
Someone like me should die.
We should go to hell.
I should've cut my wrists back then.
There's no point in cutting your wrists.
If you're going to cut them, you should cut them here.
If I hire you for 2 days, is 7 enough?
That's plenty.
I initially invested in one week.
But something came up.
This is for tip.
After waiting outside the casino for hours, I went back.
They were already dead.
Any witnesses or alibi?
Anyone you met?
Nobody.
I don't know.
Hey Kang Jong Yoon!
If you already got the money,
why did you go back?
Especially at dawn?!
Why don't you come here and draw the montage then, you bastard?!
That-
It was too dark so I couldn't see him.
Stop lying, you bastard!
That crazy bastard.
Trying to act like he didn't see him!
Senior! We were able to track his phone.
You stay here.
Everyone go go!
The perfect scenario to frame someone...
Too cruel...
Too precise...
After a fake phone call...
You even leave a photo?
Kang Jong Yoon, you bastard.
Monster vs. Viper
Don't make a sound.
We try to create a happy lifestyle for the families of gambling addicts.
We encourage them to wear nice clothes and makeup.
We want them to feel attractive.
Because of that,
we often get misunderstandings.
Ah... that's...
Those are the steps that we encourage them to follow.
Kim Eunjoo took them very seriously.
12 steps?
We recommended that they write it down on stairs.
So that every time they walked down...
They would be able to take in good words of encouragement.
Rule #1.
Let's acknowledge the fact that we live with a gambling addict.
Rule #2.
Let's not blame them.
Rule #3.
Let's accept the fact that the past is the past.
Rule #4.
Let's not give up.
She wasn't having an affair.
Wearing makeup...
to be able to smile again...
She did this to remind herself never to give up.
While hoping for her husband to return...
I thought he was just cruel but he's precise too.
Setting everything up in such a short period of time...
This punk is sleek.
What kind of show is he going to put up next time?
Senior! But...
Doesn't it seem strange that he would do all that for money?
Like the Seoul team said...
Maybe it has to do with money and revenge?
You're starting to sound like the Seoul team.
Is that a crime scene or a next door gathering?
Why is the whole world in there?
Why are you hitting me?
Maybe they went there because they're family of the deceased.
Wait.
Isn't there something weird about that bastard?
What?
For someone who wants revenge for his brother...
After seeing the body,
he's not interested at all.
There's something fishy about him.
Watch over this.
Where are you going?
There were no extra copies of the account book.
It'll take some time for us to search everyone on the list.
There's a book by Dostoevsky called, "Crime & Punishment."
It's an interesting title.
Crime and punishment...
The context is a loan shark and daughter are killed with an ax.
That kind of educational book isn't really meant for loan sharks.
Director!
You said that this case was an act of revenge, right?
After looking into Im Do Sool's medical records...
Something interesting came up.
Im Do Sool got treated for syphilis last month.
Syphilis?
Yes.
But a week later, Im Min Sub and Nam Min Jung got the same treatment.
Who's Nam Min Jung?
Im Min Sub's wife.
The brother's wife?
Director.
What if the victim messed with the brother's wife?
Im Min Sub.
Where is he right now?
What did he do here?
What is it?
What did this bastard do?
It's backwards.
5 hundred million!
5 hundred million inside of this safe?
Kang Jong Yoon...
You broke into the safe.
Wait. Then...
Since the brother was the only other person who knew where the money was...
The revenge he wanted for his brother...
Two rats were fighting each other for this money...
What?
Senior!
The Seoul team went to go catch Im Min Sub.
What?
Why Im Min Sub?
He's now a suspect for this family murder.
He killed his own brother for sleeping with his wife.
Oh and the Cheval? That thing.
That purchase was found in his credit card transactions.
What the hell are they saying?
Im Min Sub?
Where is he right now?
I'll look into it.
Shut up!
Who is it?
Im Min Sub!
Im Min Sub?
What happened?
Call the ambulance!
Get it together!
Im Min Sub...
Who did this?
Kang...
Jong Yoon...
Subtitles by CJ Entertainment
Director Yeo almost feel for it.
Didn't I tell you?
This is a territory you'll never understand.
Hell...
Where did he go?
What is he doing for us to keep looking for the criminal?
I guess there is something difficult for Yeo Ji Hoon.
Come this way.
I have something to show you.
Kang Jong Yoon is waiting for me...
Things are just coming together.
I don't understand why you're doing this.
Like you said, I don't understand why you're doing this either!