My wife likes to say
there are two kinds of people.
Those chasing pleasure. . .
and those running from pain.
Lorelei Cranston is running.
Running from all kinds of everything.
Probably has been her whole life.
If you ask me, nobody
gets to escape their pain.
It's there when you
brush your teeth at night.
It's there before breakfast.
It'll come up, fierce and sharp.
It'll lay on you, blunt and heavy.
The most you can hope for is one good day.
'Cause on a good day,
you get to tell yourself
'' I can fix this.
Today can be different. ''
''Today something might change. ''
Yeah?
Gary?
And then Mrs. Rodell yelled at Anna
and said she'd had enough of her
last year in her class.
And Anna was like,
''Hello, I wasn't in your class last year. ''
Well, it's a good thing
I didn't know any of this, or. . .
What?
I got you a little treat
for doing so well in trigonometry.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Trig's easy. It's just memory.
God, I hope you don't
remember everything
when you get older.
It's not just because
you did so well in math.
l've got some news.
Come on honey, sit down.
And how you take it is important to me.
l've asked Gary to move in with us.
For real.
Not just a couple nights
a week or whatever.
I know it's only been a little while,
but it just feels so different
this time, you know?
Yeah, it is different this time.
Yeah?
Some people live for their pain.
It's all they've got.
They stay up with it.
Afraid it might slip away.
People like me.
I would love to dream.
But one way or another--
. . . I'm always awake.
Get back! Get back!
Oh, Dotty.
She won't let you go.
You like that? Yes!
Look at that. Look at that.
Look at her. She's really amazing.
Oh, Dotty.
That's a good girl.
My stars are really nice this week.
They said, ''Financial woes through midweek
give way to--''
What's that word?
It means horns of plenty.
They're kind of bullshit anyway.
Horoscopes.
No offense, but ... kind of bullshit.
. . . confirming today the teen
will be tried as an adult
for the brutal murder of his parents.
His case will be heard
in Buffalo City Court,
commencing later this month.
By contrast, Eric Komenko committed
the same crime at 1 5,
but prosecutors chose not to try him
as an adult in this case,
citing high levels
of the antidepressant Zoloxia
found in his bloodstream
as a mitigating factor.
Komenko's sentence, juvenile detention.
He is expected to be released
this coming Friday on his 18th birthday,
his record expunged.
Public questions
about Komenko's case remain, however.
Victims' rights groups
are protesting his release,
while members of Komenko's Baptist
congregation are supporting it.
Komenko!
Lieutenant's here.
I can follow him, be close by.
It's going to pay off for us later on.
But I'm going to need your help.
Anything you need.
All right, Brian. Thank you.
Mexico.
Cool.
I wanted to take Spanish,
but the teacher here got laid off.
Spanish?
That could be helpful.
What's happening on the college front?
I didn't want to send
applications postmarked from here.
That makes sense.
So, you're going to live with your aunt?
Yeah.
You don't think that might be hard?
She said she wants me there.
Antidepressants
messed with my chemistry.
The state even testified to that.
I know. I was there.
Look, I did this evil thing.
But I know I can put it behind me.
That's what expunged means.
What do you want from me?
You're a psychopath, Eric.
You're going to kill again.
You know it, and I know it.
And I want to prevent that from happening.
And when I do, I want you to know
it's going to make me very happy.
It's the best thing for you.
When you walk out of here,
know I will be waiting for you.
I got nothing else to do.
Thanks.
I hope your wife gets better.
Let's go, guys!
Back to class. Let's go!
I could get you a magazine, John.
Sorry.
How about some pie?
Not tonight, Debbie.
Hi. Would you like some more coffee?
Yeah, a cup will do.
Come on. Let's move it.
We got five minutes to clean this place up.
Hey!
Get her out of there.
I got her.
Open up!
Komenko.
- Komenko!
- Right here!
Here you go, Eric.
Good luck.
Hey, Komenko!
Eric! Eric!
You going home?
Not exactly.
Morning.
Good morning.
We're two early risers.
Yeah.
Come and sit.
Have some breakfast.
Eric, you don't have to pray.
Or only if you want to.
In this house,
your spirituality is your own.
I do want to.
Okay.
This isn't a library.
Fuck off, Paul.
A note from Lori there for you.
Read it to me, sugar?
She's going to go stay
at Kim's for the weekend.
One of the girls from the store
is going to drive her.
Excuse me.
It's okay.
I'm sorry.
It was nice of you to use a mint.
Wow. You look like a real college kid.
You mind me saying ''kid''?
No.
Should I try that?
Sure.
- Here.
- Thanks.
So, the money for the house came to--
Well, it's quite a lot.
I'll work for my money.
College is a full-time job.
Just don't forget who you are.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
I'm sorry, too.
Where's Battenville?
North of Albany.
Some random town.
That's cool.
I was going to go to Albany
to look at colleges.
Maybe I could stop by.
Where should we meet?
There's a place out here called FunLand.
- Please!
- Let's go. Go, go, go.
Can we get an umbrella?
- A what?
- A ladies' choice.
They still have a cotillion.
ls that what they're called?
Can you be here on Sunday?
Yeah, I think so.
FunLand. Sunday.
FunLand.
How about 5:00?
Hey, Maria. . .
What do you like?
What the--
Shit!
I'm sorry.
I was just going to
wait until you stopped and then sneak out.
It was raining and I needed
a place that was dry.
I was going to go home,
but then there was this dog barking,
so I came in here.
Did someone put you up to this?
No, of course not.
You were with the reporters.
No, I wasn't.
How old are you?
I'm 16.
How old are you really?
- I'm 16.
- Get in front.
Your belt.
I'm so sorry.
This isn't how I thought it would be.
- I just wanted to--
- Just stay quiet.
Hey.
License and registration.
Was there a problem?
No, sir. Just. . .
. . . need to get some sleep, I guess.
Yeah, he had to work all night.
It's illegal in the state of New York
for your girlfriend to ride back there.
Yes, sir.
Gesundheit.
Thanks.
Get home safe.
I don't think I've ever seen
a Chinese cop before.
No, I don't think I have.
I'm Lori. Lori Cranston.
My real name's Lorelei, actually.
But I hate that name.
I don't even know
where my mom got it from.
Have you ever seen a Chinese cop?
I don't think it's racist to ask that.
Do you want me to get out?
And then what? You'll call the papers?
No. I guess my mom will come get me.
But I'd rather stay.
Are you one of the ones who wrote?
What? No.
Please. I--
I just thought after all that time,
maybe you'd like a girl around.
Just a friend.
We've met before.
You were outside my aunt's house.
I don't mean then.
Look at me and think.
I don't know. In a facility?
No.
I mean, I'm not all Suzy Creamcheese
or whatever.
But no.
Think you can find your way home?
Take it.
You really don't remember me?
No.
I didn't look like this.
Get home safe.
It was right before your parents.
By the river.
I guess nothing ever happens
the way you think it will.
I'm going to be gone
for a couple of days.
I got to look after that Komenko kid.
Now this is where you tell me
to keep my hat on.
And I tell you I don't have one.
You'd laugh, wouldn't you, baby?
Same old dumb joke.
Hey, can you think of a nastier word
than ''sneeze guard''?
I mean, it's this close to, like,
''snot window'' or something.
Hey, what's this?
I think it's curry.
Cool!
I've never had it before.
Amen.
God.
Geminis are indecisive.
About most things.
Not about important stuff, though.
About important stuff,
once I make up my mind--
Do Leos ever do that?
Just, like, go after something?
You still have to tell me where we met.
Picture a river.
A girl wearing glasses.
Can you tie them in a knot?
Can you tie them in a bow?
Can you throw them over your shoulder
Like a Continental soldier?
Do your ears hang low?
Do your ears stand high?
Do they point up to the sky?
Do they droop when they're wet--
- Hey.
- Hi.
You lost?
What are you doing out here?
Just exploring around.
Do your ears hang high?
Do they point up to the sky?
Do they droop when they're wet?
Do they stiffen when they're dry?
Can you semaphore your neighbor
With a minimum of labor?
Do your ears stand high?
Anything?
You were just exploring around.
You remember me?
Oh, my God.
Here you go.
Yeah, of course I remember you.
You were the detective on the case.
I was concerned when l
saw you at my door.
I apologize. I didn't think.
Why are you here?
Eric doesn't have a parole officer, right?
No, he doesn't.
And I'm pretty much retired, actually.
You know, actually,
I just had the weekend off,
so I thought I'd--
So you came down to Lakewood?
I just thought I would come down
and make sure his transition
was a healthy one, that's all.
Should I be asking
if your agenda is a healthy one?
Yes, it is.
And I appreciate you
asking me that question.
I'm sure it wasn't easy.
Can I ask you how. . .
how you are with him here?
It's hard, you know.
When I was in the courtroom,
all I kept thinking was. . .
thank God they haven't
called me to testify
because I'd have to tell the truth. . .
about how our family
is damaged, so damaged.
We never talked about anything,
and Eric just sat there in the middle of it,
and my sister's. . .
I don't know.
She was terrified of the world.
This one and the next.
I'm not a believer
in medicating adolescents,
but my sister had a teenage boy.
She had no clue how to deal with him,
so she drugged the feelings out of him.
Still, he killed his mom.
He said he was going to Albany
to look at campuses.
I've been a teacher for 14 years.
I have a pretty good sense
when a kid's lying.
Well. . .
I might take a run up there
to see that he checked in okay.
Thank you.
You have a very nice house.
You want to see something?
I got a lucky star tattoo.
This way, if they ever superimpose
someone else's face on my body,
like, on the internet,
I'll know, and I can really sue them.
You're a freak.
It's just ball point.
I got bored last night and drew it on.
I'm pretty vanilla, really.
No tattoos, no piercings.
Did they let you listen to music in there?
No.
I can teach you.
I know all the new music.
Here.
He's gonna establish his kingdom.
He's gonna set up his--
There's a train station in this next town,
so. . .
. . . reach for you--
So I'll give you some cash
for the train back to Buffalo.
But I just thought
I'd take one back from Albany.
Look, you're cool, Lori, really,
but I need to be alone, okay? I--
I need to make a fresh start.
Well, aren't I a fresh start?
It doesn't get much fresher than old Lori.
I'm basically a virgin.
That has nothing to do with it.
I just need to stay focused, all right?
When I find a college,
I'll send you my email.
We can write. Okay?
I wouldn't tell her.
I mean, really, there's nothing to tell.
But if there were,
it would just be what happens, right?
What are you talking about?
Your girlfriend.
I don't have a girlfriend.
You were saying her name.
I what?
When I was in the back,
I wasn't eavesdropping or anything.
You just kept saying her name,
like '' Maria, Maria. Hey, Maria. ''
Maria, Maria, Maria, Maria.
Just stop.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to poke fun at you.
I guess I'm just jealous.
I don't know what you think you heard.
There's no girlfriend.
Really?
Yeah.
That's cool.
I need to take a leak.
I wish I smoked.
I kept saying somebody's name?
Maria.
Yeah.
You sure?
I was right there.
That's pretty weird.
Oh, God!
Hey, guys?
Eric?
No!
It's a 1992 red Volvo 740.
740.
0319 Larry John Robert.
Do you want us to pick him up?
No. Don't pick him up.
Just, just tell me where he is.
Okay. We're here.
Okay? If someone spots him, let me know.
Okay, we'll call you.
You have a nice day now, John.
Okay, Hazel, I will. Thank you.
You're welcome. Goodbye.
Eric!
Somebody had to do number 2.
Let's go.
Those are probably dirty.
You wouldn't say that if you had one.
They're so fucking good.
We should get on the road.
Wouldn't you love to go out on a boat?
I've never been on one.
I can't swim.
Why can't you swim?
Aren't parents supposed to
teach you stuff like that?
My mom can't swim, either.
I lied before.
When I said I was a virgin.
Maybe I am. I don't know.
Mom has always just--
been kind of a pervert magnet.
I guess she still is.
Gary just seems nice because he's quiet
and he doesn't drink, and. . .
he acts pretty dad-like.
Mostly.
He took me on this camping trip.
Just the two of us.
The bonding weekend.
He said since I got wet,
that was a sign I wanted it.
Lori, you can't just knock on someone's door
and ask for the bathroom.
Emergency! Hello!
Lori.
Hello!
Wow. This is so cool.
I wonder why they left.
We shouldn't be here.
Look.
They took seven photos.
We should get them developed
and see what happened to them.
Here.
What if these people
are, like, serial killers
and there are seven photos
of seven bodies in here and then us?
So we get them developed,
and the cops arrest us
and we seem totally guilty
because of your record and all.
That would be freaky.
Let's get one together.
Come on. Let's go.
Let's get out of here.
No. One sec. I got to freshen up.
Holy shit. There's paper.
Yes!
Yeah.
You want to roll one?
No, thanks.
Bowling isn't gay.
I didn't say it was.
I'm just trying
to show you a good time.
I'm fun to have around.
Think of me as a dry run
for a real girlfriend,
somebody important.
Why do you say things like that?
Like what?
Like you want pity.
I don't want pity.
Fuck!
Shit.
Okay. It's 11:30 in the morning.
You can watch your language,
or you can leave.
Hey! Can we get a couple of beers?
So did you have a lot of friends?
So no one visited?
No.
This cop.
He was a do-gooder.
What do you mean?
He was just too easy.
- Easy?
- Yeah.
Easy like most people are easy.
Once he told me about his sick wife.
From then on, all I had to do
was bring her up,
and he'd go quiet.
This one time, I called him a. . .
a small beans cop
with a vegetable wife.
His eyes got all watery.
But aren't most people like that, though?
What?
Not easy, but soft?
It's gross.
What is?
That stuff.
It's gross.
What, people?
Isn't she soft?
Who?
The girl you never mention
because she doesn't really exist
or we're not going anywhere near her
because she doesn't really exist.
The one who's not named Maria.
Don't!
Eric!
Eric, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to freak you out.
I just--
Eric, wait!
I saw you kiss that girl.
That day by the river.
She was so--
so beautiful.
What girl, Lori?
The one you were with.
I wasn't spying.
What are you talking about?
Don't you even remember her?
I thought you were shy.
You're not shy.
I have a collect call from a Lori Cranston.
Will you accept?
Her mom's not here.
I can talk to her,
but her mom's not here.
Look, we should just get out of here,
keep moving.
Thank you.
Are you the guy from Buffalo?
Yeah.
ls that a new flashlight?
Yeah. Oh. Sorry, Lieutenant.
You should check in for us.
In the mind of this kid,
there's no violence,
no other will, just a desire to take a life.
Pleasure of feeling a body expire.
Feel its last beautiful sigh in his hands.
He's addicted to the intimacy of the kill--
the tenderness.
So that's the kid they let out.
Yeah.
Not the Buffalo I used to know.
And they sent you?
Well, no, not exactly.
I'm pretty much retired.
They just give me the easy cases.
You chasing after this kid?
Kind of.
Alone?
Well, I got no family. He's my hobby.
ls it because I'm a freak?
You're not a freak.
You've said it before.
You listen too closely
to every little thing people say.
You remember stuff you should forget.
You could do things to me--
things you want. . .
things you can't say.
Doesn't work like that, Lori.
That day by the river. . .
there was something. . .
so. . .
perfect in that kiss.
Lori, I never kissed anybody.
Yes, you did.
Not really.
Not like you think.
Let's go inside, Lori.
Just stay quiet.
Use your hands.
It's what I want.
Do it.
Dissolve me.
I love you.
Welcome to FunLand.
That's right. Welcome to FunLand.
Hey, kids, what's crazier
than a barrel of monkeys?
It's the Crazy Submarine ride. Now open.
But you must be this tall
to get on the Crazy Submarine ride.
Balloons! Come on, kids!
2 bucks!
Tell Mommy you want a balloon!
Folks, there's no line
at the Sky Sweep right now.
. . . by the Ferris wheel.
Good afternoon, everybody.
Welcome to FunLand.
Please enjoy yourselves today
and tell all your friends.
Hey!
Hey, Maria.
Sorry I'm late.
I had to sneak away from my mom.
It's pretty lame here.
No, it's cool.
I didn't come here for the rides.
Should we walk around?
Yeah. Great.
Now boarding, the Dragon Coach.
So do you want to go on a ride?
Yeah, I guess.
I like the kiddie ones.
Yeah, me, too.
Hey, wait up, bro!
Hi.
Are you from in town?
No.
I should keep you company.
You know?
So guys don't hit on you.
I'm 15.
So did you grow up around here?
Kind of.
I mean--
It's a long story.
Tell me.
We move a lot-- my folks and me.
That was fun.
All right. Everybody off.
That's it. Off to your right.
Follow the railing.
Right there.
You must stay on the other
side of the yellow line.
Please don't put yourself
or anybody else in danger.
So do you want to go on another ride?
We don't have to.
What do you want to do?
Be alone.
I know a place.
Follow the railing around.
Keep your hands
inside the ride at all times.
Thanks for coming.
How about over there?
I like it here.
Stop spacing out.
Oh, man!
Crazy!
That's really pretty.
Yeah.
Here we go, bro. Hands up.
Here we go!
Oh, my God.
Eric!
God! Oh, my God!
Stop! Let me off!
Get me the fuck out of this thing!
ls she your girlfriend?
Get away from him! She's a liar!
Get the fuck away from him!
She's lying to you! She's a liar!
- It's a trap!
- Lori, you're crazy!
Get the fuck away from him!
- Lori! Lori!
- Get away from me!
Why would you come here?
Why would you follow me here?
We can see you!
- Why would you come here?
- Come out, you fuckers!
- Lori!
- Look! Look!
Cristofuoro?
No? Come on. Let's go.
Stay where you are, Eric.
Stay where you are.
Step away from each other.
Step away!
- No, you cannot do this to me!
- Shut up! Put your hands on your head.
You cannot detain me!
You can't do this--
Put your hands on your head!
Kneel down now! Both of you!
Kneel.
Who the fuck are you?
Lorelei Jane Cranston.
- How old are you?
- 16.
I have my parents' permission to be here.
Eric, with your left hand,
empty your pockets.
Slowly.
Both pockets.
You can't detain me.
No, you're right. I can't.
But I can detain her.
Nothing was going to happen.
Yeah?
What were you doing?
I know what you were doing.
You were trying to entrap me!
You were trying to entrap me.
Stand. Drop your hands.
From you, I'm going
to need a phone number. Come with me.
Stand up, pal.
Well, can you get her mother to call me?
When she can.
You do that.
Get a statement from Eric
before we let him go.
Great. Wait up.
You get Gary?
Yeah.
Surprise, surprise.
Do you know who this kid is?
Do you have any idea what he's done?
He is not someone you can trust.
You understand?
Eric says you're a liar.
I have to let you go.
But when I do, if you stay with him,
there is nothing I can do to protect you.
I can't even have you followed.
So before that happens,
you're going to hear me out.
That kid is a killer.
I know that.
Everyone knows about his parents.
I'm with him because I want to be.
Not just his parents.
He only killed them
because they'd found out what he'd done.
I could show you photographs of a girl--
Alicia Vargas.
A girl just like you.
She was breathing
and laughing and watching TV
and thinking she might like a boyfriend,
and now she's dead--
in the ground, cold and dead.
And there was another girl.
She went missing around the same time.
Sophia Tersa.
My guess is when we find her body,
we'll find she went just the same way.
Lorelei, Eric liked Alicia and Sophia.
Just the same way I'm sure he likes you.
He doesn't like me like me.
We're just friends.
If you're just friends, what did he tell you
he was doing with Maria?
What? Did he say he wasn't
going to hurt her?
Just hook up with her?
I know that bothers you.
It's my choice.
And I'm just trying
to help you make a good one.
He told me about you.
Told me all about you and your sick wife.
You're just a small beans cop
with a vegetable wife.
Here you go, Mac.
He's done, fellas. He's going home.
Good work tonight.
When do I get to go home?
Just a couple more minutes,
and I'll give you a ride home.
What do you want to do now, John?
I'm going home.
Lori.
I'm sorry.
I didn't. . .
You don't owe me anything.
I was wrong.
You do owe me something.
It's cooler out here
than I thought it would be.
Mmm. Pretty much dead.
You know what I smell now?
Lake.
Tell me I'm pretty, Eric.
You are pretty.
Yeah.
But I'm breathing.
My mom has this tape.
And basically,
it's just this guy screaming
over and over,
''You have to want change,
you have to want change. ''
Nothing changes.
Nothing changes!
What are you doing?
Lori!
Stop!
Stop.
Lori, stop!
Fuck you!
No!
Lori, give me your hand!
Give me your hand! Come here!
Give me your hand!
Lori!
Take it!
Come on. Please, grab it!
Grab it, please!
Lori!
That's it.
She just fell in.
And I tried to save her.
I didn't kill her, Lieutenant.
No, I know you didn't.
I should get off this bus
and talk to the D.A. on your behalf.
Here's the thing.
You do belong here, Eric.
I say we take this any way it comes.
My wife wanted to say hi.
She wanted me to tell you
she's not paralyzed.
She might be fucked,
but she ain't no vegetable.
My wife likes to say
there are two kinds of people.
Those chasing pleasure. . .
and those running from pain.
Maybe she's right.
I don't know.
What I do know is this.
Pleasure helps you forget.
But pain--
pain forces you to hope.
You tell yourself
''This can't last. ''
''Today could be different. ''
''Today. . .
something just might change. ''