Terri!
You clean up the tub ring?
I'm still in here, Uncle James.
Did you?
Last night you said you'd clean it up.
I can't clean it
because I'm still in here, okay?
You'll be late for school, Terri.
Do you want me to go to school
or do you want me to clean the tub,
because I can't do both.
I'm hungry. You cook us up some steaks.
No. Those are for dinner, okay?
How about I make us
some beans on toast?
How's that sound?
- Hey, guys, come on. Let's go.
- Why didn't you pass it to me?
- Go.
- All right.
Yeah, wait up.
Zach, wait up!
Hey, slow down!
For all you people
who want to blame the camera
for your bad yearbook picture,
recent freshman's shot.
- But don't look for us, though.
- Because we nailed our pictures!
Yeah! I know I did!
- Until tomorrow, peace!
- Peace!
Peace.
All right, people,
I got a couple of announcements to make.
Want to remind you that those
large, round, metal receptacles
you see around campus?
They're for trash. Use them.
- Hey!
- National Honor Society essays
and applications deadline
is next Wednesday.
You can give them to me,
- or there's a designated box...
- Yo.
...in the main office.
- Trash heap.
- You know this?
- The Pioneers will be playing
three away games this month
and the team needs drivers.
- You know this. Shit is old school.
- And if anyone's parent can volunteer,
please have them contact...
- Old school?
- Hip-hop.
Go Pioneers!
- Rappers get all the pussy.
- We're instituting a no-tolerance policy...
...against cell phones.
- Okay.
If you're found texting or... Yes, Terri.
May I go to the restroom, please?
You just got here. Absolutely not.
If you're found texting or using
your phone in class,
phone will be confiscated and returned
to you at the end of the school day.
You may use the phone
during nutrition and lunch.
- You know about eating pussy, right?
- The library
will be closed intermittently next week
while construction's going on.
And if your study hall is being relocated,
there will be a notice posted by the door.
Why are you doing this?
We're all aware of the false...
Players be choking to death on the pussy.
...disruptions to the entire school,
as well as...
Okay, I get it. Okay?
Do not take it lightly
and, then, the authorities will not either.
You know about eating butt holes, right?
- I said I get it!
- Terri!
Chill out, titty-balls. Damn!
Titty-balls.
Has reminded me
to ask you not to leave food in your lockers.
Mr. Ribis, I see you brought
a hat to school today.
- Yes, I did, sir.
- You know that I collect hats.
I have a large collection.
If you would like your hat
to stay yours and not mine,
I suggest you put it in your
backpack and keep it there.
- Go to class, Mr. Ribis.
- You got it, Mr. Fitzgerald.
We have mice in the attic.
We have to do something about this.
We have valuable documents up there.
Feeling better, Uncle James?
Up and down.
I'm gonna go to the market
and get some traps and some cheddar.
You can set the traps tonight
before bedtime, okay?
I don't want to do that, Uncle James.
Well, if I set them, I'll forget to check.
- I can remind you.
- No, Terri.
You have no chores.
You have no one breathing down your neck.
I mean, you live a prince's life here.
You know that.
- I know.
- Good.
I'm gonna set up the ladder
next to the crawl space.
I want to talk to you
about my boyfriend.
Well, I don't want to talk to you.
Oh, you tango divine!
I don't know if you have heard,
but there's going to come a time...
How did we do up there?
Terri?
- Five mice!
- That's not bad.
Well, we'll put them in the marsh.
Let the other animals pick them off.
Just think of it
as feeding the animals, Terri.
- I'm hurrying as fast as I can.
- I just really don't want
- Mrs. Vick to...
- All right, class.
Now today we're going to learn
how to crack an egg.
- Do you know how to crack an egg?
- No.
I'm sure you think you do,
but there is a special way.
Now what you do is,
one, two, three, crack.
It's all in the wrist.
One, two, three, crack. Wrist.
It's so easy and a way...
I just want to be with you.
This is just the perfect moment.
All right, come on, come on.
I know you guys think
you'll never lose your memory,
but believe me, you will.
One, two, three, crack.
Ms. Hamish,
please send Terri Thompson in.
Terri Thompson.
I had hoped we wouldn't
have to meet like this.
In fact, I was sure we wouldn't have to.
Do you know all the students' names?
No, it wouldn't be possible for me
to know all the students' names.
- No.
- Why do you...
I mean, how do you know mine?
Well, every year there's two groups of kids,
who stand out here.
Okay?
There's the good-hearted kids.
And there's the bad-hearted kids.
And those are the ones
whose names I learn.
And which one am I?
Don't you know, dude?
I don't know if I know.
Well, you strike me as one of
the good-hearted ones, Terri,
which is why I'm upset
that we have to meet here today,
for reasons of discipline.
Sit down, Markson!
Sit down! In the chair!
There's something wrong with that kid.
Is he one of the bad hearts?
No. With him, we're dealing
with a third category.
As yet, unnamed and unknowable.
Where were we?
You were getting mad
at me about my tardies.
No. Um...
Listen, you want a Malt Ball?
Yeah. Thank you.
I'm not mad, but
we have a real problem here
on our hands,
and I'm for dealing with it head-on.
What do you think about that?
Okay.
Good.
Well, what's the deal?
Your grades are dropping.
Your teachers are telling me
you won't participate in the lessons,
you've begun to wear pajamas every day.
Do you understand,
from my perspective, how those things
could be categorized as red flags?
They're just comfortable on me.
Why are you late
to school every day, Terri?
- It's getting harder to be able...
- Okay.
Okay.
Stop right there.
- You all right there, Ms. Hamish?
- Fine.
You're just clearing out the old pipes, huh?
Dynamite. Listen, do me a favor.
Set aside my Monday mornings
for Terri Thompson.
Terri Thomp...
Thomp... Thomp...
And if you could also let
Mrs. Davidson know
that Terri is mine
on Monday mornings, please.
All right?
T-H-O-M...
So here's what I'm proposing.
We meet once a week
and check in with each other.
See how we're faring against the world.
You know what I mean?
Really?
What is weird about two guys sitting down,
sharing snacks and shooting the breeze?
- Nothing, I guess.
- Nothing is right, dude.
And by the way,
you get out of homeroom
at the beginning of each week.
Come on! Are you kidding me?
Up high! Fitzy needs a high five.
All the traps were empty this morning.
That's very good, Terri. We won't be
seeing those boys anymore, will we?
No, I think they'll come back,
probably next week.
- I bet they'll come back.
- Mmm.
I don't think so.
Once you dispatch that front line,
the troops always fall back
for safer ground.
You know, they got to find their food
in the woods like before.
You got plans for the weekend?
A hummingbird in flight
has the highest metabolism of all animals
with the exception of insects,
which is necessary to support
the rapid beating of their wings.
Incubation can last two to three weeks.
After hatching...
What's this about cheddar cheese?
When did you start liking that?
I don't understand.
I need you to explain this to me.
You enjoyed hurting these animals,
is that it?
I don't know.
Well, I'm so ashamed.
I didn't even know you were capable
of doing something so ugly.
It's like I went crazy or something.
I've never done
anything like that before.
It's bloodlust, dude.
It can be a hard habit to break, they say,
once you get started in on it.
I think I'm going to become a vegetarian.
Whoa. Wait a minute now.
Let's not get carried away.
I mean, you are remorseful.
And that's a positive.
I knew a kid growing up that used
to tie flaming tennis balls to cats' tails,
and loved every minute of it.
Apparently, he's a cop now.
Anyway, the thing about
this mouse scenario is
even if your uncle says he doesn't
understand why you did it,
guess what, he does.
He does and so do I. All right?
Now, that's not to say
that it's not wrong or weird
because, believe me, it is.
But it's important for you to get
that we get it, okay? We get it!
Right?
Open your legs. Okay?
What the hell is your problem?
You promised me.
Open your damn legs.
Terri, can you do the French toast?
- Hello, Earth to Terri.
- What?
- You're on French toast, okay?
- Yeah, sure.
Oh, my God.
What, Terri?
What? What?
Guys.
Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God.
- Seriously?
- I can't believe they're doing that in class.
- Oh, my God.
- In class. In class.
- So gross.
Hey, guys, come over here.
Do you see that? Right below the desk.
You stud.
- Is he so desperate to get some?
- I'd say.
Damn, dude.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
What is it?
- Tell me what it is.
- Come here.
Is it true?
- Is it true?
- Yeah. Yeah, here.
- It's true.
- It's true!
- Watch the finger.
- I'm sorry.
Let me see it again!
Watch it! Watch it!
Come on, use your traps.
That's it. All right.
I got a nose down here, so don't...
Don't kick back. Push!
Hey!
Mr. Thompson, we've been waiting for you.
I'm sorry, Mr. Flemisch.
There was a hold-up last period.
A what? A hold-up?
What do you mean, like a robbery?
Like a bandido-esque...
You know, let me ask you something.
This is something that's been bothering
me for quite a while now.
Why do you bear so blatant a grudge
towards physical education and wellness?
Hey, Mr. Flemisch.
- I don't think grudge is the right word.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Well, let's get it right, then.
How do you feel about physical education
and wellness, Terri? Hmm?
The feeling is no feeling.
All right, Terri.
Well, I got some news for you.
After warm-ups today, we're going
to start working on the high jumps.
Now, will you or will you not participate?
And I encourage you to think
before you answer.
I will not.
Well, then you get out of my gymnasium
and don't come back!
Shit!
Ms. Miles!
Mr. Ribis, you are in deep doo-doo!
No, I'm not mad. I am furious!
I am disappointed because I just
lost two average students.
This kind of thing is punishable by law!
- What's wrong, Marcus?
- Are you out of your mind?
Those guys got in trouble
and it made my meeting stop.
Don't worry, Marcus.
You'll be back in there soon.
I don't know how much more
these two lovebirds can take.
Do you meet with Mr. Fitzgerald
every Monday?
Who all comes into these meetings,
Ms. Hamish?
Well, let's see.
On Mondays, there's you and Marcus.
And on Tuesdays, Amber Zane.
- Amber Zane?
- That's right.
And on Wednesdays, there's
that little boy in the wheelchair.
I can never remember his name.
Donny Washburn.
Oh! Donny. That's right.
And on Fridays, there's Chad Markson.
It's quite a group.
Terri? What's up, dude? You all right?
Good hearts my ass!
Fuck.
Nice pajamas, man.
Uncle James? Are you okay?
Terri, what are you doing here?
Did you take too many pills?
I just need to be near some bodies.
- Come on, let's get you home.
- Okay.
Terri?
Check it out. Double D's got a shit slip.
People, hush! Terri, go.
What did you do?
I cut school yesterday.
Donny, wait out here
one second, will you?
- Hey, dudes.
- Hey, Donny.
You already done in there?
We're taking five
so he can see you guys.
Why are you wearing sunglasses?
What? Oh. These things?
Seriously, what do you guys do in there,
play volleyball?
Cool Breeze Club. Members only.
Get your butt in here!
Right now!
Uh-oh! Watch out.
What is it with you?
It's always something, isn't it?
What did he do? Do you know?
It's bad, dude.
He's not too happy
with you ditching either, Terri.
You're off the creek, pal,
and that's three detentions.
Count them, one, two, three.
Now, get out of here.
Geez!
Mr. Thompson, we've got a problem!
Get in here. Close the door.
- Have a seat.
- Here it comes.
What can you be thinking?
- The school is not a country club.
- Heads up.
I'm not really mad at you, okay?
Just go along with me, all right?
Not an option
for you to be coming in here
and try to do that kind of thing
in my school!
Sorry, Ter. That was a little show
for old Ms. Hamish out there.
She loves it when I lay into you kids.
It's keeping her going.
You yelled and screamed at me for her?
Sounds bad, I know. Yeah. Um...
The thing is she's not doing so hot.
Truth is she's dying.
She's dying now?
Not this second, no, but soon.
- What is she dying of?
- She's dying of cigarettes.
Okay? She's dying of death.
Was it all a joke with Chad Markson, too?
No, dude.
It's always something with that kid,
and today he outdid himself.
I will show you in pictograph form
What I'm talking about.
This is what he said to Mr. Flemisch
in front of the entire class today.
Yeah. Yeah, he's a tough one.
Very smart and very angry.
But, Terri, I didn't call you in here today
to talk about Chad, did I?
No.
I called you in to talk about what
you said in the hallway there.
I was mad.
And I don't blame you, dude.
- But I think you misunderstood the facts.
- What's to misunderstand?
I'm a part of a group of monsters,
you know?
I'm going to show you something,
and it's something that I've never shown
to any other student, okay?
Come on, Terri. There's something in there
I think might help.
Do you recognize that guy?
Cute little baby, happy baby.
Simpler times, right?
Moving right along.
And what could go wrong?
It's a Shangri-La.
Boom.
Now, whenever I'm down or depressed,
I take a look at that
and it clears me right up.
- This picture makes you feel better?
- Of course.
Because you see, Terri,
I thought I was a monster, too.
And believe me when I tell you,
I was treated like one.
I like this person.
I look forward to these days
and I look forward to my life.
Do you understand what I'm saying to you?
Mr. Fitzgerald,
you were treated like a monster
because you were a monster.
- Wait a second.
- I'm treated like a monster
because that's what I am to them.
- Terri.
- This morning,
they asked me if I suck on my own breasts.
Mr. Fitzgerald? Are you okay?
I'm just tired.
You know, sometimes I think
I should just leave you kids on your own.
The way these other kids treat you,
maybe that's preparation
for the real world.
I'm just trying to help you, right?
I'm just trying to give you some help, Terri.
I guess I just wish I didn't need help,
you know?
Coming at you.
So, what about the ditching?
Don't worry about it.
I mean, I already yelled at you, right?
Am I right?
You were so freaking scared.
I wasn't that scared.
Oh, dude, you were scared.
Heather Miles
and parent to see you, Mr. Fitzgerald.
Thank you, Ms. Hamish.
Just ask them to have a seat, please.
We're just about finishing up here.
What are you going to do with her?
What can I do?
Ribis is out.
It wouldn't be right if she got to stay on.
Where will she go?
She will transfer to Hollyfield,
I would imagine, like Ribis did.
All right, Terri,
we will see you next week, yeah?
Okay, Heather, Mrs. Miles,
if you could join me here?
Have a seat.
Could you tell Mr. Fitzgerald that
I need to see him right away?
- What?
- Tell him it's an emergency.
Mr. Fitzgerald,
Terri Thompson says he wants to see you.
He says it's an emergency.
Dude, I have an important conference here.
What is up?
- I know, sorry. It's about Heather.
- What about her?
Terri, I'm in the middle of a...
It just seemed to me like Dirty Zach
was making her, you know?
That is not what I heard.
It's my understanding
she was a willing participant.
Maybe once they got started,
but I saw it from the beginning,
she was shaking her head
and holding him off.
I'm telling you, she didn't want to do it.
You can't kick somebody out of school
for something that they didn't want to do,
Mr. Fitzgerald.
Terri, can I ask where this is coming from?
This sudden concern?
What do you mean?
All I know is that she didn't want to do it.
That's the truth. No bull.
Okay.
Chad?
Just wanted to come over
and see what you're doing today, okay?
Oh!
- Everything all right?
- Best ever. Thanks, Uncle James.
Yeah, it's great. Thanks.
Where's your mom?
I don't know.
Where's your dad?
You don't like the beans?
I like the beans, Terri.
I'm glad you're having a good time.
This is super fun.
I'm Joe Hollywood and I can make you
and I can break you.
So, don't forget to IM me
because I'm hemorrhaging money here
and the 101's a freaking parking lot.
The humane thing to do would be to take
the set outside and put it out of its misery.
I might have mastered life.
Yeah, baby. Joe Hollywood.
So, what did Fitzgerald
give you for ditching?
Uh, he was...
He was... He was pretty mad.
Yeah, he was mad. He was mad.
He's a weird dude.
Half the time, I think he wants to hit me,
the other half,
I'm scared he's gonna
kiss me or something.
He wants to help us, Chad.
It only creeps me out.
This one time, he shows me
this picture of him as a teenager
with hardly any clothes on.
He kept putting his hairy freaking mitts
on my shoulders,
going on about my good heart.
I think it's some straight up weird shit
I don't even want to...
He didn't show you Yesterdays.
Yeah, that was it, Yesterdays.
"I've never
shown this to anyone before in my life."
- Chad, you have to go.
- Why? What's wrong, Terri?
I've got homework to do.
I need to be alone. Please go, Chad.
- It's Sunday. What are you talking about?
- Chad, please just leave me alone.
- Terri, what's wrong?
- Just leave, Chad.
- Whoa! Dude, Terri. Chill out, man. All right.
- You need to go.
Terri, what the hell is the matter with you?
What are you? Faggot fucking psycho?
Fucking big-titty piece of shit?
What the fuck's the matter with you?
- Where'd your friend go?
- Home, I guess.
I'm glad you're having visitors.
I do understand it.
Well, you're underestimating me.
Wait. How could you... How... Well, how
could you think that I don't understand it?
Because it's got nothing to do
with aesthetics, that's why.
No. It's basic mathematics.
It has to do with incoming money
and outgoing expenses, Janet.
Hello?
The woman wants to cannonball
into a pool of Italian high-heeled shoes.
You tell me something, Terri,
is there anything wrong with my aesthetic?
What's up with you, Terri Bear?
Don't call me that.
All right, let's have it.
Come on, tell me what's wrong.
Me and Chad Markson
hung out this weekend
and my uncle made us
beans on toast and we talked.
Beans on toast?
What, you live in a hobo village?
You guys go off on your donkeys after that?
He told me that
you showed him Yesterdays.
Oh, I see.
Yeah. "Oh."
Fitzgerald.
Where?
The same handwriting?
All right, I'm coming down.
Let's take a walk.
I don't even understand this.
Well, a zombie is someone that's died
and comes back to life.
Yeah, I know what a zombie is, Bob.
I don't see the connection.
Well, go get the paint.
I'm sorry, Terri.
Come sit down over here with me.
Did you notice the new secretary
in my office?
A temp agency sent her over to help out
while Ms. Hamish was in the hospital.
Her name is Samantha.
She's a really sweet girl.
She's a newlywed, she lives here in town.
And...
I could tell from the moment she got here
that she really wants
to work here permanently.
I mean, it's a five-minute commute,
very convenient for her, right here in town.
It'd be a great job for her, you know?
Anyway, this morning,
she was trying to figure out
through a series of sideways questions
exactly how serious
Ms. Hamish's illness was.
And she was acting concerned, of course,
but I could see in her eyes, you know,
she doesn't know Ms. Hamish.
She can't help it.
There's a part of her
that wants Ms. Hamish to die.
It'll get her the job.
So?
So, Ms. Hamish is dead, Terri.
I got the call about an hour ago.
I'm sorry, Mr. Fitzgerald.
Don't say things you don't mean, Terri.
You're not sorry she's gone.
You barely knew her.
Sorry.
Now, after I got off the phone
with the hospital,
I called the temp agency and I told them,
you know, we're gonna
hire Samantha permanently.
And they thanked me and they said
they'd call her and give her the news.
And I said, "You know, if you don't mind,
I would rather do it,"
because I kind of wanted
to spring the news on her.
You know, what a great way for she and I
to start our working together, right?
But now, I have to tell her she's got the job
and I will have to watch
while she pretends to be sad.
Life's a mess, dude,
but we're all just doing
the best we can, you know.
You, and me, and Samantha,
we're just doing what we can.
So, if I hurt you or if I lied to you,
all I can tell you is I'm sorry,
and I will try to do better.
Maybe I will do better
or maybe I'll do even worse. I don't know.
I screw up all the time
because that's what people do,
you know?
Okay, Mr. Fitzgerald.
Ms. Hamish's funeral is this Friday.
She doesn't have any family
or even any friends.
I was going to go over there alone
and pay my respects,
but I got to be honest,
it is starting to feel like a real downer.
I just don't know. Uh...
Do you want to come with?
You can come sit
over here with us, Terri.
I'm okay. Thanks.
What a jerk!
Enough, people, enough.
This is something that we're going
to have to get through together,
as a group.
Now, there will be a test this Friday
where you will be asked to showcase
your mucho sewing skills
with a traditional Mexican poncho.
Take them off, Heather.
Take the sunglasses off, Heather Miles.
Take them off, Heather! God!
Hey, everybody, look at me,
I'm Joe Hollywood.
I am successful. You should come
because I'm going to help you out.
I'm hemorrhaging.
I'm on a parking lot.
Oh, Joe Hollywood.
Very nice, Terri.
Would you mind
if we continue with the lesson?
I'm sorry, Ms. Vick.
Now, the traditional
Mexican poncho
is centuries and centuries old.
And what makes it extraordinary
is the individuality of all the design,
and that's where you all come in.
Each one of you is going to leave
indelibly your own imprint.
The traditional Mexican costume
is exquisite.
And because they do not have
the kind of industrialization that we have,
they've been able to maintain
this ancient and traditional
culture and dress.
You're all capable
of going on the computer.
I want you all to look and decide
where is your particular poncho from.
Think about what towns,
is it going to be Minatitlán?
Is it going to be Oaxaca?
Is it going to be San Miguel de Allende?
What have we got?
We've got yarn. Look at those colors.
And the Mexican flag.
Look how brilliant that flag is.
I want you to incorporate these
with bright, basic colors into your ponchos.
And for people that are shy,
this will be excellent to start coming out
and wear bright colors
and say to the world,
"Here I am. This is me."
Bye, guys.
Oh, my God, that was so funny.
Bye, Heather.
Hey, hold on a minute?
Um, hi. Do you have a second?
Yeah, sure.
I guess I just wanted to say thank you
for doing that thing in there,
with the sunglasses.
Okay, yeah.
Can I ask you something, though?
I mean, why did you help me?
I'm... I don't know, why not?
I don't know.
Since last week, it seems like
everyone has decided to hate me
except for you.
Do you know what I think it is, Heather?
I think that there's good-heart kids
and that there is bad-heart kids
here at the school.
But when I look at you,
when I really look at you,
I know that you're a good-heart person.
And I guess that
makes me want to help you
or be nice to you or...
Because that's what good hearts get.
I don't know.
Well, thank you, Terri.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Bye, Heather.
Hi, Chad.
Terri Thompson, the man with the plan.
Terri T, super kid.
- Hi, Samantha.
- Terri! Terri!
Terri Thompson's here to see you.
Yeah, just one second.
Look, I'm sorry I freaked out on you, okay?
Why?
Why'd I freak out on you,
or why am I sorry?
Why?
Okay.
I freaked out on you because
you made me feel bad about Mr. Fitzgerald.
And I don't want to feel bad about him
because he's my good friend.
- And you can think I'm...
- All right. Who is ready to mourn?
Samantha, why wasn't Chad told
that his Friday meeting was canceled?
Um... Right. Just... One second.
I'm sorry about this, Chad, but you must
have heard about Mrs. Hamish's passing.
Well, Terri and I are just going
to the funeral to see her off, so...
Yeah.
We'll make it up next week.
We'll do Thursday and Friday.
- How about that?
- Mr. Fitzgerald, could Chad come with us?
I was just going to say the same thing.
To the funeral?
You know, I really liked Ms. Hamish.
She was... She was my friend.
Yeah.
I don't know, Chad...
Yeah? I can go?
I'm really going to miss her.
I'm going to need you to cut out
any kind of weirdness there, Chad.
Can I have your word on that?
Oh, yeah. Totally.
All right, boys.
What? What?
Please write down the schedule,
Thursday and Friday.
Terri, check out her skull.
Gracias. Thank you.
Please don't make me laugh.
Boys, have some respect.
There's a dead person right here.
- We're just... This is us.
- Sure.
All righty.
Please. Please.
Amen.
Um...
No baked beans in this whole place,
if you can believe it or not.
I just never know what to get.
What are you getting?
Are you guys ready to order?
You know, we're going to
need another minute, if that's all right.
Of course.
Hey, that reminds me.
What's up with you and that girl Heather?
- Oh! Did you see that?
- That did look like something, yeah.
Nothing. We've just been talking.
She's coming over tonight.
Wait, like, tonight? As in tonight, tonight?
- 7:00, she said.
- And it's a date?
- She didn't say.
- What are you guys going to do?
I don't know.
I guess I'II... I'm going to show her around
and I'll show her my paperbacks,
and introduce her to Uncle James.
And he's got some old records
and I think she likes music, so...
Is your heart breaking right now?
Mine is.
All right, Terri, no offense,
but it's time to take your head
out of your ass, okay?
Chad, watch it.
Sorry, Mr. Fitzgerald.
You have the biggest set of tits
in the entire school, besides yours,
- coming to your house tonight.
- Chad.
She says she just wants to come over
and see where I live.
Oh, you're going to blow it.
If you do, she won't. Get it?
What is wrong with you, Chad? Honestly.
- Right here. Stop.
- Okay.
Listen, Ter,
thanks for tagging along today, Ter.
It was weird.
- It was really weird.
- It was awesome.
And good luck tonight, Terri.
You look out for yourself, okay?
Thanks, Mr. Fitzgerald. Bye.
Don't touch the radio.
What's with the face?
Someone steal your crackers?
Are you...
You look pretty good.
No rhyme or reason to it.
I don't want to be rude, but I want
to take advantage of this window,
if you don't mind.
Yeah, sure.
I'm going to go clean for a bit.
Oh.
Hey, Terri.
How's it going?
What are you doing here, Chad?
Look, I don't want
to break up a party or anything.
Is she here?
No, but she's going to be here any minute,
and I just put Uncle James down.
- Are you gonna get out of here or what?
- Yeah, totally.
Listen, though.
Can I use your restroom real quick?
No. Go pee in the woods. I'll see you
tomorrow and I'll tell you all about it.
I'm afraid it's a little more serious
than that, Terri.
Are you almost done in there?
What? Who is it?
Terri? Terri Thompson?
I never liked you, Terri.
Why are you so mean?
Delivery!
Delivery, Terri.
Ooh!
Hi, Terri.
Terri?
Um...
Is that your uncle?
It's my friend Chad.
He'll be gone in a minute.
Terri.
What's wrong with him?
A few different things, I think.
Have you been drinking alcohol, Chad?
A little bit.
If you honestly think that I'm going to kill
the buzz of a $200 bottle of whiskey.
$200 for one bottle?
- It's not $200, Chad.
- It is so and it is fucking delicious.
You want... You want me to go get it?
I don't want any, Heather,
but if you do, you should go ahead.
Yeah? I should go? I'm going to find it.
Never mind, Chad.
You know, he's probably
not going to find it anyways.
Hey, do you want to go see your uncle?
Can he hear us?
I'm not sure.
Anyways, even if he could hear us,
he wouldn't remember it later on.
He looks sad.
Maybe he can hear us,
but he just doesn't care.
What are you doing?
There's no use in pretending
you're thinking of anybody but yourself.
Why do you say that?
Heather, he's sick.
Does he talk to you like that?
No.
Last one to puke is a rotten egg.
Hmm.
Meet you in the shed then, fuckers.
Come on. Let's let him rest.
You can go have a drink with Chad.
I propose a toast,
to good times and friends.
That's not how you're supposed
to drink it, Terri.
- It's how I drink it, okay?
- Wait a minute.
Shut up and listen, you guys.
Sounds like... Like...
Hey, give me that. They're not yours.
Hey!
What the hell was that?
- Chad, they're my uncle's.
- Your uncle has a whole houseful, okay?
He's not going to notice
three little pills missing.
I don't think we should.
Well...
Think she'll fuck us both?
Yes or no?
What? What?
- I know you met her first, Terri.
- Chad, I want you to take it easy, okay?
No, I'm pretty sure that...
Do we really need the radio right now?
Look, look at me.
I need you to take a breath and calm down.
Look at me. Calm down, okay?
I'm totally calm.
Look, pay attention
next time I'm over there
because she's looking at me
like I'm up for auction.
Maybe we can just deal without the radio.
I don't want you to be uncomfortable,
but I think it would be okay
if we just took one each.
Fuck, yeah. Let's do it.
- What's it going to do to me?
- Just make you feel nice.
I already feel nice.
You can always feel nicer.
Only one, though, right?
Only one.
You took two pills.
Shh!
Don't tell Terri.
Who cares about that guy?
I care. He's my great big sweetheart.
Hey.
Uh...
Heather, I have a question.
Um...
- Why did you get fingered that one time?
- Chad!
- Come on.
- I'm sorry, Heather.
You don't have to answer that
if you don't want to.
I'll answer it.
Oh, good.
All girls get fingered sooner or later, Chad,
but I guess you wouldn't know about that.
Yeah. That's nice.
Look, what I was trying to get at is,
why did you get fingered
in Home Economics?
That's where he wanted to do it.
He said nobody would see.
But why Dirty Zach?
Because he wanted to, okay?
And it feels good to be wanted.
Maybe that sounds sad to you guys.
I don't know.
No, it's not sad.
It's not sad at all.
- I feel strange.
- I feel awesome!
It's probably just the pill, Terri.
Is it too strong? Are you okay?
You look like an adult over there.
- I do?
- Like a big shot.
You're so shiny.
I am?
I'm shiny?
I just want to
fuck the whole world.
Cut a hole in the ground,
I'll fuck it all night.
It feels like I peed my pants, but I didn't.
Me, too.
Hey, let's pee our pants on purpose, huh?
What?
Go for it, Chad.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- You don't think I'll do it?
- I hope you do.
- I'm doing it, doing it right now.
- Okay.
What did you think of that?
Chad, that was amazing.
What did you think about that?
- Well, it was new.
- Yeah?
Your turn.
My turn to what, pee all over my clothes?
No, thank you.
You got to do something.
I mean, I didn't just do all that for nothing.
I think you did, actually.
Chad, what are you talking about?
You have to do something, Heather.
Gee, Chad, what do you want me to do?
Yeah, that's right.
I want you to suck my cock.
Cock?
You call that little pink thing
stuck to your balls a cock?
Fuck this.
Terri.
Fucking hell!
Hey, guys.
You're not drinking your drink.
You're supposed to hit it, not babysit it.
What are you thinking about?
He wants to see your tits.
Do you want to see?
I don't know.
No, no.
She wants to see your tits.
Show her your tits, Terri.
- Let's take our clothes off.
- I can't.
I'll help.
Terri.
Look.
Terri, come here.
Terri, come over here. Come on.
Terri.
Terri, please come over here.
I'm right here, please.
Terri.
Did you have somebody
over here last night?
A girl?
Yeah.
A pretty girl.
Who... Was... What happened?
Come on.
Thank you, Terri.
There's some aspirin in the nurse's station.
Yeah, that would be good.
Well, that was easy.
What the hell is this lock for anyway?
Aspirin and iodine?
Can I have one, too?
Sky hoop.
What do you think?
She's embarrassed.
I'm not going to say anything
about what happened
if that's what she's worried about.
Well, I'm sure she would appreciate that.
It's okay.
I don't think I'm ready
for all that stuff yet anyway.
Who is, you know?
So, do you think you and your wife
are going to get divorced?
No. No.
Just a fight.
One of many.
What was it about?
For some people, Terri,
enough is just not enough.
How do I look?
Like you slept in a car.
Oh, well.
Are you going to go home now?
Yeah. I might as well get it over with.
Where are you gonna go?
I'll probably see how Chad's doing.
Listen, Terri,
we did not just enter school property.
- Okay.
- Yeah?
- Are we clear on that?
- Very clear.
All right. Lay five on me.
Come on, lay five on me.
I will see you on Monday
for our meeting, yeah?
- Monday.
- All right.
Thank you.