Men have been
justly considered...
Ios... masters of the world.
Men have dominated
to wild animals.
Men have penetrated the
depths of the jungle...
And able to investigate the Moon
and planets...
But it still exists... a...
Where no man... has set foot.
A place that even have seen.
Ladies' room.
How are you, honey? It happened.
It comes and goes.
What a bummer.
Believe me, it does not matter.
However, I get very nervous.
The doctor told me that I should not
worry about it.
I would be worried. Dr. Vengard.
Dr. Vengard
is the doctor you need.
I'm not willing to allow
I psychoanalyzed.
Come on, Jill, you should forget
prejudice.
I am a totally normal.
Lord, how boring!
Darling, you should not talk...
That way... even in jest.
Seriously, Jill...
Vengard... doctor visit. He
Molly wonders McCleaps.
Both suffered from claustrophobia,
I could not even climb...
In an elevator.
Can you imagine...
What that means...
living in an attic?
Did Dr. Vengard the cured?
I suppose so.
I read the other day that he escaped
a very handsome elevator.
- Molly McCleaps?
- Yes.
- I'm Mrs. Baker.
- I know.
My name is Mrs. Colling. Sit.
Lady...
Baker.
- Is your first name?
- Jill.
Jill Baker.
685 Park Avenue.
- 685...
Park Avenue.
Does your age, Mrs. Baker?
22.
I'm your doctor, Mrs. Baker.
24.
Thank you.
Doctor, I want to be honest.
I am convinced
that nothing's wrong.
There will be a change of heart
when I get out of this consultation.
You see, people do not know anything
of itself. Nothing.
His true personality
is to them unknown.
What I intend is
introduce you to your inner self.
I want you to know.
- Would you like to know?
- No.
I'm a little shy.
Well, what happens?
Well, it is difficult to show
symptoms because...
Is something that comes and goes.
It comes and goes.
Yes. It is so absurd.
It's always the same thing
when I go to the doctor.
When I go, it goes.
And when I leave, come.
Mrs. Baker, that it is lo
that comes and goes...
You have it... quite concerned.
So dispense
all kinds of inhibition...
And see your inner self
and talk freely.
What is it you come and go?
Hiccups.
Does the hiccups?
Yes, when I get nervous
or irritated, I have hiccups.
It's pretty nasty
and sometimes very uncomfortable.
Naturally it is soon
to make a diagnosis...
But apparently...
gets the hiccups...
Nervous reaction... for some.
We will see what causes
that reaction.
- It seems reasonable.
- Good.
Do you want to follow me, please?
Aha. There is nothing to
of his childhood.
We will examine your current life.
The'll look through
a magnifying glass.
We will study every detail.
Mrs. Baker...
- Are you married?
- Yes.
When did you marry? At 19 years.
How old Ileva married?
- 6.
- With the same husband?
- Yes.
- Aha.
- Doctor, believe me...
I have no problems...
in my marriage.
Across Park Avenue not
find a couple...
- Happier.
- Sorry...
But it is my duty... explore
all paths.
Included Park Avenue.
How old is your husband?
- 35.
Does your profession?
He is vice president...
Of an insurance company,
but do you want to leave...
My marriage alone?
All right, calm down.
Talk about something else.
Do you have headaches?
No. Do you have a good appetite?
Yes.
How is your sleeping?
Not so good.
What about your husband, what about sleep?
Very good.
Well, think
one of those nights...
In which... has been unveiled.
When he looks to his right,
What do you see?
My dresser.
And when you look to your left?
To my husband.
- Sleeping?
- Yes.
Do you mean undo my marriage?
No.
Soio wake her husband.
Thanks, that's all for today.
Doctor, my husband is
nothing to do with my insomnia.
I am extremely sensitive
to noise.
The slightest noise.
Does your husband snores?
No. But I have to admit
breathe a little stronger.
Do not tell me?
I believe I can object...
Nothing to that.
The poor have to breathe.
I guess so. Well, Mrs. Baker...
Ease... her husband sleeping...
Is a challenge for you.
It's a bit like...
Well, have you ever
has followed a regime?
Yes, once, of vegetables.
What would have been...
If someone had eaten
beside a huge steak?
- How chips?
- Yes.
That was my husband.
And was not nervous?
No.
But now that lo mentioned,
itself was a bit irritating.
And little considered.
Certainly.
Husbands want their
Women hold the line...
But instead...
I would say it is a...
Total lack of cooperation.
Indeed.
- Jill, dear.
- Hi, Margie.
I have not heard from you.
- How are you?
- Very good.
- Did you see him?
- Margie...
You should not send me to see
Dr. Vengard.
Have you gone back?
No, I will not.
It will not destroy my marriage.
Between Larry and I...
There is no problem.
So I told myself.
Anybody? Talked about us?
Do not dare...
In my presence. Know
you and I are friends...
And that I defend. I know, dear.
Defend?? Against what?
Come on...
Tommy & Country will...
proclaimed the happy couple.
That always arouses envy.
Many friends...
Have been married...
for 6 years.
Why are we going to name
the happy couple?
And why not? You form
a happy couple, right?
Margie, lo've been fatal
últimas two weeks.
I'm obsessed with my marriage.
Watch what you look,
Io think think...
Just relating it...
with my marriage.
I hate the doctor Vengard!
However, I must confess that...
What, dear?
If you look at your husband...
With a magnifying glass
is inevitable...
You find... defective.
Yes, of course.
You see things that never...
You would have noticed. What?
Well, I will put a case
Io to understand.
The other morning...
You know that I have trouble lo
sleep? Well...
When I was lucky...
of poderme sleep...
Sound... what woke me up
at 8:15 o'clock?
- A gargle.
- A gargle?
The gargle reveille is...
And snoring...
the touch of endorsement.
And during the day?
At 9:00 in the morning...
My life is going.
Dear, is a truth as a temple.
Io I do not know to be true.
I made a mess.
I do not know what to think.
I had always heard
the perfect marriage...
Should have some mystery.
That your husband should continue
still a bit unknown.
Someone have relationships...
Every day... want to renew.
Do you understand me?
Yes, dear.
Hello.
- Hi, Margie.
- Hello, Larry.
- Hi, honey.
- Hello.
How are you? Very good. Do you?
Right. Did you have a good day?
- Very good. Do you?
- Well.
- What's New?
- No, do you?
- No.
- Well, so far.
What do you think?
Well, there was nothing new
and frankly admitted lo.
- Jill!
- Yes, dear?
Do they come to dinner the Cooper?
Do not know yet, honey.
Io tell you about Ilamen.
We appreciate lo
because if they come, I'll shave.
Okay, I lo...
I do not want to take
fuel to the fire...
But we are dealing...
some very specific facts.
If they come to dinner the Cooper,
that huge and ugly...
Mrs. Cooper ..., shaves.
And if only dinner with his wife,
not shaved.
And who should shave
is Mrs. Cooper.
I spent three hours
in the beauty salon...
Deserve... and not to shave.
Darling, a problem...
Affecting...
95 percent of all marriages...
Is that husbands...
do not shave.
Do not they realize that the beard
is growing at 8:00?
Hi, honey.
- Larry.
- Yes, dear?
He's back.
Great. Have you enjoyed it?
- Who?
- Evans.
That reminds me promised
Call me as soon as I returned.
The company Continental will
will be offering other insurance.
Evans still in Bermuda.
What it has become is the hiccups.
Hiccups??
Ah!
Hast thou a joke, eh?
You were very funny.
Keeks!
Larry...
Ilegado... when you,
you asked...
If there was any news.
Course there is a new...
And something...
quite important.
Do you know who is coming
next Thursday?
The President
Universal Mattress...
President of Furniture...
United and other senior...
Of the two companies.
What a drag.
I know it will be A boring...
Mattresses... but Universal
Furniture and United...
Have merged.
Almost all insurance...
Will be redone.
The man will have
Kafka is convincing...
Mattress... Universal.
But I have thoroughly researched.
Is Hungarian.
In fact, they are all Hungarians.
So...
So let's give dinner
a hint Hungarian, huh?
Look, Larry... Listen, honey...
Do not pretend that you... view
as a gypsy, but...
We will look...
a cook Hungarian...
That will prepare...
a wonderful "goulash".
A Kafka will love.
I will get those insurance
if I have to fill...
That Hungarian... like
one of their own mattresses.
And to make you feel at home...
Relations chief...
Io public warned me...
Right before dinner I must say:
"E dese, and des Egue senguere.
Eguec senguere ".
It means health, or something.
"Eguec Seguera".
It is only a detail,
but I like it.
Success in business
is 50 percent hard work...
And 50 a cigar.
"Eguec Seguera".
Formidable, honey! Excellent!
But a little more lively.
Look, you see.
"Eguec Seguera!"
Ah, I see. "Eguec Seguera!"
- Yes, it is.
Fantastic, honey. Yes.
Keeks!
Larry...
- Why do that?
- What?
"Keeks".
Well...
- I do it... always.
- Why?
The truth, I know.
But when you do, you
What does it mean?
Is there a hidden agenda?
I do not know, never have tried lo.
But I lo do to me.
You are my wife.
And that gives you the right...
Nonsense to me...
every time you crave.
Honey, are you okay? Very good.
Larry, please
do not make me more "Keeks".
And that way, the "Keeks"...
Disappeared... of a couple more.
It was not the dog, I did it.
Good afternoon.
Good afternoon, Mrs. Baker.
Dr. Vengard
will be delayed a bit.
I hope you do not mind.
Fea. Fea.
Is not that ugly?
Who?
People.
Is there anything uglier
that a human face?
Would you mind if I smoke?
Not at all.
Do you smoke?
Yes.
Do you have a cigarette?
Do not have no filter?
Sorry, but no.
Do not want it.
I went.
I changed my mind, lo accept.
Thank you.
Have you already visited this doctor?
Yes.
What do you charge?
Not really I know.
Io not have asked.
Do not worry, eh?
The doctor just called.
Io take at least half hour.
Half an hour more?
We have two possibilities:
We read magazines
or we can chat.
A beautiful day, is not it? Yes.
My conversation has run out.
Forget it.
Does the bored?
No, all lo otherwise.
I must warn I say what I think.
I am completely individualistic.
- Really?
- I'm against...
Communism ..., capitalism...
Fascism, Nazism.
I am against all...
And worldwide.
I hate my fellow
and they hate me.
I find it very funny.
So you amused?
I think a clown, huh?
No, I did not say that.
Anyway, do not apologize.
Is that Vengard is good doctor?
I'm sure that will do much good.
Why say that? What do I get?
I am directed to say.
I'm not a psychoanalyst.
How about you what happens?
Nothing.
Why are you here?
No visit to a psychoanalyst
to fix their teeth.
What is wrong?
- Better read magazines.
- Agreed.
I went.
Sorry to bother you again,
but...
What to do to be happy?
I think Dr. Vengard
know more about that than me.
Need more than you, Mrs. Baker?
Oh, that article.
You know, Mrs. Baker...
That is the first time
I've met...
A person... really happy?
It seems irritating.
No, arouses my curiosity.
I have often thought
to be happy...
24 hours a day
must be wonderful.
You get used.
In the morning we wake
the song of a small bird.
Before breakfast, you
and Mr. Baker dance a minute.
Then Breakfast begins happy.
You are happy,
Mr. Baker is happy...
The bird is happy,
Io everything around him is happy.
Listen, my presence
seems to upset him...
So... I'll leave.
No, I'm sorry, Mrs. Baker.
If lo is going to take so
I who must leave.
No, I'm afraid the doctor
lack makes it to you.
Are you sure, Mrs. Baker?
It is an interesting question.
The two are here
for the same reason...
Happiness.
You do not have enough,
and the other has too.
Who makes more missing
the doctor?
Interesting, do not you think?
Fascinating...
But I will not discuss it.
Yes, I understand, Mrs. Baker.
Nice to have known her.
And sorry if I have offended.
- Goodbye, Mrs. Baker.
- Goodbye.
I went.
- One moment.
- Yes?
I can ask you a question??
Of course.
Say.
Why do you dislike that picture?
- You really want to know?
- Yes.
Sit.
The artist has been able
see in that tree...
Rather than the camera
who photographed the happy...
Mrs. Baker ..., Surface only.
Art is deeper.
If I were a painter,
and do a portrait...
I do not know what aspect...
would the picture...
But it would seem...
to that photograph.
Does it make sense what I'm saying?
Yes.
Much sense.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
- Be.
- Hello, Sebastian.
Hello.
By the way, My name is Sebastian.
Alexander Sebastian.
Would you say something my name?
Be honest.
Well, since you insist, no.
No matter.
Why would know?
Let's see the pictures.
Number? 15?
It Child with trumpet?
It's bad.
I feared that he liked.
Yet artist found himself.
And when you are where is he?
It Child with trumpet?
The child is not bad,
but failed...
Completely... with the trumpet.
Certainly.
- This is horrible.
- I agree.
I went!
It's almost a masterpiece.
- Io Who painted it?
- A woman.
No man have dared.
The 26.
Ellionord Strap.
Portrait of Alexander Sebastian.
I can not deny it, I am.
That woman I painted,
I did an autopsy, he saw me.
Frankly, I think a puzzle.
A puzzle? That is, either.
I was for her a puzzle...
Io... but it was not for me.
And here's your revenge.
When I saw him for the first time,
I was angry a lot.
I'm not surprised.
What are these notes?
I'm a musician, pianist.
Oh, pianist!
And this pedestal?
Well, that...
Indicates... greatness.
Why not put a bust you over?
Is there any reason?
Any.
See that little line?
Cua?? Is this?
There's my problem.
That line sent me Dr. Vengard.
Although I am inhibited...
Honorísticamente...
Let's have a drink.
One moment, one moment.
- And this watch?
- Is the clock?
Yes.
I should not be in the picture.
Why?
You see, its...
It is a personal matter.
Do you regret coming here?
No, no, quite the contrary.
I find it fascinating.
It's a new world...
Io... but not entirely understand.
If you want to know something
about me, ask.
That clock strikes 12:15.
Is this a detail...
Minor...
or does it mean something?
It means something.
But enough about me.
Talk about something else, huh?
When will their next concert?
When?
When you can overcome it.
Overcome what?
That little break.
- Concerns inhibition.
- Yes.
You see, when I play... Tell me.
Are the 12:15 pm?
Of the night.
Alguna particular night?
Returning to my inhibitions...
When I... a private concert...
Sorry, Alexander,
Can you tell me more?
It was very hot.
Was in the summer?
Yes.
When I play
for a single person...
For the right person...
I'll be completely honest ...,
I believe there...
Best pianist in the world.
But in a concert hall,
before an audience, no.
Something is lost.
Those faces staring at me.
What right do they look at me?
What right do I hear
for paying $ 2?
Sometimes, two and a half.
Why are you bored with this?
No, please continue.
It's fascinating.
Are you a puzzle,
Mr. Alexander Sebastian.
Do not try to fit all
parts, Mrs. Merry Baker.
Come on.
The 685 Park Avenue
goulash smelled...
Mattresses Universal... when
Furniture and United...
Were about to invade
the home of the Baker.
Mrs. Kafka.
Mr. Jaujeff.
Mrs. Geverelsie.
- Mr. Jones.
- Jones?
Normal is the only name
I've heard so far.
It is the attorney for Mr. Baker.
I guess it will take
an attorney with many Hungarians.
Good evening, sir. Good evening.
How's the goulash?
Very well, Mr. Baker.
He has gotten a package? For me?
No, sir.
- Hi, honey.
- Hello.
- Alguna? Novelty?
- No.
Did you have a good day?
Wonderful.
Are you ready for the big party?
Ready.
Remember the word?
"Eguec Seguera".
"Eguec Seguera", that is. Right.
What is it?
Your package had Ilegado, sir.
Albert lo I had said.
Thank you.
I went.
I'm Mr. Baker.
I can ask? What do you do here?
- Waiting.
- Ah, waiting.
Tell me, when are we going to dinner?
Dinner??
I was invited to dinner.
Sorry.
Tell me, are you a Mattress
Furniture Universal or United?
I'm not anything.
Played with two decks, huh?
Well, is a smart move.
Tell me, How about Mr. Kafka?
I am indifferent.
Certainly not you very explicit.
The merger has seemed
a great success, and I lo.
The merger creates the union.
Hey, want to enjoy
tonight, right?
Yes, of course.
All right, come on.
This carafe disgusts me.
It's ugly. Let's keep.
Sure, whatever.
The customer is always right.
Would change something else?
Many.
I think we will go
an enjoyable evening.
I'll tell you a secret.
We "goulash".
? "Goulash"?
- Yes, "goulash".
For me, scrambled eggs.
It was only a suggestion.
Discúlpeme,
I have to finish this.
Go ahead, make yourself at home.
These Hungarians are
members were very rare.
Ilegado Have you already?
One other.
Did we smoking, no?
Why lo questions?
He does not Ileva.
Do you mean Mr. Sebastian?
Sebas??
- Who are you?
- Who?
It is against all.
It is an individualist.
So rich is?
Money does not care...
At all.
How do you know?
Honey, I is Sebastian,
Alexander Sebastian.
I told you about the other day,
but as...
Never listen... Io I say.
Absolutely nothing.
Io Now remember,
the guy who plays the piano.
Not the guy who plays the piano,
is a pianist.
And soon will very important.
And you'll be very happy
to ensure your hands...
At $ 100,000. Look, honey...
I give this dinner especially...
for those Hungarians.
Would you be interested in a policy?
Do not even know, or care.
Sometimes I just do not understand you.
Tonight we
the ability to close...
Treatment... $ 500,000.
I have not bothered to prepare
Hungarian overnight...
For president...
Universal Mattress...
And you invite...
a guy who plays the piano.
How did you come?
Musicians and mattresses
are bad partner.
Larry, for 6 years
only insurance have spoken.
And I'm sick of policies!
Is it too much to ask you to let me
spend a night in the company...
Rimsky Korsakov...
and Stravinsky?
Rimsky Korsakov?? Stravinsky??
Who else did you invite?
Why do not you invite
the entire philharmonic?
You could have brought Dim Sailor
as a presenter.
All right, all right. Forget it.
If you do not want to touch,
not touch.
Does touching?
Yes, not a bad idea.
Maybe I could liven up the party.
If Mr. Sebastian consents
in touch, which I doubt...
If consented,
not going to be Hungarian folklore.
What will then play?
Something you'd have to pay...
$ 2 and a half... to listen.
Does Carnegy Music Hall?
Exactly.
In my house, no. Not tonight.
What's this?
Is a reproduction
I saw a picture...
In an art gallery.
- Do you like it?
- I love it.
Tell me, what is it?
Do not lo see?
No more jokes, what is?
It is a portrait.
A picture? What?
From a man.
I know that I am a
ignorant insurance agent...
I know nothing... on Stravinsky.
But six years married Ilevamos
and I think I've been...
Pretty good... a husband.
When you ask something,
must answer...
As God intended. You have
why make fun of me.
You know what this is?
The Grand Canyon!
It's delicious.
Sit here, Mrs. Kafka. Thank you.
And so we are the best
company for you.
It's possible.
We'll talk after dinner.
Certainly. Sit here, Mr. Kafka.
Right.
Mrs. Baker.
Thank you, Mr. Kafka.
Not even Loend Green?
Above all, Loend Green.
There is not a work of Wagner,
except a passage from Tristan...
It's really beautiful,
because they never played well.
Touch lo Got any day?
You for me?
Maybe.
I do not like strawberries.
Sorry.
"Eguec Seguera".
Is everything all right, sir Kafka?
Very good.
"Eguec Seguera".
How I appreciate that,
Mrs. Baker.
I was excited this detail.
Now that's hospitality,
Mr. Baker.
I was surprised.
Where lo have learned?
- What does it mean?
- Health.
And lo has spoken perfectly.
"Eguec Seguera"!
How do you speak Hungarian?
Were you born in Hungary?
No, studied music in Budapest.
Budapest?
Oh, Budapest.
He lived in...
How was the name that street?
Andorussia.
I just got a call. Kafka eat...
With the agent of the Hudson
morning.
Tonight or Never.
What about the legal details?
In my office
are drafting contracts.
Right.
Did you like the goulash,
Mr. Kafka?
An excellent goulash. Excellent.
If your insurance equal lo,
maybe we sign with you.
Glad him think so.
I'll explain the details.
Yalosin, Labislav, come.
I want you to listen
the proposal of Mr. Baker.
Gentlemen, I will be very brief.
Please...
I have something special...
for you.
Mr. Sebastian has had the
kindly touch access...
For us. So if you want to sit.
Is it essential to play?
Do not worry.
Mrs. Baker.
Yes, Mr. Sebastian?
Would you mind sitting
anywhere else?
- No.
- Thank you.
- Sit down, please.
Is closed.
How strange!
The wrench should be here.
Someone closed the piano.
Where is the key?
No I know. Why would anyone
to close the piano?
- Sure.
- Is absurd.
I do not understand
why has closed.
Where is?
As I said, Mr. Kafka,
My proposal will cover...
Needs... and...
- I've broken.
- Do not worry.
Of course not.
Well, Mr. Sebastian...
Tell us, what is going to play?
Well first I will interpret...
Mrs. Baker. Yes, Mr. Sebastian?
Right.
Well, start with "The Pathetique"
Beethoven.
It has 3 times.
And then, if I'm in the mood...
Variations will touch... Hob...
Based on the second theme
the first time.
I will continue with my own variation,
based...
Changes... in Hob, based...
The second issue...
the first time.
How long does a sonata?
The only one I've heard
lasted 3 pure.
It's a catastrophe, a disaster.
We are lost.
Alexander, enough!
Please do not.
No, no, no.
That clause of the contract has
saved my bacon, admit it.
And now...
Wait I'll have some fun.
Good morning. Good morning, sir.
That picture in the window...
It's great, is not it?
No kidding, what is?
It is the portrait of a man.
Of course, obvious.
Excuse me, sir...
But not everyone
understand modern art.
Well, thank you.
If you are interested, only costs...
$ 500.
- $ 500?
It's an important man. No, sir.
Not valued by the model.
He is a musician...
Second rate.
Musician? What kind of musician?
Pianist, I think.
Could it be Alexander Sebastian?
Indeed. He has acknowledged.
So a friend of yours.
Would not it be fun to have you
at home...
Permanently?
Not very fun.
It's a phony.
Who?
IE.
Goodbye, Jones.
- Hi, honey.
- Hello.
Do not you think
a nice surprise?
Yes, great.
The Farm Alegre.
I do not notice any joy.
Not deny
the joy of learning music.
No.
Alguna? Novelty?
This, do you not enough?
I think spare.
Did you have a good day?
Nice.
It seems that you're feeling better.
Yes
I slept 10 hours straight.
And the hiccups is gone
completely.
Is not it good news?
Yes, of course.
Still visiting Dr. Vengard?
No, I do not need Dr. Vengard.
I'm so busy
with music and visits...
To art galleries
I have no time for anything.
It's wonderful.
Do you know?
I begin to glimpse something there.
Yes, it begins to take shape
of man.
Why do you say that?
You the other night...
It was a joke. I was teasing.
How will that be a man?
I was nervous about the dinner...
And said first lo... I came.
I'm sorry, honey.
No, I disagree. I think a man.
Do not be stubborn,
I say it was a joke.
So what is it?
That's a meadow.
It's called Spring Meadow.
- In spring.
- Yes.
And those musical notes
do they mean?
That is the pastor
playing his flute.
The shepherds play the flute,
Right?
Yes, yes.
And that clock that 12:15?
I do not know the exact meaning...
But I guess it is... lunch.
The pastor lunch
and then plays the flute.
By God! You talk as if never
had been in a meadow.
You see, in modern art
try to break the ways...
Conventional... represent
otherwise things...
Through the suggestion.
What are you doing?
Whiskers painting her pastor.
In this pianist
I'll give you a beating.
You could not do a worse thing.
She would get pitied him.
Io not become a martyr.
Look at it from the point
of view of a woman.
Wait a minute.
Miss Egans,
Do you want to go, please?
Miss Egans, we want to know
their views on...
Certain situation.
Well, Mr. Baker have a friend...
And is in trouble.
Who? Is Mr. Baker?
- No, the friend.
- Ah, Mr. Baker.
Mr. Baker has nothing to do.
Let's imagine that friend
Mr. Brown's his name.
Well, Mr. Brown has a wife.
- Mrs. Brown.
- Exactly.
Messrs. Brown
Use bull married...
- How long?
- Say, about 6 years.
- Right.
- Live in Accoard.
? Accoard ages 6? How boring.
Let's just say living
in New York.
Mr. Brown is concerned
by marriage.
Things are not
as well as before.
What kind of man
is this Mr. Brown?
A beautiful person.
Did not you say that?
Yes, beautiful.
Is it attractive?
Very attractive.
- Did not you say that?
- Yes.
Yet she complains.
Rather, it goes away.
Yes, and I want things
again be as before.
- Who does not?
- Sure.
Well, Miss Egans, as a woman...
Want to tell us...
Cua would be the correct method.
I would say a coat
Io mink fix everything.
Already have mink coat.
So what's complaining?
Thank you, Miss Egans.
Nothing more.
You wanted the point
of view of a woman.
Wait, wait.
Mrs. Brown is interested
another man.
- And I know Mr. Brown?
- Yes.
- Do you have proof?
- Too.
- Do you have witnesses?
- No.
So is lost.
Thank you, Miss Egans.
Sorry, Mr. Baker,
but if there are no witnesses...
Io... she will deny.
It's what any woman would do.
Miss Egans, we are satisfied.
I guess I'm the right person...
To offer advice,
because they feel too...
Sympathy... Mr. Brown,
and lose patience...
With Mrs. Brown.
We cases like that daily.
She is bored, marriage...
Has become... a habit...
Agree... but all things
that her husband provides.
The home should miss.
Do they look somewhat dated?
The will to power, Miss Egans.
Anyway, I think that Mr. Brown
is a great guy.
I always thought lo.
- What a woman.
- Yes.
But he has some ideas
interesting.
I have not noticed.
Larry, still in love
your wife, right?
- Yes.
- Where will you go when...
Out of here ...?
I have a business dinner
to Mr. Higgins in his club.
But how am I to sell insurance
with this concern?
Larry, listen, Higgins forget.
Forget insurance, go home.
There's only one thing
you have to sell...
And yourself.
The most important customer...
You've had in your life awaits.
It's called Mrs. Baker.
You are the best seller
the world.
There is no marriage
that can not be fixed...
But it needs...
selling it occasionally.
- It is not easy.
- Was it easy...
Do insurance...
Iluvias against torrential...
In southern California?
It employs a new tactic. Test.
Save My Marriage
with a new tactic.
Yes, I have said.
Yes, not a bad idea.
But Cua may be this new tactic?
Cua? Can be? Cua??
I'll find that tactic.
A surprise, huh?
Hello, my genius!
Who will you be this afternoon?
Come on, tell your little.
Will you be Mozart,
playful and tender?
Or will you be the turbulent
Beethoven...
Strong, relentless and fierce?
Come on, honey,
Tell your toddler...
Guess who's here.
The god of gods lowering the...
Is it serious? No, only fainted.
Women always are faint.
Got any particular reason??
No, no.
He thought I was a genius.
Io was discovered that no
and fainted.
Please, are you
at home, be right back.
I'll get something.
Look, Baker, clarify one thing.
You will see a discussion
very hot.
We're going to insult,
can not be avoided.
You will accuse me of something
I deny having made...
And I will believe.
So, before the battle...
I want to make one thing clear.
I will not quarrel.
My hands have provided...
My only sustenance...
and I will not hit you.
Please, love, wake your child.
- What happened?
- Well, I...
You!
Funny. You know I thought lo?
No, but I think I...
Hello?
Hello, Jones. You were right.
We had to use a new tactic...
And I think I found it.
I do not trust you.
Come on, I invite you to a cigar.
Or do you have ulterior motives
or got something in that pure.
No, no, it's one of the cigars
that gift to my clients.
How old are you, Sebastian?
Less than you.
In the prime of life, huh?
Do you have good health?
Improve a lot...
When you have eaten,
but I will not quarrel.
No, no. I do not want a fight.
But not all husbands
share a respect...
I feel for the music.
What would happen?
Come on, Sebastian.
I'll do anything for you,
like it or not.
We'll make sure your hands.
This gives you complete freedom
Action...
And I will win.
The two will have won.
I will not quarrel.
No, lo know, I know.
He likes to be isolated.
Insulate there.
Do you know?
Best of all this is that...
Sit.
Is that the insurance will
Hand...
Is a clause...
of your life insurance.
Life you sure? What
I want a life insurance?
Do not you have any relatives?
Familiar? Well...
I know, heir name my wife.
So you can buy a beautiful
piano shaped brooch...
Diamond... instead of keys.
Every time you put lo
think of his poor Sebastian.
Believe me, it should be
life insurance.
And right now.
Very well.
Where were you born?
I will not quarrel.
Are you in love with my wife?
In love with his wife?
So he got the revólver.
Io Now I understand everything.
Come on, Baker, should give
shame behave well.
A crafty insurance agent
as you...
Both understood... psychology.
I'm surprised have thought that.
Naturally I think his wife
is very attractive...
And charming and I love music.
- Is that loaded?
- Yes.
Please Baker, forget that idea.
I'm not in love with his wife.
Well, it will be a day of joy
for musicians.
Imagine Beethoven
By calling Mozart.
"Hey, Mozart, Piano dusts.
Look who's illegal,
the little genius ".
- Not funny.
- This is not funny.
I love my wife, I wanted
during the six years...
Married... that Ilevamos.
Comes a guy like you
and lo destroys...
Simply because...
has nothing else to do.
No away with it.
If I wanted to really my wife...
If it had come...
to tell me that...
Io... maybe have accepted.
If we had believed that the two
she would be happier without me...
Would have just packed...
and not have to do this.
Do you know?
For a moment I was worried.
When he got the revólver,
I thought:
Here is a citizen conventional.
It would be foolish hide
the truth to a guy like that.
But now I see the real Baker...
Modern, liberated. Baker...
I'll be honest with you.
I'm in love with his wife.
Are you sure?
- Quite sure.
- No.
So you do not have to kill him?
Do not think it's necessary.
We are faced a very clear.
You are in love
my wife, and she to you.
Yes, you will. I've watched
with my own eyes.
Soio I have an alternative.
Hello?
Hello, Jones.
I continue with the tactic.
- Have I hit back?
- No.
I should not have done that.
I know and I'm sorry.
Should not have done.
It was a primitive reaction.
I assure
that will not happen again.
I will not quarrel.
Hello? I'm Laurence Baker.
Reserve me a room for tonight.
I'll be right. Thank you.
Baker...
Leaves you... really?
Of course, of course.
I think I should leave
the floor to her.
- Oh, really?
- Yes.
Fair enough. Do not you think?
Yes, I think that's what most indicated.
I'm glad you think so.
Do not want any bitterness
between us.
Fortunately I can offer
Jill security.
Taking care of your future.
And why not?
It deserves lo. Do not think so?
Yes, yes. I think so.
She has given me
the best years of your life.
I'll take a few memories
wonderful to me.
It's a great woman, right?
Yeah, yeah, great.
But it has its flaws.
Who does not?
That is true. Yes.
Sebastian...
If you ever find
in a bad mood...
What you have to do is...
No, no, I must not tell. No.
Come on, do not act
like a child.
What is it?
You see, it's personal.
Come on, what is it?
Well, if you ever
located in a bad mood...
And wants to cheer... soon...
There's only... one way.
Cua is??
You have to give "Keeks".
? "Keeks"?
- So what is it?
- This.
Keeks!
- And do you like?
- He loves.
Man, thank you. Keeks.
Keeks!
Oh, no, no!
Now, the reason for the divorce.
According to state law
New York...
Must have...
evidence of adultery.
Is not there some way
less violent?
- In New York no.
- Well, say...
- Adúltero... that's me.
- Oh, no.
I would not mess
in that commitment.
It's the same.
But why are you going to take...
- Your fault ...?
- Do not worry.
I'll manage.
- A detail from you.
- Thank you.
Soio we have
separation of property.
The agreement between Laurence Baker,
who we mean...
As part... of the first part...
Jill Baker... and who
we refer...
As part... of the second part.
It is understood that the
of the first part...
Leasehold writing...
the floor of Park Avenue...
The party... of the second part.
To the part of the second half. What about the furniture?
- Yes, and the furniture?
What about the furniture?
Yes, and the furniture?
I did not understand...
Yes, yes, I want everything...
Transitions to...
Part... of the second part.
Can we discuss this later?
It is better to fix...
Especially now. Io you deserve.
Well, I...
He intends serjusto only.
You are very generous.
No, just only.
Nothing more.
Well, if you want to stay
with something...
No, I do not need anything.
What good would it do?
- But Larry...
- Lives in a hotel.
Where lo would get?
I would have to pay a repository.
Sure.
Well, I have to correct this.
- What's his name that?
- Jones.
I do not trust IE.
Well, here we are.
Baker v. Baker.
Sounds awful, right?
It is a legal term.
Regarding tests of adultery...
Yes? Who are you going to look?
I do not know.
Have you thought about someone?
There are several candidates
I'm interested.
Go.
It's better that way. Liquidate
the matter in a few weeks.
Nice.
Hey, do not be Mary Logan?
Adultery with Mary Logan?
I hope to find something better.
When all is settled,
I will travel to South America.
Will one of my friends?
No, you know I never
I have fallen too well.
Anybody I know??
This is a divorce...
Not a guessing game.
Is that I have curiosity.
Do not worry, you can trust me.
You will not be ashamed.
It will be a very attractive girl.
Do you really want... divorce?
Of course.
Do not lo do you want?
Well...
Do not tell me not want to lo.
It would be a great disappointment.
Come on, you're in love
Sebastian.
Otherwise you would not have...
Well, you would not be here.
You're a great person.
You have not done this
only a whim.
I have always believed
you were sincere.
Always.
I would Ilevarme this recall.
I'm sorry I hurt you.
What could you do?
For my part there is no bitterness.
It's funny.
You've always been my husband...
And now, are the
of the first part.
I was your Jill...
And now refer to me as...
Well, everything is fixed.
What happened?
- What have you done?
- Nothing...
We were reviewing...
some details.
I do not trust you, Baker.
Dear, no worry.
This is a very clear.
Alexander, please.
I'm really nervous.
Do not you understand?
Sure, we all have moments
cranky.
Keeks!
We will re-read this.
The following agreement...
Has been signed...
It is useless if we do not...
Agree... adultery.
That's not your business.
- He's right.
- You Shut up!
Of course it's my business.
I'll turn...
A laughingstock... City
by a girl I do not know.
You will not have that opportunity.
Goodbye.
- Keeks!
- Do not do that, Baker.
Jill! Jill!
Jill!
And that, my dear Jones, is
protecting your original investment.
Let's have a drink.
I think he has weakened...
- Defenses.
- Weakened?
I was the broken.
Will come back and eat in my hand.
It's what I do
with Mrs. Jill Baker.
Henceforth known
and Jill "Blanda" Baker.
If you want to buy a piano
cheap, I offer mine.
- No.
- Too bad I will be.
I'll be the mad dog 685
of Park Avenue.
Baker Hail!
Lord Jones.
Yes, Mrs. Baker?
On the evidence of adultery,
What the law requires?
- Well, I have to...
- No, if I...
- The adúltera... out.
- Well...
It must find one
in his apartment with him...
And I have removed... jacket.
I understand.
- Alexander.
- Yes, Jill?
Are you going to take your jacket
for me?
Whatever you say, honey.
Oh, no! No, no!
Oh, yes.
Do you really want to do that?
Certainly. Do you think trick...
- That guy ...?
- Yes.
Forget, Baker, already
in love with this guy. Keeks!
Gross! Alexander, Alexander!
Alexander, small.
Small?
Is that what small llamas lo?
Get up, honey.
That's it.
Then you'll be better.
Sit here. That's it.
I have been married six years
with a brute, not lo knew!
Divorce is the only solution.
Very well. Why not go to Reno?
Yes, Reno.
I do not want to go West.
Oh, honey! How are you?
Trembling.
Could establish my residence
Pennsylvania?
What Pennsylvania?
That is near Philadelphia.
Yes, of course.
It would be nice.
It has a good orchestra.
It would be easy Ilegar to New York.
Okay, put Pennsylvania?
OK, Pennsylvania...
China, wherever,
but done with it.
Let's review Pennsylvania law.
Pennsylvania... What to see?
Small!
I will divorce even
Io last thing I do in life!
Article 10.
The innocent spouse may
getting a divorce...
If it proves...
the other spouse...
For its cruel...
and barbarians has done...
Life thoroughly... unbearable...
To the innocent spouse.
Looks promising.
You will find it easy to be barbaric.
Yes, my innocent spouse.
- What do I have to do?
- Well...
We gonna call a witness.
Let my secretary.
First, you must begin
a discussion.
- Pleasure.
- Then I would say...
You have to give... a slap.
Bofe give you a... No.
Can you hit a man,
but not a woman?
You're a coward.
- Okay, I will.
- Very good.
Let's try it all. Let's see...
This is the plan.
Miss Egans,
Do you want to go, please?
Then, Mr. Jones.
Now remember,
I will dictate a letter...
Clicks... and as
fingers, start to argue.
And when you say...
Insurance salesman...
Second class.
I give you... the slap.
That's it.
Baker, do not disappoint us.
- Miss Egans.
- Miss Egans!
Here I am, Mr. Jones.
Sit down, please.
Write.
A Walter K. Dovermill...
Savings Bank... Capital City...
Columbus, Ohio.
Dear Mr. Dovermill...
Let's see...
So you're not gonna tell me lo?
I was not there.
My mother saw you.
Your mother is a hysterical old.
How dare you say that
my dear mother?
Your dear mother, puff!
Do not lo I mean, eh?
I was not there.
But my mother saw you.
Your mother is a hysterical old.
How dare you say
that my dear mother?
Your dear mother, puff!
Who are you...
To say "puff ' my dear mother?"
Your mother... You know who
I remember your mother?
Enough, enough! One moment.
Miss Egans...
No... I told him to leave.
Yes, for the love of God...
- Miss... Egans.
- Sit.
Now he has written readme lo.
A Walter K. Dovermill...
Savings Bank... Capital City...
Columbus, Ohio.
Dear Mr. Dovermill...
So my mother you dislike?
No, your family upsets me!
Oh, really?
I dislike your father...
And your brother! And you know
who I remember your mother?
Who?
To you! That should give you an idea...
Io... I think of your mother!
Insurance salesman...
Second class ...!
Insurance salesman second class.
Come on.
Do not allow
insult him like that!
That's it!
Listen, all our happiness
is at stake.
A single slap. Take.
Take another brandy.
And now, to the load!
Léamelo again.
Walter K. Dovermill...
Savings Bank... Capital City...
Columbus, Ohio.
Dear Mr. Dovermill...
Dear sir...
Everything I have said
Io keep your mother...
But falls short.
Is that what you think?
Yes, so I think.
And I'm saying...
You're a seller
second-class insurance!
Oh!
So I'm a seller
second-class insurance.
That's what I said.
- Repeat.
- Insurance salesman...
Second class ...!
I went!
Come on, Baker, calm down.
You can do it.
Be a good person.
Léamelo again.
Walter K. Dovermill...
Savings Bank... Capital City...
Columbus, Ohio. Dear...
Dear Mr. Dovermill, yes.
Did you see, Miss Egans?
He has been slapped his wife.
Yes, lo has seen? Mrs. Baker...
'm... Sorry that this has happened
in my office.
- So do I.
- Imagine a man...
Who slaps his wife.
To do had getting drunk.
Goodbye, Mr. Jones.
Goodbye, Mrs. Baker.
What do I do
Walter K. Dovermill?
Say I am not.
Thank you, sir.
Pass!
Hello, Albert.
Good morning, sir.
I hope you forgive me...
For disturbing... on Sunday.
Never mind.
Did you sleep late, sir?
Yes, Ilevo several nights as well.
I'm not as young as I thought.
I think it has look great, sir.
Thank you, Albert.
How is everything?
Not too good, sir.
For plans that have
for your future...
Could fit me, sir?
Have you left the house?
Yes, sir. I was forced.
It was for that
musical gentleman.
All we said goodbye except Emma.
He has been able to resist
because he is deaf.
How is the lady?
So lovely as always, sir.
Happy, I guess.
I would not want to offend,
but I think it shows...
Great value.
- Hello.
Is Mrs. Baker?
- Jill, my dear!
- Margie!
I was thrilled when I Ilamaste.
And how could I not?
We are close friends. Sit.
How are you, Jill? Brilliantly.
I hear you're Philadelphia.
Have you met Alexander?
Yes, but did not want to bother.
Being tested his new gig.
I understand.
Do you mind?
No, no. I love music.
Yes, I'm going to Philadelphia.
And are you happy?
Oh, yes. A lot.
Although I am somewhat stunned.
Everything is so new to me.
Must be exciting.
Yes, exciting.
Moving the world business...
The art world... surrounded
Bach, Tchaikovsky...
Is rehearsing a play Bach.
Oh, yes.
Are you sure you're okay?
No, no, no, I love it.
Do not be hesitate, not all
Everyone likes Bach.
So if you want to stop...
By God, what an idea.
Everything seems so romantic.
Yes, very romantic.
By the way, have you seen Larry?
Yeah, yeah.
I saw him last night at the Monte Carlo.
- Larry in Monte Carlo??
- Yes.
What things.
One moment.
- Sorry, Margie.
- No matter.
Well, what we said?
So my music
not to your liking, eh?
Alexander...
It seems that there is more...
A noise... annoying. Very well.
I went!
- It's so original.
- Certainly.
I hope you do not mind.
Not at all.
I love when angry.
It becomes a wolf.
- It must be fascinating.
- Yes
Jill!
The wolf.
- What is it?
- Jill...
Today... no more music here.
Oh, no?
No. And do not try to persuade me,
and do not try to shut me up.
In fact today there will be no
more Sebastian.
There will be lunch, and
is unlikely to have dinner.
If you tomártelo well...
Io So take.
Jill, I can be a person
very difficult. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
What fun.
I hope that poor Larry
Io as well as I pass.
For when I saw him
in Montecarlo...
Oh, yeah, I guess it was
to another such...
Boring dinners.
All older people, right?
Soio a woman.
More or less your age.
- Attractive??
- No.
I do not seem lo. But
George and Freddy loved.
You know how George and Freddy.
But you do not mind.
Sure, I do not care.
Larry is entitled have fun.
If you like that life...
Hello?
Hi, Sally, dear.
I feel good though
Io's happened, do you?
That's it.
What?
Are you sure you leaving lo Ilevabas
the Montecarlo?
One moment.
Do you hear? Yes, it's here.
Right.
Goodbye.
Hello.
Are you going to take?
Jill, you should not come here.
It's a bit violent.
Well, as I walked past.
But if he knew Sebastian...
Do not worry about that.
I worry.
A woman who is getting married
soon...
Should visit... not a single,
and less without notice.
Well?
Am I intruding?
Jill, what you wanted to see me?
Is there anyone?
What do you, Jill?
I was passing by with the car...
With the car on the floor 31?
You said you wanted to have
a memory and...
Like going to tea Silvia and...
Had to go through here,
I picked up a few things.
Some pictures of us together.
I thought you would hope.
Thank you.
- Do not you watch the?
- Oh, yes.
The day we met.
Here you sit on my knee.
Our wedding. Our honeymoon.
Very nice, thank you.
Aigo? Else?
I heard you were
in the Monte Carlo.
- Yes, yes.
- Are you sleepy?
Yes.
- Well, da Silvia memories.
- Who?
You were going to have tea with Silvia,
Remember?
Yes, yes.
I really like this, Larry.
It's beautiful...
And welcoming. Yes, very cozy.
It is decorated tastefully.
It's nice.
So intimate. Beautiful curtains.
And divine views.
Yes, divine views.
Sorry.
What a fool I've been.
Please forgive me.
Larry, it's all my fault.
There is no evil
that blows no good.
Do not lo be kidding, right?
Of course I'm serious lo.
Larry, please do not make me
to go to Philadelphia.
Please.
The lady has changed mind.
He tires of her marriage
and leaves for good.
She do not care leave
ridiculed her husband...
Or hurt.
He tired of the piano music,
back and says:
Soio has been a small
whim of mine...
So... please
back to our sweet home.
You destroy our lives and believe
that you can reconstruct...
In one afternoon. No, no, no.
Not so easy.
I did not think it would be easy.
To tell you what I think
you need more than an afternoon.
What about dinner?
- Dining??
- Could cenarjuntos...
Tonight ...?
Sorry, I have a commitment.
- That girl.
- Yes
I do not like your tone. Sorry.
What do you want,
spoil on Sunday...
That poor girl ...?
Sally no vacation
every day, works hard.
- Work.
- What's wrong with that?
Nothing.
Do not serve everything on tray
like you.
No visit art galleries,
nor flirts...
Mediocre musicians ...,
or visit psychoanalysts.
She has no husband
to pay their complexes.
Sally is a great girl,
than your master Sebastian.
It does not get my shirts.
- What I right?
- Forget it.
You promised to love,
honor and obey.
The day we met.
In this picture I am horrible.
But you were great.
Do not be bored insurance speak.
Listening. You wanted to know everything
about me and my work.
- You wanted to help me.
- Larry.
Io remember everything you said.
I'd love to tell you again
if you let me.
Return to forget.
No, Larry, lo not forget.
Never again.
I can not keep pretending.
I am defeated.
Good.
Do not forget this tree in front
Hotel door.
And the Italian waiter so funny.
- It was here.
- Yeah, yeah.
No, it was here.
- Was here.
- Yes, it's true.
On the terrace.
- Our first breakfast.
- Yes
Larry, could not cenarjuntos?
- Not tonight.
- Why not?
Sally.
- Let me talk to her.
- No, no.
She is a woman. I understand.
No, no.
- Please Larry.
- Well.
No lo you deserve, but
I'll see what I can do.
- Thanks, honey.
- Do not move.
It will be very violent.
Sally Egans.
Egans.
That girl.
Keeks!
How are you, Miss Egans?
Hello, Mrs. Baker.
Nice to see you.
Mr. Baker would have
happy to attend to...
But very busy.
I asked him to give her purse.
Oh yeah, forgot lo.
I did some machine work
for Mr. Baker.
What machine a Saturday night?
Well, I also know shorthand.
Sure.
And came to take notes. Oh, yes.
Io I will another day, huh?
Goodbye, Miss Egans.
Goodbye, Mrs. Baker.
What a fool.
Impossible.
It's more complicated
Io I thought.
That girl is in love with me.
I adore.
I'm not surprised.
Says he can not live without me.
- And I believe her.
- Me too.
Is understandable.
You're a wonderful man.
- No.
- Yes, yes, lo are.
What's for dinner?
You know I can not.
And after dinner?
Want to be guilty a suicide?
No, no, no. Not that.
So I can not.
You're right, it is impossible.
It's a shame.
Everything could have been
marvelous.
Yes.
Nothing would have spoiled
our happiness.
- Yes, but it's too late.
- Yes.
This looks like the end.
Goodbye, Larry, and good luck.
Good Luck.
Try to convince her.
- Is Mrs. Baker?
- Yes, but...
Dismissed.
Guess who's back.
Am Bothan, the god
of the gods, who has returned.
Do not touch so strong, please.
I went!
And, he did not hiccup anymore.