Joseph M. Schenck Presents
"Buster" Keaton
in
The Haunted House [1921]
Written and directed by
"BUSTER" KEATON
and
EDDIE CLINE
Wall Street
The palatialparking place of
the Bull and the Bear ---
mostly the Bull.
New York is not the only
town that has its master
mind of finance.
The bank cashier and his
band of counterfeiters have
a strong reason for making
people believe this house is haunted.
"I'll show you waht would
happen if the police came."
The time lock doesn't open
till nine o'clock."
Although it's a small bank it
has a president and although
he is a small man he has a daughter.
"I wonder who put counterfeit
money in the bank --- I'll
ask the police."
GLUE
1st. NATIONAL BANK
BURGLAR PROOF
TIME LOCK
That night the Daredevil
Opera Company was executing
"Faust" --- and he deserved it.
SMOKING
After searching everywhere
else the police found him
where he was.
"That house is haunted."
"The little fellow from the
bank is upstairs."
Today
-BULLETIN-
KEATON  |  OUT
Today
-BULLETIN-
KEATON  |  IN
THE END
Written Subtitle by:
Jaffar AlBori