Timing & subtitles brought to you by Gone with the Shirt Team@Viki
♫ Extending across horizontally from a mysterious temple is a thousand mile sandstorm ♫
♫ Breaking through a thousand year of unchanging legend ♫
♫ One whistle and  ♫
♫ here comes Heaven's ambush. ♫
♫ One side being blood thirsty, one side getting through one's trials ♫
♫ Wearing out one's obsession step by step, how do you explain that? ♫
♫ Empty and false life torrentially flows by;  ♫
♫ Thoughts whistling and pattering ♫
♫ Jianghu deals with sharpness by pointing one's sword scabbard ♫
♫ Destiny follows laugh;  ♫
♫ Heaven and earth attracts arrogance ♫
♫ Who says that one's reluctance to leave this world is not torture? When will gratitude and grudges end? ♫
♫ It's hard to predict a human heart; the soul is chasing daybreak ♫
♫ It's hard to predict what will happen in one's life; the soul disturbs today's morning ♫
The Legend of Chusen
Episode 8
Senior Sister! This is the green bean cake I made. I made it personally for you. Eat it!
Zhang Xiao Fan, what are you doing outside the girls' dorm?
I...I...was looking for my senior sister.
She went out for something.
Hey!
Senior Sister Lu. Can you...do me a favor?
No.
Your Senior Sister left with Senior Brother Qi Hao to have their morning training already.
Senior Sister. This food..please give it to her.
Junior Brother Zhang. Don't you have to prepare for the martial arts competition?
Are you so idle or you think that because you drew a that stick, you can be lucky throughout the competition?
Everyone is doing their best, and what are you doing? You're still doing these pointless things.
I'm sorry, Senior Sister.
Senior Brother Qi! You can just call me Ling Er from now on.
Are you so idle
Or do you feel like one picked spot can bring you luck the whole way?
It's okay. Just treat it as getting experience this time.
What can you do?
You can't do martial arts. You can't do anything right!
In the future, what are you preparing to do?
-Zhang Xiao Fan-Chu Yu Hong
Senior Brother. Who is this Chu Yu Hong?
He's from Chang Yang Palace. I'm not sure if he's skilled though.
Don't worry. Just try your best when you get up there.
Senior Brothers, Senior Brothers! Let's make a bet.
Let's see how likely Xiao Fan is to win this round!
-Good idea! I bet that Xiao Fan loses!-Okay!-I bet on the opposite!
-Okay!-What are you guys doing?
Xiao Fan is about to compete and you're here making him waver!
Eldest Senior Brother, don't get angry! I was just joking!
You were joking? Okay then!
Since we're already betting, how about I place a bet too?
Senior Brother Song, you-!
You're doing this seriously? I'm going to tell Teacher!
Eldest Senior Brother, you must not tell Teacher!
Xiao Fan, I was just joking! You won't mind, right?
I won't.
Xiao Fan, I heard you came looking for me this morning!
I-I didn't.
You didn't?
-Ling Er, let's go.-Okay, I'm coming!
Xiao Fan, I still have to compete today, so I can't watch you! I'll be leaving!
I'm coming!
I'm leaving too. Xiao Fan, work hard!
Junior Brother, Teacher and Mistress don't want to put pressure on you. Just fight a bit.
Winning or losing is not important.
Okay.
Work hard Xiao Fan!
Xiao Fan, I'll say it again. Just do your best.
I'm leaving.
Is Da Zhu Palace out of people? There isn't even a single spectator!
That's right! There isn't even a single person here, are they afraid of losing?
-How shameful!-Come down, come down!
How shameful! Hurry and come down!
-It's Senior Brother Chu!-Senior Brother Chu!
Junior Brother Zhang.
What is that? A fire torch?
A fire torch? A fire torch!
Someone from Da Zhu Palace used a dice yesterday too!
Why are the weapons from Da Zhu Palace so exotic?
Make your move, Junior Brother Zhang.
Senior Brother, who do you think will win this round?
It's hard to tell.
Good! Good!
Junior Brother. Are you okay?
I'm okay. Senior Brother, please put all your energy into it. Don't be merciful.
I think I'd best-
-Are you looking down on me?-No.
Very well then. I'll give it my all. You must be careful.
Mother!
Senior Brother Chu!
Da Zhu Palace's Zhang Xiao Fan wins!
What? He must have cheated!
He must have cheated!
He cheated! That isn't Qing Yun's martial arts!
What kind of demon magic is that?
It's demon magic! He cheated!
What kind of demon magic did he use?
Don't blame him!
I'm the one who got complacent.
Enough! If you aren't happy with anything, talk to the sect leader!
What is that demonic object you hold?
It's my treasure. It's not a demonic object!
Good! Good! Good!
Xue Qi, well fought! You're so amazing!
Senior Sister Lu! Senior Sister Lu!
-You're so amazing, Senior Sister Lu!-Good, good!
My apologies.
Good! Good!
Xue Qi is so amazing!
Xue Qi! Xue-! Did she finish yet?
My Xue Qi!
Why am I so unlucky? I just finished a fight!
You won too, and Xue Qi-
Xiao Fan, what's up with your face?
Zheng Shu Shu!
Let's talk later!
It's okay.
Did your father go look for Senior Master Sect Leader?
He looked for Junior Master Cang Song, he said he'd deal with it.
That thief was so familiar with the treasure trove.
Could he be someone like Boss Nian who's been here for a long time?
It indeed can be some remaining disciples of Lie Xie Sect.
But he can break through the enchantment my father set.
That means he has a very high level of cultivation!
We have to hurry and capture this thief.
The fewer who know about this, the better.
It shouldn't be publicized and we still haven't any clues yet.
Then, do your father and Junior Master Cang Song have a plan?
They're currently monitoring the martial arts competition. They can't clone themselves!
That person didn't get what he wanted last night.
Do you think he'll come again tonight?
If he must have the Nine Rites Cauldron,
then he will definitely come again tonight.
Then let's wait for him tonight!
Go with the flow?
Timing & subitles brought to you by Gone with the Shirt Team@Viki
Senior Brother Song.
-Junior Brother Lin.-Junior Brother Lin.
Where is Xiao Fan?
I don't know either. I haven't seen him since the competition this afternoon.
You didn't watch him compete?
We went to go support Junior Sister.
That's right. How was Xiao Fan's fight?
Xiao Fan is still a disciple of Da Zhu Palace!
Is Junior Master Tian not going to ask about it at all?
Enough, enough! Don't talk about that.
Our Second Senior Brother just lost. Look over there.
I say, Old Second! How can you lose like that?
What did I say to you?
If my teacher hears your words, he'll definitely get angry again!
I heard that Xiao Fan triumphed at his competition today.
Xiao Fan triumphed?
Xiao Fan won? Xiao Fan won!
Xiao Fan he-! My money! My money!
What?
I bet that Xiao Fan would lose-!
Quiet! Hurry and tell Teacher!
Senior Sister, you can be frank.
You're full of tyrannical aura.
At the martial arts competition, I'm afraid you'll be in danger.
If you go on like this,
to put it simple, watch yourself.
Xue Qi! Xiao Fan!
Xue Qi!
This is my Heaven and Earth One Breath Bag.
It's especially designed to hold different kinds of medicines and the seal is inherited in our family.
-Hurry and switch it out.-Okay!
I can only maintain it for a moment. You must switch out the cauldron!
Put it into the One Breath Bag.
Hurry up, I can't keep it up!
Thankfully I didn't use my hands last time!
Let's find a place to hide it.
Come on!
Shu Shu, are you okay?
My hand! Don't bother with me, hurry after him!
Wait. I'll draw you a seal talisman of the One Breath Bag.
Hurry and go after him!
Zhang Xiao Fan, you only know how to cause trouble!
Lu Xue Qi. You are your teacher's talented student. You are usually quite obedient.
Why did you go create trouble with these two?
Junior Master, this was my and Zheng Shu Shu's idea.
-It has--Your idea? You only know how to ruin the plan early!
Teacher, please investigate it well.
That black-clothed man was really wild and bold. He even dared to target the Nine Rites Cauldron?!
I was already alerted when someone sneaked into the treasure trove last time.
Your Junior Master Zheng and I just added another enchantment.
When someone touches it, we will be notified.
And then I could use it to find that thief!
But you all had to act smart!
Do you think we have all gone foolish from old age?
Okay. Hurry and put the Nine Rites Cauldron back in the treasure trove.
Don't interfere in this matter anymore.
Yes.
Hurry and go!
-Yes, Junior Master.-Yes.
How was it? Did you find it?
Thank heavens! Thank heavens!
-How is your injury?-I'm okay!
Xue Qi, are you caring about me?
Xue Qi! Xue Qi!
Did you think things through?
You like me, right?
She's shy!
Yes.
I heard that you won in your competition yesterday.
I was so happy!
I originally wanted to celebrate with you.
I didn't think that this sort of thing would happen.
That's because I was just lucky.
If you saw how I won, you wouldn't say that.
Why do you say that? You did very well.
I will definitely do my best today too!
Xiao Fan, I'll go support you this afternoon. Give a good performance!
Don't like your teacher look down on you!
I forgot to go to Teacher!
Jing Yu, I'll go back first!
Look at all of you!
And you! As the oldest,
you look very talented on the outside,
always so handsome! You-!
Teacher!
Xiao Fan, hurry and come here!
Xiao Fan!
Teacher, Mistress.
Teacher, Xiao Fan is back.
Which house's young talent is this?
Did he come to the wrong teacher?
Teacher, I know I was wrong.
Zhang Xiao Fan, you won once by luck.
You don't need to return here. Go be independent!
What a thing worth celebrating!
And you all! Look at all of you!
Don't compete anymore. Go back! You are so shameful here!
Bu Yi!
My heart!
Get up, Xiao Fan.
Hurry and get up!
Your teacher is very angry right now. Don't put it in your heart.
Compete well later. When you're done, go apologize to him.
It's my fault.
This isn't your fault. It's mostly because your senior brothers all lost yesterday.
Ling Er is the only one left. So your teacher is very angry.
Zhang Xiao Fan, you luckily won one round.
It's okay! Senior Brothers, I'll get revenge for you!
Who said we all lost? Isn't there still Xiao Fan?
Mistress, Xiao Fan is lucky. He picked the empty slot in the first round, and won the second!
Yes, Mistress. I was just lucky.
How did you win?
Halfway through, the opponent got diarrhea.
You are too lucky!
[Zhang Xiao Fan versus Huang Lei]
Xiao Fan! We're going to watch Junior Sister!
Fight well! You must be confident!
Xiao Fan!
-We're leaving!-We're leaving!
-Senior Brother!-Senior Brother.
Did I win because of the two types of martial arts, or because of this black stick?
Why can't I remember the move I used to win just now?
Could it be this stick controlled me?
Xiao Fan.
-Jing Yu.-That wasn't a bad fight.
Just lucky.
You won twice in a row. How could it be just because of luck?
Everyone is discussing that the martial arts of Da Zhu Palace is really profound.
They don't even know how the opponent was defeated.
Come. Let's spar.
Let me see your martial arts.
Why do I need to spar with you?
You can't be afraid that you'll lose to me since you already used your ultimate move?
I already told you that it was based on luck.
But on the competition platform, you did very well.
I won't fight you.
You are my best friend.
Xiao Fan. Did your teacher teach you nothing?
I already said that I couldn't master it.
Okay. Let's have a little spar.
You see? I only won because I was lucky.
Then what move did you use to win the past two rounds?
I'm telling you! I don't have the ability to win!
All I used was cheap tricks, okay?
Zhang Xiao Fan, what kind of twisted skills did you learn?
Are you going to keep it a secret even from me?
I can't even master Qing Yun's basic magic skills!
How can I learn twisted skills? You're overestimating me.
You're lying, you're lying!
Where did the magic treasure in your hand come from?
I've never lied.
I cannot tell you where this magic treasure came from.
-The competition today was so intense!-Yes.
Senior Sister Lu won again, she's so amazing!
I originally thought Junior Brother Huang could win.
I wonder what that Zhang Xiao Fan used.
He could win over Junior Brother Huang!
-It's too strange.-That's right.
Why are you here?
I'm waiting for Xue Qi.
What's up with you?
I'm telling you, Xue Qi she-
Xiao Fan, how did you win today?
Everyone is talking about you.
Okay okay, I won't talk. I'll listen to you talk, okay?
Xiao Fan, did you look on the notice board?
The one you're fighting tomorrow is my eldest senior brother, Peng Chang.
He has the highest cultivation among the disciples at Feng Hui Palace
But don't worry. I've already gone to talk to him.
He will be merciful.
Just kill me.
Why are you being so silly?
Xiao Fan, what kind of martial arts did you use today?
Did you learn it from Xiao Gui?
How about you teach me too?
Are there Qing Yun disciples who know martial arts from two sects?
Martial arts from two sects?
There shouldn't be.
Did you forget? Qing Yun Sect's third rule.
Secretly learning other martial arts is taboo here.
Whoever is caught gets their martial arts destroyed, kicked out of Qing Yun, and then...
Zhang Xiao Fan, Peng Chang
Why did your Chao Yang Palace come to watch our Feng Hui Palace's competition?
Of course we came to support Senior Brother Peng!
He must defeat that Zhang Xiao Fan. He must defeat him!
Senior Brother Peng, it's all up to you! You must not let that brat win!
It's okay, Junior Brother Xiao Fan is also under our sect.
Okay okay. I know.
I will definitely be merciful. Don't worry.
Senior Brother you're the best! You really are my senior brother!
Of course!
Xiao Fan! Work hard, Xiao Fan!
Work hard, Xiao Fan!
Xiao Fan!
Junior Brother, which side are you on?
N-n-no, we're all on the same side!
Xiao Fan! Stop going easy on him!
Junior Brother Zhang, you keep avoiding attacking. Are you looking down on me?
He used that demonic magic again! That's not a Qing Yun skill!
Yeah! Don't tell me that's demonic magic!
Twisted magic! It must be demonic skills!
Why did you lie that you don't know magic?
Didn't I tell him to go easy on you?
Why did you lie to me?
Catch him, catch him!
Hit him, hit him!
Let me do it!
Hit! Hit! Hit! Hit him!
What are you doing? Is the big group bullying the small group?
Let's talk, calm down!
That's right! Retreat! I'm telling you, our Junior Brother Xiao Fan won!
Are you guys not willing to take a loss?
Retreat! Don't go overboard!
Is the big group bullying the small? Retreat!
-Calm down!-Stop!
What are you doing?
Teacher!
Do you want to be punished?
Do rules still exist here?
Old Seven, can you tell me
how you beat Peng Chang?
You don't want to tell me?
Teacher.
I...
Teacher. I am stupid.
In all these years, I have improved little.
But recently,
I suddenly discovered a magic treasure that matched me!
Xiao Fan...you now is a dark horse.
Amazing everyone with a single brilliant feat. So in the limelight.
Teacher. No.
Okay! You don't need to say anything.
When I see you, when I see all of you-!
My heart!
Okay! I,
don't want to know how you got that magic treasure.
Do you know, that to be able to be matched with a magic treasure,
that person's skills must be at least at the fourth level?
But I remember
that I have only taught you up to the second level of magic!
Can you tell this ignorant and ill-informed Teacher of yours
how you skipped the third level to hit the fourth level?
Tell me!
Please punish me, Teacher.
Punish?
Learning magic behind your teacher's back is Qing Yun's biggest taboo!
A light punishment means reflection for ten years!
A serious punishment means your skills are destroyed
and you are kicked out of the sect!
Timing & subitles brought to you by Gone with the Shirt Team@Viki
♫ One thought became an obsession ♫
♫ The blue sea became yellow desert ♫
♫ I passed within reincarnations like a flying bird ♫
♫ Anchoring on my memories ♫
♫ Lighting a candle ♫
♫ Can that weak light illuminate sadness? ♫
♫ Listening to the rain dropping ♫
♫ Looking at some flowers blooming ♫
♫ Sighing why there are only silhouettes that were left from yesterday ♫
♫ Love chains that's hard to break ♫
♫ A simple life in one's eyes ♫
♫ A dream that no one can touch ♫
♫ I got drunk within one's lifetime ♫
♫ Suddenly, like a dream ♫
♫ When I opened my eyes, time has already interlaced ♫
♫ One feeling went on fire ♫
♫ One heart got bewitched ♫
♫ Who's going to be scared out of one's wits for whom?
♫ The pen of time can't draw us ♫
♫ Don't leave too much messages ♫
♫ One love blossoms; love is hard to copy ♫
♫ Use my lifetime to accompany you to squander ♫
♫ Be with you until even the north star has fallen down ♫
♫ One feeling went on fire ♫
♫ One heart got bewitched ♫
♫ Who's going to be scared out of one's wits for whom?
♫ The pen of time can't draw us ♫
♫ Don't leave too much messages ♫
♫ One love blossoms; love is hard to copy ♫
♫ Use my lifetime to accompany you to squander ♫
♫ Be with you until even the north star has fallen down ♫