Good, please show more intimacy.
Comrade Major! Something big happened!
The North seems to know that Comrade
Han Myeong Wol wants to surrender.
It seems as if they've already sent a sniper.
No... no...
Hyeong!
(Hyeong - older brother)
Gang U hyeong!
What's going on?
It's no big deal.
It's just acute appendicitis, appendicitis!
So then, he's in surgery now?
But what about the wedding?
The wedding has been postponed.
Postponed until when?
Can't you elaborate?
Sorry, let's stop it here.
I will contact you guys with
more detailed information.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
Tell a bit more, please tell a bit more!
Hello?
Yes, Representative.
How is it over there?
It's a mess, there are reporters everywhere!
Yes. I've said it according to the
instructions of the representatives.
So what does this matter count as?
Myeong Wol, don't wait here
go and change your clothes.
You sitting here won't change a thing.
Comrade Major, what happened
to Comrade Myeong Wol?
She's all right.
That's fortunate.
Really fortunate...
I thought something had happened.
We can't even go there,
we can only wait here...
But...
Gang U was shot.
What?
So, the wedding was cancelled.
No... how could Gang U...
It seems like Gang U took the bullet
meant for Comrade Myeong Wol.
So, it really was a sniper.
I guess so.
What should we do... what should we do?
Well, how's Comrade Gang U's condition?
Although it's unclear,
his condition isn't very good.
What should we do?
What are we going to do,
Comrade Myeong Wol?
But,
if the reason why they sent a sniper was because
they knew Comrade Myeong Wol was going to surrender,
then the matter won't be easy to settle.
Yes,
they definitely want to kill
Comrade Myeong Wol.
So, is that why you came back?
And even giving up the chance
to go back to the North?
First, help me look into where
Gang U's hospital and ward is.
That's it, then.
Can't you see that he will not leave because
Comrade Myeong Wol is in serious danger?
When we look at it this way,
Comrade Major is also pitiful.
But no matter what he does,
Gang U is all that Myeong Wol sees.
That's true.
No...
So, you didn't go to Gang U's wedding?
Why would I go?
I don't want to go and
give them my blessing.
They also would prefer if I didn't go.
Good thinking.
Then, what about you, Grandfather?
Why would I want to attend their wedding?
Besides, there will probably be a lot of people
congratulating them.
I've already paid my respects
by sending a gift.
By the sound of it,
you've sent them some money.
You hate him so much. Why would you...
Even if it's for 'face' sake,
I can't bring myself to do that.
That's why I say that you're still immature.
What good will putting up a strong front do you?
Oh, whatever! Think whatever you like.
You...have you already given up on Gang U?
How can I not give up?
I'm also tired.
Oh, how is it?
Have you sent over the money?
The wedding was cancelled.
What?
What happened?
Gang U suddenly needed appendicitis surgery.
But from the rumors,
it may have been due to a gunshot.
Gunshot?
How is that possible?
Who would want to kill Gang U?
So, how is Gang U right now?
It seems to be more serious than I thought.
Really? Who could want to get rid of Gang U?
Moreover, with a gunshot at that.
And also...
it seems that Mr. Choe may not have
left the country yet.
What? He hasn't left the country?
Yes, his name was not found
on the final boarding list.
Then, could it have been...
Choe Ryu who did that to Gang U?
If it were not, then why?
We must observe Choe Ryu's movements.
If anything seem suspicious,
contact me immediately.
Yes.
What does he mean? Why would
Choe Ryu do that to Gang U?
Please help me get an identity that can safely
get me back to the North and airline tickets too.
Going to the North seems rather strange.
Oh! It can't be that...
No way! It's not possible.
That's too ridiculous!
Ah, Doctor, how is he? Hyeong's okay, right?
We've already removed the bullet and
stitched up the wound as well.
Fortunately, the bullet missed a vital organ,
avoiding serious consequences.
Ah, Thank you! Thank you!
However, there was excessive bleeding
while making his way here.
So till now, he has yet to regain consciousness.
What?
Then... that... when would that be?
It's hard to tell.
There's no way for us to know.
We're fortunate enough as it is.
So, don't be too worried.
Gang U hyeong, will definitely wake up soon.
Yes...
But seriously, this situation is very strange.
How can he get shot in the center of Seoul?
We don't even know who did this, either.
Myeong Wol, perhaps, is there anyone
that you might suspect?
Could Hyeong, perhaps, have been
receiving threats all this while?
It couldn't be a repeat of the incident
at the Minera Hotel previously, right?
Or could it be someone like a
crazy, perverted stalker?
If I ever find out who that crazy guy is,
he'll have to deal with me!
Oppa!
(Oppa - older brother, boyfriend)
Gyeong Ju.
Is Gang U oppa, okay?
Hey, what are you doing here?
I heard that Gang U oppa had surgery,
How could I not come and see how he is?
He's fine, so don't disturb the patient.
Let's talk outside...talk outside.
What's wrong with you?
Let's talk outside!
We don't even know who did this, either.
Myeong Wol, perhaps, is that anyone
that you might suspect?
What are you going to do?
Didn't I say before,
that if we fail, we can't allow Gang U who knows
our identities to continue living any longer.
No. That's impossible.
It's not possible that he'd be there
at that time.
Gyeong Ju.
Aigoo!
(Aigoo - oh dear, oh my god)
Oppa, just what are you doing?
Oppa, you'd better come clean.
Aigoo... what about?
You're hiding something, aren't you? Right?
Aigoo, what can I be hiding?
Then why are you stuttering?
St...st...stuttering, who's stuttering?
Look, aren't you stuttering right now?
Then look at me and say it again.
You see? Oppa, do you have a
secret that you're not telling me?
So, this is the sort of relationship that we're in?
It's not like that, Gyeong Ju.
I'm really disappointed. Let's break up.
What? Gyeong Ju!
Oh, it shouldn't be like this.
Hey, Gyeong Ju, Gyeong Ju.
Comrade Ok Sun, right now,
what are your plans for the future?
Ah...
Who knows?
Since I've decided to stay, either I surrender,
or I'll just remain as I have, like before.
I have to make a choice between the two.
How about you, Comrade Hui Bok?
Isn't surrendering a better choice?
Then let's do that.
At least we can live more peacefully.
But if we did that,
just like Comrade Myeong Wol,
the higher-ups may not let us go.
Because Comrade Myeong Wol became
an actress here...
so if she surrendered,
it would have resulted into a huge issue.
For small fries like us,
why would they bother?
Well, you can never be too sure.
In that case, let's just carry on like this.
That's also too precarious.
All I really want is to be able to
sleep without a worry.
The, let's just surrender.
If I did that, I don't think I can
sleep in peace either.
Then, what do you really want?
This is really annoying.
Whenever a decision has to be made,
why must you make it so difficult?
You don't have to worry.
Let me settle it for you.
How?
I just have to report you to the authorities.
What?
Is this 113?
Don't do that! Seriously...
I'm sorry, but you can't visit him right now.
I came to see you.
I hope that you can be honest with me.
What can I tell you?
Just who are you and Choe?
What do you guys do? Why is Grandfather
and Gang U both caught up like that?
And Choe said...
that he's returning to North Korea.
What's that about?
Don't try to tell me that you don't know.
I know enough to know that it involves you.
There is something, isn't there?
Something that you can't reveal?
If it's about this,
why don't you ask Chairman Ju?
Then do you know where Choe is. right now?
I heard he didn't leave the country yet.
What?
There's no way that
Gang U's injury...
has anything to do with Choe, right?
It can't be... it's not possible!
How could it be? How could it?
Just make your way back, then I'll spare you.
I'm only trying to complete my mission.
Didn't you get what I just said?
Send a message back.
Han Myeong Wol's problem will be sorted out by me.
Immediately stop the order to terminate.
You should know well enough that not following
through our orders has serious repurcussions.
If you don't want to die, do as I say.
Oh, what's this?
What do I do? What do I do?
Don't worry, I'm fine.
Hey, how can you be fine?
You're still bleeding!
Oh, give me a sec...
This... use it to tie that up.
Thank you.
Oh...
That was rather expensive.
On my last trip to Italy,
I bought that direct from the designer.
In that case...
Oh, never mind! It's already dirty!
But...how did you get hurt?
That wound of yours...
is it from a knife?
No, it's not. It's just a scratch.
It's only a scratch?
Could he possibly be a spy?
That's not possible! He's so naive.
But if it should be the case, then...
Since you've already uncovered my identity,
I can't let you live!
Oh!
It's nothing, just wait for me here.
I'm going to the drugstore to get some medicine.
That's not right, it's too strange. That's right.
Aren't you Miss Ju In A?
No, I'm not! Oh, what should I do?
Also...do I have any proof?
That...
Oh!
Comrade Han Myeong Wol.
Why are you doing this?
I'm asking you why you're doing this?
Comrade Han Myeong Wol!
I begged you not to touch Comrade Gang U.
Have you already forgotten?
I'm warning you.
If you should touch Gang U again...
I won't let you off.
And I won't stop myself.
What goodwill I have left for Comrade Major...
ends here.
From today,
I will hate you for the rest of my life.
In A.
Where are you going to?
You can't be...
doing something useless like last time, right?
Grandfather.
Since you brought it up, let me ask.
Choe Ryu, who exactly is that man?
What's his relationship with Grandfather?
What exactly does he do?
It's better that you don't know.
Don't involve yourself.
Really, Grandfather, you keep saying that!
It keeps bugging me,
so how can I just leave it?
Are you, instead of Gang U...
starting to have feelings for that guy, Choe Ryu?
What?
Do you think I'm crazy?
If you don't have feelings, then it's fine.
I thought it might be possible, so I asked.
You should never get close to that guy.
When you're compassionate,
you can't make clear judgment.
If you repeat what you did the last time,
this time round,
you'll definitely not be forgiven.
Then why?
Why can't I get close to him?
Why can't it be like that?
Grandfather, why don't you just tell me?
You'll find out later.
You people are so annoying!
This brat, really.
How did it go?
Do you have the results for the Four Joint Books?
Yes.
Really? Okay.
So what's this map pointing to?
About the...results of the analysis...
What about the results?
Before,
they said it was located somewhere
in the Korean Peninsula.
That's right.
Now, the results according to the expert...
is pointing to a completely different location.
What?
So, we referred it to the previous expert
from before...
and he said there was something with them.
What? Choe Ryu, that guy!
Chairman!
It's fine. Alright...
That guy! He must have altered them somehow.
He has destroyed the Four Joint Books!
Then...
He surely, surely...
must have had a copy
before destroying them.
In order to capture him...
there's no other way.
Call the NSA.
(NSA - National Security Association)
Yes.
This guy...
if he should see Han Myeong Wol in a hitch,
would he ignore the situation?
We shouldn't be seen casually in
a crowded place like this.
Then what about Comrade Myeong Wol,
who's probably not able to have a decent meal...
do we just ignore her situation?
After all, she's still our daughter!
But doesn't Gang U already know our situation?
How can we still meet?
He hasn't even regained consciousness yet.
Why don't we just pop by to see
Comrade Myeong Wol for a moment?
Just now...
I think I didn't shut off the gas.
I have to attend to the gas...
Aigoo, seriously...!
That guy is so timid.
Just recently, there's an actor Gang U,
who was admitted here.
Which room is he in?
I'm warning you.
If you touch Gang U again.
I won't let you off.
Yes.
What?
Until when do you plan to lie down like that?
The self-righteous, unlucky, and demanding you.
Do you plan to just lie down there powerlessly?
Hey, hurry up and bring them over here!
Can't you do anything right?
What have you been doing as my bodyguard?
Yes, enough. Leave.
And if you attempt anything like this again,
I don't care if you're my bodyguard or not...
Are you a grasshopper?
Forget it.
If it isn't prepared by the best nutritionist...
incorporating the six main food nutrients.
I will not eat it.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Is Comrade Gang U still the same?
He'll wake up soon.
That's right. He should get better.
I'm sorry.
In making a personal choice...
I can understand you.
In the past, I was also caught
between my mission and love.
I've gone through that distressing experience.
I really don't know...
how to face the both of you.
We both, too...
have decided to follow our own choices.
Comrade Major has also allowed us to do so.
He is unable to protect us anymore.
Let's find our own way out of this.
Besides that, has there been anything else?
What?
Has anyone been threatening
or attacking you?
That... what do you mean?
It seems that you're not aware...
The injury that Comrade Gang U sustained,
was actually...
directed at Comrade Myeong Wol.
Didn't Comrade Major tell you?
What?
The North found out that you were going to surrender.
So, they sent some people over.
After Comrade Major knew,
he turned back, while making his way to the North.
Is that the truth?
Yes. Since nothing else has happened...
we're really fortunate.
In short, pay attention to your safety.
Do you understand?
Comrade Hui Bok is still waiting for me.
I need to leave now.
Comrade Han Myeong Wol. Why are you doing this?
Is there a guardian named Han Myeong Wol?
She's over there.
Han Myeong Wol! Stay still!
Stop!
Han Myeong Wol!
Myeong Wol?
Why are you asking about Myeong Wol?
We need to investigate a few matters.
Investigate?
You just need to answer truthfully
on matters pertaining to Han Myeong Wol.
It seems that Chairman Ju has already
reported us to the police.
If that's so, the public will soon know.
Even if you surrender,
you won't be able to live here in peace.
North Korea won't let you off either.
The point is, everyone now knows who you are.
Are you okay?
I'm sorry.
I've misunderstood Comrade Major.
About that...
Right now, you should be taking care
of yourself.
Let's go to the detective agency first.
Although it's not necessarily safe there,
but it'll do until a safer place can be found.
No.
Hyeong, are you awake? You're awake!
Nurse!
What exactly happened?
Hyeong, you got shot!
Don't you remember?
Where is Myeong Wol?
What?
Myeong Wol.
She was just here.
She'll be back soon.
Myeong Wol is fine, isn't she?
Why are you worried about someone else,
when you're the one that's hurt!
What? Who could have reported it to the police?
What happened...it was obvious that
they were there to catch spies.
Then, what's going to happen to Myeong Wol?
Gang U is still lying there, injured.
Myeong Wol is in trouble.
Right now, we don't even know what will happen.
That's why I'm saying,
we have to come to a decision.
Have you finally decided?
What do you think of this...
I have a very good plan.
What?
Between the two of us, one of us will surrender.
while the other who reports it to the police,
will receive the grant and reward.
What?
Think about it.
The grant and reward could
amount to 5 million Won.
One of us just needs to go in
and endure a little hardship.
Once out, we'll can start a new life together.
Isn't that a good plan?
But wouldn't someone have to go to prison?
I've thought about that, too.
In this day and age, it's very difficult for
a woman to make it on her own.
So Comrade Ok Sun, why don't you settle
for some nutritious prison meals for awhile.
Since they're so nutritious, Comrade Hui Bok,
why don't you go for them instead?
Didn't I say that I was allergic to beans?
(beans and jail food have the same first syllable)
I'll take good care of the money.
How can I trust you?
What happens if you run away with the money?
What sort of person do you take me for?
What sort? How about the sort who would
run away with the money?
What?
Comrade Myeong Wol.
Aigoo! We were really worried about you.
Right now, what should we do?
I mean, how did the situation get this bad?
I have to trouble you both in the mean time.
Until I find a place for her to stay,
please let her stay here.
What trouble? It's the least we could do.
I guess it's the best solution.
If we're all together, should we end up getting...
I can't believe this person...
We're actually her parents in name.
It's because we're her parents,
if we're found to be together...
Comrade Myeong Wol, just ignore him.
Please stay here with ease.
Yes, it's me.
By the sound of it, you seem fine.
Is Han Myeong Wol okay, as well?
Thanks to you.
That's why, you shouldn't have messed
around with the Four Joint Books!
So is that why you did that?
There's absolutely no way you'll be allowed
to take them to the North. So don't even try.
However, if we get arrested,
then Chairman, you'll also be at the losing end.
What?
Don't you want to know the secret
of the Four Joint Books?
=We are unable to connect you to the phone now.
Please wait while we direct you to the voice mail.=
Hyeong, why did you get up?
You're not suppose to get up yet.
Where's Myeong Wol?
Why don't I see Myeong Wol?
She'll be here soon.
And when will that be?
Hyeong...
I'm sure something must have
happened to Myeong Wol.
Hyeong, Myeong Wol is just fine.
Nothing has happened to her.
The doctor said that if you're not careful,
you might sustain another injury.
He said that you absolutely must not move.
I have to see for myself,
that Myeong Wol is okay.
Hyeong, I get it, I get it.
I'll bring Myeong Wol over.
Will that do, huh? Just rest for a while.
So then, what are your plans ahead?
I have no other option.
So...
By staying by his side, I'll be exposing
that person to more danger.
I don't want him to suffer any further,
because of me.
But if he finds out that you've left,
Gang U will suffer quite a blow.
If they stay together,
he'll have to live with anxiety...
unable to have a day of peace.
Hello! Ajussi! Ajumma!
(Ajussi - middle aged man / uncle)
(Ajumma - middle aged woman / aunt)
Isn't that Dae Gang?
Wait a minute!
What? She didn't drop by?
That's right.
We can't get in touch with her.
We're really worried as well.
Where could she have gone?
In order to let her rest,
I've been attending to Hyeong all this while.
Oh, by the way, some strangers came by
during the day and asked about Myeong Wol.
What?
Really?
Do you, perhaps, know why?
They appear to be with the police
or something of that sort.
How could we know?
That's right. Why would they be asking for Myeong Wol?
Just where did she go?
She's must be feeling upset, so she's
probably gone for a walk somewhere.
That's right. To have this happen during the wedding...
must have been quite a shock.
She should be back soon.
That's what I thought.
But Gang U hyeong keeps calling for her.
What? What do you mean by that?
Has Gang U regained consciousness?
Yes.
That's great. That's really great.
But when he woke up, his request for
Myeong Wol is making things difficult.
I was afraid that he would worry, so I couldn't
tell him that someone was seeking her out.
What should I tell him when I get back?
You've deciphered the secret of the
Four Joint Books, haven't you?
A few years from now, whoever that has it
will become the center of the world.
It was proclaimed that in the Four Joint Books,
lies a map with a hidden password.
I'm aware of that, too.
The map indicates a number of areas
in Manchuria and the Korean Peninsula.
The areas that have been identified,
as historians believe, would provide the treasure
that would make someone the center of the world.
So, what is that treasure?
According to the common areas
that have been identified,
and from the contents of the books,
I've managed to decipher the secret.
From the results, the treasure is...
The treasure is?
Rare earth metal.
Rare earth metal? What's rare earth metal?
It refers to rare minerals and
includes the 15 lanthanoids.
There are a total of 17 elements
in this rare earth metal.
Really?
With the electronic industries as they are now...
for all sorts of electronic products,
power stations...
and even for weapons production,
it will be a much needed natural resource.
That's right.
So right now...
in order to get hold of this natural resource,
the whole world is fighting over...
knowledge of where these deposits are located.
In the decades to come,
whoever gets hold of it will become
the center of the world.
Rare earth metal...
That's right, it's rare earth metal!
As long as you get the mining rights,
Chairman, you will gain control of the world,
as you would have hoped.
But...
if this goes through the NSA,
it  falls into the hands of the government. What then?
Would you still own the exclusive rights
to the mining sites?
Search him thoroughly.
Yes.
Unless I'm an idiot,
why would I bring them with me?
That's enough.
Okay. What's the condition?
Let Han Myeong Wol return to North Korea safely.
Why is it so quiet?
Isn't anyone around?
Aren't these the photos from Gang U's showcase?
Myeong Wol with Choe?
-=Han Myeong Wol is bodyguard to North Korea's
Politburo fifth-ranked General Kim's daughter.=-
-=Name: Choe Ryu,
Nationality: North Korean (DPRK)=-
What's this?
Then, he's a spy?
Is he really a spy?
Han Myeong Wol, as well?
Where have you been?
Is Comrade Han Myeong Wol okay now?
Yes.
So far, nothing has happened...
So, when will she return to the North?
Comrade Myeong Wol,
seemed to have made up her mind.
Right now, she seems to think that
even if she stays by Comrade Gang U's side,
she'll only bring him trouble.
That's not too far from the truth.
Where is she now?
Upstairs.
By the way...
have you heard the news?
It seems that Gang U has already
regained consciousness.
What?
Because of that,
she hasn't been in a good mood since.
She probably really wants to see him.
How can she not?
Please get up.
Comrade Major.
I'll only give you ten minutes
to see him one last time.
Being born North Korean
and falling in love with a South Korean,
is a mistake.
Such things only happen in fiction.
I should never have dreamt
about this from the start.
To finally see you safe and sound,
I feel really fortunate.
Thank you for the wonderful times.
Myeong Wol.
Han Myeong Wol.
You're awake?
It seems I woke you up.
Where did you go?
Do you know how long
I've been looking for you?
Where could I possibly go?
Am I not here?
You're okay, right?
Nothing's happened, right?
Don't go anywhere.
You must always be by my side.
All right.
I feel alive at last,
just seeing your face.
After I'm discharged from the hospital,
I'll begin preparations for our wedding again.
For all that you have suffered,
I will definitely make it up to you in happiness.
Must we do it that way?
Get some sleep...
You need to rest.
Han Myeong Wol.
This doesn't make sense.
How could that be?
How could Miss Myeong Wol be a....
What about Myeong Wol?
Hyeong, you're awake!
Tell me the truth.
Is there something going on?
Nothing's going on, Hyeong...
Are you still not going to come clean?
Sometime back, some people looking into
information regarding Miss Myeong Wol.
After that day, Miss Myeong Wol disappeared.
That's why I found those people strange.
However, don't be shocked...
It was said that Miss Myeong Wol...
is a spy.
Aigoo, why are you here?
You should still be lying in hospital.
Why did you come?
Are you okay now?
Is it alright for you to be walking around like that?
Myeong Wol. Where's Myeong Wol?
Please allow me to see Myeong Wol.
She's not here.
What?
She was here until just a while ago.
Teacher Choe Ryu just took her away.
Taken away? Where to?
He said that being here was unsafe.
So where did they go?
Where they went, we don't know either.
Do you really not know?
Or, are you deliberately not telling me?
Oh, we really don't know!
Aigoo. All right.
You'll find out anyway so I'll just tell you.
They said that before they get the
boat tickets to return to the North,
they'll need to hide in a safe place.
But they said it's not okay for us to know,
so they didn't tell us where.
To the North?
Myeong Wol...
don't go looking for her anymore.
No matter what, it's an impossible fate.
Doing this will only make things
more difficult for Myeong Wol.
Aigoo, I really can't stand to watch any longer.
Those two are just so pitiful.
Don't cry.
Where's this place?
This is where Gang U and I spent the night,
when we got lost in the mountains.
Will it be uncomfortable for you?
I'll be fine.
You'll need to endure for awhile.
Don't worry about me.
I'll go gather some branches for firewood.
Thank you.
For being able to...
accompany me at a time like this.
I've always been by your side.
You said Gang U has woken up?
Then could he have the news
about Han Myeong Wol?
I'm not too sure about that.
Yes, it's me.
I heard that you've woken up.
So I was just about to call to
congratulate you.
From your voice, you sound pretty healthy.
Thank you for your concern.
Well, that's nothing.
I realized after I woke up,
that you didn't keep your promise.
Don't blame me.
That guy Choe Ryu, wasn't sincere about
bringing the Four Joint Books over.
So what else could I have done?
Was there no other choice?
That has always been your excuse.
You've taken away all the people
who meant something to me.
However, this time, I won't just let it slide.
Right now, are you threatening me?
If that's the case, what can you do to me?
I will tell the world about how you killed my father.
Then with my own eyes, I'll watch your downfall.
What did you say?
I have been cherishing our friendship all this time.
Even till now, I've been very patient.
Just what do you hope to achieve,
by bringing up things from 20 years ago?
Furthermore, do you have the evidence
to incriminate me?
I've put in so much effort over the years
just to find you.
Did you think I wouldn't have the evidence?
For Myeong Wol's sake,
I was prepared to forget about everything.
From this day on,
you're finished.
That brat really must have something.
He doesn't seem to be joking.
All the evidence from then
should have been destroyed.
You...
Yes.
Find Han Myeong Wol.
What?
I want to make her unable to move.
That's the only solution left.
Moreover, by using Han Myeong Wol,
I can kill two birds with one stone.
Hey listen...
Do you ever think about the past?
In order to participate in
the Special Forces Division,
I had to train in the mountains then,
and I would get reprimanded
by Comrade Major every day.
Comrade Han Myeong Wol.
If you keep going like that,
you might as well not do it.
Working in the Special Forces Division
will never really suit you.
I will definitely stick with it.
Just wait and see.
At that time, after listening
to Comrade Major's words,
I should have given up.
Maybe I'm really not qualified.
Always giving Comrade Major trouble.
Why didn't you just leave me there?
Didn't I tell you before?
When your father entrusted you to me,
I promised to protect you until the very end.
That...
is the last task I gave myself.
Are you crazy?
How can you walk around in this state?
Does the hospital know you're out?
Be quiet, come and sit.
It's because you look weak.
Are you okay?
Do you know where Choe Ryu is?
How would I know?
Since we're at it,
I'll ask you one thing...
Did you already know?
Know what?
Them.
Their identities.
How did you find out about that?
You already knew and you're still like this?
She intends to surrender.
What?
Myeong Wol intends to surrender.
So we have to find Myeong Wol.
She's missing.
So what?
Please help me.
How can I help you?
What can I do?
I'm sorry.
I also don't know what to do.
Anyway, I understand now.
Excuse me.
Is Choe Ryu also involved in this?
Yes, perhaps.
I'll try.
I said I'll try.
I'll think of a way to call Choe Ryu out.
Grandfather wants to see you.
What's the matter?
Why is the Chairman looking for me?
I'm sorry, it wasn't Grandfather.
It was someone else.
Where is Myeong Wol right now?
Let me see her.
Do you know how difficult it
is for Han Myeong Wol right now?
I beg you, please let me see her.
I can't just let her leave like that.
I beg you, please.
For your own good,
you also have to give up.
That is Han Myeong Wol's intention.
You also know what it feels like, don't you?
Missing her to death.
If I'm not by her side, it's so painful
I might as well die.
Search every corner of
this mountain carefully!
- Yes.
Hey, do you know how funny
you look right now?
What are you doing?
I must keep this and look at it
when I am in a bad mood.
Han Myeong Wol...
I found you.