[Orchestral Manoeuvres
in the Dark singing
"So In Love"]
¶ Talk to me don't lie to me ¶
¶ Save your breath ¶
¶ Don't look at me ¶
¶ Don't smile at me ¶
¶ Just close your eyes ¶
¶ I was so impressed by you ¶
¶ I was runnin' blind ¶
¶ I would fall for every trick ¶
¶ Every twist of mind ¶
¶ Heaven is cold ¶
¶ Without any soul ¶
¶ It's hard to believe ¶
¶ I was so in love with you ¶
>> Check. Check.
Check. Check.
¶ All the things
you said to me ¶
¶ I was so upset.. ¶
>> Hey, Dan.
>> Jerry.
>> New sign?
>> Same sign, Jerry.
New suction cups.
Come on.
¶ God I did my best.. ¶¶
>> No. I was -- I was actually
calling about the reunion
you know, 'cause it's right
around the corner.
>> ...from Barkledge
High School.
>> ...well, I..
>> Herbert Farber
just hung up on me.
>> Jesus, dude, how many times
have you been married?
Well, bring 'em all.
>> May I speak
with Jeff Suttleson, please?
Jeff? Dan Landsman.
From high school.
The D man.
No? Nothin'?
Neil Boitress, D Money.
[laughs]
Dan...Landsman.
It was a nickname.
Everyone used to call me that.
Uh, they -- yes, they did.
They definitely did.
Class of '94?
Yes, there we go.
No, I don't think
I still suck.
Yes, it's that time.
20 years.
Can you believe it?
Well, we sent out
a paper invitation
and followed that up
with an E-vite
and a link to the Facebook page.
Oh, you did? Great!
But you're not -- Got it.
There seemed to be a little
indecision in your voice.
I'm gonna see
if I could flip ya.
Flip you to a yes.
Oh, okay.
That's not very mature.
[indistinct chatter]
Whoop!
Craig? Randy?
So, uh..
>> I'm up for beers.
>> What are you guys doing?
You guys grabbing beers or..
>> Yeah, I don't think..
>> I'm gonna head home myself.
>> Yeah. So maybe next time.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> Alright, buddy.
>> Okay.
>> Maybe next time.
>> Yeah, I'll call you.
>> Well, I'm askin' you
what the --
What is the future
of Pirates' baseball?
>> The problem is
here in Pittsburg
we know that we can't
spend as much on salary,
so they constantly have guys
that they develop,
then leave Pittsburg.
>> Well, you know what?
You can't bring
Dave Parker back.
You can't bring back
Willie Stargell.
You gotta go
with what got you there.
>> But do you think --
>> You gotta go
with prospects.
>> Do you think
McCutchen is enough
to lead this team
to a World Series?
[sighs]
[indistinct radio chatter]
[cutlery clinking]
>> They invite you for drinks?
>> No.
>> Did you tell them
that you wanted to go
like we talked about?
>> Yeah. They just
weren't goin' tonight.
>> Oh. I thought
they said that last time
but then you drove by
and you saw them.
>> Yeah, well, they weren't
doing that this time.
>> Zach, wanna tell your dad
about your new girlfriend?
>> Girlfriend?
>> She's not my girlfriend.
Just heard
this girl Heather likes me.
>> She's older. I told him
he should ask her out.
>> You think I should?
[inhales deeply]
>> Hmm.
I'd do
a little more investigating.
These girls
usually like older guys.
I think that's what
I'm bumpin' up against,
but you know..
...put some feelers out there.
>> I did.
And her friend said it's true.
>> Yeah, well, you never know.
I mean, the friend
could be lying.
>> Why would she lie?
>> Well, what if
it's a prank planned
by all the girls at school
to get you to ask her out
and then they all laugh
and make fun of you?
>> Dan!
>> What?
I'm just preparing him
for certain realities
of high school.
[instrumental music]
[bell rings]
>> Good morning.
Shurmur Consulting.
May I help you?
No..
[grunts]
[clicks mouse]
>> Come on.
Come on!
[keys clacking]
>> What the fuck is this?
Where are they?
I don't get this.
>> Bill, have you got a second?
>> Oh, yeah, Daniel, come on in.
>> I hate to bring this up again
but the Internet connection
is so beyond frustrating.
>> What do you mean, the cord?
>> No, not the cord.
The speed.
We got to get with it, you know.
>> That's why we lost
the Harkin account.
>> No.
>> I went to high school
with Dale Harkin
and he won't work with us?
>> The reason we lost
the Harkin account
is 'cause Dale's dad
is a liar.
Dale's dad is a perjurer.
>> And he wants things faster.
He emails.
>> Uh -- uh, I've been doing
this job for 40 years
without a computer,
and I'm doing fine.
>> Okay, but what happened
to the Bill Shurmur
I always wanted to work for?
The Bill Shurmur who always
loved catchin' that big fish!
>> Daniel, I get it.
I hear you.
I just don't have
the funds for these toys.
I can't. Don't do that.
That -- that's,
that's not fair.
Come here.
[Dan sighs]
Alright, you're my guy.
You know that, right?
>> Yeah, but --
>> And you've been
telling me to think bigger
for -- for -- for years,
but I -- I need to have
a little more cashola first
and then I promise you
the Dan plan is a go.
I -- I promise you.
[blows a raspberry]
Get out of here.
[sighs]
>> ...now on sale
at Cabinets To Go.
We've got solid wood,
high-quality kitchen cabinets
with features like
self-closing European
style hardware
dovetail joints
and guaranteed moisture..
>> Come on in.
You'll find the quality..
>> The ocean and the sun.
Both beautiful...both deadly.
Now, the ocean, I can keep
that safe pretty easily.
But the sun..
[tape rewinds]
The ocean and the sun.
Both beautiful...both deadly.
[crickets chirping]
>> Stacey?
Honey?
>> This is my beach.
And I need to protect it.
Now, the ocean, I can keep
that safe pretty easily.
But the sun...I leave that
to Banana Boat Triple Defense
Sunscreen for men.
[baby crying]
[sighs]
>> What?
>> You didn't
notice anything there?
>> I don't know
what we're looking for.
>> Fucking Lawless!
Oliver Lawless.
>> From high school?
>> Yes, from high school.
On a national commercial.
He did it. He made it!
Zach, that was one of
daddy's good friends.
>> Really?
>> No, it was not.
>> He was a friend.
>> This is what
you woke us up for?
Goddammit, Dan!
It's gonna take me half an hour
to put her back to bed.
Go to sleep, Zach, please.
>> Alright.
>> Jesus!
>> Let's watch it
one more time.
>> ...Sunscreen for men.
>> Hey, dad,
can I ask you about Heather?
>> Not now, Zach,
we're watching.
>> We've seen it a bunch now.
>> It's crazy, right?
>> Yeah, I guess.
>> You guess? What.. Oh, right?
How many of your close buddies
are on a national TV spot,
come on.
And I'm recording.
>> The ocean and the sun..
>> Nope. No, no, no, stop.
You got to start earlier,
then hit play, then exit
so the bar goes away
before it starts.
Okay, let's do it again.
Run it back.
Back it up
and give me some volume!
>> Mom, said that I --
>> Don't worry about mom!
I'll handle mom. Come on, Zach.
One more time, we're so close.
And play.
>> Banana Boat.
The only boat en route
to protecting your skin.
[woman screams]
>> Excuse me.
>> Good?
>> Haa!
Zachary!
[grunts]
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
>> Hang up the phones.
Hang up the phones!
Okay.
Boop. Boop.
>> Jesus Christ!
>> What are you doing?
>> And boop.
>> Huh..
>> What the fuck?
>> I'll tell you
what the fuck, Randy.
D-Fresh has an idea.
>> Who's D-Fresh?
>> It's me, Jerry. Focus.
I have an idea.
It's gonna take this thing
to the next level.
And get every single person
from our class to RSVP yes.
>> How?
>> Taj, bring up the reunion
Facebook page for me, please.
Everyone gather around.
>> Gather around?
>> Come on. Chop chop.
>> Why? Why would we do that?
>> Press play for me, Taj.
>> The ocean and the sun.
>> And full screen it
for me, Taj.
>> Both beautiful...
both deadly.
>> What the fuck is this?
>> Mm.
>> Mm?
>> Is that Oliver Lawless?
>> Yes!
It's Oliver Lawless!
He's a big
Hollywood actor now.
We get Lawless to come,
the whole class will follow.
It's like one of those
bullshit charity events.
They bring out the celebrities.
If Dave Schwimmer goes,
everyone goes!
>> Look, as chairman
of the alumni committee --
>> There is no chairman, Dan.
>> Okay, then how come
I am the only one
with the administrator password
to the Facebook page, Lucy?
>> Because you set it up
and you won't give
it to anyone.
>> Whatever!
I'm telling you
he's the answer here, guys.
>> Okay. Let's just assume
that you're right
and I'm not sayin' that you are
but let's just, uh,
let's assume it for a second.
>> Okay.
>> How're we supposed
to get him?
>> Yeah.
>> Mm.
>> He hasn't responded
to anything.
>> Nothing.
>> Mm-hmm.
Maybe I should be the one
reaching out. We're old friends.
>> Um, you were not friends
with Lawless.
>> Oh, was I not, Randy?
Is that why he sent
me the video
'cause we weren't friends?
>> Well, you could've
just recorded it off your TV.
>> Mm-hmm.
>> Yep.
That's exactly what --
>> Guys, guys, we're getting
away from the issue here.
>> Okay, okay, I want
to go to the other issue then.
The one where you're,
like, lying
about being friends
with Lawless.
>> I don't need this.
I'm going to get
my friend Oliver Lawless
to come to this reunion
and then we'll see
which issue is which.
>> What?
>> Oliver! What's up dude?
Haven't seen you
in a long time, bro.
Since high school?
Has it been that long? Jeez!
So looking very likely
I'll be headin' out
to the west side on biz.
Thought maybe
we could grab some brews
on the old expense account.
Holler at me, dawg.
You can message me here or
you can hit me up on my email.
Peace.
D-Rock.
Morning, Shelley.
>> Hey, Dan.
>> James.
[instrumental music]
[keys clacking]
Los Angeles businesses.
Drazen Partners.
Voila.
Kent Drazen.
Hello, sir.
[knock on door]
Bill, you got a sec?
>> Yeah, come on in.
>> Got a very
exciting prospect.
This firm in LA
just fired their whole team.
I got wind of it.
Made a couple of calls.
Ended up havin' a pretty
substantial email exchange
with the CEO Kent Drazen.
He wants me to fly out there
and meet him.
Here, check out the email.
Kent Drazen.
>> Oh, well, I guess --
>> He's the CEO.
>> I pressed something..
>> Oh. Here, no problem.
>> I'll get it right back.
>> Uh, please..
>> There it is.
>> No. Uh, forget it.
>> Just -- I don't..
>> Is that better?
Are you sure?
>> No, no.
>> You can see it.
>> Please.
>> Well...right here, he says
how he likes doing things
the old-fashioned way,
face to face.
Reminds me of you, Bill.
>> Mm-hmm.
And right here he says,
"I would love to do business
with your company."
I mean, that's a strong email.
>> You have
an instinct here, Daniel?
>> I do.
This could be big.
>> Let's do it.
>> Yeah?
>> Yeah.
You, uh, book two tickets.
Economy.
>> Well, uh..
...oh, you want to, uh..
>> Yeah, I should meet him.
>> Oh, yeah.
Well, I mean I hope
it doesn't spook him but --
>> Well, why would
it spook him?
>> Yeah, right.
Well, let me check
the airlines.
See if I can grab you a seat.
Thursday flights,
sold out, sold out, sold out.
Cross-checking
with the other carriers.
Ugh! Nothing!
>> And you can see that
on the phone?
>> Yeah, it's a new app.
[sighs]
We tried.
>> Hold on.
>> Looks like
a solo mission this time.
>> I got an idea.
Let me just...call Roselle.
>> She's been my travel agent --
>> She's gonna be looking at
the same screen I'm looking at.
>> Never hurts to try.
I -- I got to tell you,
I -- I, I don't trust the web.
Yeah. Roselle, please.
>> You did a soul patch?
>> Yeah.
Zach, don't drag the suitcase.
>> Oh.
>> Sorry.
>> This is huge!
>> You found this guy.
Does Bill know that?
>> Uh, yeah, he knows.
>> Are you gonna have time
to do something cool, dad?
>> Zach, this is
a business trip.
Not a lot of room
for dickin' around.
Get the suitcase out, please.
>> You're gonna kill it!
I'm so proud of you.
>> Who was doubting himself?
>> I was.
>> And who told you
[indistinct]
>> You did.
[chuckles]
>> I love you.
>> Love you.
>> Daddy's got
a business trip.
>> Ladies and gentlemen,
in just a few minutes
we'll be coming
through the cabin..
>> This is a nice plane.
>> Yeah. Glad Roselle
was able to get you a seat.
>> Oh, yeah, right away.
I told you,
online, it's crapshoot.
I want to go over the itinerary
just once more with you.
>> Okay.
>> We land at 4:40.
There should be
a Marathon rent-a-car shuttle
at baggage claim.
We go, we wa..
>> You okay?
>> Hmm?
>> Are you nervous?
>> Uh, no.
I haven't heard
from Drazen actually.
Ever since I emailed him
that you were joining.
>> Uh-oh.
>> Yeah.
>> Listen, next time
you email him
can you add me to it?
I've seen those
where there's multiple --
>> Uh, yeah,
the thing about that is
if it doesn't start
as a group thing..
...it's tough
to add someone later.
>> Well, that makes sense.
[instrumental music]
[vehicles honking]
[helicopter whirring]
>> Two rooms.
>> Thank you.
>> You're welcome.
>> Hi, I'd like to leave
a message for Bill Shurmur.
It's from Kent Drazen.
Meeting canceled.
Oh, hold on one sec.
[cellphone rings]
>> Hello?
>> Is this Daniel?
>> Oliver! What's up?
Hold on. Can you hold on?
>> I guess.
>> You sure?
>> Yeah, go.
>> I'll call you back.
[sighs]
>> Dude.
>> What's up, Daniel?
>> Uh, not much. You know
actually I go by Dan now.
>> Oh, great.
>> Right? Yeah, it's shorter.
Daniel's kinda --
>> Yeah, man.
Dan's better.
>> Yeah, thank you.
I'm glad you like it.
>> So what's up, Dan?
Why -- why'd you call?
>> Uh, well,
like I said on my VM
I'm in town on business.
>> Okay.
>> Hey, you wanna get beer?
>> Uh, no, man, this week's
kinda tough for me.
You, uh -- how long
you in town for?
>> Just a couple
of days actually.
>> Are you comin' out at all
again this year?
>> No, I don't
have that planned at all.
>> Hmm.
[blows]
Alright, fuck it.
I'll meet you.
>> Redbury in 30.
>> Redbury?
Okay, is that a..
You know what, I'll find it.
Hello?
[upbeat music]
[laughter]
>> Sir?
>> Hmm?
>> Again, if your
whole party's not here
I'm gonna need the couch.
>> He's parking right now.
Please just cut me
a little slack.
>> 3 minutes.
>> Thank you.
[Generationals singing
"I Never Know"]
¶ I bet it don't upset you
to see me get busted ¶
¶ But I've been listening
to people that I trusted ¶
¶ And I don't know.. ¶¶
>> Dan? Hey.
>> Dude, yeah. What's up?
>> You alright?
>> Yeah. I got us a couch.
>> Hey, let's sit at the bar.
>> Oh!
I'm not gonna need the couch.
>> Yeah,
it's a little consulting firm.
Um, meeting with a big firm.
Hopin' they'll contract us
to, um -- uh, this is so boring.
What am I rambling on about?
>> I've no idea, man.
>> You are killing it, sir.
"Banana Boat.
"It's the only boat
en route
to protecting your skin."
Fucking sick, bro!
>> Yeah. It turned out alright.
>> Alright?
Do you have any idea
how many people around here
are trying to do
what you're doing?
And you know
how many of them fail?
Good for you, dog.
Just like in high school.
Uh-oh, there's Lawless.
What's he doin'?
Steppin' back for the three.
Boom! So wish.
>> Fuck!
I haven't thought
about that in a while.
>> Hey, you know what?
You should come to the reunion.
>> 20 years, comin' up.
>> Nah, man.
>> That's not my thing.
>> Yeah.
>> Damn.
You must be crushin' on
out here
with the talent level
off the charts.
I mean, the acting thing
must help with the girls.
>> Girls and guys.
>> What with guys?
>> Well..
I mean..
>> Are -- gay?
Are you -- are you gay, dude?
I mean it's totally cool,
if you are.
>> I'm not into labels.
I don't know,
I...like whatever.
>> Cool.
Cool.
>> Scoop section
lists several approaches
to online privacy along with
the conventional wisdom
about each one..
>> Here you go.
>> Okay.
I've never taken
a muscle relaxant before.
Down the old hatch.
>> Yeah, man, it's a good buzz
when you booze.
>> Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm feeling it already.
>> Alright, so what,
you got married
uh, right after high school?
>> College, actually.
Yeah.
We, uh, got pregnant.
And then, uh, bought a house
down in Clarkstown.
It's a nice area,
you know.
>> Good schools.
Then, you married
Stacy Polster?
>> 14 years.
>> Wow.
She was cute.
>> Yeah.
>> She's no Holly James, but..
>> Oh.
>> Oh!
>> Fuck you, man. Holly James.
>> It's been a while
since I've heard that name.
>> I bet.
>> Oh.
Her pussy, man
>> Yeah?
>> So tight.
>> Ooh.
>> Like, almost too tight.
>> Oh, shit.
[grunts]
Hey.
She'll be there.
>> Where?
>> At the reunion.
You should come.
Fuck that tight pussy again.
>> She'll be
all over my shit, wouldn't she?
>> Totally.
>> No, no, no.
There's no way
I'm going to that.
>> No?
Okay.
[snorts]
Yeah.
Yeah, I don't really..
>> Okay. Make a fist.
>> Okay, here we go.
>> Here we go.
>> And we just
have to snort it? Yeah?
[snorts]
>> Alright. Here we go.
[upbeat music]
>> Holy shit.
Is that Dermot Mulroney?
>> Oh, yeah, that is Dermot.
>> Wait a second.
You -- you just
called him Dermot.
Are you guys friends?
>> Well...yeah.
>> That is so weird how you guys
all know each other.
>> Oh, he's big time,
but the business is small.
>> Small. Right.
You should go talk to him.
>> Yeah?
>> Yeah.
>> Nah, man.
>> Yeah, go.
>> Yeah, probably I should,
I should say hi.
>> Yeah.
>> Hey, what's up, buddy?
>> Oh, hey.
>> How you doing?
>> Uh, do we know each other?
>> Uh, no.
Uh, uh. No, no. No.
I'm -- I'm just
a big fan of your work.
>> Hey, thanks.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank -- thanks a lot.
>> I'm an actor too, so..
>> Right on, brother.
Um, it's great seeing you.
>> Ba -- Banana Boat ad
right now.
>> Cool.
>> Um..
Did you ever do
any commercials or..
>> No.
>> Okay.
>> No, I started in,
uh, studio films.
>> Films? Yeah.
Of course you did.
I've seen every one of them.
>> Thanks a lot.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Dermot Mulroney.
>> Yeah.
>> Good to see you.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> Oliver.
>> Yeah, oh, Oliver.
Yeah. Good to meet you, man.
>> Alright, now you guys..
...keep rockin'.
[laughter]
>> What happened?
What did he say?
>> He was just talking shit.
He wanted me to sit down.
I was like, "I gotta go, man.
My buddy's here, so.."
>> Oh.
>> You don't wanna get
caught up in that, man.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> He'll just, he'll eat up
your whole night.
>> Yeah?
>> Let's go have a drink.
>> Alright, yeah.
[telephone ringing]
>> Hello?
>> Hey, honey.
>> What are you doing?
It's...4 in the morning.
>> Oh, shit. I'm sorry.
Hey, did you see my Facebook?
I posted a new pic.
You gotta check it out.
Ugh, Dan, I'm sleeping.
>> Oh, please, please.
Just go down there
to the computer really quick,
honey, please?
>> Christ.
[sighs]
He's gotta be kidding me.
>> You on there yet?
Baby, you on there?
>> I just walked
into the living room.
Okay.
>> Are you on there now?
>> Wait, is that..
>> Yeah, it is.
Oliver Lawless.
I'm hanging out with him.
And you know, we just saw
Dermot Mulroney.
And he just seems like
a normal guy.
Just a totally regular dude.
>> Well, that's great, honey,
but what abo..
How was the meeting?
>> What meeting?
Oh, right, yeah.
Good, really, really good.
>> Okay, well,
so is it -- is it happening?
>> Uh, you know, it's close.
There's contingencies.
>> I'm cooked, man.
>> Oh, you're cooked.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay, I gotta go.
I'll talk to you tomorrow.
Love you, bye. Mwah.
>> Ugh.
>> Dude, I'm so happy.
>> Yeah.
>> Best night ever.
Best night ever.
>> Okay. It was great.
>> Can we do it again?
>> Absolutely, man.
Hey, take care.
>> Tomorrow night? Bring Dermot.
>> Alright, man.
Uh, yeah, I'll text you.
>> And the reunion?
>> Nah. Alright, brother.
[crickets chirping]
[cellphone ringing]
>> Hello?
What's up, man, you okay?
>> Yeah, can I come in?
>> Get in here.
>> Do you have a mini bar?
>> I don't think I have one.
>> Oh, fuck. Right here.
>> Is that what it is?
Yeah, help yourself.
>> Yes.
>> 15 bucks a bottle,
no big deal.
>> Mm.
>> I fucking
couldn't sleep, man.
>> Yeah, me neither.
[sighs]
>> Man, you ever feel like
you're just..
You're just lying to yourself?
>> What do you mean?
>> Well, when you lie
to yourself
you lie to the whole world.
And that's a shit heavy thing
to carry around.
>> It's like
do you ever feel like
you're so on the same page
with someone
that you don't even know
what to say to that person?
>> Huh?
>> Ask me why I'm here, Oliver.
Why I'm really here.
>> You're here for your
b -- business meeting, right?
>> Uh-huh.
That's what my wife thinks.
That's what my boss,
who's sleeping
right above us thinks.
But the truth is, I came here
to get you to come
to our high school reunion.
I'm on the alumni committee,
Oliver.
I'm actually chairman
of the damn thing.
>> Jesus.
>> And I told them..
...if I got you to come,
then everyone else would too.
>> You really think
they'd give a shit?
>> Are you kidding me?
They would shit themselves.
You're Oliver Lawless.
>> Yeah, whatever that means.
>> Okay.
Uh, do you know what I did
when I graduated high school?
>> Hmm..
>> I went to community college.
Down the street
from high school.
Took the first job I got.
I never left home.
I did what
every other asshole did.
But not you.
>> Hmm?
>> You said, "Fuck it."
You went after your dream.
>> Yeah.
>> And you fuckin' fulfilled it.
You're the Banana Boat's
spokesman? Excuse me?
Banging hot chicks
all over town.
Boys with Mulroney.
>> Mmm.
>> You are the best thing to
ever come out of Barkledge, bro.
By a long shot.
And if you come to this thing
you will be giving
those people
a gift that they will remember
for the rest
of their pathetic lives.
[scoffs]
>> So wait..
What'd you tell your boss?
>> Oh, no, no.
I'm so fucked.
I told..
I told him
that there's a CEO in town
that wants to work with us.
>> Why would you do that?
>> I didn't think he would come.
It's so stupid.
>> What are you
gonna do about it?
>> I don't know.
But he's gonna find out
that I made up the whole thing.
[inhales deeply]
>> Wait.
Maybe he doesn't have to.
>> And thank you, Mr. Drazen,
for reconsidering.
That's very kind of you.
>> Well, first of all
call me Kent.
Okay, let's just get
that right out of the way.
And can I just say?
This man is a superstar.
Did I tell you that already?
He -- he single-handedly
got me excited about this
and I don't get excited easy.
>> Yeah, that's Daniel.
>> Thanks, Mr. Drazen.
>> Now, let me tell you
why this deal
still isn't gonna happen.
>> Oh.
>> Ah.
>> I talked to the board
this morning.
We ran the numbers
forward and backward.
And -- I mean, we really wanted
to make this work
but sadly we are just
maxed out right now.
>> Damn.
>> Yep.
Now, here's what I propose.
We put a pin in it.
Alright?
We come back next fiscal.
When the flow's
a little healthier.
We revisit.
>> I like that.
That sounds good, thank you --
>> Uh, just hang, just hang on
one -- one second, Daniel.
Um, I won't be able to sleep
tonight if I don't say this
but there got to be some way
we could make this work.
>> Bill, you know,
they ran the numbers.
The numbers have been run.
>> Sorry.
I'm very sorry.
[sighs]
>> Um...how about
if we cut our fee?
Alright? 25%.
>> That's very generous,
but, uh,
I'm afraid this still
won't get it done.
>> 50%.
>> Whoa.
>> Bill, can we even --
>> Shh!
>> Alright.
>> Come on, Kent.
We both know
this deal makes sense.
And this guy..
...I mean, he can deliver.
So, um, I -- I just don't know
how you can say no to this deal?
>> Mm-hmm.
[Oliver exhales]
Man, I don't know what to say.
>> Say yes.
>> Okay, you got yourself
a deal.
>> Yes. Excellent.
[chuckles]
>> This feels right.
This makes sense.
>> Wow.
You see?
Okay, um..
Okay, well, I'm shaking.
[laughs]
>> I'm a little shaky as well.
[both laughing]
>> I'm gonna get
the best champagne
this place has.
>> Whoa.
>> Alright.
Fuck me!
That was awesome!
>> Wow.
>> I mean, we just had
it back and forth.
It was like it just
fucking evolved, you know.
>> That was great.
That was great.
>> I didn't go too far, did I?
>> I mean,
that felt natural to me.
>> Yeah, I mean, you know,
the part where you accepted
the deal might have been
a little bit.
>> Yeah, but, Dan, it was real.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> If I said no, it would've
been false, totally false.
He would have seen
right through it.
>> Uh, maybe.
I mean..
I was buying the whole
out of cash argument.
>> God!
It was fucking good, man.
> No, well, I mean..
Nah, nah, nah, Dan. That's fine.
You get to look great.
Nobody gets hurt.
>> Oh, but, Bill..
>> What? You kidding me?
Look at him.
He's having the time
of his life.
Guy couldn't be happier.
>> Yeah.
>> Come on, look.
We're in the catbird seat. Okay?
We can pull the plug
whenever we want.
Either way there's no deal.
Just get that in your head.
No deal.
>> Okay.
>> Why don't we
sit for a little bit?
Have a little fun with it.
I don't know.
You know?
>> Yeah.
I mean, maybe you're right.
>> Maybe I'm right?
Fuck you.
Damn right I'm right!
Damn right I'm right.
Now, we're gonna celebrate.
>> Okay.
>> We're gonna drink
some bubbly..
>> Yes, and then..
>> ...and have a good time.
...tomorrow you call him
and say..
>> Yeah, whatever,
we don't wanna do it.
Yeah. A week from now,
we'll do it tomorrow.
>> No rush.
>> But right now, we're
not gonna think about it.
>> Probably the sooner
the better.
>> We're celebrating!
[The Vapors singing
"Turning Japanese"]
¶ I've got your picture.. ¶
[laughing]
¶ I wrote me too ¶
¶ I sit there staring
and there's nothing else to do ¶
>> You don't know who that is?
>> I don't.
>> You haven't seen
his national commercial spot?
>> No.
>> Banana Boat.
He's the Banana Boat guy.
That's the fucking guy!
>> Hey!
>> That guy is this guy
and this guy is that guy.
¶ ...your picture ¶
¶ I'd like a million of them
all round my cell ¶
¶ I want a doctor
to take your picture ¶
[snorts]
We're friends from high school.
¶ ...I'm turning Japanese
I think I'm turning Japanese ¶
¶ I really think so ¶
¶ Turning Japanese
I think I'm turning Japanese ¶
>> What's up, A-time.
>> A-time.
>> Come on.
[bell rings]
>> Go on.
[grunts]
¶ Turning Japanese I think
I'm turning Japanese.. ¶¶
Whoa!
Aah!
Time out.
[bell rings]
>> Billy, K.D. here.
Listen, man, just wanted to say
it was a pleasure meeting you
and, uh, I look forward to
doing some biz. Drazen out.
>> Aah!
[music continues]
>> Hey, ladies!
[girls screaming]
>> Give me that.
>> That's so good.
>> No, no, no, no.
Come on. The coke.
>> Oh, the coke. Oh, sorry.
>> Yeah, right there..
Alright, cool. Thank you.
>> Alright.
Oh.
[laughs]
[laughing]
>> Oh, fuck!
>> Oh, my God.
[Dan laughing]
>> Dude..
[laughing]
...I haven't had a night
like that in a long time.
>> Oh, man, I -- I had
such a blast too.
[sighs]
>> Dan..
...thank you, man.
>> Oh, thank you, man.
>> Come here.
>> Hmm?
Oh, alright.
[laughing]
>> I'll come to reunion.
>> Oh, my God.
[groans]
[engine revving]
>> Hey, bro.
>> Hey.
>> It was fun last night, yeah?
>> Yeah.
>> You want some coffee
or something?
>> Uh, no, no, I'm -- I'm good.
[cellphone vibrating]
>> Oh, gee, I hate this.
What's up, babe?
What are you doin'?
Just waking up.
Yeah, left my phone back..
Sorry, babe.
What did you get
into last night?
Yeah, it was fun.
>> Uh, shirt?
>> Second drawer.
Yeah.
[sighs]
I texted you.
Fuck you.
You're full of shit.
Check your phone.
Babe...how was it?
Ah, come on, baby, not again.
It's too early
for this shit.
Yeah, nothin'.
>> I gotta..
>> Just give me a sec.
>> My plane.
>> What?
Hang on a sec.
Alright, man.
Just come pick me up.
We can go from here.
It doesn't matter..
[airplane droning]
>> Mimosa?
Mimosa?
>> Wow, wow, wow.
What a trip, huh?
Closin' that deal
like the old days, huh?
>> Mimosa?
>> Here we go.
One of the perks
of first class travel.
>> Mimosa.
>> You earned it, Dan boy.
>> Mimosa?
[instrumental music]
>> Congratulations.
Bill must be thrilled.
Did you ask for a raise?
>> Not yet. It's just happened.
>> Well, you gotta
ask him about it.
This is all because of you.
>> I know, I will.
>> And what about Lawless?
Did you get him to come?
>> What?
>> Is he gonna come
to the reunion?
>> Possibly.
I mean..
...he wants to,
but it's a big expense.
Have to fly him out here
and put him up.
>> What's this?
>> Hmm?
>> There are no buttons
on this shirt.
>> Huh? That's weird.
Were there buttons on them
when you bought it?
>> Yes, I wouldn't buy
a shirt without buttons.
>> So what goes on now?
People just try shit on
and then throw it on the ground?
Step on stuff
and buttons come off
and then just put
on the rack and sell it?
>> Okay, I'll return
it tomorrow.
>> Are you gonna say somethin'?
'Cause something needs
to be said to the manager.
>> 'Cause that's fucking
bullshit.
>> It's Lawless.
>> Olli. D-Smooth.
What's up, my brother?
Hey, that was some
fuckin' fun ass shit
out there in LA.
The LA. It's like
uh, a great place, shit.
So, yeah, give me a call back.
I wanna talk reunion with you.
I -- I'm feeling like
the more I think about it
the -- the lamer it gets,
you know, I'm..
I don't know,
I'm thinking about bailin'
on the whole thing
to be honest with you.
Who needs to see all those..
...clowns.
So, yeah, give me a call back.
I'll shoot you an SMS as well.
Alright. Peace, bro.
What's goin' on here?
What is all this stuff?
>> These are
brand new computers.
Top of the line,
just what you wanted.
>> Oh.
>> Puttin' the Dan plan
into action.
We're gonna give this office
a face lift.
Hip up the place.
>> Well, that's great
but do you think maybe
we're getting ahead
of ourselves a little bit?
I mean, what if the deal
falls through or somethin'.
I mean, we haven't even signed
the paperwork yet?
>> No, no, no.
It's as good as done.
I'm a very good judge of people
and I -- I -- I trust Drazen.
>> Yeah, I do too --
>> And guess what?
I sent Dale Harkin an email.
>> Get the fuck outta here.
>> I did. I told him
about the Drazen deal
and I told him
about what's going on here
and he wants another meeting.
Oh, man, you -- you scored.
Danny, I'm so proud
of you, bucko.
>> Oh, thanks.
>> Come on, enjoy.
This is for you.
You feel good?
>> Yeah, I'm startin'
to feel good.
[indistinct chatter]
[all applauding]
What's this?
>> Dan, uh, let me just start
by suckin' a little
shit here.
Lawless RSVP'd.
>> And then a bunch
of others RSVP'd.
>> Yeah, and I turned
several no's into maybes.
>> Several no's
now maybes 'cause of you,
your plan.
>> Well, you know,
thanks, guys, but --
>> We doubted you, pal.
We wanna apologize for that.
>> Should we just skip
this bullshit and go celebrate?
>> Yeah. Yeah, we should.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Alright, yeah.
> I think you can do it, dude.
>> Good job, Dan.
>> You, big man.
>> So walk us through it.
How did you do it?
You go out there.
You give him a call.
>> He answers, you say what?
>> Yeah, it sounds like
you turned him, Dan?
>> You know, it's
a very delicate dance, guys.
It was just, I think,
you know, the key
was makin' it seem like
it was his idea.
>> Ah. How?
>> How?
>> Exactly.
>> Yeah, how exactly
did you do that?
>> You know, I don't
even really remember it.
I just sort of flipped
the script.
Sort of like
reverse psychology
and, uh, a subtle --
I did
then all of a sudden he was
eatin' out of the palm
of my hand.
"Oh, dude,
when is it deem -- slice.
W -- w -- what do I wear?"
I said, "Calm down.
It's not for few weeks.
We'll be in touch."
But, fuck, he's been blowin' me
up ever since.
[all cheering]
[both moaning]
>> Whoa!
>> I...yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Whoa. Wow.
>> Yeah? Yeah? Yeah?
>> Wow.
[sighs]
We should do that more often.
Well, what are those?
>> Oh, uh, CK.
Boxer brief hybrid. You like?
>> Yeah, they are really cute.
Look at that tush.
[Chromeo singing
"Play The Fool"]
¶ Don't let me play
the fool yeah ¶
¶ And get carried away ¶
¶ Carried away ¶
¶ Don't let me play
the fool yeah ¶
¶ And get carried away ¶¶
[indistinct radio chatter]
[both chuckling]
>> Just the cutest..
>> So, Heather,
you like Zach, huh?
>> Dad?
>> I do.
>> Mm-hmm?
What do you like about him?
>> Well, I think he's funny.
He's smart.
Super hot.
[cellphone rings]
>> Dad, the phone?
>> Zach, I know. I'm getting it.
[exhales]
What's up, dude?
>> Huh.
>> My son's in the car.
What's goin' on, dawg?
You get my VM?
>> No, man, I don't
check those.
>> Uh, cool.
>> Hey, Mr. Lawless,
I love your commercial.
>> Okay, just hang on
one sec, Oliver.
[tires screeching]
Get out of the car,
both of you.
>> But why?
>> Just for a second.
I'm gonna finish the call,
then you can get back in.
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
>> Alright, alright.
You've put the child lock on.
>> God dang!
>> Thank you.
>> And close the door,
close the door behind you.
Close the door.
Sorry about that. Where were we?
>> I have no idea.
>> Oh, yeah,
I know the, uh, reunion.
Yeah, what do you think?
Should we bail?
>> Bail? Why?
No, man, I'm down.
>> Yeah, I -- I could be down.
I could be down.
It's just...my head keeps on
going back to when we were in LA
partying and saying how fucking
stupid it was, right?
I mean, you even said there's
no way you would go.
You remember sayin' that?
>> Yeah, but then you kinda
sold me on it.
I mean, Holly James.
Thought it'll be fun to crash
with you and Stacey.
>> Ooh, yeah. It's just, uh..
Mmm. Do we have the room,
the baby..
>> No, worries.
I'll just stay at Craig's.
>> Oh, you guys talked?
>> Yeah, he says
he's got plenty of room.
>> You know what?
I'm sure we can make it happen.
Have you stay with us.
Unless that's weird.
>> No, why would that
be weird?
>> Yeah. No, it's not.
[knocks on window]
[no audio]
>> Alright, man, either way.
>> Or yeah, just the way
we just said.
[phone beeps]
Hello.
Okay. Okay, alright. Come on.
Let's go.
Let's go!
Come on, guys!
[instrumental music]
There he is.
See my sign?
Like I'm your driver.
>> Where are we? Which way?
>> This way.
Alright, I'll just put it
put it over here
if anyone needs it.
>> Care if I smoke?
>> Not at all. God no.
Ah, please, go on ahead.
Mind if I bum one?
I mean, unless you're low.
Thank you, kindly.
Uh, make yourself
comfortable, yeah.
>> Alright.
>> Hey, uh, real quick,
just to clear up any..
What happened in LA..
...if we could just keep that..
>> Oh. Oh, yeah.
Yeah, of course.
>> Cool.
I mean, I don't even know
what that..
>> Dan, it's in the past.
>> Hmm.
>> Let's have a fun weekend.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, absolutely.
>> That's where we did.
Where else
were we gonna hang out?
>> Yeah, I don't know
how you did it, man
but you bagged yourself
a good one.
Yeah, I had a huge crush on her.
>> What?
>> Okay.
>> You didn't.
>> Come on, you knew.
>> No.
>> Yeah, you knew.
I would stare at you everyday
in that class that we had.
>> Oh.
>> Remember with
the freak teacher?
He wears fucking pants
up to here.
>> Oh, right, what was his name?
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, Mil something.
>> Milman?
>> Milton. Jesus.
>> Oh.
>> Dad, can I ask you something?
>> Yeah, yeah.
In -- in a bit, Zach.
>> Milburk?
>> Milhorn.
Milhorn.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
That's right. Milhorn.
[laughs]
Ah, the memories...
with the pants.
Milhorn.
>> Were you in that class?
>> We had that other class
together, remember, too?
Which one was that?
>> Um..
I don't, I don't know, man.
>> Drama. That's what it was.
And that teacher
was a character.
>> Was she?
>> What was her name?
>> Spicer.
>> Yes, Spicer, thank you.
>> It's amazing.
>> She remembers all the things.
>> Okay, I had to ask
you something.
Jenny Lehmer.
>> Oh, God.
>> She said that you guys
hooked up. Was that true?
>> Let me tell you
what happened with Jenny.
>> Uh-oh.
>> She's, like, always
passin' me these notes..
>> It's Heather.
She's maybe too fast.
>> Shh.
>> She follows me
into the locker room.
>> Oh, shit.
>> She told me
about the locker room.
>> I'm getting ready
to do some crazy shit.
>> Uh-oh.
>> She wants to have sex
and she wants it
to be threesome.
What do I do?
>> Zach, not now!
>> What's the matter?
>> Nothing. Zach's just..
It's fine. What -- what's
the rest of the, uh..
>> Zach? Is he upset?
>> I don't know.
>> You alright?
>> I'll go check on him.
>> No, honey,
Oliver's mid story.
>> Zach?
>> I can tell that story
anytime. It's no big deal.
>> Zach?
Honey? Are you crying?
Zach is really upset.
You should talk to him.
It's a girl stuff. He's not
gonna talk to me about it.
>> Okay, I will.
So what was up
with the whole Spicer thing?
>> What?
>> You came in
with the name right away.
>> What are you talking about?
>> You guys were tryin'
to think of Milhorn's name
going back and forth,
but then when Oliver
and I were tryin'
to do the drama teacher
you just came out and said it.
You killed the whole thing.
>> Killed what whole thing?
I knew her name.
>> I knew Milhorn's, but I still
let you have fun with it.
>> What is going on
with you exactly?
>> What?
>> You are acting so weird.
>> How am I acting weird?
>> Dan, Wi-Fi password?
>> What? It's easier
if I do it for him.
>> Yes, go.
>> There's lots of numbers
and letters, case sensitive.
[sighs]
[game beeping]
>> Hey, man.
>> Oh, hey, what's up?
I'm just, uh --
>> I just got off the phone
with your boss.
>> What? He called you?
>> Yeah, man, he called..
Oh, dude.
>> Oh, yeah, yeah, sorry.
So how did he get your number?
>> He said he had it from
when I left him that message.
>> He learned how to check
his recent calls.
Fuck, he's getting smarter.
What did he say?
>> He wanted to know
where we were at?
Whether or not
he should send paperwork?
>> Shit!
>> Yeah, this is
out of control, man.
Now, he is callin' me.
You gotta put this
into bed today.
>> Oh, today?
I was gonna hang with you.
I already called in sick.
>> No, no, no, man.
You gotta handle this.
It's uncool.
>> W -- wait. Oliver?
Are you mad at me?
>> What?
No, I'm not mad at you.
I just can't have him
callin' me, you know?
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, it was fine in LA.
Now, it's just weird.
>> It is weird.
Totally.
>> Fix it, dude.
>> Got it.
I -- I -- I'm on it.
Consider it done.
[instrumental music]
>> She doesn't sleep,
that's the problem.
When she does.. Dan?
[music continues]
>> So we move a mouse
to the search bar.
>> This is --
this is the mouse?
>> That's the mouse.
>> We click
and the cursor will appear.
So we just type Bill..
>> Lower case?
>> Enter search bar here.
>> My screen looks different.
>> Sorry to interrupt.
Bill, can I steal you
for one second? It's important.
>> Yeah. Can you just
give me 5 minutes, please?
>> Yeah, I'll be right
outside the door.
>> I think I hit..
>> Would you help him please?
>> Enter.
>> Oh.
>> Return.
>> And click "Search."
[instrumental music]
>> Hey, you alright?
[sighs]
What's with the pink?
>> Well, this is
my sister's room.
My dad made me move in
since you were comin'.
>> That sucks.
I could have stayed at Craig's.
You should have told him
to fuck off.
>> I would never..
>> Well, sometimes
you got to, man.
>> Everybody's got their line
in the sand, you know?
>> Right.
>> Alright, what else you got?
>> Well, my girlfriend Heather?
>> Mm-hmm.
>> She wants
to have a threesome.
>> Guy or girl?
>> Girl.
>> Okay.
So what's the problem?
>> I'm nervous.
>> About what?
>> I think she thinks
I'm more experienced than I am.
>> How many girls
have you fucked?
>> None.
>> Why?
>> Well, I'm 14.
>> Uh-huh.
What'd your dad say?
You talked to him about it?
>> I've tried.
I feel like he's weird
about sex stuff.
>> Yeah.
>> He thinks you should
only have sex with someone
if you love them.
[sighs]
>> You know what I think?
I think you should find a way
of loving both these girls.
Simultaneously.
>> Hey, uh, what's goin' on?
I'm in the middle
of my internet class.
>> Did you call..
Wait. What internet class?
>> Well, I gotta learn
how to use these machines.
Steve just taught us how to
search for someone on Google.
>> Okay, first of all, I'm not
even sure that's the best way
to search for stuff.
Google has kind of
a dated thing, you know?
It all depends on
what web browser you are using
and if the, uh,
search engine is compatible.
I don't wanna confuse --
>> Hold on, didn't you --
didn't you call in sick?
>> Yeah, I'm, uh, I'm fine.
I'm feeling much better.
Did you call Drazen?
>> Daniel, I cannot afford
to get sick now.
>> You're not gonna get sick.
Did you call Drazen?
>> Yeah, I call -- I called him
just to check in.
What's wrong?
I was just -- just checking in.
>> Okay, I really wish
you would run that
kinda thing by me first.
It turns out
he did not love that call.
>> Oh, why?
>> Because he's been dealing
with me.
Exclusively. He's been, you
know, communicating with me.
We got a rapport and now,
he just seems really rattled.
>> Damn it, Bill.
I'm sorry.
>> It's okay. It's just I feel
bad you spent all this money.
>> Can you fix it, please?
Please?
>> I don't know. I'll try.
But I doubt it.
He's genuinely pissed.
But I'll try.
>> I thank you.
And again, I'm sorry,
I just blew it.
>> But no more calls.
>> You know what?
I'm not calling anyone.
>> Okay.
>> Ever.
God damn it.
Sorry, guys.
>> So you're kissin'
Heather, right?
>> Uh-huh.
>> Focus on her.
She's number 1. You don't
let her forget that.
But you also now want
the other girl.
What's the other girl's name?
>> Jill.
>> Jill. Now, you don't want
Jill to feel left out.
>> Of course.
>> Alright?
So you're gonna do
one these guys.
>> Okay, that makes sense.
>> Okay? Now, let's say,
things are heating up.
Clothes start comin' off.
We're fucking.
Obviously you got one cock.
So you can't do 'em both
at the same time, right?
>> Right.
>> We wanna try
and get as close as possible.
>> How?
>> You stack 'em.
You know, man, like,
lawn chairs, one on top
of the other.
>> Like lawn chairs?
>> Think about it.
Visualize it.
Works.
>> Uh, okay.
>> Oh, hey.
Don't forget. Wear a condom.
>> Right.
>> Then, rip that thing off.
Hose down those lawn chairs.
>> Sure.
[instrumental music]
>> It's Lawless.
>> Yo, yo, yo.
What's up, dawg?
It's the D man.
Just wanted you to know,
the Bill's itch? Handled, dawg.
You will not be receiving
another call from him,
of that I can assure you, sir.
Headin' out of the office now.
Guess I'll see you back
at the crib.
And we gotta figure out what
we're gonna get into tonight.
You and me, playa.
Okay. Cool.
Late.
>> So what did he say exactly?
He was going --
>> He didn't say.
They were just going out.
>> They?
>> Yeah.
Craig already came by
to pick him up.
We all had a drink together
and then they left.
I said that you would
text him when you got home.
>> Yeah, I've been texting,
Stace. I've been texting.
>> It's Lawless.
>> Hey, um, it's getting late.
I guess you're still out.
Not getting texts.
If you could just let me know
maybe ballpark
wherein you're gonna..
Or whatever.
I can just leave
a key under the mat.
The one right at the front door.
I'll leave it under there.
Alright.
Hope you're having fun.
Goodnight, Oliver.
[instrumental music]
[tires screeching]
>> Whoo!
[man laughing]
[engine revving]
[indistinct chatter]
[laughing continues]
Oh, man, this is
our night, okay.
Bye, Craig.
[indistinct chatter]
[engine revving]
>> Later.
>> Looking good.
>> Later, dudes.
[glass shatters]
>> I don't know
if he'll kill me.
>> Don't worry about it.
[indistinct chatter]
>> Oh.
[moaning]
[knocking on door]
Shit. Are we being too loud?
>> A little.
>> Okay.
Sorry, bro.
We'll try and keep it down.
>> Actually...hi.
>> Hi.
>> Can I talk to you
for a second?
>> Right now?
>> Mmm.
>> Yeah, man.
[grunts]
What's up? Sorry.
>> So...is everything okay..
...between us?
>> What do you mean?
>> Uh, I don't know, I'm just
feeling a little
bit of a distance.
[Dan sighs]
Has something changed
that I'm not aware of?
I mean, maybe we
should talk about it.
I don't know,
we haven't really
talked about what happened.
>> Oh..
I mean, I'm kind of in the
middle of something, you know?
Hey, sit down.
Uh, fuck me.
Dan, LA was fun.
>> We did it up.
>> Mm-hmm.
>> But it was a one time thing.
>> Oh, yeah. I know, totally.
I -- I -- I don't want
that to happen again.
I need you to know that.
I'm not...gay.
>> I'm not, either.
>> Right. I mean, I'm married,
I have a family..
>> Exactly.
>> But, but -- but..
...uh, w -- what if we were
in like an alternate universe
where I wasn't?
>> Why does it matter?
>> I don't know.
>> Dan...go to sleep.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
[rustling]
>> Ow.
Ow. Dan.
Jesus! No!
I'm sleeping. Get off of me.
>> Sorry. Sorry.
>> It's delish.
>> Oh, I just put
it together, guys.
>> Home cooking, man.
I miss it.
>> Aw, stop.
>> Lying in
the tall grass..
>> Good morning.
>> You just stay focused.
We got a big night.
>> What's going on here?
>> What's up, buddy?
Hey, man. You remember Alyssa.
>> Hi there.
>> Yeah.
All cleaned up.
So, uh, what were
we laughing about?
>> Z-Bone's got himself
a big night lined up.
>> Z -- Z-Bone?
What is that?
>> Nickname I gave the kid.
>> I don't think
that works at all.
>> He's going to have
his first threesome.
>> What?
[laughs]
>> Right? I mean, I was
16 before I did that.
>> Did what?
>> Nothing.
>> Uh-oh.
[laughs]
Alyssa, would you
like some potatoes?
>> Mmm. Yes. I would love some.
Thank you, Stacey.
>> Hey, man, he's ready to go.
>> So, where is this
supposed to go down?
>> At Heather's. Tomorrow night.
>> Uh-huh. And where
are her parents?
>> Oh, they are going
to be at your reunion.
>> Oh, they are? That's perfect.
>> Yeah, it actually is.
>> So, I'm just the last
to find out about this?
>> No, man. Stace doesn't know.
>> Please don't tell her, dad.
>> Hey, he's not
gonna tell her, dude.
He's cool.
>> Yeah, I'm cool.
But I should have
known about this.
>> I tried to tell you
but you wouldn't listen.
So I asked Oliver.
>> Oh, so you encouraged this?
>> Yeah, why wouldn't I?
>> He's 14.
>> What are you gettin'
so upset about, Dan?
You should be celebrating this.
He's a stud.
[Alyssa and Oliver laughing]
>> You know what?
I want you out of here.
>> What?
>> You heard me.
I want you out of this house!
>> Dan!
>> D -- S -- Stacey,
this does not concern you!
>> It's okay, Stacey.
>> No, but it's not okay!
>> It is okay!
>> Maybe I overstayed
my welcome.
>> I'm gonna get my things
and crash at Craig's.
>> I am so sorry, Oliver.
Dan, what is
the matter with you?
>> So sorry..
>> So you can see that the
ladies are on the dance floor
underneath this
beautiful railing.
If you get a chance later,
have a free moment of time
come and check out the model.
It's almost to scale.
>> Uh, if you actually
could hold on that
for a second, Louise?
Thank you so much.
Uh, I just got
a text from Lawless
and he needs the password
to the Facebook page.
>> Uh..
>> What does he need it for?
>> Oh, Jesus Christ.
>> He wants to post a photo
of us from last night.
Who gives a fuck?
>> Dan, you're not the
gatekeeper of the Facebook page.
Please give him the password.
>> Oliver is not
a committee member, Lucy.
>> Yeah, but Craig is.
>> But he's just gonna
give it to him, Jerry.
>> No, I won't give it to him.
Because I can only
give it to people
who are on the committee.
>> Okay, everyone
heard him say that.
You're on record.
>> Uh..
[sighs]
>> Okay, fine.
R...E..
...U...N..
...I..
...O..
...N.
>> It's reunion?
>> With three exclaims
on the end.
>> Good password.
Randy, come take a look.
[laughing]
>> Oh, look. He's doing it.
>> Uh, no, we're talking
about something else entirely.
>> Oh, really?
What are you talking about?
>> Just give me a second.
>> Wish I had Facebook.
[laughing]
>> Me too.
>> Okay, you know what?
This has gone off the rails
and, uh, what are we doing?
We're giving passwords
to non-committee members
we're letting them upload
unauthorized photos.
>> Dan, I'm gonna
ask you to calm down.
>> Lucy, I'm totally calm.
What the fuck is going on here?
This is ridiculous. Okay?
It's one guy and we're
gonna build the whole
fucking thing around him?
>> It was your idea.
>> What the fuck?
Wha -- wha -- what
the fuck do you care?
Renina, you never ever
talk, and now you pipe in?
>> She's right, Dan. We --
>> Okay, so what?
So I made a mistake. Am I not
allowed to make a mistake?
Am I not human?
This reunion is for everybody.
It's for all of us!
Not just him!
God!
[sighs]
[laughs]
Okay. Announcement.
I think I'm out, guys.
>> Alright, man.
>> No, I mean, out out.
>> No, we get it.
We know what you meant.
>> You know,
it's honestly fine.
I mean,
all the work's done, so..
>> Okay.
>> Anyway..
[Ace Of Base singing
"Don't Turn Around"]
>> What that?
>> Yeah, look, and then.
[laughing]
>> Is there a picture
of just me and him?
¶ If you wanna leave ¶
¶ I won't beg you to stay ¶
¶ And if you gotta go darling ¶
¶ Maybe it's better that way ¶¶
[knock on door]
>> Hey, Daniel.
>> Hey, Bill.
[music stops]
>> Are you okay?
>> A lot of stuff, Bill.
>> Yeah, well, I hate to pile on
more, but, um, we got a problem
because I am...I am 90% sure
that this is not
the guy we met with.
And I do not know
what is going on.
But I think we're
being duped in some way.
And see w..
...when I click this
like Steve said
the picture stays the same.
Now, if I could enlarge this
then we would know who this is.
But I...I can't..
I don't know. There's
no way to enlarge this.
>> Yeah, there's no
way to enlarge it.
>> Right?
[sighs]
Fuck.
Maybe if I hit this.
[laptop keys clacking]
No.
>> Bill.
>> Yeah.
>> There is a way to enlarge it.
>> That's not him.
>> No. It isn't.
And Google is a great
way to search for stuff.
It's actually the best
engine out there.
>> What?
>> And you can add someone
to an email chain at any point.
It's so easy.
>> Daniel, what's going on?
>> I lied to you.
There's no deal in LA.
Kent Drazen isn't real.
The guy you met, his
name is Oliver Lawless.
And he was the coolest guy
in my high school and..
...I just wanted
to go out there
and convince him
to come to the reunion.
>> You faked a deal?
So you could...
take a trip to LA?
Why didn't you just buy
a ticket and go on the weekend?
>> Yeah. Yeah.
In retrospect, that would
have been a lot easier.
But I needed an excuse
for my wife, so..
>> Okay. I got you.
So couldn't you
have just told her
it was a business trip and..
...and left me out of it?
>> I could have. I could have.
I could have done that.
[sighs]
Actually, I'm not sure
why I didn't.
[sighs]
So what now?
I mean, I assume I'm fired.
>> Fired from what?
I don't even know if we
have a company anymore?
>> Right.
>> I spent so much money..
>> I know, right. Right.
I don't know
what to say, Bill.
I mean, I'm so sorry.
I never meant for
it to go this far.
>> You know what's funny?
I actually liked Drazen.
>> I did too.
>> Yeah, you know
it just felt good, you know
chasing the big fish
again, you know.
>> He liked you, Bill.
That was real.
>> It wasn't real.
>> Well, right, I mean he
wasn't really Drazen, but..
>> Did you get him?
>> Who?
>> Your friend, Lawless.
>> I got him.
>> Good.
>> Bill...are we cool?
>> Have fun
at the reunion, Daniel.
[Erasure singing
"A Little Respect"]
¶ I try to discover ¶
¶ A little something
to make me sweeter ¶
¶ Oh baby refrain.. ¶
>> Ready?
>> Yep.
¶ I'll be forever blue ¶
¶ That you give me no reason ¶
¶ Why you're making
me work so hard ¶
¶ That you give me no.. ¶¶
>> Dan, this is gorgeous.
>> Stacey Poster.
>> Oh, my God!
>> Wendy Fleur.
>> How are you?
>> I'm good. Um, it's actually,
uh, Stacey Landsman now.
You remember Dan?
>> Hi, Wendy.
>> Hi.
>> Math, Spanish and chemistry.
>> Oh.
>> I'm gonna go get some drinks.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Perfect.
>> Thanks. Just a white wine.
>> Yeah, um, two.
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
>> Yeah, Lawless crew.
[laughs]
>> Hey.
>> Dan.
>> Dale Harken.
>> What's up, buddy?
>> We're gonna be seeing
you next week, right?
>> Hey, I hear big things
are happening over there.
You know, uh, Sherman tried
to FaceTime me the other day.
I didn't even know
the old man had a phone.
>> Yeah.
>> Hey, did I, uh..
...did I hear right?
You got Lawless here?
>> Yeah, I might have had
somethin' to do with that.
>> Nice job, dude.
Oh, man.
Hey, not to sound
gay or anything
but I always thought
he was just the shit.
Like I would've done anything to
have been his friend, you know?
>> Yeah.
>> Anyway, let's get
fucked up, right?
>> Yeah.
[Inxs singing
"Never Tear Us Apart"]
¶ Don't ask me ¶
¶ What you know is true ¶
¶ Don't have to tell you ¶
¶ I love your precious.. ¶
>> Hey, Dan.
>> Hey, fuckin' A,
guys, you did it.
¶ I was standing ¶
¶ You were there ¶
¶ Two worlds collided ¶
¶ And they could
never tear us apart ¶
[instrumental music]
¶ We could live ¶
¶ For a thousand years ¶
¶ But if I hurt you ¶
¶ I'd make wine
from your tears ¶
¶ I told you ¶
¶ That we could fly ¶
¶ 'Cause we all have wings ¶
¶ But some of us
don't know why ¶
¶ I was standing ¶
¶ You were there ¶¶
[indistinct singing]
>> How you doin'?
>> I'm fucking great.
How are you doin'?
>> Smoking?
>> You know, whatever, I smoke
when I drink, sometimes
I'll have a smoke.
What -- what's the big deal?
>> Are you okay?
>> I'm fucking great.
It's a party. You know what?
I'm partyin'.
Just loosen the fuck up.
>> Who are you right now?
You're wasted!
You're obsessed with Oliver.
Wearin' the same
underwear as him.
>> How do you know what
kind of underwear he wears?
You fuckin' him?
>> What?
I did his laundry, Dan.
[indistinct singing]
[music continues]
[door closes]
[groans]
>> Dan.
>> Jerry.
>> Was that cocaine?
>> Come here.
>> Okay.
>> Jerry, Jerry, Jerry.
Let me ask you somethin'.
How about this?
D-Nice.
>> What?
>> Have people just call
me that from now on?
>> Uh, I don't know.
It feels forced.
>> It's a little bit forced.
That's what I was thinkin' too.
Okay, come on,
give me some options.
Pitch me out some new ones.
>> I don't know.
You just have to find what
works for you, you know?
Like me, it's -- it's J-Dawg.
It's obvious.
>> Fuck.
You've got it all
figured out, don't you?
Don't you?
>> Uh..
I don't know. I don't think.
>> You have such
an easy life, J-Dawg.
>> Let's go back
to the party, okay?
>> Yeah, let's get back in.
J-Dawg wants back in.
[laughing]
Why wouldn't he?
[door opens]
[instrumental music]
>> Whoo-hoo!
Holly James!
Lovebirds back together.
>> Who is this guy?
>> You alright, Dan?
[mumbles]
>> Is that it?
You're not gonna say hi?
You're here because of me
and you're not gonna say hi?
That's pretty fuckin' rude.
>> Why don't you go sit down
for a little bit, buddy?
>> How was Craig's house?
>> Bye, Dan.
>> You're gonna fuck that pussy?
That tight puss?
He said you have one.
Probably not
anymore though, right?
Probably gotten a little loose.
>> Alright, let's go.
>> What are you doin'?
>> Excuse us for a sec.
>> Where are we goin'?
Are you gonna..
We're gonna go
talk over there? Ow!
Why do you gotta
squeeze so hard, huh?
Ah!
>> What are you doin'?
What's happening?
I mean, we..
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Can we..
Can we start over?
Let's just start over.
>> Start what over?
>> Hey.
I'm Dan Landsman.
We went to high school and never
had sex with each other.
>> Dan, go home.
>> What? No, no, no. Come on.
Wait. Wait, what..
>> Why can't we just talk?
>> There's nothin'
to talk about, Dan.
>> Oh, really? 'Cause I think
there is stuff to talk about.
Why won't you talk to me?
Talk to me, Oliver!
>> Okay.
What do you wanna
talk about, Dan?
>> You know what
I wanna talk about.
>> Yeah?
And what do you wanna hear? Huh?
You wanna hear that
I wanna be with you?
>> What, Oliver, wait,
why did the music stop?
>> Would that do it
for you, Dan? Tell me.
You wanna hear that I can't stop
thinkin' about when we fucked?
>> No, no. Outside.
>> That I'm rock hard right now
just thinkin' about it?
How's that?
Oh, Dan, I can't wait to get
my dick back in your mouth.
I'm so dying to make you come,
since you didn't last time.
How's that? Maybe that's
what you're lookin' for.
>> Oliver --
>> No, no, no, let's
fuckin' talk, man!
You wanted to do this.
Let's talk.
Let's get some closure.
How do we end this?
How's this?
It meant nothing to me.
You weren't even a blip
on my fuckin' radar.
Goddammit, Dan.
>> Jesus Christ.
[indistinct chatter]
[car engine revving]
[grunts]
[exhales]
[baby cooing]
>> Dan.
I need you to
take Zach to school.
>> I'm on it.
I'll just..
[door closes]
[sighs]
So, uh..
...how was your...three-way?
>> Didn't happen.
>> Oh, damn. It was a prank.
>> No, dad. It just wasn't me.
>> Look, I know..
...I've been
a little absent lately.
You've tried to talk
to me about this stuff..
I just want you to know, you
can talk to me about whatever.
And I wanna talk
to you about some things.
>> Like how you
had sex with Oliver?
[school bell rings]
[Dan sighs]
>> You heard.
>> How did it even --
>> I don't know, buddy.
We were out in Los Angeles,
one thing led to another.
I mean, you know,
these things happen.
>> They do?
>> Yeah, you'll see.
When you're older,
a lot of different factors
come into play.
I mean, a lot
of it had to with..
>> Dad, are y -- you okay?
[Dan crying]
It's -- it's okay.
It'll be okay.
>> Uh, I fucked up.
I really fucked up.
Mommy hates me.
>> I don't think she hates you.
I just think maybe --
>> She does.
>> Maybe she's just
weirded out.
>> Are you?
>> I mean, yeah.
It's messed up.
>> Well, what do I do?
>> I don't know.
Figure it out with mom?
>> Will you come with me?
>> I have school.
[Dan sighs]
I'm gonna get
a lot of shit today
and I just have to deal with it.
So do you.
[school bell rings]
Hey, babe.
>> Hey, Mr. Landsman.
>> Hey, Heather.
>> Heard about last night.
>> Oh, you did? Great.
>> Well, it's pretty epic.
It's all over Facebook.
>> It is?
>> Yeah, you're fucked up, dude.
I like it.
>> Oh.
Yeah. Thanks.
Yeah.
[instrumental music]
[engine revving]
[music continues]
>> It was so awesome
havin' you here, man.
What a great weekend.
>> Hey, it was weird all that
shit you blasted Dan
with last night
in front of everybody,
but, you know..
...classic Lawless.
>> Thanks for the material. That
stuff's gonna last us for years.
>> For years. Yeah.
>> Guys.
>> Oh, buddy.
>> I could've fucked
either one of you.
>> Mm-hmm.
>> At any point.
>> Uh..
>> But I didn't.
>> Why is that?
Alright, fellas.
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[door squeaking]
[indistinct chatter]
[dog barking]
>> So there were buttons on
that shirt when I bought it.
And I yelled at that manager..
...for no reason.
>> Yeah.
>> How did the buttons
come off the shirt, Dan?
>> He ripped 'em off.
>> Hmm.
Yeah.
>> Stace, I'm not..
>> So, what was it, Dan?
Can you please explain it to me?
>> I wish I could.
I don't -- I don't -- I..
If you had asked
me two weeks ago
what the odds
of this happening --
>> Oh, my God. Stop.
>> I'm just tryin'
to talk about it.
I mean -- I mean -- I,
to deal with it.
You know? I mean,
because we have to.
Right?
[doorbell rings]
>> Fuck!
[sniffles]
[instrumental music]
[Stacey sighs]
>> Is this a bad time?
>> Um..
>> What are you doin' here?
>> I was just
headin' out and, uh..
...I don't know, I kinda feel
like I needed to apologize.
I said some things --
>> Yeah, we heard them.
>> Look, Stace,
you gotta know..
...I did this. Not Dan.
It was all me.
>> Is that supposed
to make me feel better?
>> Well, can I
at least come in?
>> I'll come out.
It's okay.
[door creaks]
[door closes]
>> Dude, listen to me.
Last night, rippin' you
to shreds like that..
It was..
It must've been
embarrassing for ya.
I'm sorry.
>> Well..
...thanks for saying that.
>> In LA..
...I treated you like
a piece of meat, man.
It wasn't right.
>> Yeah.
Uh..
...thanks for that as well.
>> I don't wanna be doin' that.
You know, I don't
wanna be that guy.
>> Yeah, I don't
wanna be the guy I was
in that scenario.
>> It's just you put me up
on this pedestal, you know?
It was like..
I don't know, it was a lot
of pressure to deal with.
>> Huh?
>> It kinda made me feel like
I needed to play the part.
Didn't wanna let you down.
>> "Play the part?"
>> Dan..
...you gotta open
your eyes, man.
I'm a mess.
That Banana Boat spot..
...it's pathetic.
>> That's a national spot.
>> Ah, you saw my apartment,
man, I'm broke as shit.
I don't know fuckin'
Dermot Mulroney.
>> But I saw you guys.
>> I mean, he's a super
down-to-earth dude.
He's fucking normal
as hell, but..
...he didn't have
a clue who I was.
Because we'd never met.
I'm nothing, man.
I peaked in the 11th grade.
>> Hang on one second.
[instrumental music]
[honking]
>> Hey, Mac.
>> Relax, man.
>> I am relaxed.
You wanna miss your flight,
I don't give a fuck.
It's on you. Your call.
Yeah.
>> What's that?
>> It's yours.
I borrowed it.
After you fucked me.
And you probably,
uh, don't remember.
It's just a blip
on your radar, but, uh..
>> Keep it.
You weren't just a blip, Dan.
>> Even if I was.
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
>> Take care of yourself, pal.
[engine cranking]
[music continues]
>> Dear Grant Barkledge,
class of '94.
Fun times last night.
Although I do apologize
for my personal life
taking center stage
like it did.
That was unexpected.
Had a great DJ
who, if you ask me
got unfairly overshadowed.
Sorry about that, Tyler.
But it's funny.
I brought it all on myself.
I thought if I could deliver
Oliver Lawless, I'd be a hero.
Single-handedly
saving our reunion.
But we didn't need him,
did we?
We didn't need the most
popular guy from high school.
We didn't need the face
of a national
Banana Boat campaign.
We needed a symbol
of something more.
And I for one
was ready to risk
everything I had
for the chance to find it.
But it took all this
to make me realize..
...Oliver Lawless
was inside me all along.
There's a Lawless
inside all of us.
Sometimes you just gotta
give him a little nudge
and wake him up.
After I post this update
and leave you all
ample time to read it
I will be deactivating
this Facebook account.
For I am the only
one in possession
of the new password.
But I shall
leave you with this.
Be grateful for what you have
and you'll end up having more.
If you concentrate
on what you don't have..
...you will never..
...ever..
...have enough.
That's Oprah Winfrey
for you right there.
Tellin' it like it is.
Goodbye, old friends.
I'll see you all
on the other side.
And I will forever be..
...your chairman
of the Alumni Committee.
Daniel Gregory Landsman
AKA..
[intense music]
...The D-Train.
[instrumental music]
¶ If I am you and you are me ¶
¶ Then I know
the world will see that ¶
¶ I was weak
but now I'm strong ¶
¶ This will be
a different song ¶
¶ So here I am ¶
¶ The better man ¶
¶ Not the one you thought I am ¶
¶ And here we are
not the same ¶
¶ 'Cause tonight
I win this game ¶
¶ So hold me tight ¶
¶ 'Cause a million stars
could die tonight ¶
¶ And when they're gone ¶
¶ There'll be nothing
for you to wish upon ¶
¶ A million stars
depend on us tonight ¶
¶ I count on you
you count on me ¶
¶ Just this once
please let it be ¶
¶ And catch me
if I'm fallin' down ¶
¶ One last chance
to wear this crown ¶
¶ There's nothin' left ¶
¶ For me to say ¶
¶ Dreams come true if we pray ¶
¶ I'm reachin'
for the Milky Way ¶
¶ A super star is born today ¶
¶ So hold me tight ¶
¶ 'Cause a million stars
could die tonight ¶
¶ And when they're gone ¶
¶ There'll be nothing
for you to wish upon ¶
¶ A million stars
depend on us tonight ¶
¶ So.. ¶
¶ So hold me tight ¶
¶ 'Cause a million stars
could die tonight ¶
¶ And when they're gone ¶
¶ There'll be nothin'
for you to wish upon ¶
¶ So hold me tight ¶
¶ 'Cause a million stars
could die tonight ¶
¶ And when they're gone ¶
¶ There'll be nothin'
for you to wish upon ¶
¶ A million stars
depend on us tonight ¶
¶ Tonight ¶
[instrumental music]
¶ A million stars
depend on us tonight ¶
¶ Tonight ¶
[music continues]