(BARKING)
(PIANO PLAYING)
ALFALFA: (SINGING) Beautiful dreamer
Wake unto me
Starlight and dew drops
Are waiting for thee
Sounds of the rude world
Heard in the day
Lulled by the moonlight
Have all passed away
(SINGS TUNELESSLY) Beautiful dreamer
(GROANS)
Queen of my song
(SIGHS)
List while I woo thee
With soft melody
-Gone are the cares of...
-(BLOWS)
(GAGS)
-(CHOKES)
-(STUDENTS REACT)
Alfalfa? Are you okay?
-Yeah, thanks, Darla.
-(GIGGLES)
Well, thank you for
that lovely performance for Share Day.
But I'm not finished yet.
Yeah, you are.
Allow me to show you how it's really done.
All right, Waldo,
but this will be the last song today.
Afterwards, we need to get back to work.
(STUDENTS GROAN)
-(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
-Oh.
(SINGING) Well, she's all you'd ever want
She's the kind they'd like to flaunt
And take to dinner
But she always knows her place
She's got style, she's got grace
She's a winner
(SCOFFS)
She's a lady
Whoa, whoa, whoa
Talkin' about that little lady
And the lady is mine
Well, she's never in the way
Always something nice to say
What a blessing
Well, to leave her on her own
Knowing she's okay alone
And there's no messing
Psst, psst.
(BLOWING)
(BARKING)
-Huh? What? Hurry, it's the signal.
-Come on.
She's a lady
Whoa, whoa, whoa
Talkin' about that little lady
-And the...
-(MUSIC STOPS)
-Thank you so much, Waldo.
-But...
-Please, take a seat, that was...
-Wait, but I'm...
Nope, take a seat. Thank you very much.
-That was, uh...
-(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Unique. That was very unique.
Hold your horses, I'm coming.
Oh. Hello.
And what can I do for you two?
Stymie has to come home.
Our daddy broke two of his legs.
Two of his legs? Oh, my.
Mary Ann has to come, too.
Her mama's havin' a baby.
A baby? Since when?
BUCKWHEAT: Since this morning.
She found out about it
and now she's having it.
And my mama says Spanky and Alfalfa have
to come home right away.
Right away? Why?
It's important business.
Oh. What's the important business?
Beats me. That's what Spanky told me to say.
Right, Spank?
(STUDENTS LAUGH)
Spanky, Alfalfa, Stymie,
Mary Ann, get up here right away.
KID 1: They're in trouble.
Something important has come up
and you all need to go home right away.
Well, Miss Crabtree, it's been a real great year.
Yeah, have a good summer, Miss Crabtree.
See ya next year.
Don't take any wooden nickels.
Ah.
Beep, beep.
Miss Crabtree, I've got your ice cream cake.
-Oh, yes, bring it right in.
-(STUDENTS GASP)
(STUDENTS EXCLAIM IN AWE)
All right, boys and girls,
I have a little surprise.
We're not gonna do any more work today.
Instead, we're gonna have
an end-of-the-year party
with a great big ice cream cake.
(STUDENTS CHEERING)
You know, Miss Crabtree,
I think our folks can wait a little while.
Yeah! My mom's had babies before.
I'm sure she knows what to do.
My daddy isn't goin' anywhere. He can't.
His legs are broke.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
You can't keep
your families waiting just for a party.
Now run along now
and I will see you next fall.
(STUDENTS PROTESTING)
-No, please.
-Run along. See you next fall.
-She had them before.
-Oh.
You kids don't know what you're missing.
Who wants cake?
ALL: Me!
Oh, man. Did you see that cake?
Not just a cake, an ice cream cake.
Yeah, ice cream and cake.
The two best
things in the world all mixed together.
Too many calories, men.
And you all
could stand to lose a few pounds anyway.
Mmm.
Man, that cake was good.
You said it, pal.
No time to dwell on the past, men.
Summer vacation has officially begun.
No school, no homework, no getting up early.
-We're free. Come on, time's a-wastin'.
-All right!
-(BARKING)
-BUCKWHEAT: Whoo-hoo!
Hi!
-SPANKY: Hiya, Pops!
-Hi there. Hi.
SPANKY: Yay!
Oh!
-Kids! (SCOFFS) Watch where you're going.
-STYMIE: Sorry.
-Sorry, Officer Kennedy.
-Wait a minute.
Aren't you kids supposed to be in school?
We got time off for good behavior.
That would be a first.
So who are the flowers for? Miss Crabtree?
ALL: Yeah!
They were.
When are you finally gonna work up
the nerve to ask her to marry you?
I will, I will.
When school's out and the time's right,
I'll be ready.
I got the ring. Finally paid it off.
-ALL: Ooh!
-Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah!
Look, don't touch. You understand?
Isn't there supposed to be a diamond on it?
Oh, there it is.
It looks real nice when you can see it.
-Well, good luck, Officer Kennedy.
-Thank you.
Try not to blow it. Come on, guys.
(CHEERING)
SPANKY: To the bakery!
Hiya, Grandma.
Oh, hi, kids. Oh, hi!
ALL: Hi, Grandma.
Oh, boy. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, so, isn't there still
one more day left at school?
They never do
anything important on the last day.
Except eat ice cream cake.
Okay. I don't suppose
I could interest you in cinnamon muffins.
Yeah!
GRANDMA: Here we go.
STYMIE: Me, Grandma!
I caught it!
Thanks, Grandma. You are the best.
ALL: Yeah! Thanks, Grandma!
-(BARKING)
-I didn't forget you.
Come on, gang. To the tree house!
(CHEERING)
STYMIE: See you later, Grandma.
-After you, Petey.
-(ALFALFA LAUGHS)
SPANKY: Home, sweet home.
ALFALFA: Mmm-hmm.
SPANKY: Petey, do your stuff.
(WHINES)
(SCHOOL BELL RINGS)
(KIDS CHEERING)
Whoa! No! No, no, no!
Kids.
Are they gone, Miss Crabtree?
Oh, they are indeed, Officer Kennedy.
And now that they are,
I think that we
can call each other by our first names,
Ed.
-Of course, June.
-(CHUCKLES)
What are those?
Oh. Uh...
They were flowers,
till your kids got a hold of them.
Thank you.
It's the thought that counts.
(SNIFFS) Mmm.
I was thinking,
maybe you and I could have lunch
at this very special place
that I happen to know of?
A date with my man. Why, I'd love to.
Oh.
ALFALFA: (WARMING UP VOICE)
Me, me, me, me, me, me, me.
Me, me, me, me, me.
Me.
Ready, gang?
-Yeah!
-Ready!
Ready, indeed.
Hi, ladies and gentlemen.
Tonight, we're going to perform an oldie,
but a goodie
called I Got You, Babe.
My name is Spanky and we are
the International Silver String
Submarine Band.
Huh?
PORKY: The what?
That's our band name? Since when?
Since I just thought it up a second ago.
Makes us sound important.
-Okay.
-I agree.
Okay, I like it.
And a one and a two and a three.
(BARKING)
(ALL PLAYING TUNELESSLY)
Hello, Mrs. Larson.
Hi.
You're early today. Here you go.
On the house, as usual.
-What is that noise?
-That's the kids' band.
Oh...
Well, tell them to keep practicing.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, and you got
a certified letter here from the bank.
Oh.
Sign here.
-Here you go.
-Thanks.
Thank you!
You're welcome.
They'll get better.
I hope so.
(GROANS)
(LAUGHS)
Oh. Oh.
Hold it. Hold it. Why'd you stop?
We were just
getting to the best part, where I sing.
We're supposed to be playing,
I Got You, Babe.
It sounds more like, I Got a Headache, Babe.
What's wrong with everybody?
We're doing the best we can, Spank.
You know, he's right.
Our music lacks a certain je ne sais quoi.
Like what?
Like a girl singer.
That would complete our sound.
And I know the perfect girl.
Let me guess, Darla.
SPANKY: Not again.
-Great minds think alike.
-(SPANKY GROANS)
You've heard her sing in class before.
She's really good.
No girls allowed in the gang.
But Mary Ann's in the gang. And she's a girl.
I meant a real girl.
I am a real girl.
Okay. Okay. You're a real girl.
Kids? Kids.
What is it, Grandma?
Would you all watch the bakery for me?
Something urgent came up
and I've gotta go to the bank.
-What's wrong, Grandma?
-Everything's fine.
You just watch the shop and I'll be back soon.
Don't worry, Grandma.
I got everything under control.
No problem.
Hello?
Anybody here?
-SPANKY: Hi!
-Yes, ma'am. How may we help you?
Is there somebody else
working here today who's a little older?
Don't be fooled. We're older than we look.
Why, I'm nearly nine.
-And our combined ages equal over 45.
-Mmm-hmm.
And if you count, Petey, it's 103 in dog years.
So, what can me
and my staff do you for today?
I need a large birthday cake by 5:00.
Don't worry. Our expert
bakers can have it ready for you in time.
-What kind of cake do you want?
-Red velvet.
(GASPS)
-You want a cake made out of velvet?
-Yuck!
Yes, red velvet.
Okey-dokey. It'll be ready by 5:00.
-5:00 sharp.
-Okay. Thanks!
5:00? But Grandma won't be back in time.
That's why we're going to make it ourselves.
But what do you know about making cakes?
How hard can it be?
I've been eating 'em my whole life.
First off, a little vanilla.
And flour.
(CHUCKLES)
Don't forget the sugar.
More. More. Just a little more.
(CHUCKLES)
Perfect.
Isn't this gonna be a little too sweet?
No such thing as
too sweet when you're talking about cakes.
Don't forget the eggs.
Had to go out to
the garage to find it, but I got the oil.
Hey. As long as it says oil, it'll do the trick.
(WHINES)
STYMIE: What's that?
SPANKY: Yeast.
It's something my mom always puts in cakes.
It makes the cake grow big.
Well, this woman wanted a big cake.
So let's put it all in.
MARY ANN: Got the main ingredient.
Our red velvet cakes
are made with 100% pure red velvet.
And how!
(BARKS)
Mmm-mmm-mmm.
Mmm.
I sure could go
for one of those delicious-looking cupcakes.
But Spanky says
we can't eat the merchandise.
We're not gonna eat them,
we're just gonna
test them out to make sure they're still good.
Well, this one's good.
This one, too.
Better test the rest.
Good idea.
This is gonna be some cake.
ALL: Yeah.
BANK OFFICER: Well,
I've reviewed your paperwork, Mrs. Larson,
and I'm very sorry,
but you owe this bank $10,000,
and it is past due.
You must pay it back
or we will be forced to take away your bakery.
Oh. Would you like to
try one of my chocolate chip cookies?
Ooh.
No. No, I'm trying to watch my calories.
Now, about the loan.
Well, I don't think one would hurt.
I mean, they're from my bakery,
and you would just be doing due diligence.
I'm sorry about not paying back the money,
but if you could
just give me a little bit more time.
Mmm...
Oh, my gosh.
That's the best
chocolate chip cookie I've ever had.
It's got just the right crunchy to chewy ratio.
Ooh, I'm so glad you like them.
This isn't a cookie.
It's nirvana.
It's bliss.
It's a warm puppy.
-(GIGGLES)
-It's sleeping late on a summer morning,
or walking barefoot on the beach at sunset.
If this cookie were a woman,
I would ask it to marry me.
You see? With a cookie like this,
business is just bound to pick up.
And I'm sure I could
pay back the $10,000 in two months.
-Would you like another one?
-Yes. What? No.
Look, I'm sorry, Mrs. Larson,
but you've already had three extensions.
My hands are tied.
You simply must
pay back the $10,000 by the end of the month.
But that's only two weeks away.
-Maybe it's time you retired.
-Oh.
Yes, sell the bakery.
Do what makes you happy.
I'm happiest when I'm baking.
Well...
Do you mind?
They're just so good.
(BELCHES)
Our work here is done.
What shall we have for dessert?
Hmm? More!
(BOTH BELCHING)
I can't wait to
see the expression on Grandma's face
when she sees
how we made a cake on our own.
(RUMBLING)
I don't like the sound of that.
Me neither.
Is it supposed to be doing that?
(RUMBLING)
What was that?
Sounds like a moose trying to sing.
Maybe it's Alfalfa.
Come on, let's go check it out.
Take cover!
(WHIMPERS)
(GASPING)
(WHIMPERING)
Kids?
I think we used a teeny bit too much yeast!
You think?
STYMIE: What do we do?
Don't worry. I'll just take some air out of it.
-STYMIE: Uh-oh.
-(WHINES)
-Kids?
-(EXPLOSION)
Oh. Are you all right?
(UTENSIL CLATTERING)
Oh, my goodness.
What happened?
-(WHINES)
-(DINGS)
Guess that means the cake's ready.
What a mess you are.
-It was a delicious mess.
-Oh, good.
-What's Waldo doing here?
-Where?
(GROANS)
Oh.
Oh, this is sweet.
Mrs. Larson?
Ray Kaye, but my friends call me Big Ray,
because I think big.
Well, what can I do for you, Mr. Kaye?
No, no, no. It's what can I do for you.
I understand that your property here,
its loan is coming due.
And I'm here to offer you
a business proposition.
And I'm consulting on the deal.
He's so cute.
I'm gonna offer you
$100,000 here and now if you sell it to me.
RASCALS: $100,000!
That's a lot of money.
Now, that's a...
That's a lot of cute little people.
You wanna buy my bakery?
Yes, I do.
-Why?
-Progress.
Look, here is your bakery right now.
And as you can see, it's old, it's rundown,
it's desperately in need of a face-lift.
And here's my plan.
We're gonna tear it all down
and then in its place, this.
Say, what happened to Grandma's bakery?
RASCALS: Yeah!
Who's that? It's you again. Little short stack.
I'll tell you what happened.
Mixed-use development.
Retail stores, office space, luxury apartments.
All very modern.
A mall?
Oh, no, no, no.
Not a mall. A Big Ray's Malltopia.
All glass and steel.
It's gonna kick this sleepy city
right in the 21st century.
What, you're just gonna tear down my bakery?
No, no, no, no, no.
No, I wanna offer you a very fair price,
then tear it down.
WALDO: What about the tree house, Dad?
No, don't worry about the tree house, Waldo.
We'll uproot the tree and the tree house,
and we'll have it moved
right into our backyard.
That's our tree house.
RASCALS: Yeah!
Not after my dad buys it.
Then it will be my tree house.
Members only.
And none of you will be members.
(CHUCKLES) Isn't he cute?
I'm sorry, Mr. Kaye,
but I can't imagine closing this place. No.
See, my grandparents started this business.
Oh, well, you can sell it to me,
or lose it to the bank in two weeks.
Unless, of course, I don't know,
you got $10,000 lying around. No.
Look, you're gonna get a much better deal
from me than you will from the bank.
Well, I have two weeks to raise the money.
Until then, I won't sell.
Well, I'm just trying to be the good guy here.
All right. Have it your way.
Two weeks. Bye-bye.
Grandma, you owe the bank $10,000?
Yes.
I know.
When we win the talent show, Grandma,
we'll just give you the $10,000.
(CHUCKLES) Oh.
ALFALFA: Yeah. That's first prize.
Did you hear
what we sounded like this afternoon?
We were terrible.
Speak for yourself.
She's right.
We'll never win the talent show.
Sorry, Grandma.
GRANDMA: That's okay, kids.
Please excuse me,
but I think I'm gonna clean up the kitchen
while I still have a kitchen to clean.
What are we gonna do?
Not only will Grandma lose her bakery,
but we're gonna lose our tree house to Waldo.
SPANKY: Hold on.
I have a great idea
and I'm gonna give it to you in one word.
Jobs.
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
(BARKING)
MARY ANN: Hey, guys.
OFFICER KENNEDY: Thank you!
Oh, come on!
Mr. Kaye!
Here they are, gentlemen.
Your new caddies.
Is this some kind of a joke?
I'm sorry,
but three of my caddies called in sick.
They're all I've got right now.
Haven't I seen you
two guys somewhere before?
Where would you have seen us before?
Yeah, we travel in different social circles.
I don't know. They're awful short.
Hey, as long as they can carry a bag,
what difference does it make?
Okay, let's go. We're late.
Come on, grab the bags.
Now you two do exactly what Mr. Kaye says
or you're out of a job. Understand?
BOTH: Yes, sir.
Oh, Edgar, how did you
manage having lunch here?
You're not even a member of this club.
Let's just say
I have a few friends in high places.
Oh, you mean the Chief?
Yep, that's one.
Ooh, fancy.
(PANTING)
Man, this working
for a living sure is a lot of work.
Yeah, I think
I'm more cut out for executive work.
You know, with a corner office.
You said it, pal.
Oh, Ed, this is lovely.
Well, it is a special occasion.
After all, we've been dating for
one year, five months, three
weeks, four days and nine hours.
But who's counting.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, every minute of it has been wonderful.
It has, hasn't it?
(SPANKY AND ALFALFA GIGGLING)
SPANKY: Who does he think he is, a pro?
ALFALFA: I don't know, but he sure is lame.
It's gonna go...
(WHISTLES)
-That's exactly what it's gonna do.
-Yeah. Yeah.
-I'm sorry, it's not gonna work.
-Lame.
Maybe you'd like to share with us
some of your golfing expertise.
With pleasure. Watch and learn.
Oh, good. I can't wait.
Show him how it's done, Spank.
Hmm.
Hmm. Mmm!
-Ooh.
-Mmm.
You're not getting any taller.
Simmer down, hot sauce.
June, there's something
that I've been wanting to ask you.
Yes, Edgar?
SPANKY: Fore!
June, will you...
(GROANING)
Ed, are you hurt?
What in the world is going on here?
I got hit by a golf ball.
It came from over there.
(GROANS)
(OFFICER KENNEDY GROWLS)
Kids.
Those kids!
Quick, Spank. Ditch the evidence.
Oh.
(GROANS)
Fore.
And stay out. You're fired!
Ugh!
MARY ANN: What are we going to do now?
Yeah, we all got fired from our jobs.
Alfalfa and me didn't get fired, we resigned.
-Working conditions were terrible.
-Mmm-hmm.
Okay, but how are we
gonna raise enough money to help Grandma?
Nobody ever got rich
working for somebody else, right?
Right.
So we're going to start our own business.
-Our own business? What kind of business?
-Hmm.
Let me think.
(GROWLING)
What's up, Petey?
(BARKING)
Petey just gave me an idea.
GIRL 1: Thank you.
SPANKY: Thanks.
DARLA: Hi, Alfalfa.
Hi, Darla.
Five whole dollars? I'm not sure.
That seems like an awful lot of money.
What exactly do you
get for five whole dollars?
The question really is, what don't you get?
Here at Komplete Pet Kare,
our expert staff will provide your pet
with the finest services
known to man or beast.
For the price of just $5,
our deluxe spa package
includes pet walking and washing.
But wait, there's more.
Your pet will also be
groomed by our patented Groom-O-Lator.
Well, that does seem very nice,
but Princess Flufferina
means the world to me.
And I've never left her
with anyone else before.
She's my prized pet.
You have nothing to worry about, Darla.
She's in good hands.
In fact, people call me the Cat Whisperer.
Hi there, kitty.
-(HISSES)
-(GASPS)
Spanky here will escort
Princess Flufferina to the spa.
Bye, Alfalfa.
Bye.
Come on, Romeo, time to make some moolah.
How's the grooming going, Mary Ann?
-Yeah?
-Pretty good.
It took a while
because he kept trying to hide in his shell,
but look at that smile now.
Show them, Cecil.
How are the fish comin'?
They're on the rinse cycle.
But I need both your help
bathing and grooming the other animals.
-Alfalfa, fire up the Groom-O-Lator.
-Why can't you fire it up?
-'Cause I'm the leader. I'm supervising.
-(SIGHS)
Ready, Petey? Here we go.
Here you go.
SPANKY: First stop, the rinse station.
Next stop, the soap-down station.
Then onto the rub-a-dub-dub scrub station.
After that, the dry-o-matic station.
And finally, a little perfume
to make them smell sweet.
Fresh and clean.
If this isn't a license to print money,
I don't know what is.
I gotta say, I had my doubts at first,
but when you're right, you're right.
MARY ANN: Hey, Spanky, when you're done
signing autographs,
we need more soap.
Okay, okay.
The way I figure it, if we can see 50 pets a day,
we'll have Grandma's money in no time flat.
Here's another one.
(BIRD SCREECHES)
-Ready for grooming.
Okay, guys, load up the other pets.
-We've got a lot of animals to groom.
-Gotcha.
(BUBBLING)
Oh, Ed, this is lovely.
I can't believe that you put this whole
thing together on your lunch break.
Well, our last date didn't go so well,
and there was something I wanted
to ask you before we got
interrupted.
Ask me anything, Officer Kennedy.
(CHUCKLES) Okay.
PORKY: Let's go to the park, little doggies.
Giddy up.
Whoa.
Whoa, whoa! Slow down!
Well, Miss Crabtree.
I mean, June...
PORKY: Officer Kennedy.
MISS CRABTREE: Oh.
-Hi, Miss Crabtree!
-Hi, Officer Kennedy!
PORKY: Are you guys having a picnic?
-BUCKWHEAT: Yeah, a picnic.
-(GRUNTS)
Here you go, little guy.
Hold still!
(SQUEALING)
(CAT HISSING)
Spanky, maybe
you should handle Princess Flufferina?
-(GROANS)
-It's just a cat, not a mountain lion.
All I know is, when Darla sees
how well I took care of her cat,
she's gonna find me irresponsible.
Don't you mean irresistible?
(SQUAWKS) Irresistible. Irresistible.
Yeah, that, too.
(MEOWS)
Oh, no. Guys, look.
-(GASPING)
-The machine is turning them all green.
Remarkable.
What did you do, Mary Ann?
What do you mean, "What did I do?"
You're the one that put the soap in.
-(GASPS)
-Look! It's green dye.
You distracted me, Mary Ann.
Oh, no. Darla's cat!
(BUBBLING)
Wait, come back! Watch out!
Hurry! Make it stop.
(MEOWS)
(MEOWING)
Mmm. That chocolate sure looks good.
-Oh, would you like one?
-Yeah!
No, no, no, no.
Those chocolates are expensive.
Oh, there's plenty here.
Here, take some.
Now, are these all your dogs?
Nah, we're just
walking 'em to make money for Grandma.
Aw, that is so nice. Isn't that nice, Edgar?
Uh, yeah, that's lovely.
Now I'm sure you have
a lot of other dogs to walk,
-so take chocolates to go. Okay?
-Oh.
(BARKING)
Oh. Oh...
(GRUNTS)
Ooh!
No, sit! Stop, stop. No! Sit, doggie.
No. Mush. No! No, no mush!
No, come on, sit, stop.
No. No.
(GRUNTS)
-(GASPS)
-(GROANS)
Good thing that lamppost was there
to stop him.
Mmm-hmm.
(WINCES)
Kids.
Come back. If you don't like green,
we can make them any other color you want.
Alfalfa, what happened to you?
Oh, just been working hard.
I'm here to pick up Princess Flufferina.
Is she ready?
(HESITATING)
Sure.
And wait until you see her exciting new look.
What new look?
Here you go. One Princess Flufferoni.
(CAT MEOWS)
(SCREAMING)
(SIGHS)
Darla hates me now.
At least we made a little money for Grandma,
thanks to my great idea.
No, we actually lost money.
Yeah, all the pet owners
wanted their money back.
Did I mention Darla hates me now?
Don't worry, I'll think of something else.
-What?
-Yeah, what?
I'm thinking.
-Anything yet?
-No.
Now? How about now? Anything yet?
Not yet.
Now? How about now?
Don't rush me. Genius takes time.
ALL: Grandma!
GRANDMA: Hi, kids, I got some good news.
I sold off some old stock,
and I was able to raise $5,000.
-(ALL GASP)
-That's great, Grandma.
You're almost halfway there.
And if I can drum up enough business,
I think I can get the rest.
But I need your help.
Sure, Grandma, no problem.
Would you mind
handing out these flyers all over town?
Sure. You bet!
-Yay!
-(ALL CHEERING)
(HORN HONKING)
(SPANKY GROANS)
Guys?
What are they doing here?
Hey. What do you think you're doing?
Which color do you
think would look better for the tree house?
Caribbean green or Georgia peach?
It's fine just the way it is.
Desiree doesn't think so. Do you, Desiree?
Desiree?
My decorator.
This dump is gonna need a total makeover
when my father moves it to our back yard.
So, how do you even get in here?
I wouldn't do that.
The burglar alarm is set.
A burglar alarm? On this dump?
Get real.
(LAUGHING)
I told you.
Yeah, he told you.
PORKY: That's hilarious.
I really don't like him.
Me neither.
Me three-ther.
No time to waste, men.
We're gonna distribute these flyers.
And then I'm gonna come up
with another great plan
to make money for Grandma.
Now, let's go. Come on!
-Yeah!
I call on you, my friend
A helping hand you lend
In my time of need
Whenever I'm down
I call on you, my friend
A helping hand you lend
In my time of need
Whenever I'm down
I call on you, my friend
And all that's going on
Is really going on
Just one of those days in joy
You say the right things
To keep me moving on
To keep my going strong
Going strong, going strong
Hey, Alfalfa!
Hi, Darla!
(SCREAMING)
(CAT SCREECHING)
-(ALFALFA GROANS)
-(GASPS)
Are you all right?
I've died and gone to heaven.
Actually, this is Maple Street.
Let me help you up.
You have a nice voice.
Thanks. You have a nice voice, too.
Why, thank you, Alfalfa.
I'm really sorry about your cat.
I hope you're not still mad.
It's all right.
When my friends saw
Princess Flufferina, they got jealous.
So now they all want green cats, too.
Hey, are you going to the library?
Yeah. I love books about cats. See?
Cats and You, Illustrated History of Cats,
Heroic Cats, Great Cats of the Civil War.
Can I give you
a ride to the library on my bike?
Yeah. That would be very nice of you.
Hey, the gang and I, we have a band,
the International
Silver String Submarine Band.
-I.S.S.S.B. for short.
-Oh.
And I was wondering
if you'd like to sing with us
in the talent show next week.
I'd love to, Alfalfa,
but I already agreed
to be in the talent show with Waldo.
Waldo?
-WALDO: Hi, Darla.
-(GASPS)
Look at what my dad just bought me.
Waldo!
It's beautiful!
Isn't it? Want to go for a ride?
Do I? Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
But I thought we were going to the library.
That's okay, I'll take her.
I'd offer you a ride, too,
but clearly there's not enough room for three.
Sorry. Bye, Alfalfa.
(AIR HISSING)
(SIGHS)
(PLAYING DISCORDANT MUSIC)
Hold it! Hold it.
And what happened to our lead singer?
Darla and I could have
made such beautiful music together.
What does she see in Waldo
and that car of his?
Forget about her.
We need to rehearse for the talent show.
But you don't
know how hard it is to get a girlfriend
when you don't have wheels.
-Hmm.
-Mmm-hmm.
Wheels? Wheels!
I've got it. I have my next great idea.
-What do you have in mind?
-PORKY: Yeah.
Not only will we make money for Grandma,
but you can impress Darla.
(KLAXON HONKING)
Hey, Darla. Like a ride to the library?
Alfalfa? Where did you get that?
Me and the gang made it.
It's our new taxi cab service.
What does it even run on?
ALFALFA: Petey power.
And it gets 3 miles to the bone.
So would you like a ride to the library?
It's for a good cause,
to save Grandma's bakery.
Okay, I'd love a ride.
-(HORN HONKING)
-(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hey! I'm supposed to drive Darla.
Sorry, Waldo,
but Alfalfa already offered to take me.
I'd offer you a ride, Waldo,
but, clearly, there's not enough room.
-Let's roll, Stymie.
-See ya.
-(MEOWS)
-(BARKING)
(HORN TOOTING)
Home base calling dispatch.
Home base calling dispatch. Come in.
Dispatch here. What's up, Spank?
Tickets are selling like hotcakes.
When are you guys coming back
to pick up the next batch of passengers?
Be back in an jiff.
Got one more stop to make at Walnut,
then one more at the library.
-Great. Over and out.
-Over and out.
Step right up, folks.
One dollar for the ride of your life.
DARLA: This taxi's great, Alfalfa. I love it.
Oh, no. It's Butch and Worm.
DARLA: Uh-oh.
(GASPS)
Well, well, well.
Nice set of wheels you got here.
Yeah, nice.
BUTCH: Fancy running into you on our street.
How's about giving me and Worm a ride?
-Huh?
-Okay, Butch. That'll be one dollar.
I was thinking more like you pay me.
-(GULPS)
-How much you got on you?
-(GASPS)
-A robbery.
Yes!
You guys are gonna get it now.
-Hey, look. The cops!
-Where?
Whoa!
(LAUGHING)
-Yeah!
-DARLA: That was awesome, Alfalfa.
I'm gonna get you guys.
ALFALFA: See ya! Wouldn't wanna be ya!
(HONKING)
See you later, guys!
Next stop, Walnut Street.
And we have officially arrived.
Thank you for riding with Komplete Taxi, sir.
Tell all your friends.
-Next customer?
-Here, here, here, here. Thank you.
STYMIE: Ladies and gents,
it'll be a few minutes.
Gotta cool off the engine.
How about a little music, Darla?
-Sure.
-Okay.
(KAZOO PLAYING)
STYMIE: Okay, Petey.
This ought to wet your whistle.
Alfalfa? Do you suppose
you could change the station?
Of course, no problem.
(SIGHS)
Can't it play anything else?
Sure.
(SINGING) With a moo moo here
And a moo moo there
Here a moo, there a moo
Everywhere a moo moo
Old MacDonald had a farm E-I-E-I-O
Can't you play anything else?
It's the only song I know.
We'll just have to enjoy
the silence for a while.
Okay, everybody. All set to go.
-(GROWLS)
-(MEOWING)
(PETEY BARKING)
ALFALFA: Next stop, the library.
Have a nice trip.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we will be arriving
at our destination in five minutes.
But in the meantime,
please allow me to be your tour guide
pointing out all the sights of our fair city.
On the left, you will see the home
of 11-year-old Freddie Gillespie,
the only person to
eat 27 Atomic FireBalls at once
and live to tell the tale.
Alfalfa, aren't we going a little fast?
Don't worry, we're fine.
This is the express taxi.
-Uh...
-And on your right, you will see the very spot
where Miss Mugilicutty's rottweiler ate...
-Alfalfa?
-Stymie, I'm conducting a tour here.
-It's important.
-What's so important that it can't wait?
No brakes!
No brakes?
(SCREAMS) I'm too young
and handsome to die.
(ALL SCREAMING)
-(SCREAMING)
-ALFALFA: Watch out!
-Stymie! Do something!
-Like what?
Like don't crash!
Slow down!
Speed up!
Watch out! Get out of the way!
MAN: Whoa! Hey!
-Watch the road!
-I can't see!
Hurry. Be careful!
Hurry!
-Watch out!
-(DARLA SCREAMS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Oh, remember this spot?
It's where we first met.
Aw.
That's right. You gave me a parking citation.
Oh.
That's right. I did.
Oh, it's okay, Ed. It was dismissed in court.
-Oh.
-(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, yeah. Well, I mean, technically... I did.
Attention passengers,
the taxi is arriving at Gate 1.
Please have your tickets ready to give to the...
(SCREAMING)
Come on, guys!
Anyway, uh, June.
We've been spending
a lot of time together and I've been thinking...
(HORNS HONKING)
-Oh.
-June.
What's that?
I don't know.
-All right, stay here, I'll handle this.
-Oh.
(BLOWS WHISTLE)
Get out of the way.
STYMIE: Watch out!
MAN: Hey, you kids!
(BLOWING WHISTLE)
Whoa...
(GROANING)
-(GASPS)
-(GROANS)
Is everyone all right?
(GROANING) What happened?
(GROANS)
Are you guys okay?
I think we need a tow truck.
That was amazing! Let's do it again!
My ring! Where's my ring?
I'm so sorry, Darla.
I don't know what went wrong.
What went wrong was me accepting
this ride from you in this death trap.
OFFICER KENNEDY: You kids
have really done it!
Do you know how many laws you've broken?
I have had it with you kids!
Edgar, calm down. They're just children.
They're not children. They're monsters.
Public menaces. Dangers to society.
They're future criminals.
(TOGETHER) Sorry, Officer Kennedy.
He seems a little mad.
(HORN HONKING)
-(GASPS)
-Darla, I heard the crash. Are you all right?
Thank you, Waldo. I'm fine.
Just a little dizzy.
We were just trying
to make money for Grandma's bakery.
I don't wanna hear your excuses.
And if I had my way,
I'd lock each one of you up in jail right now
and save the world
a whole lot of trouble in the future.
You know what, Edgar?
I don't think
you and I should see each other anymore.
What? Why not?
What kind of future do I have with a man
who doesn't even like children?
-Goodbye!
-Junebug.
Junebug, I like kids...
From a distance.
Would you like that ride to the library now?
With pleasure.
ALFALFA: Darla, wait.
(SCOFFS)
Hope you have insurance, Alfalfa.
(SIGHS)
(SCOFFS)
-(SIGHS)
-Officer Kennedy, I found this.
I thought you might want it back.
Women.
I don't think I'll ever understand them.
Join the club.
ALFALFA: (SINGING) Well, I don't know
If all that's true
'Cause you got me and baby, I got you
Babe
Hold it, hold it. That sounded terrible.
Alfalfa, what's the problem?
The problem is I don't got the babe.
And I don't got Darla.
I'm too depressed to sing.
Face it, Spank, we're never gonna be
ready in time for the talent show.
And we're never gonna make enough
money to save Grandma's bakery.
-Yeah.
Okay, so we had a little
setback with the taxi service.
A little setback? We lost money again.
And I lost Darla again.
To Waldo. Boy, do I hate that guy.
Want another reason to hate him?
Look. The brake lever from the taxi cab.
The cables didn't snap, they were cut.
(GASPS)
And who would want to
see us fail more than anyone?
-Waldo.
-Exactly.
That's it. I'm gonna tear him limb from limb.
Boy, Waldo messed with the wrong guy.
And he's gonna be sorry he did.
'Cause I'm a caged tiger. A hurricane.
And when someone crosses me, they unleash
the sledgehammer!
(GASPS)
Did I win?
Alfalfa, you're a genius.
You've given me a great idea.
How we can raise money
and help you get Darla back.
Isn't that what you said last time?
And the time before that?
ALL: Yeah.
This time, it's a sure thing.
Here you are, Darla.
One refreshing
jumbo strawberry fizz supreme.
Two straws.
Thank you, Waldo. It's so nice of you.
Anything for my partner in the talent show.
You and I are going to be unstoppable.
BUCKWHEAT: Come see
the wrestling match of the century.
-PORKY: Tell your friends!
-Alfalfa versus the Masked Marvel.
Yeah, you don't want to miss it.
One day only.
Alfalfa's gonna wrestle the Masked Marvel?
Sounds dangerous.
Sounds ridiculous.
He couldn't wrestle a teddy bear.
I think he's pretty brave to do this.
Something fishy here.
Would you excuse me a moment, Darla?
Well, of course, Waldo.
BUCKWHEAT: Alfalfa is gonna
beat the Masked Marvel.
PORKY: Yeah, tell your friends.
Excuse me, my good man.
You don't happen to know
who this Masked Marvel is, do you?
Yeah. But it's a secret.
Yeah, a big secret.
Spanky told us we're not supposed to tell.
I don't believe it.
Spanky would never tell you
who the Masked Marvel is.
You're too little.
We're not too little. We know.
Yeah, we know exactly who it is.
My friend,
Abraham Lincoln here, says you don't.
I bet you $5
you don't know who the Masked Marvel is.
Yeah? Well, guess what.
I'm going to be the Masked Marvel.
Yeah, Porky's gonna be the Masked Marvel.
Now pay up.
Well, you guys sure showed me.
Here, don't spend it all on gum balls.
-Yes!
-Yeah!
Gentlemen.
Who you callin' a gentleman?
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
I'm here to make you a proposition.
Yeah? What kind of proposition?
The best kind.
A profitable one.
Give me that.
Oh, there's more where that came from.
Follow me, there's a secret entrance.
Hurry, I hope it hasn't started yet.
I don't wanna miss it.
-Me neither.
-WALDO: Two tickets, please.
DARLA: Thanks for inviting me, Waldo.
Normally, I abhor violence,
but this seemed too good to miss.
Enjoy the match. Next!
Popcorn! Get your popcorn!
Can't enjoy a wrestling match
without a big old bag of popcorn.
Thank you.
Popcorn! Get your popcorn!
Welcome to the match.
Welcome.
Psst. Spank. How we doing so far?
Great. We got a full house.
Boy, are we gonna clean up.
-I'll take that.
-(WORM LAUGHS)
KID: I paid good money for that.
I just hope Alfalfa doesn't
hurt the Masked Marvel too badly.
Oh, I wouldn't worry about that.
(GASPS) Hey, this area is for wrestlers only.
-There's been a change of plan.
-Yeah.
(YELPS)
Hello, Spanky.
Waldo? I didn't think of you
as the wrestling type.
I couldn't pass up the opportunity
to see the Masked Marvel
wipe the floor with Alfalfa.
Oh, yeah?
You're gonna be disappointed, Waldo.
There's no way Alfalfa's going to lose.
Oh, really? Care to make it interesting?
What do you mean?
I'll bet you all the money
you've made from collecting admissions
that Alfalfa is going to lose.
You're on, Waldo. It's a bet.
(SPITS)
Sucker.
Showtime, Porky.
Wow, Porky. The costume looks great on you.
You even look taller.
Oh, and remember,
when I give you the high sign,
that's your cue to take a dive. Got it?
(BOTH SIGH)
Ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to the world
championship wrestling match of all time.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(BARKS)
Are you ready to wrestle?
(CHEERING)
In this corner,
the most dangerous man in wrestling.
Let's hear it
for the undefeated "Wildcat" Alfalfa.
(CHEERING)
CROWD: Alfalfa! Alfalfa!
How is he undefeated
if he's never wrestled before?
That's why he's undefeated.
Ah...
In this corner, his opponent,
the most feared man in wrestling.
The man, the myth, the legend,
the Masked Marvel!
(CROWD BOOING)
Whoo! Go, Masked Marvel!
-(CHEERING)
-(BOOING)
Okay, men, bring it in. Shake hands.
Men, I wanna see a fair fight.
Good luck and may the best man win.
And remember, Porky, make it look real.
(CHEERING)
And, fight.
CROWD: (CHANTING) Yeah! Alfalfa!
Ooh, yeah!
(CHANTING)
(YELLING)
Oh.
-Ooh. (LAUGHS)
-(GROANS)
Are you okay?
He knows he's supposed to lose, right?
Yeah. He's just makin' it look good.
Now get back in there, champ.
CROWD: Go, Alfalfa!
Go, Masked Marvel.
Okay, Masked Marvel.
Get ready for my
signature move, the pulverizer.
It puts the "ow" in pow!
(CROWD GASPING)
(BELL RINGS)
CROWD: Alfalfa! Alfalfa!
Alfalfa! Alfalfa!
(MUFFLED GRUNTING)
(POUNDING)
Holy guacamole. What happened?
(MUFFLED CRIES)
Hmm?
(CROWD CHEERING)
(WHINES)
And, fight.
CROWD: (CHANTING) Alfalfa! Alfalfa!
(YELLING)
Yes!
Whoa!
Porky.
Don't you see he's giving you the high sign?
-Oh, I can't watch!
-I can.
You're supposed to make it look real.
Not that real!
I don't remember this as part of the plan.
Me neither.
Spanky!
-Spanky! Spanky!
-(GASPS)
-Psst.
-(GROANS)
(SOFTLY) Alfalfa.
(GASPS)
If Porky's there, then who's...
Butch.
-Butch!
-(GASPS)
(GROWLS)
(GIGGLES NERVOUSLY)
Run, Alfalfa, run! Run for your life!
-(GROANS)
-Ooh!
What are you doing?
(SCREAMING)
Ooh!
Oh, no.
Yeah! And the winner is Butch!
(GROANS)
This isn't fair.
You cheated by putting Butch in the match.
And you cheated
by rigging the match with Porky.
I just cheated better.
But don't worry, it's going to a good cause.
I'm going to use the money
to put a security system in the tree house,
so I can keep you all out for good.
Come on, Darla.
DARLA: Sorry, Alfalfa.
You lost all our money, Spank?
How come you didn't ask us
before you did that?
BOTH: Yeah!
Because I'm the leader and I had to make
a split-second, executive decision.
I almost got killed for nothing.
Okay, so I made a bad call.
But don't worry. I'll come up with one
of my great ideas any second now.
Every time you come
up with one of your great ideas,
something bad happens.
-Yeah!
Well, someone has
to do the thinking around here.
You guys would be helpless without me.
Right, Alfalfa?
Alfalfa?
They're right, Spank.
We're all supposed to act as a team,
but you never act that way.
Ever.
And now, thanks to you,
it's too late to save Grandma's bakery.
It's over. We lost. Come on, guys.
Hey. Where are you going? Come back.
We still have a little time left.
Porky? Buckwheat?
You're too bossy, Spanky.
Yeah, too bossy.
(SIGHS)
Petey?
(WHINES)
(SIGHS)
Oh, Spanky!
(LAUGHS)
Want a muffin? It's hot.
No, thanks, Grandma. I'm not really hungry.
A Rascal doesn't want a muffin?
I've never heard of that before.
Never get tired of this.
Oh...
I'm gonna miss this old bakery.
I'm really sorry, Grandma.
Been trying so hard to make money to save it.
Spanky, I do appreciate
all of you trying to help me, honey.
But you're losing your bakery.
And we're losing our tree house.
You have your friends.
That's what's important.
Not anymore. They're all mad at me.
They say I'm bossy.
Well, is that true?
I'm not bossy. I just tell people what to do.
(CHUCKLES) That sounds kind
of bossy to me.
Well, someone has to give the orders.
Otherwise, nothing would ever get done.
A good leader has to be also a good listener.
'Cause you can't just give orders.
You have to inspire.
What difference does it make now?
They don't need me anymore.
Oh, they do need you, and you need them.
Let me show you something.
This is pure cocoa powder.
I want you to smell it.
(INHALES)
Mmm, smells great.
And now, try to taste it.
Yuck. It tastes bitter.
(LAUGHS) That's because it's cocoa.
And not until it gets mixed in
with all those other ingredients
does it become a wonderful cupcake.
Okay, but what does
this have to do with me and my friends?
Well, it's because you and your friends
are like the ingredients of my cupcakes.
Not until you all come together
do you become something wonderful.
(SIGHS)
Oh, June. June! I was just coming to see you.
We need to talk.
I think we've
said everything we need to say, Edgar.
No, then I need to say more.
I can't sleep, I miss you.
Junebug, I miss you. And I feel terrible
-about the way I acted the other day.
-Oh?
I'm really, really sorry
about what I said to the kids.
It's just every time they're around,
our dates get ruined, bad things happen
to us, every time.
Well, they're just children, Edgar.
They're not trying to make your life miserable.
They don't have to try, they're succeeding.
Oh, if you can't be patient with children,
you shouldn't date a school teacher.
I'll be patient.
I'll be patient. Just give me a chance.
I know I can be the kind of guy you want,
the kind of guy that likes kids.
Loves... I love kids.
Let me prove it.
You wanna prove it?
Well, tonight is the kids' talent show.
How would you like to be my date?
Are those kids gonna be there?
Yes, Edgar, those kids.
You wanted a chance to prove yourself.
That sounds great.
-Good.
-I love kids.
Now, are those flowers for me,
or are they just there to make you look pretty?
No, they're for you. And the balloons.
-I like chocolate, too.
-Okay, okay.
SERGIO: Ready to commence? Here we go.
Two, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
And here we go, spinning in an orbit
like the Mars Rover and spinning out.
Spinning in and dipsy-doodle.
Stop. Stop. Stop.
-What's wrong?
-It's very nice, Waldo.
But when you make this gesture...
I want to see a little more,
"I'm a pre-teen idol, worship me,"
and a little less,
"I'm your next president, vote for me."
Gotcha. Thanks, Sergio.
Now, about you, Darla,
when you come out of the double spin,
I want to see a bigger smile, like this.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Ha!
Bigger.
Bigger!
That's it.
My cheeks are starting to hurt.
(SIGHS)
Trust me on this, honey.
I was a smile consultant to presidents,
captains of industry, and super models
before I became
a choreographer and musical director.
Darla, Sergio's the best there is.
Okay.
Now for the finale.
I want you both to watch me
very, very,
very, very, very closely.
One, two, three!
Showgirl, showgirl, showgirl, showgirl.
Huh? Huh? Huh?
And the bunny hop!
Bunny hop! Bunny hop! Bunny hop!
And the fishing.
We are fishing. We are fishing.
(GASPS) The big one got away.
And we go into the La-Z-Boy!
And then the butterfly.
Ooh!
-(VASE SHATTERS)
-And for the big finish...
(GASPS) Ha!
Thank you. Thank you. Now, follow me.
Your costumes have arrived
from the tailor in Paris.
STYMIE: Remember when we carved these?
It was the day we finished building this place.
Do you ever think we'll
have another tree house as good as this one?
Even if we did, it wouldn't be this one.
What do you want?
Guys, we gotta go for broke.
We have to do the talent show.
We don't take orders from you anymore.
Yeah. You said it.
We're tired of
being bossed around all the time.
Okay, I admit that lately
on some select occasions,
-I may have been a little on the bossy side.
-Huh?
(BARKING)
Okay, okay, I've been a lot on the bossy side.
You happy?
And I shouldn't have bet that
money without asking you all first.
-Hmm.
-But this is our last chance to save
Grandma's bakery and our tree house.
You're not the leader anymore.
Well, then who is the leader?
I guess we're all the leaders now.
It's a democracy.
Yeah, democracy.
SPANKY: Fair enough.
So I'd like to propose something
to all the leaders of the club.
The grand prize to the talent show is $10,000.
That's more than enough
to stop Big Ray and Waldo.
But we've hardly practiced.
And when we have, we've been terrible.
Stinky.
What chance do we
really have of winning that show?
None, if we don't try.
(GROWLS)
You know, this club
is like one of Grandma's cupcakes.
You mean bad for our teeth?
No. We're like the ingredients.
Separately, we don't taste very good.
-Huh?
-But together, we're like an awesome cupcake
or something.
All I'm saying is,
we're better together than we are apart.
Now who's in?
Anyone?
(SIGHS)
(HEAVES)
All right, guys,
the International Silver String
Submarine Band is playing tonight.
Gather up your instruments.
BOTH: Okay!
For Grandma.
ALL: For Grandma!
ALFALFA: Come on, hurry, guys.
ANNOUNCER: Hello, Greenhaven!
Please give a warm welcome
for our host with the most,
Mr. Leo McCarey!
Thank you!
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome
to the talent show!
Who let you in here?
Since it's a talent show, we thought
there ought to be some talent in it.
WALDO: Come on, Darla.
Good luck, Alfalfa.
You, too, Darla. I hope you win.
(SHEEPISHLY) Or at least come in second.
(CHEERING)
All right, then, help me give a warm welcome
to our esteemed panel of judges
who will be deciding
which act is going to take home
the $10,000 grand prize tonight!
Our first act tonight,
an amazing duo of tap dancers.
Please put your hands
together for Tap Tenacity.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
They're really good.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, that was good.
Next on stage, please welcome
McKible the Magnificent.
-MCKIBLE: For my first trick...
-No.
...I'll pull a rabbit out of this hat.
Alakazam.
I will now shuffle the deck
and magically make your card reappear.
(LAUGHS)
-Um, is that it?
-No.
-That one?
Amateurs.
For my grand finale,
I will escape from these solid steel handcuffs
in three seconds.
One, two, three.
Ta-da!
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
-Mystical, wasn't it?
-(LAUGHTER)
Please help me welcome to the stage
the new musical stylings
-of Waldo and Darla.
-(LAUGHS)
(WHOOPING)
Notice how Waldo's name is first.
Mmm-hmm.
(SINGING) I've been a-searching
All this big wide world
Now finally I found
My candy girl
Candy girl
I found me a girl
She sets my heart awhirl
Candy girl
With hugging
-Hugging
-And kissing
-Kissing
-And loving
We're fishing. The big one got away.
-Mine
Whoa
And he twirls her around.
-They're super good.
-Yeah, I'd vote for them.
-What?
-Okay, what?
Candy girl
-She vows eternally
-Candy girl
Three, two, four.
To hold me
-Hold me
-And love me
-Love me
-Until the end of time
-He's mine
-Mine
Whoa
Candy girl
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
(GRUNTS)
Thank you. Thank you, everyone. Thank you.
(LAUGHS)
Number one!
Bravo!
Thank you.
-Thank you.
That was amazing.
It looks like Waldo and Darla
are the act to beat.
Spanky, I don't think
we can compete with Waldo and Darla.
Oh, come on.
What do they have that we don't?
Uh, fancy costumes.
Great choreography.
And a pretty girl singer.
Face it, we don't stand a chance.
Okay, men.
Maybe we don't have all those things.
Maybe Waldo has more money than we do.
Maybe he has more of everything than we do.
But this it. Let's go in there together,
as a team and give it our best.
At least we'll know we tried.
HOST: And now,
last but certainly not least,
our final act.
I'm intrigued by their name when I saw it.
Please welcome the one and only
International Silver String Submarine Band.
(SCATTERED APPLAUSE)
Hi, everybody.
Tonight,
we're going to perform I Got You, Babe.
It's an oldie, but a goodie.
And we'd like to dedicate it
to a very special lady who's here tonight.
-Ready, gang?
-RASCALS: Ready.
And a one and a two and a...
(PLAYING TUNELESSLY)
(YAWNING)
(SINGING) They say we're young
And we don't know
We won't find out until we grow
Well, I don't know if all that's true
'Cause you got me and baby, I got you
Babe
I got you, babe
I got flowers
In the spring
I got you
To wear my ring
And when I'm sad
You're a clown
And if I get scared
You're always around
-Don't let them say your hair's too long
-(CHEERING)
'Cause I don't care
With you I can't go wrong
Excuse me a second.
I have to handle something.
Okay.
Then put your little hand in mine
There ain't no hill
Or mountain we can't climb
(GASPS) Waldo? What are you doing?
Setting off the fire alarm.
Those Silver String Slimeballs can't win
if they can't finish their act.
But that would be cheating.
That would be winning.
You want to win, don't you?
It's not winning if you don't win fairly, Waldo.
I just can't believe
you would do something this sleazy.
Like my dad always says,
"It's not how you play the game,
it's winning that counts."
Oh, no, you're not, Waldo.
Huh?
(GRUNTS)
What kind of girl are you?
The kind who doesn't like cheaters
and who has a brown belt in karate.
(SCOFFS)
Doesn't matter. They'll never win anyways.
When I'm sad
You're a clown
And if I get scared
You're always around
Don't let them say your hair's too long
'Cause I don't care
With you I can't go wrong
Then put your little hand in mine
There ain't no hill
Or mountain we can't climb
Aw...
(TOGETHER) Babe
I got you, babe
I got you to hold my hand
I got you to understand
I got you to walk with me
I got you to talk with me
I got you
Babe
Everybody!
(CHEERING)
I got you, babe
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Oh. Looks like the judges
have made their decision.
(DRUM ROLLS)
And the winner is
the International
Silver String Submarine Band!
(GASPS)
(SOBBING)
(SCREAMS)
(CHEERING)
(BARKS)
Bravo!
SPANKY: Grandma.
Oh, you, kids. Thank you so much.
How are we gonna fit this
check in the ATM machine?
(LAUGHTER)
I don't know!
Hey, Alfalfa. You were great tonight.
Thanks. So were you.
But what about Waldo?
He just became a solo act.
And I'm looking for a new band to sing in.
Any ideas?
Well, Mrs. Larson,
I hope you're proud of yourself.
Not at all.
I'm just so proud of my Little Rascals.
Well, what about the tree house, Dad?
I'll build you
another new tree house from the ground up.
-But I want that tree house.
-Look, I've got a great architect.
-I want... They don't deserve it! I do!
-You know.
-I want! I want! I want it!
-I'll take care of it, all right?
Congratulations, kids. You were great.
You really were.
I'm even thinking you could perform
at the policemen's
Fourth of July picnic next month.
(CHEERING JOYOUSLY)
SPANKY: That would be awesome.
Or we could perform
at your wedding instead?
Uh, my wedding?
No. Alfalfa.
Yeah, hasn't he asked you to marry him yet?
He showed us the ring and everything.
-(BARKING)
-Uh...
(STUTTERS)
He certainly has, and I just told him...
"Yes."
-You have?
-(LAUGHS)
(LAUGHS)
She has.
Yes?
-Aw.
-(RASCALS GROANING)
(GAGS)
-Hi, Grandma.
-Well, you're just in time.
-Who wants muffins?
-ALL: Me!
Get in line. Ready?
Okay.
I caught it.
ALL: Thank you, Grandma!
(BARKING)
Here we go.
Come on, gang.
Wow!
Home, sweet home.
RASCALS: And how!
And how.
(BARKS)
BIG RAY: Keep your eyes closed. Ready?
(LAUGHING)
Wow.
Yes, it is "wow." It's got all the amenities.
Central air and heat,
Italian marble floors, granite countertops.
It's amazing, Dad.
Yes, it is. Here, you do the honors.
I christen thee "Club Waldo."
Members only, no riffraff.
Well, built to last.
Didn't see that coming.
I think I still have the receipt.