http://subscene.com/u/659433
Improved by: @Ivandrofly
(PHONE RINGING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
MAN: Hello? Tracey,
it's Bradley.
Bradley, where the
hell are you guys?
I am freaking out!
BRADLEY: Listen.
We fucked up.
What are you talking about?
Me and Doug are about to get married and
I haven't heard from him in two days.
Things got a little out of
control last night and we...
We lost Doug.
The wedding is in a few hours!
In Santa Barbara?
Yeah!
That's not gonna happen.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Look, I know everyone's a little
miffed we couldn't do Vegas this year,
but I'm telling you, Chief Loose
Slots is the next best thing.
I don't care where we have
my bachelor party, guys.
All that matters is that
we're celebrating together.
And that we don't have AIDS.
Anyway, I bet once you get
inside, it's not so bad.
(BEEPS)
All right!
Hey, it's cute.
I am honestly impressed
by how shitty this is.
You don't even need a blacklight
to see all the stains.
Maybe that's yogurt.
Nah, it says right here in
the pamphlet, it is semen.
Look, semen or no semen,
the important thing is that Doug
found his soulmate.
DOUG: Thanks, man.
Tracey just completes
in me, you know?
Did you say, "Completes in you"?
(GROANS)
You know, that reminds
of the love shared
between Peeta and
Katniss in The...
I'm gonna need you to stop
talking about that book.
No, I will not stop
talking about a novel
that blogcritics.org/reviews
said was "a page-Turner."
Have you even read it?
I'd love to, man. It's
just hard to find time
to enrol in 7th grade
and cut off my nuts.
Well then, maybe I'll find it hard
to find time to share my goodies.
Oh, nice. What do
you got in there?
I've got all kinds of fun stuff.
I have Chernobyl potato vodka,
standard-issue roofies,
I've got Chinese
black tar heroin,
I've got drug mule
rectum-release opium,
and some plug-in air fresheners.
How did that get in here?
All right. You got
any bath salts?
Tons. Help yourself.
I've also got skunk,
scoot, snap, flippers,
flappers, floppers,
uppers, downers,
and cyanide chewables.
Cyanide? Poison is the best.
Hey! Those are my
fun-time candies!
No. Uh-uh.
Every time we go out, we end up
blacked out and looking for somebody.
Vegas. Thailand. My nephew
Ruben's Bar Mitzvah.
Whatever, we got him back
in time for the service.
Yeah, and then he puked
all over the Torah.
(CHUCKLES)
Classic.
No, not classic. That
is a holy document.
(GROANS)
All right, let's just get Zach
dressed and head to the roof.
Dressed?
Small request, you guys. Could
somebody scratch my nuts?
I respectfully decline.
Non-alcoholic beer?
I told you. No risks tonight.
Pussy!
Excuse me, I was
calling you a pussy.
All right.
Let's put our shitty
rehab beers up
and toast Doug and Tracey.
I never thought your soulmate would
have an Adam's apple and a penis,
but, hey, life's a
journey, I guess.
We're happy for you, man.
Thanks, guys.
To Doug and Tracey.
BOTH: To Doug and Tracey.
And to a night we'll
never forget.
Those look really good.
Could you just pour
it in my cone?
(GROANS)
What the fuck?
Oh, God.
(GROANING)
What?
Scuba guy on the ceiling.
That makes sense.
Watch out!
Jesus!
You stepped on my balls, dude.
Sorry.
Where the hell are we?
Fuck if I know.
All I know is I am hungover
as shit right now.
I think I'm legally dead.
And my mouth tastes assy.
Please tell me I ate cheese.
I don't know. My
ass kind of hurts.
Oh, no! Did I do cocaine?
I'm deathly allergic to cocaine.
And I'm allergic to gluten.
ED: I hope that's gluten-free.
Oh, no.
Did we kill Waldo last night?
Um...
Maybe he was fucked to death.
(GAGGING)
(IN SING-SONG VOICE)
Morning, fellas!
Oh, God damn it, who let Zach
out of the straitjacket?
Is that a man-thong?
No, it's a regular thong.
I wear them all the time.
That's disgusting.
(GAGGING)
Okay, we need to find Doug and
get the hell out of here.
Somebody call him.
Where's my phone?
Oh, holy shit. Is this
a rocket launcher?
BRADLEY: Zach?
Dude!
Come on, we have to find Doug.
But that was...
Oh, my. Gentlemen,
this is quite a mess.
Okay, this is awkward, but I'm
just gonna go ahead and ask,
maid or hooker?
Manners! That is no way
to speak to your escort.
I always ask. The
answer's always the same.
It's been real nice talking to
you, but we're just gonna go.
I wouldn't do that.
Okay.
(SCREAMING)
We're on a fucking train?
I knew it!
That means you're Effie Trinket!
No, my name is Effing.
And the three of you are
on your way to the Games.
We discussed this all after
your courageous gesture.
EFFING: Why don't you look at your phone?
(CHATTER ON VIDEO)
Fucking Reaping, bitches!
ED: Oh, that's my phone.
Let me see it.
Doug's trying to kiss me again!
Doug, how you doing, buddy?
Fucking Reaping, bitches!
(ALL WHOOPING)
The first name of the girl...
Why is Lady Gaga on the screen?
And a happy Games goes to...
Change the channel!
Young Boo!
(BOOING)
And now for the boys.
I volunteer!
We volunteer for the
Hungover Games!
EFFING: What a
wonderful development!
Three of our brave volunteers
to add to the race.
May the chances be
ever in your comer.
Attica! Attica!
Okay, Okay.
Hey!
Oh!
(LAUGHING)
Okay.
Will you keep it down?
I can hardly hear myself drink.
Haymitch!
That's not my name, you
scruffy half-tard.
It's Justmitch.
Look, I'm enjoying all of this.
I really am.
Especially that little
blonde schoolgirl
situation you've got
going on right there.
But right now we
really just need to
find our friend and
be on our way.
The Sponsors will eat that
bromance shit up with a spoon.
Speaking of which.
Okay, let me guess, now you're gonna
tell us how to win the Games?
If you wanna live long enough to
find your Pansy little friend,
you'd best learn
to listen to me.
If there's two things I
know, it's hangovers
and murdering for sport.
And, hey, if you're
lucky enough,
one of y'all might get
out of here alive.
Did you just say "one" of us?
Mm-hmm.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I gotta find a vein.
WOMAN ON TV: You're
watching Capitol Sports.
Skip, it's my favourite
time of the year.
The weather is warming, the
tig ol' bitties is coming out
and right now, it's time
for the Hungover Games!
A great competition
shaping up this year.
Contestants from the
Superheroes District
and the Middle Earth District are
once again among the favourites.
The Puppet District and the Depp
District are particularly intriguing to.
Stephen A. Timplesmith.
Johnny Depp. Is there any
weirdo this guy won't play?
Straight freak!
Next up, we have The Real
Housewives of District 8.
Now these trashy bitches
have about a 0% chance
of surviving the Games.
White girls! Got me one at home.
Next up, we've got
the Django District.
Now Django is tough, but let's
get this straight, Skip.
He will never be LeBron.
Now, on the Django team
we have famed plantation
owner, Calvin Dandy.
Ironically, he's a
good friend of mine.
All right, next up we have the
Gratuitous Nudity District.
Dizzamn!
Everybody knows you cannot
make entertainment like this
without some inexplicable,
unwarranted nudity.
And finally our field is rounded
out by our outlying districts.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
District 9, Avatar.
District 10, Horror.
District 11, Katnip Everlean.
District 12, The
Hungover Guys.
Hey! That looks
like us and Doug!
Look, we've got about
48 hours to find him
and get him back
to that wedding.
Okay.
I guess it's time for us to
kill some motherfuckers.
(GIGGLES)
WOMAN: All right, I need three
to run this drill. Let's go!
I have the power!
Come on, cunt.
Oh, foo. Another year,
another murder.
What a crop of freakazoids.
(GRUNTING)
Stop swinging that in my face.
That is dangerous.
That is not a toy!
Zach, will you stop? You're
making us look like idiots.
No, Mr I Can't Even
Pick Up This Boulder.
(YELLING)
You're making us look bad
in front of the Sponsors.
Why are they all
dressed like that?
Looks like a Lady
Gaga family reunion.
Look, you see that?
Our odds are pretty
shitty right now.
ED: Hey, why do the puppets
have better odds than us?
Go ahead and cross check
your information.
Excuse me. Sorry, I hate to bother you
with this, but my friend is stuck.
World War Z, right?
No. Walking Dead, actually.
Oh, right, right. You
were the one that bit
that guy's ear and then
ate his face off, right?
Guilty.
So who else came
from your district?
Just that crazy blood-covered
bitch over there.
She scares the shit out of me.
I can see why.
Wow. Kaptain Kazakhstan is
really rocking that burlap sack.
Look at the size of
those Oompa Loompas.
You're welcome.
That's quite a bit of
shrubbery he has down there.
Can you say, "Ch-Ch-Ch-Chia"?
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Listen.
They're looking at you
like you're a meal.
Especially that flamboyant
Scandinavian guy.
Ew.
He wants to roll you in
sugar like a dick churro.
So what am I supposed to do?
They need to know that
you can take a punch.
What?
Yeah. Trust me.
Okay.
(GROANING)
(GIGGLING)
Okay, I'm good.
All right, I'm good.
The elbow didn't count.
Come on, come on.
Now, just remember, this hurts
you more than it hurts me.
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHING)
Why, dude? Why?
I don't know. I forgot why
we're even doing this.
(ED GROANING)
I'm pooped.
I want a vitamin
water or something.
Not bad.
That means I need
a vitamin water!
Okay, okay, I'll get it! I'll
get a vitamin water for you!
Not again.
(GRUNTING)
My right nut is numb.
I can take a hit, Zach.
I can give one, too.
You ready for the thunder?
Well, here's the lightning!
Oh, son of a hooker, that hurt!
Hey, watch it!
Sorry, I didn't see
anything, I swear to God!
My elbow may have grazed...
Ed.
Hey...
Okay.
Uh...
How are you?
Hey... Hi.
You.
Oh.
You don't remember me.
It's Katnip.
Katnip Everlean.
I'm sorry. It's just
that last night, we...
You were wasted.
Yeah.
You guys bought us drinks
after the Reaping.
You said you were going
district-hopping, and you up and left.
Jeez! You guys clearly
have a drinking problem!
Um, is that a talking bird?
I'm a talking Jay,
you birdbrain.
For a nerd, you're pretty dumb.
Sorry. He's really nice
once you get to know him.
Yeah, just ask your mom.
That's rude.
Go away. How are you
feeling, by the way?
Well, besides the
raging hangover,
the free-for-all death
match coming up,
and the shit taste I can't
get out of my mouth,
I'm actually doing great.
Hey, look, it's
Dumb and Dumberer.
A talking Jay.
So elegant.
Hey, get your mitts off me!
Where'd you go to
school, Penn State?
Wow, okay, yeah.
I'm not even gonna try to
process that right now.
Excuse me?
It's Katnip, Bradley.
We met last night.
Yeah, Bradley.
Yeah, right, okay.
About last night,
do you have any idea what
happened to our friend, Doug?
Uh...
(LAUGHING) No. But I did wake-up
today and I saw you all volunteered.
That was really brave of you.
That is one word for it.
No, seriously. You guys were talking about
it so much you inspired me to do it.
That's why I took my
little sister's place.
That was stupid. Sorry.
You have a little sister?
Is she into husky bearded guys with
low-level personality disorders?
(YELLING)
Nice!
I like this girl.
That got more hand than apple.
(BUZZER RINGS)
Attention, battlers,
battlers, battlers.
The training centre
is now closed.
It is time to die.
Make that work.
That's my catchphrase, you know.
"Make that work."
WOMAN: Hello? A
little help here?
AUTOMATED VOICE: 20, 19, 18,
17,
16,
15,
14...
Doug! Dougie! Doug man!
Doug? Doug?
Doug!
Doug? Where are you, man?
Where the fuck is he?
Doug? Doug?
Was that him?
Hey, sweetheart.
Looking for a white guy, yea
high, generic, unfunny,
really forgettable. Was
that him right now?
Come on, talk to me.
She's a goddamn
mute or something.
Man, fuck you, white boy.
What are you guys doing here?
You need to get to your
tube room immediately.
Okay, you don't have to
manhandle me! Oh. My tea!
You just got bubble tea all
over my control panel.
Get him out of here!
16,
15,
14,
13,
(LIFT CLANGS)
12...
Jeez, guys. Portion
control much?
No, no, no! Don't step off
the platform, we'll explode!
Oh, God.
MAN OVER PA: Now the contestants
line up before the Pornucopia,
no doubt picking out the
weapons they wanna grab.
Doug, Doug, come on, man.
Where are you?
He must be on the other side
of that tent full of...
What are those? Sex weapons?
ED: Where the fuck are we?
MAN: This is a great
time to mention
that the weaponry has
been provided by.
Delta Venus, Queen
of the Sex Toys.
(DRUMS POUNDING)
Let the killing begin!
Shit, come on! Maybe we can find
him before he gets slaughtered.
I got this. Yeah.
Fuck! My hammie! I
should've stretched!
Oh, I should've stretched first!
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Yeah!
Holy cow. White wine!
I hate white wine!
Okay, barrel roll!
BRADLEY: Shit, really?
Are you all right?
At least tell me that
looked awesome. Yeah. Sure.
Oh, it's a red man. High five?
No? How about this?
You like?
Put penis away, kemosabe.
(ALL CHEERING)
Is that labia?
That is a bear!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
Wait, wait! No, no, no!
Doug must have come up
right here! Where is he?
Fuck!
Whoa!
Come on, man.
Come back here!
Fuck! And where's Zach?
Well, hey there, boy.
Ow!
Goddamn women!
Don't mind if I do.
Now, now, don't do nothing
foolish there, N-word.
I like the way you die, boy.
(SCREAMING)
Django's free!
Take that, black! Dude!
You like baseball,
Jackie Robinson?
Oh!
TEDDY: Shit! Oh, that's cruel!
Hey, you thirsty?
Here's some tea!
Teabag! Oh, that's nasty.
That's real gross.
Bag, bag, bag!
Please stop. Just please stop.
Wait, you want some fucking
lemon? Yeah, bag it up!
Come on! Jesus!
I know that looked
bad, but, come on,
let's keep in mind that the purpose of
this competition is to kill people, yeah.
So that was technically
not a hate crime.
I'm not a racist. I got like eight black
guys on my fantasy football team.
I mean, not the quarterback obviously,
that's a thinking man's position.
Seriously?
(SHUDDERS)
Oh, no, not this!
Fuck this! Go!
Whatever.
(ALL GROAN)
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
I just watched Django get
kerb-stomped by a Teddy bear,
two of our friends are Mia,
and, oh, did I mention,
did I mention this, that my
mouth still tastes like shit!
All right, dude,
quit being a baby.
My ass still hurts, too. You
don't hear me whining about it.
It just won't go away.
BOTH: Oh!
What's happening, honkies?
What the hell? That Asian guy!
Really?
What? Oriental man cannot
practise acrobatics in the woods?
You racist assholes think
I'm Viet Cong or something?
Wait, why the fuck are you here?
We had a sick night last night.
I still hungover.
Just tell us what the
fuck happened, okay?
You mean you don't remember?
No.
Human Centipede, bitches!
What's a Human Centipede?
Human Centipede only the
greatest idea ever.
You sew a chain of people
from asshole to mouth hole.
You share the same
digestive system.
Check it out.
We shit brothers! Oh!
I was the middle.
No!
What the fuck? Fuck!
Why would we do that fucking...
That's disgusting!
You have really potty mouth.
You get it? Potty mouth!
Because your mouth was potty.
(GAGGING)
Just let it out, man.
(LAUGHING)
Wait, hold on. I was in the
front, so I didn't eat any shit?
Nope. You were total
party pooper.
Literally.
(CHUCKLING)
Well, that's a relief, huh?
ED: That's disgusting.
(YAWNING)
It's getting really late.
You know what they say,
early to bed, early
to Human Centipede.
I gotta go Human Centipede
with the Olsen twins.
They've done it before.
See you gay boys later.
Let's find a place to sleep,
buddy. It's been a long day.
Oh, Jesus!
I didn't eat corn.
Yeah, I did.
(GROANING)
Shit, human shit inside me.
Hey, man, we've all been there.
Really?
Fuck, no, I've never been there.
It's the most disgusting
thing I've ever heard.
(CRYING)
It is real gross.
Hey, shit-for-breath,
be quiet for a second.
Look over there. Someone's
got a fire going.
That's dumb.
Yup.
MAN: I appreciate the spirited
conversation, gentlemen,
but we all know
there's no debate.
I am the weirdest
of all the Depps.
I mean, for fuck's
sake, I'm a pirate
who sashays round
like a bloody poof.
And what of you there, top hat?
Well, I do have my fair share
of psychological issues.
My speech patterns mirror
those of sexual molesters.
I keep a bunch of
dwarves as my slaves.
And I masturbate
in the chocolate.
(GIGGLES)
Every single batch.
I think I might puke.
(WHISTLES)
Nice work, Tonto.
Say good night, weirdos.
A bloody smoke signal!
You fucked us, you
bloody Native!
Tonto sick of white man.
Yes, but we're all Depps, mate!
Tonto especially sick of Depps.
Are you gonna rape
and murder us?
TEDDY: Keep it in your
pants, Scissorhands.
Me next! Me next!
If you don't mind, I prefer
it in a chocolate factory.
That's brutal.
Now that's what I
call a deep throat.
That means a dozen gone in the
first eight hours, Stephen A.,
and I think I smell
an alliance forming.
What the fuck do you
mean, an alliance?
If it's supposed to be
every man for themself,
they ain't gonna create
no fucking alliance.
They're gonna be out there
killing each other.
That don't make
no goddamn sense!
I know. I can barely keep myself
from killing you, Stephen A.
Can't fault you there.
THOR: That creepy,
pale guy was bananas!
B-A-N-A-N-A-S!
TEDDY: Hey, Thor, we get it.
You like cock.
Fuck, dude.
Don't stay here, don't stay
here, don't stay here.
Anyway, guys, I'm pooped. What say
we just stay here for the night?
ZACH: Do you guys think
there's a Chili's out here?
I'll settle for an Applebee's,
but it would be grudgingly.
What the fuck is he
doing with them?
I think he's looking for a reasonably
priced casual dining restaurant.
Thor?
Awesome Blossom?
Tonto? Jalapeno poppers?
Something for you, Bloody?
If you talk to me again, I
will murder your whole family
and terrorise whatever little Podunk
town you come from, you hear me?
Okay, more fully loaded
potato skins for me then.
How about a bear claw?
Maybe a bun for the wiener?
All right, table for six, seven.
Ladies?
You know, I don't think
we fit the dress code.
Oh, it's a Chili's. You
guys will be fine.
I kill him now, yes?
No.
Let's lock him in a
burning gymnasium
and wait till his guttural
screams slowly fade away.
TEDDY: Easy, Scary.
We need to keep that fat sack
of Asperger's alive for now.
He's our best shot at finding
those two other fuck nuggets.
Would you guys shush already? I
need to get my beauty sleep.
(GROANS)
I'm never gonna be
able to sleep now.
I'm gonna have
insomnia for sure.
(SIGHS)
This was the worst day ever.
(SNORING)
What the...
Shit!
Jesus! Shut up, Ed.
Got hit with a fucking Boulder.
Hey!
She seems friendly.
What are you nodding at?
I don't...
Use your fucking words!
She wants us to saw the hive off
so that it falls
onto them below.
GIRL: No fuckin' shit.
Vulgar little child.
Oh, I have a Swiss Army knife.
Okay.
Uh, hey, you know, I'm
not really athletic.
Do you mind just
climbing up there?
Take one for the team?
Come on.
Nice.
Oh, snap! Now looky here.
Them motherfucking hungover honkies
got a trick up their sleeve.
Is that a Swagger
Jacker nest, Skip?
Correct, you are. Now these guys
are gonna have to be careful.
Swagger Jackers are
no ordinary bees.
They are genetically
engineered wasps
that when they sting you,
they drain your body's
natural swagger supply.
In other words, they make
you a straight bitch.
Precisely. And just a few
stings can prove lethal.
I'm crossing my fingers, Skip.
Me, too.
I know you aren't trying
to cut down our nest!
Does that hurt?
Yes, it hurt!
Dude, don't be a pussy. Saw!
(SNORING)
Oh, God.
They're not gonna sleep in
much longer. Hurry up, man!
(SWAGGER JACKERS CHATTERING)
Hurry up!
Get away from the
nest, jerk-off!
TEDDY: Flew in my fucking hole!
(SHRIEKING)
TEDDY: Oh, shit! Got
a bee in my cock.
(ALL SCREAMING)
Oh, Jesus.
Hey, you okay?
A couple of Swagger
Jack-offs stung me.
(SLURRING)
But I'm good.
Hey, hey, hey, sure? You
don't look too good.
I don't feel too good.
No, no, no, no! Bradley!
I'm coming for you!
You guys see that?
(SCREAMING)
Shit! Shit!
This chubba has
literally no swag.
Hey! I was looking all
over for you guys!
(ALL GROANING)
BRADLEY: God, my face hurts.
Oh, I can feel my
heartbeat in my ears.
It's throbbing.
It's really loud.
Hey. Does my head look weird?
It's so loud.
No.
But your body is super tiny.
It is?
Your body is super tiny, man.
Do I look okay?
Yeah.
You're cool.
I am cool, thank you.
This is napping
cool time for me.
(GROANS)
This is a terrible pillow.
Sleep sounds good.
Hi.
I've missed you.
I've missed you, too, Katnip.
I'm only 17.
What?
Nothing.
I have something to show you.
ED: Yes.
Yes.
No!
Why?
Hey, are you having a
wet hallucination, Ed?
Yeah, you know, a
nocturnal emission?
God, just when I thought I
couldn't hate you any more.
Hey, ease up. We didn't
choose this way of life.
Yeah, it's no picnic.
You know how hard it is
to motorboat yourself?
God, please don't do it.
This is the worst wet
dream of my life.
See?
Zach, how can you
even ruin boobs?
Hey, does my mouth
look like a nipple?
Uh...
It kinda does.
Okay, this is getting weird.
Maybe we should wake him up.
Okay, okay, okay.
On my count.
One, two, three!
BOTH: Boom!
Bearded boobies!
(SHOUTING)
How long have we been out, man?
Couple days.
I've been licking your wounds.
What?
I've been watching you guys sleep,
nursing you back to health.
Scrotal touching was just
for medicinal purposes.
We saw those Swagger Jackers
sting you, man. A lot.
Yeah, but their
venom has no effect
if you have no swagger to Jack.
Hold on a second.
What the hell were you
doing with that gang, man?
You were gonna
help them kill us?
You guys, I don't do
well with peer pressure.
I didn't really
want to murder you.
But you would have?
Oh, come on!
I'm sorry! I had a
moment of weakness!
I nursed you back to health.
Don't you feel swaggy?
Yeah.
I really do, actually.
It's because of this.
Swagger Balm.
"Ingredients, aloe, palm oil,"
"and Kanye West extract?"
Tastes just like the real thing.
(GAGGING)
WOMAN: Hey, boys.
We thought we smelt
some swagger.
Puts the rocks down, buddy.
(WHOOPING)
I just wanna get sloppy
drunk and slutty!
Way too late for
that, sweetheart.
I get the blondes.
Okay.
That's rich!
So then I divorced that asshole
and took half of everything.
That's how I got my lucky charm.
Is it that ring? It's lovely.
I'm not talking about that.
I'm talking about
this.
(LAUGHING)
Is that a fucking ball?
Neat!
I told you, when I took half of
everything, I meant half of everything.
You girls are such a treat.
Great! Here's to good friends!
And you two bitches.
Well, well, well,
if it isn't the popular girls.
Nice blood outfit, honey, but
that's worse than pleather.
What is that, O positive?
Awful. So last season.
What is that, gas?
You got that on my Gucci dress!
Bitch!
What are you doing?
Do you know how much this cost?
Wait, I just wanna see
where this is going!
Zach, let's go!
Game, set...
No! No!
Match!
(ALL SCREAMING)
WOMAN: My tits are gonna melt!
You wanted to see me,
President Snowbama?
Tell me, have you
ever been hungover?
Why, yes.
I'm actually hungover right now.
Never pass out in a crowded bar.
Yes, they shaved a
dick on my face, Sir.
These hungover contestants,
people seem to care about them.
Yes? Is that a bad thing, Sir?
The Games are a distraction
so people won't notice
the crap we peddle out.
Sequels, remakes, spoofs.
When people start to
care, bad things happen.
Ratings go down,
beards get shaved.
I've got it under control, Sir.
It's a kitty cat.
'Cause you're a little pussy.
Thank you, Mr President.
(CANNON BLAST)
Shit! Any one of these
Cannon blasts could be Doug.
We don't even know
if he's still alive.
Hey, I'm scared, too, but the one
thing that's not gonna get us
back to that gay wedding is
sitting here crying about it.
There should only be a
handful of contestants left.
We can do this, man.
You guys.
Hey, since we're standing around
sharing things, I've got a doozy.
What the hell did you do, Zach?
You know the air fresheners
that I plugged in?
Best thing you ever did.
They were delightful.
Well, it wasn't Lilac or Morning
Mist or Brazilian Breeze.
It was Midnight Berry.
What the shit is Midnight Berry?
From the novels. It's aromatic.
What's so bad about that?
Well, I didn't
finish my thought.
It's aromatic,
poisonous and lethal.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Are you kidding me?
I think you guys are getting Hung up on
the fact that it's poisonous and lethal.
They smell fresh.
Smell.
Jesus! Fuck, man!
God!
(GROANS)
Yeah, it says right
here on the label,
"May 'cause transportation
to futuristic dystopia."
"Maw."
You're the reason we're here,
you sausage-fingered fuck!
This is all your fault!
Hey, you said you liked the scent!
Because I like floral scents!
Well, there, he said it!
So now I forgive you guys
and we can move forward!
I... Ooh!
I hope you die out here.
No.
You fucked up.
That was harsh.
The sloth is heading towards
the soup pot. Over.
MAN: 10-4, squaw without bra.
Nice.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah. Real nice.
Stupid Midnight Berry!
Why does something so
fragrant have to be so bad?
(SIGHS)
Thank God, thank God. Thank God.
(WOMEN GIGGLING)
Get outta the way.
Yeah, that's more like it.
There.
I thought I'd never say this,
but Daddy wants blue balls.
MAN OVER PA: Attention,
everyone. Attention.
We have some new
rules for you kids.
From this point forward
contestants of colour will be
granted special consideration.
Yes, I'm talking about
affirmative action, people.
Zach! It's the 21st century...
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
Whatever you say.
I think I speak for all of us when
I ask you to give us some privacy.
With pleasure.
WOMAN: Boys, have at him.
Nice weave, bitch.
Her hair is all natural.
Take that back!
You wanna kill her, you
gotta kill me first.
(SCREAMS)
Blue scalp. Rarest of scalps.
Your turn, dumpy.
Yeah!
Gratuitous nudity no match
for gratuitous violence.
Farewell, my Princess.
(CRYING)
Maybe just one more squeeze.
Go in a bit tighter.
What the hell is he doing?
Nothing on three.
I don't know.
Oh, no.
Vivian, would you
please get IT in here?
Oy vey.
What up, bitches?
You fix computers?
Hell yeah!
I may be sociopathic gangster, but
I'm still Asian, motherfuckers!
What?
No, no, no, I really don't think you
should be messing around with...
Finished!
Excellent.
Thank you.
We're back up, people.
Oh, come on, Zach!
That not cool.
(LAUGHING)
Excuse me. You may leave now.
What, I get no tip? No.
I take cash, credit, no cheque.
But I'll take a bump of coke.
All right, get the hell
out of here. Chop-chop!
(SIGHS)
What to do, what to do?
You wanna get the ratings up?
I got one word for you,
bromance.
That's not a real word.
You wanna give these
districts a story?
Well, you need to keep
these guys together.
Not separate.
Hmm.
I got one word for you,
heroin.
"Heroin" is the one word?
No.
I'm just really looking
for some. You holding?
I'm sorry.
I got one word for you,
dicksauce.
"Dicksauce"? "Dicksauce"
is the one word?
You can't buy that shit.
Well, thank you. Your time
here has been so valuable.
(SHOUTS)
Bromance. Hmm.
(PANTING)
Hey, hey, hey.
Is that water?
Fuck it, I'm thirsty as hell!
Don't put your mouth on that.
It's gross.
Do you think it's filtered?
Really?
I only drink bottled water.
Didn't you just have shit in
your mouth? All right! Fine!
I didn't intentionally
have shit in my mouth.
It tastes a lot like blood, though.
(SPITTING)
What?
MAN OVER PA: Check, check.
Hot mic. Hot mic.
Attention, everyone.
Attention.
There has been a
change in the rules.
Yes, from now on, multiple
Victors may be crowned
if they survive the Games and
share a long-standing bond
of exceptional male bromance.
They can do that?
Yes, I am allowed to do this.
I can do whatever the fuck I want,
I'm a motherfucking Gamesman!
Noted.
So good luck to you all
and may the probabilities
be ever to your liking.
So that means we can all
get out of this alive.
All we have to do
is find Doug and
Zach! Zach! Zach! Zach!
BRADLEY: We're sorry, buddy!
Zach!
Where are you, man?
You dropped your glasses.
Hey, quick question.
If they can just change
the rules at anytime,
why don't they just pick who they
want to win and make it happen?
This is confusing to me.
Don't worry about it, man.
It's just a plot hole.
Hold on a sec. What?
Zach said they used these birds
to find each other in the book.
Like by whistling to them.
Hmm.
Worth a shot.
(WHISTLING)
Yeah, that worked.
Shut up.
All right, one more time.
Damn it.
Sure, I'll help.
(BOTH WHISTLING)
TALKING JAY: Suck my bird cock!
Come on! Really?
Marco! Marco!
We don't have time for this!
Marco!
Why couldn't you
just say, "Polo"?
There you are.
Listen, not that I give a hoot,
but your fat friend Zach's about a
half mile away from here with Katnip.
How do you know?
A little Birdie told me.
And by a little Birdie, I mean a
chickadee who gave me a beakjob.
You want to find this
overgrown garden gnome?
Yeah. And Katnip. And stop
fucking yelling, man.
TALKING JAY: Anyway, that's why I'm not
allowed to go near schools any more.
Good to know.
Yeah!
You guys! Oh. My God!
I missed you guys so much!
Yeah. Okay.
Where's Katnip?
She's over there.
You've got the talking Jay!
Sorry, Bradley, but this guy just
made me crap down your shirt.
Everything he says is so foul!
Yeah, he says disgusting stuff.
Come on!
Where are we going? Fuck.
Ooh.
Maybe I should tell her I'm...
No, no, I should not.
(SIGHS)
Wow, yeah, this is not...
This isn't pervy at all.
Yes, it is.
Hey! Perverted ass cracker!
Hey!
Trees are nice here.
Ed!
Oh, my God, you're okay!
Hey!
Oh...
Um, that is a respect boner. A
boner achieved out of respect.
Um...
You know I'm 17, right?
La, la, la!
What? I can't hear you! It
just got real loud in here!
Hey, guys. Hell.
Hi.
No sign of Doug?
Nope. Nothing.
Wait a minute.
He came with your district. You were
the last one to see him at the arena.
Do you have any
idea where he went?
Well, do you feel
like telling us?
Okay, I've had about enough of
this. Hey, hey, hey, come on!
That's like a triple hate crime.
Hey.
They're just looking
for their friend.
Do you want to tell them?
For me?
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
You got Norsed!
Shit!
What the hell is wrong with you?
Oh, shit!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
That took awhile. Who wants
to go get margaritas?
What the frick do we do now?
I don't know, Zach,
it's been a while since
I've had to battle
the God of Thunder!
Hey, blondie!
Pick on someone your own size!
(CHOKING)
Yeah! Nice shot, Ed!
I just killed a God.
Did you guys see...
Oh, shit.
Hey.
You okay? Come on, wake-up.
You're a doctor, right?
You can help her.
I'm a dentist.
Check her teeth.
♪ ZACH:  Ave Maria ♪
♪  Gratia plena  ♪
You guys wanna
hear some Wu-Tang?
She was so young.
What a waste.
There, buddy.
She had so much ahead for her.
Her first kiss.
Her first handjob.
Her first bukkake.
Unless you guys wanna
give her a send-off.
No. Wow.
She's at peace.
Or in some dark, endless abyss.
Wait.
We need to pay our respects.
With a salute.
Two in the pink.
One in the stink.
ALL: Forever.
Can I ask you a
serious question?
Yeah, anything, man.
Which one's the pink and
which one's the stink?
Because they're both pinkish.
And they both stink.
Yeah.
Remember when I told you
to ask me anything?
Forget I said that.
You don't know, do you?
MAN OVER PA: Hello. Attention,
everyone. Attention.
It is my profound pleasure
to invite you all to
a feast!
Feast?
And this will be no
ordinary occasion.
We know that you
all want something
and you want it bad.
And we are aiming to be
very generous hosts.
Now, there will be some
weapons available,
but I strongly suggest
that you all BYO weapon.
Because I don't
wanna get blamed
if we run out like
the last time.
That was embarrassing.
Oh!
I also really need
someone to bring ice.
I had a sign-up sheet
at the Reaping.
Nobody fucking chose ice.
What's the big deal?
Come on, somebody. Be
a rock star. Own it.
Ice, out.
Has anyone seen a
7-Eleven out here?
Attention, everyone. Attention.
We are looking for a competitor
named Harry Ballsonya.
Harry Ballsonya?
Please report to the
control room immediately.
I repeat, Harry Ballsonya.
This will be the...
(ALL GIGGLING)
Oh, damn it! Who did this?
Making me look like
a fucking asshole!
(SHUSHING)
We really should
have brought ice.
Don't worry about it.
Hey!
Is that a cell phone?
Maybe we can use it to call the
wedding. Stall them or something.
I'm on it. Hey!
I wouldn't do that.
See those lumps of dirt?
Dog poops.
Landmines.
If you guys are gonna get through
this, you better watch your step.
Check it out.
Hey, when you said, "you guys,"
are you not coming with us?
I need to go find
Tonto and kill him,
but this is for you.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, if you...
If you just wait,
we'll go with you.
We can protect you.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Awww.
Oh, you're serious.
Yeah.
Look, the only reason I don't
want you guys coming with me
is because you would
completely fuck it up.
No of fence. Oh.
Okay.
I really do love you.
Frankly, I'm surprised
you're still alive.
Okay, got it.
Bye, Ed.
Yup, bye, Katnip.
Be safe. Yeah.
Try not to die.
Sorry, buddy. She'll be back.
Mm-hmm. Although unless
she has a birthday
in the next couple of
hours, she'll still be 17.
Yeah, got it.
I know we're in a futuristic
dystopia and everything,
but jailbait is
jailbait, brother.
Yeah, what dating site did
you get her from? J-Bait?
Get it?
Not now, Zach. But good one.
Hey! Hey!
What the fuck are you doing?
What Katnip would do.
(EXCLAIMS)
Okay, I'm good. Oh, shit.
God damn it.
What?
Oh.
Hi.
You mind if I just
grab a weapon?
(SCREAMS)
It's too bad you couldn't
help your friend.
A generic straight man.
What was his name?
Doug.
And he's not a straight man.
Well, he's probably long dead.
And soon,
you'll be long dead, too.
(SCREAMING)
This is for threatening
my friend!
This is for being a bitch
to me in the woods!
This is for calling
my hometown "Podunk"!
This is for not
returning my sexts!
And this is for
ruining the prom!
Yeah!
Holy fucking shit.
You just brutally
murdered a young girl.
Yeah.
And the weird thing is I thought
it would take more hits.
But I guess you live and learn.
Or at least, she doesn't.
Am I right? Am I right?
Yeah, whatever you say.
Of course.
All right, look, we can still
get out of this thing.
We just gotta get this
bromance thing back in gear.
Oh, be careful! Oh, Jesus.
If you were Doug,
where would you be?
Maybe these guys can
help us find him.
Hey, little buddies.
How are my favourite
imitation puppets doing?
Oh, fuck! My hammie, again!
Kick his ass!
Let's fuck him up!
Wait, wait! I thought you puppets
were the good guys! What the fuck?
We used to be.
Yeah, but now we've
stared death in the face.
We've seen the depths of human suffering.
And we're already dead inside.
Yeah.
That's awful.
My God, I'm sorry.
Come on, you bitch! Yeah,
you scared coward!
You're not man enough
to fuck with me!
You wouldn't last two minutes
in my world, you bitch!
Is that the Mike Tyson rant?
Fuck you. Fuck you, you ho.
I'll fuck your ass in front of everybody!
Yeah, that's definitely the Tyson.
Enough talk! Kill them!
(ALL CLAMOURING)
(SCREAMING)
A mine is a terrible
thing to waste.
That was actually a
pretty good one, Zach.
Yeah? Yeah.
At least that was
just my reader copy.
Guys, a little help?
You four-eyed fuck.
You see this coming?
(SCREAMS)
Fuck me! Right in the smarts!
That's painful!
But also hilarious.
(MOANING)
That's my girl!
Oh, my God! Oh, my
God, you're hurt!
You should see the other guy.
You killed Tonto?
Yeah.
Come on, we need to get you
in the shade. Can you walk?
It's okay, I got you.
I got you, I got you.
Move! Move!
It's okay.
You all right? You're
gonna be okay.
It's okay, I got you. I got you.
I got you. There you go.
You're gonna be okay. It's all
right, it's not that bad.
(SHUSHING)
Ed, it's okay.
No, no, no, it's not okay!
You need help.
Ed, one of us had to die.
Well, I wish it was me.
Me, too.
What?
Sorry.
That slipped out. Sorry. Yeah,
that came out real fast.
It's okay.
Um...
Speaking of,
since...
Since this is it for me,
do you want to see them?
See what?
My boobs, dummy.
I...
I would. Very much.
Okay.
I know you've been
waiting for this.
Pretty nice, huh?
Unbelievable.
Wow.
No tan lines.
Unbelievable.
But if he'd move a little
bit, I could see them better.
Ed? Yeah, yeah.
The light is starting to fade.
Will you look deep into
my eyes as I fade away?
Absolutely, Katnip.
Ed, up here.
Yeah? I'm sorry. I love them.
I mean, I love you.
I love all of you.
I know.
Goodbye.
I'll...
I'll see you soon enough.
Okay.
Wait, what's that
supposed to mean?
Katnip?
Hey, do you know something
I don't? Am I next?
(CANNON BLAST)
Yeah, she's dead,
that'd be weird.
That'd be weird. I'm sorry.
I think it's time
we made the call.
(PHONE RINGING)
Tracey, it's Bradley.
MAN: I don't know who you
are or what you want.
Fuck, I think I dialled
the wrong number.
What I do have are a
particular set of skills.
If you give my daughter
back to me now,
that'll be the end of it.
But if you don't...
Okay.
I will...
(ENDS CALL)
Crazy.
Definitely not Tracey.
Let me try again.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
Tracey, it's Bradley.
Hey, man, what's wrong?
I don't know.
The first girl lever
loved just died.
I watched you murder a
girl with your bare hands.
We're as good as dead.
And the worst part is we
lost our best friend.
That's what's wrong.
I can't help but accept some
responsibility for this.
Yeah, no, I blame you
for the majority of it.
Seriously? I mucked up
the bachelor party.
I got us stuck in some
weird alternate universe.
This whole thing just went
right down the tubes!
I didn't even get to be a part
of the Human effing Centipede.
What did you just say?
I don't care how awkward it is,
sharing a gastric system
is a life experience.
I could have
scrapbooked about it.
No, no, before that.
This whole thing
went down the tubes.
Doug!
Are you having a
flashback montage?
The tubes! I know where Doug is!
Bradley!
Where are you guys?
What's going on?
Bradley!
Bradley? Bradley?
Hey, Tracey! It's Ed!
Ed! Ed, what in the H-E-double
hockey sticks is going on?
We're gonna go pick
up Doug right now,
so don't you worry your pretty
little man face about it.
Okay, but we gotta go. We'll
see you real soon, bye!
What the fuck, man?
I know where Doug is!
Come on! Go!
Let's go, let's go!
Hello? Hello?
This is it! Doug's
tube never came up!
What?
Well, if he's not down
there, where the hell is he?
Okay, let's face it.
Doug's not in the tube.
There was no sign of him
in the arena. He is gone.
That is a fact.
You fucking idiots!
(ALL GROANING)
God fucking damn it!
Jesus!
That bush is angry!
I'm not "that bush," you
bearded piece of afterbirth!
It's me! Doug!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Shut up! All you guys,
just shut the fuck up!
You guys forget me all
the fucking time!
In Vegas! In this fucked-up
alternate universe!
Yeah.
I'm barely in the
goddamn movie trailer!
It's true, I don't even
think he's on the poster.
I never get any punchlines,
and you keep leaving me in
enclosed fucking places!
You think maybe we can talk to
you about this at sea level?
Not this time.
This time, I get the last laugh.
Jeez, dude! Wait, wait, wait!
You're right! You're right!
We're sorry.
We haven't given you
your proper due.
You are the perfect blend
of handsome and humourless.
Without you, there are no jokes.
Hell, without you,
there is no us.
You may be a gay man,
but you are the best damn
straight man we've ever met.
Ah!
I could never murder you guys.
(ALL SIGH)
You!
Wait here one second.
(ALL GRUNTING)
You guys!
That worked great!
I'm so glad you're alive, man!
Bradley, bring it in!
You guys, this is just perfect.
Nothing could possibly
ruin this moment.
MAN OVER PA: Hello out
there, everybody.
Hey, remember that earlier
"bromance revision" I was
telling you guys about?
Well, you can
forget about that.
There's only gonna be one
winner of the Hungover Games.
So if you're a foursome of dudes
who recently bro-conciled,
you're gonna have
to kill each other.
You're just gonna have
to fight to the death.
I'm sorry, I don't
make up the rules.
Wait, I do.
I do make up the rules.
Suckers!
Well, good luck and may
the odds be forever
in your blah-blah-blah,
et cetera, et cetera.
This is gonna be good.
Nope. No way.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Wait, why are all these
weapons shaped like dicks?
All right, listen, guys. Listen
up. Let's talk about this.
I can't die now. I'm
about to get married.
I have a wife and kids at home.
I just lost Katnip! She
was my everything.
She was also very much underage.
DOUG: Seriously?
Ed, buddy, there are laws against that.
You can't statutory rape your soulmate.
Jeepers creepers! You
guys, don't you remember?
We're a brotherhood!
You heard the announcement.
It's every man for himself.
No! I have an idea.
We all need to eat these.
They're Midnight Berries. It's
the only way to end this.
That is what got us into this
mess in the first place.
Yeah, these berries
would kill us.
But the Capitol won't
even let us swallow them.
They'd rather have four
winners than no winner.
So before we even get
these in our mouths
they'll cancel the whole thing.
You have to trust me.
Absolutely not.
Doubt me all you want,
but don't doubt
my knowledge of young
adult fiction.
I'm in.
What?
Me, too.
Really?
Fine.
Me, too. I'm in.
But only because
I love you guys.
Okay.
On the count of three.
One.
Two.
Three.
What do we do now?
Come on! Kinda tasty.
(GAGGING)
Zach, you dumb motherfucker!
What the...
Morning.
You guys sleep well?
Yeah.
Pretty well.
Anyone have floss?
I think I've got Midnight Berry
seeds stuck in my teeth.
Wait, wait. What time is it?
It's 10:00 A.M.
We'll never make the wedding.
Wanna bet?
You guys think you can take me
out of the straitjacket now?
Guys, I am just so pumped to be
a real member of this group.
It's so cool you're gonna let me
have more lines in the next movie.
That's right, yeah.
Totally gonna happen.
Yeah, more lines, definitely.
(TYRES SCREECH)
Come with me if you want
to attend a gay wedding.
Sorry. Getting here
was a real bloodbath.
What the fucksticks, you guys?
Honey,
I am so, so, so sorry.
You had better have a good
explanation for this.
Trace, the last three days
were, without a doubt,
the most backwards, fucked up,
inexplicable experience of my entire life.
I saw brutal death.
I saw murderous talking puppets.
I saw gay Thor.
But all I could think
about was you.
Can you forgive me?
Well,
boys will be boys.
So are we gonna talk
about last night?
Okay.
Whatever the hell we think happened,
it obviously didn't really happen.
Zach just got in our heads
with that dumb book of his,
so just forget about
it and move on.
I'm over it, too. I'm
onto Fifty Shades now.
This rich guy is erotic.
You know what? You
guys are wrong.
Over the course of
one day, I loved,
I lost, and I almost
died, like, 10 times.
You also ate a boatload of shit.
Thank you for the reminder.
But thankfully, it wasn't real.
You gotta let it go, man.
You know what? You can
believe what you want,
but I know my connection
with that girl was real.
There's a lot of
wiener in this book.
But I'm not mad about it.
This probably would make
a really good TV movie.
Get Alyssa Milano.
Oh.
Sorry.
So sorry about that.
It's been a bit of a...
Don't worry about it.
Wedding's that way.
(LAUGHS)
Well, it was nice
bumping into you.
Hey, bud.
We gotta go.
I know. Do you...
What are you stammering about?
MAN: We are gathered here
today to celebrate the pure
and magical love of
these two deeply,
deeply passionate men.
Guys, that's her. I swear
to God, she's right there.
Stop, man. There is no her.
Yeah... Do I need to set
you up with a shrink?
I'm telling you, she's...
Dude.
Enough. Fine.
Letting it go.
Thank you. MAN:
Some people say
love is nothing but
a battlefield.
Not me.
These days, people don't view
marriage as something to enjoy.
They view it as
something to survive.
So Doug, Tracey,
with that, I say
may the odds be ever
in your favour.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
This tree has a vagina.
(LAUGHING)
http://subscene.com/u/659433
Improved by: @Ivandrofly