(The following content may not be suitable for viewers under 15.)
(Viewer discretion is advised.)
Park Hae Joo...
transferred from Seyeon Girls High School...
in Hyehwa-dong in Seoul.
Her father is a professor...
at Seoul University. He is a great man.
- Seoul University? - Really?
Quiet.
Moreover, Hae Joo...
has been top of her class...
the entire time at Seyeon.
- Top of her class. - Wow.
As the top student at her last school...
Well...
Compared to you stupid pigs whose grades stink,
she will be the model student.
We have high hopes for her.
Okay, Hae Joo.
Say something.
Don't mind those punks.
Speak comfortably.
Sir.
I feel bad introducing myself...
while my friends are being punished.
I'd like you to let them sit back down.
Wow. She's got guts.
- Wow. - Seriously.
Oh my gosh.
Hae Joo,
not only are you smart, you have a heart of gold.
You guys lucked out because of Hae Joo.
Get down.
Jung Hee. You punk. What are you doing?
Hey, Jung Hee.
Come down.
Thank you.
Hello.
I'm Park Hae Joo.
I'm not a genius,
or a model student.
I'm an average student who likes...
Sanulrim, Hae Eun Hee, and the Beatles.
Also,
one day,
I want to experience passionate love.
I am a hot-blooded woman.
Yes.
- It's nice to meet you. - Welcome.
(Episode 2)
Did you see Hae Joo's skin?
Is it because she's from Seoul?
She has incredibly nice skin.
She's pretty too.
She kind of looks like Jang Mee Hee.
No way. She looks like Im Ye Jin.
Whatever. Im Ye Jin would cry out in anger.
Im Ye Jin? Whatever.
She looks like Bae Yun Jung.
- The comedian? - Yes.
- No way. - That's not true.
- Not Bae Yun Jung. - No way.
What? She has eyes like this...
- just like Bae Yun Jung. - No way.
Hi. You're the girl from yesterday,
right?
What?
Do you know her?
How's your knee?
It didn't get infected?
No.
I'm glad. My dad and I were worried.
Jung Hee?
Hi, Jung Hee.
Let's be friends.
Hey. Jung Hee.
That's right. We have history class.
I didn't do my homework.
That's right.
What?
We didn't even go in.
You're being so mean.
What?
What are they doing?
We didn't do anything.
Jung Hee, isn't that your brother?
- Dong Moon is here too. - Fish Head is here too.
What are they doing?
Hey! Here she comes!
- Yes. - She's coming!
She's here.
Are they all here to see Hae Joo?
They are.
I guess word got out that a pretty girl...
transferred here from Seoul.
What pretty girl?
Let's go.
Hi, Jung Hee. You just finished?
Aren't you going down there?
Not me. I'm here...
to see you.
Don't.
Jung Hee. We'll go first.
Wait for me! Eun Ja!
What? Do you need to talk to me?
Well...
- The thing is... - If not, I'm leaving.
Jung Hee.
Aren't you hungry? Want to get pastries?
I got my allowance.
I don't like pastries.
Then do you want tempura? Spicy rice cakes?
Eat by yourself.
I'm busy, so bye.
Jung Hee.
Why is she always so busy?
Excuse me. Didn't we meet...
yesterday at the intersection?
The pharmacy.
Yes. Hello.
Hello.
A junior?
- Yes. - Then I'm older.
I'm Son Jin, a senior at Gyeryoon.
May I speak casually to you?
Anyway, the thing is...
If you have any questions...
or need help with anything, call me.
But...
Okay. Goodbye.
See you.
Hey. Jung Hee.
Is it true? The cosmos flower is in your class?
Cosmos?
You know, the new girl that moved recently.
Cosmos? What garbage.
I was worried...
because I thought Cosmos was older than me.
How lucky. Bring her home.
What? Why?
What do you mean?
Your big brother wants to get close to her.
Hey, Bong Soo. I saw you camped outside my school.
Get it together...
before I tell Father.
Tell me what?
Hello, Father.
Tell me. What?
It's nothing.
- It's nothing? - No.
Okay.
Why are you always bugging your brother?
You wench.
You couldn't be born a boy like Bong Soo.
Go inside.
Have a nice day!
Sure.
Jung Hee.
- Jung Hee. - Jung Hee!
Yes?
Show him respect.
Get home safely, Father.
Jung Hee.
Hi, number three.
Jung Hee. Hey!
Cosmos?
Jung Hee. Cosmos.
- She's in your class. - Get out of here!
Mom! Jung Hee is hitting me!
What Cosmos?
Hae Joo, that Seoul chick,
is getting on my nerves.
What's so pretty about the Seoul chick?
I'm much prettier.
(September 10, 1979)
When will Sunday come?
I miss Jin.
- All right. - What did you bring?
Jin.
Jung Hee, let's eat our yummy food.
I'm not hungry.
Don't you have a broadcast today?
We're taking turns starting this week.
Where did the Seoul chick go?
This is JHBS,
Jeonghyeon's broadcasting club.
We will now begin the afternoon broadcast.
Hello,
my fellow students.
The canna flowers that graced the streets...
have shed their petals...
Isn't that the Seoul chick?
But the club president was supposed to do it.
Were you surprised by the unfamiliar voice?
I'm one of your afternoon broadcasters.
My name is Park Hae Joo.
I'm nervous because it's my first broadcast.
It would be very encouraging...
if you'd cheer me on.
Jung Hee.
Didn't you say you'd do the broadcast?
Carpenters' "Top of the World".
"Top of the World". Awesome!
I was going to,
but I'm a senior now, so it's sort of a burden.
- Was I okay? - How is Hae Joo...
in our broadcasting club?
She was the DJ at her old school.
The club president there is my junior high friend.
She recommended her.
Why was our schedule changed again?
The instructor is going somewhere for training.
Change quickly!
If you're late, you have to take 10 laps.
- You know that, right? - What's this?
Where's my gym uniform?
Look carefully.
Hurry it up!
Hey. Look at the Seoul chick.
A strappy undershirt?
Wow. Ae Sook's strappy undershirt...
doesn't even compare.
You said only delinquents wear strappy ones, right?
Is she a one too?
Who knows? Maybe she is a total delinquent.
Where is my gym uniform?
Attention!
At... Ease!
You two.
Get up here.
Get up here!
Jung Hee.
Why are you dressed like that?
I lost my gym uniform top.
- And you? - I just transferred,
so I do not have it yet.
Being a transfer student...
is an excuse!
How could a soldier enter a war...
without her uniform?
I tried to borrow one from another class,
but our class schedule was suddenly changed,
so I did not have time to borrow one.
- That is unacceptable. - She is pretty.
Make the impossible possible.
Don't you know that is the attitude...
the youth must live by in this new era?
We do know!
Why aren't you answering?
I think...
trying to force something that is impossible...
to make it happen is reckless.
- What? - Rather,
I think trying my best in something I can do...
is much more productive.
Two of you.
Take 10 laps around the field.
That's not fair.
Shall I make it 100?
I'll run.
What are you doing?
Stay in line!
If either of you stops,
you'll have to run 200 laps!
Attention!
At ease!
Poor Jung Hee.
What if she faints?
Gosh.
What?
Hey. Ae Sook.
Oh Man Sang wants you in the teacher's office.
Ae Sook.
You smoked in the bathroom at Ahram Church, right?
I did not.
Yes, you did. There was a witness.
Darn it.
Did Jung Hee tattle on me?
"Did Jung Hee tattle on me?"
I guess that means you did smoke.
Look at these fingers.
Do you smoke Guhbooksun?
No. I smoke Chungja.
How fancy.
Chungja?
Chungja? You punk. You smoke Chungja?
You smoked Chungja? Then get smacked!
You need to get smacked for smoking.
Jung Hee.
Sorry.
I shouldn't have talked back.
Run properly.
She's watching.
Run straight.
Hang onto me.
1, 2.
What are you doing?
3, 4.
1, 2.
Jung Hee.
Are you free today after school?
There's a lot I don't know about the broadcast club.
I have to rush home.
You do?
You know Soo Nim from the club?
The producer.
She'll tell you anything you ask.
Okay.
Hey.
It was you, right?
What?
You tattled on me...
about seeing me smoke, didn't you?
To get back at me.
Shoot. I got probation again because of you.
I wouldn't get back at you.
I'm not you.
I didn't tell.
Jung Hee. Just wait.
Once my probation is over,
I'll get you back.
I told you, it really wasn't me.
Are you girls fighting again?
Young Choon. Where are you going?
Ae Sook, let go. It's hot.
Are you free tonight? Want to go clubbing?
No. I have to work.
That's right. Dang Pyo was released.
He wants to see you.
"Released"?
- Let's go. - Let go of me.
Keep fighting. She's running away.
- Go catch her. - No, it's okay.
Let's go.
Are you just getting home?
Do you feel sick?
No, I'm just tired.
Was Young Choon at the pharmacy?
Sewing machine number two broke this time.
That's right.
Auntie. Young Choon...
must really be a gangster.
He must be friends with someone in jail.
- Is that right? - Yes.
I told you to be careful, and that he's a gangster.
We have no idea where Young Choon...
came from or what he did before.
I'll take that, ma'am.
Auntie. Don't be good to that gangster.
You watch yourself too.
- What did I do? - Still,
Young Choon is good to his little sister.
Sister? Whatever.
People say Eng Cho is not his little sister,
but actually his daughter.
Really?
Then how old was he when he had her?
Study if you have time to calculate that.
Auntie, why do you always wipe that chamber pot?
- It's dirty. - It gets tarnished.
You have to wipe it every day like this.
You can go on a chamber pot wiping contest.
Number three.
There's no contest for wiping chamber pots.
Hello.
It looks like the one next to it may fall too.
I know.
Didn't you help us with our move?
Thank you.
Do you work at the pharmacy?
Okay then.
Young Choon!
- Eng Cho. - Are you okay?
You got hit hard.
I didn't. I'm fine.
What are you doing?
What else? I'm working.
Go to the pharmacy. Don't walk around alone.
It's boring there.
Can't I stay here too?
Eng Cho? What a pretty name.
Do you want to play with me while he works?
- Yes. - No, it's okay.
I'll stay with her.
Let's go, Eng Cho.
Miss.
What is that you're carrying?
Egg pastries.
Hae Joo made it. It's super tasty.
Why did you take that?
She said to give it to you.
Let's go.
"The night sky is a deep red,"
"and your lips are also dyed red."
"They look like they turned red..."
"from longing."
Hello, my fellow students.
The first song today will be...
the Carpenters... The Carpenters'...
"Top of the World".
World.
You scared me!
What is it?
You brat.
Are you impersonating Olivia?
Because you're jealous.
- Olivia? - Come to think of it,
Olivia Hussey is more her than a cosmos flower,
so that's what I'm calling her.
Goodness. You and your gibberish.
I said to stay out!
- What? - Get out!
Stop hitting me!
Olivia Hussey?
(September 11, 1979)
Is it still only Tuesday?
Auntie. What are you doing there?
Hi.
I need to put this in the master bedroom,
but your mom is at the factory.
Can you put it here?
No. You do it.
Why would I go into the master bedroom?
- I don't want to either. - Gosh.
Give it to me.
Give it.
Happy?
Get back to work.
That's right.
Are you studying hard?
Yes.
You are?
Do it right.
Don't waste time doing other things.
- Okay. - Good.
Gosh. Why did your mom send a girl to school?
Gosh. Sleep.
A girl this, a girl that...
Number three! Check for defects!
Yes, I'm doing that now.
Auntie! Where did you go? You said you'd be quick.
I'm sorry. I had to go to the washroom.
Did you poop?
I'm so tired.
Where's the chamber pot?
You've got to be kidding me.
What are you eating so late at night?
- What? - Where's the chamber pot?
- Father took it in. - He did?
What got into him?
He pees and poops in it, but never touches it.
That's strange.
He touched it fine.
Hae Jung made it.
It's super tasty.
Why did you take that?
She said to give it to you.
(September 13, 1979)
(September 14, 1979)
(September 15, 1979)
Hi, Hae Joo.
What about this song?
That sounds good.
I like it.
This one and that one.
How's this?
(September 16, 1979)
(Kim's Pharmacy)
Why are you always...
Jin.
Are you not coming today?
Poor Jung Hee. She's waiting so long.
That's so strange.
He said he'd see me again.
- I... - Hi, Jin.
Hello, Jin.
Hi. Are you here to study?
Yes.
I thought you weren't coming today.
I got here late, so I was studying...
in the boys' room.
Are you leaving?
Yes, I have to go tutor.
Don't follow me today.
Study hard, okay?
- Okay. - Good.
See you again.
The boys' room?
No.
I will follow him.
Did Jin leave already?
Jung Hee.
Hi.
Are you here to study?
- Yes. - I heard they had...
a nice music room, so I'm here to listen to music.
I see.
Are you going home?
Let's go together.
Jung Hee.
Is something on your mind?
No.
What? Another English song?
This is my favorite song.
It always cheers me up when I'm down.
We first met yesterday And fell in love
And we made an oath
When the night is over, I'll take the first train
And leave for the land of happiness
The river flows
Under the bridge
Carrying our dream
Carrying our hearts
We first met yesterday And fell in love
And we made an oath
When the night is over,
I'll take the first train
And leave for the land of happiness
Go in.
- Jung Hee. - Yes?
To be honest, I was moved that other time.
When we were punished and had to take laps,
you took my hand and ran with me.
That's when I decided...
that I'd become best friends with you.
Jung Hee.
We're friends now, right?
What?
What a pretty bag.
I made it in junior high.
Is that right? You're talented.
I'll see you at school.
Okay.
Good night, friend.
Sure.
That moment,
I became very ashamed for how jealous I was...
of Hae Joo the past week.
And that's when I realized...
that I also wanted to be good friends with her.
Jung Hee.
- What is it? - Open it.
You said you liked it,
so I made it last night.
It's to commemorate our becoming friends.
May I really...
accept this?
Of course, you may.
Joint?
With Gyeryoon High?
Yes.
So...
they're coming here tomorrow afternoon.
With their student body president.
The student body president?
As in, Son Jin?
Yes.
I'm going crazy.
- Jin? - Son Jin is coming?
- He's coming here? - My heart is racing.
This is a chance of a lifetime.
That's right.
While preparing the show,
you and Jin can naturally...
get closer.
It's too soon to relax.
- Why? - Hae Joo.
That pretty Seoul girl may be an obstacle.
What do you mean?
Hae Joo and I are friends now.
She'd never do that.
What does it matter if she's good?
How could you say that...
after seeing the mob outside the school?
You're right.
All boys are the same.
If they see a pretty girl,
they become complete idiots.
Then what?
What if Son Jin falls for Hae Joo too?
What?
Jin.
He can't!
- That's right. He can't. - That's right. He can't.
There's only one way.
The Jang Hui Bin tactic.
The Jang Hui Bin tactic?
Jang Hui Bin hid all the pretty court ladies...
where the king couldn't see them.
In case the king...
would like them?
- That's right. - Then...
we should hide Hae Joo where Jin...
won't see her?
No.
I can't do something so cheap.
Do you want to lose him?
Still. I can't do that.
Don't get blood on your hands.
We'll do it in the name of friendship.
Where's Hae Joo?
There was some stuff in our class.
Really?
Why today? The Gyeryoon guys are coming today.
(Self Study)
Look at you.
Sit straight.
- X becomes... - I should kill you.
Do you understand?
I get it now.
I couldn't understand a thing...
when Eun Ja tried to teach me.
Now, I get it.
Good.
What do you need?
Thanks, Hae Joo.
If we don't get their math grades up,
Mr. Oh said he'd kill us all too.
Hae Joo.
Don't you have to go to the broadcasting club?
Oh no.
- I'm late. - Hae Joo.
Can you teach me this too?
Wait. Me too. Me too.
I need help with so many problems.
This isn't right.
Jung Hee.
This goes against your fair-play attitude.
They're coming!
- They're coming. - Really?
- He's really cute. - Wow.
- He really handsome. - He is.
He's so good-looking.
- Jin. - He's so good-looking.
- Hello. - Nice to meet you.
- Hello. - Hello.
Hello. It's nice to meet you.
Jin.
Are you ignoring me?
We meet again.
This must be fate.
We're estimating about 150 people.
- 150? - Yes.
Let's use the auditorium here for the venue.
"Fate." He said it was fate.
What could he mean?
Did he miss me too?
Does he...
I think we have about a week left.
Jung Hee...
should be with Jin by now, right?
She must be so grateful for our friendship,
since we're holding Hae Joo here like this.
Where's Hae Joo?
Ki Ryuh, where's Hae Joo?
She had to run to the broadcasting club.
- What? - What?
Let's have a student from each school be the host.
Okay.
We decided to have me be the host.
What about you?
For us...
Excuse me.
I'm glad you're here.
Which of you do you think should host the show?
Maybe Hae Joo should do it.
She's smart and speaks...
with a Seoul accent.
And she's pretty and tall.
She's perfect.
I believe Jung Hee should do it.
This is Daegu.
I believe Jung Hee who speaks...
with a pretty Daegu accent should be the host.
Jung Hee, what do you think?
Obviously, I want to do it...
with Jin.
- I think Hae Joo... - I also think...
Jung Hee should do it.
It's a joint broadcast representing Daegu,
so the host should show off Daegu's charm.
Jin is looking at me.
Only at me.
Then let's do that.
Okay.
Let's work hard.
Thank you.
Hae Joo.
I'm sorry.
What?
No. You're great.
I can't wait for the broadcast.
That's not it.
I really am shameless.
Let's meet by Daeil Books at Jungang Market.
I'll wait until 5:30.
Hae Joo. I have to go.
What?
Jung Hee.
Sir.
Here.
Get home safely.
Hello.
I can't give you medicine.
The pharmacist is out.
I see.
Our school is having a broadcasting show.
Here's an invitation.
Okay. I'll give it to the pharmacist.
No, it's for you, mister.
You fixed our gutter last time.
I wanted to thank you.
Please come if you have time.
Where's Eng Cho?
Did she go somewhere?
She's napping.
I see.
Okay then.
Also,
I'm not a "mister".
Have a nice day.
(Jeonghyeon and Gyeryoon Joint Broadcast Show)
Park Hae Joo.
Jung Hee, you brat. Why didn't you see it sooner?
Jin!
I only saw this now.
Did you wait long?
I'm sorry.
It's okay. You're all wet.
It's okay.
But sorry,
I have to go tutor.
Here. Take this with you.
What about you?
I'm fine. Don't fall again.
See you again.
Jin just wanted to see me one more time.
I'm sure of it.
I could see deep in his eyes...
just how...
he felt.
Have you gone insane?
Can't you see it stopped raining?
- I see. - What?
Then why are you walking with the umbrella open?
It's none of your business.
She's completely insane.
She's gone insane after chasing Jin.
Jung Hee.
Wait. Does she still like Jin?
"Still"?
She's falling deeper and deeper.
She'll be crying her heart out soon.
Here's an invitation.
Please come if you have time.
I'm not a "mister".
Young Choon.
Long time no see.
You heard I got out, right?
Ae Sook told you.
I heard you ignored her when she told you.
Is that right?
Come on. A gangster doesn't become a saint...
by living like this.
Move.
You coward.
What?
Happy?
Go.
Young Choon. That hurts.
Hey, "friend".
Don't mess with me. I'll kill you.
Jung Hee.
What are you doing?
Auntie.
What...
Gosh.
Oh my gosh. Are you just getting home?
Why didn't you come?
I'm sorry.
Do you...
Are you just getting home?
Yes.
Gosh. Did you drink...
again?
What?
Are you sleeping already?
Darn it.
Why is he complaining about my sleeping?
What are you doing at this hour?
Something spilled here.
What spilled?
Did you eat?
(Joint Broadcast Show)
Hello.
I'm Son Jin, a senior at Gyeryoon High,
and I'll be hosting with Lee Jung Hee today.
Lee Jung Hee!
Jung Hee.
The club president said to go home...
and get rested up.
I'm fine.
Go home, and rest.
That way, your voice will be nice and fresh.
And you'll look prettier.
Then maybe I'll go to the bath house.
Yes, that would be good.
Jung Hee.
- What is it? - "What is it?"
It isn't much.
I wanted to thank you.
My probation ended today.
Thanks to you, I wasted away in detention.
I have a nice red mark on my transcript too.
I told you, it wasn't me.
I didn't tell the teacher on you.
Sure, whatever.
Jung Hee.
I hear you're hosting the broadcast show.
- Why? - What perfect timing.
Timing for what?
For you to take the stage with all of your teeth...
knocked out.
Let go.
Jung Hee. Clench your teeth.
Mr. Oh!
- Get her. - Jung Hee!
- Jung Hee! - Jung Hee!
- Jung Hee! - Stop!
Jung Hee!
- Stop! - Get back here!
- Stop! - No!
Stop chasing me!
How long will you chase me?
Stop, Jung Hee! Stop right there!
Stop right there!
No!
- Stop chasing me! - Stop!
Stay away from me!
If I catch you, I'll rip you to shreds.
Darn it.
Are you playing with us?
You're a pretty good runner.
Try running all you can.
You're in the palm of my hand.
Don't come any closer.
"Don't come closer"?
Keep going. It's water.
Don't come closer. I'll really fall in.
Then fall in. You'll fall in, not me.
Are you insane?
I'm not insane, you are.
Was it fun, tattling on me to the teacher?
What do you take me for?
Did you just duck?
Hold her down.
You psycho.
- Jung Hee! - Stop it!
Hey!
Why you...
Help me!
- Someone help me! - Look at her.
Are you a frog?
I really can't swim!
Jung Hee really can't swim.
Hey. You go in.
I can't swim.
Jin. I guess this is how I die.
I didn't get to share my love with you.
I guess I'm going to die first.
She's drowning! Oh, no!
Jin?
Jung Hee!
Jin.
I'm so happy.
I can die now, and I'll be happy.
Jung Hee. Wake up.
Jung Hee.
You need to give her CPR.
Do it.
What did they say to do?
I don't know.
Get the water out. Press down on her chest.
That's right. Get the water out!
You do it then!
- You do it! - You do it!
- You do it! - Hurry!
How can I do that?
You do it.
- Hey. - You do it.
Hey!
Darn it.
Jung Hee.
Don't die. Jung Hee.
Sorry.
I'll take care of you no matter what.
Jung Hee.
Jung Hee. No, no, no.
No.
Mouth-to-mouth.
Commencing.
Is this... Mouth-to-mouth?
Does that mean these are Jin's lips?
Jung Hee! Jung Hee, are you okay?
Are you awake? Jung Hee.
You're alive. You're alive. Jung Hee.
I'm so glad. You're alive.
I was so scared.
I'm so glad.
Mom! Jung Hee's awake!
- What? - Jung Hee!
My baby girl!
Are you finally awake?
- Jung Hee. - Mom.
- Where am I? - It's a hospital! Look!
You brat!
Do we not have water...
at the house?
Why were you drinking water from the river?
- Where's Jin? - What about him?
Where's Jin, who saved me?
You brat. Don't even get me started.
Because of you, you brat,
another family's precious son...
almost drowned and died.
How can I face his parents now?
Dong Moon is hospitalized next door! Dong Moon!
No way. The one who saved me...
You may have died if not for Dong Moon.
Shoot.
Shoot. That's right.
- I have to take a bath. - You crazy wench!
You want to go into water again?
I have to take a bath before tomorrow's show.
The broadcast show ended already!
What do you mean? It's tomorrow.
Today is "tomorrow".
You slept for over a day!
- Today is "tomorrow"? - That's right.
Is that true?
- It is. - No.
No. No!
No what?
- Hey! Hey! - Hey! Jung Hee!
Get back here!
Get your act together, you brat!
It really...
is over.
Hae Joo.
Don't do this.
Please don't do this.
Can't you think it over?
I'm sorry.
Why...
don't you understand how I feel?
Jin.
Hae Joo?
Are they...
dating?
Did Jin...
fall for her too?
Jung Hee.