(Episode 15)
Don't move.
Ha Wan Seung?
Hey.
Detective Ha. Did you kill Jang Do Jang?
Arrest him.
It was all designed from the beginning.
The case file went missing.
I couldn't find them.
That case was...
100 percent suicide.
Hey, how did you know?
What a good hunch.
How did you know something
would happen here?
Why did you kill Jang Do Jang?
You said you were getting farsighted,
but you have a great eyesight.
You recognized Jang Do Jang from there.
Arrest him.
Let's see if you stick to the rules.
First one is a blank-fire.
Get him!
Don't let him get away!
What are you doing? Go after him!
I had him ready for you.
How can you miss him?
I'll get him today no matter what.
You have until the end of the day.
If it takes any longer,
Mr. Ha will be on the move.
(Mr. Ha of Ha And Jung Law Firm)
How dare you make my son a murderer?
I'm trying, but...
your son is pouring oil on the fire.
So what?
What are you trying to do?
As you know,
I only follow orders from my superiors.
I have to obey them. What else can I do?
It's time...
for you to decide.
17 years is a long time.
I can't have your back anymore.
All right.
Sir.
Your life...
and mine are at stake.
I know that.
I'll take care of everything. You stay put.
Mom. Dad.
You must've been upset.
I thought we'd catch the culprit soon...
because Ho Cheol is a prosecutor.
I'll get the culprit myself.
I won't rely on Ho Cheol anymore.
(Shinim-dong taxi driver
and wife commit suicide)
(The police concluded the
case as a double suicide.)
Dad.
Mom!
That's my dad's taxi!
It's my dad's! Why won't you let me go?
- Dad!
- Hey.
Hey.
They're both dead.
Pardon?
That's a lie.
My dad has...
never been sick.
My mom got over her cold.
They committed suicide.
Mom!
I'm sorry.
Mom, don't go!
Dad, no!
Mom! Don't leave me alone.
Dad!
It's not a suicide.
Who is it?
Lady?
Detective Ha?
I'm sorry it's late,
but I have to see you.
What?
Why would you call out a
married woman this late?
We don't have enough time.
I have to see you.
Where are you? I'll be there.
In front of the lunchbox shop.
What?
Lady, what are you doing there?
What is this? What are you doing here?
Detective Ha, your leg.
It's bloody.
A bullet brushed past my leg. I'm fine.
A bullet?
Are you crazy? Let's get you to a hospital.
I can't go to a hospital.
Gosh, why are you so dull?
Didn't it hurt?
My goodness, go easy on me.
You walked around fine
with all these blood.
Why, does it hurt now?
My gosh. I thought you were
an experienced detective.
Why do you always get hurt?
Do you know how many times
I saw you get hurt?
I think I mostly got hurt because of you.
If that's so, it's the biggest
reason not to get hurt.
It makes me angrier.
Try to loosen that. You're
cutting off my circulation.
This is how you're supposed to do it.
And take this.
I'll use it often to prevent infection.
You're a lot nicer now.
Were you waiting for me,
pretending it's a coincidence?
This is my workplace.
It's not your working hour.
All right, fine.
I've been waiting all night...
to see if our precious little detective...
would stop by.
Are you happy now?
Did I ever tell you?
I'm a bad boy.
(Shinim-dong taxi driver
and wife commit suicide)
You and I are connected.
Forget about it.
It's too burdening...
to receive attention from
a pretty boy like you.
(Shinim-dong taxi driver suicide case)
This is your parents' case file.
No one is here.
There's no way he would be at home.
Oh, are you tracing his phone?
It's not available.
Darn it.
What are you doing? Search the place again.
Yes.
Seven years ago,
I killed a woman who got in my taxi.
I tied her body with a heavy weight...
and threw her into the ocean.
My wife and I cannot live with this guilt.
I will pay for my sin with death.
Please take care of my daughter.
National Forensic Service said...
the handwriting is your dad.
This is my dad's handwriting.
But this isn't his will.
He wrote it himself,
but it isn't his will?
He just copied whatever someone else wrote.
I see evidence of murder on this will.
Wan Seung?
If he's not home,
he's not here, so he must
be at the lunchbox place.
But it is rather late now.
Oh, really?
No, it's nothing. Don't call him.
I'll call him.
No, it's nothing urgent.
Yes, I'll visit you soon, Captain.
Goodbye.
Speech and writings are like fingerprints.
Fingerprints again?
It means there are a set vocabulary...
and writing habits for each of us.
My dad never used "I" correctly.
He always used "me" instead.
And my dad...
always had the wrong spelling.
He would always get a
couple of things wrong.
But this has everything
spelled out perfectly.
(Me will put the car out quickly.)
It is a bit odd.
Before someone dies,
they look back on their own life.
He only talks about why
and when he killed her...
and where he threw out the body.
It's only about the murder.
This isn't a will. It's a report.
He doesn't know words like
"statute of limitations"...
That's what detectives usually say.
The case file went missing.
I can't find it anywhere.
The detective who looked into
this case is suspicious.
He's the guy who waited around to catch me.
It's weird how Jang Do Jang
suddenly changed the place.
I'm going to change the place of meeting.
Come alone to...
the empty Muju Factory in Shinim-dong.
That's Detective Ko's jurisdiction.
Shinim-dong.
Detective Ko has never left
Shinim Police Station.
Something is going on.
It's someone above.
We can't reinvestigate with just this.
We need a concrete evidence.
I do have it. The concrete evidence.
What evidence?
A fingerprint. The one on our fingers.
There were no fingerprints found.
Exactly.
How can there be no fingerprints?
How can there be no fingerprints in a taxi?
Hundreds of people get in and get off.
It wouldn't make sense
even if it wasn't a taxi.
The fingerprint of the person
who died should be there.
What if the person had gloves on?
The gloves would be in the car.
But they weren't. They
weren't on him either.
Someone erased the fingerprints.
And...
(Briquette)
look at this briquette.
It's only half burnt.
It went out in the middle.
With this much gas...
A person can't die.
They didn't die in the taxi.
They were moved after they died.
We can tell by the purple
spots on their body.
(Purple spots appear on
a dead person's body.)
There's no autopsy result.
The evidence here only leads to a suicide.
They hid the most important autopsy result.
Detective Ha, where did
you get this case file?
This is the last present I can give to you.
Seo Hyun Soo's murderer...
is in here.
Detective Ha, are you
hiding something from me?
Detective Ko.
You can't enter without a warrant.
Hey, that's not the problem right now.
We don't know when the murderer will run.
- What?
- Move aside.
I read it on the advertisement.
It was on a pretty detective
in Seodong Police Station.
I learned a lot about you through that.
Right after...
Ms. Seo Hyun Soo went missing,
February 26, 2001, you got
into the Police University.
You started out in the
intelligence division.
It was to find Ms. Seo Hyun Soo.
March 21, 2007.
You applied for traffic safety division...
in order to find the taxi Ms. Seo took.
10 years ago,
you found the taxi driver,
Yoo In Sang,
my dad.
November 13, 2007.
You two were going to meet in Shinim-dong.
The man had a tattoo on his arm?
He had a snake tail tattoo
and needle marks on his arm.
Needle marks on his arm?
Was he a drug addict?
Well, I'm not sure.
Can you tell me more details in person?
Of course. I have a good memory.
You didn't get to meet the taxi driver.
Ever.
You joined the narcotics
division in 2009...
to find the man...
with a snake tail tattoo and needle marks.
Jang Do Jang.
- Here.
- Thank you.
Let's go.
All right. Here we go.
My dad died on the day...
he was supposed to meet you.
Was it a coincidence?
I'm sorry.
If only...
I hadn't been looking for...
My dad could be...
so meddlesome.
- Is he in there?
- No, sir.
- Search the kitchen.
- Yes, sir.
It's the police. They're after me.
Why is the police chasing a police?
I'm accused of killing Jang Do Jang.
What?
What's going on?
It's a security alarm.
I believe the police
substation has been informed.
Gosh, this is annoying.
Let's move out.
Yes, sir.
The one who killed my parents...
must be related to Seo
Hyun Soo's case, right?
I'll catch the culprit no matter what.
Do you have a place to go?
(Dong Ho's Lunchbox)
Hey.
What happened to your leg?
Don't ask. Just come here and help me.
I asked you to give me the passcode.
Why would I give you that?
Tell me. I might come here again.
Are you okay?
Hey, you should get home early.
It's dangerous out there.
You're right. It's dangerous
even for a police.
It's really terrible.
Hey, give me my pajamas.
Pardon?
Why would your pajamas be here?
We had matching pajamas.
Those were really comfy.
Where did you buy them?
Matching...
pajamas.
Who could that be?
- Captain.
- Hey.
- Wan Seung...
- He's here.
- Hey.
- Hello.
Are you all right?
What's that? Did you get hurt again?
I'll be fine. As long as
he doesn't kick me out.
What do you mean I'll kick you out?
I'll give you the pajamas.
Tell me the truth.
Did you really kill Jang Do Jang?
What? He killed Jang Do Jang?
Captain, I'm a detective.
I didn't go through all
the trouble to kill him.
That's not what I'm asking.
Are they saying you killed Jang Do Jang?
Yes, I think so.
What will you do now?
I'm going to catch the real killer.
Where?
Hi, Captain.
Hi, Detective Ko. Did you
meet with Detective Ha?
Detective Ha is on his way to my place.
I'm not sure. I think he
wants to borrow money.
You should come over if
you need to talk to him.
We'll head over to Captain Bae's house.
They left.
You have an hour.
Don't use your cell phone.
They'll track it.
That's a given.
Detective Ha.
You're under arrest for the
murder of Jang Do Jang.
Let's go.
You entering the crime scene was...
caught on tape.
Jang Do Jang's last phone
conversation was with you.
You've been after him for a long time.
You caught him every time he ran away.
You two have a long history.
Just confess.
It's for your sake.
He said he didn't do it.
What was it that he didn't do?
He was going to tell me everything.
But he died when he was about to.
And you came right in time to catch me.
Detective Ko. Do you know Seo Hyun Soo?
You're pathetic.
Request a visit if you want to see me.
People are watching.
Go to the US.
I'll get everything ready.
Ha And Jung Law Firm is amazing.
It can let a murder suspect fly abroad.
Thanks to Ha And Jung Law Firm,
you're still alive.
Without Ha And Jung Law Firm,
you're nothing.
The same goes for you.
Do you think people grovel
because you're great?
This is your last chance.
I'm not in a great shape,
so I can't see you off.
(Shinim Police Station)
Detective Ko started
working in Shinim-dong...
Right before Hyun Soo went missing.
Everything was planned.
It was all designed...
from the beginning.
Everything began in Shinim-dong.
Detective Ko probably
had his eyes on my dad.
Even if you didn't find him,
he would've...
I will save you, Detective Ha.
Lady, I'll clear myself of false charges.
Don't go messing around. It's dangerous.
You don't have anyone
to save your life now.
I also want to be conceited to you.
False charges and your
life aren't the same.
Goodness.
You should go. A lady shouldn't come here.
A crime always leaves a trace.
You cannot go in.
I just need to go in for a bit.
You may not. Please leave.
Corporal Park.
Hello.
Come in.
I didn't know you were here.
I'm here to help the forensics team.
The National Police Agency
calls forensic officers.
I can tell by the bloodstain...
that the victim died...
facing that way.
Detective Ha came in this way.
Jang Do Jang...
Jang Do Jang drove a car
in and came this way.
And the car door was supposedly left open,
so it looks like he was killed immediately.
But Detective Ha...
got on the car and ran away.
Detective Ha couldn't be the culprit.
He walked in from this way,
but the victim fell facing that way.
Then the knife should be on his back.
Oh, look.
Inspector Woo.
Are you going to let him go to jail?
Just drive.
Yes, I apologize.
Is the headquarters doing the profiling?
It's a case involving an officer.
Please do it well.
Detective Ha's shoes had blood on them.
You can see bloodstains
here, here, and here.
But there's nothing above
Jang Do Jang's head.
Let's take a look.
Excuse me.
Do we have any other suspects?
Not yet.
The only working security
camera was at the entrance.
No one else was on it
other than Detective Ha.
So the other cameras were
broken just in time.
This is interesting.
(Experimental pills)
That's fake blood.
Where did you get that?
170.
175.
180.
It looks like the blood was dropped from...
Okay.
His height is 180cm.
Age, from the late 30s to early 40s.
The deep wound shows it's a man with power.
He weighs around 90kg...
and he's not used to using a knife.
It's probably his first time.
He stabbed him four times.
A lot of blood must have splattered.
You're right.
He must have looked for...
a place to wash up and get changed.
I saw a restroom over there.
I'm not sure if you'll like it, Ms. Yoo.
It had no toilet papers.
Was that a joke?
Sure.
His clothes were probably covered in blood,
but he didn't throw them away here.
There must be traces left elsewhere.
Jang Do Jang was a guy who
knew how to use a knife.
Don't you think...
he let go of the knife too easily?
His defense marks weren't severe.
He didn't really fight back.
We should run it by the
National Forensic Service,
but the victim was blood type A...
and no other blood types were found.
It'll have to be a gun...
for him to give over the knife so easily.
And it's probably a person he believed...
would not kill him so easily.
For example, it could be a detective.
Blood type A.
He made a call here.
He reported the case to the police.
Then the police came right away.
To infer from your hypothesis,
this person checked to see
if the police got here,
then somewhere from this building...
Height, 180cm.
Weight, around 90kg.
A detective who's more used
to a gun than a knife.
A detective who came onto the scene...
a bit later than the other officers.
Why aren't you controlling the scene?
- I apologize.
- Don't let strangers in.
Please come out.
Oh, okay. Fine.
My goodness.
I'm sorry that the scene is so chaotic.
I heard you're a profiler
at the headquarters.
You look better in real person than on TV.
Thanks.
Here.
You're a lefty.
Pardon?
Can I have a look at your hand?
It won't take a minute.
What do you think you're doing?
Get a warrant.
The killer isn't that detailed.
He'll have left evidence elsewhere.
Let go of me.
Your job is to stop
people from trespassing.
Officer Hong, the cameras
might have caught the killer.
Can you get the footage?
Okay. I'll come right over.
I'll see if there are any
other security cameras.
They're gone.
Did someone take them?
Some detectives came and took them.
Detective Ko was on it.
Did he have a beard?
The bloody clothes are
the only evidence left.
He joined the team after he had changed.
Where did he dispose of them?
He wouldn't have thrown
it away just anywhere.
The trunk of his car?
It's a safe place.
Very private.
Did you see the footage?
No, but I did see who took it.
Was it Detective Ko?
We'll need a warrant...
to get into the trunk.
He parked illegally,
so I had it towed.
Can we open it at the impound lot?
That's also illegal...
without a warrant.
This is insane.
(Shinim Impound Lot)
He opened it as you said he would.
The evidence is ours.
You're under arrest for the
murder of Jang Do Jang.
Get off me!
Don't move! Freeze!
Murder suspect Lieutenant
Ko Jae Heon fled the scene.
Put him on the wanted list.
We have evidence that Detective Ko did it.
Well done.
Inspector Woo took it to the
National Forensic Service.
You'll be released when
the results are out.
But...
Detective Ko got away.
Keep a leash on Seol Ok, so
she doesn't go after him.
No one knows what he'll do.
Okay, I'll remember that.
What did he say when you
told him he'll be out soon?
Did he thank me?
Well... He told me to keep
you on a tight leash.
I'm the one who cleared his name.
Give me a call when he's released.
Bye.
I saved his life.
He was getting cabin fever in that cell.
There's evidence that Detective Ko did it.
Why won't they release Detective Ha?
I don't know.
The blood in the public
toilet and phone booth...
belonged to Jang Do Jang.
So...
why are the superintendent and chief...
asking to see you one after the other?
Is it a cover-up?
I did my job thoroughly...
and said I would report
my findings by the book.
Corporal Park, you're suspected of...
corruption related to equipment supplies.
You need to come with us.
What do you mean? I did...
what with equipment supplies?
Yes, Captain.
A corruption related to equipment supplies?
Yes.
Things are looking very strange.
Are you at the National Forensic Service?
Yes, I'm just outside.
(Recent call)
I'll call you back. Bye.
Inspector Woo.
Detective Ko?
Can Wan Seung leave when
the results arrive?
Yes.
- Inspector Woo.
- Hello.
Did you leave the clothes at the NFS?
What?
Detective Ko's bloody clothes.
We procured them from the tow yard.
We talked on the phone.
I don't know what you're talking about.
What's going on?
I have work to do inside.
Hey.
What's he up to?
You scumbag. I told you.
I'm sorry.
Hello? Mr. Kim.
I dealt with it.
Come along.
- Save me.
- Move.
Inspector Woo got rid of the clothes.
It was the only way to get you out.
Why are you here?
Do whatever Ha And Jung Law Firm wants.
Do you work for them too?
Is that why you destroyed the evidence?
I don't work for them,
and I didn't destroy evidence.
How can I trust you?
Detective Ha, you must believe
what I'm about to say.
You need Ha And Jung's
help to save Seol Ok.
Seol Ok?
What about her?
Detective Ko abducted her.
Bring me the clothes you took.
Come alone.
You know what'll happen
to Seol Ok if you don't.
The time and location...
He sounds anxious.
He's very likely to do something drastic.
One wrong move could put Seol Ok in danger.
Detective Ko works for Ha And Jung.
How do you know that?
That's not important.
Detective Ha!
Inspector Woo.
Hey, it's Wan Seung.
I'll be there. I have the clothes.
What are you and Inspector Woo up to?
Your business is with me and Seol Ok.
Is that so?
Come alone.
I'm a fugitive myself.
Would I bring a team?
In return, Seol Ok...
Be here by 6pm.
She'll be safe until then.
That scumbag.
I'll save her.
What can you do from here?
Are you all right?
Detective Ha. Help him.
Detective Ha.
Detective Ha. Stay with me.
(Blood for testing)
Don't use it too much. It's expensive.
Don't people think you're weird...
if you carry this around?
No, you're weirder.
It looks so real.
That's more than enough.
Detective Ha. Detective Ha.
Are you okay? Detective Ha!
Detective Ha.
- Stop screaming.
- Save me!
Stop it already.
No one's looking.
Really?
This is hard work.
My throat's sore.
Did you have to use so much blood?
Detective Ha! Be strong!
He's losing blood!
I feel dizzy. Save me!
I feel so dizzy.
I'm off.
I see.
- Shall we?
- Sure.
Dad.
Detective Ha, get out.
Let me through.
This is your last chance.
If you go with the police,
you'll become a murderer.
If you come home,
everything will go back to normal.
There's nothing...
I can do for you now.
Dad.
I'll do everything you want.
I'll live the life you want me to.
Please...
let me through.
Hello?
Put your guns down.
Let's go.
Hyun Soo. Hyun Soo. Hyun Soo.
Wake up. No, Hyun Soo.
Hyun Soo.
If you go in now, it will put her at risk.
It's worse to leave her alone.
Detective Ha's lost it.
No one knows what he'll do.
Captain!
Are you not coming?
Are you kidding me?
Do you think I'm joking?
What are you trying to do?
I'm almost there. Wait a bit more.
Darn you. I told you to come by yourself.
Did you think I'll fall for this again?
I am by myself. No one knows.
Hey, Seol Ok's blood is in your hands.
No!