___
Just give me the necklace!
Mari. Mari?
You're okay?
You sure you want a coffee?
After what just happened,
I could use something a little stiffer.
Coffee's good.
Thanks, Chuck.
I'm beat.
If you want to stay and I hope you will,
your room's how you left it.
The girls at school...
They said my mommy was a junkie.
That's why she gave me up.
- What's a junkie? - It doesn't
matter, because it's not true.
Those girls,
they were just being nasty.
Then why did my
mommy give me up?
You were just a baby, when the
foster agency placed you with us.
You didn't even have a name.
But you did have something.
Something we've been waiting to
give you until you were old enough.
- What is it?
- It belonged to your mother.
Chuck asked a friend of his about it
and he said it was an "Anansi Totem".
- What's that? - I don't know,
sweetie. But I have a feeling,
that one day it might help you
find the answers to all your questions.
- Dr. Macalester. - Uh, office
hours were over 20 minutes ago.
I'm Mari McCabe.
I called earlier.
Of course, my apologies.
Come in.
You said you had an artifact
for me to look at.
Yes. Though...
I'm not sure it's an artifact.
Normally, this is where I'd say,
"My eyes are up here".
This is extraordinary.
Where did you find this?
I guess you could say
it's a family heirloom.
I don't really know anything about it.
I... I don't even know where it's from.
That type of stone is indigenous
to the M'Changa province, in Zambesi.
- And it has someting to do
with "Anansi", right? - Anansi.
The trickster God. According to legend,
he fashioned a totem, which he gave...
To a warrior named Tantu.
When I was a kid I looked up
Anansi in the encyclopedia.
I'm sorry to waste your time.
I honestly don't know what I was
expecting to learn when I came in here.
What did you want to learn?
- I don't know. I... It's stupid.
- Oh, I have three PhDs so...
How about you let me be
the judge of what's stupid.
I've had this thing
since I was 10
and I always thought it was
just a piece of junk jewelry.
But lately, some things
have happened to me.
And now, I think it might be the key
to finding out more about my family.
- Who's your family? - That would
be the 52 million dollar question.
Sorry to waste your time.
It's said the totem grants it's wearer
access to the "Ashe" of the animal kingdom.
It means life force,
power, essence.
The totem harnesses the Ashe of
any animal the wearer conjures up.
- What?
- You know, speed of a cheetah,
agility of an antelope,
strength of an elephant, etc.
Relax. All of this
is just a myth.
- In reality, that pendant is just a finely
polished piece of stone. - Too bad.
If it was magic, I might be
able to get something for it online.
Thanks for your time.
You know the McCabe woman? The one who
tuned up the three gang-bangers you hired
to steal the Anansi totem off her.
She just walked out of my office.
That certainly is a fortunate
turn of events.
I can get her back here anytime
you want. But in return...
Relax, Dr. Macalester.
Once I have the totem in hand, you can
consider your next expedition fully founded.
And the girl?
What'll happen to her?
Don't worry about
Mari McCabe, Professor.
I need her alive.
For now.
Made by vbalazs91