Spellcheck (fast) and modified by kloofy, enjoy ;)
Breaker, breaker one-nine.
Smokey report.
We got a bear--
Breaker one-nine.
Any takers.
Breaker.
...1-40. His 20, mile marker 2-4-3.
Anybody out there ?
Copy. Over.
Hello?
Lewis.
No!
...for the first time I see myself
through somebody else's eyes.
Yeah. Yeah.
It's completely claustrophobic.
Big surprise.
And we 're like, "Okay--"
Aren' t we supposed
to get a hell of a downpour?
- Two hundred mile slipper-slide.
- Anybody out there ?
Yeah, they had a speed trap set up.
No one ever said
freshman year 'd go by so fast.
At least Colorado has seasons.
Berkeley's like summer all year.
Yeah. It's late. I'm not
keeping you on the phone, am I?
No. No, not at all.
So, what's, um-- You know,
what's David doing this summer?
- I don't know. Who cares?
- What?
Sorry. I didn't tell you before.
I just...
felt a little strange,
you know?
You what--
I don't understand.
We broke up.
He--
He's been acting serious and weird.
Serious and weird, how?
He was getting all serious and weird?
- I mean l-- I told you
what he was like, and--
- Wait, hold on.
- Lewis, it's 3:00 in the morning.
- I got a final tomorrow.
- I'm sorry.
I-I'll be quieter.
Lewis?
I'm sorry. So, what happened?
He kept...
Looking at me, as if, you know...
he totally thought
that he knew me...
which he so obviously didn't.
And he started crying.
Which sort of sealed
the deal, you know?
- You made him cry?
- I broke up with him.
Wouldn't you cry?
Listen, Venna,
you're cute, but you're not that cute.
I was kidding.
Well, I'm not
in the mood to go home.
Wish I had a car,
then I could...
just get there gradually.
Decompress a little bit, you know?
If you had a car, you could
stop by Colorado and pick me up.
We could have an adventure.
The two of us and a windshield.
- I have a car.
- No, you don't.
Yeah. Didn't I tell you?
- No!
- Yeah, well, like, I got one.
- Sexy choice. Yeah.
- Yeah?
Vintage 1 971 Chrysler Newport.
* Show me am I right *
* Show me how you feel *
* Gimme all you've got *
* Show me where to start *
* Give me love and breathe *
I've changed
my plans. I'm no longer flying back.
-I bought a car, so I'm driving.
- By yourself?
No. Actually, I was thinkin'
about picking up Venna.
Mom ?
Sorry. I-It's-- Sorry.
That's great, Lewis.
- What's the matter?
- Your brother just called.
He was arrested again.
Drunk and disorderly.
- Where, in San Diego?
- Salt Lake City.
Don't worry. It's not your problem.
- What did Dad say?
- You know our dad.
He didn't even want
to talk to Fuller.
Said if he hadn't grown up yet,
it was never going to happen.
-Fuller!.
-I know.
-I miss him too.
Listen, before
you start writing anything--
- License, please. Registration.
- My brother's in jail.
And I haven't seen him
in almost five years.
So, I'm like driving 200 miles
out of my way just to help him out.
That U-turn, it was based on
a whole, like, good deed scenario.
I'm also writing you up
for a broken tail Light.
I have one of those?
Look, I'm aware of how frustrating...
the prison system in this country
must be for you.
Repeat offenders,
the unrehabilitated--
I watch American Justice,
with your host, Bill Kurtis.
But I'm different.
I'm reformed.
You know, I'm strong. I'm--
Officer Wilkins, this is my--
Listen, this is my pledge to you.
You will not be
seeing me again.
Two strikes are enough
for Fuller Thomas.
Hey.
You look... tall.
Taller than me.
- How's it goin'?
Well, a lot better now.
Kid. Good to see you.
You came all the way
to Salt Lake just for me?
Well, technically,
you are still my brother.
Hey, this is my brother.
I can't get--
Look at you, man!
- Mr. Thomas!
- Thank you for coming.
- You're welcome.
- Thank you.
-Sign out, please.
- You're welcome.
Listen, I'm supposed to
be picking up a friend.
- And I'm running kind of late, so--
- Uh-huh?
I just, uh, well, I just wanted
to see how you're doin'...
and take you wherever
it was you needed to go...
because I sorta need
to hit the road.
- Yeah, where are you goin'?
- Um, Boulder, Colorado...
- and then I'm goin' home.
- Oh, perfect.
- Yeah, that's great!
- Wait, what?
With the exception of
the seatspring piercin' my ass...
this ride's excellent.
So, uh, who's this friend
you're pickin' up?
Her name is Venna. She's a friend
of mine from back home.
Wait, the blinker?
That girl from the Heights?
The one who was like--
all day long?
No, she's not like that all day.
You haven't seen her in years.
Oh, okay.
You're fuckin' her?
Well, what question's
more legit than that?
- We're just friends, okay?
- Okay, you're not fucking her.
- But you want to.
- You don't know
Oh, I don't?
I don't know what I'm talking about?
All right, here's how it is:
Um, she's always dated guys
from the right side of the 'burbs.
You were always left on the sidelines.
You get your scholarship to Berkeley.
She's off to the University
of Colorado. Right?
- You don't understand.
- You guys have been talking
and now she realizes that you have
the warm fuzzies for each other.
You're not lettin' on, even though
you scrambled and bought this car...
just topick her up.
No, you're still playing
the neutered boy "friend'"...
who's like,
always there for her...
because you're nice--
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
What are you doing?
Whoa, whoa!
So, you're still good,
or need me to drive, or--
No more bullshit small talk.
About me, my relationships,
or my car.
- Okay.
No, I swear. I'm barely
slowing the car in Denver.
I'll give him a seven-mile-an-hour
chance to jump and roll.
You did your mom...
a big favor,
and she's happy now.
And this time tomorrow,
you'll be here with me...
and it'll be a whole new
level of stress to deal with.
Okay, well, I'm gonna get goin'.
I guess I'll see you tomorrow.
- Okay, I'll see you tomorrow.
- All right.
- Good-bye.
- Downsizing?
Gas company just lets
a talented man like you go?
-Just like that?
- Yep.
Well, that sucks.
But this job kicks ass, huh?
Got your trailer here, and now
you're workin' kind of outside.
You got a view.
- What is this?
- C. B. radio. Olive branch.
- Check it out.
- You put a hole in my car.
I talked him down to 40 bucks.
Breaker one-nine,
breaker one-nine.
We need a westbound,
come on.
You got Black Sheep here
ridin' front door with...
uh, Mama's Boy.
We're barrelin' down on ol'
Eye-8-Oh east away, just wonderin'...
- if you could see any bears
from your rockin' chair, over.
Roger, you got a 40-mile
clear shot, 'cept for Jamestown.
Got yourself a Kojak
with a Kodak at 1 -8-5.
All right, no cops
till Jamestown.
Free to speed like a motherfucker
for like the next 40 miles or so.
Aren't we supposed
to get a hell of a downpour?
We got a 200-mile slipper-slide.
Come on?
Doesn't
matter, not from this rocking chair.
Some people like it when it rains.
It's gonna rain hard tonight.
- Keeps everybody inside, you know.
-What the hell's with this guy?
Howdy!
You got Black Sheep here,
with Mama's Boy. Who we got? Over.
Could I please get a better handle
than Mama's Boy?
No.
Yo, Rain Man,
what's your 20?
- Hey, can you do a woman's voice?
- What?
Do a girl. Say, uh...
"Hey, Black Sheep,
this is, um, Miss--"
- No. Forget it.
- Come on, man.
You did a girl
when we pranked, uh--
- Oh, yeah, Mr. Schramm.
-Yeah.
- That was good.
-No, I was nine.
That was what I sounded like then.
This is like a prehistoric Internet,
or something.
Come on! You fuck with
someone in a chat room.
- It's the same thing.
-No, forget it.
Come on, man!
Say, uh, "Hey, Black Sheep,
this is, uh, Candy Cane. '"
Just say it.
You'll be amazing.
Hey, Black Sheep, this is Candy Cane.
I been lookin' for ya all day.
That was horrible.
Howdy there, Candy Cane.
This is Black Sheep.
I'm right on schedule.
Now, say, uh, "I'll see ya
later on tonight, honey."
- Go, go, go!
- So I guess I'll be seein' ya
- You got it.
and I'll see
your beautiful ass in the P.M.
- So, what was that about?
-Just wait.
Candy Cane, come on.
I knew it!
These guys are so fuckin' horny.
Get him goin'. Get him all worked up,
and then in the middle of it...
say, "Hey, guess what?
I'm a dude."
No way. I can't do that.
Come on, man!
Come on.
-Come on, man, it'll be fun.
Come on, just do it.
Do it.
Hey there, who's this?
- Rusty Nail.
- Nice. Nice.
Well, Rusty Nail, I hope
you're doin' better than I am.
Man, this drive, it seems like
it's takin' forever.
- Roger that, Candy Cane.
- Aw, you got him. You got him!
You know what makes it easier
sometimes, is pretendin' the person...
that I'm talkin' to
is right next to me.
So, why don't you pretend
that I'm sittin' there with you...
just the two of us...
and the windshield?
All right.
-Go, go! Tell him what you look like.
- Shh!
So, I'm 5'1 0", I got dirty-blond
hair down to my shoulders...
I got blue eyes,
really soft skin--
Wow, man.
This is turning me on.
And ifl were there, Rusty Nail,
you know what I'd do?
- Tell me.
- Awesome!
- I'd makeyou feel good.
You would?
Ifl were there and I asked you to,
would you unbutton my blouse?
Sure.
Well, then I'd just
take it off, so now what?
- What do you want to do with me?
-I've never really done this before.
- This is so classic!
I-l--
I'd take off your bra.
Ooh. Okay.
You take that off.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
We can't lose this guy! Go.
I couldn't hear that,
Rusty Nail.
- Rusty Nail? Sweetheart?
That was almost so good!
- Damn!
- What, did we lose him?
Yeah. Shit!
Hey, man, you're a gifted C.B.
prank caller when you commit to it.
"I'd take off your bra."
Hey. Hey, don't park
in a handicapped space.
There's spaces
all over the place.
Yeah, I know.
That's my point.
Dude, I'm gonna gimp it.
I'm not just gonna run in there.
God! Just sit here.
I'll work us a deal, okay?
One more goddamn maid knocks
on my door askin' about towels--
Sorry, Mr. Ellinghouse.
Sorry, my ass!
Where's your boss?
I want the real manager.
The white one.
The one whose first language
is fuckin' English?
- Can you understand that?
- Hi. Could I get a room for the night?
You can disturb me all you want.
I love towels.
- Not done here, friend.
- I know that, amigo. I'm just--
I haven't slept in two days.
You'd best not mess with me.
- You just take care of your own shit.
- Peace.
Tomorrow mornin',
you mark myw ords, asshole--
...a long talk
with your manager.
Your brown ass is gone.
Fuckin' punk.
- What a dick.
Candy Cane.
Hello?
Candy Cane?
- Did you see that fat fucking guy?
- Shh.
- Listen.
- Hello, Candy Cane. Are you there?
- You are kidding me.
- Can you believe that?
- H-Have you talked to him yet?
- No.
- I haven't said anything.
Anybody out there
know Candy Cane? Come on.
What?
Tell him you want to meet up.
Tell him you want to get together.
You're turnin' in for the night.
You want to see him later
at the Lone Star Motel...
in Table Rock, Room 1 7.
Do you just love prison so much?
- We're in 1 8. I mean,
you saw that prick, right?
The prick is in Room 1 7!
Nah, I can't do that.
Come on! That guy sucks, okay?
He body-checked me on the way out.
- Yeah, I know. I saw that.
- What? You-You saw that?
And you're not jumping at this
extraordinary opportunity...
to exact some
much-deserved revenge?
Are you crazy?
Come on! Do it!
Calm down.
- This is amazing!
Rusty Nail. Hey, there.
Candy Cane.
I thought I'd lost ya.
Well, I guess fate
wouldn't allow that.
Glad to know you're
thinkin' about me.
Listen, I'm pullin'
over for the night.
You wouldn't be interested in
gettin' together later, would ya?
I-l thought you were
meeting with Black Sheep.
Well, that was the plan, but
how about I blow him off...
and take a chance with you?
-God.
- I love you, man. This is so great!
Relax.
But I'm not sure that
I'd be what you'd expect.
Please.
Well, you are a man, aren't you,
with a soul and a heart?
- That's all I'd expect.
- Great.
Listen, I'll be
at the Lone Star Motel...
in Table Rock,
if you're interested.
Pink champagne.
Tell him that you like
pink champagne.
And if there's anyway you could
bring some pink champagne...
it's my favorite.
That as good.
- What room?
Room 17. Midnight.
You got that, baby?
I got it.
- I can't wait.
- That was mean.
- I know! I know! This is awesome!
That guy sucks, okay? He totally
body-checked me on the way out.
- All you do is put--
-Do you miss home?
Yeah. I miss...
Mom's chocolate chip cookies.
Playin' football with Dad, Sundays.
Goin' to-- Oh, wait. That's
somebody else's childhood.
What I meant was,
"N-No-o."
You should call sometimes.
You know, when
you don't need bail money.
Yeah, but how often is that?
- I'm serious.
- I call.
Yeah, I know exactly what he says
every time he hangs up the phone.
That I'm the world's biggest loser.
That's comin' from a plumber.
That's comin' from
a guy who wears...
a full-length lime green
jumpsuit to work every day.
They don't needme.
I don't need them.
It works like a charm
if you repeat it enough.
- Listen.
Hit the TV.
Oh.
It's Rusty Nail! It's him!
Shh.
Who the hell is it?
I brought the, uh, the drink.
This is amazing!
I brought
the, uh, pink champagne.
Is this a goddamn joke ?
I swear to fucking God.
What are you-- Are you Black Sheep?
Why don 't you come over here ?
Are you fuckin '
with me, standing in the dark?
This prick is such an asshole!
Show me your face. What was that?
That was weird.
Hey, you know what I think?
I think someone
might have gotten hurt.
No. No, we would
have heard that.
We did. That was a gasp.
Bet that Rusty Nail guy got hurt.
No, it wasn't a gasp.
That was a laugh.
Hey, where are you going?
- What, are you calling Mom?
- Front desk.
- Hi, we just, uh--
We just heard some disturbance from
the room next door, in, uh, Room 17.
"Yeah, hi, this is the drama queen
from Room 18--"
That's hard to say.
It was like a-- Iike a thud.
What are you
No, we think someone
might have been hurt.
And we thought you'd want
to check that out, maybe.
All right. Thank you.
You know what's
gonna happen now, right?
Prick's gonna kill
the night manager.
Hello?
Guy said everything's fine.
All right. Thank you.
The guy said everything's fine.
What'd I tell ya?
-Good mornin'.
-How are you today?
Pretty good.
How are you?
- Where are you boys from?
- Originally, New Jersey.
- U h-huh. What are you doi n' here?
- We're drivin' cross-country.
- My brother-- Yeah, Lewis.
- Your brother?
- Where is he?
- In the room. I don't know.
We had a little incident here
last night. Did you hear anything--
any sounds, or anything
out of the ordinary?
Yeah, actually, uh, uh, next door
I heard some sounds.
-Next door?
- Yeah.
-Could you describe those sounds?
- Yeah, sure.
They were like, uh--
No, wait.
Like that.
- What's goin' on?
- All right, this is Lewis.
There was a "sitchy-ashun"
Iast night. That's all I know.
So after you heard these sounds,
uh, did you look out your window?
- Did you open your door?
- No, sir.
- What happened?
- After you closed your door,
you didn't see anybody else until
I knocked on your door this morning?
That's right. Well, we did call
the night manager, because we were...
uh, concerned, right?
- Right.
- Oh, yeah. Yeah. He mentioned that.
And he also said that one ofyou
had an altercation with the victim.
- Which of you was that?
- Wait. The night manager said what?
Apparently one ofyou had words
with the victim, in the motel office...
- when you were checkin' in?
- No, no. We never met--
- What?
- Ellinghouse.
Ronald Ellinghouse.
He was staying in Room 1 7.
The huge guy?
Yeah, I met him.
-But he's-- He's not the one--
- What happened to him?
It wasn't comely.
I'm sorry. I don't know
what that means.
He was found early this mornin'
lyin' face down...
on the highway median.
So, you're saying that the--
the huge guy is the victim.
You have no idea who might have visited
Mr. Ellinghouse's room last night?
No, sir.
I wish-- I wish we could be
more helpful, but l--
- Is he dead?
- Coma.
You know what I'm thinkin'?
I'm thinkin' that a little look-see
might "refreshify" your memory.
Takin' a look-see at what?
Ripped his jaw...
clean off.
That is the pain in my ass.
My own personal file of ongoing shit
that I got to deal with.
And now, guess what?
Now, I got me another one.
Mr. Ronald Ellinghouse...
Layin' two inches from dead
in my jurisdiction.
Why? Because you sorry-ass punks
thought you'd have some fun.
Fuck!
I'd keep you retards in custody
if I thought it would help answer...
one of the hundreds
of new questions I got.
But, no. All you know
is his damn C.B. handle.
And maybe he drives a truck.
Doyou understand the kinds
of shit I got to grapple with now...
because of what
you assholes did?
You! You got out ofjail when?
Yesterday?
I want you outta here.
This is like an old-fashioned western.
I want you out of Wyoming
before the sun goes down.
I can't believe it.
I can't believe you told them that...
we invited Rusty Nail back.
They could have
thrown me back in jail.
A man is half dead
because ofwhat we did.
Oh, bullshit.
Bullshit!
What, you order ten pizzas
foryour neighbor...
a delivery guy gets there and
your neighbor opens up with an AK-47.
- Is that your fault?
- Yeah, maybe it is.
Fine.
Be the martyr all you want.
No, that's not what I'm doin'.
I'm trying to figure how I'm gonna
drive away after what we've done.
Do what I do.
Just remind yourself that
in 1 00 years, you're gonna be dead.
It's the closest thing
I've got to a philosophy.
No, you know what? I'm taking you
to Denver, and that's it.
Great.
Eastbound,
looking for a westbound...
- for a bear report?
Not a soul.
Never any Smokeys on that str--
- ...andy Ca--
Candy Cane.
- Hello.
- Hey!
- Candy Cane.
- I'm asleep.
- Hey, Candy Cane!
Candy Cane?
Jesus.
Anybody out there know
Candy Cane?
-Or Mama's Boy?
Baa, baa, Black Sheep.
- What are you gonna say?
-Hey, Russell.
This is Black Sheep.
Go to 23.
Hey, Black Sheep.
Do you know
where I can find Candy Cane?
Hey, uh,
what is your deal?
I mean, seriously.
-I'm looking for Candy Cane.
So, you've been
driving around all day...
Looking for a voice?
I think that you can
tell me where to find her.
- Tell him it was a joke.
- Uh, I talked to Candy Cane...
about last night.
And she said
that she's not interested.
- No!
- She's not interested in you--
- Don't do this.
-...ory our pink champagne.
I need to find... Candy Cane.
You need to find...
a highly-qualified psychiatrist--
not a psychologist--
you're gonna need some drugs.
You're gonna have to find
a damn good lawyer...
because the cops
are all over your ass.
- Goddamn!
- Give it to me.
Hey, there,
Rusty Nail, y-you hear this?
That was me, all right? I'm a guy.
It was just a joke.
Apologize.
- Right.
- No,just do it.
- Apologize to him?
- Yeah.
- I-I'll do it.
- No.
Listen, you sick fuck...
you pathetic,
lonely walkie-talkie...
freak show motherfucker, you're
not getting anything from me.
Know why? I have something
more powerful than your psychosis.
It's called a volume knob.
And the only thing I need to make you
go away is to turn it counter clockwise.
Got that?
You copy that?
You know, Black Sheep,
you really ought to get that fixed.
Get what fixed?
Your tail light.
-Do you see anything?
- Yeah. Cars and trucks.
-Just drive.Just be cool.
- Oh, my God.
- Did he follow us from the motel?
- I don't know. I don't know.
- As long as we keep drivin',
we're safe. What?
- Oh, come on, come on!
- I know. But it's okay.
I saw a sign.
"Gas at Laramie."
- There'll be a phone there,
and I'll call Sheriff Ritter.
-Laramie. That'll be good.
- We'll be all right.
- Oh, my God. Oh, God.
- Okay, just stay cool.
- Oh, shit! Will you stop
telling me to be cool?
You're makin' me like, crazy.
Get the map.
- Okay. All right.
- Fuck! We're not gonna
Wait, take the next exit.
I think there's a town there.
- How far is it? How far is it?
- I don't know.
My cuticle to my knuckle.
I don't know. Twelve miles.
- We might not make it twelve miles.
- Take this exit right here.
Yes!
Yes, you're a genius!
I'll pay, you pump. Or doyou
want to pay? I don't care.
- I'll pump.
- Okay. Okay.
Uh, Table Rock, please. Rawlins County
Sheriff Department. Yeah.
Oh, my God.
Hey.
-Hey. Hey.
Hey. Hey!
Sheriff Ritter is not available.
At the tone,
please record your message.
When you have finished recording...
you may hang up or press one
for more options.
Please wait for the tone.
You just got the gas?
Oh, right.
Come on, come on,
come on! Aw, come on.
Come on. Get in the car,
get in the car! Come on.
- What?
- Go, go, go, go!
- He's in there, man.
Did you see him?
Keep driving, keep driving.
Go! Yeah!
- Whoa!
Oh, my God!
-Can you see an on-ramp?
- No!
Okay-- Damn it!
The guy's comin' after us.
- Oh, no. Shit!
- Okay, we're not gonna panic.
- Right.
- We missed the on-ramp, man!
Ooh, mailbox--
Whoa.
No, no, no, no!
Shit!
No.
Lewis! Lewis!
- He said Lewis!
- Stay the fuck back, man!
And I got
a MasterCard.
- Thanks, man. We thought--
- You really scared us.
- Yeah.
- It wasn't the mustache, was it?
My old lady keeps telling
me to shave the thing.
No, no. It wasn't
the mustache, man.
What the-- We're not hip--
What is that thing, your club?
- My tire thumper?
- Yeah.
Shit.
Just checkin' pressure.
Yeah, pressure.
Yeah, the pressure thing.
Are you boys all right
to get back to the main road?
Yeah, we're fine.
Now that we're not murdered.
Thanks a lot for this, man.
That was nice ofyou.
- Y'all have a good night.
- Sorry about that.
- Fuckin' Fu Manchu.
I've never felt like
more of a pussy in my whole life.
- Oh, my God.
Hey, what kind of range
is there on a C.B.?
Uh, I don't know.
Maybe...
five miles?
Well, hey, you know,
I think we should get to a phone.
Call the cops in Table Rock...
Leave a message and let 'em know
that Rusty Nail's in the area.
- Shh. What the hell is that?
Go!
Go, go!
He's right on us!
Oh, man,
he's right on our ass!
- No, don't use that!
- 9-1-1 !
We need some help. Please!
Is anyone out there?
Goddamn it!
Come on! Fuck!
Yeah! Yeah!
Tree! Tree!
- You okay?
- Yeah.
I'm okay. Let's go. Come on.
Yeah, come on, come on.
Come on, let's go!
-Let's go, let's go.
- Shit!
It's not goin' anywhere!
- Come on! Come on!
- Shit!
Shit!
All right!
Come on! Go, go!
Come on!
Go, go, go, go!
Aw, shit!
Oh, no! No!
Come on!
Don't kill us, man!
We apologize!
- Don't kill us, man!
We were just playin' with you, man.
Why?
Just--
Just for a laugh.
A laugh?
Just for fun.
Well, I was
So, where are you now?
We're about
ten miles outside ofLaramie.
We had some car trouble, and, uh,
we're gonna be a little late.
That's all right.
Is everything okay?
Yeah. No, I mean,
it's been a long drive.
- All right. See you then.
- All right.
They fixed the taillight.
So, why don't you
just come home with me?
Blow off Denver
and come home with me.
No, I'm okay.
Listen, I don't want
to tell Venna what happened.
I don't want to ruin things.
Freak her out, you know?
Hey.
The color's not great, but
it's spacious. It's a big car,you know?
- I love it.
- When did you get it?
- I've had it for a while.
- It doesn't look too beat up.
- No.
No, actually, I think the dents
add some character.
- Actually, I was talking about Fuller.
- Hey!
- Hey.
- So, it's been a while.
- Yeah.
So. Well, have you named it yet?
Well, we were thinkin',
uh, either Tad...
or, uh, "Lewis's Shitty Newport."
Hey! She's hot!
- Hey.
- Have a good summer, Vee.
Uh, guys?
My friend Charlotte.
She'll be
my roommate next year.
- These are the infamous Thomas boys.
- Oh, Lewis, right?
Yeah. Nice to finally meetyou.
And, look, I'm Fuller. I'm Lewis's
older, somewhat troubled brother.
- And you're definitely
goin' with us, right?
I kind ofhave to go back
to San Antonio.
Isn't San Antonio
on the way to New Jersey?
- It was nice to meet you.
- You're breakin' my heart,
- I'm gonna miss you.
- Me too. Miss you.
- I love you. Be safe.
- I loveyou too.
Ah, that's so Charlotte.
- Wavin' and drivin' off like that.
So, are you guys ready
for an adventure orwhat?
Oh, completely.
Yeah! Yeah, sure.
Shotgun? You want it,
you gotta call it.
Uh, shotgun.
* Even heavy things
are weightless,yeah *
* Don't take up
any space at all*
* Ride on, ride on *
* Oh, yeah, it's so clear *
Hey.
Welcome to Nebraska.
See this hat I got you?
* Ride on, ride on *
So.
I want to tell you how much
I appreciate you doing this.
Picking me up.
It's pretty much the nicest thing
anyone's ever done for me.
This is the part
where you kiss the girl.
Well, historically.
Hey, Lewis. You're blushing.
* Ride on, ride on*
* Oh,yeah, it's so clear *
* All the bad things will go *
- Thank you.
-* All the good things are here *
- Hey, the room's this way.
- Yeah, but the bar's this way.
- Here's to--
-...Nebraska!
To states? All right.
Ah, look what
Uncle Fuller found.
Three tequilas.
All right.
Well, I can, uh, tie a knot
in a cherry stem with my tongue.
- Shut up!
- Uh-huh.
All right, choose your weapon.
Let's see what you're made of.
- And... go.
- Mm.
- Done.
- Mm-hmm.
Still medalled.
- Bronze.
- Not even close.
Oh, it's straight. It wasn't even bent.
May I have
three more shots of tequila...
- and some matches, please?
- What's your name, sweetheart?
Come on, what's your name?
Hmm?
Oh, what's your name, sweet thing?
I'm just here to buy drinks.
You can call me whatever you want.
How 'bout I call you Peaches?
Do you like Peaches?
- No, not really.
- Oh, you don't like Peaches?
- Hey, what's goin' on?
- What?
- Is this your bitch?
- Excuse me?
Excuse me, I said...
is this your bitch?
'Cause ifit is, you better
shut your bitch up.
Hey, look at me, campus boy. Huh?
Did you hear what I said?
Look me in the face.
You better shut your bitch... up.
Bitch, shut up!
Are you mouthin' off again? God!
Damn it! You can't turn your back
for one minute, you know.
I owe you one.
Now, come on!
- Back on the truck with you, Daisy!
Drunk in the bar!
Now, come on!
Goddamn it!
Gentlemen.
Careful, those are expensive.
Ohh.
What?
Hey.
Hey!
I got a plan.
- And what's your plan?
- Let's never go back there again.
Oh, I can't wait
to never go back there.
Yeah.
I'll be in my presidential suite.
Excellent.
We're gonna head to our--
- our spinning hotel room.
- Okay. See you later.
Good night.
I get the orange one!
This one.
Hey! See, I told you
this was a good place.
Adult channels.
Good. Hey, are you
in the mood for...
a story, or, like,
a collection of scenes?
She isn't a Navy SEAL.
God! Takes me right out.
Hey, Venna's great, man.
She's got--
I mean, you guys--
You guys are just friends, right?
I mean,
that's what you said.
Right? You're just--
just hangin' out, and--
Cause if you're anything
you tell me right now,
and I'm gonna just-- I'll--
...off.
You know?
Great.
Oh, we never got
those last drinks.
Yeah, um...
you know, if we're gonna
get an early start...
we should probably
just crash and go to bed.
Yeah. But, hey...
I'm a-- I'm a licensed bartender.
Yeah, I'd show you my license,
but my hands are full, so--
Oh. Where's your better half?
He's busy. Snoring.
Well, you know, I really don't
think that I can drink anymore.
I disagree.
And I'm a professional.
You know what's amazing?
Nobody knows
where we are right now.
Just kinda...
out there.
Floating.
If anybody wanted to find us
for some strange reason...
they couldn't.
What am I talking about?
I have no idea. Here, try this.
- Yeah!
- Yeah.
Is Lewis okay?
He doesn't normally drink so much.
Yeah, he's totally fine.
Fuller, get the phone.
Hello.
How I thought
you said there was no girl.
- What?
- You said there was no girl.
Fuller.
Listen, there--
There isn't any girl.
Then, what's she doing
in the other room with your brother?
- He's out there!
- He's watching us!
- Rusty Nail?
- Hejust called me.
- Who's Rusty Nail?
Yeah, just now. He knew you were
in here. He's watching us!
- There's somebody watching us?
- He just called.
He said, "I thought there was no girl."
And what you were doing...
in the room with her,
which is an excellent question.
- We're gettin' out ofhere, so
put on your shoes.
- Just do it!
- How scared am I supposed to be?
Much more than usual.
Okay, there's nobody behind us.
Can somebody please talk to me?
He knows we're brothers.
How does that happen?
All right, we're goin' to the police,
we're gettin' of fthe highway...
- then we're goin' home!
- Lewis, goddamn it!
Something weird happened to us
before we picked you up.
- I didn't wanna tell you 'cause
I didn't wanna freak you out.
- You want the short version?
- Talk to me.
- There's this sick guy.
He put this guy in a coma.
This Rusty Nail guy
did something?
- Because of something that we did.
- What did you do?
Hey, man, what the hell
are you doing?
He wants us
to look in the trunk.
There were signs
spray painted back there:
"Look in the trunk."
Signs? What makes you think
they're for us?
Look.
What's going on here?
That's a pretty elaborate
thing to do, paint those signs.
- No, no, no! No!
- What? God!
- Don't open it!
- Why?
- What if there's a head
or a body in there, man?
- Think a bomb's a reason
not to open the trunk?
I say we don't open the trunk!
I'm not getting back into the car
till I know what's in the trunk.
What are you doing?
Oh, shit.
Okay, we plug it in,
and we don't talk on it.
We just listen.
And whatever he says, we just--
We just go straight to the police.
I'm not going to go anywhere...
until somebody tells me why
I should be afraid ofa radio.
Candy Cane, are you there?
Oh, that's right.
I don't mean my Candy Cane.
I mean yours.
Venna?
- How does he know my name?
- We're not getting into it
Let him talk all he wants.
Just tell me where we're going.
You know when a corpse
can't be identified?
No next of kin.
No one to claim the body.
What they do is,
they cut off all the fingers.
All ten of them.
And then they cut offt hejaw.
They cut off
the person'sjaw...
and they put it all in a jar.
- They put it in a jar
with some number on it.
- Oh, my God, that's Charlotte.
- What?
- That's Charlotte.
- That girl ? Your roommate?
- Yeah, yeah.
Hey, what the hell do you want?
I want you to go to the State Line
Truck Stop parking lot.
- I'll find you there.
- Venna, please help me!
And if you go to the police...
I will take her apart
piece by piece.
Good morning.
Hey, he's back.
We're here.
Okay, here's what I want.
Fuller, Lewis...
I want you two
to head inside.
Take a seat at the counter.
Order six cheeseburgers each.
What about Venna?
She stays put.
But you two are
going in... naked.
Naked?
If we go i n there dicks hangin'...
they're just gonna call the police.
Aw, come on.
It's just for fun.
Bullshit,
I'm staying here.
Just stay up front.
I want you to keep the car running.
And if you see anything,
honk the horn and drive.
God, I can't fucking believe
we're doing this.
Billy, come on.
Get in the car.
Sissy.
Now they know what it feels like...
to be the brunt ofthe joke.
Your heart pounding.
Face burning hot.
Now they know what it feels like...
to be the fucking punch line.
They told me what they did
to you, and I'm very, very sorry.
Well, it's a little late
for that, isn't it?
I bet your friends
hada really good laugh...
seeing me standing there
in the rain, holding my bottle.
Well, that's a lesson your friends are
gonna have to learn the hard way.
You wanna see Charlotte alive again?
Here's what you're gonna have to do.
Twelve cheeseburgers, please.
You want fries with that?
ls this a fraternity stunt?
Because if this wasn't
my restaurant--
A man's gonna kill our friend
ifwe don't come in here like this.
I'd say it was
a pretty good one.
- We're not joking, man.
Man, we should be going to the cops.
We're not going anywhere
till we find out what he wants.
Right up here.
This is where we turn.
That's-That's what he said.
You out there ?
We're here.
Something special's
waiting for you.
I'd say it's about
a hundred feet up the road.
So, get out ofthe car.
Wait. I'm not walkin'
one foot out of this--
We don't have a choice.
We're doing what he says.
- What?
- He's-He's got Charlotte.
- Wait! Goddamn it!
-Get out of the car!
What the hell is this?
Wait, how many feet did he say?
- A hundred. A hundred.
- Huh?
Do you hear
or see anything?
This is it.
Shh!
Whoa!
Hi. Uh--
- He's not slowing down.
- He's not gonna stop.
- What's he doing?
- He's not slowing down!
- Run! Car! Go!
- Run! Run!
Whoa, whoa, wait.
What the hell is he doing?
He's coming.
Let's go! Let's go!
Let's go! Come on! Let's go!
Run! Run! Run!
Run!
- Turn left!
- Keep going!
- Whoa!
That way!
Get down! Get down!
Let's go! Go! Go! Go!
Let's go! Come on!
Come on!
Go! Run!
Turn, quick!
Venna?
* Why did I listen *
* To my friends *
* When they told me*
-* What to do *
- Lewis!
* Yes, I still *
* Have my friends *
* But I don't have you *
Venna?
Lewis.
-* Should I say I'm sorry *
* You're blue *
Lewis.
Lewis!
Venna.
Fuller!
- Venna?
- Lewis?
Fuller?
- Lewis!
- Venna?
- You guys okay? Oh, man.
- What?
- Hey, Venna.
- Did you see that?
- Yeah.
- I was sitting back there.
- Venna. You can come out. He's leaving.
- He tried to back up.
- Venna?
- You let her out of your sight?
- Lewis, goddamn it!
- Where the hell were you?
I was over there, man!
Back there!
Venna!
Venna, come out here!
Lewis!
Lewis, help me, please!
Stop, you gotta
leave her alone! Please.
- We'll do whatever you want.
- Lewis!
You don't feel like
meeting me at a motel later, do you?
We'll do whatever you want!
Meet me at the next town--
Medford. Room 17. Midnight.
Do not be one minute late.
Lewis, gas tank!
Come on!
And if there's any way that you could
bring a bottle of pink champagne--
- What are you doing?
Come on, goddamn it!
Venna.
Seven miles. Hey!
Come on!
Hey! Hey!
He said not to call the cops!
Keep a look out.
Don't worry. I've done this before.
What?
Hey, man, we're runnin'out oftime.
God... damn...
- thing won't start.
Uh, hello.
Hey.
- Hey.
- Need some help?
No, I thinkwe're fine.
- And he wonders why I drive a Chevy.
- No shit.
Come on. Come on.
I got some jumper cables.
I'll hook you up.
Uh, no, no, really.
I think we're all right.
- It's just flooded, right?
You'll get it started.
- Just take it and turn it
all the way off, then on.
Want me to show you?
You gotta hesitate it for two seconds.
- There it is.
- All right, perfect.
Hey, you're the man.
Thanks a lot.
Where the hell you goin'?
That's my truck!
Everything's going to be all right.
We're gonna get Venna.
And we're gonna find Charlotte.
Everything's--
Everything's gonna be okay.
Don't you think?
* I wonder *
* My little darling *
* Where can you be *
* This moonlit night *
Okay, motel. Motel.
- Which one?
- He didn't say. Shit!
* My heart
My heart is aching *
* To let it go on breaking *
Venna?
Hold on.
- Venna!
- I said hold on!
I'm sorry.
* Baby, since we're through *
* I've been through lovers' lane *
* Oh, but in my heart *
* There's only pain *
* You went travelin'
but will it last *
* While I'm travelin'
I'm travelin' awful fast *
- * Sweetheart of mine *
- Help you?
- Is this your room?
- Yeah. What of it?
* It's where, where
where it'll be *
* If this new love dies
where will we be *
Oh! Oh! Oh!
* Will your heart*
* Come running back to me *
What's the problem here?
- Shit!
- What did we miss?
* Baby, since we're through *
* I've been through lovers' lane *
* Oh, but in my heart *
* There's only pain *
* You've been travelin'
but will it last *
- Hello, police.
Yeah. I'd like to report
some dead bodies.
Your name, sir?
Hello?
Come on.
It's unlocked.
- Comin' in.
- Hey, we're comin' in.
- We're comin' in.
Venna? Hello?
- Venna?
- Hey.
Oh, the switch.
- Hello?
- Nice, isn't it...
being on the receiving end?
- Where the hell's Venna?
- Who?
Look, I'm not kidding.
Where's Venna?
You see, you might not
be kidding, but I am.
- What did he say?
- That's the point.
- Get it?
- No, believe me...
you made your point, all right?
And we're sorry.
We told you that.
Hey, Lewis, you know what
I think is a real kick?
Pretending the person that
I'm talking to is right next to me.
- Right next to me.
- What?
What the fuck is he talking--
Not what you expected, is it?
That's not what I expected
when I came to room 17, neither.
You guys sittin' right next door...
Listening through the wall.
That's what you did, right?
You listened through the wall.
What do you want?
I just want to enjoy this for a second.
We gotta call the cops.
No. If we call the cops,
he'll kill her.
- Well, what the fuck, man?
- You--
I think you should go outside.
- See if you can see in his room.
- Are you crazy?
Just do it! I'll keep him on the phone.
Go out there now. Go.
Shit!
- You still there?
- Oh, yeah, I'm here.
Why don't you come on over?
Your Candy Cane's waiting.
Listen. We learned
our lesson, all right?
- Oh, is that right?
- Yeah. Yeah, that's right.
So, this is what
we're gonna do, okay?
You're gonna
give us back Venna...
then Charlotte and we're gonna
walk away from this whole thing.
And we're not gonna
tell anybody, all right?
And we sure as hell
won't tell the cops.
Don't!
Don't open the door!
Come on!
Wait! Aah! Shit!
Lewis!
Fuller, where are you?
Fuller?
- Fuller?
Fuller, come on.
Let's get you off this.
- Aah! Don't!
- What?
Pipe! Jesus, there's a pipe
in my leg!
Aah!
We've got a body in here!
We've got a possible 839!
Search every room!
Oh,jeez!
What is he doing?
- Come on, come on, come on!
Sheriff's Department!
Open up! Kick it open!
Clear the door!
Twenty-four, clear!
Move!
On the ground! Now!
- Watch it!
All right, let's go!
Police!
- Come on, come on, come on, come on!
- Twenty-two's clear!
Come on, put your foot--
put your feet on this!
- Twenty-one, clear.
Oh, jeez! Jeez!
- Twenty, clear!
- Come on, get out!
Sheriff's Department!
Open up!
- Nineteen, clear!
- Venna.
- What?
- You gotta stop 'em
Go!
Sheriffs Department!
Open up!
Show me your hands!
Help, Lewis!
- Don't move! Don't move!
- Lewis!
-Just freeze right there!
- That's my brother in the back.
- Get back on the ground!
Get on the ground!
- Don't shoot!
- Stay with the girl!
Hey!
Pull!
- No! No, no, no, no!
- Freeze!
Shoot the truck!
It's not gonna stop!
Run!
Jeez!
Oh, God!
I'll be all right.
Yes, sir.
- Uh, excuse me.
- Yeah.
Did you figure out
who that guy was?
He's just some trucker
named Jones.
Looks like he drove for
some ice company in Wyoming.
Ice company?
What's goin' on?
Breaker one-nine, come on.
Breaker, breaker.
Lookin'for a break.
Westbound l-80.
How's that storm lookin'?
Is it rainin' out there?
Hello?
I'm lookin' forward
to this storm.
Keeps everyone inside.
Washes everything clean.
* Oh *
* I let him in *
* He won'tstay out *
* The wrong one
he loves me *
* Unshakable doubt *
* He waits for me *
* To wake me up *
* Till he wrings me out *
* Every drop, yeah
Every drop *
Subs sync by nEraNga.  http://neranga.smf4u.com/index.php