Our Loves Cheaters.
See you later at the office.
Agreed.
You have to start to follow until...
That was the black man.
And this is WHN in 1050 its dial,
the home of country music
in the city of New York.
It's a beautiful Monday in the Big Apple.
So, city dwellers, If you feel sad,
stay here already become.
Stavros.
Been a long time. Long.
- My wife.
- How are you, Mrs. Niota?
HELICOPTER FLIGHTS CENTER HELIPORT.
I just got and I must go.
Tomorrow I will go to Washington.
So take good care of my wife.
Dad, Dad.
Come in, look at this. It's beautiful.
No, stay here, I'm going to fly.
Take care of your mother.
Are we going to the Plaza, Mr. Niota?
It was Rodney Crowell, and now, quickly,
we have another rookie running
well, they say is New York,
Christy Miller 'Kentucky Nights.'
- Leave it here, Sam.
- Who is Sam?
- What is your name?
- My name is Deborah.
So I called Sam.
Makes sense.
Accept a tangerine
if you give me a cigarette.
What is police?
What? Do I look like cops?
Could be. My brother was a policeman. So?
So your brother was a cop.
Go here, will you, Sam?
Okay, boss.
Who is your friend beard?
Are the mafia or something?
You smoke too much.
But I'm much better.
They used to be three bundles.
Your friend's beard is weird.
I am now about to end a bundle.
- Too.
- I know.
These damn things kill people.
- I stop.
- Yes, I stopped.
Your friend does not smoke,
not like the music.
Do you is rare as a friend beard?
Me? No, Sam, I'm charming.
- Leave me here.
- I love it.
Well, Sam, see you later.
I think it will, boss.
I do not know why I like you,
your freckles o... your freckles.
It...
Dad, Dad, Dad.
Wait, Stefania.
My God, the best girls the world.
Knew you'd come today. I knew it.
- I knew it, too, Dad.
- Not true.
It was I who said to wait
more. You do not say anything.
- But what I thought.
- I thought.
- You're lying again.
- Of course not.
You're smoking, Johnny.
- God, how did that there?
- How did that there?
She is Sam, girls. This is Steffie.
- How you doing, Steffie?
- Pretty good.
- And Gina.
- Hello, Gina.
- Hello.
- I gotta go.
Yeah, go ahead, Sam. Have a nice day.
See you later, girls. Nice to meet you.
Bye, Dad.
- Is it new?
- What do you think?
- It's very pretty.
- I liked his freckles.
- Did you have freckles?
- Yes, Dad, lots of freckles.
Dad noticed the freckles.
- Thank you, Stefania.
- What about Christy?
You always say 'Christy, Christy,
Christy, 'Dad.
Why do it? It is so nice.
- I do not know what I do.
- I have not seen you in two days.
Two days passed, Dad.
Shut up, idiot keeps repeating
everything I say.
- I do not.
- Sure.
Maybe she has the same idea.
- But you always wanted.
- I have the same idea.
Very boring.
Dad, I can buy a pineapple?
What will you do with a pineapple
at school?
Who do you cut it? Your mother
you buy a pineapple.
- How is your mother?
- Okay.
- He threw a vase of roses Dad.
- I mean, Cliff.
- Roses, huh?
I do not know why I called him Dad.
You do not call it that.
- Do not worry about that.
- Mom likes to call Dad.
No, does not care.
Do not worry. It's crap children.
Call it whatever you want.
They look at it much more than me.
I was the one who left.
Sometimes I wish they were together.
But then we would not have known
Christy or Alicia.
O Suzanna. Are you still in Albuquerque,
New Mexico?
Yes, there will be a while.
- Christy is so funny. I like it.
- I like Alicia.
I also like Alicia. I said I did not like.
You like more Christy.
No, I like both.
But sometimes I feel bad by Christy.
- Why Angel?
- I do not know.
Christy's funny, Dad.
Christy is in love you, Dad.
Yes, well, I love her.
But you're not in love it.
What the hell do you know that?
- Feminine intuition.
- It's feminine intuition, Dad.
- Do you want to complete it?
- Come on, come later.
- Did you finish that case, Dad?
- Why not see me.
- Today I started a new one.
- You got a date tonight?
- What about the driver?
- Well, I hate to be alone.
Stop worrying, give you an ulcer.
- I love you, Dad.
- Oh, Gina, my Gina.
When can we eat?
- How about tomorrow?
- Well, goodbye.
Goodbye.
Be good to your mother.
- Good luck tonight, Dad.
There you go again. Stop doing that.
Taxi.
Take me to Wall Street, yes?
God is very beautiful in that dress.
Keep your head in the business,
Charles. Already dark?
- I think not.
- Whatever you say, Chas.
Do you think it will be with her boyfriend
or your husband...?
We'll find out. Come on, come on.
It costs so much to say.
Yes, I think it happened once, but...
You never know.
I do not know.
Do you?
- No.
- Are you sure?
Goodbye. Goodbye.
- It's a hotel.
- Well, Chas.
- I can help you, sir?
- No, thanks. I am...
...well...
...yes, do you...? In fact, I already ate.
Then maybe...
Do you have a specialty? O...
It may take a tomato juice.
- Ice, I guess.
- Very good.
Unless... thanks...
Forget it, leave it pending.
I never want to talk to her.
Wait, wait, Amy.
The gaucho has just arrived.
The boyfriend of Ms. Martin.
She has a girl I wish to know.
I do not know who the other girl.
You know what, I'll find out.
Johnny tell where we are, right?
I must go, little one.
See you later.
Mary, you got a cigarette?
It's Sylvia.
Glad to hear it, Sylvia. Got a cigarette?
Sure, why not? Is something wrong
in sight, son?
Yes, you dazzle me attractive.
Got a match? Where will you be later?
- I'm busy.
- With the Gaucho?
Maybe. What do you care? You know him?
No, do you?
Are not you getting curious?
How I can help?
No, just a friend. A rich kid.
But it's nice.
At least I can see his eyes.
The glasses disappear
at midnight. Where will you be?
- Here, sir.
- What?
Okay, thanks.
Georgie-George, one of the great
men. Can I borrow your phone?
Sure, Johnny, go ahead. Are you working?
No, never.
Yes, dear, do you communicate
with the Algonquin?
Honey, call Arthur Brodsky
to lobby for me, okay?
Mr. Arthur Bromsky.
- Yes? Yes?
- Telephone.
Brodsky.
Yes? Hello, Johnny, What's up?
Is the Plaza? What do the...?
Oh yeah? Really?
Not much.
Ms. Martin is leaving with her boyfriend.
What? Oh, again, no.
Christy is not so silly.
Da tip, friend.
Do not worry, I'll be there.
- Who was that?
- Johnny, nothing important.
Go, go.
Perhaps best left to remove
the groom in the reports.
- Groom...
- You are four times this week.
- Yes, but never alone with him.
- Yes.
- Until today.
- That's what I meant.
I do not like. I do not like at all.
Quiet, quiet, well. Right here.
Thanks, buddy.
The husband asks many questions.
Already dark?
Yes, I suppose.
Just give me a puff.
It will be a long night.
Me too.
Look at it this way, Chas.
Is in preparation with boyfriend...
...when it has a husband.
If the groom goes on to deal
as husband, will be...
Will be away from her husband.
And if that happens with her husband,
the case is over, pay us...
...and then it's every man for himself.
Yes, change the boyfriend what worries me.
Yeah, well, that's what worries everyone.
So we got the job.
Remember, Chas?
- Yes, yes.
- Chas...
Remember?
I know, I know.
No, no, I'm leaving. Keep it.
I will see Johnny.
Call me later to Christy if you can, okay?
See ya.
Hello, beautiful.
City Limits.
You shit.
Christy Miller, ladies and gentlemen.
I'm past tired, honey, old-sick.
I will not be another your passive women...
...who tremble at the thought of you,
and have to endure any type of abuse...
...only for the glorious opportunity...
...spent a glorious night you,
once in a while, every death of bishop.
No, sir, for nothing, honey.
No way.
Unfortunately, honey, kiss very well.
And you're very wrong with me.
Very bad. What you need is a good man...
...see all your actions,
have drinks waiting in the dressing room,
you rub your feet at night.
Protect your throat...
...tell you how great you are,
and prepare eggs in the morning.
Once I made eggs.
Yes, and burned them.
They looked delicious.
Why you looked at the clock?
- Why would you tell time?
- Why? Have an appointment?
Yes, redhead, tall, freckled.
- It's a taxi driver.
- Do you take a walk?
- Not very far.
- You're such a liar.
I think so.
Hey, Christy.
It's Arthur.
- Sounds like it.
- What does Arthur here?
I do not know, why do not you ask?
Did you tell Arthur to come?
Why would you say to Arthur to come?
Something is not right. Pasa.
Hello, Christy. Sorry for the intrusion,
Johnny was looking for.
- Hey, Johnny.
- What is it, boy?
- Well...
- We have a little problem.
- Yes, for Martin. Leon is...
- Furioso.
- It comes foaming at the mouth.
- In fact, you're right and said...
If you're not there immediately,
are all dismissed.
I guess you better get out.
Yeah, I guess I better go.
See you soon.
I doubt it.
Sure, sure.
Hey, where are you going?
Where are your skates?
Yes, but I catch this guy.
Sylvia, still do not know what will later.
I must first find this other guy.
I love to be with both,
Tulips especially with your friend.
How are you, chasy, boy?
Hey, brother.
- Oh, God, thank you.
- What are you doing here?
I do not know. I do not know what to do.
- Have you smoked the whole joint?
- I was just standing there...
The whole joint. ...Watching.
When I realized I was here
skating like an idiot.
Look, we'll get into serious trouble.
You know. I think we should
be more discreet.
I know, but let me kiss in the mouth.
The husband will like.
No, Arthur, I thought.
- What?
Now what you thought.
Yes, if the groom...
Chasy what do you do?
Better take a break.
Be right back.
Hey, Tulips.
- You known?
- Who? She? No.
Well, Sylvia, Tulips, he is...
What's your name?
- Go maneuver.
- Not bad, huh?
Just say your name, girl
is incredibly resilient.
I called Barbara Jo.
Hello, Barbara Jo, what's up?
What if you skate? Come on, come on.
Are you okay?
Okay, thanks. How are you?
Sam, Sam, refrigerator.
- How was your day babe?
- I'm starving.
Yes, what you had in mind?
Nothing in particular.
- Frozen pizza?
- Well...
I am a bit particular.
Yeah, well, I know a French.
Sounds chic.
But it is not.
LUNCH...
- Deborah, how are you?
- Well, well.
- Cretin.
- Friend of yours?
- Briefly.
- You have a broken heart.
- You can see bleed.
- You think so?
- And I can see why.
- You're just a romantic.
Yes? What's wrong romance?
There is nothing wrong.
It costs only to find it.
You never had much of it, Do not you, babe?
Not much. I just do not like
sleep alone, I guess.
Well dressed lie. Why do not you?
- Why can not I sleep dressed?
- Yes, exactly.
A man and a woman sleep in the same bed...
...but a plank between them,
a plank of wood.
He can see it, you can hear her breathing
but can not touch.
What will you do if you can endure?
Eventually splintered.
This line here is the heart.
Show that you're very emotional.
Emotions are great.
Besides, no one can avoid feelings.
- That's a problem.
- What?
- You're married, right?
- Yes.
That line is short, is weak.
- But that's not what worries me.
- No?
There's a bad romance.
Really?
Very bad. You see this line?
It's not going anywhere.
Well, that will not let me far, right?
Well, I do not know.
Here's something new.
Very promising. You see this line?
Goes on forever.
Maybe my line as a skater.
Your line as a skater.
No, your true online of passion.
But is separated line marriage.
It does not start until...
Are you going to divorce?
You get very personal, right?
Sorry. Sorry.
They just have to step aside these...
- I gotta go.
- Yes?
Well thanks for reading. Got a phone?
If I have...? Yes 33901 Trafalgar.
- Goodbye.
- Can you... remember...?
Sorry, sorry.
I'm not rude, it's just that my shoes are...
The temple... I left my shoes...
...and my skates.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
Willy, a friend of mine, let it go, okay?
- Well, Arthur.
- See you tomorrow.
- Listen, I have a knot...
- Go.
Go ahead, it's fixed.
Toma.
Hello, Chas. How are you?
Good. Go ahead.
- Wait...
- Come on.
- Come on, chasy.
- Come on, turn here.
- Holy God.
- Have you...?
- Yes, here it is. Give me your foot,
- And I will.
- What happened? Did you get anything?
Pretty much. Three votes say
that marriage will not last.
- Sure, but what about the groom?
- The gaucho?
- Two to one is not. Tulips says yes.
- Tulips says yes.
A big no to Barbara Jo. Sylvia
undecided, which is what I like.
- Sylvia is undecided...
- That's what I like.
- See, I call you BJ.
- Yes, I'll be home.
Good. I liked his hair.
- What?
- Nothing.
- Here's your change.
- Thanks.
Play serious brother.
Something must have made her
change your mind.
- You think so?
- Chasy, chasy.
- I know.
I go see Barbara Jo and find out more.
Wait, what...? What... Why...?
Smoke this, try to sleep.
Tomorrow will be a difficult day.
Now she knows you.
Incidentally, I met her. Worth the wait.
¿Snoring?
A lot?
Do you kicked?
A couple of times without bruising.
No splinters.
Listen, you know where is the key.
When you...
- Need sleep?
- Yes, indeed.
See ya.
Hello, Ritzi, how are you?
Hello, Johnny, Where's Arthur?
I do not know. I was going to ask.
Tell him to call me, okay?
I will, I will.
Arthur.
Shit.
Sorry, Arthur. I thought not.
Love, the girl is love.
I'll call you tonight at 6:30, Rita.
One day you stab.
What can you do? Is love.
Yes, have to queue behind Leon.
- Do you?
- Why? What happened?
I called him from the gym, is the day
Dolores in the gym.
Now is Dolores.
- Yes.
- It was cold.
Worse, it was nice.
I must go to the gym.
What? Will the spies this morning?
No, but now much more difficult.
- I say...
- Yes, I know Barbara Jo,
not as good as I expected, but still.
What, were discovered?
No, no, but we talked.
- You spoke.
- A while.
A while.
Enough.
- A little more.
- I figured.
- But we connected.
- Still.
Well you need a beard.
- A front.
- Intelligent, yes.
Odyssey Detective Agency 'NEVER SLEEP'.
Odyssey Detective Agency, never sleep,
- Can you wait, please?
- Amy, Amy.
- Hey, Amy, Leon is busy?
- Thanks.
Charlie, where the hell are
case reports in Martin?
- Well...
- We have them, Amy. Any calls?
Yes, Mandy, Sherry...
...Terry...
- Terry's sister, Sherry.
- The very same.
- Interesting.
- Any calls for me, Amy?
- Only your father, Charles.
Ah, her father again.
Why do not you call and ruining your day?
Oh, God.
- Charles.
- Hello, Mr. Leondopolous, how are you?
Where are the reports Martin case?
Yeah, well, we have been
very busy lately, Leon.
We have them, Leon just yet tipeamos not.
So we do not have, Arthur.
The typing is not a bureaucratic flourish
middle class.
And I'd really rather not hear exasperation...
...in the tone of one this morning.
Because I'm on the verge of a precipice,
further irritation and smallest...
...could cause me to fall a yawning chasm,
which I seriously doubt I would
able to leave.
Jesus, Mary and Joseph. Holy Mother.
- Damn, that burns.
- Charlie.
- I know.
- Bring the ice.
- I have it.
- Butter.
Ice, ice, butter makes it worse.
Once a week the same story, Leon.
Thank you. Thank you.
All right.
In any case... in any case...
...when Mr. Martin called this morning...
...requesting information on
his wife... Thanks, Miss Lester...
...for the first time in three weeks...
Thanks, Miss Lester...
...would have been happy with scribbles
in toilet paper.
Anything would have been
better than nothing.
Charles, the file was empty.
- Is this all, I will tonight.
- The will tonight.
Tonight is too late I need them now.
The need now.
- Dolores I re...
- I could deal with Amy.
Have a call in line four, Mr. Leondopolous.
Go ahead, Chas.
We can take care of everything,
Mr. Leondopolous.
They can handle everything, Leon.
Well, someone take care of something. John.
- Yes, Leon?
- I can see you a minute?
Sure. Sure, sure.
Let's talk.
It has two calls on hold Mr. Leondopolous.
I am very aware of this, Ms. Lester.
One of them is Mrs. Leondopolous.
Hello, yes?
I hear every word what the doctor said.
- Very good.
- Thanks, Amy.
- Sure.
- I love your wings, you know?
I know. Detective Agency Odyssey...
...rarely sleep.
Hello, Christy.
What a pleasant surprise.
Good morning, Amy. You look great
this morning.
- Thanks, Christy.
- Very good.
Thanks, Christy.
Do you know the desktop Mr. Russo, Amy?
Right there, Christy, not far Mr. Russo.
Thanks, Amy. I can see that all
work hard today.
- Good morning, Christy, how are you?
- Good day, Judas.
Here are some things I have
belonging to Mr. Russo...
...and I'm sure that will need
much more than me.
Yes, Harold, shut up.
Who's this, honey? You have the wrong guy.
Very funny. Excuse me.
And Charles, how are you this morning?
I am a bit exhausted...
Travel Odyssey ¿I can help?
Just a moment please.
Arthur, is the line of travel: Barbara Jo.
Barbara Jo.
Hi Jo, what do you know?
You look sexy, Charles.
Yes? I've been late, it.
You say you always look sexy
when you have delayed?
I guess I'll have to stay delayed.
Yes, Harold. Say hello to Harold, Charles.
- Hey, Harold.
- Well, Jo, I must go.
- What?
- Meeting in the gym.
Christy, I must go.
- Can you drive?
- I can not really.
- Thank you, Charlie.
- Sorry.
- Where are you going?
- North of the city.
- But there I go.
- Well to the north.
- Do you shave today, Charlie?
- What? Yes.
It's funny, here it seems you had a beard.
Barba ¿?
No, smooth as silk.
Christy, where you said you were going?
- North of the city.
- What a coincidence, me too.
- Come on, I'll take you.
- Thanks, Charles.
It's been a rough day
My toilet exploded this morning.
- Oh, really?
- Yes, I pulled the chain innocently...
...and believe that a bomb exploded.
- I was lucky not to be granted.
- Yes..
Yes, thanks for calling.
Listen, we will call you back.
I saw that.
- What did you see?
- Nothing.
- Type.
- Ray.
Three back Monday... When?
Well, copious notes.
All right, dear. Very good.
Yes.
God.
There is a virus going around.
Excuse me, my back.
People drop like flies.
I have not seen anyone fall, Leon.
I saw a couple of guys running.
They will fall soon.
Leon, last night I slept with a 23.
Redhead.
I put my arms around him, kissed.
- And fell asleep.
- Is there something wrong?
No, there was nothing wrong.
In this case, it must be spring.
Is that it?
I've been noticing an expression
distant dreamer...
...in your eyes lately.
I have the impression
that your personal life is...
Yeah, well,
Sometimes we all come good a map.
- What about the husband?
- Stavros?
Yes, Stavros, the husband.
Rare. That marriage is rare.
- When is it going?
- Tonight, for five days.
- Is he kidding?
- I really do not know.
But it was always a womanizer.
Actually, I have 15 years without seeing it.
This is his second wife, I met the first.
For man believes in marriage.
Do not we all?
Yes, indeed.
Well I'll take the boy with me.
You have to rest the back, Leon.
What's that supposed to mean?
You have to rest your back.
- Ready, son?
- Yes, it's good, Dad.
Is there anything I can read?
What will Mr. Leondopolous.
Odyssey, never sleep. Can you wait, please?
Take care of your back, Amy.
He is sensitive.
- It's a sensitive man.
- I know.
- John?
- Thanks, Ames.
Bye, guys.
Yes? One moment, Ms. Leondopolous.
I have another call.
- Is your wife again.
- I went.
- Where'd he go?
- Anywhere.
Yes, Ms. Leondopolous, sorry.
Went to lunch early.
¿I can give you a message?
I will. Have a nice day.
- It feels a lot worse.
- Sorry to find out.
- Me too.
- Amy, I think John suspicion.
Yes?
Keep doing jokes about my back.
Probably right, we are overdoing it.
Do you agree?
Stop here, driver, fine.
- Well, Mack.
- Please, beware the change.
- Sure, sure.
- Thank you.
Charles certainly are the man
more impulsive.
- Have ever known.
- Repulsive, you said?
'Im'... impulsive, Charles.
I do not believe at all repulsive.
I thought you might want to juice
orange or a hot dog.
- I think you're very handsome.
- Thanks, Christy.
You look good. Do you want juice
or sausage?
Yes, I would really like a juice big orange.
A large orange juice, please.
- Are you Greek?
- Yes.
Thank you very much, dear.
In addition, Charles, I
thought you were late.
No, my watch is running fast.
Would you like to walk?
Why did not cross the street?
Honestly, Charles, sometimes you're weird.
Sorry, Christy, would you like sit?
What's on your mind, Charles,
on the sidewalk?
Want to come to lunch, Charles?
I can not cook, but I know
where everything is.
Do you like eggs, honey?
I have no bread and eggs.
Are bread, Harold? Remember? Yes.
Harold also believed to no bread, Charles.
I have not really hungry, Christy.
- No?
- No.
- Would you like some new shoes?
- New shoes?
Did I say if you would like shoes
new? Those are quite old.
Thank you very much, Charles. These are
original design of the 30s.
That's what I mean.
Would not you like some new?
Well, Christy...
- Charles.
- Here, stay with Harold.
You are so strong about it.
Look at those beautiful shoes, Harold.
Are not they beautiful?
- I can help?
- We would like to see new shoes.
Yeah, well, here we do not sell used shoes.
- Good.
- This way.
Sorry, I'm terr...
Sorry.
Do you like this, Charles?
- Yes, great.
- Really?
I try them. I also I'll try a dress.
Watch Harold, will you, Charles?
Harold, quiet.
More or less.
I like it.
What do you think, Charles?
God, Christy, what are they?
Where did you get? Not at all attractive.
I hate you, honey. I thought you liked you.
No, no, talking about these boots.
Here, why do not you testing?
Whatever you say, Charles.
I just have to take off this dress
no use to me.
How do you like my new coat?
- Thank you, Charlie.
- The only...
Harold. I can not even leave
take care of the dog.
I can not believe I'm so sorry. Harold.
Harold, just calm down.
Hello, I'm sorry.
Sorry, I'm Christy Miller.
Hello, you're the singer.
I'm afraid so. The record goes
through lists right now.
- I am Dolores Martin, gladly.
- Likewise.
- Ms Martin, Miss Martin?
- Mrs.
Ah, madam.
And who is this big glass of water?
Joseph, it is Christy Miller country singer.
Hello, nice to meet you.
Charles. Come here.
Who, me?
Charles is like
the absent-minded professor.
- What? Who?
- Charles.
He is Charles. Charles, she is Dolores.
- Hello, Charles.
- Nice... know, Dolores.
And this is Joseph, Charles.
- Hey, who are you?
- I'm Charles, Joseph, how are you?
- I am Joseph.
- Good.
Hello.
This way.
And at any time the groom, right?
No, the husband.
- Is the husband?
- And the son.
Do you agree?
Ah, yes, there it goes.
LIQUIDATION...
- Do you like this?
- Yes.
- Hey, no skating here.
- Yeah, agreed.
Come, come, come on.
You said just a week, Dad, right?
Maybe more, maybe less.
- May depend on your mother.
- Dad.
Well, look after your mother.
Goodbye, Angie.
The two behave yourselves.
The other side of the disc works well...
...will also be a success.
This very excited about it.
- Do not you think, Charles?
- Sure.
Sure. What?
Gosh, really distracted.
Dolly was telling the disk,
how excited I am. It
fantastic, the trials were hard...
...but are great Do not you agree?
What are you looking at?
Christy, what time did you say Friday?
At 8:00.
- At 8:00, right. Do they come, girls,
Friday night on the street Greene?
Yes.
You're acting very peculiar, Charles.
Anyway, it's Friday. At what time
Tonight we, Charles?
- Where is fine.
- Arriving late to class.
We better go.
Heavens, I agree.
- The dog, the dog.
- Bye, girls.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Dolly, nice to meet you.
- Bye, I'll call you later.
- Bye, Joseph.
Christy, here. Then I'll see tonight, right?
One minute, Charles. Coming to take
something to my house?
I can not really, Christy. I re...
Charles, you are tense,
nervous and apprehensive.
We will go to my apartment right now.
I do not want to hear another word.
- Well, I do feel tense...
- Taxi.
I can not believe Charles,
really I can not.
The dog is hurt. Charles.
- I cover the cost.
- Take off your skates.
- What?
- Do you think we should go?
- We're going to pick it up.
My God.
Your father is good for this.
I do not.
Well, it is very difficult.
- Want to try?
- What you had in mind, Laura?
- Nice.
- Laura, Laura, face in the half,
give my son a rifle. Give a rifle.
- Thanks, Dad.
- It's not really your son.
Sure, the hair curling to shame.
My son is a hippy aged.
- Finally.
- My God, I thought I was.
- I think it was you.
- Thanks, buddy.
What is it, brother? Do you
Polish accent? What is that?
- Me? No, English.
- Really? Excuse me...
Come Viville. Let's see some action.
Laura, I read your mind.
There.
- Congratulations.
- Slow down, take your time, Arthur.
- Yes, Arthur, slowly.
- It's open shot, I can not miss.
You gave everything except what you want.
It is the story of my life, honey.
- Maybe he should point to.
- What say you, Mitchell?
- Michael.
- Hi, Mike, I'm Arthur.
That's my dad, and that, John.
- Come on, honey, it's late.
- Just a second.
You have to aim carefully...
...to the bottom of the light.
Then you have to slowly squeeze.
I can not believe it. You're a prince.
- Prince Mike, thanks for the advice.
- Nothing.
- Goodbye, nice to...
- Listen, Mike, something more.
Did you ever play checkers by computers?
No, I do not.
Laura, would you mind showing
my son and me some moves?
I have a hunch you know them.
It's pretty good, what do you say?
Puzzle, puzzle.
Please, my husband I still do.
Yes, I know.
I am following.
- I do not know what to say.
- Me neither.
Why not have lunch and talk about it?
Sorry, that is not possible.
Of course it's possible.
It can be difficult, but definitely possible.
Now you bring your child I will bring mine.
That is not his son, Mr. Russo.
Michael, are we?
- You said that?
- Quiet.
- Sorry.
- Tell me what, honey?
- They work in secrecy.
- Top secret.
Yes, and we should not tell anyone
who knew them.
They are in covert mission. So the hair.
- I see.
- They need our help.
You two think of everything.
Come on.
Laura, see you after work.
- Yes? Too bad.
- Better than none.
- For the penguin.
- See you later.
- Is in love with me.
- I noticed.
Mike, do you have a girlfriend?
- Two or three, nothing serious.
- Already have a stable.
- Do not call it stable.
- Chiquita...
I'll continue until you change mind.
I guess that's your job.
- See you.
- Bye, see you.
- Dad?
- What?
What do we do?
I do not know.
I think I better bring your sisters.
- To my sisters?
- Tell them to go to work.
Yes.
Here we are, home at last.
Do not make much mess, Harold,
be a good boy.
Yes, Charles, just put it there.
Go ahead, Charles.
Calm down, Charles, calm down.
Is not it lovely? Do you hate dogs, honey?
- Because I can lock him up.
- No, not at all.
A record, Charles. Want to hear?
Sure. Nice view.
Thank you, Charles. Why do not you
feel? Get comfortable.
Can I get you a drink?
Yes, Harold. Calm down, dear.
- Do you have vodka?
- Indeed yes, Charles.
Do you have a match somewhere, Christy?
On the way, honey,
but that smoking probably is a year ago.
All right.
How are you, Charles?
- Harold bother you?
- No, no. All right.
Thank you.
- Do not you love that song?
- It's very pretty.
Here, Charles, but do not approve.
Want to sit back, Charles?
I really do not feel very good Christy.
Do not, Charles? What is it?
- I think I have a headache.
- Okay, Charles.
- We have to do anything.
- Why do not we talk and nothing more?
Sure. Want a massage Charles?
Why do not you give acupressure?
- What?
- Acupressure.
- I will relieve all the pressure.
You'll feel like a cloud pants.
- A cloud in trousers?
- Come on.
- What?
- You have to sit back, Charles.
Now, do not hurt.
How beautiful how music does that
there, do not you think?
- Very nice.
- Not yet decorum that room.
Look, I have a terrace.
Will you go out to the terrace?
That's not a terrace, Christy, is a ledge.
- No, seriously, Charles, come on.
- No, Christy, no.
Heaven, Charles, today you really nervous.
Now take off your tie, jacket
and shirt, honey.
Be right back.
Want to play on the terrace, Harold?
Charles, I can not give Acupressure.
- If you stand in a corner.
- Christy, I do not.
- I really feel like...
- Of course not, Charles.
I'll give you acupressure...
...and then you go to enlist tonight.
Now come on, lie down here.
Is not it beautiful? Wants to play.
Calm down, Harold. Charles is very tense.
Had a bad day. Come on, Charles, lie.
Will not you take off some clothes?
- You will feel more comfortable.
- No, okay.
I'm pretty comfortable.
It is enough, Harold.
Leave in peace Charles.
Let's give acupressure Charles.
Here we go, Charles. Just relax.
- Is not it nice the song?
- Very nice.
- Do you feel my finger?
- Yeah, right.
Well, just concentrate feel it.
Do you feel my finger?
- Tell me, Charles.
- Yes.
Close your eyes, dear, and feel my finger.
- Do you feel my finger?
- Yes.
- Christy, not really think I can...
I feel too much pressure here.
- Do you feel my finger?
- Yes, sorry, but...
Just hold me, Charles.
We do not have to do anything.
Put your arms around me Charles.
No... anything.
- Do you feel my finger?
- Christy.
- Yes, but...
- Do you feel my finger?
- Yes.
- Charles.
- Yes?
- Do you feel my finger?
- Christy, I...
Do you feel my finger?
This is a little crazy, right?
Yes Do you feel my finger?
Yes Oh, God.
- What is it, Charles?
- Do you feel my finger?
Sorry, honey. It could be my agent.
Sure, I feel much better.
Hello? Who? Did Joseph?
Hello, Jose, how are you? Joseph.
- Did something happen?
- What?
One moment, Joseph. Calm down, Charles.
He just wants to know the time for this
night. Send a car.
At 8:00 is okay, honey. I can not wait.
I said I can not wait.
Wait. What?
No matter, Joe. We'll see you tonight.
This guy is very attractive,
but I do not understand language.
Everyone has that problem ever, Christy.
- Do not you think?
- Sure.
Kiss me again, yes, Charles?
I really like you, Christy, Did you know?
Yes, I know, and why not keep it
well, right?
- Do not you think?
- Yes, I suppose.
But why do not you kiss me
anyway? It's so nice afternoon.
Well, here.
Well, come on foot.
Grab your skates and went inside.
Here we go, my beautiful girls.
Sorry. Are these seats are occupied?
By the way, have you seen Arthur?
Yes Where is Arthur?
Where's Arthur?
I thought it was you.
- Of course not.
- Not laced.
- God.
Arthur, of where did you get?
- We are your sisters.
- We are your sisters...
- They are my sisters.
- Ah, yes.
Are your sisters.
I really fell into it, right?
- I'm not saying...
- I do not think she says...
- Arthur always cares.
- Arthur is accustomed to children.
You say you do not trust me...
...to care for these three Dwarfs?
No, I do not know Who takes care of me.
- John.
- That's what I'm afraid.
You talk nonsense, mother.
The evening does not make sense.
- John is very good with women.
- You have many girlfriends.
- Would you shut up?
- Come on, leave it on site.
- No.
- That's great, Mr. Russo.
Mom, I promise that we will care.
- Iran to skate.
- Yes, waiting there.
- The wait there.
- Thanks, Mom.
- I said yes.
- You did not say no.
- The child is right.
- Come on, get a taxi.
Arthur, look after them.
- Do not worry.
- Taxi, taxi.
As for you, you forgot of it before.
Oh yeah? Well, not mine, is it.
Here you go. See you later, Dad. You too.
- Take care.
- Michael, take care.
- Do not worry.
- Bye, Johnny.
- You're amazing.
- Come on, Stefania...
Why you have to repeat everything?
- I could never deal with men.
- I know what you mean.
- You bet.
- No, not with women.
I, with women.
You say you do not know deal with women?
You? How funny.
You are a professional, Mr. Russo.
- Women are their line.
- Why do not you call me Johnny...
...or Jack, or Jake or Harry?
- Whatever you want...
- Do I have reason or not, Mr. Russo?
- About what?
- That women are their line.
Could be.
That proves nothing.
Only really matters falling in love.
Because when you fall in love,
no one is professional.
Well, what if a girl
falls in love with a professional...
...and the professional is not reciprocal?
The girl has a problem.
Are we talking about someone you know?
Only slightly.
Are you in love right now Mr. Russo?
I mean, personally.
On a personal level, no. Do you?
It's a silly question. I am married.
That's why I asked.
Mr. Russo, promise me never get married.
I promise.
Promise you will never fell in love.
Mr. Russo, he begins to like.
Honey, if you like the country,
I love this place.
What? What?
Country is the best place, Joseph.
I love music West, you know?
- Can you really sing?
- Has a hit record, Joseph.
You hear that, Charles?
- He heard it, honey.
- What?
- What? What?
Ladies and gentlemen,
Christy Miller is with us
tonight in the audience.
She believes it is his night off
but we will give.
Up here, Christy.
Sing with us.
Come on. All singing.
Ladies and gentlemen, Christy Miller.
Thanks, Christy.
- This is funny.
- What?
I was going to buy you a drink.
I live here.
What a coincidence.
But I see that my friend used the house.
A taxi driver I know.
That is his taxi.
Do they use it, or you are...?
No, no, just hang out.
Oh well, I'll chaperone.
- Where is that drink?
- Here.
- Your friend loves music.
- I like it.
- It's me, Sam.
- I was going to drop you a note.
She is Angela, Sam.
Hi, Deborah.
- Just me going.
- Hi, Deborah.
What are you drinking?
I have to work. I drive a taxi.
Yes, he said. I'll have a Scotch.
- Do you enjoy?
- How?
- Okay.
- Pure, thanks.
Management for my dad.
Had a slight... you know.
Sorry, how are you?
Great... will be great.
Goodbye. I left the keys on the table.
Thanks for the house.
- Sure, Sam. Anytime.
- Goodbye.
Nice to meet you.
Why do you call Sam?
Because it looks like a Deborah.
Well, not like a Sam.
Sam seems more than Deborah.
- So why do not you call me Steve?
- Well, Steve.
But you seem a Angela.
How do you 'Angela'?
It means 'angel', right?
Now you know why my husband I still do.
I am a woman who blatant
can not be trusted.
I had another idea.
Reminded me of someone
whom I met at school.
My sister in eighth grade.
He loved her.
Surely it with me too.
But I waited for her make the first move.
What did?
Just do it.
I think it's sexy to have that car...
...follow us the whole way.
Charles And why?
Are you in love or am I crazy?
It seemed a bit obvious that he wanted
take your friend home alone.
Oh, just, yes.
You are incredibly beautiful.
Are you rich or something, honey?
- A little.
- I think I'm falling in love.
Love? Do you want love?
Yes, bright eyes. How old are you?
- Me? 19.
- Not true.
Will soon turn 20.
Well, there's no rush, honey.
I came to drink, yes?
You came to drink, no.
I have to rehearse early in the morning.
I have to rehearse too early.
But call me.
This is fine.
- Well...
- Well.
I must go, my husband...
Yes, I... I just get up early.
- Goodbye.
Go ahead, slowly.
Good evening, sir.
Pumpkin.
Pumpkin, what is there?
What do you smell there?
Come on.
What is it, Pumpkin?
What is it, Pumpkin? What is it?
Charles, what are you doing down there?
I could not leave.
What work, Charles? I never said it.
I am a travel agent.
You know, travel, trains, planes...
...bus, all that.
What... rare.
Yes? Why?
Do not look like a travel agent.
- No.
What look like then?
I do not know exactly travel agent but, no.
- Maybe...
- Yes?
It's more like...
...someone who travels.
Take us to Foley Square.
What are you doing?
Do not you know do not work?
It's an emergency.
Want to continue the taxi?
- Just drive, sorry.
- What taxi?
That there. I'll show you,
just drive, we go.
Sorry I'm late.
Okay, boss, Need help?
- What?
- No, thank you very much.
Hey, buddy.
Sorry...
Hello, sir, sorry to be late.
Hey guys, wait until you tell them
who just see here...
Ms. Niota.
Sorry, Ms. Niota, just come this for you.
Thank you.
Okay, it's her husband. Have a nice day.
Mom, come on foot.
- What?
- Nothing, dear.
Look, it's your father.
Return home tonight.
Really? Good.
Not so much, we're leaving tomorrow.
¿Go? I thought it would be two weeks
and spent only one.
Something must have happened.
What would you say to Georgina?
It will be so disappointed.
- And you, little boy?
- I too am disappointed.
Well, then we all are.
- Have a good day, sweetie.
- Bye, see you tonight.
Do not think about tomorrow.
Where to, lady?
No, that's all, thank you.
- There.
- Thank you.
What are you looking clown?
A vision in Stuyvesant.
They should stay here fix the place.
Are not we happy?
Did you see Arthur?
If I see him cut off the instrument.
Well, I will.
- Five minutes angel.
- Insurance.
Five minutes.
Angela.
It makes no sense, Johnny, not after
the last four days.
- It does not.
- Where the hell is Amy?
- Where is Leon?
- In here.
- Leon?
- Here, for the love of God.
Charles was trying to communicate you.
Ms. Martin seems to have Mr. Martin left.
He left a note.
- Where did it go?
- It was my fervent hope...
...you to have the answer, Charles.
After all, Mr. Martin we
pays for that very answer.
What do you mean with where he went?
Have not you followed this morning?
- Is your day off?
- I lost it, Leon.
What wonderful news.
Around City Hall. They just disappeared.
- I searched and searched.
- Who disappeared?
Joseph and her. They had luggage.
- Who is Joseph? Does the boyfriend?
- Well...
I guess you could say that.
Do you suppose you could say that?
Charles, you talk nonsense.
I want you to find out where woman...
...and I want to do it soon.
Because if we do not find,
will be difficult for Mr. Martin...
...justify pay us.
It was a wonderful morning so far.
Niota The case is over.
No I told you.
- No.
- Come, gentlemen.
Martin Hall to the girl.
What are you waiting for?
Arthur, look for us new secretary.
Amy left us.
Niota What about?
I thought it was two weeks.
You must return to London for business.
I do not know. Arrive at midnight.
All will go tomorrow.
- John, I'm mortified.
- She'll come back, Leon.
- You think so?
- Insurance.
I guess... you have guessed...
From the beginning.
- When?
- For the past three years.
Have you heard for three years
and never tell me?
- Yes, indeed.
- God.
Everyone knows it.
I do not know what to do.
Who knows?
- Good morning everyone.
- Wait.
- Christy, why are you here?
- I hope you all come...
...the new show tonight.
And what they think of these leaflets?
Are not they beautiful?
The album works so well...
...are beginning to invest money.
The magazine 'People' want an interview.
The mention as good in bed, honey,
But detectives are terrible.
They could not keep an elephant
on Fifth Avenue.
The girls were drained
between your fingers like sand.
Christy, what are you talking?
- Do you know where are they?
- Charles, what are you talking about?
What do you mean with 'what I mean?'.
How we could not continue
an elephant on Fifth Avenue?
Gosh, you're very nervous this morning.
Did you have a bad day in court?
Did you hear that? Know where they are.
- Where is Christy?
- Today you do not shave, Charles.
- Do you let your beard?
- Johnny, can you help us?
What they all talk?
What has she to do with this?
Are you kidding? Christy Miller knows all
what everyone in the city.
- You probably know where is Amy.
- Yes.
- See?
- What?
- It's in the toilet.
- Agreed.
Barbara Jo is dumb.
As Sylvia and Tulips.
- As Christy.
- Nobody knows anything.
- The girls agreed?
- What do you think?
- Come on, baby, give conditions.
- Wait a minute.
What does the toilet?
Go detectives.
Well, look who's here. Hi, Amy.
Hello, Christy.
Leon, say hello to Amy.
- Hi, Amy.
- Hey, Leon.
Well, folks, I gotta go. See you later.
- I'll walk down, John.
- Christy, you can not go well.
- Wait a minute?
- We miss you.
Thank you.
Is Ms. Leondopolous.
Can not say I'm here?
Tell him.
Hello, I'm not here. I have long
delay. I'll call you later.
Done.
Big deal.
Amy, I love you.
So why do not you kiss me?
¿Kiss you? There would... I did not think.
- That kiss would be appropriate, I mean...
- Will you shut up?
Christy, this is not very funny.
- Arthur, tell him not funny.
- It's not funny.
Have to wait for tonight affection.
Only nine hours. Honestly, Charles.
- I wonder who they are talking.
- I tell you.
- Will you come tonight, Johnny?
- I'll try, girl.
- I know what that means.
- Look, Christy.
This is my job, right? It has nothing
to do with my personal interests.
Well, Charles, forgive me if I laugh.
Goodbye.
- Christy.
- Best.
- What?
- The follow.
Clever, huh?
Yes, yes.
- Look what I found.
- How are you, Sam?
- I can not complain, boss.
- Johnny.
- Another cab driver?
- Singer.
- Sorry to bother you. Hello, girls.
- Hello.
They told me the deal and business need.
- What I can do?
- I have one.
You're the singer, it's your show, right?
- Hi, Angela.
- Hi, Angela, I'm Christy.
Christy Miller Are You? Really?
There is some doubt about it, honey,
but thanks.
I love your album.
- Thanks, honey.
- Mr. Russo can enter your club?
- Perhaps you could take me tonight.
- If you can get in?
I drive.
- Can you take, darling?
- Come on.
So long, boss. Take care of yourself.
Also, Sam.
- Thank you for smoking.
- Thanks for the fire.
I'll see tonight, but if they can
come, come whenever they want.
Goodbye, Johnny. Beware it, Angela.
It's slippery as fish.
Is it slippery as fish, Mr. Russo?
I do not know, but I'm dizzy.
I must say that you
very good taste in women.
Which is more than can be said
about my taste in men.
Where does that leave me?
Hanging miserably I hope.
Come on, show me the town.
Tell me your funny stories.
And take me back to your loft and Sedúceme.
You talk too much, you know?
I know.
I can not believe you manage a taxi.
You have to be an actress,
model or something.
- You are beautiful.
- Thanks.
Used to model, but is a nuisance.
- You know...
- Everything is a hassle, honey,
- Unless you're in love.
- And that is a nuisance.
- The greatest.
- Yes.
- Where can I get that?
- I would love, love.
Boy, I love it. I could show you...
Yes, here they come.
- What did I say?
- Wait.
Do not go anywhere.
Stay there. Stay right there.
Where the hell believes that going?
Passing an intersection and...
Hello, Mr. Russo.
What fun now?
I never had a girl call me
sir at this particular time.
I have no time to call me 'Girl'.
Neither had I felt like one.
Well, I feel like one to me.
Could you say how long since...?
Did you feel like a girl?
- You get used to everything.
- Can you?
You know what makes me follow?
- I could guess.
- Yes?
Some think that whatever they do,
someone else should be doing well.
Where did you go recently?
Everywhere.
Greene Street.
Got a cigarette?
Nothing more, right?
Makes sense.
What do you think I am a rat?
So do an exchange.
News Johnny news for Charles.
Look at the poor devil.
You've smoked two bundles today.
What do you do, kill him?
Personally, I also came
late for an appointment.
Collect the son of Angela.
Forget the deal.
I guess I have not heard to exchange.
What will you do later?
- Sleep.
- Do you want company?
- Welcome to the floor.
- I accept it.
You've got three girls there, curls.
What will you do with them?
Do you have a large floor?
It is a pleasure to meet you, Sam.
Similarly, doll.
Thank you.
Come on. One, two, three, four.
Dolores, will you marry me?
Well, I will.
Will you?
Well, yes, after my divorce.
Well, okay.
I can wait.
Hey, folks, is my fiance.
Is not it beautiful?
Goodbye.
- I'm watching, curls.
- I know it is, Sam.
- Are not you late?
- Yes, why do not you take me?
I thought about that.
That's where I go pumpkin.
I regret that we did not see Christy's show.
Maybe we can tomorrow.
Yes, tomorrow. Sure.
Goodbye, Arthur.
- Thanks.
- Why?
So long, Mike. See you soon.
- Maybe next year.
- Yes.
Michael said you were...
Yes, but I knew it.
I guess everyone knows it.
What do you know?
I knew this was too good to last.
See you, Angela. I meet with John.
Michael, take care of your mother.
How is John? Where is it?
Remains concealed.
Goodbye.
Are you crying, Mom?
No, honey, I got the wind
an object in the eye.
- How are the sisters?
- His parents were good tonight.
I think Georgina is in love me.
Do you?
I do not know. I love her, clear, but...
I do not know if I'm in love with her.
We write.
- Good.
- And we'll see how it goes.
- No commitment, huh?
- It's better that way, huh, Mom?
Much better, dear.
Listen to Benny Goodman.
It's a beautiful Saturday morning...
- Well, six, beware the change.
- Thank you.
Look who came.
Angela, do you remember Leonida?
Yeah, how are you?
Well, thank you.
It's good to see you again.
Alike.
This is the partner of Leonida, Angela,
Mr. Russo.
How are you, Mr. Russo?
How are you, Mrs. Niota?
I talk to Leonida a moment.
Do we apologize, please?
I hope that the case to work, John.
Thanks, Mike. Are you a good double agent.
Well, I'll watch the action.
Expect much to come.
I expected much not to.
Yes, me too.
We had a promise fired on, Mr. Russo.
Yes, yes, we had it.
All right. Now we're even.
I broke the biggest.
So do I.
You broke all his promises, Mr. Russo.
Leave without us.
Goodbye. I'm looking
forward to seeing you again.
Me too.
- Bye, Angela. Good flight.
- Bye, Leon, thank you.
- Good.
- Goodbye, Mr. Russo.
John.
- Michael?
- Yes.
- Come quickly, we must go.
- Coming.
- Goodbye, Michael.
- Goodbye.
No need you tomorrow, John, if you feel...
What do I walk? Yes.
Goodbye, friend.
Hello, boss. Are you going to where I am?
What did you have in mind?
Go to Brooklyn cause problems.
Sounds good.
What are you doing here anyway?
Women.
I thought you might need look after you.
Have chips, eh, Johnny?
A few, Sam.
Well cheer up, boss.
We're going to get drunk.