May I help you?
A friend of ours would like
to speak to you this evening.
I just shine shoes.
There'll be shoes there.
Two weeks ago, a man named Aaronberg
was shot to death...
the corner of Racine and Belden.
This is public knowledge.
Two people saw the crime,
and this was also in the papers.
This is public knowledge.
What I am going to tell you now
is not public knowledge.
Do you understand?
Good. The act was committed
by a person unknown...
a man in a gray overcoat.
Unfortunately, a friend of ours
has been mistakenly identified...
as the man who did the murder.
Show him the picture.
This is the man who has been
mistakenly accused.
Do you understand?
To prevent a grave injustice
from being done...
to protect an innocent man...
someone must confess
to the crime...
someone who looks like...
This person would plead guilty
to murder...
and would unfortunately spend a term
of three to five years in prison.
To such a person,
we are prepared to pay...
this amount of money
per year...
for each year he spent
in prison.
You could say
you were in prison now.
You must have a dream.
Do you have a dream?
What is that dream?
A boat.
A fishing boat.
Your dream is a fishing boat?
In Sicily.
In three years...
you could have that fishing boat.
You could earn yourself
that boat.
If you stay in your shoe store...
what will you have in three years?
What will you have in three years?
What do you have now?
Will you do it for me?
You've just made a grave mistake.
All right.
Shine 'em up, Joe.
Get me Marty in Detroit. Tell him
I want to see him as soon as possible.
- And get me whats-his-name downtown.
- Yes, sir.
Watch out for the socks.
These are cashmere socks.
Yes.
Mr. Silver, get me downtown...
and tell them I need a guy
for that project...
we were discussing.
- He'll know what I mean.
- Yes, sir.
Come on, boy.
We want to get you back
to your shoe shine stand.
Yes, this is Mr. Silver
in Chicago.
That's right.
No, I have the number on his boat,
but I was told I could find him here.
I'll hold.
A man comes into my house,
what does he want?
I tell him, "Whatever you want."
A fellow's dying.
Fifty bucks a week, says,
"Buy me a boat."
Fine.
I'll buy him a pushcart.
Buy him an organ with a monkey,
and he can put a bandana on his head.
Son of a bitch immigrant said
he wanted a boat. I'll give him a boat.
I do it.
Just a minute.
It won't be necessary.
Thank you.
This is a Sicilian coin.
- The Sicilian people say...
- Mr. Green.
- "A big man..."
- Excuse me.
"A big man knows the value
of a small coin."
My friendship is a small coin...
but it is all I have
to offer you.
Thank you.
The papers, please.
Sign here.
This is your confession.
Good. And now...
We need your fingerprints.
Pick up the gun and close it.
To my new friend.
- You done good on that thing.
- Thanks, Frank.
Marcotti. What, are you
gettin' ambitious?
- Just doin' a job.
- Willie.
- Thanks, Frank.
- Guys.
Thank you.
Jerry, we got a...
What is this?
Jerry somethin'-or-other works here?
I thought we sent him to the farm team.
- Why's that, Frank?
- Seems he can't follow orders.
Can't follow orders?
Is the guy a team player or what?
- No, it would seem not.
- That's a shame, Frank.
- Yes, I agree.
- No pain, no pals, no prospects.
- What kind of guy is that?
- A word to the wise is sufficient.
What's happening on the South Side.
Lead off with the shipping thing.
Here are the figures
on the shipping.
Glad to hear from you too, Jerry.
Maybe when you get off probation...
Do you think
you can get this clean?
What does a guy get
who can't toe the line?
- Probation.
- Right.
Frankie.
- What's up?
- I have a little errand for you.
I want you to get the right guy
for this and take care of it for me.
Hey, Cinderella.
Come here.
I want you to get me in the area.
Jerry's gonna handle it.
He's a very good man.
- What did you tell him?
- To stick to this guy the whole weekend.
- He won't let him out of his sight.
- Don't screw this up.
He's good.
He'll handle it.
Mr. Green?
All right.
Listen and learn something.
- Now you do this one right.
- I'm doin' it right.
I'm gettin' off probation.
Just do this,
and then we'll see.
Why did you kill him?
He was a no-good son of a bitch.
And?
- He...
- You owed him money.
Yeah, yeah.
Owe him some money.
- How much did you owe him?
- Fifteen hundred dollars.
That's right.
What did you do with the money?
I lose it at the racetrack.
What time was it you killed him?
Hold it. You know that one.
How many times did you shoot him?
Three times.
Don't get it too pat.
Three or four.
I shoot him three or four times.
Son of a bitch.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You're a natural.
You got the thing cold.
We're not gonna do no more?
No, you know it.
You know it.
Hey, this is ridiculous.
You're goin' to jail for three years.
What do you want to do?
We'll do something, huh?
What?
What do you...
Want to get a couple of broads?
- Do you want to see a show?
- No.
Hey, I'll get you tickets
to something.
They're telling me
I should not leave this room.
They?
There is no "they."
I am "they."
What do you want to do?
Can we...
Can we take a walk
down by the beach?
It'd be okay?
Okay?
I'll show you what's okay.
Have a nice day.
Take care, now.
- You like to travel?
- Sure.
- Okay, good.
- I like.
Good.
Glad to hear it.
Here to make you happy.
Anything to please.
That's me.
Two days, understand?
A little fun, a little memory,
then back to Chicago.
Back to Chicago. I shoot
the son of a bitch in the heart.
When I say it, out here,
do it.
- You the boss.
- I am the boss.
You keep that clear,
we're gonna get on fine.
Hey, how you doin'?
What are you doin' here?
How are you? I'm doin' fine.
How should I be doin'?
You know. Heard you mucked up
back there last month.
- What does that mean?
- Heard they slapped your wrists.
- What wrists?
- Heard you had to stay after school.
Couldn't obey orders.
Stay after school?
Are you joking me? Does this look
like staying after school?
Who is he?
If you don't know,
then maybe you shouldn't know.
- Are you staying at the hotel?
- Yeah, we're staying at the hotel.
- Someone picking you up?
- I think they're sending someone down...
Get in the car.
Hey, you know, I heard you got
in some deep powder back there.
I heard they put you on probation.
You can't believe
everything you hear.
Sometimes they put out
a story, you know.
And so you're...
What, so you're...
What I am is what you see.
And so your guy,
he's big back there.
Babe, this is the guy...
behind the guy behind the guy.
But what I got to tell you is...
I cannot talk about it.
- I understand.
- He wants to have a quiet weekend.
- But of this, bit of that. No fuss.
- Billy. Thanks, pal.
- I'll walk you in.
- Thanks, pal. I'll take it from here.
- No problem.
Hey.
Right this way.
I'm trying to keep a low profile
here, you understand?
- We like to go in quiet.
- Could we get some attention here?
May I help you?
Yes. I'll have to get
right back to you.
Good morning, gentlemen.
How good to have you with us.
Shall we go up to the room?
We're going upstairs.
We'll be going to the Criterion Floor.
Welcome to the Galaxy, gentlemen.
- Tell them our guests are coming.
- Yes, sir.
Anything you might need in Lake Tahoe,
sir, I'd be honored if you'd ask for me.
Billy Drake.
- Who is he?
- From Chicago.
Yes, sir.
I understand.
Absolutely.
Yes, sir.
I understand completely.
Ah, here they are now.
Hi.
Welcome to
the Criterion Floor, Mr...
Johnson.
Look, it's a good idea...
It's very important that nobody know
that Mr. Johnson is here.
I understand. I am your butler.
My name is Randy.
And I'll be at your disposal
24 hours a day.
See to the bedrooms, if you would.
And turn on the music, please.
Any help with travel arrangements,
special dietary preparation...
cleaning, mending,
shoe shine, shopping...
or any other aid that you require,
don't hesitate to ring.
The manager has informed me
that all the staff have been advised...
that any wish expressed by you
or Mr. Johnson...
No, no, no. Nobody is to know
that Mr. Johnson is here.
Believe me, I understand.
Your privacy will be respected.
We're here for two days' quiet.
A little low-profile relaxation.
I completely understand.
We at the Galaxy understand
and appreciate your position.
Believe me.
The Criterion Floor in concept
and execution exists only...
to cater to your special needs.
Secretarial or legal services.
I am a notary, should you require it.
Where are the bags?
We lost our bags
on a connection.
Our stores and shops are yours.
Whatever you require...
go down or ring
and they'll have it sent up.
- That's very kind of you, but...
- Credit in the casino.
Whatever you require
in financial services.
We have a 24-hour access
to a ticker tape of the major markets.
Allow me.
Tickets to the show, Jackie Shore,
tonight in the Constellation Room...
or tickets for
any other show in town.
The sights and sounds of Lake Tahoe.
And here's my card. I'm at that number
or they'll beep me there...
at any time, any time at all.
Oh, Mr. Johnson,
any questions about the room?
I believe we have anticipated
your tobacco requirements...
but if there's anything we've left out,
don't hesitate to let me know.
It is a pleasure and an honor
having you as a guest of the Galaxy...
and of the Criterion Floor.
My name is Randy, and whatever I can do
to make your stay more enjoyable...
it will be my honor
and pleasure to serve you.
The concierge desk and our kitchen
are at your disposal...
and should you wish to shop,
our shops and stores...
are open to you on a private basis
24 hours a day.
And whatever services you should desire,
there is, of course, no bill.
Your money's no good in this hotel.
Mr. Johnson...
you have beautiful hands.
Yes, and a lovely treatment
of the hands, if I may say so, sir.
An excellent choice.
Clean without being austere.
Mr. Johnson, it's been a pleasure.
It's always a pleasure to clothe
a man of your physique.
You honor it, sir,
with your custom.
Yes, yes, yes.
Okay.
Wanna pass, huh?
Clothes don't make the man.
I make the man.
You understand me?
Just because we got new clothes...
- Something to drink, gentlemen?
- Scotch, please.
Nothing for me.
I'm here to gamble.
Here we go.
Give me 5 on the 9, 5 on the 19,
and 5 for you, dealer.
Round and round she goes.
No more bets.
Where she stops, nobody knows.
Good luck. And the number is...
- You got to put money in it.
- Now taking reservations for the shows.
- I'll be with you in a moment.
- Give me $20.
- So we're gonna have 2 wonderful days.
- I understand.
- We aren't gonna go crazy.
- Two days, we go back to Chicago.
- That's absolutely right.
- 10:00 Monday morning...
28th district,
I wear the gray overcoat.
I see the son of a bitch
and three shots in the heart.
So how do you feel?
Tight but aggressive?
- Okay.
- May I help you, gentlemen?
Yeah. Give me $20.
- Everything all right, gentlemen?
- No, we're just, uh...
Whatever credit these gentlemen require,
there's no limit.
- And I mean no limit.
- Twenty dollars.
Yeah.
No, no, I think...
I'm making a joke here.
Just give me a thousand.
Give me a thousand bucks.
Tab it.
Would you like a table for the late
show, Jackie Shore, Constellation Room?
- In the back.
- One thousand dollars.
- Thanks.
- Mr. Shipp, may I have a moment?
Excuse me.
If you got the name,
go get the game.
Let's gamble.
Okay.
No, hey, this is for show.
Play what you got
in your pockets.
And if there's anything at all
that I can do for you...
- Thanks.
- I'll tell you, Jerry...
I never win nothing.
- Maybe we can fix that.
- Jerry.
Not even you can fix
something like this.
- Not even me, huh?
- Not even you.
Not even someone like me?
Put it in.
Hey, wait a second!
There is something
you could do for me.
I'd like to give Mr. Johnson
a little treat.
- Absolutely, sir.
- Could we arrange for him...
as a lark,
to win a little, you know?
- To win?
- Just a little.
- To win at the casino.
- Just a little... $50, $100.
As a thrill, you know?
Can you do that?
- Well...
- Whatever it is, I'll make it up.
- You're saying you'll pay it back?
- That's what I'm saying.
Broke so soon?
The slots are cold.
Let's try something else.
Twelve.
- This table open?
- Yes, sir, it is.
Okay. You got black, you got red,
you got numbers.
- What do you want to bet?
- I'll take black.
Take a number. Pick a number.
You pick a number, it hits,
it pays 35 to 1.
Put five bucks on a number.
- We're partners.
- No, it's yours.
We're partners.
Whatever happens, we're 50/50, okay?
- Yeah, okay.
- Okay.
You know what number
I always play?
My flight number.
What flight did we come in on?
- Twelve, wasn't it?
- Yeah, yeah.
I think you're right.
I think it was number 12.
- I got to talk to you.
- Not now.
Twelve.
The number is twelve.
- I win.
- Yes, sir.
Did you see what my friend did?
Bravo, Mr. Johnson. Good play.
We got to lose the lighting guy.
He's napping up there.
I'm not saying it's hurting
the show. It's not.
Have you seen the show?
- Have you seen the show, Mr...
- And here's your winnings, sir.
- Have you seen the show?
- No, I can't say that I have.
What do you mean, you haven't seen it?
How long have you been here?
Place your bets.
One thousand dollars
on number 12.
- There's a bit I do, working the crowd.
- This is not the time, Jackie.
I want to make a point here.
You've got a beautiful, fine show...
well thought-out,
but if you don't have the support...
- This is my theme: Support.
- Twelve again.
I win again!
Yes, sir, you did.
How much we win?
Thirty-five thousand dollars.
We fly number 12,
we play number 12.
That's a lot of money.
What number do you want
to play now?
That's enough.
Come on.
I'll buy you a car.
- Sir...
- Yeah, hold on a second.
- What's happening?
- That guy just won a couple bucks.
Hey, what we do with this money?
Gino, we got to give it back.
Why?
I win this.
Yeah, but...
- I win this money.
- Yeah, but listen, listen.
It's a thing of hospitality.
We're...
We're guests in their hotel.
Sure, we could take the money.
It's not a question of the money.
It's just for the sake of...
honor.
To be an honorable guest.
It's not the money?
It's honor?
Would you move back, please?
- What happened?
- That guy just won 35 grand.
Excuse me, sir.
I have to talk to you.
- In a minute.
- I have to talk to you.
How this game work?
Well, we pay a hundred to one.
What that means is, if you bet a dollar
and your number wins...
you win $100.
- How much I can bet?
- Just as advertised, sir...
the Wheel of Fortune,
the pride of the Galaxy...
never refused a bet
of any size.
If I bet $35,000, how much I win?
If you bet $35,000...
you'd win $3,500,000.
I bet $35,000.
Put on number 12.
Thirty-five thousand dollars
on number 12.
Do me a favor, honey.
Put $1,000 on number 12.
A hundred on 1, a hundred on 2,
500 on 12 and a hundred on 21.
- Lord hates a coward.
- Bet for me.
- Five hundred on twelve.
- Twenty on 12.
- Another 50.
- Thank you, and bets are closed.
- One dollar on 12.
- All right. Thank you.
And bets are closed.
And round and round she goes.
Where she stops, nobody knows.
Good luck to you all.
- Please, please.
- Come on, baby. Come home to Papa.
One time, baby. This is it.
Come to Papa, baby. Come on.
And the number is...
seventy-four.
The number is 74.
I'm sorry.
No winners on 74.
No winners.
Hell of a bet, son.
I'm sorry you lost
all that money, sir.
Things change.
Your drink, sir.
Thank you.
I'll tell you what's crazy, folks.
The longer I'm married...
the more I'm losing
my single instincts.
I was at a party in Hollywood...
big show business party...
beautiful blonde starlet
comes up to me.
She says, " My husband's away
for the weekend. How about a lift home?"
I said, "If you knew he would be away,
you should've made travel arrangements."
I have a theory criminals want
to get caught.
The Reporter said 18 of the 20
suspects arrested are known...
to have organized crime ties.
If they don't want to get caught, don't
wear the ties. See what I'm saying?
- How's your drink?
- Good. Good.
You handled yourself
very graciously back there.
When you are in Rome,
you do like the Romans do.
I saw a guy today down at the tables.
Shoots 35 grand in one roll,
craps out. He says, "Things change."
And one thing that does not change,
ladies and gentlemen, is friendship.
And I want to say hi to a good friend
of ours from Chicago, Mr. Johnson.
Would you please stand up, Mr. Johnson?
Ladies and gentlemen, let him know.
Mr. Johnson?
Come on, folks. Give it up.
Give it up!
Mr. Johnson. Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. Johnson from Chicago.
Give it up one time
for Mr. Johnson.
Folks, take it from a man who knows,
there is nothing like friendship.
'Cause if there was,
somebody would have invented it already.
- Check five and thirteen, please.
- One minute to curtain.
- Hey, have you got a minute?
- Stop me if you got a problem.
Why am I getting this again?
I walked out of my light.
- What is your guy doing up there?
- I can't talk about this now.
Your lighting guy,
what is this, your wife's cousin?
Now it's Jackie. Great.
What?
Did I do something to you
in a previous life? What is this?
- Roger, microphone check.
- Hey, Mr. Johnson!
- Mr. Johnson, what a nice surprise.
- Yeah, very surprised.
I hope you guys enjoyed the show,
and good of you to play along.
Really very supportive, and I
appreciate that. You looked great.
I thought I told you I didn't want any
publicity. We don't want any notice.
Thirty seconds to curtain, please.
Hey, guys, look, if I jumped wrong...
if you don't want any notice.
Yeah, bear with me here.
- On your cue, go black.
- On stage, please.
Maybe a little notice.
Cherry, Grace!
- This is curtain, ladies and gentlemen.
- I'd like you to meet Mr. Johnson.
- And now...
- Let's go, girls.
The one, the only, the greatest revue
in the great state of Nevada...
ladies and gentlemen, the Galaxy Hotel
is proud to present...
the Fertile Crescent.
Do you mind if we come in?
I always wondered
where I was meant to be.
It's good to work, Jerry,
but it is also good to play.
"The Ant and the Grasshopper."
Once upon a time, there was
an ant and a grasshopper.
All summer long,
the ant worked hard.
The grasshopper,
he played the violin.
He dance.
Winter come.
The ant grow fat.
The grasshopper is cold.
The grasshopper
eat the ant.
Return to me.
My darling, I adore you.
Only you...
in my heart.
You guys like the water?
What do you have in mind?
We have a little cabin,
up on Falling Leaf...
and we're going fishing
for a few days.
Would you...
We wanted to know if you want
to come there and go fishing with us?
Really, fishing.
For fish.
Tomorrow, when we get off.
- We have to be back in Chicago.
- Well, you know, anytime.
- Anytime you come in.
- Anytime you're in Tahoe.
Anytime. Six months, a year.
Well, actually, it might be
a lot longer than that.
We're gonna be gone
for quite a while...
dear girls.
Good morning, good morning,
good morning.
Where is everybody?
- Good morning.
Would you be so kind
as to send up some coffee.
- Right away. Coffee.
- Lovely. Thank you very much.
Not at all.
Gino, wake up
and smell the coffee.
This is the kind of day.
Listen and learn something.
- You rub too hard, then...
- You take off the polish.
So, the trick is...
Not too hard and not too soft.
And you can't make
the shoes shine unless...
They're clean.
If everyone knew everything,
there wouldn't be no schools, eh?
- Yes.
- Shine shoes like anything else.
It seems so simple now.
- Eh, yes and no.
- I'm really sorry, Mr. Johnson.
Don't you be sorry.
Live and learn.
Where have you been?
I put my shoes outside,
they come back dull.
You're gonna come back dull.
I told you, don't go anywhere.
Anywhere. Do you hear me?
Anywhere without me.
We're gonna go back today.
- I just go down the hall.
- We're going back to Chicago today.
- Why?
- You can't obey orders.
Get your stuff. We're outta here.
We're going back to Chicago.
- I can't go back.
- Who the hell do you think you are?
I stepped out of channels.
I put myself out for you.
What did you do for me?
What did I say?
Stick by my side.
One thing, and you couldn't do it.
I was your friend,
but you weren't my friend.
The hell with you. Go back to Sicily.
Go back to prison.
- We're going to Chicago.
- I can't go back to Chicago.
- Why can't you go back to Chicago?
- I no gotta my shoes.
Thank you.
Catch me ever doing another favor.
- You mad at me.
- Mad at you? Yeah.
If I come back without you,
they'd kill me. Think that's a joke?
I no gotta answer.
I give my word.
Can we get some coffee in here?
I'm on the corner, 4:00 p.m.
He's driving big black car, Lincoln.
He come on the street.
I'm on the street,
I shoot the son of a bitch.
Fine.
Yeah. What do you want
to do today?
We go see those nice girls, eh?
Yeah, don't take that "we go fishing"
line too seriously, okay?
Everything's for sale
in this town.
Everybody loves ya
when you got the dough.
No. They like us.
Yeah, they liked us real good. Everybody
likes you when you're someone else.
Hey, we got one day left.
We got one day worth of a good time,
then we go home.
Come in.
I'll get dressed.
Let's get outta here,
and you stick by my side.
Uh, Jer, there're two friends
of ours, Kenny and Harry...
they wanted to know if perhaps
they could take just a little bit of...
Thank you, Billy.
Mr. Johnson.
Joseph Vincent sends you greetings
and welcome to Lake Tahoe.
He extends to you this invitation:
To be his guest at his estate
for luncheon today...
if this is convenient
within your plans.
Well, you know,
we have a lot of...
If this would be convenient, 1:00 p.m.,
we'll pick you up downstairs.
We'll be waiting in the lobby.
We're in some very deep shit.
Okay, now,
look, look, look.
Whatever he asks you, say...
no.
Whatever he...
You're on vacation.
You don't... You're on...
You don't wanna talk no business.
You don't wanna hear no...
So when we get there,
like, if he asks who you are...
just let me handle it.
Whatever it is, I'll...
Approved list, the vehicles.
I'm on top of it.
You got a load
of vegetables, 4:00.
- From where?
- Reno.
Stop 'em at the gate
and call me.
- Eggs.
- Anna?
Put it in the pantry.
Hey, I need to see
about the Chevy.
A dealer from the state line.
This is the swing-shift broad?
She used to date with this
whatchamacallit, the big guy.
- Who's this?
- You know, the big guy.
Oh, right, right. So?
Now she's torn between two guys.
- And she's hiding the sausage with both?
- She's the one.
- And she's the one that stabbed him?
- The same one.
She knocked the other guy's teeth out,
she stabbed him...
and she also knocked
the other guy's teeth out.
- I can't believe this.
- It's true. He had caps.
Hey, Jerry, what's a good price
for a '56 Chevy?
Yeah.
It's good to know one's family.
A good man...
A good man takes pride in knowing
those who are connected to him.
Would you agree?
I got a big family.
And no matter how big that family is,
still we remember all of their names.
From the little one.
So tell me some names.
Names of my family?
Is Bruno Gaddo...
and little Bruno Gaddo.
I don't know them.
See what I mean?
What brings you here?
- I no here for talk business.
- We'll talk business later.
But now I must know.
What brings you to this occasion?
What a lovely old coin. Is there
anything you can tell me about it?
A big man, he know the value
of a small coin.
It's always good to make
a new friend.
I haven't heard that
in 35 years.
That's a beautiful boat...
and you got beautiful shoes.
Even the best shoes wear out.
No, you take care...
they last a long time.
You watch close.
You look for the crack.
And then?
Then you look more close.
Show me your boat.
Best part of the day, isn't it?
- You tired, Don Giuseppe?
- You know how it becomes...
the pressures.
Gino, stay with me tonight.
Will you stay?
You give me your home.
What I can give to you?
This is not an old coin.
It's a new coin.
But it, too, is a symbol...
and should you ever need
my friendship...
you take this coin...
you put it into a telephone...
and you call this number.
Whatever you may wish...
if it is within the power
of your friend...
that wish will be granted.
Gino, you got grass stains
on your pants.
Your mama gonna kill you.
Have Mr. Johnson's things cleaned,
brought to his room.
We'll talk tonight, after dinner.
Mr. Johnson is staying
with us tonight.
As much as we'd like to accept
your hospitality...
I put him on probation.
We're having some people tonight.
Perhaps you know some of them.
We'll have some dinner.
We'll talk about shoes.
Tomorrow we go fishing.
Whatever you need,
you talk to my people.
Whatever Mr. Johnson requires,
see that he has it.
Otherwise,
see that he is not disturbed.
We're going out tomorrow.
We'll take the boat out.
I'll show you some fighting fish.
You like northern pike, Gino?
First, we're gonna catch 'em,
then we're gonna cook 'em.
Come on, we're goin' over
to the hotel.
So...
how big is your guy?
I mean, I never seen the Don pal up that
close with someone like that before.
Unless it's something
I shouldn't know.
What are they,
friends from the old country?
And how are you
and Mr. Johnson today, sir?
You know, we don't gotta do this.
Come on, we'll get a cup of coffee.
- Somebody check out Mr. Johnson.
- Check out Mr. Johnson.
Front, check out Mr. Johnson.
Let's show some service here, can we?
What are you doin'?
What the hell are you doin'?
I told you no,
we wanna keep a low profile.
What are you crawlin' all over us
the whole time?
You don't know who... What? Mr. Johnson?
You don't know Mr. Johnson.
You what? Do you know
what we're doing here?
- I thought...
- What?
I thought you were here
for the meeting.
- What meeting?
- Check in, Mr. Green, from Chicago.
Mr. Green, good to have you with us
again. Welcome back to the Galaxy.
What time are we due
atJoe Vincent's house?
8:00. You just have time
to change.
- Did you bring the present?
- Yeah.
We'll be back from the meeting
by 10:00 and get some sleep.
You look lovely.
Check us in.
I'll be at the tables.
Mr. Green's party is here.
- Do you have the two cars?
- Yes, sir.
Have you arranged for
a line of credit in the casino?
- Yes, sir.
- I don't want him showing I.D.
- Good.
Oh, heck.
1968396 Chevelle,
sort of a light green.
It's my brother's car.
Oh, it was a cherry car.
Had a four-barrel on this sucker.
It was the size of a basketball.
You'd punch it down,
and you'd see the hood cave in.
We used to get tanked up,
go to Ridgely, West Virginia.
This place called the Hog Trough.
Sorry I'm late. Got a couple things
I want to go over with you guys.
Number one is the cutoff time,
which is 8:15...
after which point,
nobody gets in.
They're at the gate after 8:15,
they're an Indian.
The second thing is, nobody is anyone
unless I introduce you to 'em.
Listen closely to me now.
Better you should have to apologize to
someone what you said to him than, huh?
You know what I'm talking about.
Like that time with the guy at the lake.
- Come on.
- What? What for?
- We're going home.
- We don't gotta go until tomorrow.
We're cutting short our trip. We got
45 minutes to make our plane to Chicago.
- We gonna stay here one more day.
- Forget it.
If the guy is wrong, what do you do?
You send him scuba divin'.
That's what you do.
Now go solve my problem for me.
The rest of you guys,
come with me.
Oh, Lord, are we in trouble.
Get dressed. Come on.
- What?
- I forget my lucky quarter.
Are you nuts? Come on.
- How was the weather in Chicago?
- Sleet, rain.
Nothing changes.
- Smooth flight?
- Excellent flight, thanks. No problems.
- Hotel treating you well?
- Just fine. How you feeling?
Oh, fine. Never better. You'll find
the food here better than the hotel.
- That's what I expected.
- Of course, Max...
the same could probably be said
of your place in Chicago.
And you don't have to bring
your lunch next time.
And now, I want you to meet
my companion, Miss Bates.
Miss Bates,
you're an adornment to my home.
I have another one. Token of respect
from your friends in Chicago.
- A set of dueling pistols.
- Thank you. This is a magnificent gift.
- 1827?
- If you say so.
Joe, though we are involved in business,
we in the midwest...
are never unmindful that our business
is fathered on friendship...
and we are honored to be invited
to the home of such a friend.
May peace and prosperity
grace your door forever.
Thank you, Max.
Thank you very much.
- Mr. Silver.
- Thank you for inviting me.
It's my pleasure.
Please treat my house as your own.
Tonight, there's somebody
I want you to meet.
It's a friend of ours.
Oh, there he is now.
Seven and one-half.
You got a big head.
Max, come here.
There's something I'd like to show you.
Thanks for the gift.
Did you have a good nap?
Everybody treat you...
- Joe! Good to see ya!
- Excuse me. Willie, good of you to come.
- It's been too long.
- Yes, it has.
- I brought you a little something.
- Willie, that's magnificent.
Nothing's too good for you, Joe.
- We'll talk later.
- Mr. Bagwell.
Ken, good to see you.
I think you know
who most of these people are.
- It's a life full of business, huh?
- Don Giuseppe...
we was planning
to go fishing tomorrow.
Don Giuseppe!
Giovanni!
If I can't stay until tomorrow,
if I gotta go...
Joe Vincent.
It's an honor to be in your house.
- Howard!
- How you doing?
Fine. Listen, that's a long trip
for you to make.
No trip is too far
to pay my respects to you.
I gotta have just a minute
of your time.
- All right.
- We...
Come over here.
I got a question for you.
We'll talk later.
After they've gone, hmm?
- What is it, Max?
- Look at this. I'm ashamed of you.
- I've seen that.
- You have?
- Sure, it's my book.
- It came from your library.
Come on, come on, come on.
We're gonna walk away from here nice
and quiet, like nothing's happening.
And... Will you take off that hat.
Don't drop out on me now.
Just a nice stroll
in the evening air.
What are we gonna do?
We're gonna find ourselves a car.
We're fine.
Everything is gonna be okay.
I no get to say good-bye.
Just keep your nerve.
Don't lose your nerve
on me here.
Just a couple of mice.
Come on.
Okay.
I'm gonna hot-wire the car.
How do you hot-wire the car?
You...
You cross the...
Okay.
Now, the keystone to the security
system is the infrareds.
We have the dogs, and we have them
out on the perimeter...
but after that thing last year,
I said...
"Why keep them if you can't
believe in them?"
In a moment, I'll take you down
and show you.
And also, our feeling is...
don't show the guy what to look for.
Make them look for everything...
which, in this case, you gotta do.
Make 'em wonder about everything,
the point being...
it's not gonna be some dog barking
that he hears.
We got him on the infrareds.
The last thing he's gonna hear
is gonna be his heart exploding.
Yeah, the key to the security system
is definitely the infrareds.
Now look at this car over here.
It's a 1935 Cadillac.
They just don't make 'em
like this anymore. I swear.
Hey, what's the matter with ya?
We're going home.
I know where we're going.
- What? What?
- We're out of gas.
Guy's the head of the Vegas mob.
He can't keep gas in his car.
What the hell kind of a country
is this?
- You got any money?
- No.
- Great. Give me a dollar.
- Okay.
Man, I'm running on empty.
It's a good thing we're going home.
- We was gonna go fishing tomorrow.
- Who?
- Me and Don Giuseppe.
- You were gonna go fishing?
Don Giuseppe found out who you were,
then you were going fishing as the bait.
It's okay. We're gonna make it.
You be thankful you're alive.
Anybody talks to you on the plane,
you don't say nothin'.
You don't even speak English.
We get back to Chicago.
This never happened.
Five dollars, please.
- I just asked you for a dollar.
- Well, I'm sorry, I didn't hear.
Okay, look, it s a misunderstanding.
We got a plane to catch.
- But you owe me four bucks.
- Yeah, we're gonna send it to you.
I'd love to help you. Can't.
Look, I don't want any trouble.
Do you know who this is?
I don't know, and I don't care.
You owe me four dollars.
Look, I didn't ask for the gas,
and I don't got time for this chat, pal.
- We're sending you the money.
- No.
I think not, mister.
Why don't you just wait here
until we work this out.
- What do you think you're doing?
- I'm calling the cops.
I gotta catch a plane.
Gimme the keys.
You took the gas, you can't pay for it.
That's called theft.
Oh, hell.
Please, gimme a break.
Gimme a break.
We're gonna catch a plane.
Treat a working man like this?
You didn't work for that gas.
I worked for that gas.
- Yeah, let me speak to the sheriff.
- Look, man. Look, man, please.
We have to catch the plane.
Just give me back the key.
I'm holding for the sheriff.
Throw your ass in jail,
trying to defraud me.
What are we gonna do now?
We drive home.
Look, look, look, a plane ticket
to Chicago. I give you the ticket.
I trade you the ticket
for a full tank of gas.
You're going to give me a ticket
to Chicago for a tank of gas?
You give us a full tank of gas,
and we get out of here.
Where's my jacket?
I have no idea who some people think
they are. I swear that I don't.
- Just when things were going so well.
- Yeah, let me speak to the sheriff.
The sheriff.
This is Jack at the gas station.
I'll hold.
The car's probably stolen too.
- You want a cigarette?
- No, thank you.
Hello, Sheriff. Yeah, this is Jack,
down at the gas station.
I got a couple of fellas
down here who...
Take the money.
Hold on.
Never mind. It's all right.
We go now.
Your key.
- Come on.
- Here's your change. Thank you.
What is this place like?
You eat, you sleep,
you got a job.
You go and do your job.
You don't, you stay in your cell.
And we'll have people there for you.
Sure, there's people there.
Yeah, there's lots of people there.
I can handle this.
Don't tell me you can handle it.
You never know
till they close that door...
and then you find out.
And then I find out.
That's right.
Then I get out...
and you come and see me
in my boat.
Yeah, I'll come see you
in your boat.
Sun come up and we fish.
Sun go down, we drink.
We talk about old times.
We talk about number 12.
Yeah, okay.
It's not such a long time.
What's the big deal?
That's right.
Well?
What do you think time it is?
5:00, 5:15.
Well, we got about five hours.
What do you wanna do?
I wish you didn't have to go.
- Don't go.
- I gotta go.
You know I gotta go.
- No, you could...
- A deal, it's a deal.
The hell with the deal.
The deal is they're buying three years
of your life for pocket change.
You come out of there an old man,
a bunch of money don't mean shit.
- What "eh"?
- I got a deal.
Three years in prison.
I get out, I go back, I buy my boat.
You buy your boat.
Know what your money's gonna buy in
three years? It won't buy a toothbrush.
What do you...
Three years of your life.
You... No, this is not a deal,
it's a hustle.
They hustled you.
Three years for three days.
I give my word.
You walk. You could walk.
I go in the bathroom,
I slip in the tub.
- Jerry...
- You walk, who's gonna know?
Who's gonna know?
Who's gonna find you? No one.
Who's gonna look for you?
Go on, go on.
Go on, get outta here.
Get out of here.
Get the hell out of here.
Get outta here!
What the hell do you want?
We have a good time
in Lake Tahoe, eh?
We drink champagne
with the girls.
The guy on stage say,
"Mr. Johnson, take a bow."
They'd break their word to you.
Maybe yes and maybe no.
What they do, no matter.
I give my word.
I gonna miss you.
You stupid son of a bitch.
You gonna miss me too?
I ain't missing no dummy
don't know when to run.
- You know what I mean?
- No.
Yeah. I'll miss you
all my life.
Get outta here, you stupid lame.
Where you going?
I gonna shave.
- What?
- Can I come in?
Yeah, yeah.
- What are you doing here?
- Come to walk you guys over.
- We got till 10:00.
- They want you there at 8:00.
So what have you guys
been doing in here three days?
Playing gin.
The guy's here to take us over.
We're going over early.
Where we goin'?
I thought we'd take a walk by the lake,
give him some air in his lungs.
- You guys have a nice weekend?
- Yeah.
- Does he know his confession?
- Yeah. Frankie, what's going on?
I told you.
We're taking a walk.
Hey, we gotta get to court.
He ain't goin' to court.
He knows his stuff.
He's gonna keep his word.
Jerry, the thing was, our guy needed
two days to get out of town.
This doesn't work.
The whole thing was...
set this guy up, get his prints
on the gun, get a confession.
Later, he gets remorse,
the murder he did. He kills himself.
We stick the confession
in his pocket. Life goes on.
It's cleaner this way.
The Don said, tell him to be at
the 28th district, 10:00, Monday.
That's right. He said tell him to be at
the 28th. He didn't say take him there.
Nobody told me
this was gonna be the thing.
He had a deal.
Things change.
You son of a bitch.
What the...
Who are you, all of you?
Make a deal with the man.
You set the guy up,
promise him this, do the thing.
He does it, stands up.
- Hey, Jerry!
- Come on, come on.
You're telling me the things
you promised this guy, lied to him.
You're gonna turn around
and kill him?
I'm not gonna kill him.
You're gonna kill him.
You're gonna kill him, pal.
You wanted to square yourself,
get off probation.
What do you think the thing is,
sitting in a hotel three days...
order room service,
that's gonna get you back in?
That's not the job.
This is the job.
You come up to his head,
you shoot him right above the eye.
Put the gun in his hand,
let it fall.
You got two minutes.
Hey, man, you can't make me
do this.
Hey, I'm not making you do anything.
You turn it down, you turn it down.
You can't handle it,
I handle it.
What?
- Something happened.
- What?
We got a different situation.
I don't even know how to say it.
I see.
Didn't I tell you to run?
I told you to run.
I threw you out of the hotel,
and you came back.
I told you to go.
I told you.
- Why didn't you go?
- I gave my word.
You gave your word.
- Hey, Jerry!
- Hey, fantastic! You gave your word.
- Hey, Jerry.
- I said I'm gonna do it.
I gave my word.
Everybody gave their goddamn word.
Oh, God.
Hey, what are you gonna do?
What are you gonna do?
You gonna shoot me?
Shoot yourself, shoot yourself.
You're dead.
Great. Now I'm dead.
You're dead. We're all dead.
You got the keys to the car?
I only...
I just keep...
What? What?
I gotta make a phone call.
What phone call?
Don Giuseppe say,
"If you ever need my friendship..."
Are you nuts?
Yes, I make a collect call
to Mr. Joseph Vincent...
from Gino Gaddo in Chicago.
- Great.
- Gino Gaddo...
collect to Mr. Joseph Vincent
at this number, and thank you.
The defendant, having pled guilty
to murder in the first degree...
and in the absence
of extenuating circumstances...
we have no alternative
but to sentence the defendant...
to the maximum allowed by law.
The term of imprisonment
of 20 years to life.
Do you have anything
you want to say?
The car comes on the corner
at 4:00 p.m.
I shot the son of a bitch
three times in the heart.