Since the beginning of
and humanity throughout the history of the world
there are rituals of manhood well defined.
Such rituals were decisive
in determining the exact moment when
boy became a man.
THINK LIKE A MAN
For example, when
when a boy joins the men
in your first battle.
Knew what they were doing circumcisions public in front of the village?
Thank God mine was not public.
And the most significant moment of all,
marriage.
Yes, that's what I said.
In fact, marriage was the main goal of
boys and men.
Because in the old days
Was the only way to get a guy
what I really wanted a girl.
And these days? Wow!
Things have changed, folks.
We no longer have to fight both
get what we want.
We have the internet, my God.
I can be anything you want on the Internet.
Today, men have the advantage of home court
,
which left you with various types of men.
I mean, I do not know where to start.
Has the player.
PLAYER
Hello, Zekey.
Texted me sexy?
Not mine, idiot.
Are you sure you...
Wait, not done.
Has a mama's boy.
FlLHlNHO OF MOTHER
Happy Valentine's Day, baby.
To you too, Mom.
Thank you, dear.
You know, I think I'll leave you alone.
Wait, dear, where are you going?
All right, Michael.
I do not want to intrude.
Can I call you later?
-I think not.
Coitadinha.
She is blonde.
Is the dreamer. The dreamer is funny.
The Dreamer
I quit my job.
Yes
wanna be a chef.
I wanted to be a paramedic,
public relations agent, and now
want to be a chef?
Honey, is my dream.
Seriously, Dominic?
Because I wanted to be a dancer and Janet Jackson.
When I was seven.
You know what I want to be now?
No.
Your ex.
Last but not least,
is without compromise. Pass the ball!
The SEM COMPROMlSSO
This is mine.
Okay, honey.
-Okay! That beat the drums.
-Okay, big guy.
My God. Accepted, accepted, accepted, yes!
Accept what?
Earrings.
I Agree to these beautiful earrings.
You're the man.
I told him.
-Hey!
-You want a beer?
I'm not saying there is no
guys out there.
For example, the happily married.
The MARRIED AND FELlZ
Which brings us to my favorite, the
divorced and even happier
The DlVORClADO AND MALS FELlZ AlNDA
See that smile.
What I'm saying is that
the balance of power changed.
Zeke, there are more problems with Gail,
is the complaint, is shouting,
humor is crazy.
It will not talk to me
that way. I am an adult, man.
-Adult, man.
-You know me, Don, I grew up.
It is not the only problems he had with Gail
, right?
Hey, Zeke, do not start.
-I'm asking a question!
Ask anything you like.
Begin! Come on, jerk it out!
According to the rumors,
Gail was beating down on you.
According to what?
'' 'I think that was beating down on you.''
No,'' was'' rumors.
There were only rumors, Zeke.
Ced, you got
next day with a spot below the eye.
Falling from the ladder, Mike! Okay?
I have stairs with a slope.
Already descended the stairs with a slope of shoes?
Wait,
it hit you and then you fell down the stairs?
See, now makes sense.
It's very funny.
White solving relationship problems
-a brother.
Not-so.
Way to go.
I'll tell you, J.
Blacks protested, died
for the right to treat each other badly.
My-God.
-You did not protest,
has no such right.
Neither you Bennett.
I saw on TV.
These protests are shown in February.
Stop.
His wife beat you.
It's nothing more.
-There are worse things.
-My ex-wife, right?
All
have to get used to saying it. Ex-wife.
You know, kill me,
you laughing at my pain.
I can not wait for you to live
this drug experience.
I say  Rush Street,
first round due to Bennett.
Should dinner with Kristen today.
She will understand, it is legal.
I will send a message to her.
Welcome back, folks.
We're still here with the author of bestsellers
Steve Harvey.
What I try to make women understand
is that times have changed,
but the playbook is not.
I received thousands of letters from all types of women
can not find, keep or
get what you want from your man.
Until you understand how a man loves,
operates like a man, as he thinks,
and until we get into the mindset of a man,
will never win us the game of love
.
Well, we certainly want to win
in the game of love, Steve.
Dear  - mind if I hang out with the guys?
I take a pizza...
-Question from the audience.
-Hi, Steve.
I live with my boyfriend for five years
and he says he loves me
and is totally committed.
I think I want to know why he had not asked the question?
He
not asked the question because you did not require it.
Will return soon.
-Can you give me two beers?
-Hey!
I am Cedric. Cedric, Cedric.
I'm not married.
This is why not use alliance.
Excuse me, I am a Christian.
Yes, no, no, no, I understand.
I also love Jesus.
I spoke with him today:
'' Jesus, I need a girl!''
And I come here and see you,
then say:'' Thanks.''
You are seeing Ced
azarando that cat?
Much the same cat.
See, if you think so,
loses the game before you start.
What are you talking about?
I'm leaving.
It is crazy. I do not like her knees.
Excuse me, miss, I noticed that...
Honestly,
could not care less with what he has to say.
I appreciate that.
I only know that I saw here before
and is always so impressive...
And you'll always have those memories.
Actually, why do not you walk away and pretend that this
...
What I did to get defensive?
Whatever it is,
is not reason to be less beautiful, that's it.
Less beautiful?
I did not mean to disrespect you...
I'll tell you one thing, asshole.
Something happened to you.
Typically, there is an aura,
there is a glow about you that I'm not seeing.
I do not know if a relationship is
or if the work is, it's just...
Is this?
It's about the job?
Well, to be frank,
I was fired two months ago.
This drug economy.
-How was it?
-Not good, man.
I literally have nothing to say.
Do not know what is happening.
And my breath is sinister.
-Have a beer.
-You feel?
Can not let it steal your smile
because he,
will ensure your next job
success.
See? Now he is smiling.
Now I'm smiling.
I will go now as a fairy godmother,
because I'm happy.
-Fairy Godmother?
-Yes.
-Have a good night.
-Thank you.
Has been slaughtered.
Wait.
It is
calling back to the insult.
Take.
It probably insulted. Twice.
Crazy, huh? Dude. He talked about Jesus, and said
who speaks no English and such, right?
I was lucky.
It really gave me the phone.
The Dark Knight strikes again.
Kristen is amazing.
Legal.
It is a phenomenal girl.
I just do not understand why she's with this guy.
How is your credit?
Movers. Below 400, 430?
Caramba! 430?
Can not even have a grocery store card!
Whites  start with 500 points?
Five hundred and fifty, 475 if mulatto.
Cedric!
Yes, Gail.
Gail, hear what I'm trying to say!
I do not care!
I do not care to take the garage!
Gail, you can get everything out of the garage.
I'll tell you one thing.
I want, and that's what... Hello?
Gail?
Yes, I swear...
Do not let him finish his sentence.
Do not like it.
Hey Ced.
When it comes to divorce?
If I had to guess,
say four weeks, 367 hours,
22 minutes, 32 seconds.
It's just a guess.
: Who's counting?
You know what we do?
Let's go out to celebrate with Cedric.
I can not on Sunday.
I have dinner with my mother. She will do...
Every Sunday is like that.
I can not on Sunday.
Jonah has a violin recital.
My God, man, your child does
recitals too.
Wait a minute.
His son plays the violin?
E-cello.
Hey, he's gay.
-Play the violin does not make him gay.
It's true.
Name-a gay violinist. His son-
.
Listen. Cedric is about to
be released from the shackles of Gail-lnfernal.
Forever. And we're about to lose
? On the other recital of Jonah.
-By the way, it sucks.
-Seriously?
I expected it of them, not you.
How-so,'' them''?
-Theirs who, black or what?
Absolutely.
I'm not mad because he has the courage to speak.
Seriously, the boy has no musical ear.
This is your big solo.
Will roll the Gap Band.
Know, Dropped a Bomb on Me,
he is the last... '' Baby''!
See, I have a great idea.
My mom cooks for us.
It'll make some cookies, a delicious dish
. Let's celebrate.
Mike, I almost punched
at you now, man.
I almost took a header.
I'm not in his mother's house to celebrate my divorce
!
-We have to eat. We'll start there...
-I do not want to eat there!
I'm not in his mother's house.
She has a new film by Tyler Perry,
For Colored Girls on Blu-ray.
We will have a nice night,
a night to unwind.
I'll count ,
Janet Jackson caught the end AlDS
and crazy plays
their children out the window. Okay?
Can we celebrate now? Come on!
-I hate you.
-Okay, raise!
Yes, sir.
Okay, I'm inside.
Life is great, guys.
May it never change.
We could not know that the first bomb had fallen.
The war was declared.
And our secrets
had fallen into enemy hands.
BEHAVE YOURSELF AS A Lady THINK LIKE A MAN
We were betrayed by one of our.
A man.
I'm talking about a man with a penis.
Someone who should know how.
And because of these actions,
a war that was now under way,
affect all my little band of brothers.
We have another question
at the hearing, Steve.
Steve, I get
guys who do not want relationship.
Why not?
Did you hear that?
Men respect women of character.
Arrange some.
Exactly.
Steve, I am a member of an office
law firms, have their own house,
but I'm single for three years.
Why not find a guy
according to my standards?
You may need to adjust them a little.
-Bullshit.
Should we lower the standards?
You have an income of six figures. He must also have
?
Yes
Do you have home ownership. He must also have
?
Yes and yes.
We have another question from the audience.
Hi, Steve.
I am currently dating and I just want to know
when the time is right to present
my boyfriend to my child?
I know that single women do not want
a parade of men entering the house.
-Exactly!
-I understand that.
-But if the guy is serious...
-What, Mom?
How is it?
-... Bring it soon.
Good morning, mother.
Why invest in a man six months
and then present it to children
and he do not like their children or vice versa
,
then guess what?
You wasted six months.
That's true. I did it.
Alex?
Alex!
Wake up!
See, honey, brought two coffees with milk
double.
Thank you, dear. Take-
.
We need a little caffeine
after last night.
It was wonderful.
I will refresh.
So I'll be back soon.
'll Be here.
Do not move.
Do not worry. I will not.
So
was thinking we could have our first real date.
-Can we go see a movie?
Yes, dear.
We should do this.
Things between us will start getting serious.
I was thinking of seeing the new film by Tyler Perry.
You know, one where the guy is bad
with girlfriend
and a guy comes and rescues
and in the end, both found Jesus.
Alex? So
agrees to see the movie Tyler Perry?
Alex!
Michelle was Fun
Michelle'' ''?
You Mya, idiot!
Mya.
He took my coffee black?
It was as if a hidden truth had been revealed
hardcover and paperback.
For my book club.
-To me! To my mother-
!
For the first time in their lives, women stopped
to get advice on relationships to other women.
Really?
I have others.
Thank you.
Instead went straight to a man,
Steve Harvey.
He became famous as a comedian, but this drug
? It was not funny.
And because of this,
things would never be the same.
'' Mama's boy'' and''
'' The Single Mother
Excuse?
Do you happen studied at Fairfaix?
Yes
Me too. Michael Hanover.
-Candace Hall.
Yes, I remember.
I had classes with her sister Lisa.
Near-line.
-Sorry, do not recognize.
Yes, I had 1.5 I
44 pounds when we graduated.
He wore glasses and was toothy.
Just look familiar, maybe here?
Yes, it seems.
Do not know if it's a good thing or bad
. You are already shipping me?
Well, you grew up. Very well.
And you have not changed anything.
You are beautiful.
Well, you need to put the glasses back
, obviously.
No, actually, I'm nearsighted.
Also, how could I forget
my teenage crush?
I used to look at you walking down the aisle
and was awestruck by his smile.
I'm rambling,
I do it when I get nervous.
Next in line.
Well, it was nice to meet you,
I say, see you.
It was good to have been noticed.
Next in line please.
Candace?
We could have coffee or something?
Recovering the past we did not have.
I can not, actually.
I have to get my...
-Husband? There...
-
Do you have a boyfriend?
No, I have a son.
What about going out to dinner?
Yes
'' The No Compromise'' and''
The Girl who wants to marry''
-I finally understood.
-Understood what?
Jeremy
ask me to marry is like asking to paint the kitchen
or lower the toilet seat.
It will not happen until I require.
And I never demanded damn it.
You know that still divide
all accounts?
-I thought it was his idea.
Yes, in college.
He ??worked and studied and I felt sorry for him.
But I'm still paying for it until today.
Hey, I'm Kristen.
-Hello, welcome.
-Welcome, please sign.
-Congratulations.
-Thank you. Six months.
Yes, we can not wait.
Thank you.
Here we come.
-Watch your step.
-Here is a man with a plan.
He knows what he wants,
he knows what he has.
I sell beautiful homes to live
and we live in a dormitory for boys.
On Valentine's Day  last
boys were there.
You're saying...
My God, I'm one of the boys,
except that I have a vagina!
I swear it was easier for Frodo Baggins
.
I'm sorry, who?
-Frodo, a Hobbit.
I do not understand the hobbits.
Okay, no, not me. That's so stupid.
Jeremy had a game of chess.
It's totally stupid.
So what you gonna do?
Vai trick him into getting engaged?
I will not deceive you.
I require of him.
They have been together for nine years.
So what makes you think
that will change now?
I have some new information.
It?
Yes, as Steve says,''
Do not hate the player...''
Change the game.
Your turn . Wait!
Lift your left leg.
C-A'''' ca.
Really? '''' I am a ca?
with the same woman for nine years.
I am Stedman Graham relationships.
I'm not talking about a'' cad'' ca.
I'm talking about, his face dominated by women
,
has no courage, because the woman
the breadwinner.
-Way, as is Kristen?
-You are great.
We stayed until two o'clock
playing Call of Duty. She loved it.
It does this... She does it for you.
I know my wife. Fantasy?
Science fiction? Action?
All-Love, she also loves.
No, she does this drug
for you In the end, she thinks...
That's just stupid.
What the hell?
Jeremy course not proposed to her,
not out of puberty.
It's time to clean.
You first.
No, no. This is your problem, Gail.
You do not want to hear,
just want to talk.
What I said?
Who will be there tomorrow.
No, no. Listen, Gail...
-I will not argue with you.
-Face.
I'm trying to talk and you will not let me... Hello?
Gail?
Did it again.
Hung up on me.
What do you call the wedding rings?
I do not know.
The engagement ring, wedding ring, ring
and suffering.
In your case, who picks up the ring.
It is not time for that.
You underestimate me because I'm short.
No, it's because you're a fool.
What's up? What's happening, baby?
What the hell is wrong with you?
-You're stoned.
Yes, is on drugs!
You're stoned or whatever
on my eHarmony profile is true.
I'm in heaven, gentlemen.
I met a girl.
No, in fact, she is a girl.
I met a woman.
You are acting like a woman in love.
'' The Dreamer'' and''
The Woman Who Is His Own Man''
Request it!
Hey, guess who's back. Table eight.
It is a lot of sand for your own truck, Sun
That does not exist, man.
She probably spends more here in
night than you earn in a month.
Okay, but think about how much it will save
if I cook for her.
Ah, you're crazy.
Dominic. Chives?
Okay, chef leaving.
-Well, it's beautiful. What is happening?
-I?
'Yes.
-Thanks, that was nice of you.
Duke joined a team,
bought a new laptop, I met a guy.
I think I'll try the white bass.
Hey, know what?
A guy.
Really?
Not an inflatable doll?
Do not be so surprised. Not that...
Honey, I'm just saying, you
divorced two years ago.
And three, maybe four years
last time we had sex.
He said he knew a guy, Lauren, not
I changed my last name.
Yet.
I want all the details, darling.
Tell me everything.
-It is attractive?
-Pure fire.
She has big breasts?
Yes, as are her breasts?
Tell us all.
Breasts? Surely something white.
White thing. We love breasts.
You is not white, Bennett. You of course.
-He has lovely eyes. Emotional.
-Yes!
He is sensitive.
I know she has an ass.
It has one rear
JLo or Serena Williams.
Ass so big, can you hide
underneath it if it rains.
-Butt is too much.
-There is no such thing.
Whew, there. The bigger the better.
But it was not just physical attraction,
was intellectual.
He ??loved The Immortal Life of Henrietta Lacks.
Bought  a book club for the mother.
Not that cute?
Yes, and a little gay.
He is a gentleman.
-It is a'' ca.'' I know it is.
-Surely a dog.
You two, you see what they are talking.
It is not like that.
She is a lady.
-'ve Been hooked.
-Enjoy it while it lasts, Mike.
Let me tell you,
will not last forever.
All they get happy.
See, but here's what is real.
When you wake in the morning, and go in the room
,
and you see it pissing
with their Jordans.
Jordans And not normal.
I'm talking about the patent leather,
the most expensive.
Do not listen to them, Mike.
Relationships are beautiful.
My opinion-.
-So when they go out?
Saturday night. She has to find a babysitter
first, and then...
A dog sitter?
No, she has a son.
What?
-She has a son.
Careful when dating the mother of a baby.
-Why?
-Why is the mother of a baby.
Dude, she's not looking
a few good laughs and sex.
She has had many good laughs and sex.
-Sermon.
-She wants a husband.
A father to his son.
Speaking of which, where's the father?
-Good question, Zeke.
-Thank you.
It may be a psychopath.
Had parole for killing her boyfriend before.
Or it can be a
of hiding in a bush
Expecting a stranger in the house that goes from the baby's mother.
And when he gets there, he jumps from the bushes
reaches
this guy in the head with a brick.
Without even realizing that the relationship with her mother
baby was platonic.
They never caught this guy?
There is a case filed.
The police will not reopen the case.
They said they found the brick.
I'm just saying, I'm just saying.
-None of that matters.
-Seriously?
You should see her smile.
'Oh, damn. Right. Alright.
-Good night, Mike.
I speak of bricks!
You want to talk about a smile.
-There is one thing, however.
-I knew he was born a woman.
No.
-He  is, you know, it's...
-He is what?
A little younger.
You kidnapped a baby, is not it?
No, he seems very mature indeed.
Wait, why am I so excited?
We have not even left.
I still need to qualify if it is even a candidate.
Qualify?
What are the long-term goals?
And the short term?
It's a good provider?
Do not ask all at once.
I know, do not worry.
I plan to be reserved.
You? How?
Act like a lady,
but think like a man.
Ah, you fell in that sexist crap?
It gives us a vision
the male perspective.
Why
lower my standards to have a boyfriend? Who does that?
I'm sorry. Now, what man?
Someone like me.
Or at least, an attractive man, worship.
With 1.80 m, six-figure salary and
is not intimidated by my success.
Stop chasing the ghost of James Merrill.
He is married and gone.
This guy was great.
Here we go.
Let's do a little research.
This-is you.
-Please, I do not...
'' Strong Women,
independent and solitary.''
I do not need a bald man in a book
telling me I'm strong and independent.
Honey, this is fact.
Lonely but forgotten.
You are a bitch.
You are very strong, Lauren.
No such thing as too strong.
And you know what?
If I were a man, the youngest director of operations
a Fortune 500 company
would actually be a good thing.
Choveria women.
Yes, but the men fled when they discover
.
It's not just your work, Lauren.
Do you remember what Marcel said in his last meeting
,
when he chose another wine?
-I made a better choice.
-What were your words?
'' You do not need a man, Lauren,
you are a man.''
Happy belated birthday. For you.
Do you know all this waiting for something better?
Is making it bitter.
Hey, honey?
I stopped for a beer, but
brought dinner.
My God.
Oh, my God! My anime posters!
We were robbed!
Kris! Are you home?
Yes Where's the fire? What?
You do not realize they were robbed?
I took a tidy things. Relax.
-He repaired?
-Yes.
Justice League? Darth Vader? SpongeBob?
Where are they? Are they okay?
They are safe. They are well.
I just thought we could paint the room.
Paint.
-Right.
-E redecorate.
-Redecorate?
-Yes.
I thought I loved those things.
Why did you do that?
Well, looks like a dorm, Jeremy.
-Stop it.
-We are adults, Santo Cristo.
We have a decent life.
It's time to invest here and make a real home.
With  plates and matching cups
and a new sofa.
What's wrong with my sofa?
You got him in a dumpster.
Yes
I'm sure
Annalisa was conceived there.
There are cigarette burns, stains based on
, 2006 and scabies.
-You're being dramatic.
-I'm not.
His aunt who pees when she laughs?
She peed all over the couch last Christmas.
It's disgusting. We are like animals.
I cleaned the cigarette burns
based and shed.
This sofa has history.
And now it was.
So here are some new ideas.
We could take a look.
Find some new styles.
We have to decide the color.
I know you like mauve. Do you know?
There was a time  you enjoyed salmon.
I'd rather watch Letters to Juliet
with you again.
I know that you prefer.
For cried at the end when they meet again.
I was not crying, right?
I was having an allergic reaction to perfume
film.
You bought the soundtrack.
It's a good soundtrack.
Look, I'm very bad at it. Okay?
Please can redecorate your own?
-Without me?
-Seriously?
Seriously.
Alone?
Yes
-I trust you.
Great.
Let me ask you a question.
Where is the last guy you slept with whom
in less than 90 days?
I mean, John?
Hey! Gata!
What's up, girl?
Hey, I had fun the other night.
That's right, Alex?
Yes, Melanie. I was going to call...
Melanie? Mya is, black.
Yes I have to go. I'll call you.
Do not believe you called Melanie.
Okay. That 'will not affect me.
I have control over my life
and I'm better.
'' The Player'' and'' The Girl's Rule 90 Days''
I do not know, Sonia.
I feel like an X-ray vision.
How glasses men.
We lost a lot of time complaining because men do not want to compromise,
just want to stay.
But in fact, always had the power.
True. We?
Yes! We control the wafer.
Who controls the wafer controls the game.
Okay, got it. What is a cookie?
It's a metaphor.
-What?
Da ..
'Yes. The wafer! The wafer-
!
Understood. The wafer!
I assure you, the power is on the wafer.
Then, we control the wafer?
Putting it in the pot
and closing the lid.
Right.
Until some kid grow up and really deserves.
Understood.
It's like the rule of the five meetings of my cousin.
No, that is for amateurs.
I'm talking about something a little more radical.
You need to buy the book,
has a whole chapter about it.
'' How to Get the Respect You Deserve:
The Rule of 90 Days.''
Are you stoned?
-No.
-Who waits 90 days?
If it works in the largest companies in the country,
Will work with me.
When I worked at Ford,
had a trial period of 90 days.
I had to work 90 days
before receiving benefits.
Ford thinks so.:
'' Let's see how it behaves.
'' If it does not delay and to demonstrate its value
, receive benefits. ''
So, if Ford Motor Company expects to release 90 days
benefits,
why women can not wait?
This is our problem.
Always just releasing to any stallion that wears Axe
and think my name is Melanie.
But no matter, we also have
needs.
Listen to what you're saying.
Do you really think I could wait 90 days?
Yes  I spent six months
dreaming with a guy I once saw a wedding.
The one who slept on the beach?
Yes, and you never called me.
So, certainly,
wait 90 days.
Actually, it could wait another 90.
I'm sick of men.
Maybe I should start dating women.
My God, paid $ 50
if you kiss.
-It has to be with his tongue.
-Man, get outta here!
Experienced.
The
What's wrong with men of this generation?
I wonder the same thing every day.
What happened to respecting women?
What happened to decency?
Give me the honor to pay them a drink
?
Absolutely. Thank you for offering.
-We would like to...
-Why?
Because  want an intelligent conversation?
Or because you want to discuss the Policy for the war in Chechnya?
I do not talk about politics on a first date
.
-We do not. So I...
No, I know.
It's a visual thing, right?
You saw me, I sexualizou
and now wants to take my clothes off?
Definitely not.
So why?
Because, you know, you do not know me.
I may be a psychopath.
Can I be a serial killer.
I have 16 personalities.
Whiskey with Coca-Cola.
-It's for now.
16 And drinks her?
My name is Zeke.
Mya.
Nice to meet you, Mya.
First day. Missing 89.
Request table 16!
Dominic .
The valets are not realizing. Go help.
Thank you.
-Thank you.
Hey, that's my car!
Who said the standard should be high?
Where do I open the window?
Glass. Glass.
It is not the final destination.
Door open.
Drugs.
If I was less smart,
'd think you were following me.
No, I just...
I was just strolling.
Enjoy the ride.
Well, wait.
Change your mind?
I could take you to dinner one day?
What about tomorrow night?
We love the fact that you are a woman
strong and confident with a good job,
but we are men.
Our DNA is coded to be the provider.
And if you never leave us thinking we're in control
,
do not declare our love for you.
And yes, a woman
try to make us feel like a man.
It is a bitch.
We are like dogs. If we cuddle,
be faithful to you forever.
, dogs. That's right, Steve.
Do not need this book.
QUESTION NUMBER 1: Equals
ARE YOUR OBJETlVOS SHORT TERM?
Ah, yes!
Oh, dear. Jennifer
will take care of you tonight.
You're going to bingo with Grandma?
-No. I actually have a meeting.
-Seriously?
With a man or a woman?
With a man!
Why are you asking me this?
Because
heard Grandma say that is beginning to suspect.
You know, I do not care.
Sorry for the delay.
Hey, Bennett, enter the game. Come on.
-And here, man?
Yesterday was the best night of my life.
-Really?
-LncrIvel.
-Look at the ball.
-It was fired yesterday?
Okay.
I will earn double the buffet.
-Right, throw the ball.
-I hope she's worth.
What will you do with it?
Tell!
Passed behind!
I'll take you to The Lounge.
Maurice got me a private room
and I only have to pay
wine and tip.
Great. Will take her 2005 Honda Civic that
without the bumper or car at
U.S. $ 155 000 which she thinks is her?
I think I'll be honest.
What truth? You
is an unemployed waiter?
Zeke, aspiring chef unemployed.
We have already discussed this.
-That is not the issue.
-It would be stupid.
If you want to take her to bed,
will have to lie.
I told Gail that he had won the lottery.
And I had to supply to get the prize. She gave me $ 20.
Do not lie to her.
Do not want to lie to her.
Okay, wait.
You do not need to lie. Omit.
That's right, omit.
Say it's a chef
crowded with several job offers.
Your car is in the shop.
You're not expensive your car is in the shop because
.
Actually, my cousin,
he rents luxury cars. I'll get one.
All you have to do it drunk is
and drowning the goose,
then you tell the truth.
Gail thought I was an executive, and
met at the gate.
I was collecting cards.
But soon after you became executive.
It had nothing to do with it.
: Who got the interview?
-Thomas.
Do not interrupt me, Mike.
That's what Gail does. I hate it.
-Why is it so sensitive?
-Okay. Don, when
a woman falls in love,
stand anything.
-Trust me.
-Just do it right.
Right. That's...
Hey, man.
-I clean the ball. Best throw-
.
No, I have sanitizer in your backpack.
Sorry . Wrong apartment.
It's my lucky chair.
What are you doing?
Dear, what do you think?
We spent all day at the mall and we chose
-something modern with a classic touch.
-'' We''?
It. Gianni, our designer.
Old out, new inside.
Beautiful, no?
Seems I do not think our apartment.
Exactly. It looks like a house of adults. Loved.
Stop!
Unhook the chair.
The chair is lucky.
Ceded.
Hey, wait a minute.
Since when do you speak Italian?
Goodness.
-This is the dress.
-Really?
Your butt looks great in that dress.
No, it's too sexy.
Does not happen.
Sonia  I want it to wait 90 days, not 90
seconds.
'' I look like a potential girlfriend,'' not''
other fish in the sea''.
'' What the hell is other fish in the sea''?
You need to read the book!
Do not want to read the book.
Steve says one guy fishing
for two reasons.
A, he fishes to eat.
Other words, whether a potential girlfriend,
someone to take home
and submit to the mother,
someone to build a life.
Or two, he wants another fish in the sea.
Other words, he wants a trophy,
someone to show to friends
and hang on the wall as a prize.
Be careful with this award,
because it will play back at sea.
Right.
How am I?
As a potential girlfriend.
With a nice butt.
-Really?
-Really!
Great. The question is: what about him?
Just missing my list of success.
What is a list of success?
You can take your wine off the list?
You're crazy.
Is where I wrote my strategies for today's meeting.
Sounds like you're going to war.
Yes, because love is a battlefield.
My God.
Steve says we have to establish conditions
before you even get in the car,
'' are not an unlock and enter''.
A what?
He barely unlock the car and have you enter.
He does not need to open the door.
I see nothing wrong in being so
.
You are beautiful.
Thank .
LncrIvel.
What cute!
Where?
My God, that short skirt!
Right. Unethical.
Sorry, sir,
cashing of my tip.
Is open.
Do not go out with men that do not open the door for me.
Really?
-Seriously.
-Really?
-Yes.
I, huh!
He did not!
Gotcha!
His carriage waiting.
Thank you.
Very funny, huh?
I know.
There are some basic questions that every woman should do to man
to find out if this guy wants
take you seriously
or if you just want to take you to bed.
My short term goals?
Type, tomorrow?
I need a joint.
To answer your question ,
I think my goals in the short and long term are the same.
How so?
My whole life I have dedicated myself to work and tried
me highlight
and guess what I'm looking now
is someone to share it.
-So...
-So you...
You first.
What are your short term goals?
You know what? I would like to
skip dinner and go straight to dessert.
This was the beginning,
-know?
-Really?
This wine is great.
Thank you. Thank you.
Lauren, tell me more about you.
What do you do?
Work with the administration.
For a media company.
I do not want to talk about my work.
Week long.
Talk about yourself.
What do you do?
I am a chef.
Really? Where?
Well, actually,
'm considering two proposals.
You're so good?
Yeah, but do not want to give chance
talking about it, you know?
No, I understand. Stop there.
You know what?
Better not talk about work.
It is better.
And then, what you want in a relationship?
Or what are your long term goals?
One of the two.
Sincerely,
I want to open my own restaurant one day.
Sorry, I'm talking about work.
No, this is a dream.
Can we talk about dreams.
Dreams are good.
It's nice to hear a woman say that.
I believe you can accomplish any dream
if you are willing to fight for it.
Could not agree more.
-Health.
-Salud.
Remember when we were in college
and smoked and talked for hours?
Yes
About our dreams, plans and objectives
.
What about time travel.
What do you expect of the future, Jeremy?
I do not think there will be
flying cars, androids, but yes.
Definitely. There has to be androids.
No, I mean their future, Jeremy.
What are your long term goals, Jeremy?
Who are you, Oprah?
You're funny.
I have some ideas of design style rock chic
I'm very excited.
It does seem exciting-.
-Is.
It.
E then
What are your long term goals?
I'm a guy more impulsive, you know?
Oh, I know.
Legal.
Turn up the volume. Increases.
This is my... It is.
Know-these guys?
-Course.
My band has opened a show for them.
Do you have a band?
I had.
Almost signed a record deal.
Let me hear your CD. Please!
Why do you think I have a CD?
Do not know anyone who has had a band of R & B
and not have the CD in the car.
Wow, I feel so unique in this moment.
-So, you'll find him.
-Is.
Let me see.
Wow!
What madness.
At least not permanently used.
What?
Put ??your favorite music.
Wow.
Please indicate command.
CD. Play track
seven.
Playing  track seven.
Last night I had a dream about a dream
With you
You wrote this?
Now every time I think
seems that only think of you
That's beautiful.
In an instant I had given up on love
I was in another part of us
Who was she?
Who?
The girl who broke her heart.
Why
think someone broke my heart?
Range seven.
I left the past in music.
Last night I had a dream about a dream...
Oh my God.
Okay, wait. Wait.
-What?
I. .. do not do it on the first date.
Okay, I understand.
I am also a Christian.
I respect that, you know, and...
I enjoyed myself.
Me too.
Well, thank you.
Pronto. I got it.
Got what?
True My short term goal.
You fool.
Listen.
I thought about it all night.
I want to meet my mother.
Really?
It's very important to me.
Well,
want you to meet my son.
I love.
Just tell the time and place...
Hi, I'm the Duke.
You rang my mother?
No, mate.
I behaved nicely.
I know. He likes video games?
Ever played Street Racer Three?
-No.
-So you do not know what is good, buddy!
Have a good evening, Candace.
Good evening. Thank you.
-Nice to meet you, Duke. Do not forget...
-Enjoyment.
I enjoyed myself.
I also enjoyed myself.
Right.
Doing this is a'' good night'' official.
You know, I need a drink before
sleep.
-A drink.
-Is.
Course. It has a great bar around the corner.
-Have fun.
-I'll dispense with that?
I can not do anything.
How long will it take to invite me to join?
Five meetings.
To drink a drink.
Good evening.
This woman is crazy.
Good morning, beautiful.
Thank you.
Prepared his breakfast.
Really?
Yes
-With what I had in the kitchen?
-Give it to me.
They are simple to eggs Florentine, with a touch of my
,
ingredients left over from their Thai food.
-Single? Sounds great.
-Tell me what you think.
It's delicious.
Really? I love women who eat.
And I love men who cook.
Maybe I can do for you again someday.
Juice, please?
Medium spicy?
Thank you.
Who is this?
My best friend, Candace.
-Right.
-And my godson, Duke.
You know, you is not exactly the stereotype of a
godmother.
Thank God.
Entered without knocking again, no?
I did not know would be here.
Should be running away from her house.
Firstly,
I live here, you do not,
, and secondly, she has a rule
five meetings before inviting me.
Can you believe it?
I am a black pimp, a negrolo'' original''.
Five meetings?
It is a Muslim extremist or something?
She is a diva.
She refuses to go
if I open the door.
Gail did.
It took me over the edge.
'' Open the door. How will I spend
if you do not open the door?''
'' My hands hurt.
You better open the goddamn door!''
'So I will end soon.
-Do you really need.
Do not need it. You got me
and what we have is special.
Open the door for her.
We at  201 2.
It does have to open my door.
I do not know, I feel like a new woman.
I felt powerful, strong and...
What about him?
Well, I guess...
Can Zeke dinner tomorrow night?
It's him.
'' You can have dinner tomorrow night?''
Well, can you?
I think I can.
But do not go out with guys that I invite
per message.
Do not go out with guys for SMS!
It's crazy.
Gail always suggested omelets
only with the clear, it is healthier.
Can you put a shirt
while cooking?
Woke up early.
Where does all this brilliance?
My friends.
Hey, you got it.
Wow! At the first meeting?
-Point for him.
-Is.
I'm screwed.
Neither  talked about my work.
-You really like him.
-I do, yes.
I do not know as it gets.
And you know what?
I do not care!
I believe in your dreams.
She thinks I'm a chef on the rise.
With a beautiful Mercedes.
And a sexy chauffeur.
I was elegant,
hat with the hand.
People, she will run away when
discover the truth.
Whatever you do, do not tell the truth
.
-Right.
-You have to postpone.
Damn, I would not count
before she becomes pregnant.
-I can not do that.
-Don, I know.
You are trying to do the right thing.
Trust me.
Sincerity is overrated, man.
In the Bible. Old Testament.
Only
do not want a relationship based on lies.
That 'is called marriage.
Don, you do not fool me.
I know what it is. Sex.
You did right in the room.
So come here every downcast
and with low self-esteem.
True.
When your performance is not good, your insecurity is visible.
Know what happened? PP.
Lazy Pipi. That was it.
Exactly. You need to apply correctly.
Do not take it anymore. Enough is enough.
To me arrives.
Dude, put a shirt!
No one else here, just us!
You're telling me that she has a son?
Yes! The Duke. He is six years.
A great kid, full of energy.
That's a big responsibility, son.
Well, she is a woman
very responsible mother.
I'm not talking about it,
I'm talking about you.
Do you really think that
is capable of dating a single mother?
Well, I
I was raised by a single mother, no?
Ah, but I'm only son.
Trust me, Mom.
You will love it.
Thank God!
A familiar place.
A place that has not changed,
which remains the same.
J, what happened?
My Fortress of Solitude
was invaded by a wave of bed and bath.
-What does this mean?
-I said, he speaks in code.
Kristen redecorating the house.
Redecorated? Why did not it?
No, she redecorated. She eliminated.
My identity in the trash!
My anime posters ,
glasses of Battlestar Galactica
that you liked everything in the trash.
I?
Wait. She even asked?
Just threw it all away?
-It seems that is taking over.
-It's crazy.
I was feeling another person.
Someone modern with a classic touch.
You must be sick. It is an STD.
You drank the beverage of Zeke.
-And she threw off my couch!
-Thank God!
God save Kristen!
-He has many memories.
-So that smell?
Yeah, we all fucked on that couch.
Twice.
-You had since college, right?
-Yes!
Thing whitey.
No, the thing Jeremy.
No, whitey thing.
I graduated and got rid of my couch.
What went right?
DeVry, class of February. Valedictorian.
Whose side are you on?
No brother on earth would a sister hot
sit on a couch stinky college.
-Amen, brother!
-No matter what happens,
needs to grow and buy furniture,
in several installments.
Do not do it.
It's a black thing. Never do this.
It's the same thing in black!
Do you always buy things they can not afford.
Ced, you could not afford your wedding!
I am paying today.
Listen, Kristen is a great girl.
Do not spoil a good thing because of a couch, right?
It is up to something.
The game had started,
but not what we were watching.
As we sat watching the game,
Our team was being beaten.
The other team was creating plays, devising strategies
and plotting their next moves.
Still awake?
I thought you were asleep.
-I could not stop reading.
-Ah.
Jeremy did not even know he was being attacked.
Wow, something amazing happened today.
I found the brother of Sarah.
And he told me he got a job at
Neversoft.
Legal.
It.
Do not offered an internship there once?
I refused to accept a real job.
Okay, that post below
he still holds today.
What?
My brothers knew nothing about war.
They were distracted by the honeymoon phase.
They were too busy having fun.
Okay, who's hungry?
I'm hungry, but get off, baby!
Caramba! Look at that ass!
Legal. She's hot.
Guys, stop, she has no father.
Wait, this is a single mother?
It is Candace?
-Is Candace.
-I know a single mother.
No, she is the best friend of Lauren.
It seems they play basketball three times a week
,
and Dominic said Michael
is very successful.
Really?
-Point for you!
Mandel right? You know what?
The  Michael said Dominic
is an amazing chef.
I know! I love food.
-Oh, my friend.
-What?
Can we hang out together.
-That is not good.
Let's play basketball, folks.
-Yeah, come on.
Whatever you do, do not leave together
.
That's right. Ced...
Really?
I was getting changed.
J, is making us lose!
-I?
-Yeah, we're sinking.
I talked to score.
-You just hit a 27.
-A I got right was important.
Enough. New teams next week.
I want to leave his team.
Do not I who is not scoring!
Excuse me, have ended?
We need all of the court.
Yes, yes.
-Stay with it.
No, not done.
We still play a lot,
then chose the wrong
court to take possession.
We've played three times!
Yeah, Ced, we have.
-Not just, no.
Do not just. I'm sorry.
And then will leak or not?
It is, as we exit...
Drain? What is this slang?
Do not know anything more recent?
For you and stronger version of the Prince
not return to their side of the block
and do what they were doing?
If you want to block,
will challenge us as real men.
So you want to play against us.
You heard me.
Am I
speaking another language? Losers.
-They will not defeat us. We are men!
-Ced.
-You think you can take advantage of us.
-It's not serious.
I am, yes. I never spoke so seriously.
Oh, damn.
I thought they were the only two.
I have not seen the others.
Turn and apologize.
-Too late.
-Apologize.
I will not ask anything.
Michael, being a man is this!
Okay, folks. If you want a game, a game will have
.
Want to play?
Ced, drop it!
-Cedric!
-What are you doing?
-Are you okay?
Get up.
What an embarrassment.
-I tried to catch it.
-We saw.
I tried it.
I swear that I gave up on me.
I hoped  the esophagus in the last game,
so I will not be able to play.
The esophagus is the throat.
-Shut up.
-Zeke, we need six.
Forget Zeke,
will play with five.
Listen, we're men.
We tied our shoes like them.
The largest of them are.
Does not matter. Be a man!
Each one has to choose someone to mark
.
Come. Defense.
I March. Come on. Choose
. I've chosen.
Everyone should be welcome to
JW Marriott Los Angeles.
But then the truth came out.
For Dominic, the situation changed
on Tuesday afternoon.
... The best year in company history.
It is not only the director of operations more
young woman who has had, but better.
Ladies and gentlemen, Lauren Harris.
Thank you.
Oh, damn.
Mother? THERE you are.
-Hi!
Mother, I would like you to meet Candace.
Hi!
Michael received the pump on Wednesday.
I have heard much about him.
I have not heard anything about you!
Talked about it at dinner yesterday. What...
Well, I do not remember.
Mother, why are you...
I do not remember.
Your home is beautiful.
Wonderful. Best.
Oh, wow, just look!
I have this same frame with a picture of my son!
FlLHO NUMBER ONE!
The ASTRO
Oh, yes, you're the one who has children.
I want to ask you something, dear,
what daddy your baby
think about you going out with my Michael?
Or is he stuck?
Everyone knows how to type
of people flee from responsibility.
Arrested? No, why do you...
Candace, want to see the rest of the house?
Yes, why not show the house to Tandace
?
Candace. My name is Candace.
Tan... Tandace?
It... Candace with a...
I realize that she really likes you.
Let's take a walk around the house.
-That we will.
Come.
They do not explain our relationship?
I tried to capture all the special moments
between me and my big boy.
There should
remember when I gave him the bracelet.
In a town near Paris,
in a small jewelry store with cute...
Do you remember his expression when you open the box?
Yes, I know, I know.
I thought we were in Milan
No, we left the restaurant...
Honey, you're in my room.
This is where the magic happens, baby.
-Our.
What do you think?
It's as if I had gone back in time.
I keep everything the same way,
for when he sleeps here.
Do you sleep here?
On Sundays, my dear. Nothing much.
And Sunday evenings
always been reserved for his mother.
And always will be.
I make his favorite dish,
and then play cards.
Mom
is the best player of letters I know.
A game of little note
inho zinho inha zinha
Come.
Do not do that, not in front of Candace.
Let me get your clothes clean.
Clean clothes?
Let me help you with that, mother.
I need more socks, mother.
They stink!
But you know, do not care about the stench.
I just need to rub some more.
Wash and scrub to clean.
Michael Nene will shine!
FlLHlNHOS OF MOTHER
excessively attached to their mothers
do not want to grow,
they can not compete
Drugs.
For Zeke, no'' cookie'' on Thursday.
The night is young.
What do you do?
This is our fifth meeting, right?
Really? I do not know, I lost count.
Lost it?
How about a drink to relax?
Okay.
Yes
It's kinda small, but I liked
because of French windows
and being close to work.
So...
A beauty.
Maybe we should look for a more comfortable place.
Yes
'Yes.
-Yes.
'll Put a song.
You know what? Maybe you should.
Choose the music you want.
Legal.
Do you have vinyl records?
Yes, I'm a purist.
-I'll be back.
-Okay.
Do not go. I mean...
Do not go.
-I will not.
-Okay. Alright.
Our. You really are a purist.
How the hell did you get this on vinyl?
No.
How do you like your coffee?
Zeke discovered the hard way,
which means a drink to relax
a drink to relax.
Three doses of Jack.
You're so silly.
Hi!
Ah, Ced, why are you here?
Do not have any milk.
Hey, wanna ask you something seriously.
Do you think I look like the ldris Elba?
The stripper club
Sweaty Crack told me last night,
but I had a note with me,
do not know if she tried to fool me.
Do not respond. Do not worry.
I felt good when she said that.
Looks like someone was invited to spend the night
. How was it?
We had coffee.
?
-Eat biscuits.
E?
And we talked about our childhoods, art and music
and on Plato's Allegory of the Cave.
What the hell is this?
It's actually pretty deep.
Lgual the book by Bishop Don Magic Juan
wisdom on the streets,
which is a great read.
Five meetings and just got a coffee.
What is her problem?
It is not the problem.
What's wrong with you?
It seems that the stallion
is losing its charm.
I'm in a relationship without sex,
when
all I want is sex without a relationship.
When you see it again?
Saturday night. Do not mess.
Good job.
Hey, Zeke, when up there, take a look at
toilet,
because it seems that is clogged,
but not sure.
Do not know where the plunger was,
then do not be surprised to see the stretch.
It's full.
-We were up all night...
-Okay.
... And talk about everything.
You left without the cookie?
But, of course.
-Legal.
I can not say it was easy.
I do not know when he kissed me, as if we were
sex.
So, thanks for your advice about
panties.
What did you use?
-A grandma.
The big one-granny style?
I told her that her panties ugly work.
-You would not listen.
-And it worked.
Now that you know is not just a theory,
think you can last 90 days?
Monique!
It's Mya!
Call me!
You Mya, asshole!
Yes I can certainly last longer than 4 days 7.
Okay, Monique.
-I'll cancel the meeting.
-Why?
He works as a waiter part-time.
Can I remind you, Miss. lmportante, we were waitresses
for two years at Olive Garden?
Candace, we were in college.
I'm talking about a grown man,
parking to be admitted that the Mercedes he used to follow me.
It's kind of romantic.
It's kind of pathetic.
I thought I did not care about money.
I thought you believed in his dream.
Not in- absurd. As if!
-Okay, okay.
Freedom is the first guy who treats you well
just because he does not win as well.
Please, he does not earn much.
And I can not invest time in something
that
I do not bring profit for my time and effort.
You heard what you said?
Dominic is a person, Lauren,
and not a stock portfolio.
As Steve Harvey says,
there is a perfect man.
You have to accept some defects.
What you got to lose?
My youth.
Wait. She canceled the meeting?
It would cancel.
Was interrupted by his boss.
-What the hell.
-You know what?
Who cares about the success of her
and the board that she run it?
take an honest living and pay my taxes. Most of the time.
You know what, Don? I agree.
I am also American and I agree with you, brother.
Me too.
We give full support.
-And then, Mike?
-Okay?
How was everything between Candace and her mother?
It...
I will slow down with Michael.
-Why?
-He already has a woman in your life.
Oh, that bastard. Who is she?
-Your mother.
-What?
My mother thinks she's cool.
Oh, I know.
No woman is good enough for his mother.
Do you think she'll like
just a single mother?
-Good luck.
-Listen to this.
'' You can redial the day at the beach?
I promised I would take my mother to the school choir.''
I can not do that to me again,
and will not do that with Duke.
Deserve a man to commit himself entirely.
So imposes standards.
Oh, my God,
not believe I'm quoting that book ridiculous.
Tell Michael
not want to interfere in his relationship with his mother
and if you want to go out with you,
you must become a priority in his life.
She was a lifetime.
I can not compete with that.
Then, drop the first guy in three years
who really likes you and Duke.
Wait, there
a perfect man, is not it?
What you got to lose?
Not what you told me the whole night?
Right.
I will continue if you continue.
It was the worst moment.
The boys were being attacked with full force.
But everything changed on Day D.
FOR A FABRlCA butts
Tell me one thing.
How do you feel like a free man?
Great. Okay, listen,
-I do what I want...
-Yes.
-... When I want, with whomever I wish.
-Okay.
I am free of all cop-nia''''...
-Is'' tyranny.''
-Shut up, Bennett.
-Let him finish.
-I'm just appreciating the grammar.
Okay!
I am free from all tyranny and oppression.
And the boring
all women forever. Understood?
So
the only woman I want to talk today
The dancer is
Factory naked butts.
What happened to the Sweaty Crack?
-Closed. Sanitary violations.
-I've heard.
But what matters is that I prefer
Factory butts,
because the girls are naughty.
The way I like.
Ced! Ced.
Do not judge me!
I am going through a divorce, a friend.
Hey Lauren
confirmed our meeting tomorrow.
I thought you were finished.
Why are meddling in his life?
My friend said they broke up with her.
You have been tamed!
More than that, Mike.
-Stop it.
-Wanna hear a good story?
-No.
Ced, tell them about the night that saved
Gail.
I'll finish with you
a damn bottle of Gail speak again.
Do not wanna talk about Gail.
I want to talk about breasts and butt!
It's Candace. I must meet?
No, man! Give me the phone.
Friends come before women.
Hi Candace. Hey, there, girl?
-Michael.
-I was thinking of you.
No, hi, I thought I'd drop in the mailbox.
No, I answered, dear.
Look, Michael.
We need to talk.
Few words are more threatening than
.:'' We need to talk.''
That means we did something wrong
or you literally want to talk.
-She wants to talk.
-This is new.
That's bad, man.
Great! Hopefully
chatter until you get bored.
There is something good in a woman want to talk?
No. Not that I know.
Kris used to be alright
and now everything she does is argue with me,
pentelhando me with:
'' What are your immediate goals?''
What are your ultimate goals?
Jeremy, what do you think of relationships?''
I'm playing Call of Duty...
Wait, go back to tape. What did you say?
The ultimate goals, immediate... Do not make me
-repeat.
Yes, that's crazy. Do you know?
Candace
asked me the same things at the first meeting.
Mya asked me the same thing.
And Lauren too.
You know what?
Do you know who asked me that?
No one! Strippers do not ask me anything!
She  told me the other day,''
I'm not a fish in the sea.''
What is this?
A trophy. To show your friends.
What the hell are you talking about Bennett?
I was watching Oprah.
-Why watch Oprah?
-I like.
Appears saying that a gay party in a divorce.
Steve Harvey was in the program.
He wrote a book.
It's for women but about men.
-The Steve Harvey Family Feud?
-I heard something about it.
He betrayed us like this?
How rude. I would not.
I thought he was a friend, but...
Me too.
-What?
-You what?
-I said nothing.
Tell me exactly what it says in the book.
A lot of junk.
This is why we are
ruining my party. Because of this.
I found the book on the internet.
I found a critical...
I need to get this book.
No, do not do that now.
-You told friends before women. A second-
.
Guess what?
The friend needs a wife!
My pocket is full of money
and I'm not in his underwear.
I do not wear underwear today.
Should be my companions.
Come, join me!
Celebrate, men! Take your...
Please join me, men! Damn it!
This does not good.
Yes, we looked for a book called...
Behave Like a Lady, Think Like a Man
.
. Sold out? Thank you.
They say  is sold out a week ago.
Great.
-There may be exhausted.
'They have neither on eBay.
-It's the power of Oprah.
I've got something.
Right. Where is San Pablo?
On the boundary of Oregon.
That does not work out.
: It seems we tried.
Hi. Now?
Tomorrow is another day.
Try again.
Time-strip!
-I can bring home to mom?
Driver, go to my house?
I thought it was going to cancel with her mom.
Have you tried to cancel with my mother, Ced?
I will say, since nobody else wants to speak
, Michael.
Have you tried to become a heterosexual?
Mommy!
I made your favorite.
The smell is great.
-Look at that, eh?
Let me get a chicken.
Let me get a chicken!
Stop. You know I love
sauteed onions and cornbread.
I know. I'll get a plate for you, but clean everything before
.
Right.
And make sure that the sweet potato pie...
You can leave, little, just wipe the counter.
Mommy, what is this?
It is the book that bald
participating in the show Family Feud.
Act in a way,
Think of another.
The book for the club.
Every war has its turn.
In the Civil War,
was the Battle of Gettysburg.
In World War II,
was the invasion of Normandy.
The
turn this war was that night at the home of Loretta.
It was like finding the Holy Grail.
Jeremy . Ask the bus to turn around.
The power was in our favor.
We did not know it yet.
'' Why Men Do That '.
'' Look at that.
Steve Harvey is a traitor.
Look,'''' Little children of the Mother.
Chapter 7. It's you.
I'm not a mama's boy.
Jer, do not think I'm one, is not it?
-No.
-Listen it.
'' Men respect standards, create some.''
I prefer women without.
Actually, if I had to choose, choose a
no standards.
Look. '' Until it achieves its goals are near or
,
'' will never be number one in his life.''
See, this is not true.
Not won anything yet and prioritize my women.
Doing this is terrible-.
-It's brainwashing.
You are trying to lead me to my dreams
and help me reach my goals.
Why would she do this?
At least you're having sex.
Ninety days, this is not a test,
is a death sentence.
I wanna taste your cherry.
Hey Mike, how old is your mother?
What?
No, not that. No, it does. That's right.
How old is she?
I go and she says,'' Want to eat?''
I say,'' Eat what?''
Drop the plate and stop giving the top of my
mother's face.
Do not be mad!
I do not want to be here.
Do you want that is,
I want to go to a strip club!
To Complete this soon. I have several notes of a
and someone will take it from me.
Miss. Loretta!
I am ready for you to show me the house.
You are so screwed.
And there's nothing they can do.
Maybe we can do something.
They have a book about our secrets.
You know everything about us.
Yes, but do not know what we know
who know our secrets.
Saw that not only go out with Jeremy?
I never know what he's talking about.
It's like the Patriots, Bill Belichick when
robs the play of the Jets.
-Were caught and punished.
-But won the game.
And where gone? In the Super Bowl.
I would like to know what you mean.
We will use the words of Steve Harvey against them.
Pretend to give what they want, and
get what we want.
We'll lie to them.
Exactly. We are at war, gentlemen.
There are no rules.
As the great Khan said, not Genghis,
I'm talking about the Latin Star Trek ll.
'' Revenge is a dish best served cold. ''
Michael, I must admit one thing.
You know what?
Before admitting anything,
I must admit something.
You know I can be a mama's boy?
I think it all started when my father died.
It was a difficult time for us, you know?
And my mother began to tell me more
. Count me too.
You know, I had to be
the man of the house still young
and that's why we are so close.
Michael.
I think what I'm trying to say is
I want to be the woman
number one in my life.
It was like making a test
for which already had answers.
You are my priority, Candace.
Are you okay?
Yes
Right.
You said you wanted to talk about something.
I said?
The women had no chance.
We assume the command.
I updated my resume and sent it to Neversoft.
Really?
Are you serious?
I was intrigued by an ad in Adweek
I saw and thought:
'' Why not try, Jeremy?
You have nothing to lose.''
Dear, this is wonderful, very good.
I am very proud of you.
My God-.
-Nothing excitement, okay?
Just sent my resume.
They probably will not call me.
You're underestimating.
Jeremy, you're the best in its class
Parsons, is a brilliant designer.
No. You're a brilliant artist.
They would be lucky to have him.
I'm lucky to have him.
Do you?
Know what was I thinking?
What?
No one has slept on this couch.
-No, it's a sofa virgin.
-Really?
What should we do about it?
I can think of a dozen things.
Only ten?
Will be screaming like crazy after the third.
Now I'm scared.
I love this couch.
After a careful study,
Dominic saw that there was only one man
impressed that  Alpha Women.
'' The Man With Potential.'' Zeke.
What?
-I have to show that I have a plan.
-Lnvente some crap, man.
-No.
-Remember the idea of ??the restaurant?
-Yes.
Help me with a business plan.
Cook for her. Jerk.
I already did that. Breakfast.
I'm not talking about breakfast, man!
Something chic, Don!
One of those dishes with apostrophe in the name.
This is your robe?
Yes
Dude, you're here again?
Yes! The Factory butts does not open until 22h
I have time until then.
Slut-, move here.
What do you say?
I like being with my friends when I'm
divorced.
What was I thinking?
You're from another world, man.
Gail used to love when I cooked for her. That 'excited her.
You can do several things in the kitchen.
Was something we did with the food.
I picked strawberries covered with chocolate, right?
And I descended using a G-string thong.
Know what I mean. She loved it.
The game was the'' Strawberry Swing''.
I put the strawberries in...
But the way it is...
The strawberry
will not be there long, so...
What I'm trying to say is this, Sun
Food is his art.
Use it to win Lauren.
It's a good milk, Zeke.
He's right.
I will.
-Over.
-Wait, what happened?
Dominic's car broke down.
I have to go get him?
So? Calm down. Do you know how many times
I got him when his Jaguar broke?
You can stop, Candace.
The guy is a loser.
I am the fool who slept with him.
On the first night.
Something he will be remembered with pride for ever
,
it never happen again. Never.
Hey, beautiful.
Dominic.
You are beautiful.
Yes, I mentioned that.
-I would like a glass of wine?
-Actually came here to...
This is a Chateau Montelena, 2006.
Won first
in the Judgment of Paris in 1976.
Actually,
was the Chardonnay that won 73,
but I heard that this is better.
It was a gift.
But I wanted to save it
for a special occasion.
Well, thank you.
Then
a toast to this night.
Yes
Oh, my God.
Doing this is good.
Yes, and there's more.
You did this to me?
Good evening, miss.
Wild...
-Damn.
-Face...
I'm sorry. Very much.
'' Wild Mushroom en Crout''?
Croute.
Croute?
Thank you.
-Enjoy your dinner.
-Thank you.
I would like to stop seeing me
like a waiter serving hors d'oeuvres.
What do you think?
LncrIvel .
As you.
Thank you.
And watch the stars.
Make a wish.
Okay.
You will not make a request?
Is not necessary.
And that night, Zeke was
on a completely different mission.
Do not tell me what I said. I know.
-But I'm telling you, eventually.
-What?
Do not agree with this rule 90 days.
You have the ammunition needed.
Dear, I'll rise.
Okay, listen.
Use'' as'' men show their love
against it to get the wafer.
Confess your love.
Call it girlfriend.
Stop. Do you have any idea what I spent?
I am tired of paying the account and open doors,
and feelings and talk about our childhoods.
It's like  in the '50s, man! I just want sex.
And if she thinks another 7
wait to have sex one day,
-she waits alone.
-Are you counting?
I'm not telling,
but you know the number of days...
You really like it.
No, man, trust me. It's over, okay?
I'll end this now.
Yes, have fun on your date.
I'll give you a kick in the rear of 90 days of it.
Listen.
Mya, on tonight...
Okay, got a surprise.
Do you?
Yes, I bought tickets for
John Legend's concert at the Nokia Theatre.
Okay, cool.
Yes
-Right.
-Okay. So, come on.
I hope you do not get mad at me,
But my uncle is a music producer
and I gave him your CD.
You took my CD?
Yes, and the three gum stuck in it.
You know what?
I was looking for chewing gum.
I've had enough of the music industry, right?
I love what I do.
Okay, Zeke,
he is not forcing him to sign anything.
Just want new songs for the album you're working.
Yes, my album got a disk''
'' brass, okay?
Two people heard and both were related.
True, but I was praising
and he decided to listen.
Should have been my agent.
Zeke!
Zeke stallion! And here, man?
-Man, hi, and then... Xavier!
-And here, man?
My lord . Honey, this is Zeke.
The guy who taught me to dance.
The Chimichanga!
It was he who taught me.
This is my girl, Crystal.
So, Crystal? How are you?
Oh, sorry. Xavier, this is...
Ladies, if a man
to present as a friend
understand, you're nothing more than that.
If a man has
plans for the future with you, he'll confess.
It will add a title to his name.
You will be his wife,
his girl, his bride or...
My girlfriend, Mya.
Zeke realized that he could reach far beyond
with a good confession than six wonderful encounters.
Oh, my God.
I think we should stop.
I need to get up early.
I better go.
Okay.
Good night!
I could walk with you until...
No, you can leave. I'm fine, good night!
The
boys may have lost some battles but the war earned.
I'm telling you, Gina. It worked.
He ??is finally trying to get a good job.
Family Feud knows what he's talking about?
I changed our relationship.
Zeke is in a relationship.
How this affects the rule of 90 days?
The rule of 90 days
was what brought me here.
What I mean is
that I am not opposed to change it
for good behavior.
How to change the relationship status on Facebook?
That 'shows good behavior,
but it still will not win the'' cookie''
Unless you say the three magic words.
I hope you are ready for fun in praiao.
Ah, yes, fun in praiao.
Wait. Honey, should meet?
Is the work.
Yes, all right.
Do not! Why should I answer calls
working with you with me?
Do not worry about it.
-No work.
-You're right, Duke?
-Yes.
Do you have your license?
For you will drive back in, right?
I'm kidding.
How romantic.
Things were going too well.
The
boys had even forgotten that they were at war.
Okay, thank you, guys.
I am Danny Vola.
Go up there and sing.
Come on, you should...
No, do not sing for years, sit there.
Wait, slow down! Sure, Duke!
-All right, you can.
-Care!
Will buy a bike like that to you, dear.
Ah, want one?
Sorry it took me, dear.
One of the boys needed some advice.
Where were we?
Right here.
But then things started to go wrong.
What happened with that job at Neversoft?
I forgot to tell you,
heard rumors that they filled the position.
Really?
Yes
How strange,
since talked with the younger brother of Sarah...
-Yes?
-... In LinkedIn.
And he said that the position was still open.
-Really?
-Yes.
And he
personally recommend it to your boss.
But his resume was not received.
What?
I waited all this time.
You know what?
I had to restart the modem the other day.
I bet you did not receive my e-mail.
I'll fix it tomorrow morning.
You are blaming the internet?
It happens all the time.
Kris?
The truth was coming out.
I'll miss you.
It's mine, right. Even more.
Right.
James?
-James Merrill?
-Lauren Harris.
Wow, look at you.
Look at you.
It's like a fine wine.
It gets better with age, is not it?
And you more charming.
What are you doing in LA?
I'm renting an apartment.
I was promoted to executive director of Sensala.
-Our.
-Yes.
I'm moving to LA.
-Are you kidding?
-No.
Nina I can not imagine moving from Chicago.
Well, it will not change.
We are finalizing our divorce.
-Really?
-Yes.
-I'm sorry.
No, okay.
-We are still friends.
-That is good.
Do you? You are engaged? Married?
No. Not engaged or married.
Really?
Only dating, but nothing serious.
So what about dinner?
Course.
I want you. I mean, I dine with you.
So I have to call.
-It's the same number?
-The same.
-Right. Call me-
.
Tomorrow night, .
-Absolutely.
-I liked the car.
-I also.
I liked the format.
From car.
-I hate to bother you...
Go away!
I saw this episode yesterday at home mom.
It's very funny.
There had been called back to work last night?
Ah, yes, last night I went to work,
but said I had to go in the house of Mama
to get things that she had left...
I told you, dear.
No, do not think you...
-Give me a kiss. You did not hear me.
And the lies were increasing.
My mother is planning a big family reunion.
-I would love if you were.
-What you want, dear.
-Really?
-Course.
The only problem is if your mother and grandmother are beautiful as you
,
you can have competition there.
Come here.
Cool!
It is in the park in Culver City.
You'll have a trampoline and barbecue.
These walls have ears.
Duke, go back to bed.
So, it will be on the 20th and will be great.
We will have cotton candy machines...
20-Day this month? -
Carousel...
Honey, can not in 20 days.
Why?
Actually, it's
anniversary of the church of my mother and promised her...
Really? You must be kidding!
Good night, Duke!
I'll see what I can do, right?
-Right.
-I'll fix.
Come here, girl, come on.
Turns out the only problem
pretending to take a step forward
is that sometimes you even need to.
Keep an eye on it.
Pay attention, this will jump...
Okay, what?
Right.
I wanted to wait until we were in the restaurant
but I spoke to my uncle last night
and he heard his CD and loved it.
He is obsessed with track seven,
and want to find him on Tuesday!
Congratulations!
My God. You did it for me?
No, you did.
You put your heart in the range.
I love you, girl.
Even unwittingly
Zeke made a mistake and said the three magic words
finally opened the cookie jar.
But Zeke's victory was short lived.
MYA  - FUL BUY THE BREAKFAST NOW TURN
- Zeke
This is not good.
No, no, no.
RULE OF NINETY DlAS
Getting the Respect it Deserves
I'm crazy or
last night was the best of my life?
'' You got the cookie.''
Cracker? I am the eater of cookies.
Do you know what I bought? Coffee with milk...
Mya, I can explain it.
Your lying piece of shit!
I was just using it in self defense.
If defending against what?
Against the Rule of 90 days.
It was created to protect women against
idiots like you.
So I'm the villain
and you do not have the courage
to say that I was
on a 90 day trial.
-I would say.
-When?
I'd tell you.
But then I thought I could change it.
Because I thought you were the right guy.
Something was real?
Something? Dinners, Exits?
Call me his girlfriend?
Or was it just to get a cookie?
Our.
You won, congratulations.
You did it, right? You win.
Mya, wait a minute.
Mya was all true.
Zeke, do not touch me!
God, you're so good.
You're pretty good.
Because even though I know you're lying,
I can almost believe you.
In The Art of War, Sun Tzu wrote.:
'' All war is based on deception. ''
He forgot to say.:
'' Only fools are caught. ''
Work Phone 310-555-0162
Dear, your phone!
Meanwhile, Candace needed
or find the book to understand everything.
Phone Michael Atwater.
Tandace?
Loretta?
Look, I'm calling to tell Michael
he does not need to take me to church.
Deacon Johnson will take me.
Let me talk to him. He is free?
He will.
Here goes! That dunk!
Michael.
Can I say something to you?
What is it?
You'll see.
Duke, go inside.
Darling, saw the skills this kid?
If I continue...
What happened, honey?
His work called.
I thought it might be an emergency and answered it.
But it was only his mother.
Really? You know, the list of contacts
is giving you problems...
No more nonsense, Michael.
Honey, I know that sounds, but trust me...
Believe? I trusted you.
I can not compete with her mother. And I'm not going.
You do not have to...
So why lie to my face?
You need to go.
Honey, listen...
Get out my face, Michael.
And Candace
was not the only things that solved that day.
Hi, beautiful.
Hi.
-How are you?
-I have a meeting at a 4h, then...
-You are beautiful.
Thank you.
You said you had news.
Yes
investor knows the friend of whom I spoke?
He read its prospectus ,
and loved whatever you call it.
Really?
I said I was fantastic.
Thank you. Thank you.
We have to celebrate. Let's go out tonight.
I'm not free tonight.
Okay, and tomorrow night?
Dominic, I'll be honest with you, right?
I rediscovered an ex-boyfriend
of my college days.
He ended up divorcing
and is moving to LA and I...
's Up with me?
Do not! I'm not ending,
I'm just taking a break.
-I need space.
-Space.
-We were going too fast...
-You are talking like a man.
What did you say?
Said you're talking about the same man.
So I called him to come to this place?
For a business lunch?
To be able to leave me?
Dominic, I really like you.
Right? I do not want to get you rolling.
Let's be friends.
Do not need more friends, Lauren.
I do not need your friends to console me.
Do not be stupid, Dominic.
That 'is business, not personal.
And you know the difference?
You know, Lauren, I...
I had not a prospectus, you know?
I made just to impress her.
You inspired me, motivated me
to do something for me first.
And all the time
I thought you were too good for me.
Kris? I bought a pizza.
I found this. Boys want convenience.
Men build homes. Fui. K
What I do not understand is that according to the book
I was the guy with potential.
I told her the truth, I ventured
and it was not enough.
At least it was caught in an outright lie
.
Things are really bad with Candace now.
Kristen did not want to see my face when I showed up at Ginny.
It will change your mind.
No. You do not see the way she looked at me
. With so...
-Rage? Grief-
.
It is anger. Women
get angry more easily.
Either way, friends.
I think we caused it ourselves.
It was in self defense. They attacked first!
We had to give change.
Only
protect our natural right to be men.
-That.
-Okay.
Love us or leave us, right?
Right!
And they left us.
Right.
We're back.
Take the time you need.
Thank you.
Zeke, take a look.
To his right. My left.
Not my type.
This is how we do, Zeke.
I and you point out the attacks.
You can bring me the bill?
TO SELL
-You can only get once a year.
What kind of meat is the McRib?
's Friends.
-Let me guess,
photos for the album of the school?
Looks like a substitute teacher.
Finally sent my resume to Neversoft. I did my interview today.
And they just call me.
I got the job.
-Really?
-Congratulations, man!
I am a senior designer at Neversoft.
With full benefits.
It will soon be spending their benches.
I have to call Kris.
She is not talking to you, is not it?
-No.
-Connect for her anyway.
It was because it happened.
Yes
-It was good advice.
-How will your project?
Actually, it's going very well.
I have to go away soon and work a little
.
Know what we do?
We should celebrate, right?
-Legal.
Yes-new job, Michael's first round.
'Yes. Liked it.
-No. I paid the last...
That's cool, just the guys.
Just like old times.
Not like the old days,
I no longer have a curfew.
Speaking  curfew, I gotta go.
It's my night to cook.
Bennett, is looking woman.
We have just heard good news,
us and the guys drinking.
He runs home the same puppy.
Come on, man!
Do not cook because I have to, but because I want
.
Seriously, Bennett.
I'm not fucking with you, but for now...
Do not be mad because I have a wife.
That means that
can not spend all night with you.
I have to get home early.
I'm just saying.
I'm buying this round.
-I'm happy for you, congratulations.
-Thank you.
-So long, folks. Great-B
!
$ 20 is missing, Bennett.
I cooked for
Gail on Thursdays. It was my day.
I'm happy to be free. I get it.
We're better off without them.
This, who needs to put up with them?
Their demands, their boring...
Expectations.
The expectation is the catalyst for everything.
-Here comes.
You know what's funny?
Gail
loved when I was cooking bolognese sauce from scratch.
It was his favorite, so...
Okay, guys, we are free to
do what we want,
with whomever we choose,
whenever we want, right? A freedom!
Freedom!
Ced, raise your glass, toast with us.
-Right. I'm sorry. No.
-Drink it all, man.
A freedom.
Turning.
Do not need them.
I have to pee.
I'll be back.
You look like you need to do something else.
Incoming Call Cedric
What is it?
Gail, I'm not calling for a fight.
-What the hell...
-Look! I'm coming home.
Even Cedric?
Gail, I'll tell you something.
It's my house, too, Gail!
Pay bills in this house!
It's my house too. I'm coming.
Where I belong, girl.
Gail, I'm tired of this nonsense.
I miss you, Gail.
Gail, I no longer have been the same.
I am here on the streets and all that shit.
I'm going to strip clubs.
The girls calling me by my first name
, like I'm always there.
And I am, but because
'm going through something, Gail.
I have to be careful.
I need you to cuddle my back, give me love.
I changed, I want my wife back!
I am surrounded by these guys and stuff!
Do not want it. I no longer want this life
I want you and Jesus.
That's it.
Okay, Papaizao.
What did you say?
What time can you get here?
In some 20, 22, 23 minutes.
Bring your body sexy face.
I'll be waiting.
Do you want me to bring something?
Doritos or something?
Can I stop and buy dear.
All that makes you happy.
-Just come home.
-Okay.
Okay, I love you.
Our.
Thank you.
That '.
Yeah, man. Go back to Gail.
He rubbed shit on my back?
You wash your hands, man?
Who shits wearing a hat?
She said she was coming from Shanghai.
Friends, see you later.
Let's pay and we will too.
You are going to the Factory butts?
Gail took me back.
I'm going home.
Home!
Hey, I'm married. Please!
Thank you. Married man!
That night,
we saw that all the plots,
plans and schemes
did not compare to a simple thing, the truth.
Mommy!
What the hell?
Hi, dear.
Flowers, breakfast. Ours.
Arrived early, dear.
I know, but I wanted to tell him to come
that I can not go to birthday today, Mom.
I have to go elsewhere.
Well, it's the 75th anniversary of the church.
What is it, dear? Where have to go?
See Candace.
At the meeting of her family, mother.
Good for you.
Okay, honey.
-Really?
-Okay.
I'll see you tomorrow, right?
It's time you go.
Loretta,
is my turn to have to spank.
Deacon Johnson?
, It has the keys?
-Put it down, you idiot!
How long does this happen?
Ninety days.
Well, now they are 91.
Sorry to have stretched his shirt.
How you doing, Michael?
-Okay, idiot, go now.
-You know, these pills cost $ 19.
Mom, you used my chuck it?
dear. You can go.
Listen, you idiot!
I said that would take the coffee up there, you old fool
.
Look who I found.
Okay, the third time I hope it luck.
Actually, I think it gives.
-Go, tell.
-We want to make an offer.
-I told you this would happen.
-Actually did not speak.
What good news.
We had a good feeling about you.
Kris?
Jeremy, what are you doing here?
I need to talk with you.
I can not. I'm in the middle of something.
Is important.
No problems. Take your time.
I'll get the papers and we can start.
I'm sorry.
Someone died?
What? No
Well, you're in a suit, I thought...
-I got the job at Neversoft.
-Really?
Yes
I mean, good.
I hope I have done that for me.
I did. At the beginning.
But somehow, throughout the pretense
,
I knew that I wanted it for me.
And now that I have, I want for us.
You were the first to whom I wanted to call
count,
and not being able to drove me crazy.
You're the last person whom I think
before going to sleep, Kris.
Look
miss.
Oh, dear.
I miss you and want you back.
So beautiful.
I want to buy a house.
This is my guy in charge.
I want to buy this house for you.
You can stop, idiot.
Not going to buy my house.
Okay.
Who is he to buy my house?
Breathe .
I'm breathing. I'm fine.
Right.
I want to be his wife.
I want you to be my husband...
I want to be her husband.
And I want you to be my wife,
very much.
So...
Will you marry me?
I agree.
-She did.
-That there, man.
-She got it changed the game.
-She what?
Do not worry about it.
Zeke was singing a new tune.
The last was
Bitch Betta Have My Money AMG's.
I'm not in order to stay away from home today.
Let. You know the best way to forget a guy
is find another.
-You will.
-... Show him some love.
Zeke, go here.
Hey, thank you.
Oh my God.
I do not play this song for years...
It is the...
... But it was inspired in a special woman
by whom is worth the wait.
Last night I had a dream about a dream
About Me
-I gotta get away.
-Mya!
Mya!
Mya, you can expect? Mya?
Do you think
going to sing a song and all will be forgotten?
Do not! Just thought it could be a start.
You know what?
You can not change the nature of a person.
That is not true.
I know that is not true.
-How?
-Because I want to start over.
I want another 90 days.
No sex?
If you need to.
I do not want sex, Mya. I want you.
That's bullshit.
Sure, it's bullshit. Yes!
Course I want sex.
But sex was all I wanted
before you know it. Now,
want you.
Right?
Now? I want coffee.
I want to stay up all night talking about his childhood
mad. I want to...
I do not know.
I want to talk about the Myth of the Cave of Aristotle.
It is in Plato.
Plato also had caves?
Yes
Mya, I love you.
I'm in love with you.
Never told anyone in my life.
Why not say so?
It turns out that my epiphany had a domino effect.
All were committed to their wives. Really.
I did not catch anything.
Candace?
His mother told me that you're still single.
Do not worry,
I think I have a solution.
I have someone in my office that
will be ideal for you. Her name is Amy.
It? She does not play the other team.
She might want to try.
Mother!
Thank you, Duke. You can leave me.
-Hi, girls.
-Look at that face!
Good to see you all.
What are you doing here?
I had to go to church?
It had.
And then? It was canceled?
No. Why all these questions, woman?
I just thought you needed to be there.
Why would I be there when he needed to be here
,
number one with the woman of my life?
While you're thinking so much,
Why do not you think
get me a hamburger in
with pickles and mustard?
Sorry,
you say'' number one''?
So do not believe?
Wait a minute.
Ladies and gentlemen. Excuse me.
I need attention.
Hey, guys... That '.
Thank you.
My name is Michael Hanover
and want everyone to know
I am madly in love by Candace Hall.
And I want everyone in the world to know
it is the number one woman in my life.
Thanks, guys.
Now back to the meeting!
It was enough for you?
What do you want on your burger?
Do not give a damn girl.
I came for you. Come here.
And then ,
the book had a happy ending for all of us.
Well, almost all of us.
Hey, girl. I have not seen in a while.
I know. Sorry. I've been busy.
What do later today?
Actually,
I have a meeting with James.
He is executive director and I
operations, there is not much time for us.
And what else is new?
Anyway, you have plans for later?
Actually,
three of us go to the opening of Dominic's restaurant.
He found an investor for the restaurant?
She arranged a loan for a mobile restaurant called...
Avenue D.
It is located in Pueblo Plaza.
He ??wants to start small and increase gradually.
Good for him.
Anyway, have fun tonight.
We will .
Thank you.
James, how was your day?
It was good. In fact, it was great.
I told the The Wall Street Journal
did a story about me?
Yes, the...
-'' Whiz kid''. Yeah, I know.
'' The Boy Wonder.''
I know I am no longer a boy,
but I'm the youngest CEO of a
Fortune 500 company.
Yeah, we talked...
Now I'm focusing on the Far East.
Other day I talked to Warren.
Meet Warren Buffett?
Dub-Beezy, my friend.
He was talking about diversification.
So I bought a G6.
One, the company bought a G6.
From New York to LA
costs about $ 60,000.
They spend it whenever I go.
I also talked to my friend, Kobe.
He wanted
I bought an NBA franchise.
I'm fine, James.
Thank you for asking.
Sorry, did not understand.
I know.
I know, but I finally understand.
Right.
Okay, a little bit.
Only one sample for the girls.
Friends, now bring more.
Come on, Don!
Give it to his wife.
To his girl, right, that's it.
Okay, one more?
Here, J.
I'll be back. Thanks for coming.
-I'll be back.
-That is too much.
Next!
I want the chef's special.
Chicken or...
Hey, go to the end of the queue.
-Look, this is personal, not business.
Take your arm!
Congratulations.
It seems to be a great success.
Not been waiting for you.
I could not lose its grand opening.
Ceviche fish?
Sal, the two lasagnas are for travel.
You can leave.
Where is your CEO?
I finished everything.
Dominic!
He ??can have all the money and power in the world
, but has half its potential.
-Stop!
Stop.
Do not need to do it again for me.
I am in charge.
Right?
Thank you for coming,
but I have a business to touch.
I'm sure I can respect that.
-But I would...
-Next!
What's good here, man?
Has the pork less greasy?
Sure.
-I want it.
Dominic?
Excuse. What are you doing?
I want you back, Dominic.
-Staff, just a minute. I know.
-We have to cook it.
I'm sorry.
-What are you doing?
-I want you back.
Look, I'm not an acquisition.
You can not decide...
-I am asking.
-Really? And I'm asking for service.
You'll have your pork sausage,
fat man! Shut up!
Lauren, are very different, right?
Yes, we are different.
But I think that's good.
What you need is status.
Need titles.
-I do not care...
No, I do not care.
Need
is a man who makes me feel special.
Do not care for the title,
and do not care how much you earn
car drives.
I just need you.
Please? I'm sorry.
I think ultimately we want different things.
No.
I disagree.
I think I want the same thing.
What is it?
Well, first,
want my chef's special, not the pig.
Don! Okay, man, no more kissing.
Grab her ass and such.
That's my girl!
Show me something!
Something for me to think tonight.
Know that I am not having much sex.
Gail and I are not so active.
Even Cedric?
Come on.
-Bring your butt here now!
Hey Gail, I was talking about...
Lift your pants, Cedric!
I'm with the guy in purple.
-Hi, I'm Bennett.
-We use our ball?
Let's see on the court! Save for the game!
Listen, little one. Where is your twin?
You will need someone to climb.
That's funny. Very funny.
Ria when my balls are on your back!
'' LlVRO BASED ON HOW TO BEHAVE-
A LADY, THINK LIKE A MAN''
OF STEVE HARVEY
-The ball is in play.
-Oh, shit.
Pass the ball, man!
It will make the defense?
Wait, wait!
Pass!
Just throw the ball.
It is better to get out of here, little one.
Are you okay?
Hey, no jokes.
Good pitch.
Good-pitch?
-It was the same!
-Bennett is a man and push it!
-It was a good pitch.
Stir with someone your own size.
Oh, my knee!
Dude, you have to calm down.
He put his balls in my head.
Where is my help in the defense?
Get out of here!
Bennett! Jeremy!
I'm trying to get my ball back!
Can you give me the ball?
Let them. Let them.
Thank you, guys! -
Go grab.
Hey, we play here every Thursday.
It was not so bad.
Think about it.
Well, that was fun.
It was a good year, folks.