Bad boys, bad boys
Boys will be boys
- Boys will be boys
- Always gettin'so restless
Bad boys, bad boys
- Boys will be boys
- Nothin'but trouble
Bad boys, bad boys
- Boys will be boys
- Get me feeling breathless
Bad boys, bad boys
- Boys will be boys
- Nothin'but trouble
Bad boys, bad boys
Bad, bad, bad, bad boys
You make me feel so good
You naughty
bad, bad, bad, bad boys
You make me feel so good
Knew you would
The way you hold me tight
You get me so excited
You do me, oh, so right
My heart goes beep-beep
beep-beep, beep-beep
Bad, bad, bad, bad boys
You make me feel so good
I want ya
Bad, bad, bad, bad boys
You make me feel so good
Knew you would
- Boys will be boys
- Always gettin'so restless
Bad boys, bad boys
- Boys will be boys
- Nothin'but trouble
Bad boys, bad boys
- Boys will be boys
- Get me feeling breathless
Bad boys, bad boys
- Boys will be boys
- Nothin'but trouble
Bad boys, bad boys
And when he drives me home
I feel safe at night
You call me on the phone
It goes ring, ring, ring
Ring-a-ring-ring
Bad, bad, bad, bad boys
You make me feel so good
I want ya
Bad, bad, bad, bad boys
You make me feel so good
Knew you would
Boys will be boys
Bad boys, bad boys
- Boys will be boys
- Always gettin'so restless
Bad boys, bad boys
- Boys will be boys
- Nothin'but trouble
Bad boys, bad boys
- Boys will be boys
- Get me feeling breathless
Bad boys, bad boys
- Boys will be boys
- Nothin'but trouble
Bad boys, bad boys
- Boys will be boys
- Always gettin'so restless
Bad boys, bad boys
Boys will be boys
- Good evening.
- Is this the penthouse?
- Yes, ma'am.
- On the roof.
Welcome to another edition of
Lifestyles of the Average and Anxious.
We move about the apartment
of Peter Mitchell...
young architect about town.
It's his late 30s... Or is it his
early 40s? We'll never know...
- birthday party!
- Hi!
Entranced by
the euphoria and ease...
these glamourous people exude...
I think I spy
the birthday boy himself.
Peter!
How are you, old chum?
You're looking so well, so well.
Over here is his semi-main squeeze,
Rebecca Davidson.
The public wants to know
what an attractive,
witty, successful woman sees...
in a bozo like my roommate.
Well, he's, um,
he's charming and he's sweet.
He's very thoughtful.
He's sort of boyishly handsome.
But he has got
the most amazing...
- Thank you, Rebecca.
- You're welcome, Michael.
So, Peter, tell me, are you
and Rebecca still exclusive? Hmm?
- Me and Rebecca?
- Yeah.
- No, we both see other people.
- Oh, really? Oh.
- Yeah, a lot.
- Oh, that's nice to know.
- Bye, Vanessa.
- Bye.
- Hey, uh, birthday boy.
- Oh, hi, Adam.
- Rebecca's looking sexier than ever.
- Yeah.
- You two, uh, still together?
- Oh, yeah. Me and Rebecca
for fıve years now.
- Tight. Tight as ever. Excuse me.
- Cool.
- Good lovin'
- Gimme that good, good lovin'
- All I need is good lovin'
- Good lovin'
- James!
- Yeah, baby.
- Remember the Young Rascals?
What happened to them?
- Man, they old.
- No, don't say that.
- Real old.
- I think one of them's a senator now.
- No, God, no, no!
- A real old senator!
- Jack. Jack. Can I talk
to you for a minute?
Paul, I'm serious. I'm not doing
commercials any more. Really.
No more talking T-bones
or cowboys with heartburn.
I'm only doing serious stuff now.
- Hi. How are ya?
- Oh, Jack.
Whew! Angela. Whew, boy,
you look different. What happened?
- I'm dressed.
- That's it. That's it.
Everybody gather 'round now
Move your body to the beat
Gentlemen, I'm in love.
- You?
- Yeah. In a generic sense.
- Right. Right.
- Oh, my. Oh.
- So many women...
- And so little time.
So little time, yeah.
- So, Jack.
- Yeah, what's up?
- You're not really gonna
do this movie in Turkey, are ya?
- Yes. Yes, I am.
As a matter of fact, I leave
in a few short hours. Here.
- What is it, uh, Zalmon the Beautician?
- Barbarian. Zalmon the Barbarian.
I knew you were gonna say that.
Okay, well, what about the play in Soho?
The one you said you wanted to do.
- You said it was a chance to...
- Uh, excuse me, please.
Excuse me. You said it was
a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
- Hi.
- Oh, come on.
What d... What do you want,
my inevitably brilliant reviews,
or, uh, next month's rent?
Forget about next month's rent.
I'll cover you, you do the play.
That's sweet of you. You know,
you are a very decent man, Peter.
- I'm a goddamned saint.
- "Saint" is a little bit much, but...
Hey, how's it goin', baby?
Name's Johnny. Gimme fıve.
Ooh, I mean, gimme three.
Yeah. Yeah.
I can't believe you draw Johnny Cool.
Coolest cat in the world, right?
No one cooler, baby.
I can't believe it.
Makes me so happy.
- What's wrong?
- It's David.
- The guy you broke up with?
- The good-looking one.
Incredibly good-looking.
He used to read me Johnny Cool
every morning over breakfast.
Hey. Hey, hey.
Oh, you poor baby.
You know how
to get over a lover, hmm?
Dance with a stranger.
David's an incredible dancer.
He studied for three years
with the Joffrey Ballet.
Three years? Joffrey Ballet?
I think you guys
are gonna get back together.
You think that I could call him up
and invite him to the party?
Uh, yeah, uh...
Come on, shake your body
Baby, do that conga
I know you can't
control yourself any longer
Feel the rhythm of the beat
It's getting stronger
Don't you fight it
till you try to do that conga beat
Twins!
There it is.
Yeah! Arguably one of the best
clutch shots of all time.
Forget the guys playing today.
Nobody played this game better
than Reed, West, Chamberlain, Baylor.
I'll run it for you again
in slow motion.
People are asking for you.
Come on, let's go mingle.
I hate that word. It sounds like
something sea lions do before they mate.
You are the guest of honour,
and they love you.
Of course they do,
but these guys need me in here.
Don't you need me in here, guys?
- Go on, get outta here.
- Leave your money.
- Yeah, we need that.
- Wait, there it is.
- Yeah!
- Undoubtedly, the greatest clutch shot
in basketball history.
...clutch shot in basketball...
- Unarguably.
- In slow motion.
The best.
Oh, Paul, Paul. Wait, wait.
Listen to me, man.
You are my friend.
You're a great director.
But I am not doing commercials
ever again. I mean it.
Jack, I don't want you to do
a commercial. I need a favour.
Oh. Yeah, all right, shoot. What?
I'm having a package delivered tomorrow,
but I won't be home to get it.
I gotta go off to San Francisco all week
on a commercial shoot.
- You're gonna shoot in San Francisco?
- Yeah.
- Who are you using?
- Oh, Len Peters.
Lenny. Lenny. What's wrong? Didn't you
like my last dog food commercial?
Oh, Jack, that was a classic.
But now look,
I was hoping that I could have
this package delivered here instead.
Sure, no problem. No problem.
Listen, let me ask you something here.
- Do you think I'm overexposed?
- Overexposed? Oh, no, Jack, not at all.
Now look, it'll be delivered tomorrow
and picked up by a couple of guys
on Thursday morning.
- That's all there is to it.
- All right. Tomorrow, pick up Thursday.
Okay, but this is... this is
a very delicate matter, Jack, so don't
mention it to anybody, all right?
- All right, yeah. Delicate.
- Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, dear Peter
Happy birthday to you
He's so shy.
- Speech! Speech!
- Oh, look, um...
First of all, um, uh...
I wanna thank, uh,
Jack and Michael and Rebecca...
for, uh, embarrassing me
with this unending flow of sentiment.
- Oh!
- I, uh...
- Thanks for coming.
- Hey, all right! All right!
- Go on! Blow out the candles! Quick!
- Whoa! Whoa!
I think everybody had a great time.
Don't you?
I sure did.
Why don't you stick around a while?
I thought sentiment
made you uncomfortable.
- I can handle it...
- Mm-hmm.
As long as it's disguised as sex.
So stay tonight.
I can't.
- I have to be up at 7:00
for a pretrial meeting.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
Happy birthday, Peter. Mmm.
Yeah, right.
It was a great party.
You know, in this light
you're kinda ugly. Yeah.
Yeah, that rut
in the middle of your forehead?
Gettin' out of hand. Out of hand.
- How come that always happens to you?
- What?
Well, as soon as you get
a woman into your room...
you turn into her big brother
and start solving her problems.
Well, unlike yourself and our
sexually insatiable roommate...
I happen to be a sensitive guy,
and I have more on my mind
than simply pronging chicks.
Hey, guys. Say, what's a good year
for pronging chicks?
The '82 bordeaux on the left
works every time.
Thank you very much.
- What happened here? Somebody die?
- Rebecca left early.
- Oh.
- Michael saved another
doomed relationship.
Post-party depression.
Listen, you guys, you know,
I'm outta here tomorrow for ten weeks.
What do you say
I get rid of Cherise...
No, no, the three of us
hunker down here with a bottle of wine
and shoot some pool.
I got a better idea.
Why don't you two guys hunker down,
shoot some pool, and I'll, uh, take...
- No, no, no.
- Why don't you just go
and have a good time?
- Yeah, enjoy yourself.
- Oh, guys.
Tough job, but it's gotta be done.
Oh.
- He's unbelievable.
- The man is one giant gland.
- Jack.
- Seventy-nine.
- Jack!
- He left already, Cherise. Eighty.
- Hi, this is Peter, Michael and Jack.
- Great. I think he took my mousse.
- We're out playing
and can't come to the phone.
- That's our boy. Eighty-two.
- We'll call you back as soon as we can.
- So leave a message
at the sound of the tone.
- Thanks, Peter. See you around.
Yeah. Eighty-four.
Hi, it's me, Jack. Uh, I'm at the
airport just about to board the plane.
But I forgot to tell you something.
There's a package
gonna be delivered today.
Uh, some guys'll pick it up
Thursday before noon.
Just put it aside, don't worry about it.
And, oh, wait a minute.
It's, uh, it's a very delicate
matter, so don't, don't say
anything to anybody. Okay?
I'll bring you guys something back
from Turkey if you're good.
Maybe a drumstick or somethin'.
- See you later. Bye-bye.
- Ninety.
- Hi, Harry.
- Good morning, sir.
Michael! Michael, get out here!
- What is it?
- Just get out here.
What?
- What's goin' on?
- I don't know. What's goin' on?
Oh, okay.
Just look out in the hall.
- Yeah?
- Just look out in the hall.
Okay.
- That's a baby.
- Oh, I know it's a baby.
- What's it doing there?
- It's sleeping.
Oh, okay. Who do you
suppose it belongs to?
Oh, Peter, there's a little note.
All right, I'll just go in and...
okay, play along.
"Dear Jack, here is our baby..."
Oh, no.
- You really don't know
anything about this?
- I knew it.
I knew it. I knew this was gonna
happen to him sooner or later.
- "I can't handle this now.
I don't know where else to turn.
- Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm. Right.
- "Someday I hope
you can both forgive me.
- Unbelievable.
Her name is Mary. Love, Sylvia."
Who's Sylvia?
How am I supposed to know?
You have to be a social secretary
to keep track of all his women.
He left a message about a package.
He said it'd be delivered today.
He said to put it aside
and not to worry about it.
- He said that about a baby?
- I'd say he takes his procreation
business a little lightly.
- So what are we supposed
to do about this?
- We pick it up.
- You pick it up.
- I'm not picking it up.
You found it!
- Look, we gotta do something.
One of us has to pick it up.
- Well, it's not gonna be me!
Now what? I don't know anything
about taking care of babies.
Well, neither do I!
- Look, we gotta do something!
- Be my guest.
- Hey, it's not my responsibility.
- It's not mine either!
- Don't yell at me, Peter.
- Well, it can't be that diffıcult.
All we gotta do is, is feed it.
It'll shut up.
- Well, I don't know what babies eat.
- Soft stuff.
I mean, we were babies once, for God's
sake. What did... What did we eat?
I don't know. It couldn't have been
very good. I can't remember.
- Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Where you goin'?
- I'm going to the market
to get some baby food.
We can't feed it birthday cake
and goat cheese.
- So what am I supposed to do?
- Entertain it.
"Entertain it."
Entertain it?
How do you entertain a baby?
Hey, junior. Hey, look.
L-Look at my hands. Hey.
Hey. Look at this. Look at this.
Oh, it's a... it's a gla... it's a prism.
Whoa. Look at those colours, huh?
This is nice stuff, huh? This is
expensive. You don't like that, huh?
Well, how about, uh... Oh! Ooh, look!
It's almost like, uh...
Look, Japanese origami, almost,
with the hands.
It's a bird! It's a bird!
No, huh?
Uh... Uh... I'm gettin' a headache.
You're givin' me a headache.
Uh, how about, uh... how about this?
How about this? Look at this.
Look at the hairy chest.
You like that? You like that?
You wanna... You want one of these?
Price check!
Excuse me. Uh, where could I
get a jar of baby food?
- Uh, third aisle to the right.
- Right.
- Joe, I need a cheque okay on three.
- It's the larger size?
- Got it.
- This is cheaper.
- Oh.
They gotta be kidding.
What's happenin', baby?
How you doin' today, huh?
My name is Johnny.
That's right. That's right.
But you can call me Mr Cool.
You know what I'm sayin'?
Hey, wh-what's your name, huh?
Huh? Haven't I seen you
around the neighbourhood?
Come on, baby, wh... Wait, what's
the matter? Cat got your tongue?
Why can't you talk? Huh? Huh?
Come on, kid, laugh it up.
I'm doin' my best.
Mr Foley, I need
a cheque okay on two.
Excuse me. Uh, is this
a good meal for a baby?
- That's for toddlers.
- Toddler? What's a toddler?
- Ayear and half, two years.
- No, no, l-I need something for a baby.
- This is your fırst.
- First what?
- Baby.
- Uh, yeah. First and the last.
- No matter how much you prepare, you're
never quite ready for 'em, are you?
- No, you're not.
- Um, listen, could you... Can you hel...
- Did you know that what an infant eats
in its fırst 12 months...
can determine its entire
psychological and physical future?
That's fascinating,
but all I need is some food.
Just some food, that's all, uh, Edna.
- What's the best-selling brand?
- That white can over there.
- Great. This is the best, then?
- No, it's the cheapest.
That's why it sells the most.
- Uh-huh. How about this one, then?
- Oh, that's good.
- Good.
- But it's got iron in it.
- Is that bad?
- It is if your baby's allergic to it.
- How do you know
if she's allergic to it?
- They throw up all over you.
Of course, they throw up all over you
even if they're not allergic to it too.
Some babies can't hold anything down
for more than a minute.
- What about this one?
- That's for older babies.
How old's your baby?
- About that old.
- You don't know how old your baby is?
Yes, I do. I know...
I know how old my baby is.
- Is she teething?
- Teething?
Well, you know, uh,
does she cry all night?
Does she chew on her fıst
and drool a lot?
All right, okay, then I'll take three of
these and I'll take some of these, and
thanks very much for your time, Edna.
You've been a source of great stress.
Don't forget, if the baby's
less than three months old,
you gotta sterilize the nipples.
Aw, shit!
Here I come!
Hey, hey, hey, look, I'll, uh... I'll
give you ten bucks if you stop crying.
Huh? Ten bucks. Huh? You like that?
Hey, I'm gonna pick you up now, huh?
Here you go, junior. Here you go.
Is that better? No, huh?
All right, well, how about,
uh, how about a little walk, huh?
How about a little walk?
Here, hey, wait a minute. Let me...
Let me... Here you go. Here we go.
Okay. Hey, how 'bout this, huh?
There... N-No, no-no, no-no-no.
We're not gonna keep cryin'.
No, no, no, no! No, no!
Hey, wait a minute. Oh, look! Hey!
Rock-a-bye baby
On the treetop
When the bough breaks...
Something and something
Something...
Come on. Where the hell is he,
milkin' the cows or somethin'?
Hey, look. No, no, no, no, no crying.
No, no, no. No... No crying.
Hey, wait a minute. Whoa, ooh, no!
You can... You can drive a guy to drink.
You know that?
No. No, not you.
You're a cute little thing. Yeah, yeah.
Oh, wait a minute. How about...
Hush, little baby, don't you cry
When Peter gets home
I'm gonna punch him in the eye... Hush.
All right... All right, here we are.
Here we are in my room. Yeah.
Look... Look around here.
This is nice, huh?
Uh, uh, maybe you can, uh...
Here, we'll sit down here and, uh...
Oh, look! Look!
We're gonna watch a little TV.
Yeah. Yeah. We'll watch a little TV.
Just you and me, huh?
Here you go. There you go.
Amuse yourself.
Women are wondering:
Are they having an orgasm?
- Men are worried
maybe their penis isn't...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
No, no, no, no, no, you don't want
to hear that. No, no, no, no, no.
Okay, we're gonna have a nice
conversation with Uncle Peter...
and let him have some fun now, yeah?
Yeah, that's a good idea.
Where the hell have you been?
- Oh, hi, Mrs Hathaway.
- Mr Kellam, this package just arri...
- Oh, what a darling little baby.
- Yeah.
- Is it yours?
- No, no, no, no. It's not mine.
- Mr Mitchell's?
- No, no, no, no, no.
Someone sort of loaned it to us.
- W-We're watching her for a while.
- Well, what is its name?
Her name is, uh, it's, uh, Sylvia.
No, Mary. Mary. Mary. Yeah.
Well, we've had a tough morning,
and we're all tuckered out.
We've been drooling, so, uh,
we're gonna just say goodbye, okay?
- Bye-bye, Mrs Hathaway. Bye-bye. Yeah.
- Bye-bye. Bye-bye.
Oh, by the way, um, this package
Just arrived for you downstairs.
Uh, all right, great. Great.
Th-Thanks, Mrs Hathaway.
- Could I hold her for just a minute?
- Oh, I don't think so.
She doesn't really...
I just love babies. Oh, yes.
I just love babies.
Unfortunately, Mr Hathaway and I
were never able to have any of our own.
- Mr Hathaway has a low sperm count.
- Well, some guys have all the luck.
Oh, oh, you are...
You are a cute little bundle,
aren't you?
You do realize she did a doodle.
Yes, you did.
Would you like me to
give you a hand in changing her?
No. No, no, no, I can do it.
L-l-I'm used to it. I'm used to it.
Well, thanks a lot, Mrs Hathaway.
We gotta go now. All right?
So, uh, so we're gonna say bye-bye now.
- All right? Bye-bye. Bye-bye.
- Bye-bye. Bye-bye, Mary.
- Bye-bye. Bye. Bye-bye. Okay, bye.
- Little child.
Of course, if you ever need
anyone to babysit...
All right. Yeah? All right.
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
- Mr Mitchell, she's a lovely baby.
- Yeah, adorable.
Where the hell have you been?
This baby hasn't stopped crying
since you left, and she did a doodle.
"Doodle"? What the hell's that?
No, don't tell me. I don't want to know.
Oh, you're gonna know, pal, 'cause
she did it. What's with all the bags?
I had to go to three different places to
buy four different kinds of formula...
two different kinds of diapers,
bottles, towels, nipples.
You have no idea
how much crap these kids need.
- How old is she, anyway?
- How should I know? You want me
to check her driver's licence?
- Feel her teeth.
- What?
- Just feel her teeth.
The druggist said that you can tell
how old she is by feeling her teeth.
Well, I'm not feeling her teeth!
You feel her teeth!
I'm tired of holding her, anyway! Here!
No! Uh, no, I can't hold her and,
and make her bottle at the same time.
All right, I'll hold her,
you check for the teeth, okay?
- Come on!
- All right.
- I can't feel anything.
- What do you think that means?
- It means she doesn't
have any damn teeth!
- Well, neither did Gabby Hayes,
and he was 90! So what?
All right, then we'll give her
the stuff for newborns,
hope she's not allergic to it.
You have no idea how much stuff
these kids can be allergic to.
What's that stench?
Michael, hold her.
Just hold her. That's it.
- Wait a minute. Peter, this is a girl.
Should we be doing this?
- Michael, just hold her, will ya,
so I can get the diaper off.
- Ohh!
How can something so small create
so much of something so disgusting?
Oh, God. Beats the shit out of me.
All right, hand me the other diaper.
There, take...
- Wait a minute.
Shouldn't we wash her fırst?
- Uh, we'll wash her later.
Just... Well, give me the cotton.
Give me the... Oh!
How about this?
Come on. Uh, Michael, l...
Just give me a little cotton.
- I don't need a package.
I just need some cotton.
- All right, here.
Oh, no, wait, g... The wipies. Get me the
g... the, you know, the cotton wipies.
Right.
Here it is.
- All right.
- Ooh, this is disgusting.
It's all over, and it's, it's...
it's sticky and...
We're gonna need some kind of
cleaning fluid to get it off.
- How about after-shave?
- Aw, come on, Michael!
Just get me one of the diapers!
All right.
All right, good. Now, these tape things
go in the front or the back?
- Uh, how am I supposed to know?
- Okay. There.
Whoa! These diapers are way too big.
- What size did you get, adult?
- They're ultra-absorbent.
The more absorbent the better,
if you ask me.
Will you hold her for a minute?
The kid's going crazy. L...
- I don't want to.
- Come on, Michael!
- Hey, don't pull that so hard.
It's gonna rip.
- I'm not gonna rip it.
Yes, you are.
All right, well, okay, uh, get me
another diaper. I'll use the tape.
I'll use the tape from the diaper,
I'll tape it up.
I'm an architect, for Christ's sakes.
I build 50-storey skyscrapers.
I assemble cities of the future.
I can certainly put together
a goddam diaper.
Take it easy, kid, all right?
There. There. See? It's working.
Piece of cake. There. Yeah.
Nice job, Pete.
The little insect was just waiting
for that diaper to fall off.
I think we're in trouble.
I'm gonna kill Jack.
I'm gonna kill him.
- This is the deal. Yeah, that's it.
- Michael.
- What?
- You're gonna have to wash
where the poop was.
- Now, come on.
- All righty.
- Come on.
- I've got that handled.
- No, no, just...
- Perfect.
- You're not getting
anything off that way.
There. There you go.
- That's clean. Isn't that clean?
- Yeah, right.
- And her... her privates.
- I'll rinse her.
- All right. Rinse her out a little bit.
- There we go.
Okay. This says...
This says "For moisturizing and..."
- Don't use the baby lotion now.
It's lotion.
- Well, it says... -
- It says "Prevents
chapping and chaffıng."
- Just wash the baby.
Well, I should put some in there anyway
Just to sort of make sure she's not...
Okay.
We gotta get some help.
Jack said this is a delicate situation,
that we shouldn't tell anybody.
Can you believe him, putting us through
hell to save his precious reputation?
I'm not doing it any more.
Odds.
Willie, they need you
over here a minute.
Make a little room.
- Well, at least it ain't rainin'.
- You're gonna have a headache.
- Try sleepin' nights, Peter.
Mary, let me have the pen.
Come on. Come on. I'm later than usual
this week for the deadline.
Come here. Okay... Oh!
Actually, Sam, l... I don't seem
to have them here after all.
I must have left them at the offıce,
but, uh, I'll get them
fırst thing in the morning. Right.
Your daddy's a dead man.
- Rebecca, you're...
- Yeah, I came as soon as I got
your messages. What's the emer...
- Who are... Who are you?
- Um...
- Jan.
- This is Jan Clopatz.
This is Peter Mitchell.
- Pleasure to meet you.
- How do you do? Come on.
Jan is a cellist from Hungary.
He's playing with the Brauslau
Baroque Ensemble at Carnegie Hall.
- What a thrill.
- Peter, what's the emergency?
Just come with me.
This is the big emergency.
- It's a baby.
- Why is that the fırst thing
everybody says..."It's a baby"?
Of course it's a baby.
- It's your baby?
- No, it's not my baby.
- It's Jack's baby.
- Jack has a baby?
I realize such a concept
tends to negate our belief
in a benevolent God, but yes.
Well, it doesn't look like Jack.
Jack's got more hair.
I'm glad you can joke at a time
like this. See? She needs to be held.
- Babies like to be held.
- Hmm.
- Where is he?
- Jack? Oh.
Jack's in Turkey, which is where I'd be
if my baby was in New York.
Now look, Rebecca, we're dying here.
Michael doesn't know
anything about babies.
I don't know anything about babies.
On top of that,
I got deadlines hanging all over me.
I've been reading these...
these books about babies.
I can't fıgure it out.
For instance, it says here... Look.
"Feed every two hours." Well, it takes
me two hours to get her to eat anything.
So does it mean feed her
every two hours from when I start?
- Yeah.
- Or every two hours from when I fınish?
Because I've been feeding her
every two hours from when I start,
and I'm feeding her all the time!
- Mmm.
- So which is it?
- Why are you asking me?
- Because you're a woman.
Yeah. That doesn't mean I automatically
know what to do with babies.
Rebecca, now, pl...
please, uh, stay with me and,
and help me take care of her.
- You want me to take care of her.
- Yes.
- Now?
- No, when she graduates from college.
Yes, now.
I can't do that, Peter.
Baby take very,
very much work, huh? Yeah.
Thank you for telling me that, Jan.
I didn't know that.
What is he, an idiot savant?
Rebecca, we... we'll be late and...
Uh... W... Uh... Rebecca, no, now...
Rebecca, please! Stay with me!
- I have got a date.
- Oh?
Oh, excuse me for cramping
your romantic style.
Rebecca, we'll be late, huh?
- Uh, just...
- You can't be serious about this guy.
Oh, come on, Peter. You go out
with other people and so do I.
We agreed to that.
You can go out with the whole damn
string section for all I care.
That's not the issue.
- Right now I need you here.
- Well, I can't be here now.
- Oh! She doodled.
- Doodled!
Yes, doodled! What's the matter?
Don't babies doodle in Hungary?
- We're leaving.
- Uh, Rebecca, no, wait.
Come on, Rebecca, please. Don't go.
Peter, you're a very big boy,
you're very capable...
and you're gonna get through this
Just fıne.
I hate the cello.
Don't.
I keep waiting for Candid Camera
to walk through the door.
- What did you cancel for tonight?
- Box seats at Shea. You?
Dinner with Cheryl.
Two more days.
Where'd you put the baby powder?
I'll get it.
What'd you put it out there for? We're
bathing her in here. You should have
brought it in with her bath stuff.
- It's just down the hall.
- Well, we're not bathing her
in the hall, are we?
Well, maybe we should start, goddam it!
You're going to clean that up.
- What time are those guys
supposed to get here?
- Jack's message said before noon.
Good. I gotta see my editor
about 1:00.
Michael, did you move my blueprints? I
need 'em for my meeting this afternoon.
Sorry.
I think she did a doodle.
Your turn to change her.
I'll give you a thousand dollars
if you'll do it.
Check this out.
What do you know?
Coming! Coming!
- Does, uh, Jack Holden live here?
- Yeah.
- Someone asked us to pick up a package.
- A package?
I love the way everybody
keeps calling it a package.
You can tell Sylvia for us
that she's got a lot of nerve
dumping her problems in our laps.
- Who's Sylvia?
- When it fırst got here,
we considered calling the cops.
- Hey, w... Hey, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Wait. No, no, w...
- But we didn't. We stuck it out, even
though it totally disrupted our lives.
No, you wait. Hey, we haven't
been able to work or to sleep.
- And there's been shit
all over this place for days.
- "Shit"?
- What?
- You mean the package? It busted?
Busted? Yeah.
Yeah, you could say that.
- Well, did you put the shit back?
- Put it back? No, we had it bronzed for
posterity. What do you think we did?
Michael.
Her next bottle's in 45 minutes. I
made it up already. It's in the basket.
- It's a baby.
- You're sharp, aren't ya?
He's all right, huh?
Twenty minutes after she eats,
she gets tired. Put her to bed.
- And I'm getting you a can
of powdered milk.
- Oh, yeah.
- Yeah.
- Right. Powdered milk. Right.
- Yeah, powdered milk.
So, all right, so we'll
take the "powdered milk"
and, uh, we'll get out of here.
What, you want us to take the baby?
That was the arrangement.
- Are you sure that's the plan?
- You're damn straight.
Well, if you say so. Let's go.
- You won't forget what we said?
- No.
And she likes to be
rocked to sleep. Gently.
Gently. Absolutely. Gently.
L-I can handle it.
Maybe you should leave a phone number,
in case you need some advice.
Oh, uh, I'll call you.
Do you hear that, Peter?
Just listen. Isn't it wonderful?
- Isn't what wonderful?
- Quiet.
Peace and quiet.
There's something screwy going on,
Michael. I got a funny feeling.
What are you talking about?
You've been tense the last fıve days.
It's just your nerves unwinding.
Maybe you're right.
Michael.
- Michael, what is this?
- A package.
- When did it get here?
- Sunday.
- Mrs Hathaway br...
- Go to the window.
See if you can stop them.
I gotta try and catch up with them!
Hi. Hello.
Yeah, you're beautiful.
Come on. Wanna go for a ride?
Hey! Hey, up here!
- Where am I gonna put this little baby?
- Right on your lap.
Huh? No, we need
a little baby car seat, I think.
- Put her in the trunk.
- Yeah? You wanna go for a ride
in the car, in the trunk?
Huh? Wanna go in the trunk?
Oh, no. Oh, my God.
Hey, hey. You wanna try this?
It's an adventure.
Why am I listening to you? Why... Why do
I listen to you? I mean, this is absurd.
I can't put a little baby in the trunk.
- Hey!
- It's okay. Yeah.
- Oh, Mr Wonderful.
- Hey!
- Yeah?
- Look, uh, I gave you the wrong package.
- W-W-What wrong package?
What are you talking...
- I made a... I made a terrible mistake.
I gave you the wrong package.
Look, I've got... Give me the baby fırst.
- No. Hey, no... Take it easy. Be gentle.
- Give me the... Give me the baby fırst.
- Give me the baby. Give me the baby.
- Be gentle. You're disturbing the baby.
- Hey, hey, hey, what are you, crazy?
- Give me the baby fırst.
- Look, hey, Satch.
Hey, listen, this guy's an animal.
- Give me the baby! Please!
I keep him chained to the wall.
I feed him raw meat.
- Hey! What's goin' on here?
- Oh, God, it's Roy and Trigger.
- I said, what's goin' on here?
- Nothing, Offıcer.
- You gonna ride
with that kid in the trunk?
- No! Of course not. That's absurd.
I mean, it's unhealthy for the child,
and it's illegal also, I understand.
- No, he's not, Offıcer.
Give me the baby.
- Yeah...
- All right, let me see
your licence and registration.
- Why?
- Yeah, why?
- 'Cause you're double-parked, wise guy!
- Oh. Why... All right.
Wait a minute. What's...
- Give me the baby.
Just be gentle. Be gentle. Be gentle.
- Hey. Stay there.
- One second, Offıcer.
I'll be right with you.
Book! Book! Book! Book!
Hey, come back here! You, freeze!
I have no intention of moving, Offıcer.
I'm not a criminal, I'm an architect.
- W-With a baby. See?
- Ah, let me see some I.D.
Oh, yeah, sure.
- I don't have any with me.
- Up against the car. Spread 'em.
Uh, Offıcer, look, uh, uh,
my wallet's up in my apartment.
It's right up there. You can
come up with me. You're welcome to.
Uh, uh, l-I'll some you some I. D,
but I'm not gonna spread 'em because
I have a baby, as you can plainly see.
All right, architect, let's go.
Here we are. Come on in. Can I
get you a cup of coffee or something?
No, thanks.
I'll just wait here by the door.
Michael!
I'll just be a second.
Come with me, Michael.
Here we go. I'm coming.
Uh, just listen. The package
those guys came for is full of drugs.
- What?
- Drugs. All right, here.
- Coming. Do something with it.
- Like what?
Hide it. I gotta show him some I.D.
I'm coming.
- Sorry to keep you waiting.
There you are.
- Would you mind removing that
from the cover, please?
- Well, sure.
- Thank you.
Shh, shh. Shh, shh. Shh, shh, shh.
Shh. Sure. Shh. Shh. Shh.
Thanks for coming up, Offıcer.
I hope it hasn't been an inconvenience.
And if there's anything else
I can do for you, just let me know.
I was just doin' my job.
Hi. I'm Detective Sergeant Melkowitz,
Narcotics.
Offıcer, you can go down
and saddle up now.
- Yes, sir.
- I'll handle this.
Aren't you gonna ask me in?
Can I, uh, get you a cup of coffee,
some water, a beer?
No, no. No, thanks, I'm fıne.
Ah.
- You don't mind me asking
a few questions, do you?
- No, not at all.
- Is that your baby
I saw you with downstairs?
- No.
Uh, well, um, it's my roommate Jack's.
Well, who were those two men
I saw you talking to?
Friends. Of the mother's.
They were gonna take her for a ride.
The baby! Baby. Not the mother.
But they couldn't, see,
because they brought the wrong car.
There's no baby seat.
Well, do you mind if I have a look at
that baby? I just love little babies.
She's sleeping.
Sounds like she's awake to me.
Do you mind if I see her?
I don't know. You know,
she doesn't really like strangers.
- She may not be decent.
- Oh, I don't think she'll mind.
Well, there she is.
And she's got a friend.
Oh, yeah,
this is my, uh, other roommate.
Uh, Detective Melkowitz,
this is Michael Kellam.
- Hello.
- Oh, what a cutie.
Do you mind if I hold her?
I just love kids.
Well, I'd rather not, actually.
She's, um...
- Go ahead, Michael. It won't hurt her.
- Uh, well, you know how she is
around people, Peter. She's so...
Michael, will you let him hold her.
He's not gonna hurt her.
He's a police offıcer.
- All right.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
Oh. Oh.
You're a heavy little girl,
aren't you?
Yes. Yes, she really is heavy,
isn't she?
- She's a good eater.
- Yeah. That's a good sign.
It means she won't grow up
to be a nervous adult.
You've got nothing to be nervous about,
have you, sweetie?
- Feels as though
she's ready for a change.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
- Oh. You know babies.
- Yep.
- All they do is eat, sleep and poop.
- Here, Michael.
- Yeah, I'll take her.
- Good idea.
Oh, what a cute little baby.
Uh, do you happen to know
where her father is at the moment?
- No. Uh, yeah, he's on location,
uh, doing a TV movie.
- Huh?
- But l-I don't have any idea where.
- Uh, do you know this guy?
Oh, not very well. He's a friend of
Jack's. Uh, I don't remember his name.
His name is Paul Milner.
He directs TV commercials.
And on the side, he just happens to
dabble in a little heroin smuggling.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I don't know him. I don't...
I'd appreciate that glass of water now,
Mr Mitchell.
- Of course. No problem.
- Thank you.
I got it.
- Hi, this is Peter...
- Michael...
- and Jack.
- We're out playing
and we can't come to the phone...
- But we'll call you back.
- Shit!
- So please leave a message
at the sound of the tone.
- Hold on. Whoever it is, I'm here.
- Uh, Peter! Jack.
Yeah, how are you? L-Listen, uh,
I got a message saying you're trying
to get through to me. What's up?
Jack, Michael and I really have to
talk to you, but, uh, uh, you called us
at a bad time. We'll call back later.
Wh-whoa, wait a minute! Wait a minute!
Don't hang up. I'm calling from Turkey.
It took me an hour to put this call
through. It's not an easy place
to phone from, you know.
Hey, Peter, this place is amazing.
You will not believe some of the stuff
I bought for you guys.
- Jack!
- I mean, the shit is so cheap here.
I probably bought too much of it,
but what the hell,
I can always smuggle it in.
- Just kidding.
- Jack, thanks for calling.
Uh, and we'll see you when you get back.
I gotta get him a glass of water
so his mouth doesn't go dry
when he reads me my rights.
- Here you are, Sergeant.
- Oh, thanks.
Goodbye.
Nice talking to you.
It was very illuminating.
- He heard the phone call.
- We're dead.
- You think Jack's involved in this?
- I don't know.
We gotta talk to Paul Milner.
- Why him?
- Because he is involved.
Couldn't you think of somewhere better
to hide the drugs?
Hey, it was perfect until you insisted
that he hold the baby.
All right, you're right, Michael.
I'm sorry. Where'd you put 'em now?
In the garbage pail
under the other dirty diapers.
Nobody's gonna look for it there.
You realize we're in trouble
with this cop.
You realize, of course, that
no one's coming back to get this kid.
...is not in service.
- Jesus, you're right.
We're stuck with her
until Jack gets back.
It's disconnected.
- Oh, I'm late.
- Wait a minute, wait a minute, so am I.
Oh, damn it.
Mr Kellam?
Mr Mitchell?
- Hello, Mrs Hathaway.
- Oh, Mr Mitchell.
It seems that a horse
has befouled the front walk.
Do you know anything about it?
- Mrs Hathaway, how nice to see you.
- Really nice to see you.
Oh.
- She can sit till 5:00.
- Well, I'll try and hurry.
Me too. I'm worried.
- I got the one with the mustache.
- I'll call Sergeant Melkowitz
and tell him we're moving.
Right.
There.
Here you go, pal.
What can I do for ya?
I'd like, uh, Sports Illustrated,
Popular Science, some of this gum...
and that giraffe up there.
- Which one's the giraffe?
- The rubber one.
That's not a giraffe.
That's a dinosaur.
- Whatever.
- You mean the one with
the little polka dots up there?
- Yes, uh, thank you.
- That's a dinosaur.
A giraffe has big ears.
- I don't care whether it has ears
or not. Just give me the damn thing.
- It's got little ears. It's a dinosaur.
- Hey, what about your change?
- Never mind.
- What about your change, pal?
He left at 4:00.
He'll be back on Thursday.
Mrs Hathaway.
Mrs Hathaway, I'm home.
Mrs Hathaway, where's Mary?
- I don't know. I don't know.
- Where's Mary?
Mary?
Oh, my God.
Mary! Mary!
Mary.
Mary!
Thank God.
No, everything's fıne, darling.
Everything's fıne.
Don't you worry.
Nobody's gonna hurt you.
No. It's okay.
Peter? Peter!
She's okay. She's not hurt.
- How are you?
- I'm fıne. Just...
See what those bastards did
to my videotapes?
We got a message.
What'd it say?
"Next time we'll take the baby."
- It's okay. It's okay.
- Mr Kellam.
Mr Mitchell!
"The champ caught Smith
with a savage left hook...
"that sent the challenger
crashing into the ropes.
"Smith, his left eye swollen
and the cut above his right eye
now much more bloody...
countered with a barrage
of vicious body blows."
- What are you reading her?
- It doesn't matter what I read.
It's the tone you use.
She doesn't understand the words anyway.
Now, where were we?
"The champ began the fıfth round...
"like a man possessed...
"going straight for
his opponent's body...
with ferocious energy."
Here you go, darlin'.
Stupid... I can't believe...
My face! Watch out for my face!
Peter, it's me, Jack!
- Jack!
- Jesus, Jack!
- Get up!
- No, wait...
- W-What are you... Get him off!
- You irresponsible... Come here!
- What is it with you guys?
- We should be asking you that question!
- Why? What'd I do?
- What the hell are you doing
back so soon anyway?
- My part got cut. Okay?
- Good!
What is with him? Wh... Je...
Look at this place.
Will somebody please tell me
what the hell is goin' on around here?
- Oh, shit!
What was that?
No, I'm not goin' anywhere
until you tell me what's goin' on.
- We'll be glad to.
- That really hurt, Peter.
- Ow, ow, ow.
- Sunday morning
I come back from jogging...
to fınd this basket with this baby in it
waiting in the vestibule.
- Well, why...
- Inside is a little note
from a Sylvia...
saying that the baby was yours
and she was leaving it here
for you to deal with it.
- M-Mine?
- Then along comes another little
package with your name on it...
only this time
the package has heroin in it...
and the narcotics squad permanently
camped downstairs knows all about it.
The cops? I don't believe this.
I don't know anything about any drugs
or any police.
I mean, I thought
I was just doing a favour for Paul.
I didn't know what was in that package.
And I certainly don't know anything
about that baby.
I mean, for God's sake, somebody
drops a baby off on, on your doorstep,
and you automatically assume he's mine?
Look, the child doesn't look
anything like me.
I'm bigger and, and I have more hair.
"Dear Jack, Here is our baby.
I can't handle this now.
I don't know where else to turn. S..."
Sylvia? Oh, my...
Oh, my God. Stratford.
Ayear and a ha...
Ayear and a half ago.
I was doing Taming of the Shrew.
She was the shrew.
I mean, I did some of
my best work in that.
- I got great reviews.
- Jack, you're such a jerk.
- You're always thinkin' about yourself.
I wanna kill you.
- Michael, you won't have to.
Jack, I would like to introduce you
to your daughter Mary.
Now, wait a minute. Wait a minute,
you guys. You can't be sure
that this is my kid. Uh... Um...
- What the hell am I
supposed to do with it?
- We've put our lives on hold, Jack,
taking care of this kid...
and now it's your turn.
Okay. All right. All right, fıne.
All right, until I straighten this mess
out, I'll, uh, I'll take care of her.
I mean, sure, why not?
I'm an actor.
I can, uh, I can do a father.
Yeah. Yeah. See, huh?
What could be so diffıcult, huh? Yeah.
- Goodnight, Jack.
- Goodnight. Goodnight.
Oh. Down we go.
W-W-Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
What-What's the matter with her?
- Goodnight, Jack.
Hold still, kid. Gee... Hey, how do you
put on these goddam things anyway?
Figure it out for yourself,
dickhead.
- Nice shot.
- Look at that stuff. Oh, my God!
What are you guys feeding her, huh?
Oh, no, no, please!
Not on the silk sheets.
Not on the silk sheets. Please, please!
Maybe I should show him
how to put on the diaper.
Oh, no. I don't believe this.
Why me? Oh, come on, baby.
Nope. Let's give him
another half hour.
Let him suffer.
Yes, yes, I'm trying
to reach Paul Milner.
No, he was supposed to be
in San Francisco, but I can't fınd him.
Wo-Would you please tell him to call
Jack Holden as soon as he gets in?
- Is this urgent?
- Yeah, urgent's an understatement.
Lady.
I don't know why I bother giving you
this. It just goes right through you.
- Did you get a hold of your friend?
- No.
- Don't forget to bolt the door.
- I won't.
And remember, there's
a quarter of a million dollars
in heroin in that diaper pail.
- And the new baby wipes
are in the cabinet.
- Right.
Heroin's in the diaper pail.
Baby wipes are in the cabinet.
Where else would they be?
I can't believe this.
You're kidding me. Thirty-two
Benningtons i-in the London area?
Yes, sir.
Uh, uh, uh, I'll get back to you.
L-l...
Oh, boy.
Oh, baby. Look, l-I know.
I know. I know. Yes.
Yes, yes, yes.
Oh, God. Y-Yeah.
Well, we tried your mommy.
Maybe I should, uh...
Maybe I should try mine, huh?
Yeah.
Mom?
- Well, where is she?
- Oh, Mom, wait till you see her.
Oh, you won't believe this.
She is so beautiful.
She looks just like you.
- You know, you boys live like pigs.
- Oh, Mom.
Look, look. There.
Isn't she beautiful?
There she is.
Look at that little baby!
- Yeah.
- You're such a pretty little girl.
Will you come to me?
I'm gonna pick you right up.
- Yes, I'm gonna pick you right up.
- Oh, I am in awe. I mean, look at you.
You-You pick her up like a pro.
I pick her up like a grandmother.
It's called experience.
Darling.
Let's see you. Oh, she's so lovely.
What's her name?
- Mary.
Well, Mary!
Look at the way
she's looking at me.
- For a moment there, I had her laughing.
- Yeah, just like me, huh?
Don't ruin this for me, Jack.
- Oh!
- Oh, she adores you!
- You... Well, well, well.
- She knows that you're her grandmother.
It's like a... It's like a biological
thing, an instant connection.
Cut the crap, Jack.
What do you want?
Mom, I can't take care of her.
I don't know what to do.
I was kinda hoping that... that maybe you
could take her, just for a little while.
Not forever. You know,
until she's ready to vote.
Oh, I would love to.
Do you know, Jack?
Some people live all their lives...
without having anything as wonderful
as this to show for it?
- I know, Mom.
- So I'm gonna do the most wonderful
thing in the world for you.
Absolutely nothing.
Why?
Jack, you've always run away
from responsibility.
Now you have to turn and face it.
Mom, I'm a screw-up.
You were a screw-up.
Now you're a father.
And you'll be a fıne one.
- You think so?
- I know it.
Your father, God rest his soul...
he was a screw-up
and he turned out just fıne.
- Really?
- Don't you remember?
- Well, yeah, I guess.
- Now, give me a kiss.
Mary, give me a kiss.
And now, you and your friends
clean this place up.
If not for yourselves,
do it for my granddaughter.
- We-We will. We will.
- Bye.
Bye. Thanks anyway, Mom.
Well, looks like it's just
you and me now, kid.
What? Mama.
Oh, Jack? There's four bottles
prepared already.
So you should be fıne
till tomorrow morning.
And if her bottom gets red,
you just give her a bottle of water.
Works miracles.
In about three hours, white as marble.
We'll be in seats D-11,
12, 13 and 14.
Yeah, if there's a problem, just call.
The usher will come and get us. Oh!
Here's the number.
- Wait a minute.
Are you leaving right now?
- Yeah, now.
- When are you coming back?
- About midnight.
All right. Don't worry about us.
Wait a minute. Is this a four?
Yeah, it's a four.
It's good to have.
So, uh, what do you want to do?
You know, this show's been running
longer than Mary's been alive?
Peter, we agreed not to mention
her name tonight, right?
- Right. My mistake.
- Who did you guys con
into sitting for you?
- Jack.
- Jack? Daddy?
Patty.
Are you hungry? Huh?
Well, we're in luck here.
Uh, oh-ho-ho!
Tonight, uh, the chef has, uh...
cooked up something
very special for you.
He has taken the juice
of one cow...
and, uh, sauteed it,
uh, with a fıne sauce.
It is, uh, presented
surrounded by a bottle...
and topped off, uh, with
a delicious rubber nipple, huh?
Oh-ho. Yes.
Oh, excellent choice. Yes, yes.
Here we go. Oh, yes.
Wh-What?
Here you go. Come on.
Please?
You don't want it, huh?
Yeah, I just changed you. Huh?
And you're not hungry.
What else is there in life?
I always wanted to be
a musical comedy star.
- Did you ever try?
- No.
Ladies and gentlemen,
act two will begin in three minutes.
Three minutes.
Michael, have you
ever done any acting?
No. No, I leave that to Jack.
The idiot.
I got sunshine on a cloudy day
When it's cold outside
I've got the month of May
I guess you say
What can make me feel this way
My girl
But maybe he fell asleep.
Maybe he fell and hit his head.
He's probably unconscious.
- Will you come on? It's started.
- It's terrible, terrible.
- I had a great time.
- I'll see you at P.J.'s later.
Oh, you can sing us a song
from the second act, okay?
Are they always this strange?
Yes, since they got involved
with another woman.
Wasn't that fun, huh? Yeah.
Oh, cover that.
- Jack?
- Jack, where are you?
- Jack!
- I'm right here. What? What?
- What are you doing?
- Well, what's it look
like I'm doing, Peter?
- Is everything all right?
- Everything's fıne, yeah.
Why you guys back so soon
anyway, huh?
Uh, we thought that we might
have left the stove on.
No, no. The stove's not on.
I think that Uncle Peter
and Uncle Michael are having
a nervous breakdown, yes.
I called, Jack.
I let the phone ring for fıve minutes.
- Why didn't you answer the phone?
- Well, because Mary and I
were taking a shower.
Weren't we?
Yeah, we didn't hear anything.
Yeah. Yeah.
Isn't that the truth, mademoiselle?
Yes.
Oh, you are cute, yes.
I never put a phone
in a shower before.
- You get many calls in here?
- A steady stream.
- What if you slipped down there?
- Well, I did try.
- We did pretty well
for the fırst time out.
- Yeah.
- Here.
- What?
"Commercial director hospitalized
after mugging."
- What?
- Yeah, take a look at this.
This is your friend, Paul Milner.
"Don't let this happen to you.
"Be at the phone booth at the corner
of 81 st and Columbus...
at exactly 8:00 p.m. Tonight."
They're trying to intimidate us.
I hate that.
- I've had enough of this doo-doo.
- I want to fınish this, okay?
Hello?
Yeah, we got your message.
Uh-uh. No good.
We do it our way.
Because we got the stuff,
and if you don't do it our way...
- Come on.
- Say it, say it.
We flush it down the toilet!
Okay, now listen, and listen good.
There's a... a construction site.
Car 20 following suspects,
southbound Central Park West.
Come on, Peter!
- Damn it, Joe! We lost 'em!
- I got it. Three blocks, turn around.
That was great. That was great.
Everybody remember what they're
supposed to do?
Oh, come on, Peter.
It's not that complicated a plan.
Yeah, next he's gonna want us
to synchronize our watches, right?
Should we do that?
Yes, thank you.
Hello, Sergeant Melkowitz.
Uh, my name is Jack Holden.
I think you know my two roommates.
I must have been crazy
to agree to this. Goddam.
- Orange elevator. Here it is.
- Right.
Close door.
- Okay, 15, please.
- Fifteen?
Yeah. I'm all fılthy
and everything.
What's wrong, my sweetheart?
Come here. What is it, huh?
Sweetie.
Oh. Well, you should have
told me before we left.
Oh, boy, this is not a...
this is not a good time to do this.
Hold still.
Oh, you make such a...
There you go.
Michael.
They're here.
- Hey, look. Hey, you know,
this is really aggravating.
- I'm here.
- I'm here by the pipes.
- You know, I don't have
a lot of time, but, uh...
- Hold it.
- What, what, what?
- Hold it! All right, just hold it.
Look, where is the stuff?
Will you give it to me?
- It's in the elevator.
- Oh, bullshit.
Uh, i-it's in the control panel.
Uh, check for yourself.
What am I supposed to do,
bring my handy little tool kit here?
You realize that, uh...
we had absolutely nothing
to do with this.
We had no idea
what was in the package.
Yeah, no kidding. I mean, I could have
fıgured that out in about four seconds.
I mean, you know, you guys
don't behave like a couple of pros.
- You know what I mean?
- Right.
- Yeah.
- We're not pros.
- I just said that, didn't I?
I'm sensitive to that.
I mean, why do you make it
so complicated?
- We've never done this.
- I got it.
- Great.
You're forgiven this time.
Very wise of you to cooperate,
fınally.
- Glad it's over.
- No-No happier than I am, believe me.
I mean, dealing with, uh, amateurs
is a real pain in the ass.
- So is dealing with professionals.
- No doubt.
Hey, what is that?
- What, are you abusing
my trust here or what?
- Whoa!
- There's someone in there!
- Come on.
Come on, Michael.
- Oh, no.
- Oh, look... look out.
- I lost my balance.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
- Did you get it?
- Yeah. Yeah, I got it!
- We got 'em!
Who's doing this? Huh?
I want that camera, punk!
- There's six switches!
- Aw, these guys wrecked my day.
- Jack!
- What the hell happened?
- He hit the wrong button.
- He what?
- Can it go any faster or what?
- This is it.
- Huh? Come on. You punks!
- Jack!
- Nowhere to run, nowhere to hide.
I want that home movie.
I'll wait for you. I want that movie.
- Oh, no.
- Jack!
- Hit the button on the left!
- The button on the left, Jack!
- What? What?
- Hit the button on the left!
There is no left. The le...
- Come on, get it going faster,
will ya? Is that it?
- I can't.
Please.
- Hey, why are we stopped?
What's the matter? Huh?
- I don't understand.
- Why is this elevator stopped?
- What do you want? It's dead.
The whole thing's no good.
I got 'em!
- It ain't running.
It just ain't running.
- What's going on?
- Did you hit the button? Jesus.
- Yeah, it's dead.
- Oh, boy.
Uncle Peter and Uncle Michael are
gonna be plenty ticked off with Daddy.
- Aren't you glad he's on our side?
- What happened? What happened?
Can you get...
You wait for me.
I know where you live, man!
- Oh, no, no, Vince.
- Oh, why? Why is this happening?
- Oh, no!
- Why is this happening? Why?
Okay. It's okay, guys. It's okay.
Hi. Um, are you Sergeant Melkowitz?
- Yeah.
- Oh, good.
- Are you... Are you the father?
- Yes. Yes, yes, I am.
Hey! Oh, thanks for the phone call.
Oh, actually it was, uh,
Peter's idea. Hi, guys.
- She's okay, she's okay.
- Hello, Sergeant.
- The guys you want are in that elevator.
- The drugs are up there too.
- Everything you need
to know is right here.
- It's very illuminating.
Oh, thanks. Thanks a lot.
If I have any questions,
I know where to reach you guys.
- Yeah.
- Okay, fellas.
- Let's get 'em, Jimmy.
- Hey, can I hold the baby, huh?
- No.
- Oh, I guess not.
When the sun goes down
and it's getting late
You say it's time for bed
Shejust takes her time
acting like she never
Heard a word you said
Little baby
want to hold you tight
She don't ever wanna
say goodnight
She's in love
She want to be Daddy's girl
When the morning comes
and it's time to go
Start another day
She won't let you leave
and she does her best
Try to make you stay
Pretty baby
gonna start to cry
She don't ever wanna
say goodbye
She's in love
She want to be Daddy's girl
She don't ever wanna be
without you
Never have to worry
She won't doubt you
Then she puts her head
upon your shoulder
- Says she'll marry you
when she gets older
- Go again, please.
- I will see you burn in hell.
- You'll see me where?
- In hell. You heard me.
- Yes, and where will you be...
while I'm burning in hell?
I'll tell you where I'll be,
you silly bitch.
I will be in Niagara Falls,
that's where.
Can you say "Michael"?
Michael.
Huh? Yeah.
Can you say "Michael"?
Michael. Michael.
She won't understand
why you're feeling sad
'Cause she's leaving you alone
Little woman gonna make you cry
You don't ever
wanna say goodbye
She's a lady
She'll always be Daddy's girl
Little woman
gonna break your heart
- She's a lady
- One bottle, please. One bottle.
- She'll always be Daddy's girl
- Bottle.
- Bottle, please. Bottle. Here it comes.
- Always be Daddy's girl
She'll always be Daddy's girl
Shh. I know, I know, I know, I know.
I know, I know. Yes, yes, yes.
- What's the matter?
- I don't know. She just... She doesn't
seem to want to stop crying.
That's not like her.
- Well?
- Let's give it a try.
Really? All right. I'll, uh...
Goodnight, sweetheart
Well, it's time to go
I hate to leave you
but I really must say
Goodnight, sweetheart
Goodnight
Well, it's 3:00
In the morning
Baby, I just can't treat you right
Well, I hate to leave you, baby
I don't mean maybe
Because I love you so
Goodnight, sweetheart
Well, it's time to go
I hate to leave you
but I really must say
Goodnight, sweetheart
Goodnight
I didn't know you sang so well.
Well, you know, it, uh,
kind of helps her sleep.
This is having quite an effect on you.
You gonna have any more kids?
I don't want to talk about it,
Rebecca. Goodnight.
Peter, I'm having
a lot of trouble sleeping.
Could you sing to me, please?
All right, so, uh...
Thank you. Thank you.
Great.
- Good morning.
- Hello.
There you go.
Yes?
I'm Sylvia.
Mary's mother.
I've come to get her.
- Just a minute.
- How is she doing?
She's fıne. She's teething.
That can be rough.
- Can I see her?
- Yeah, sure. Come on in.
I don't believe
how wonderful she looks!
Oh! Hello, Mary.
Hello, my darling.
It's your mommy.
Yes, it's your mommy.
You're very beautiful.
Your hair is growing.
You've changed so much,
and I've missed it.
Mommy has missed you.
Oh, I never thought
I'd miss her this much.
Hello!
Where's my baby?
Is Jack here?
- I'll get him.
- Mary, look how big you've gotten!
Michael. Michael.
Sylvia's here.
Mary's leaving.
She looks very happy, Jack.
You've obviously taken
good care of her.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have left her
the way I did.
I hope it didn't cause
too much trouble.
Uh, no, no. No trouble at all.
Sylvia.
There's something I need to know.
Is she really mine?
Yes. She is.
So, uh, what are you gonna do now?
Do you... Do you have any idea?
I, um...
I'm going home.
I can't work and take care
of Mary on my own...
so, um...
we're going to move in
with my family.
They said they'd help.
You're going to London?
Yeah.
When?
Tonight.
- Is that what you really want to do?
- Sorry?
Never mind.
- You pack all the bottles?
- Yeah.
And cans of formula?
- You packed 'em.
- Yeah.
What about the blender?
Maybe we should give her that,
to mash up bananas and stuff.
Sure.
And diapers?
You pack extra Pampers?
Yeah.
How can he let her go?
If I were Jack, I would not let her go.
Neither would I, Michael.
Neither would I.
But he's the father.
I don't think he wants her to go...
but he just can't admit it.
You know, if you want anything,
anything at all, you call us, okay?
She'll probably be hungry in an hour.
She's a real good eater, so, uh...
- Like her daddy.
- Some of this stuff's fragile in here.
- Okay, I got it.
- You know, if she... if she wakes up
in the middle of the night...
she likes to be sung to.
'50s and '60s music works best.
- Thanks. I'll remember that.
- You're all set. Everything's packed.
If there's anything else you need,
Just, uh, call us.
- Anything. Okay?
- Thank you.
Well, maybe, uh...
Here, let me, uh... Go ahead.
- Gloucester Hotel, please.
- The Gloucester, okay.
I'll write and let you know
how we're doing.
Come on, darling.
Wave goodbye, sweetheart.
- Bye, Mary.
Goodnight, sweetheart
Well, it's time to go
I hate to leave you
but I really must say
Oh, goodnight, sweetheart
Goodnight
Goodnight, sweetheart
Well, it's time to go
I hate to leave you
I really must say
Oh, goodnight, sweetheart
Goodnight
Well, it's 3:00
In the morning
Baby, I just can't do right
Well, I hate to leave you, baby
I don't mean maybe
Because I love you so
Goodnight, sweetheart
Well, it's time to go
I hate to leave you
I really must say
Oh, goodnight, sweetheart
Goodnight
I hate to leave you
I really must say
Oh, goodnight, sweetheart
Goodnight
Guys like us shouldn't be
raising kids anyway.
Right?
Well, should we?
I suppose not.
She's better off with her mother.
And we are defınitely better off
now that everything's back to normal.
- Right?
- Whatever you say, Jack.
Right.
So how come I feel so bad?
What'd you say?
How come I feel so bad?
I have this ache right here.
I don't know.
What do you think, Mike?
- It could be the wine.
- It's not the wine.
Well, what is it then?
I don't know.
I wish it would go away.
Maybe it's something you ate.
- Maybe you're not getting enough sleep.
- It's not that.
Then what the hell is it?
I miss Mary.
Okay?
I just wish there was
something I could do.
Well, maybe there is.
- What?
- When's her flight leaving?
- Yo, taxi!
- Taxi!
- Kennedy Airport.
- Yeah, Kennedy.
Kennedy Airport.
- Who you guys chasing?
- My baby girl.
- Her mother's taking her to London.
- Oh, yeah? How old?
- Se-Seven months.
- Seven months.
- Seven months? That's hard work.
But pretty soon,
they start to walk.
And let me tell you, the fırst time you
hear the word "Daddy"...
I don't care who you are,
your heart just melts.
- Can you drive a little faster, please?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- Good luck to you.
Thanks. Good luck, guys.
Four. Gate four.
Excuse me, sir.
Hold it, fellas. One at a time.
Please, one at a time.
Any metal.
Put it in here, please.
Thank you, sir.
One at a time. Thank you.
One, two, three, four. Four!
- 176. Flight 176?
- That's it.
Thank you. Goodnight.
Sylvia, are you all right?
What happened?
- We thought you'd gone.
- I couldn't go, Jack. I couldn't do it.
I mean, I don't want to
make another mistake.
And I knew if I took her away,
I'd just be making another mistake.
I mean, l-I have to work.
I mean, I can't do that
and take care of Mary alone.
I mean, do you know what it's like?
A one-room flat,
on your feet all day...
working or auditioning.
And I'm on the job sometimes
until 3:00 in the morning.
- And since Mary gets up at 5:30...
- Oh, I know, I know. It's awful.
- I mean, you can imagine
how much sleep I get.
- Yeah.
A-And after the 5:30 bottle,
it starts all over again at 9:00.
And by the time I change her and play
with her a little, it's already 8:00.
Well, forget about sleeping after that.
It's impossible.
And then the babysitters
until 3:00 in the morning.
All my money
is sucked down the tubes.
And me so tired.
I can't take Mary to the park.
Oh, tell me about it. Gettin' time to
take her to the park? That's a bitch.
- Sit down.
- I mean, I love my job, but...
I sometimes feel like I'm
Just working to pay the sitters...
and I run around all day...
and l-I don't get enough sleep.
And what's worse, I don't think
I'm taking very good care of Mary.
- No, of course you are.
- I am? I mean, I couldn't cope.
- Sylvia, we know how hard it is.
- Yeah, there's three of us.
We could hardly manage.
And I don't want to go to London.
I want to work in New York.
But I can't do that alone.
I hope I don't have to.
I need help.
I need someone to help me.
We'll help. We will help.
- Yes, yes, absolutely. I mean,
you can leave her anytime you want.
- Yes. Yes.
- We'd love to have her.
- Oh, gosh, yeah.
When you go for an audition or...
or you go shopping, or... or whatever.
- You want to be by yourself.
- I was hoping you would say that.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Really? Oh...
- Thank you so much. Mary.
- Yeah, of course.
Hold it, guys. I don't think
I like this arrangement.
I just don't want to be
Mary's babysitter.
I want... We want to be able
to see her all the time. May I?
L-I agree. So what are you saying?
What do you... What do you mean?
I'm saying...
that I think Mary should
move in with us permanently...
that we should be her family.
Well, l-I think it's lovely
of you to offer, Peter...
but l-I couldn't let Mary...
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
- Oh, no, you don't understand.
You're right, Sylvia. She's... She's your
daughter. She needs a full-time mother.
- That's why we think that...
that... that you should move in too.
- We... We...
- Oh, it's a great idea. Oh, Sylvia.
- Yeah!
- L...
- What do you think? Come on.
- Of course, it's better than...
Four is better than three.
Uh... Do you... Do you have room?
I'll build you a room.
I'll build Mary a room.
- That's what he does in life.
- Yeah, that's what he does.
He builds rooms.
- Oh, please, say yes.
- Yes!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Something happened, baby
in my life
The minute I saw you
All the others faded from my life
Hey, nothing mattered, baby
in my life
Till the minute I saw you
The minute I saw you
All the others faded from my life
I'm happy when I'm near to you
Yeah, it's true
Can't get any better
If someone else
would ever turn from me
You would see
that I wouldn't let her
Trust me, baby
You're the only one
Trust me
Don't let me be the lonely one
Something happened, baby
in my life
The minute I saw you
All the others faded from my life
Hold me, hold me
All I want to do
is kiss your baby face
Hold me, hold me
I wanna rock you in my arms
till I know you're safe
Till I know you're safe
Been waitin'all my life for you
Yeah, it's true
You better believe it
There ain't nothin'
I would hide from you
Trust my heart
You're all that I needed
Trust me
Baby, you're the only one
Don't let me be the lonely one
Something happened, baby
in my life
The minute I saw you
All the others faded from my life
Hey
Something happened, baby
in my life
The minute I saw you
All the others faded from my life
Yeah, something happened, baby
in my life
The minute I saw you
All the others faded from my life
I saw you
Hey, hey, hey
Hey, yeah, yeah
I saw you
Hey, hey
Just don't want to
leave her alone