Thrill! Aka no Sho! Episode 2 by addictt9
Initially I had an accident, and then somehow I can see people's secrets.
So, can you menyewaku as an advisor?
What is it?
So. Sorry, but why should I?
I can see the thinking of scheming to defraud sensei.
Bullshit! It's up to you to want to talk about it.
We appreciate your feelings, but ...
Sensei does not need people with the strength of as-
Chief Sponsor, Goda-san.
You take advantage of your position as Chairman of the Sponsor.
Most political fund sensei you used to own perusahaanmu interests, right?
What you say?
I could see everything. Then ...
Taoka-san ...
Soon there will be people working with you.
And that person might be. ...
... kill you.
Kill me? It's not likely to happen.
Really?
You will need my strength.
According to police, they received a report that a man lying over the phone 110.
The names of the men it was Taoka Haruki.
The inventor of the first remains of this man was a local security guard.
He seems to find it when doing a morning patrol.
Dense rain Yes.
Oh, the suspect hit him with a blood-stained pipe it Yes.
It seems so.
But, why do these people have in place like this huh?
Thank you to JPSub for the Japanese Subtitles translated by DecaDroid8 Thrill! The Red Chapter!
Overnight, the murder of Haruki Taoka who was the Secretary of the legislative, Kenichiro Ohata occurs.
But it looks like a woman has warned him 3 months ago.
I've warned repeatedly Taoka-san ...
Briefly sekerjamu friends will kill you.
Do you know who the culprit?
Yes, but ...
Because he did not want to ask for protection to the police, then it cannot be avoided.
How can you see the future?
Well, but the Minagawa Shoko-san is indeed very good Yes.
I figured it would be very helpful if the police recruited him here.
"It's happening now could change the future."
His victim, Taoka-san ...
What is lately there are problems associated with it?
Addressing the problem is her work Taoka-kun.
Ah, so yes.
Your Office late these days often accosted by a mysterious woman named Minagawa Shoko-san ya.
Yes. He's over to be advisory.
So, you believe in the power of the woman huh?
Its power is real.
Of course at first I also do not believe it.
But he proved all the work of corrupt bawahanku.
First, the Chairman of my Sponsor, Goda-san ...
... political funds embezzlement.
After kuselidiki, it turns out the word right.
Then I immediately dismissed Goda-san.
But, Taoka-kun is not at all believe it.
If he trust that woman ...
... maybe something like this will not happen.
He also dared to utilize members of Parliament.
Ah-Senior! -Ah, Kuroiwa-San!
Yes.
Based on reports from the criminal lab, they found this thing.
What is this?
May have belonged to the suspect.
Either.
-What is it? -I dunno ...
Candy?
Oi, oi mau until when making the police waiting for?
Outrageous.
There may be something he has planned.
Thank you for waiting. Please.
MINAGAWA-san, you ...
You have been predicting the death of the Taoka-san ya?
Correct. I already know whodunit.
Sorry, but we are here not to ask it.
-I want to? -My ass?
Us reveals the dirty work you now too.
Oh. Interesting. Please!
Kuroiwa-san, you use the money police ...
... to date many women, huh?
-Dating group huh? -Eh?
-He's just menggertakmu. -I know.
Three days ago you go where?
-If it's not wrong to Akasaka ...-wait-wait!
On five days ago you went to Roppongi right?
The name of his shop ...
-Already, Enough. -Kuroiwa-San!
Maybe there will be some people who will be menuduhkan at you.
It. ... Who?
You will soon know.
Later you will receive your phone.
Scary!
-The power of women is real! The way what the hell?
A lot of the right things.
EH?
Hello.
I am Nakano Hitomi from the Accounting Division of the police force.
Three days ago, you went to the Akasaka Navy Blue, and five days ago to Roppongi Dream Queen.
So I want to make sure of a few things.
Akasaka Navy Blue? Where is kutahu?
Ah there it is! I get there at night!
-Who is it? -Nakano.
But why is she menelponku?
Because you also get there with me.
Do not let that woman blocking us!
-Wait a minute! -Do you want fired?
-Our careers at stake tau! -Wait!
Dream Queen. Hello?
Ah, Hello! Nakano-kun huh?
Not fishy.
Suspicious.
Not fishy. Not fishy.
Nakano-kun!
Fishy!
Not fishy.
This is why, here a great many odd notes.
By the way, how about we have dinner together?
Hah?
Fishy!
But, why suddenly took me here?
You many helped in the case yesterday ...
I haven't had a chance to thank you.
Any message that you like.
Either.
Ah! It was tasty!
EH?
Please beef tenderloin Rossini style with seaweed.
Please enjoy.
8.900 yen.
I'm sorry. If that message could be gak ya?
It's okay. If ...
If you are requesting.
Excuse me!
Mmm! Yummy!
So ya. Thank goodness.
Sorry, excuse me.
-Hello? -How to deal with women accounting for it?
-Well that's how. -Don't tell me so!
Our destiny is at stake tau!
Well, I'll do something. By the way this is hard!
-Sorry! -What are you doing, basic sloppy!
I am sorry! I will immediately replace it with a new one.
Then the question of the last notes that ...
Then I and Kuroiwa-san is doing the investigation confidential.
So we stopped by briefly to make a report.
GAK! GAK! That does not mean the reason I asked you here!
A woman named Minagawa Shoko was not clairvoyant.
He's just a con!
-What now do you understand? -About what?
When I saw the Shoko-san on television, I so want to make sure what is real or not.
Then before Togawa-san consulted him, I found him.
I was there for a bit and then go.
Please wait a minute.
I thought in that room there's a hidden microphone.
He told people to wait, then she listens to their conversation.
And pretend as if he knew.
It is a mode of deception.
Then I did an experiment.
I pretended to be talking about information from n. Togawa-san and Kuroiwa-san.
It's a matter of note from Togawa-san and Kuroiwa-san from Division one.
After kuperiksa many a strange thing.
3 days ago to Akasaka Navy Blue, and on 19 February to Dream Queen Roppongi.
And then there are still more.
I think what kulaporkan is not better on tops ...
If only there's really no hidden microphone.
Then the things I said earlier it would surely have told the man.
If after Togawa-san to hear it ...
You brought me here so I did not discuss that issue.
-You're using us as guinea pigs? -Iya.
But thanks to that, I so know if he is a cheat.
If so tell me from the start.
At least say this before ordering.
Because these are things that cannot be bought, so. ..
Jeez ... don't mess around!
Hah?
You brought me here for the sake of covering up the bad things that you're doing, right?!
I figured this supervisor reported it is true Yes.
Ah! It looks delicious!
-It looks delicious Yes. -Messages that one, and her two.
-All right. -Excuse me, the message of wine two.
Oh! Such a handsome guy!
It looks like I drank too much wine.
Do not ever trust another person.
That's the thing the words written by my father before leaving.
Good morning! Thank you for last night.
Hey, why are you here?
Because last night I said it.
I know when Togawa-san came here early in the morning to make sure what is the hidden microphone.
-Come on! -Don't bother!
Please wait a minute.
You two are good acquaintances ya.
There is this thing in the waiting room.
This is a hidden microphone right?
I dunno, I've never seen it.
Lest it be yours eh?
The rings here ...
What do you always wear?
I lost it a few days ago.
It may just be stolen.
The bracelet was found at the scene of his Taoka-san.
Then ...
Then the time killing Taoka-san on 23 February at 10 to 11 nights ...
You are no where at that time?
February 23, 10 p.m. until 11 p.m. ...
I'm on my way back here.
What anyone could ascertain the truth?
When I passed the garden Tsujiyama, I met with the former Chairman of Sponsor, Goda-san.
I don't know if he did want to meet with me or just a coincidence only.
It's a pity, but it is not possible.
According to a report of other investigators, Goda-san said that at this time he was in Office.
Employee named Morikawa ever justify his words.
Can you join me to the police station?
It seems that the detention warrant Minagawa Shoko already out ya.
Because the proof was already strong.
-Oh yes, Aono-kun-Ya.
Flake bracelet found on the scene apparently belonged to him, and I proved it.
Then she also lied.
He is indeed the conjunction is not good with Taoka-kun.
But I can see the good side of him.
Right, Kuramoto-kun?
Kuramoto!
YES.
MINAGAWA Shoko-san is an important person to me.
Please help fast Please free him.
Togawa-san!
I'm curious will be something.
The bracelet fall debris on the scene ...
I figured someone deliberately put it there.
What is it?
From the beginning of the perpetrators had planned to kill Taoka-san using a pipe iron, right?
Wait a minute, why are you can know if the killer is a pipe iron weapons?
EH? I saw it on the news.
It has not been published to the media.
Lest you see it from the book catatanku huh?
Where possible! Her book brought Togawa-san continues, right?
Actually Togawa-san also minded ...
If the killer is someone else, right?
The death toll was hit from behind.
There were no signs of resistance.
Then, I think is not a coincidence if there is debris on the scene rings.
But, why Minagawa Shoko ...
its existence is a matter of lying at the time?
Maybe Goda-san was the one who lied.
Oi, come on!
Beware.
Sorry, according to the rule, please wear a helmet.
Ah, Yes.
Then please leave your stuff here.
-Yes. -Sorry.
Ah, you also ...
Pak police, sorry meet in a place like this.
I am Nakano Hitomi from the Accounting Division of the police force.
Tomita, please help point to the sector C.
Please follow me to the sector C.
Thank you for taking the time. This reserved Minagawa Shoko-san.
She said that on the night of the incident, you met him.
-What do you know? -No.
Somehow Minagawa-san to lie like that.
On that night I was with Morikawa-kun supervise the work in the Office.
Right, Morikawa-kun?
YES.
Really?
Just because it was asked by the head of the Pack ...
... you still shouldn't lie.
Where it might lie.
We know if you grudge against Minagawa.
But if on the night of the incident you are in Garden Tsujiyama for. ..
... met with Minagawa Shoko, then he is found not guilty.
No more need to talk about.
Oh yes, and while you're here ...
Could you have a look at a few of our projects?
When it is finished it will make Ohata-sensei will put great expectations on me.
Morikawa-kun, please transfer out Yes.
Please.
Hmmm .... Mr. Goda clearly lied to Yes.
The police might have done a big mistake Yes.
Then why the Pack heads told us to look at the unresolved project?
If so how about 120 million?
Well if so. Excuse me.
Well, I'm sorry all of a sudden there's a telephone.
I heard from the Police Department to question murder Secretary Ohata-sensei.
A woman named Minagawa Shoko has been arrested Yes.
Because the woman was also you have been fired from the post of head of her sponsor Ohata-sensei huh?
If so let's sue the woman in court.
-The lawsuit? Women have made you fired.
Then kill Taoka-san.
Surely he wanted to do something against the Ohata-sensei.
Now is the time to stand up to uphold justice!
But it is true if the flow of political funds sensei has me black out.
No, no. It is not a problem.
Please sit down. What are you sure? The woman is suspected of murder!
Otherwise you are the importance of Ohata-sensei in development.
You think the community will trust the which?
But if the woman is not the culprit ...
No, no. He was arrested because the police would have found strong evidence.
Sensei.
Actually I want to consult about one more thing.
The question of what?
Before that please berjanjilah if you're not going menghianatiku.
Until now I have never betrayed anyone.
-Chika-chan.-Yes.
Please buy food at the supermarket for our clients.
Either.
So, want to question what consultation?
The actual culprit is not Shoko Minagawa.
-What? -He has a strong alibi.
When I was questioned by the police, I'm lying if I met this lady in the garden Tsujiyama.
I figured when I met him
I think for swearing before him, but ...
When I talked to him, I kicked off the Board and ruin it.
I've been trying to clean up the paint that is inherent in the shoes, but not lost.
Sensei, can I membayarmu to improve papannya and please dispose of those shoes?
For the sake of Ohata-sensei, I let the woman was arrested.
It was the best thing I could do to sensei.
Please.
I'm Shirai Shinnosuke, a lawyer.
I can directly mengeluarkanmu from this place now.
MINAGAWA-san, during the night of the killing incident happens, you meet with Goda-san in the garden Tsujiyama, right?
Yes, but Goda-san denied it.
Of course, because it has a grudge Goda-san you.
Ah then when it Teased-san is angry ...
... What is she ruining something?
Ah yes, something in the garden.
-Nameplate! -Nameplate?
-Are you sure? -Iya.
I will soon mengeluarkanmu from here.
Leave it all on me, Shirai Shinnosuke.
This is the head of the Pack of loafer Goda.
You can see there are spots of paint on his shoes.
This attaches when Mr. Goda Head damage the nameplate in the garden Tsujiyama.
After kuselidiki catnya stuck in the same night when the murder happened. — san Taoka
In other words, Goda-san kicked nameplate in the same time.
This is in accordance with the testimony of Minagawa Shoko-san.
If you think I'm lying, please go to the Park and check.
The woman ...
Not guilty.
MINAGAWA Shoko out!
MINAGAWA Shoko was arrested for the alleged murder of Haruki Taoka.
Then today was freed.
MINAGAWA-san what is your opinion ...
Well, this is definitely bothersome part investigator Yes.
I'm thankful is not a police officer.
Where national television stations?
This proves the inability of police to prove the truth.
I did menuntuk harsh punitive damages against police for Minagawa Shoko-san.
Aono-kun, this makes the image of the police force for the worse.
We should also apologize to the Ohata-sensei.
Kukeluarkan police will soon be in charge of the case.
This is bad!
MINAGAWA Shoko arrested too because ulahmu.
But, Kuroiwa-san, isn't it you who claimed to have caught it?
What is it?
Yes, this Togawa.
MINAGAWA Shoko wants to meet with us.
We're here to apologize,
We're sorry!
Not what. I'm also sorry it's been a hassle.
If I say in detail when I met with Goda-san that night
Then you both will not engage the issue.
Well, if so ...
As long as you guys here and I will help you guys.
-Help? -I apologize in advance.
I know who killed Taoka-san.
Even without the need to see the work of dark somebody ...
Because it was obvious the culprit.
We do not need such power.
Please ...
Please let us know.
The culprit was the Second Secretary of the ...
Instead, it is now becoming first Secretary, Kuramoto-san.
The man looks very ambitious.
When Taoka-san does not exist, then he will be the first Secretary.
So, using a pernyataanku, he killed Taoka-san.
Excuse me.
The base of the damn lawyers! He menghianatiku.
But Goda-san, you're also lying to police.
The obvious culprit is the woman.
I am Yes, Kuramoto-san ...
Until now still think for the good of Ohata-sensei.
Though he was young ...
But she has a rare understanding.
Then everything is broken when the woman suddenly appeared.
Kuramoto-san lest you quite happy when Taoka-san dies huh?
What do you mean?
When Taoka-san dies, then the first Secretary kaulah!
Don't talk like that.
Correct, right?!
Lest kaulah Who Killed him!
Please stop this.
Don't you dare look at my eyes right!
Come on Goda-san!
Because I'm not drunk, I'll drop you home.
Watch your head.  Put your feet.
-Sorry troublesome yes.  -Duduk correct yes.
We must do something for her.
Minagawa Shoko!
No matter what happened, the woman had to be removed.
You're the one who is responsible.
Can you buy me a drink of water?
Tu-wait a minute ya.
Air circulation is not good, so there are a lot of bad things happen.
Then the existing field across the road ...
Please planted tulips.
Then place the fountain in the middle.
I think it will improve air circulation is good.
thanks.  Kuramoto, immediately contact authorities.
-Kuramoto! -Ah! Iya!
There is a need to do?
Please start now stay away from sensei!
Since you came, Sensei be strange!
Then why did you kill Taoka-san?
What next I?
What did you say?
What do you really want to sensei !?
Help!  Someone!
He'll kill me!
Ti-no!  Are you talking about?
Previously, sensei plans to bring up the biggest sports centers around the office.
Tapi, setelah play lidiki ...
The budget is not enough to plan.
Moreover, it is doubtful the plan will be profitable or not.
Sensei thought that the project would not be profitable, so she resisted.
But she was persuaded sensei to quickly finish the project.  Sensei also suddenly agree.
I think if this continues ...
It's enough talking.
Can I explain to you?
You killed Taoka-san the first secretary.
Lalu untuk menutupi itu, kau menggunakan Minagawa Shoko ...
Demi dikenal Ohata-sensei.
But he had a perfect alibi.
So in order not to compete, you kill him.
Please do not say anything bad like that!
When we checked the car, we find this thing.
Ini adalah gelang yang digunakan Minagawa Shoko-san kan?
After killing Taoka-san, you're leaving a few pieces of bracelets at the scene.
So you think killing is Shoko Minagawa-san.
I do not know this thing.
He wants to tell on me, so I forced him into a car.
How?
Do not you steal it from him huh?
What do you drive together?
Basic man mask!
It was a confession!  Well, the case is resolved.
Ah, thank goodness not be fired.
But I'm curious.
What?
What she is saying is always true.
We may be manipulated by the woman.
I'm very attracted to you.
Nice work you can find a hidden microphone.
But the real strength.
I could see all the things you are hiding.
I'll try to prove it right now.
Please.
Actually, you want to be a cop, huh?
But you can not.
Because it will be a problem if questioned about family information.
Your father is a criminal.  Is not it?
Fraudsters are very cunning.
Since childhood you and your father are always trying to avoid being caught by the police.
Hah?
-Halo? Togawa-san? -Iya, ada apa?
What Kuramoto-san has been arrested?
No, not yet.  Soon a letter out of his detention.
Kuramoto-san is not the culprit.
-Pelakunya are others.  -What?
I will go for sure!
Hei!
Then we set off, yes.
What's up?
Wait a minute.
From the police huh?  Is there anything you want to ask again?
Turns out you're the mastermind behind all this is yes.
Minagawa Shoko-san hanyalah alat kejahatanmu.
What do you mean?
Earlier, Shoko-san suddenly appeared before me.
Then he mentions secrets.
Supposedly it surprised me but he just made a mistake.
About my father's a liar, and I really wanted to be a cop.
I think I've heard of it, so ...
I know he read it from here.
Ah, this is a record of my imagination, so everything here is just a lie.
But this is precisely why my fantasy writings referred to as secret by Shoko-san?  Strange is not it?
Now that I think, there are peep this my notebook ...
Then tell Shoko-san.
It is true that the story is interesting, but ...
Is it just a mirage as you wrote in your book?
No, this is not an illusion anyway.
It fell when I opened my notebook.
After I checked, this is the same sand dust sand dust that is in this place.
That means people who work with Shoko-san is here and peek notebook.
Goda-san, when I and Togawa-san went to this place ...
You told Morikawa-san to leave luggage.
Then we told you to look around.
I wonder why you do it.
You're doing it to check our baggage right.
In other words...
Working together is you, Goda-san.
Shut up and do not say anything stupid.
What can be proved by the sand dust?
Anyway, I was fired by Ohata-sensei for her.
So where might I collaborate with her?
What if it is part of your plan?
You deliberately let Shoko-san accused of embezzlement.
So people believe that Shoko-san's power is real.
Your real purpose is ...
Using Shoko-san to control MPs Ohata.
I would say it is on the part of the investigation.
If it is checked again, would definitely see the evidence.
Excuse me.
Stop saying things that are not necessary.
You do not mind do you?
Yes.
Your company will initially set up a new sports center yes.
If according to plan, then it will be a great advantage for your company.
But MPs Ohata know that it is suspicious.
So he rejected the plan.
By doing so you will lose big.
Then you plan on using Minagawa Shoko to control MPs Ohata.
What else can we do.
At that time, the constraints are Taoka-san.
You know who pleaded not approve of the plan is the first secretary, Taoka-san.
So, most agree will plan the sports center is Taoka-san.
While Taoka-san was killed,
Aku sedang bertengkar dengan Minagawa Shoko di taman Tsujiyama.
Too bad, but I had a strong alibi.
You do not have an alibi.
Do you think we will immediately believe it?
Hear.
All the evidence now point if you cooperate with Minagawa Shoko.
Shoko Minagawa that destroyed the nameplate and make these shoes no trace of paint.
When that, too, you killed Taoka-san.
Taoka-san...
You also make the Kuramoto-san was accused.
You put the rings in the car Kuramoto seemed as proof.
Drinking water can be traded?
Wait a minute, please.
There are other reasons?
If only the seer was not negligence ...
The soothsayer ...
Since the female detective discovered a hidden microphone, it becomes a problem.
So he came to me and told me to find out his secret.
However it is written in the book like the real thing.
But because of the greed of the seer, he made everything a mess.
We also will not be fooled ...
If the woman detective ...
... do not know if diintip by your notebook.
-Hello to you.  -Why again, Shirai?
I think it will be a difficult trial, so ...
I would not mind if it should continue to be your lawyer.
Of course, if the pay is appropriate.
I will not ask for help ...
... the traitor like you.
Come on.
You're not a cop.
So, do not again come to the suspect alone.
Sorry.
But if not done, then there would be no evidence ...
Lest you purposefully make Goda attack huh?
I did know that Togawa-san will come soon.
Look, do not do anything like that again.
By the way you really do not want to show ...
... notebook that spy by Goda?
Yes.
Its content is simply wishful thinking.
What it's really just your imagination?
What?  Yes.