A
J&H Entertainment
Release
Suspects described as white males,
approximately 25 to 30.
Suspect number one
about five-eleven, medium build,
brown hair, brown, dark pants.
Suspect number two,
about six-one, medium build...
brown hair, round glasses,
dark clothes.
Be advised suspects are armed and should
be considered extremely dangerous.
Use caution apprehending them.
- Hey, Earl.
- Yes, sir.
- What do you know?
- Well...
it's a hot goddamned day.
I haven't felt it a bit.
I've been inside with the
air-conditioner blastin' all day long.
- Oh, is that right?
- That's right.
Didn't you break for lunch or nothin'?
I'm by myself today.
I ate my lunch out of the microwave.
Jesus H. Christ, Pete.
When are you gonna learn that microwave
food will kill you faster than a bullet?
I mean, them damn burritos ain't good
for nothin' but a hippie...
when he's high on weed.
Pull me out a bottle of that Jack,
will you?
Yep.
I think I'm gonna get tanked tonight.
What's the matter?
Ohh, hell.
Been one long goddam hot,
miserable, shit-ass fuckin' day...
every inch of the way.
First off, Nadine over
at the Blue Chip got sort of sick...
since she got that goddam Mongoloid boy
of hers workin' the grill.
I mean, that fuckin' idiot doesn't know
rat shit from Rice Krispies.
I eat breakfast about 9:00,
and I'm pukin' up pigs in a blanket...
like a sick fuckin' dog by 10:30.
Isn't there a law or somethin' against
retards servin' food to the public?
Well, if there ain't, there ought to be.
I mean, who in the hell knows
what's goin' on in the mind
of a goddamned Mongoloid?
Nadine should've hit that boy in
the head and sold the fuckin' milk.
You could sue the shit
out of her, you know that?
That kid belongs under a circus tent,
not flippin' burgers.
- You could own that fuckin' place.
- Oh, shit, Pete.
What would I do with that grease pit?
Besides, Nadine's got a cross to bear.
I mean, taking care
of that potato head.
I guess you heard about that shit
up in Abilene. Bank robbery?
It's all that's been on the box all day.
They killed some people, didn't they?
Yeah. Killed four Rangers...
three cops...
one civilian.
Took a lady bank teller
hostage with them.
Supposed to be headed for the border,
which'd bring 'em right my way.
Get my hands on them crazy, sick
fuckin' bastards, it's payback time.
I mean...
Well, we'll get 'em.
- We'll get 'em.
- Well, I don't doubt it.
Well...
I gotta drain my lizard.
Mind if I use your commode?
- Knock yourself out.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
Do you think I'm fuckin' playing
with you, asshole?
Do you want this little girl to die,
or that little girl or yourself?
Or your bosom buddy with the badge?
Now, I don't want to do it...
but I will turn this place into
the fucking Wild Bunch if I think
that you are fucking with me.
- What do you want from me?
I did what you said.
- You let him use the bathroom.
- No store does that.
- He comes in here every day,
and we bullshit.
He's used my toilet a thousand times.
If I told him "no," he'd know something
was up.
All right. I want him out of here,
in his car and down the road...
or you can change the name of this place
to "Benny's World of Blood."
Were you giving that pig signals?
Are you kiddin'?
I didn't do anything!
- He says you were scratching.
- I wasn't scratchin'!
- Are you calling him a liar?
- I'm not callin' him a liar, okay?
I'm simply sayin' if I was scratchin',
I don't remember scratchin'.
And if I did scratch...
it's not because
I was signalling the cop,
it's 'cause I'm fuckin' scared shitless!
Wait a minute.
The guy's in the bathroom.
Why don't I just go back there...
- shoot him in the back of the head,
and we can get the hell out of here?
- Don't do that!
Look, you asked me to act natural,
and I acted natural.
In fact, under the circumstances,
I think I oughta get a fuckin'
Academy Award for how natural I acted.
You asked me to get rid of him.
I'm doin' my best!
Well, your best better get
a hell of a lot fucking better,
or you are gonna feel
a hell of a lot fucking worse.
Everybody be cool.
You be cool.
Yep. Be back at it tomorrow.
Tonight I'm gonna sit in front of that
box and get higher than a Georgia pine.
- How much you want
for that hooch, Pete?
- Oh, 6.50.
Jesus Christ. You buckin'
for early retirement?
Shit, yeah.
Hey! Hey! What the fuck is that about?
- He signalled the Ranger.
- I didn't! Ya gotta believe me!
- I didn't!
- When they were talkin',
he mouthed the words, "Help us."
- You fuckin' liar! I didn't say shit!
- Why don't you shut the hell up?
Hey! Will you stop it! What the fuck
is your problem, goddam it?
Seth, he did it!
You were by the beer cooler
with your back turned.
I was by the magazines.
I could see his face!
And I saw him mouth the words,
"Help us."
Start the car.
- You believe me, don't you?
- Yes. Shut up.
And start the car, all right?
You start the car.
- You believe me, don't you?
- Start the car. You know that?
Shut the fuck up and start the car.
- Wait, wait.
- I believe you. Start the car!
You-You're not just sayin' that?
You do believe me?
- I believe you! Let's go!
- That means you believe me.
- Yes, I believe you!
- You should, 'cause I'm right.
- Oh, shit!
- Ohh!
- Richie?
- Yeah?
You okay?
He shot me in the fuckin' hand!
- Like I told you, he said, "Help us."
- I never said "help us"!
Well, that doesn't matter now,
'cause you got about
two fuckin' seconds to live!
- Richie?
- Yeah?
When I count to three, you shoot
the bottles out from behind him.
Oh, yeah!
- One.
- Fuck!
Two.
Three.
What did I tell you?
What did I say to you?
- I said, "Buy the road map and leave."
- What the fuck am I supposed
to do, Seth?
- He recognized us.
- He didn't recognize shit.
Seth, I'm telling you,
the way he looked at us...
you, especially... I knew he knew.
Low profile. Do you understand
the meaning of the words "low profile"?
"Hey, Richie, how's your hand?" "It
hurts like a fuckin' son of a bitch!
- Let me tell you
what "low profile" is not.
- Thanks for askin'!"
It is not taking girls hostage.
It is not shooting police.
It is not setting fire to a building.
Bitch, bitch, bitch.
Hot air hangs like a dead man
From a white oak tree
There's people sittin' on porches
Thinkin' how things used to be
Dark night
It's a dark night
My wife left home about a week ago
She stole the kids
and she took all my dough
- Move it!
- Goddam you. Goddam you.
- What the hell do you want?
- What do you think I want,
you mean old bastard?
I want a fuckin' room.
Okay. All right.
She peed on the carpet
She shot my horse
And now things are goin'
from better to bad to worse
Do they have cable?
No.
- Do they have the X-rated channel?
- No.
- Do they have a water bed?
- Nope.
- What do they got?
- They have four walls and a roof...
and that's all we need.
All right, pop the trunk.
Let's do this fast.
- Oh.
- Don't say a word.
You, plant yourself in that seat.
- What are you gonna do with me?
- I said "plant yourself."
Plants don't talk.
Now, you wanna get on my good side...
you sit still
and you don't make a peep.
- All right, how does this feel?
- How do you think?
It hurts like a son of a bitch.
All right. It's wrapped too tight.
Nice and easy now.
- Okay.
- All right. Okay, I'm gonna
go get the money.
It's 6:00. What time does it get dark
around here?
- About 8:00.
- Good. I'm going to the border,
check things out.
I'm gonna call Carlos, try and arrange
some sort of a rendezvous.
- I don't know what yet.
- Could you see if he could arrange
a better deal than 30%?
It's their standard deal.
They're not gonna change that for us.
Did you even try
to negotiate with them?
Richie, these guys are not spic
firecracker salesmen from Tijuana.
They don't even know the meaning
of the word "barter."
You wanna stay in El Rey,
you give them 30% of your loot.
It's scripture.
So it is written, so shall it be done.
- Look...
- Yeah, I know, listen. Hey, you want
sanctuary, you gotta pay the price.
The price is 30%.
- All I'm sayin', man...
- This conversation's over.
Okay?
We need to have a talk.
What's your name?
- Gloria.
- Hello, Gloria. I'm Seth.
That's my brother, Richie.
Let's cut to the chase.
I'm gonna ask you one question...
and all I want is a yes or no answer.
Do you wanna live through this?
- Yes.
- Good. Rule number one: No noise.
No questions. If you make a noise...
Mr.44 makes a noise.
If you ask a question,
Mr.44 answers it.
Now, are you absolutely, positively
clear about rule number one?
- Yes.
- Rule number two.
You do what we say when we say it.
If you don't, see rule number one.
Rule number three: Don't you ever try
and fucking run on us...
'cause I got six little friends...
and they can all run faster
than you can.
Open your eyes.
Gloria, you hang in there,
you follow the rules...
and you don't fuck with us,
and you'll get out of this alive.
I give you my word. Okay?
I'll be back in a minute.
You wanna come over on the bed
and watch TV with me?
- Hail!
- Come on.
Have a seat.
Come on.
Take off your shoes.
Foolish heart
- Foolish heart
- You made me weep
We got about two more hours...
till we get in to El Paso...
which is right next to the border.
- Then we'll stop at a motel.
- Stop?
- We're not actually gonna stop
at a motel, are we?
- Yeah, what for?
We have a motorhome. We don't wanna
stay in those roach haven motels, do we?
- We're self-contained.
- Okay, okay.
Maybe I was a little overzealous.
But give me a break. I just bought it.
How come you wanna stop anyways, Dad?
- I'm exhausted.
- Exhausted? Just lie in the back, Dad.
- I can drive us into Mexico.
- I just bet you would.
Don't even think about it.
Besides, I-I wanna have...
just one night's sleep
in an honest to goodness bed.
The beds in the home are okay, but...
they're not like a real bed.
Excuse me.
I have to use the restroom.
Oh! Guess what. When I called
the machine to check the messages, um...
one of them was from Bethel Baptist.
And Mr Franklin said that...
he wouldn't permanently replace you
until we came back.
- And he said that...
- That's very nice of Ted.
But I'll call him tomorrow
and tell him not to bother waiting.
Daddy, I didn't wanna talk
about this in front of Scott...
because he gets upset,
but I just wanna know.
Don't you believe in God any more?
Not enough to be a pastor.
Look, I know this is hard on you kids.
After Jenny's death, this is probably
the last thing you need, but...
my congregation needs
spiritual leadership.
Well, my faith is gone.
To answer your question, yes,
I do believe in Jesus.
Yes, I do believe in God.
But do I love Them? No.
Well, it's just that all our lives
you've been a pastor.
And then one day, you're just gonna
wake up and say, "Fuck Him"?
I didn't say, "Fuck Him."
Every person who chooses...
the service of God
as his life's work...
has something in common.
I don't care if you're
a preacher, a priest...
a nun, a rabbi or a Buddhist monk.
Many, many times during your life,
you'll look at your reflection...
in the mirror and ask yourself...
"Am I a fool?"
I'm not going through a lapse.
What I've experienced is closer
to awakening.
Daddy?
What do you think Mom would say?
Mama's got nothing to say.
She's dead.
This bloody crime spree started
just a week ago today.
The oldest of the two brothers,
Seth Gecko...
was serving time in Rollings, Kansas
State Penitentiary...
for his part in the 1988 Scott City
bank robbery...
in which two law enforcement officers
lost their lives.
It was while at the court house
that this man, his younger brother...
Richard Gecko, a known armed robber
and sex offender...
pulled off a daring daylight escape...
resulting in the death of four
Wichita law enforcement officers...
and this woman,
Heidi Vogel, sixth grade teacher,
who was run over by the Geckos...
during a high-speed pursuit
through downtown Wichita.
And earlier today, during a daylight
liquor store robbery in Big Springs...
the Gecko brothers killed
another Texas Ranger, Earl McGraw...
and liquor store clerk, Pete Bottoms.
That changes the death toll to 16:
Five Texas Rangers, eight
police officers, three civilians...
and one hostage: Bank teller
and mother of four, Gloria Hill.
For the time being, we're very confident
that we'll apprehend...
these fugitives
within the next 48 hours.
The bureau, local law enforcement
and the Texas Rangers have all joined...
in forming a dragnet
to snare Seth and Richard Gecko.
Is it safe to assume that because
of the death count involved...
and the loss of life
of law enforcement officers...
that the bureau, the Rangers
and the police force...
are taking this manhunt personally?
I would say that's
a very safe assumption.
Shit, I was really worried.
Where the fuck you been, man?
- Sightseeing.
- What'd you see?
- The cops.
- Did you see the border?
Yes, I saw the border.
What'd the TV say?
They're gonna apprehend us
in about 48 hours.
I gotta figure out a way to get us
across this goddam border.
The longer we stay here, our lives
ain't worth shit. Here you go.
We gotta get our asses
into Mexico tonight.
Then Carlos is gonna meet us there
at the rendezvous tomorrow morning.
Well, now, he and his boys...
both of them... all of them...
are gonna escort us
into El Rey, and...
- Where's the woman?
- What?
What do you mean, what? The woman...
th-the host... the fucking hostage.
Richard, where is she?
- She's in there.
- What the fuck is she doing in there?
Now, Seth, wait a minute. Seth.
Richard, what's wrong with you?
Before you flip out, okay,
let me just explain what happened.
Yeah, ex-explain to me.
I need an explanation.
What is the matter with you?
There's nothing wrong with me, brother.
That woman tried to escape, and I did
what I had to do.
No, that woman wouldn't have said shit
if she had a mouth full of it.
- Wrong, wrong, wrong.
- Yeah.
- After you left, she became
a completely different person.
- Yeah.
Is it me? My fault?
- It's not your fault.
- Is this my fault?
- No, it's her fault.
It's not your fault.
- Is this my fault?
Do you think that this is what I am?
- I don't...
- This is not me.
I am a professional fucking thief.
I don't kill people that I don't have
to, and I don't fucking rape women.
What you are doing...
What you are fucking doing...
What you are doing is not how it's done.
Do you understand that?
Do you? Just say fucking "yes."
Say, "Yes, Seth, I understand."
- Yes, Seth, I understand.
- Say, "Yes, Seth,
I fucking understand."
I understand, Seth.
I fucking understand.
We'll get to Mexico,
and it's gonna be sweet rosemary...
and 100 proof liquor...
and rice and beans,
and none of this shit's gonna matter.
I can't believe he's stopping here.
This place is totally cruddy.
Dad, why are we stoppin' here?
There's nothing wrong with this place.
It's a flophouse.
It's not a flophouse.
It's basic and simple.
That doesn't make it a flophouse.
All right. Well, if it doesn't have
a pool, then we're going someplace else.
It has a bed.
That's all I care about.
Well, other places have beds too...
and they also have a gym, tennis...
Jeez, what is this guy's problem?
No idea.
Creepy guy.
- What?
- Yes, I'm your neighbour
from, uh, room 11...
and I hate to disturb you,
but I'd like to ask a favour.
I hope none of this is disturbing you.
Hi. Uh, I'm from room 11, and, uh...
me and my lady friend need some ice,
and we don't seem to have an ice bucket.
If it's not too much trouble,
could I possibly borrow yours?
I'll bring it right back.
- Sure.
- Thank you.
What is this?
It's called a punch.
Lose the guitar.
- What's your name?
- Jacob.
Jacob, get up, get on the bed.
If you make a wrong move,
I will shoot you in the face.
Open your mouth. Wide.
Let's go. Let's move the Jap
over here too. Let's go.
So what's the story with you two?
You a couple of fags?
- This is my son.
- How does that happen?
- You don't look Japanese.
- Neither does he. He looks Chinese.
Oh, ooh, well,
excuse me all to hell.
- What's this about? Money?
- It's about money, all right,
but not yours.
My brother and I, we're in a little
hot water. Now, I need your assistance.
- Stop!
- Wh-What's, um, goin' on?
We're havin' a bikini contest,
and you just won.
It's okay, honey.
Everything's gonna be all right.
You listen to your daddy, sugar,
and you don't do anything stupid.
You two...
Simon says sit the fuck down.
Sit down.
Now, where are the keys
to the motorhome?
On the dresser.
All right.
Richie, you take these keys.
You start this big bastard up
and drive it up front.
Richie, would you do me a favour
and eat my pussy for me? Please?
- Uh, sure.
- Richie, hey!
Not when you get around to it. Now.
You, Gidget, go in the bathroom
and put on some clothes.
You got three minutes. One second
longer, I shoot your father in the face.
- Do you understand what I just said?
- Yes.
- Do you believe me?
You damn well better. Go.
Look, if you want the motorhome,
just take it and get out.
It's not gonna be that easy, Pops.
We're gonna go on a little ride.
Not a chance.
- Come again?
- If you're taking people, take me.
But my kids aren't going
anywhere with you.
Sorry, Pops. I need everybody.
My children are not going
with you, and that's that.
That's not fucking that.
This is fucking this.
Dad.
You sit down. Sit down.
You, go sit over there.
Go sit over there now. Move it.
Sit down.
Now, I don't have time to fuck around,
so I'm gonna make this simple.
You take your kids and you get
in that motorhome...
or I will execute all three
of you right now.
So, what's it gonna be?
Yes or no answer.
- Yes.
- Hey, your old man's all right.
He just saved your life.
Time's up, princess. Here we go.
Okay, ramblers, let's get rambling.
Excuse me.
What?
Where are you takin' us?
- Mexico.
- What's in Mexico?
Mexicans.
- Richie?
- Yeah?
Put in your bit.
- I grind my teeth.
- Dengue woman
- What are their names?
- Scott and Kate.
Scott and Kate. Who's this?
- My wife.
- Where is the little lady?
In heaven.
She dead?
- Yes, she is.
- How'd she die?
Auto wreck.
Come on, Jacob, give me some
more details. How did it happen?
Some fuckin' drunk kill her?
No. It was a rainy night.
The brakes on the car weren't great.
She had to stop suddenly.
She slid on the road.
She crashed. She died.
- She died right away?
- Not quite.
She was trapped in the wreck
for about...
six hours before she passed on.
Yep. Those acts of God really stick
it in and break it off, don't they?
Yes, they do.
Is that real?
Yes.
I've seen one of these things before.
A friend of mine had himself ordained...
a minister of his own religion.
Some way to fuck the IRS.
Is that what you're doing,
or are you the real McCoy?
Real McCoy.
You're a preacher?
I was a minister.
"Was," as in not any more?
- Yes.
- Why'd you quit?
I think I've gotten about as up close
and personal with you as I'm gonna get.
Let's just keep this friendly, okay,
Pops? Let's not get too sensitive.
Oh, you're right.
Enough with the gettin'-to-know-you
shit. All right.
I don't give a rat's ass
about you or your fuckin' family.
You can all live forever,
or you can die this second.
And I don't give a shit which.
The only things that I care about...
are me, that son of a bitch back there
in the back and our money.
So you help us get across the border
without incident, you stay with us...
through the night
without trying anything funny,
without trying to escape...
and in the morning,
I'm gonna let you guys go, all of you.
How do I know you'll keep your word?
You have to convince me
you're telling the truth.
Look, dick-head, the only thing
that you have to be convinced about...
is the fact that you are stuck
in a situation with a couple
of real mean motor scooters...
and I don't want to have to worry
about you all fuckin' night.
You know, and I don't think you wanna
be worrying about my brother's...
intentions towards your daughter
all night either.
Did you notice the way
that he was looking at her?
- Yes.
- You didn't like it, did you?
- No, I didn't.
- I didn't think so.
You get us into Mexico...
and you don't try to escape,
and your daughter will be safe.
And in the morning, I will let you go.
I give you my word, Jacob.
If he touches her, I'll kill him.
Fair enough. You break your word,
I'll kill all of ya.
You got me all crazy
I can't get outta of bed
Bones are achin'
Backed up in my head
Dengue woman
Stay away from me
You got your aches and pains
All over me
Did you mean what you said
back there in the room?
What?
In the room.
Did you mean what you said back there,
or were you just foolin' around?
Because if-if you really want me
to do that for you, I will.
I'd be happy to.
Do what?
What you said back there in the room.
What did I say?
- You asked me if I would eat out...
- Richie.
- What?
- I told you to watch those kids,
not to talk to them.
You don't have nothin' to say to one
another, so let's just cut the chatter.
We'll talk later, okay?
- Just stand back there.
- Move it up. Move it up.
All right, everybody. It's show time.
Richie, you take Kate into the bathroom.
Scott, get up here with your dad.
Let's go. Let's go!
Now, what are you gonna say?
I don't have the slightest idea.
Just keep thinking about that gun
next to Kate's head.
Get in.
- Another one up. Come on.
- Come on. Let's go.
- This isn't gonna work, Seth.
- Shut up. It's gonna work just fine.
Dad, what are you gonna do?
I'm gonna try and get us
across the border.
Dad, you have to tell them
that they're back there.
- Have you forgotten about your sister?
- I want to go on record right now as
saying that this is a very bad idea.
Duly noted. Now shut up.
Step right over there.
That's okay.
They're gonna kill us, Dad. They're
gonna get us across the border...
take us out in the desert somewhere,
then they're gonna fuckin' shoot us.
If they get over the border,
they're gonna let us go.
They won't. Dad, come on.
I watch those reality shows.
They never let anybody go.
Any cop will tell you...
in a situation like this,
you get a chance and you go for it.
I know it may not seem like it,
but I know exactly what I'm doing.
- You're gonna have to trust me on this.
- I can't do that, Dad.
If you don't tell the cops, I will.
Listen to me. You ain't gonna do
a goddamned thing, you hear me?
I'm runnin' the show.
I make the decisions.
- He is running the show.
- I'm running the show!
- Dad!
- I'm runnin' the show!
Shh. I make the plays.
You back the plays I make.
I need your cover.
Cover me.
How many with you?
Just my son and I.
What's your purpose in Mexico?
Vacation. I'm taking him
to see his first bullfight.
- They're gonna search the van.
- As long as you don't act...
like a fuckin' nut,
we're gonna be just fine.
What the hell's
that supposed to mean?
- What?
- You just called me a "fuckin' nut."
- No, I didn't.
- Yes, you did.
You said as long as I don't act
"like a fucking nut."
- Implying that I've been acting
like a fucking nut.
- Take a pill, all right?
- I just meant be cool.
- Yeah, you meant that.
- But you meant the other too.
- This is not the time, Richie.
- Hey, fuck those spic pigs, man!
You called me a "fucking nut."
- Would you just...
- Now, where I come from,
that stops the train in its tracks.
- Keep your fucking voice down.
Or what?
What was that?
Oh. That was, uh...
just-just my daughter
in the bathroom.
I thought you said
it was just you and your son.
Um, I meant me and my son
and my daughter.
Open up. I'm comin' aboard.
What was the nuttiest thing
I did, Seth?
- I'm curious. Tell me.
What? What was it?
- This is not the time, Richie.
I know. Was it possibly when your ass
was rotting in jail and I broke it out?
Was that the nuttiest thing?
That was nutty, not to mention stupid.
Thanks.
- I'm in the bathroom.
- Open up. It's the Border Patrol.
It's open.
Do you mind?
Shut the fuckin' door, please.
Excuse me.
Goddam, that was intense!
Oh, baby, we did it.
We're in Mexico.
We're fuckin' in Mexico,
you little piece of fuckin' shit!
Come on! Kate, get out here.
Come on.
All right, listen up.
Everybody listen.
Now, I know that I've put
you all through hell...
and I know that I have been
one rough pecker.
But from here on out,
you guys are all in my cool book.
Now, Scotty, I want you to help me
with Richie. We're gonna lay him down
on the couch over there.
Jacob, you're gonna keep driving
down this street...
until you come to another street
called Digallo.
When you get to Digallo, you're
gonna turn this big bastard left...
and you're gonna go down a couple
of miles until you see a bar
called the Titty Twister.
From what I understand,
you cannot miss it.
- Then?
- And then you stop...
because that's where we're goin'.
Listen. Don't make a career
out of this, okay? Come on. Hey.
Hey. You okay?
Yeah, I think so.
What happened?
I don't know.
You just passed out.
- I did?
- You said something
about your hand hurtin'...
and then you just hit the ground
like a sack of potatoes.
- Really?
- Head hit the toilet.
You scared the shit out of me.
You sure you're okay there?
Yeah, I-I think so.
I'm just a little fucked up.
Well, let me tell you something
that's gonna clear your head right up.
- What?
- We are officially Mexicans.
- We're in Mexico, buddy.
- We are?
Yeah, we're headin' down
to the rendezvous right now.
We're gonna pound booze,
wait for Carlos.
When he gets there,
he's gonna take us down to El Rey.
And then you and I, my brother,
we're gonna kick fuckin' back.
How you like them apples?
Far out.
- Where's my glasses?
- Oh, uh, yeah, they, uh...
They broke when you fell.
- Fuck, Seth!
These are, like, my only pair.
- Well, don't worry about it.
- We'll get you another pair.
- What do you mean, don't worry about it?
Of course I'm gonna worry about it.
- I can't fuckin' see!
- I'll take care of it when we get
to El Rey.
Yeah, like some Mexican
hole in the wall's gonna
have my fuckin' prescription.
It-lt's not a big deal
until you make it a big deal, Richie.
Now, I was in a very good mood, so stop
bringing me down with this bullshit!
I can't wear this shit.
Hey, guys. We're here.
All right.
Pussy, pussy, pussy!
Come on in, pussy lovers!
Here at the Titty Twister,
we're slashing pussy in half.
Give us an offer on our best selection
of pussy. This is a pussy blowout!
All right, we got white pussy, black
pussy, Spanish pussy, yellow pussy.
We got hot pussy, cold pussy.
We got wet pussy. We got smelly pussy.
We got hairy pussy, bloody pussy.
We got snappin' pussy.
We got silk pussy, velvet pussy,
Naugahyde pussy.
We even got horse pussy, dog pussy,
chicken pussy.
Come on. You want pussy?
Come on in, pussy lovers.
If we don't got it, you don't want it.
Come on!
Okay, troops, it's the homestretch.
Here's the deal.
This place closes at dawn.
Carlos is gonna meet us here
sometime before dawn.
Now, we are gonna go in there.
We're gonna take a seat.
We're gonna have a drink.
We're gonna have a bunch of drinks.
And we're gonna wait for Carlos.
Let me say something.
I'm very happy about where we're at.
We got a real, nice...
l-don't-fuck-with-you, you-don't-
fuck-with-me attitude goin' on.
So if everybody just
keeps playin' it cool...
and I'm talkin' to you too, Richie...
then everybody's gonna get
what they want.
Okay, hard drinkers. Let's drink hard.
I'm buyin'. Come on.
Here we go.
Out of the stew pot
and into the fire.
Attention, pussy shoppers!
Take advantage of our penny pussy sale.
If you buy one piece of pussy
at the regular price...
you'll get another piece of pussy of
equal or lesser value for only a penny.
Try and beat pussy for a penny!
If you can find cheaper pussy anywhere,
fuck it!
Hey, what do we have approaching here?
A new flavour: Apple pie pussy.
- Hey, not so fast, slick.
- Step aside, asshole.
Now, is my shit together
or is my shit together?
Here we go.
Hi. How ya doin'?
Enjoying it? I hope so.
Now...
this is my kind of place.
I could become a regular.
Whisky.
- You can't come in here.
- What do you mean?
It's a private bar.
You're not welcome.
Are you tellin' me that I'm
not good enough to drink here?
This bar is for bikers
and truckers only.
You, get out!
- Take your hand off of me.
- I'm gonna count to three.
No, I'm gonna count to three.
- One.
- Two.
- Now, wait a minute.
There's no reason to get ugly.
There is just a misunderstanding
going on here.
You said this bar is
for truckers and bikers?
Well, I'm a truck driver.
If you look outside your door
in your parking lot, you'll see...
a big recreational vehicle.
That's mine. In order
to drive that legally...
you need a Class Two driver's licence.
This bar is for truck drivers?
I am a truck driver.
And these are my friends.
Welcome to the Titty Twister.
Bottle of whisky and five glasses.
Coming right out.
- They serve food here, Jose?
- The best in Mexico.
I kind of doubt that.
We're gonna go over here. You send
a waitress over to take our order, okay?
Yeah!
Mary had a little lamb
His fleece was black as coal, yeah
Any time you want a lap dance
with that girl, kid,
just let me know, all right?
It's on me.
- He followed her to school
- Pass.
- Is it against your religion?
- No, I do drink.
I'm just not drinkin' now.
Fair enough. More for me.
Scott, how 'bout you?
- No.
- Kate, how 'bout you?
No, I can't. I'm not 21 yet.
That means yes.
Post time, Kate!
Here we go. You slam it down, you knock
the glass down on the table, all right?
One, two, three!
Thattagirl, Kate.
Scotty, you ready? Here we go.
You ready for one?
- Okay.
- No, you won't.
Yes, he will. Yes, he will,
because I'm not drinkin' by myself.
- Kate, round two.
You ready? Here we go.
- Yes, I'll have another one. Thank you.
On three. One, two, three.
Why are you so agitated?
I'm still stewin' about that ape
layin' his hand on me.
- What are you gonna do?
- I'm gonna sit here,
and I'm gonna finish this bottle.
And when I am finished,
I'm gonna take this bottle...
and I'm gonna bust it
over his melon fucking head.
Before we stepped in here,
you told all of us to be cool.
- So that means you too.
- I never said do what I do.
I said do what I say.
On my way I passed it
Express yourself
Are you such a fucking loser...
you can't tell when you've won?
- What'd you call me?
- Nothing.
I didn't make a statement.
I asked a question.
Would you like me to ask it again?
Are you such a loser,
you can't tell when you've won?
The entire state of Texas,
along with the FBI...
are looking for you.
Did they find you?
No, they couldn't.
You've won, Seth.
Enjoy it.
Jacob...
I want you to have a drink with me.
I insist.
To your family.
To yours.
And now, for your viewing pleasure...
the Mistress of the Macabre...
the Epitome of Evil,
the most sinister woman to ever dance
on the face of this Earth...
- Bite this!
- Lowly dog.
Bow your head.
Kneel and worship at the feet...
of Santanico Pandemonium!
Watching her
Strolling in the night
So right, wondering why
It's only after dark
In her eyes
The distant firelight
Burns bright, wondering why
It's only after dark
Find myself
In her room
Feel the fever
Of my doom
Falling, falling
through the floor
I'm knocking on
the devil's door, yeah
Burning, burning
In the flame
Now that I know her secret name
You can tell whose heaven will go
But she'll be back
and through the gate
That's what I call a fuckin' show!
Come here!
- That guy. It's the puta over there.
- Richie, get back on the clock.
- How many?
- Three.
Which one?
This piece of shit here, man...
broke my finger and my nose!
And this faggot kicked me in the ribs
while I was down.
- Up!
- Fuck off, bogeyman!
Fuck!
All right, everybody be cool, or you'll
be just as dead as these fucks!
How's your hand?
Let me see it.
Shit.
Do you think that was funny?
Sit down!
- Richie, look out!
- Motherfuckin' shit!
- Get the fuck off!
- Hey! Hey!
- Get her off me!
What the fuck are you doing?
Shoot her!
I'm comin', buddy!
- Richie. Richie.
- Fuckin' bitch.
Richie.
Fuckin' bitch.
Hey. Hey.
Hey.
What the fuck?
Dinner is served.
Fuck!
Get off me, man!
Come on! Come on, you!
Jacob!
No, no, no!
Look out! Look out!
You know what everybody
says about me, huh?
I suck!
Let's see if you taste
as good as your brother.
Fuck you.
Hey, hey, hey!
Oh, shit.
Huh?
Give me that!
I'm not gonna drain you
completely.
You'll be my slave.
Because I don't think
you're worthy of human blood...
you'll feed on the blood
of stray dogs.
You'll be my footstool,
and at my command...
you'll lick the dog shit
from my boot heel.
- Oh.
- Since you'll be my dog...
your new name will be Spot.
Welcome to slavery.
No, thanks.
I already had a wife.
We might be in trouble.
Yo. Monkey man.
Anything you got
to say to them...
you can say to me first.
That's enough.
Ain't they supposed to
burn up or somethin'?
Fuck.
Now let's kill that fucking band.
I can do that.
Fuck you, everybody!
Good night!
Fuckers.
Hey, buddy.
I'm sorry
I fucked things up, Richie.
You would've liked it in El Rey.
You would've...
You would've found peace there.
I love you, buddy.
I love you too, Seth.
You touch my brother
with that stake, biker...
and vampires aren't gonna have to
suck your blood; they'll be able to
lick it up off the floor.
- He's not your brother any more.
- That's a matter of opinion,
and I don't give a fuck about yours.
Don't be a fool!
He'll kill us all.
- Shut up!
Let's go. Move. Move. Move.
Hold him down.
Richie, here is the peace in death...
that I could not give you
in life.
Fuck.
Seth, are you okay?
I'm peachy. Okay?
The world is my oyster.
Except for the fact that I just...
I just rammed a wooden stake
into my brother's chest...
because he turned into a vampire...
even though
I don't believe in vampires.
Aside from that
unfortunate business...
everything is hunky-dory.
- I'm really, really sorry.
- Bullshit! Bullshit!
If it were to up to you
if you had half a chance,
you would feed us to those fucks.
Then why didn't I?
I'm sorry you lost your brother.
I'm sorry he's dead.
I'm sorry everybody's dead.
But if we're gonna get out of this we
need you clean and sober and thinking...
not drunk.
- What is that?
- Don't know.
First I thought it was just birds.
It's bats.
Give me a hand.
Hey!
Whoa.
You're dead! Oh!
Come on!
We'll take care of this mess.
Go stake the rest of those ugly fucks.
I'm way ahead of you.
- Watch your step.
What's your name, girlie?
- Kate. What's yours?
- Sex Machine.
Pleased to meet you, Kate.
- Me too.
Okay.
- Is everybody okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
- Does anybody know
what's going on here?
- I know what's going on.
We got a bunch of fuckin' vampires
out there trying to get in here
and suck our fuckin' blood.
And that's it.
Plain and simple.
And I don't wanna hear anything about
"I don't believe in vampires"...
because I don't fucking believe
in vampires...
but I believe in my own two eyes
and what I saw is fucking vampires.
Now, do we all agree that
what we are dealing with is vampires?
- Yes.
- You too, Preacher?
- I don't believe in vampires,
but I believe in what I saw.
- Good for you.
All right, now that we all agree
that we're dealing with vampires,
what do we know about vampires?
Crosses hurt vampires.
Do we have a cross?
- In the motorhome.
- In other words, no.
Wait a second. I mean, just look around.
We got crosses all over the place.
All you gotta do is put two sticks
together and you got a cross.
Yeah, he's right.
Peter Cushing does that all the time.
Okay, I'll buy that.
So we got crosses covered. What else?
Wooden stakes in the heart
been workin' pretty good so far.
And garlic. Sunlight. Holy water.
I'm not sure... Eh, doesn't silver
have somethin' to do with vampires?
- That's werewolves.
- I know silver bullets
are werewolves...
but I'm sure silver has
something to do with vampires.
Well, does anybody have
any silver?
Okay. Then who cares?
Has anybody here read
a real book about vampires...
or are we just remembering
what some movie said?
- I mean, a real book.
- You me... You mean,
like a Time-Life book?
I take it the answer's no.
Okay, then, what do we know
about these vampires?
Well, we know they got superhuman
strength, but we can hurt 'em.
- Yeah.
- Another thing, though.
If you're gonna drive a chair leg
through a human, you'd better be
one strong son of a bitch.
I mean, the human body
is one rough, tough machine.
But these vamps... these vamps,
they're, they're, they have soft bodies.
The texture of their skin is softer.
They're mushier.
You can push it right through them.
You see, but if you hit one hard enough,
take their head right off.
Actually, our best weapon
against these satanic cocksuckers...
is this man.
He's a preacher.
As far as God's concerned, we might
as well all be a piece of shit...
but he is one of the boys.
Only one problem:
His faith isn't what it used to be.
I've had enough of your taunts.
I'm not taunting you, Jacob.
We need you.
A faithless preacher
doesn't mean shit to us.
A servant of God can take a cross
and shove it up these monsters' asses.
A servant of God can bless the tap water
and make it a weapon.
Jacob, I know
why you lost your faith.
How could holiness exist...
if your wife can be taken away
from you and the children?
I've always said
that God can kiss my ass...
but I just changed my lifetime tune
about 30 minutes ago...
'cause I know that whatever
is out there tryin' to get in...
is pure evil straight from hell.
And if there is a hell
and those sons of bitches are from it...
then there has got to be
a heaven, Jacob, there's gotta be.
So, which are you?
Are you a faithless preacher, or are you
a mean motherfuckin' servant of God?
I'm a mean...
servant of God.
I don't know if I can take
much more of that noise.
Sure you can.
You can take it
because you got no choice.
How'd you like to spend 24 hours of it
lyin' in some muddy ditch...
with nothing but the rotten corpses
of your friends to keep you company?
What are you talking about?
I was in 'Nam back in '72.
I was trapped behind enemy lines
with my entire squad dead.
They thought
they had killed everyone.
Except for me,
they was right.
But it wasn't for
their lack of tryin'.
A grenade blew up right beside me.
That's why I'm so pretty.
And they started pushin'
all them bodies in on top of me...
and all I could do was lay there,
play possum...
listen to the enemy joke, laugh.
Hour after hour after hour
I lay...
- Kill them. Kill them all.
- Kill them.
- Kill them all.
Sex Machine.
- Kill them.
Kill them!
So I finally climbed
out of this hole...
and I sneaked up on the enemy
while he was sleepin'...
and I killed one,
two, three, four, five...
When I came to my senses...
I realized I'd killed
an entire V.C. Squad single-handed.
There was blood...
and chunks of yellow flesh
clinging to my bayonet.
To this day, I don't remember...
Get it off of me! Get it off of me!
Please! Get it off!
No!
Dad!
Fuckin' bit me.
Fuckin' bit me!
- What are you gonna do about it?
- Come on, Sex Machine!
Oh, shit!
Get up. Get up! Up! Come on!
Go! Come on!
- Wait. We have to go back
for my father.
- Your dad's dead, Kate.
He is the light.
The people who walk...
in the darkness...
have seen the light!
Open the door!
- Go! Go!
- Daddy!
Jacob, are you bit?
Yeah.
Motherfuck.
Motherfucking vampires!
I'm gonna kill every last one
of you godless fuckin' pieces of shit!
You bet you are, and I'm gonna help
you do it. But we ain't got much time.
- You're gonna be okay, aren't you?
- No, I'm not.
I've been bit.
In fact, I'm already dead.
Now, I'd say in the next
20 or 30 minutes...
our friends outside
will bust in this door...
and I'll probably turn into a vampire
within the hour.
Now, you have two choices: You can wait
for me to turn, then deal with me,
or we can kick open that door...
and the four of us can go at 'em,
hit 'em with everything we have.
But if we're gonna go at 'em,
we gotta go at 'em now.
What's this stuff?
My guess is this little dive
has been feeding on bikers
and truckers for a long time.
This is probably the shipments
that they stole off the trucks.
Well, I say let's tear
this place apart for weapons...
so when they burst through the door
we'll make 'em wish they never did.
I don't care about livin' or dyin'
any more. I just wanna send as many
of these devils back to hell as I can.
Amen.
Loving God, bless this water and give us
your protection and strength...
- in this, our darkest hour. Amen.
- Amen.
Before we go any further I need
you three to promise me something.
I'll fight with you to the bitter end,
but when I turn into one of them...
I won't be Jacob any more.
I'll be a lapdog of Satan.
I want you three to promise you'll take
me down, no different from the rest.
I promise, Jacob.
Kate? Scott?
- I promise.
- Scott.
Yeah, I promise.
Why don't I believe you?
I'm gonna ask you two again.
Then I want you to swear to God
that you'll kill me!
If you don't, I'm gonna just
kill myself right now.
Now, since you need me
I think you'd better swear!
Kate, do you swear to God...
that when I become one of the undead
you'll kill me?
Kate! We don't have much time, so I'm
only giving you to the count of five.
One, two, three, four...
Okay! All right!
I promise I'll do it!
Good girl. Now, Scott,
we have even less time...
so I'm givin' you
to the count of three.
- One...
- You don't...
You don't believe in suicide.
It's not suicide
if you're already dead. Two!
Okay! Okay.
I'll kill you when you change.
I swear to God in Jesus Christ's name.
- Thank you, son.
- Okay, vampire killers.
Let's kill some fuckin' vampires.
Come out of darkness
and see the light.
From the darkness to light.
Come out of darkness
and see the light.
Kill 'em all!
Come on! Come on!
Dad?
Dad, not y... Aah!
Dad! Dad! Dad!
I swear to God
in Jesus Christ's name.
- Oh, my God!
- Fight now, cry later!
Get the fuck off!
No! Get off! Get off! Off! Get off!
Kill me, Kate.
Just kill me, Kate.
I can't.
- How many bullets do you have?
- I don't know. Not many.
When you run out, start cold-cockin'
'em. Make 'em sing for their supper.
Seth, should I save
the last bullets for us?
No. Use it on the next fuck
that tries to bite you.
Shoot more holes.
Shoot more holes!
- Perfect.
- Oh, they can't go into the light.
Perfect.
All right, go.
Seth, don't leave me.
Hey! Come on, then. Come on.
Come here. Come on!
Come on, you! Come on!
Come here, you fucks!
Hello!
I'm looking for my friend Seth!
Carlos! Kick in the door!
- Go!
- Son of a bitch.
What the fuck
was goin' on in there?
What's the matter with you?
Are you crazy?
Why, out of all the godforsaken
shitholes in Mexico...
do we have to meet here?
One place is just as good
as another.
- You never been here before?
- No.
I drove by it a couple times.
It's a rowdy place. It's out in the
middle of nowhere. There'll be no cops.
And it's open from dusk till dawn.
Hey, didn't you say you wanted
to meet in the morning? Here we are.
Well, since you just picked this place
out of a hat, my brother is dead.
That girl's
entire fucking family is dead.
- What, were they psychos, or...
- They look like psychos?
Is that what they looked like?
They were vampires.
Psychos do not explode
when sunlight hits 'em.
I don't give a fuck
how crazy they are.
Seth, how can I make it up to you?
Can't... You can't make it up to me,
Carlos. I tell you, you can't do it.
Can't make it up.
Fifteen percent instead of
thirty percent for my stay in El Rey.
That's a good start.
- Twenty-eight.
- My brother's gone.
You understand that? He's gone, and he's
not coming back, and that is your fault.
Twenty.
- Twenty-five.
Kate, go to the RV,
get the suitcase.
You look like hell.
You want a cold beer?
I got some in the car.
Come on. They're cold. Huh?
I got Mexican and domestic.
- So, how do you like the car?
- It's all right.
I said "like new."
This is a '90.
Hey, it is new, cabron. Belonged
to a drug dealer friend of mine.
Hey, he only drove it, like,
14 times in five years.
It's like new, I swear to God.
- So, what do I do, follow you?
- Yeah. Follow me.
All right, let's do it.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, I'm sorry too.
- I'll see you.
- Seth.
You need some company?
Kate, do you know where I'm going?
Do you know what El Rey is?
- No.
- Hey, Seth.
It's time to go.
Go home, Kate.
I may be a bastard,
but I'm not a fuckin' bastard.