Yes, Bernard.
Exactly.
A painter without a ladder is like...
Or a baker without sugar.
Take Pablo's.
The facade will be done by tonight.
The scaffolding's back.
I'll talk to them
about colors inside.
Okay, thanks, Bernard.
Goodbye. See you tomorrow.
To Paint or Make Love
Who's painting?
Good day, sir.
It's a woman.
- She's the painter?
- Yes.
At last!
Where are you?
Here.
Speak to me!
The air is whirling.
I'm here.
Sorry I called you sir.
The smell of paint
covered your fragrance.
It doesn't matter.
Are you lost?
No, not at all. Don't worry.
I often come here.
It's on my route.
It's only here,
exactly where we are,
that I can make out shapes.
Shapes?
Yes, shapes,
like currents of colored air.
Yellow, orange, rust.
They're like...
Flames?
Flames, yes,
but comforting flames.
Like a volcano but...
without the sulfur or eruptions.
A very gentle volcano.
A breeze
that's warm and silent.
Just the wind in the leaves.
Yes, of course
but I'm only an amateur.
I paint landscapes to get fresh air
and wind down after work.
Am I bothering you?
I can move away.
No, not at all.
Is the house at the end of the field
in your painting?
No, but...
Let's go visit. It's for sale.
I'm the mayor of the village.
I know where the key is.
It will only take a few minutes.
Do you mind guiding me?
We'll step into your painting.
My name is Adam.
Madeleine.
Home ownership is an emotion too.
Madeleine, it's me again.
Everyone's waiting.
I don't know what's for dinner.
I'll serve drinks.
These winding roads
are dangerous at nightfall.
The deer are out. They cross.
Bang! It happens in no time.
- Retirement anxiety?
- Early retirement.
It's not easy.
Weather is a real passion,
not just a job.
I know.
It took me time
to forget teaching and mathematics.
Then one day,
you realize there are
more exciting things in a man's life.
I feel completely useless.
Elise called me this afternoon,
for two seconds,
to say she got
an architecture residency
at the Villa... something, in Italy.
The Villa Medicis.
What an opportunity
for your daughter.
Yes but...
she's never traveled.
We won't see her anymore.
In Rome! That's fantastic.
You two will be able to visit.
Where's Madeleine?
It's almost dark.
Dear William, you don't know
what happiness awaits.
All that free time still scares you
because it's so new.
The eternal vacation
you dreamed of as a kid...
Don't deny it.
It's yours at last.
You mean the last stretch before...
For your outfit, drop by the store.
It's a wonderful sport.
- About time!
- Hello, everyone.
Why are you sitting in the dark?
- You're getting mud everywhere.
- Sorry!
Fresh country air!
At sunset, a cool breeze sets in.
It's so invigorating.
It's amazing how many wild animals
you see at nightfall.
William, didn't you reheat
the rabbit stew?
I completely forgot.
Let's eat. I'll get the boar pate.
Let's eat.
Who'll get me a glass of port?
Smoking again?
No.
You're lacking magnesium.
Maybe.
Now I don't work,
I have nothing to tell you.
Let's take a walk.
Now?
You're free, aren't you?
What do you think?
The advantages of the country:
calm, charm and beauty,
without the isolation.
Unfortunately, Ma'am,
walnut orchards
are renowned for being damp.
Cool in summer.
This magnificent walnut drier
is sold with the farmhouse.
Home ownership is an emotion too.
It's exactly the aspect you want:
facing sunrise at dusk
and the Vercors sunset at night.
How much is it?
140,000, agency fees included.
Double with renovations.
For an old retired bachelor...
Old! Come now, Mr. Lassere.
Many women find you attractive.
Take me for example.
I've wanted you from day one.
Come here.
I don't know what got into me.
Not at all. It's been a long time.
Ready? I have to get going.
I'll take it.
- What?
- The house. We're buying it.
It is for sale?
You're not rushing it?
- Who's selling?
- I don't know.
I met the village mayor by chance.
He told me.
Okay. You can go back.
I'll work it out.
I have time. A whole lifetime.
Don't worry. Everything's fine.
See you tonight, darling.
Got your cell phone?
- You'll call me?
- I'll call you.
Hello, Elise? It's Dad.
I have some big news too.
There are...
There are snowfalls in Kergellen
The coral in Vanua Levou
The "Hello, how are you?"
There are worries and heartaches
Religions and gurus
Big questions that are taboo
You can see that man is mad
Mad like someone in love
There are...
There are Indians and totems
Rocky mountains and gold diggers
Travelers and meteors
There are the secrets of poems
A hundred thousand other treasures
Like evening or daybreak
You can see he ignores them all
For he knows that Jessie loves him
Goodbye.
Have a nice weekend.
Perfect timing, darling.
Light mist, mild autumn, rising sap,
first night in dream home,
starlit dinner with new friends...
What dinner? Grass clippings?
Roast roasting.
Time for gardening together
in new room.
Adam!
Don't move!
Sorry, I didn't warn you.
I planted it yesterday.
My fault. I should have smelt it.
It seems magnificent.
Or sturdy at least.
And its fragrance
is as delicate as yours.
Hello, Adam.
That must be... Eva.
Eva?
My wife's name is Eva.
I didn't tell you?
No.
I know what people
are like in the valley.
How could they elect you?
Close your eyes.
Done.
See how dependent you are
when you live in the dark.
Absolutely.
They asked me to run for office.
I was elected.
I realized nobody dared lie to me.
They assumed I had the power
to read everyone's mind
like an open book.
Look, William's running off.
He's hiding something.
Not at all.
I'm getting the roast.
We're out of wine.
I love you.
It's as mild as it is in June.
We called it an Indian summer
in my weather days.
We should let you
enjoy your first night here.
I have something for you.
It's a surprise for me too.
Here.
It's the painting I started
when we met the first time
in the field.
Eva will describe it better than me.
If you like it, it's yours.
This enchanted evening
must have been under its spell.
We like it very much already.
- Does it have a title?
- I don't know...
"Sun going down on..."
Or maybe
"Sunset over the Vercors"!
I think they're very lonely.
I feel so small.
I feel proud.
It's full of new sounds.
- Time for bed?
- Yes.
I think I have an idea.
Hello.
I don't want to bother you.
I came to invite you
to dinner tonight.
Why not? Yes, we'd love to.
See you tonight.
I'm going to the village.
He's always flat out
at the weekend.
I like your painting a lot.
Really? Thanks.
I felt embarrassed.
I painted it so fast
and I didn't touch it up.
I'd like you to do my portrait.
I'm flattered but I'm not sure I can.
I've never done it.
I've never posed.
We'll improvise.
Okay, why not?
- Can we try?
- Now?
Okay then.
This way.
Here?
Fine.
I'm diving in.
It's been so long
since anyone saw me.
- Do you like...
- Who?
The cart.
Welcome.
Hello.
- How are you?
- Fine.
Go ahead. Step inside.
The last six months
have been intense.
But it's strange.
I feel I lived them in reverse.
Like I'm ten years younger.
What were you doing
ten years ago?
The cold snaps of '95.
Another Glenfiddich?
Yes, please.
Are you happy with the spot
where we hung your painting?
It's embarrassing...
Sorry!
Nonetheless,
the true value of a work of art
lies in the atmosphere
that develops around it.
Your sunset in our bedroom
will have an interesting influence
on our nights.
What do you want to drink
after all this excitement?
A glass of port.
There are a few caves
painted in prehistoric times
where there is no trace of fire
and no light source.
They painted...
We painted
at that time and in certain places,
in complete darkness.
They never saw
the shapes we see now in the caves.
They caressed them.
These paintings
are invisible sculptures,
like everything around me.
When I was a student,
I worked as a guide in a cave.
A man visited regularly.
He had lost his sight.
He didn't know my name
but I learned his: Adam.
He asked me to describe
the shapes of the bears.
The women's genitals,
the men running after their arrows.
Once, after a visit, for fun,
I asked him to describe me.
He described a naked belly dancer.
I decided to become
his invisible wife.
I often feel I see
through Eva's eyes.
Like when you're in love.
Do you mind?
Go ahead.
You have it?
It was playing when we first met.
Good night.
Sorry, I forgot the flashlight.
Could you lend us one?
We haven't owned a flashlight
for ages.
I'll give you a lift.
It's okay, Eva.
It takes no time through the forest.
Let's go.
Give me your hand, Madeleine.
Take William's.
I'll be back soon.
Are you sure?
Hear the stream on your right?
Yes.
For 120 steps,
you keep it by your right ear.
- Everything okay?
- Yes.
Feel the different breeze?
Very clearly.
Now we take a left.
We'll soon feel grass...
What's that?
A wild boar.
We're walking against the wind.
- Where are you?
- Come to me.
Nothing's in your way.
Come to me.
There's Madeleine's hand.
No, it's William's.
Let's go.
It goes downhill but not for long.
Knees up.
We're going over a dead tree.
Recognize the grass?
It's the sunset field.
Is it?
Your field, Madeleine.
Here's the rosebush. You're home.
Do you think?
So, if we're home,
the light must be...
here!
Thanks a lot, Adam.
I'll be going. Good night.
Will you be okay?
I'll drive you home.
Don't worry.
What is it?
A cart.
Very nice.
My God!
See, it's at their place.
It's us!
I was so scared!
Come on. Don't stay here.
How did it happen?
I don't get it.
I didn't smell a thing.
Wow, they look great!
So, what are you up to?
We haven't heard
since you moved.
You look radiant.
Look at you.
- You've toned up.
- It's the gardening.
- Smoking again?
- No.
How's the new life coming along?
It's wonderful!
They live at your place?
The council couldn't help?
It must be hard work.
No, it's going really well.
How long's it for?
We asked Adam and Eva
to move in with us.
All that's left is four black walls.
Furniture, books, clothes.
Up in smoke.
Imagine losing
your whole history in a few hours.
They were literally
stripped bare overnight.
How long will it take
to make sense of it?
They don't know and nor do we
but we'll be there until they do.
How's Elise?
Everything okay in Rome?
No news is good news.
Can we start playing?
I said I'd be back early.
No coffee?
He's motivated for once.
You're picking me up?
Tonight at 7 o'clock.
I have to go too.
You're not playing?
I open the store at 3:00.
Janine's away.
- Let's go swimming some time.
- We can try.
Hey, I know.
Would you lend us the chalet
this weekend?
Why not?
I don't know what we're doing.
I'll ask Jean-Marc.
Can you call me later?
Hello there!
You're home early.
For me?
For you and our friends.
For our friends and you.
What's the weather forecast?
Blue skies. Why?
The four of us are going
to the mountains.
I'd love to.
We're home!
They've gone shopping.
Adam was going
to the town hall today.
- What's for dinner?
- Duck in orange sauce.
Adam and Eva won't be here
for dinner. They're seeing friends.
They could have called.
Last minute decision.
That's my point.
In this weather,
they'll stay overnight.
So much for the forecast!
It's a local low pressure front.
I'm worried about mud.
Maybe they're bored here with us.
Want some cognac?
We can't wait all night.
I'm going up.
What's the forecast for tomorrow?
Where's the remote control?
Hello.
You've been shopping.
I feel all new.
This afternoon I had a dream.
For the first time,
our house wasn't on fire.
It was an underwater house.
I swam through the living room
to get your painting.
The water was very clear,
very peaceful.
We're sleeping better
now the Azores anticyclone has hit.
- You didn't predict the rain!
- True.
How was your evening?
Very emotional.
They're people
we haven't seen for years.
Since we first met.
They're jazz musicians.
They were playing here.
We dropped in on them.
Did you find our note?
You didn't come home for us?
No.
We have some good news.
The insurance company
will pay all reconstruction costs.
That's excellent news.
We'll even get money
for immediate costs.
We'll rent something locally.
It's time for us to ease up on you.
You've been great the last 10 days.
Let's discuss it tomorrow.
It'll be blue skies all weekend.
We're leaving you some time alone.
Our friends invited us
to the Montreux Festival.
It's more fun with jazz musicians
than with us in a little chalet!
- Madeleine...
- Oh, you!
We wanted to surprise you
with a weekend away.
I was coming up.
Sorry, I don't know
what came over me.
I work too hard.
Some fresh mountain air
will do us good.
I'd love to hear
the glaciers crack.
We can see
our friends play any time.
Let's spend the weekend together.
Coming up?
Yes, let's go up.
What happens now?
Nothing.
I can't...
I can't paint.
Come here.
Ready?
We need some sleep.
Are you okay?
Fine.
It's fine.
A wild boar.
- Did you hit it?
- I don't know.
Maybe I killed it.
Did you find the car?
Good.
No, the sooner the better.
We'll get the bodywork done later.
About 6 o'clock? Thanks.
Two coffees, please.
Got any cigarettes?
You smell.
Does it bother you?
Do you have a room?
Yes. Room 11 or 17.
The keys are on the board.
It's 40 euros.
Thanks.
What time is it?
I don't know. Late.
- I dozed off.
- Me too.
It hurts.
It's 5 o'clock.
No message.
Maybe they were true friends.
We ruined it.
I started it
and they didn't dare refuse.
That's exactly
where they want you.
They're cunning. You feel guilty
when it's their fault.
We were completely...
Fucked over.
Adam's not blind, we were.
We were manipulated.
They're swingers,
they're very dangerous.
We have to get rid of them.
We're losing our grip.
- Does it still hurt?
- Yes.
Let's go home.
You're right.
They understood.
They've already gone.
Or they're with the musicians.
It's over, my love.
The room's empty.
Want a drink?
I'm sorry.
What for?
I'll get it.
Yes, it's me.
No, we didn't get away.
We had an accident.
No, a roebuck.
Very early this morning.
Okay, why not?
Fine. Let's do that.
It was Suzanne.
I'll make dinner.
Jean-Marc and Suzanne want
to go mushrooming tomorrow.
Excellent idea.
Coming up?
Go up. I'll deal with it.
It's open.
Hello.
The Italians.
Dad, this is Joao.
- Hello, Villiam.
- Wi-lliam.
Joao is Brazilian.
- Mom's in bed?
- Yes... no.
- Everything okay?
- Yes.
You're locking Elise and Joao in.
Sorry.
Where will
the mayor and his wife live now?
That's their problem.
It's not easy
living on top of each other.
Take your cell phone.
Adam.
How are you?
What?
The night in...
Tomorrow night in Futuna?
Where are they?
What did they say?
Tomorrow night in Futuna.
Is Futuna in the Pacific?
Absolutely.
I'm worried.
Maybe they'll call back.
I'll go home.
I'll come too.
Don't wait for us.
Something wrong?
No, go without us.
Hello.
Nobody called?
- Did you sleep well?
- Yes.
The room is lovely.
It's cyclone season in the Pacific.
What did you say?
Maybe I heard him wrong.
Do you mind the music?
Not at all.
- Want one?
- No.
Still painting?
I'm fed up with still lives.
William?
Yes, it's me.
It's Adam.
Where are you?
We're in Paris.
We fly to Sydney tomorrow.
The day after, we'll be
on the Pacific island, Futuna.
William, can you hear me?
I'm sorry about yesterday morning.
And we were mushrooming earlier.
My phone didn't work.
We're the ones who apologize.
Eva and I were distraught.
We panicked when you left.
I decided to take up an offer
a friend made when he heard.
We left immediately.
I hope we didn't hurt your feelings.
I'm truly sorry.
Don't be. It's our fault. I mean...
How long will you stay there?
We're not coming back.
You and Madeleine
were fantastic with us
but we were shattered by the fire.
We don't feel
up to living there again.
We'll sell the house
as soon as it's rebuilt.
It's not possible...
What's wrong?
My daughter's
getting married next month.
We hoped you would...
Of course, William.
We can come back for it.
I'll resign from the council
just after.
That's fantastic.
How do we do this?
I'll back in a few days
and we'll fix a date.
Okay, perfect.
Is Eva okay?
She's fine.
She's by my side.
She sends her love.
Me too.
Well?
They're distraught.
Where are they?
Heading for the Pacific.
They're fine.
You mean the mayor and his wife?
Yes. The ones who lost everything.
- They'll come back?
- Yes.
When?
In a month or two, if...
Go ahead.
Right now?
Joao and I are getting married.
We'd like to do it here,
in the village.
- Are you pregnant?
- No.
But it could happen.
That's wonderful.
- When's Adam coming?
- Whenever we want.
Let's drink a toast.
Done!
What did they say exactly?
Why did they leave?
We left, not them.
I was wrong, Madeleine.
I'm sorry. They're so sensitive.
This wedding is an excellent idea.
If you say so.
We always begin life
in an admirable twilight.
Everything that later helps us
transcend disappointments
depends on our first steps.
Madeleine's field!
Sweet as the first day.
To think yesterday
we walked on golden sands.
It's a miracle
you were only an hour late.
What time is it there...
in the Pacific?
The sun's rising.
We're about to wake up.
Where's your luggage?
At the hotel.
The hotel?
We thought that for a few days...
Elise and Joao are sleeping upstairs
but we set up a bed in the studio.
Madeleine, that's very sweet,
but stop worrying about us.
You have enough to do.
Have you seen them?
Not for a while.
They hardly spoke to us.
- We make them sick.
- No, it's jetlag.
I forgot where I was.
Somewhere in heaven.
We're going to a club,
the New Lagoon.
How are our travelers?
Sorry, we couldn't help it.
Sorry we put you through this
in the state you're in.
Now you must be starving.
- Don't let us spoil it for you.
- We're off to the New Lagoon.
Coming?
Go ahead. We're coming.
Let's go.
I can tell you're hungry.
Are the islands as pleasant as they say?
Very.
You're going back...
At the end of next week.
I'm scared it will rain.
It's ridiculous.
Don't stay at the hotel.
Stay here.
The studio's almost ready.
You're exhausted.
Do you really
want to go to a nightclub?
You know me.
In that case...
the only problem
is our toothbrushes.
I'll make the bed.
I'll help you.
Don't bother, Eva.
It's done except for the sheets.
I'll go get a...
They talk about death
Like you talk about fruit
They look at the sea
Like you look at a well
The women are lascivious
In the fearsome sun
Although it's not winter
Nor is it summer
Rain cuts across
Pelting grain by grain
A few old white horses
Are humming Gauguin
For lack of a breeze
Time stands still
On the Marquesas
From darkness, fires rise
And dots of silence
They expand outwards
This gives a softer light.
The sea tears itself apart
Infinitely shattered
By rocks that take on
Delirious names
There in the distance, dogs
Chants of repentance
And a few dance moves
And a few dance steps
Can I make myself useful?
Anyone home?
You turned off...
the light.
Are you here, William?
Yes.
Welcome.
We're over here.
Has the sun risen?
Yes.
I wish I could see you.
Why don't we move to your island?
We could go for a month,
and come back to sell the houses.
I'll sell the company
to my workers.
You didn't come.
No, we're sorry, darling.
No problem.
See you later.
Elise will visit more
if we're in the Pacific.
"Couple Making Love
in a Lotus Flower"
Gauguin.
Painter of the islands.
Ma'am?
I drifted off!
It's all done.
Perfect.
You can go, Bernard.
See you tomorrow.
See you.
Goodbye, Fabrice.
I'll pass on your offer
to the owners tonight.
We're in touch by e-mail.
We'll call you early next week.
Okay.
- And the other house for sale?
- It's ours.
- It's sold.
- Already?
Already.
Goodbye.
Ghastly people
with their pools and ponies.
What counts is to sell.
Not just this house but ours too.
If you won't let anyone visit...
I know but they were
unbearable enough here.
His face when you said,
"It's a waterfall in the rain."
- Shall we go home?
- Let's go.
By foot?
- What about the cars?
- We'll get them tomorrow.
That's for us.
Another one?
I thought we were done.
Hello, Mr. Lassere?
Sorry to turn up unannounced.
We saw your ad for the house
by chance.
We don't live here
but we often pass by.
We were at Lake Leman.
We lost our phone
but we wanted to visit.
Come in.
They were at Lake Leman.
Lucky you!
We were having a drink.
Join us.
Why not?
Madeleine.
Mathieu.
Julie.
The light was exactly like this
when I first saw the house.
It's beautiful.
Imagine your sculptures here
at this time of day.
You're a sculptor?
We're graphic designers.
Freelance.
I sculpt in my spare time.
I'd love another...
"Tohu-bohu", is that it?
That's it.
Of course.
It's what we drank there.
You too, Mathieu?
Yes, please. It's delicious.
Why are you selling up?
It feels so right here.
To go back.
To the islands to join friends.
It's tempting.
You're not scared you'll get bored?
Is it as pleasant as they say?
Yes, it is.
What we'll miss the most
is the charm of the seasons.
Starting over.
Like tonight.
Stay for dinner.
You'll have time to visit the house
and drive home later.
We'd love to.
"They talk about death
like you talk about fruit
They look at the sea
Like you look at a well
The women are lascivious
In the fearsome sun
Although it's not winter
Nor is it summer"
"A few dance moves
And a few dance steps
Night is submissive
And the wind fades"
"Laughter is in the heart
The word is in a glance
The heart is a traveler
The future left to chance"
"Coconut trees pass by
Writing love songs"
The truth is
we were bored stiff there.
Tiramisu, anyone?
It was delicious.
I'll go get it.
I'll help you.
It's even magnificent inside.
You can visit it all.
Thanks.
I'm getting the cognac.
I'm sorry.
- We were cold.
- Come in.
It cools down quickly.
Cognac, Mathieu?
Yes, please, Madeleine.
Where is the bathroom?
It's upstairs.
I'll show you.
After you.
Here it is.
Stay, if you want.
I'd like that.
Thank you.
Let's go down.
Thanks for your hospitality.
You don't want to finish dinner?
No thanks.
We have a long way to drive.
I don't like driving at night,
especially on Saturday.
Some other time?
Sorry, we never see people again.
I understand.
Good luck, then.
You too.
Thanks again.
- It was really nice.
- Thanks.
Did you come to see the house?
Yes.
We like it here a lot.
Things don't always go as planned.
Do you often...
meet people like this?
Sometimes, on a Saturday night.
Hardly ever by chance,
like tonight.
It was really nice.
Drive carefully.
I forgot to tell you.
Michel and Annick
are getting married.
When?
This summer, I guess.
It will be in the North.
Annick is from Calais, I think.
It's me. Hi, Jean-Marc.
We were just talking about it.
The Wedding's on August 15?
We didn't have definite dates.
We'll still be here.
What's another season?
Anyway, they don't have seasons.
I wonder if life is not made up of
rare moments of great importance
and lots of interludes
that are only a shadow of them,
hovering around us.
Love, a beautiful melody...
I haven't been drinking.
Okay, see you Sunday.
Depending on the weather.
I'm going up to the studio.
Tomorrow, I'll send the offer
to Adam and Eva.
I was thinking...
You were thinking?
Why sell after all?
Absolutely.
Let's stay. We can travel
wherever and whenever we want.
Exactly.