My father wanted to
teach me from childhood.
Than the one who is
afraid of something.
Gives this fear immense
power over his life.
Come on, jump.
"He told me that
fear is an animal."
And that an animal can
be tamed or killed.
I did not always understand
what my father meant.
But that day, I realized
he wanted me to be a man.
Thanks, Sam. It was great.
- See you next year.
- Yeah.
"Are you coming, children?"
- Good-bye, captain.
- Hello!
- Hi, Sam.
- Hi, guy.
Good-bye, captain.
Bye madam.
I'm not disturbing you?
Samantha! I did not see you.
You told me four o'clock. It is 6:30 pm.
- Yes. You are going to laugh...
- No! I do not have the time.
Just a phone call
to warn, Samuel.
"Samuel"?
Looks like a kid you're hooking.
You're a kid.
I say nothing when you
pretend to be the boss,
when you bring your
daughters back on the boat,
but 150 Euros more
gasoline, it gets drunk.
And that?
Is that my tip? No.
It's for the full.
I prolonged because they burst.
Result:
15 days booked next year.
Then limit.
A little thank you or a
kiss and we are quits.
- I hate you.
- Me too I love you.
This evening, no overtaking.
I cut at 4 o'clock. 1 h.
- 3h?
- 1 h.
- 2h?
- You're fired.
Ok. 1h, that's fine.
1h15, 1h30, what.
- 1 h!
- Here.
Hi, Sam!
It's okay? It goes well?
- Thank you.
- It's cool. Great.
The day I drive the
yacht that is there.
So you can call me "captain".
- Right?
- Yeah.
Or "skipper".
You can also...
But "captain", it works.
Are you okay, captain?
What's wrong?
Have you seen the time?
Samantha stop calling me.
Tomorrow we have the biggest
customer of the season.
- It's okay, relax.
- I am relaxing?
We're not having a good night?
- I'm having fun.
- That's it. Kiffe.
Do not worry about tomorrow.
Everything will be alright.
Sit down or dance.
She's not harassing you?
Because it makes me a hell.
- Yes, she called.
- I am fired.
I'll handle it.
Are you gonna manage?
I am waiting to see.
Yes look. Look well.
Do you want the
party to continue?
Yeah!
I'll ask you to make
a little game for me:
A silence of one minute.
It starts now. Hush.
Hello? Samantha?
5 h of the mat. What are you doing?
Well, I'm sleeping. Is there a worry?
"All the neighborhood calls me."
There would be music.
What? Music? Well no.
I would have heard it.
I can not hear him.
I'm connected. Neighbors invent!
Yeah. They are a bit mythos.
I'm on the boat.
I have the beach in front
of me and it is deserted.
There is not a cat around.
Stop playing.
It was cute when you were
little, but no longer there.
Oh yes, you're right.
At the time for me.
I see a guy with a hat.
They're in band.
They are going to move,
make a campfire...
I'll fire them.
- chut!
- Hush!
I do not want any more noise.
Okay, I'm telling them.
Count on me.
Okay. So much the better.
Good. Where were we already?
Sam, are you there?
Sat?
"Samuel?"
Good morning.
It is impossible to
go out to sea today.
It looks very quiet like that.
But it's dangerous.
You do not recognize me?
Kristin.
Last summer, the boat,
the calanques...
"Ah, but yes!
Kristin... Kristin from Berlin."
- From London.
- That's it.
- It's cool to see you!
- Yes.
With your baby. Hey? Your baby.
And actually...
Sorry, you can not
get on the boat.
I tidy.
I'll introduce Gloria to you.
Good morning, Gloria.
It gurgles in English.
Hey, Gloria.
She's hurting, huh? Bravo.
It's your daughter.
Hmm?
Your daughter.
Your daughter, Samuel.
Here. Your daughter.
In French, when you mean.
You say "ma", you see.
I know it must be a
shock to you, but...
It's your baby.
No. "Your baby of me," no.
It has nothing to do.
It's not me.
It has 3 months.
Yeah, 3 months, but what?
What are you doing to me?
I know, it's crazy, but...
- I came to...
- It's not crazy.
But no, it's not crazy!
It's not crazy at all.
It's not crazy.
Because in fact, no.
It's unfortunate, but not.
I am sorry.
Because if you think...
Well no. You see?
So sorry, but no.
Ok, kiss.
You got 20 Euros for the taxi?
Please.
Um yes. This, yes! This, yes!
I'll get that for you.
But 3 months, no.
Here. 20 Euros and kisses, bye.
Here!
Here.
Thank you very much.
Can you keep it for me?
Uh... yeah, but...
So wait. You do... hurry up!
It's heavy, though.
Do not worry, she's coming back.
Look.
She pays and she comes back.
Look, do not worry.
It does not help. She comes.
But do not worry!
Yes but no. Look.
Here.
She's going to pay.
She's paying. Look.
What the hell is she doing?
Is she busy?
She's standing there, right?
Kristin!
You've forgotten your stuff!
Kristin, the bags!
Not without the bags!
Stop, stop, stop!
Sleep with ladies.
- What's this?
- Nothing. An abandoned baby.
- Hey? It's disgusting.
- Exactly!
Her mother stole 20
bullets and stood up.
- She stole 20 bullets?
- Yes.
You know that girl?
No! What dalle!
We vaguely slept together,
but not enough to say:
"It's your daughter."
It's too easy! I also
take a kid and I give it!
Why is she crying?
"It's obvious, she's upset.
You reject it."
It's not easy,
father-daughter relationship.
Me, with my father, it's...
"Stop, with your father!"
She is hungry. That's all.
You do not have milk?
Wait, I got something.
Her name is Gloria Stuart.
Here. Stuart, it's not my name.
So it's not my daughter.
You're all confusing.
I have a Kristin Stuart from
London on Facebook, there.
Maybe it's her. Show me.
It's her.
Looks like she's blocked her account.
She has no friends.
Normal!
Did you see what she does to people?
- Well, answer.
- Yes.
Hello?
"Ah, Samuel?"
Kristin, where are you?
Immediate boarding...
Sorry, I...
I can not.
Take the plane. Do not do this to me.
That's not cool.
I know nothing about baby.
You can not trust me.
I'll spoil it.
Hello?
"I'm the one who ruins it, Samuel."
It's me.
*-no! She's doing very well, this girl.
I'm not doing well at all.
I'll never be a good mother.
I'm sure you're going
to be a great father.
No! I'm not a super father.
I'm a kid.
You do not give a kid to another kid.
Hello, Kristin? Kristin?
She hung up.
She's going to fly.
It's far, the airport?
Hey! It's okay, is not it?
Gloria screams.
Cuckoo, Sam.
It's the brothel on the boat.
Yes I saw that.
I do not know what happened.
Two naked chicks
drink champagne!
I'm here in 15 seconds.
* -no, not in 15 sec.
There are bottles everywhere,
hoods and diapers!
No, but are you serious?
I'll explain, but I'm taking
care of something before.
I kiss you. Kisses.
"Bisous"...
immediate embarkation
for London...
Whore!
Sorry!
I will give up a child.
It's not mine...
Kristin!
Boarding pass and passport.
- My girlfriend has forgotten her daughter.
- Boarding pass and passport.
It's not me who's leaving.
It's her. With her!
Kristin, the little one!
Sir, bring him back.
That's the girl out there.
Give him back directly.
She's over there.
- Boarding pass and passport.
- You know a sentence!
- Yeah, well, please!
- Do not touch me.
Boarding pass and passport.
Samuel? What are you doing here?
Samantha, I'm a little late, but
I'll be there this afternoon.
I'll be back at 3pm?
Yes, you will be in London at 11am.
To go to the pub, it is direct in tube.
Why are you laughing?
It seems like you said "cock".
Not at all. I said tube.
The Metro.
Put the cream.
No, there's paraben!
- That's good, guys!
- Must do that well.
Look.
The fasteners behind and
tuck you on the stomach.
Squeeze too much,
she can breathe more.
If you do not press it, it's gonna run.
No, it's baby-dry.
Its good.
Thank you, stéphane, Philippe.
It's the opposite.
What if she's crying on the plane?
Impossible.
She ate and she is clean.
She's going to sleep all the way.
It's certain.
Gloria screams.
The hostess speaks in English.
Welcome to London.
We hope you enjoyed
the flight...
The worst flight of my life.
It's okay.
Have you ever wept for your life?
She does not like the plane.
What line?
Here! Piccadilly.
Good game.
Not bad, for a girl of your age.
Sam baragouin in English.
Sir?
Can you tell me the "teub"?
"Teub"?
"Teub".
The tube!
The man arle an lais at full speed...
I did not understand anything. Sorry.
You speak too fast.
Fuck!
That's what I understood. It was slower.
Good. He just insulted us.
We must find the "teub".
Next station...
But no, we're fine, there.
Ah shit...
It stinks.
Well yeah.
Well yeah...
Oh yeah, okay.
A man yells in English.
Find me a guy who
looks like our guy!
Do your job, damn!
Or I turn you!
They're shit, shit!
- You speak French?
- It happens to me.
- You're going to save my life.
- With pleasure.
- Me, it's Bernie.
- I'm Samuel.
That's sublime.
That's fine, yeah.
You will help me. I'm lost.
- Stay to the left.
Wrote: "Hold your right."
The English laugh not even
with the seductive tourists.
I'm not a tourist.
Is not that close?
It is not false.
That's good. Been to londres?
15 years I live here.
What are you looking for?
I have to give a baby back to his mother.
- What baby?
- The baby that's there.
Whore!
Hold your right!
No no no!
Damn, damn it!
Hold your right!
I'm here, I'm here!
She's good! Yeah!
Bravo!
Yeah, she's good.
Hello, Michael. I found it.
- Wait!
- I do not have the time.
It's a golden opportunity.
Stuntman, it is a sublime craft.
There's lots of money to be made.
I'm looking for his mother, not work.
And I go home.
"Where is her mother?"
She works at old queen's head.
It would be in the corner.
It's right there.
- That's it!
- No, but wait!
If you change your mind,
there, there are my pro
and behind coordinates...
It's personal. We never know.
Domino effect that makes
snowball and needle thread...
The bird makes its nest.
"What nest?" There is no nest.
Well, I... Well, here we are.
Good. Nice to meet you.
Stay cool.
We're not bored with you.
What's the matter?
No, do not start.
You'll be fine with your mother.
A dad like me on a
daily basis is tiring.
Do not look at me like that.
It's hot. It will not work.
Trust me, nothing
replaces a mom.
It's a canon, a mom.
A Coca light.
Sorry?
Coke light.
The sugar-free, light.
Do you understand "light"?
No, she does not speak English.
It wants a diet coke.
It's not the same here.
You all speak French?
A bar is not a surprise.
London would be the 6th French city.
There would be more French here
than in Bordeaux. It's crazy!
It's crazy.
Look.
So we would be more
of bayonne, dijon...
It's less crazy.
And otherwise, you may
be able to help me.
I'm looking for that waitress, Kristin.
- No, never seen.
- You can not tell me that.
She works there.
This is the queen machin.
It's your colleague.
I never saw her.
It's a new owner.
She changed her pub.
You know the number of waitresses who...
Leave it.
How much do I owe you?
Two pounds.
Fuck, it's pounds here!
- Yes.
- I have Euros.
We can settle it.
Oh damn, it's not possible!
Sorry! Excuse me! I lost...
Ah well, it is... He's there.
Whore! No!
What the hell are I doing here?
Oh no!
Shit!
It was not raining two minutes ago.
I will find a solution.
Hello? How are you,
my favorite Samantha?
Where are you?
In London.
- What?
- I explain to you.
Big galley.
I have a baby on my arms,
I do not find his mother.
I lost wallet, passports...
She is hungry. It is raining.
You really have to help me, Sam.
Hold on. Are you in London?
Yes, but it's not that far.
Ben, stay there!
I warned you, okay?
You're fired.
Yes, make me a transfer...
Listen to me. I'm joking more, there.
Ok, it hurts, but you're fired.
Good-bye, Sam.
"Do you know that address?"
"That place?"
- Yes.
- Continue, then right.
Right, like that? Ok. Thank you.
Hush! Come on, do not cry.
It will be fine.
We will find a solution.
Do not be afraid.
We must not be afraid.
Come on. You must sleep, my daughter.
My daughter...
Thank you.
Sir?
You can't be here.
The house is under video surveillance,
and the police will be here in a minute.
So, you better go now. Please sir.
Sir I warning you.
I have a pepper spray, and
I'm not afraid to use it.
Sir. Last warning.
Dad.
You said it! You said it!
She said "dad"!
It's daddy. It's me. Redirect it!
Dad.
- Dad.
- Tata.
Tata.
- Dad. Dad!
- That's dad.
Dad.
Come on, come on.
Gloria, come, come!
Come!
Cuckoo, my baby.
It's okay?
Ah, you got a bobo? Hold on.
Do not move.
I have an idea.
Hop there!
She works well, this ointment.
Gloria!
What did you do!
We must not do that.
It's not good.
How do I clean?
Are you ready?
Oh sorry!
No!
Yeah!
Good night.
"Here!"
Hop!
Here. We're all right.
Dad? One day you can
take me to the cliff?
Where you jumped when you were my age.
Yes, I'll take you.
When?
When you're able to
dunker all by yourself.
I go. The first down has won.
We can not see each other this weekend?
No, not this weekend.
Gloria has no school.
I'll stay with her.
There's no school on weekends.
Yes that's it.
I'll stay with her, suddenly.
So we never have a moment both?
Cut.
It's perfect!
But it's got to be a lot worse.
Add more blood, or something.
We have to do more reality.
Great, we are goning to keep up!
Sam, are you OK?
Is Sam doing well?
Let me go through, please.
Please. He only needs me.
Dad... Awake, you are immortal.
French shit humor!
We laugh.
He jumped from a cliff to 8 years.
This stuff does not scare me.
Get him out.
We done with this dumbs.
Get the real actors!
Bring all the stars!
We take back!
Here.
I do not care who is responsible.
But I do care,
it is that this shit
does not happen again!
He's not happy.
You have 10 s to find a solution.
Starting now!
You did well yelling.
It was a bit violent.
Nothing to see. It was my tax expert.
No, you were perfect.
The scene was sublime.
The more I touch
death, the more sublime!
Well, it's a bit of interest in the job!
What do they still want?
Get some rest. Big day tomorrow.
What did he say?
He speaks too fast.
- You gotta rest tonight.
- Yes.
You still do not get
a word of English!
I am here for this.
Great day, tom.
See you tomorrow.
Here's yours.
What do we do tomorrow?
We're shooting the scene... uh...
You run under the plane taking off.
6 h of the mat '.
- Why do I do this job?
- You know nothing else.
You take me 6000 pounds a month.
You are lodged by the prod.
You adore me. Gloria...
Its good. It's okay.
Its good?
You're 18 seconds late.
Good. What is the score already?
- 4591160.
- So... Match point!
And hop I.
"Oh, that's wonderful!"
- Past!
Magic Gloria will immediately
switch to magic Samuel.
What a move! What a move!
- And hop!
- What a move!
I go.
Hop!
Bernie!
My heart!
Oh, you missed me so much.
We left two hours ago.
It's way too much.
Would you like a slice with us?
Drink? Spent a night?
No thanks.
I have to work.
- He's not an naughty boy.
- Leave him alone, Bernie.
He's not gay.
I think he's curious.
I feel it in my eyes.
There is a possible slip.
I've got the knack for it.
Thank you. See you tomorrow.
Bernie.
Stop darting the delivery men.
Tomorrow, love.
Come on, we go up. It goes into 5 min!
What is this scarf
with cat paws?
It's a silk stole.
A little camouflage tone on tone sublime.
Okay. Yeah.
Jack bates!
He lost his past.
He never had a present.
He is fighting for the future.
Bates is back. Season 8.
Exclusively on channel 4.
Yes, I am!
You are too strong, dad.
Oh, that tweete!
That's it.
- Double sprain for this teaser.
- For millions of viewers.
And the signing of a season 9.
Put on the ointment.
You're right. I'm looking
forward to burning for season 10.
No, that's the end of the 8th.
For the 10, it would require
a more powerful stuff.
"He could jump from a
burning helicopter."
And land in an acid bath!
Well yeah.
Yeah, great!
It'll slam!
I'll slam!
"That would be sublime!"
Mermaid.
It's a mamma's mail. Dad!
Mom sent me an email!
Yes yes yes!
"After Russia, here
I am now in China."
"I do not have time to enjoy it, because
I have to infiltrate the Chinese mafia."
"To catch this villain
of wong kar-wai."
"As usual,"
"I miss you honey.
The only thing that comforts me,"
"is to know that you are with the
most loving, intelligent dad,."
"Courageous, and above all, the
most seductive in the world."
"You can be proud of your dad,."
"Because he is the
best man in the world."
"I love you mom."
"What is she doing this time?"
She's infiltrated
in the Chinese mafia.
Ah cool!
And it's fine, over there?
- Yeah, super nice.
- She is lucky.
We're rotting right now.
Hum...
And she has a long time?
Time to wedge wong kar-wai.
It's the bad guy.
Ah, wong kar-wai! Yeah.
It will last for a while.
Yeah, I know.
- Wish him good courage.
- Yeah yeah.
Because wong
kar-wai, we need it.
"I'd love to see you so much, mom.
Promised,."
"If you are on a secret mission,"
"I'll do as if I did not know
you to put you in danger."
"Maybe one day you'll
end up coming to London."
"For one of your missions.
I love you. Gloria."
Soon, mama will have made all
the countries of the world.
Oh, right?
No, there must be a few.
- Four.
- Did you count?
Yeah. When it has finished,
she will return to London.
No, it does not mean anything.
It depends on his mission.
She has already made ltaly twice.
Three.
3 times ltaly, 4 times Germany, 5
times Japan and 6 times Thailand.
Ok. Well yeah.
So she'll end up going through here.
"Or she has already come,
but she can not tell us."
Oh, there's that too.
It's not con.
It is still the class,
a secret mamma.
Sometimes I think you're lucky.
It could have
happened on anyone.
You could have a normal mother.
It's cool. No?
This is so cool.
"Can you give me a recap of all
the countries of your mother?"
Because sometimes I forget.
History to make me a recap, what.
Hey, glo?
What are you doing?
Excuse me.
I send an email. I arrive.
Have not you let the matter go?
You know that one day she will understand?
Do not start, please.
Ok. Well, I'm going.
Ok. See you tomorrow.
That's it, tomorrow.
"Can you get out of school earlier?"
At 3:30 pm, there is a 3D session.
No, no, you're meeting
with my manager.
- This evening, the director?
- Yeah.
A hard time! Well tomorrow, then.
No more.
You've got to go to the doctor.
What's the bad
news this morning?
Sorry.
You know what?
We're not going to go tomorrow.
I do not like doctors.
They make bites.
They give out disgusting drugs.
We will not go. What?
Are you afraid of bites?
No, I'm not afraid.
- Yes.
- No.
Whatever!
Yes, you're scared of bites.
But no. Im shy.
It has nothing to do.
You'll be less afraid
if I come with you?
- Yes.
- Ok.
But you have to
learn to go alone.
When we're more both...
Why do you say that?
When I get a job, I can
not go with you anymore.
You know what you want to do?
Yes. I want to be like you.
Come on. Hello.
You want to be stunned?
Immortal.
In a row two by two, the children.
"Let us go back to Gloria's
repeated absences.
"Repeat"? It's strong.
There was a wake-up call yesterday, but...
Last week, she did not come.
- Oh, right? Not even on Monday?
- No.
The week before, either.
"At this moment,"
I shot the explosion scenes
on the tower bridge.
Life is not an entertainment
or an amusement park.
Do you have any idea of the.
Of your education...
Yes, I know the
consequences, but in fact...
She was sad.
Because of the disappearance
of sergeant Newman.
And I thought to
cheer him up in...
What happens to sergeant Newman?
Oh, sorry, I spoiled.
"He's not gonna die?"
Secret of production.
I can not say.
Oh no.
Not Newman.
Here, I brought you that.
It is... Yes, it's
the real ones.
Worn by the actor.
Oh thank you. How nice.
It's a pleasure.
Oh yes, it's great.
I'm telling you this for
the good of the little one.
You are a good father.
You love your daughter.
She is adorable,
when it is there,
but here we are in real life.
Yes.
I do not want to interfere
in your private life, but...
The stories.
She tells about her mother.
Are surprising. As an educator.
Your daughter, I must
know what it really is.
Of his mother. You told me.
That she was to return to London.
You really want
to know the truth?
I lent 20 Euros to his mother
8 years ago for a taxi.
And she never came back.
Oh...
Aie aie aie!
There you go.
'It's okay.
We did not feel anything.
Still stings.
Thank you for accompanying me.
Every time.
"I'm counting on you to remind
her to take her medication."
Yes. Morning noon and evening.
As for my vitamins.
"Luckily you're here
to set an example."
Want to come see my baby dog?
- Yes.
- Come!
"I have the test
results, Samuel."
Yes...
The treatment did not work.
How long?
I do not know.
Not a lot.
I am sorry.
We'll have tried everything.
Good bye, sir.
Glo?
You will never guess what
the doctor has prescribed.
What?
Oh dear!
I do not feel very well.
I am dizzy.
Hold on. I check the order.
Of course! We forgot the cotton candy.
That's why.
Come on, dear.
Let's go honey, come on.
Sorry.
I thought you were my daughter.
You're so cute. Sorry.
We're going, dear.
Another one, please.
Honey, I was wrong.
I read wrong.
It is 2 cotton candy.
One in the morning, one in the evening.
You want big or big?
I want mom.
You know what?
Drop the prescription.
We'll make a good cheese.
Or a hot dog. Or both.
"I want to see her in real life, dad."
I want to see her in real life.
I know, my dear.
I know.
Gloria, my little
wonder everyday...
Oh, Gloria!
Gloria!
Every day that passes is
an unbearable heartbreak.
Gloria!
"Ah!"
My heart...
I only have a few minutes
before heading back to Bangkok.
But I promise you,
at each mission, you are there.
And above all, you are here.
I love you so much.
My little baby.
Me too, mom.
A lot.
And if not, it's nice in Bangkok?
- The weather is good?
- Oh yes.
Very good. Wonderful!
No, you know.
That is the problem.
- No?
- No, it's not good.
Not at all!
It is raining! It's the monsoon, damn!
She knows everything about her mother.
She holds a notebook.
Notebook...
Must be unstoppable.
Even on the weather.
Shit!
Yeah. Too bad.
I liked it, but it's not worked.
- Yes, it's worked.
- No no no.
- File the wig.
- No!
Please. Give me one more chance.
I do everything perfectly.
Weather, monsoon...
Ok, and then it's over.
I do not have the time.
We have to find it.
What is this bullshit?
Oh, Bernie! You're here.
I was looking for you.
When I got home a while ago...
What is this casting?
- Girls, are you doing here?
- For the role of Kristin.
Gloria's mother.
Thank you. Kiss my ass.
Wait, Bernie!
Bernie!
Listen to me.
Gloria asked me to see her mother.
- Find the real one.
- She does not give a fuck, the real one.
She does not respond to Gloria's mails.
"Say the truth to your daughter, fucking!"
I do not want to make her unhappy.
Can you hear that?
Oh, right? You think you're the
only one worrying about her?
I was there for his first steps,
his first teeth, his first words!
I'm not his father, but I
love him as much as you do.
She will soon be 9 years old.
One day, she'll understand
you're lying to him.
And that's going to
make her unhappy.
I know, but it freaks me out.
I'm not telling you it's easy,
just that you have to do it.
So, tonight, you stop
sending fake emails.
And tell the truth to your daughter.
It will be fine.
Ho! Ho!
At table, filibuster.
Here is our Booty.
Grilled crocodile.
And its wild potatoes.
Lend your knife.
I'm sorry, there.
Thank you.
Will we talk afterwards?
I need to talk to you about something.
Do not you touch it?
"Yes, but I'm not very hungry."
What's the matter?
It's mom.
She did not send me an
email this evening.
This is not normal.
You know, honey...
"It's the first time she forgets me."
Can I go to bed? I am tired.
Yes if you want.
We're still going to the circus tomorrow?
Yeah. We'll see.
Good night daddy.
Oh fuck!
She reads.
She reads, fucking.
Gloria! No... hush, shit.
Hold on.
Must answer, meuf!
I am coming tomorrow!
See you tomorrow my love.
Dad, wake up!
Mom will come to see me.
Dad! Mom will come to see me!
Dad!
Mom comes to London! Oh, right?
Yeah.
She took wong kar-wai?
I do not care. Look.
She sent me an e-mail.
It's awesome!
Yeah! I'll see her
for the first time.
I'm going to get ready.
Get up, papa!
We are going to be late!
That. It...
Very good. All very well.
"My feet are sore, papa."
Me too.
I prefer the Jordan.
Yes. Me too, but do not
tell your mother right away.
Why?
"The last time I saw her,
I was barefoot on a boat."
You have to show him that
things have changed.
Do you think mom will love me?
"Of course!" It's your mother.
"And you think she's going to love you?"
Me? So that...
It's another delirium.
Mom!
Mom...
I'm so glad to see you.
Me too.
Good morning, Samuel.
Hello.
And your sunglasses?
We'll recognize you.
"Will they recognize me?"
Yes...
Mum had to secure the perimeter.
- That's it?
- Yes.
Yes. Here.
So we're connected?
I see no headset.
- No, I do not have an earpiece.
- Because you do not see her.
But she has a chip
directly on the eardrum.
As it's inside, you
can not see it.
Need a microscope.
Cool! They hear what they say?
Yes, thanks to the
microphone in the tooth.
It's an implant.
But there, it must be disabled.
You confirm? We are.
We're - cool, we're between us.
What would make you
happy, Gloria?
Do you want to eat ice cream?
Walk around?
What do you want to do?
It was planned.
To go to the circus.
If you want to eat ice cream,
do it in the meantime.
As you wish.
I'd like to show you my room.
I'd love to see your room.
"Can we, papa?"
- Can we please?
- Yes.
Yeah! Lets' go.
Come on!
That fuck up the circus
program, but we can...
You have to explain the
earpiece and all that.
You, you have to explain
the taxi and all that.
Welcome.
It's incredible here.
"But it's up there, my room."
You come?
I have a whole wall of lego.
No...
If I swear to you.
That's my dinosaurs. Here.
That's my shark.
And that's my giraffe
from Madagascar.
"You went to Madagascar?"
- No.
It is a cartoon.
You do not know?
But I did not see him.
Mom has no time to
watch the movies.
She knows the country. Hey?
Yes.
Oh, right?
I did not know you were there.
Oh yes.
Did you meet who?
Uh...
Eddie Murphy.
'Who ?
He was in the Beverly hills cop,
in an armchair for two.
She did not see that. She is 8 years old.
It was in doctor dol / file.
She saw that. No? She knows?
Eddie Murphy.
It is in Shrek.
Remember the donkey?
It's his voice.
Ah yes!
"You definitely you need a tic tac.
"Your breath stinks!" Here!
She has an American accent.
For a little English girl.
She learned with the movies.
She goes to the French school in London.
There is a good level.
That is true?
Your school is far away?
No. We'll go tomorrow.
You'll see my naughty teacher.
"An naughty teacher?"
Why naughty?
I do not like her, she never laughs.
He's a good teacher?
Yes.
If you love depressive witches.
Depressive witches, can't wait to meet her.
She fell asleep at once.
No problem.
It's all her.
Why did not you
tell him the truth?
I thought about it, yeah.
But even looking good, I
have not found it correctly.
To explain to him that his
mother had abandoned him.
Even you, you prefer to be the
secret mamma that I invented. No?
You made her a
wonderful little girl.
I did not do it for you.
- It was not easy, you know.
- Are you kidding?
You left us like shit!
We'll forgive you because
you answered a mail?
I'm not asking you.
I know it's unforgivable,
what I did.
"Then why did you do it?"
I was lost.
I was doing anything.
When I got pregnant,
I thought I could get away with
it, but it got worse and worse.
I could not impose that on a baby.
A baby blues and you leave your
daughter to a guy who has jumped you!
"To his father."
I knew you'd be up to it.
It lasted 8 years.
You know what it's like, eight?
It's an eternity.
I've been thinking of her
every day for 8 years.
It's been 8 years since I was
ashamed, it's been 8 years since...
That I tell myself that my
daughter will ever forgive me.
I was afraid, and the
more time passed,
the more I was afraid, because
a mother like me, we hate her.
That's easy.
No, it's not easy.
I come back from a distance, Samuel.
But thanks to you, I
have existed, for her.
Thank you.
You got a place to sleep?
I'll find a hotel.
You can stay here
tonight, if you want to.
That is true?
Yeah. It will make him happy.
- And hop! Hi mom!
- Ah, you won.
- Yeah.
- Hello. Are you ready?
Yeah, yeah. I got up early.
- Checkpoint!
- 8h16.
We got a minute!
- Laces.
Slept well?
Yes. I prepared a
breakfast for Gloria.
Mom, we never eat here in the morning.
Yeah. We prefer to sleep
more and eat on the way.
- Checkpoint!
- 8h17.
- Jacket.
Vitamins.
- Hop!
- Thank you.
We're ready. You come?
Yes. We leave all this here?
There are eggs, muffins.
Even chouquettes.
Oh yeah anyway.
We got it.
And dinner too.
Checkpoint?
- 8h18.
- Perfect.
Backpack.
Um yes.
Good morning, Gloria.
Hello madam.
It is my mother.
I am the director
of the institution.
Glad to meet you at last.
Me too.
"Come on, mamma, I'll
show you my class."
- Bye madam.
- Goodbye.
Goodbye.
"She paid for the
taxi and came back."
The driver had no money...
I have the episodes
of next week.
I do not know if you saw them.
"Sit in silence, please."
Hello madam. I'm Gloria's mom.
No parents in the class.
It is the rule.
Of course. Sorry.
- Sorry.
- And again, she's cool.
"Are you coming for me tonight?"
If you want. At what time?
- Normally...
- 15h30.
It's written here. Just read.
Gloria?
- We hate her. No?
- Yeah.
Good. By the time Gloria settled down,
you can open the notebooks.
Today we are going to talk
about the solar system:
The earth, the moon... Gloria.
Thank you.
Why are we here, Bernie?
The view is sublime.
- What?
- Get out of here, please.
Hello sir.
Did monsieur make his choice of tea?
Yes...
A dis-z 'coke.
I am sorry, sir.
We do not serve colas.
Get some tea, shit.
The tradition.
I knew it was a rough place.
I was sure of it.
An ice tea.
Sorry?
My god.
Tea with ice in it.
Tea with ice, inside.
It's tea, it's not a.
It's not a - no.
"I am confused, sir.
He is French."
It's tea.
It's not a colas.
Yes, we understood that. Oh...
"Are you gonna check
it all afternoon?"
"He comes here every Thursday."
He makes me his show.
He drives me crazy.
"This father of a family?"
It's a blanket!
He's gay. It shows.
You got drunk.
What?
Your chandeliers at 6 billion, your
tea, your papas dep, it's too much.
It's okay. Take a seat.
You do not even listen to me.
- Tell me about it.
- Tell what?
About Kristin.
If she comes fuck shit in the
family, it's not worth it.
You're having a fit of jealousy.
Nothing to see.
It's just that I see you more.
It's been 2 days.
- It's too much.
- It pleases the little one.
I have a say.
I'm a little bit like that child's mother.
Stopped.
More than her.
Do not worry. She's lost.
She came to see Gloria
and she will leave.
"But she is sleeping at home."
You laid back with her?
"I'm not fine?"
- She is big?
- Oh, no.
You laid back with her!
I was sure of it.
Stop with that!
She stays with Gloria.
You promise me that there is not
an ounce of seduction between you.
Not an iota.
That's right, people
say I'm a stuntman.
That is true.
Let's say that the
cinema has fallen on me.
And I fall in the movies.
Stuntman.
Tom cruise, jacky chan, bébel...
'Who?
Belmondo, Jean-Paul.
If you want a picture
of your lovely family...
Thank you.
What's the matter?
Nothing. He says we're
a lovely little family.
Oh, right?
It is true that it is not false.
Why not?
No, because I have someone.
Ah super.
We met four years ago in New York.
It is serious.
We live together.
He's a very good person.
It's thanks to him... it's cool.
That I got out...
I did not dare tell you about
it, but it just happened.
In London and...
I would like to present it to you.
Great boss. It's cool.
Very cool.
- Well, if it's possible. Me I...
- Yes it's possible.
We need to organize, what.
But it is possible.
No problem.
Here, Gloria.
What? He's there?
Ah yes, he's there.
Hello. You must be Gloria.
Yes.
Hello.
And you're... Samuel, right?
Right...
Lowell. I prefer om. Sorry.
What?
Uh... Ol, om, teams.
- Soccer.
- Ah, football.
That's it.
Paris Saint germain.
No. I prefer the other.
I prefer om.
He does not speak English.
Yes, of course. Hold on. He speaks.
Sometimes a little.
Sometimes, no.
It depends, in fact.
It depends, but he speaks.
Of course.
What do you think?
Well, do you sit in there?
We'll be better. No?
Yes.
- What do you think?
- Yes.
Say it.
Sit in it.
It's good. Come on!
My dad is the best man ever.
Everyone wants to work with him.
You know Jack bates?
Of course.
Well, it's him.
Oh, right?
It's me!
"And the real actor in the series?"
"The only risk he takes
is smoking cigarettes."
Dad does all the rest.
Wow! That is pretty impressive.
Yes, I am!
- You did not want to go to the bathroom?
- Yes.
Me too. Let's go.
We will be back.
Ok.
I love "bucu" "the" France.
What?
"France. I like "bucu".
"Ah! Okay.
"The" France, yes.
Okay. So...
You like "bucu" tout "le" France.
Or a part of "the" France?
What?
I like "bucu"
the south of "the" France.
The "zaousse".
The "zaousse"?
Yes, the "zaousse".
At the seaside.
Ok... the south.
That's what I said.
The "zaousse"!
Very good.
Yeah, very good.
He does not care about me.
There is a toilet
for 300 people.
"Why do you prefer
lowell more than daddy?"
But I never said that.
No, but if you thought the other way
around, you'd be at home with us.
We can see each other without
living in the same house.
It does not mean we love each other less.
Okay?
Look at me, Gloria.
I'll never leave you.
Okay?
I promise you.
Come here, come.
Can I avoid kids clothes
when I have a thermal suit?
- Hi, my cat.
- It would be good.
Whore! Shit!
- Thank you.
- Thank you!
1000 hours to dress!
Whore! This is the end of the day!
"Stop there!"
It's not our fault that
Kristin has a guy.
Nothing to see. I do not
understand what she finds.
- He's fat?
- Not especially.
It's a little disgusting little bastard.
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah.
Dad, I have a surprise.
Is this sublime guy?
I'll die, he has
the tom Ford news.
He is small.
Can I talk to you, Gloria?
- Hello.
Gloria insisted.
Is not that a problem?
Well, you know. In fact no.
Sorry excuse me.
Without warning,
it is complicated.
There are standards.
Hein... hey, Bernie?
Secured, insurance...
It is cheese. No?
Cheese? Not really.
- Okay.
- Do not worry.
Me, it's Bernie, the producer.
Nice to meet you.
We'll set you up to look at me.
It is fabulous. You will see.
Be my guest, I'll be there in a minute.
Over there?
Be the guest... No problem.
On the other hand I
reassure you, he's gay.
Stop please.
"Why is he here?"
To watch us.
"He may like stuntmen."
That's it.
All is said.
Perfect!
But even more.
It must burn alive.
Glo!
Come and see, dear.
I do not feel it, the scene.
You ask them to leave the
1st floor, not the 3rd?
Hey? We'll play it soft.
I do not know, it's...
A feeling.
- Okay, I'm asking.
- Thank you darling.
I love what you do.
It's great to meet you.
This is the most important
scene of the season.
A big waterfall.
Bates jumps from a building on fire.
Samuel will jump from up there.
That is really?
Is not little bit dangerous?
"Yes, that is the point."
Do not worry about him.
From the 3rd floor, kid could do it.
I thought it is the 6th?
That would be great,
but I doubt he'll be great.
"He says he wants to
do it from more."
"Would he jump off the 6th floor?"
No.
From the 11th floor.
"11th?"
This is the top floor.
"He wants to show my mother
how courageous he is."
Ok.
OK, that's great. Let's do it!
You are the man, Sam!
Here!
One floor, we agree.
Thank you my friend.
We're gonna rip everything up.
It's exciting, is not it?
OK guys, let's go!
We're going up.
Hold on. What are you doing?
What are you doing?
One, I said "one."
You said eleven.
Eleven? You're maboul or what?
No way.
No no. Stop!
Stop that. Chopped off. Chopped off.
I do not have control.
Stopped.
It's automated.
What, "totomatisé"? Stop that.
Stop I.
Never will I jump
eleven stories on fire!
You realize?
Do not shout at me.
I'm feeling dizzy, please.
Are you ready?
Almost.
Great!
Cameras?.
No no no! Cut!
Cut!
Cut that!
I do not move if I'm not
on the 1st floor. Ok?
He wants to do it from the 1st.
What? You kidding? What a fuck?
Gloria, a word please.
We had an agreement.
You said he would jump from the 11th.
"What's he doing to her?"
He does not care about me?
It's not the empire state building!
What's he doing?
Your daughter said eleven. She lied.
Hold on!
Stop! Okay?
You do not talk to her like that.
She's my daughter.
He said what?
What he says to me now?
You translate or you gland?
Hold on... He is a
stuntman or a performer?
What is he: Man or a mouse?
I am a guru!
I will do it! Ok for 11.
Tell him "ok for 11."
She's not lying.
"He's going to jump off the top floor."
Bring the airbags!
I do not have time to deal with this creep.
Lets' go.
Fuck, Gloria.
"Be quiet!"
cameras!
8-176. One.
Action!
Cut.
Sublime!
He's not moving.
My god! Call Emergency!
Let it pass.
I'm here.
No help, he just needs me.
Dad.
Awake, you are immortal.
Papa 'g.
Sam, answer.
It' ok mate?
Yes I am!
Too strong!
He is alive!
Thank you.
"But speak more like that
to my daughter." Ok?
Yeah, okay. Back to work!
Back to work!
- Come on, are you okay?
- Yeah, thanks. It's okay.
It will be fine?
Did she tell you what in the ear?
It's a game between us.
I pretend to be dead.
She thinks she is bringing me back to life.
Another lie.
That's it. Another lie.
"What will happen
when she finds out?"
"You give me lessons?" You?
"No, but one day she'll grow up."
Stop please.
I want to tell him the truth about me.
It would be better for her.
For her? You do not
know what's good for her.
You know nothing.
So you're not going to say anything at all.
We forget this conversation.
I am going to rest. I am tired.
I'm going to mix in the countries.
I do not know Obama.
I'm not a secret agent!
That is the truth!
Thank you so much.
See you soon.
Yes, very soon.
- Goodbye, Gloria.
- No, I want to come with you.
We'll go see mom tomorrow.
I'm not talking to you.
You liar!
Calm down, darling...
I do not want to go with you!
I want to go with you, mom.
Well, come on, we'll talk...
I will call you tomorrow.
Started.
You do not want to sleep at home?
With you?
Yeah...
A small head-spade to the old.
Not sure if it makes
me feel better.
Do not worry. A good night's
sleep on it, it'll be fine.
This is the first time I
will not put him to sleep.
She's coming back.
Just give him a little time.
I do not have time.
Yeah, I know, buddy. I know.
Come on... beers.
Hello, it's Kristin.
Leave a message, thanks.
How is she?
"She falls asleep always so quickly."
I do not understand. It's
against you she should be angry.
Today she asked to see you.
He misses you.
Must go in and everything
is the same as before.
It may not be like before.
That is to say?
Things have changed.
We will find an equitable solution.
Stopped. I raised her.
It will never be fair.
I'd like to see her more.
Catch up the time I lost.
"Yes, when you pass in the
corner, you call us!"
Go on Facebook, now
that you master.
"Stop, I should like to
have it also at my house."
Habites is in New York!
We can get organized.
No! My daughter and I
are very well organized.
There are lots of happy
children with separated parents.
And full of happy children,
alone with their father!
You give me a second chance.
I seized her.
I gave you nothing.
I allowed Gloria to see her mother.
"Now I am here, I
am his mother."
You're gonna take her out and
stop me from seeing her?
We will not go so far as to
settle this before a judge.
A judge? Are we in there?
It goes to the penal, downright!
Ben. Go ahead!
Go and tell everything to your judge!
He'll love it!
Meanwhile, Gloria stays with me!
His house is here,
his school is here, his life is here!
End of the discussion.
We stop the bullshit!
- Hi, Sam.
- Shut up!
It's me, darling.
We go home now.
You're doing a lot of bullshit.
You did it eight years ago.
It's too late.
Now you have more choice.
Sir.
Excuse me, my dear.
I did not want to lie to you.
It was for your good.
Sometimes, for the good of the
people, you have to lie a little.
Everything will go
back as before.
Good morning everyone.
We are gathered here today.
To Kristin Stuart.
VS Samuel Abelli,
to determine custody,
Of their eight-year-old daughter, Gloria.
The mother will speak first.
Ms. Stuart, step forward.
It will be fine.
He was preparing that, the bastard.
And he's getting the lawyer.
I should have known.
I'm going to get screwed in English.
I will understand nothing.
Tell the truth.
No I can not... put on
your headset, then.
- What?
- For English. Put on your headset.
- Which channel, French?
- 5.
You're welcome.
"I know it's unforgivable
to abandon your child."
I understad that.
That my past actions can not
be excused or undone.
But I do not want to
lose my daughter again.
I'd like to thank Samuel.
He's been wonderful father...
I wish I had not come this far.
I can never make up the lost years,
and I live with that every day.
But I want to be mother to my daugter now.
I hope you will give
us and I this right.
The question is: "Is not
it too late, young lady?"
I do not know.
Next.
In your own time, sir.
Any mother would dream of a father,
like Samuel for his child.
He's a superman
and no one knows.
Which he had to overcome.
I assure you that he raises his
daughter in the best way possible.
His way.
Beacause this man.
Has turned all his
life so that Gloria.
Have the happiest life possible.
In fact,
I remember our meeting. We were.
In the tube,
Gloria was in great danger at
the foot of the escalator.
Alone. And I saw this man.
Risk her life to save her.
At that very moment,
I knew he was ment
to be a father.
And stuntman.
The question is:
"Why did he leave his baby
unattended in the subway?"
Hmm?
I have met.
Many parents of students.
During my career in education.
I must say that Mr. abelli
is, without a doubt,
the most endearing father.
I had the opportunity to meet.
It transforms.
Every minute of her daughter's life.
In a magical moment.
In my opinion,
magic is cruelly
lacking in modern live.
Amen.
The question is:
"How many days did Gloria
go to school last month?"
Five.
Or six.
Six, that's good.
Six, definitely.
Very well thank you.
Next.
Mr. Abelli.
Sir.
Gloria has arrived
in my life overnight.
I was not ready.
But I did the best I could.
Maybe I have not quite high enough,
maybe my love is too
strong, too loud.
But I can not do otherwise.
The question is...
I'm not done.
No "the question is."
Forgive me if I do not know the laws.
I'm not a super father.
But I'm fighting for
my daughter to live.
In a world where all
children dream.
I can change my job,
I can make sure she does
not miss a school day.
I can even learn
English, if you will,
but I implore you,
do not take my daughter away.
Do not tear my heart away.
Do not do that.
That's all.
The question is:
"What is the child best interest?"
That is the solely
question we are asking.
The solely we have to answer.
Before you today.
Following the conscience,
we unanimously decided.
That the custody of
Gloria should return...
To the parent she knows best.
We give you custody of
your daughter, sir.
- Yes!
- Thank you.
Provided that...
That you take English classes.
Yes.
"That you cease to be a stuntman."
- We do not care.
- Yes.
And that Gloria goes to school.
The meeting adjourned.
Thank you everyone.
Mr. Abelli.
Be worthy of this judgment.
Ok. Ok.
Hard, but fair.
One year has 12
months, 365 days,
and especially 4 seasons.
Very distinct...
Someone's knocking at the door.
"Mademoiselle."
Children, sit down.
Some know it,
but I present Samuel, your
new general superintendent.
- Hello.
- Hello sir.
Hello madam.
The father of...
It's before all.
A new member of our institution.
The staff must therefore accommodate it.
"Do not worry, madam,
I'll make you forget."
I do not think it's
a good idea to...
Come and think in my office.
I will explain to
you in private.
Who will take care of my students?
The new general supervisor.
Are you okay, guys?
You were on what?
The four seasons.
It's not complicated:
Winter, it's cold.
Christmas trees, Christmas dad, snow...
And there's summer too.
It's hot.
The sun, the palm trees,
the orangeades...
They do not care.
Good!
What is the four seasons?
It's Vivaldi.
Vivaldi, great musician.
Hair cut questionable, but
composer unavoidable.
So we, it is normal, in
tribute to the good man,
you, you keep this cup,
it will make him happy,
and we play music.
You have instruments?
Yes yes yes!
Congratulations! 20 out of 20 direct.
Who wants 20 out of 20?
'Me!
It's the big brother!
I love this job!
Hello?
I can not talk to you,
I'm history.
Samuel, we have a problem...
What is happening?
"Listen, miss Stuart asked
for a paternity test."
What?
I'm sorry.
"I'm sorry, sir."
I 'll be back.
Kristin!
- Come.
- It's okay.
Just tell me.
Did you know it from the beginning?
No.
I was convinced it was you.
I'm sorry.
"What does mean" organic "?
"That means the little
seed is not mine."
- But you're still my daddy?
- Of course.
You have a dad who designed you
and a dad who brought you up.
- All that is just words.
- Exactly.
It's just words, my daughter.
Good morning. "Sir."
Is that obligatory, Scotland yard?
I did not want to.
This is the procedure.
You are ready?
You leave me 2 m?
Goodbye, that does not mean we'll
never see each other again.
Hey?
Yes I know.
Dad...
My love.
Do not worry, it's okay.
And then you'll love New York.
You never took a plane!
It's going to be crazy. Hey?
Sir?
Come on.
Let's go!
Put that. We're expected, come on.
You know what? We'll make a game.
You're going to run down.
If you're down before
I'm at the window,
you won.
- Ok?
- Ok.
Ready?
1...
2...
3!
I'm sorry, Samuel.
It could have happened otherwise.
That should have been.
I won.
Hi, Bernie.
We're going.
"Is this the first time
you've been on a plane?"
Yeah.
- You'll see, it's a great journey.
- Hum.
"Where up to miss?"
Heathrow, terminal 3.
Wait!
What's the matter?
I gotta go back, I
forgot something.
You're sure?
- Yeah, that's super important.
- Ok.
Hurry up.
Yeah.
What are you doing here?
I told mom I had
forgotten something.
But in truth, I do
not want to leave.
You lied to her?
Ben... for the good of people,
we have the right, right?
I want everyone to
live the whole life.
We're gonna miss the plane.
Sat! Open it!
Open the door, please.
Sam.
"But where are we going?"
No idea!
Over there!
"Where are they, Bernie?"
Fuck, Samuel...
If you know, tell him.
- I dunno!
- The judge decided.
It's an abduction!
No. It's not an abduction!
Are you going to report the
disappearance of their daughter?
Tell me the truth.
He makes a bullshit!
It's irresponsible!
Stop saying that!
This "irresponsible" guy,
it's been four years since every day,
he fears that this is the last time
he will see his daughter smile.
That is the truth.
What does it mean?
She is sick.
What?
You know nothing.
- Over there!
- There's nothing!
"Yes, we're going to jump as on
the cliff when you were little!"
"Truly, I've never jumped!"
Not serious! You're immortal!
Trust me.
Hold on! No!
Did you know this thing?
"Of course!"
I know where I'm going to take you.
Here.
It was here that I did not jump.
Okay.
We can skip today.
No. We're going to start from scratch.
If you start.
To say stuff like that!
Lets' go.
There are more difficult tests than
jumping from the top of a cliff.
When Gloria entered my life,
I found the courage to throw
myself into the void.
She taught me that fear
of dying is nothing.
Alongside that are not living.
That a 20 euro ticket to pay
for a taxi could be the key.
Of absolute happiness.
A.
There is no perfect
mother or ideal father.
One does what one can.
We improvise.
Today, I just need
to look at Gloria,
to hear her laugh,
to forget all the rest.
Only count that moment.
And that little music
that will never leave me.
It was worth it.
Even when life reserves
you a setback,
a defect in the machine,
a weakness,
just here,
close to the heart,
and that the doctors explain to us.
That there is no explanation.
It's like that.
It's life.
That one day,
Gloria will fall asleep and never wake up.
The doctors had not been mistaken.
Gloria left a few weeks after she passed,
the most beautiful moments
of her family life.
My father prepared me
to face my fears,
and my daughter, to face life.
There are sometimes
falls that never stop,
but I wanted every second of this fall
to be a feast.
And today I have engraved in each
of these seconds with my daughter.
Gloria is there, near me.
Every moment. Forever.
And tomorrow