Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
# To the crowd #
# To the world #
# You were so dry #
# And with a token bird I made-- #
Once in a lifetime, a girl comes along
who's the center of your universe.
A girl who's everything and everyone.
A girl who can rock your world.
Well, Brooke Kingsley is all that and more.
And ever since I first laid eyes on her--
not a second has gone by--
that I haven't been totally--
faithfully--
and deeply in love.
# Well, if the birds #
# Can reach the sky #
# To this land #
# I'll be with you #
# Till the sun bursts from your sigh #
# With my hands #
Take me, Brad. Take me now.
Take me now.
Brad--
Brad?
Brad.
Brad!
Mr. Kimble,
would you stand up, please?
Uh--
I don't, uh--
Stand?
Uh-oh. He's got to time the wood.
You know, um, to be honest, my leg's asleep.
Actually, they're both asleep.
I don't remember having excused anyone.
Aw-- Aw-- Aw--
I hate when he does that.
The end of the school year's but a week away.
And that means that some of you
will finally be graduating high school.
And in honor of this momentous occasion,
the board of health has asked me
to give you a little going-away gift,
in the high hopes that most of you will not
litter this planet with your seed.
Hey, turn around.
- Kyle.
- Huh?
Take two.
Oh, hey, uh, no, thank you,
'cause, um, I'm already wearing one.
Dr. Brookie's orders.
Class dismissed.
I can't believe you just said that, you creep.
Scum!
- Get a little line going on.
- Sex fiend.
- Hey, let go my Eggo!
- I was joking.
Yeah, right.
So you going to Kenny’s big party this weekend?
Yeah.
Hola, mamacitas.
Uh, ¿dónde está casa le pepe?
- Oh, God. Them again?
- Losers.
No, okay, look, this is how it works, right?
You got to give them a little romance, a little mystery.
Give some of the myth before you dive in on the fluff.
Two f's.
Brad, seriously, get a life.
No, I'm telling you, Leah, you're wrong.
I mean, Brooke and I are meant for each other.
Brad, she's a wench, okay?
Don't you want someone who'll appreciate you
as a whole dialectical being?
Yeah, or at least somebody who maybe digs you.
Same diff, dork. Semantics aren't important here.
Yeah, maybe not, but fate is.
- I don't know.
- Listen to this.
My last name's Kimble.
Hers is Kingsley. K- I, K-I.
I mean, we've been seated right next
to each other in school since we were eight.
Okay, okay, fine. Give me this one.
Brooke and I would look great in family photos.
How do you know that? You two
have never shared a Kodak moment.
See, that's where you're wrong. Check this out.
Right here. Check it out.
- See Brooke cheering right here?
- So?
There I am. Bleachers. Row twenty-three.
"I Love Gumby" t-shirt.
I rest my case.
Dude, you're very creepy.
- Can I see that?
- Sure.
- Yeah?
- Aah! What are you doing?
Hello. As your best friend, I need to warn you
that you're dangerously close to
becoming an obsessive freak show.
Brad, you're crushing on a girlie-girl
who doesn't even know your name.
- Uh, Rod?
- It's Brad.
- Right.
- Brad, listen, school's over next week,
and I'm so not passing biology.
- Uh-huh.
- So, you're supposed to be like a full-on genius.
Will you tutor me, Brent?
- It's Brad, you mindless--
- You know, I would be honored.
Really? Great, um, okay.
My house, eight o’clock, Friday night. Dress casual.
And bring a big pencil.
Okay, see you later.
Wow.
You definitely just had a
conversation with the Brooke Kingsley.
Yeah, man, you didn't even piss your pants.
Right on, Kimble.
You know she totally goes all the way, right?
How would you know?
She's got the hair color. Big factor.
Invisible pantyline.
Trust me. I know.
Is it just you three, or is your
entire gender completely mental?
No, it's pretty much all of us.
This is it, guys. Fate.
You know, Bradley, when I was your age,
it was all I could think about.
Now, the first time is always the most important.
So you need to remember three things.
Number one, always treat her with respect.
Two, never push her faster than she wants to go.
And most importantly,
always make sure that she's well lubricated.
She drinks a lot of oil.
She's my pride and joy, Bradley.
And tonight, you get to experience all of her majesty.
- Leah, how are you?
- Rockin', Mrs. K.
- Uh, Brad is, uh--
- In his cave? Yeah, I know. Have fun.
- Ben, I couldn't find my ear--
- Shh. You look gorgeous.
Are you sure we shouldn't take the Jag tonight?
Oh, let's let the kid have a little fun, huh?
Amazing. All this existential hell over a cheerleader bimbo?
Hey. Okay, here we go.
- Well?
- Yeah, it'll do.
- Okay. All right.
Wait a minute.
What?
Let me see your hand, Brad.
- What?
- Your hand.
- My hand?
- Yes.
Other one.
It's--
God, it's been four days since she scribbled that.
- Don't you bathe? I mean--
- Yeah, I bathe. Plenty.
What do you do, Ziploc your digits every time you shower?
- Wow.
- What? What?
Check this, Valentino, okay?
Look, we've been best friends since, like, sperm.
And every time you get hurt, I have to be--
nice to you for a good two weeks, and--
I hate that. So let me school you
on what's gonna happen tonight.
- Sit. Okay, I'll be Brooke.
- You, be Brooke? Right.
Yeah. It's really quite simple to do.
Just think bobbing-head doll.
Ready?
Hi. I'm Brooke.
I'm a vapid, vacant, vacuous girlie-girl.
Tee-hee. Hee hee hee.
Yeah. Impressive. Uh, I think--
Come in, Brett. I've decorated my desk
extra special for you tonight.
- She doesn't have a desk.
- What?
A girl like Brooke is not gonna have a desk.
I mean, it would clash with her whole bedroom motif.
I mean, she'd have a, uh, vanity over here.
A, uh, little ribbony pillow
just filled with her magic Brooke scent.
Yeah, whatever. Anyways, now you
come in, and I'm sitting on the bed.
- Lying.
- Excuse me?
Come on, you'd be lying on the bed. Here we go.
- Look, I'm Brook, not Miss July, okay?
- Okay.
This is your big move?
- Do you remember Crayola crayons?
- Huh?
They have this one color. Uh--
What was it called? It was, um--
Oh, yeah. Blizzard Blue.
That was my favorite color in the world.
Until tonight, I didn't know why.
That's the very color of your eyes.
My eyes?
Yeah. You know, I-- I schedule my entire
day just to get a glimpse of you.
It could be the worst day ever, but seeing you--
makes everything okay.
Does it?
Yeah, it does.
I don't know why. And I want to know--
know you more.
I want to know you today, tomorrow--
forever.
Huh? That was pretty good, huh?
It took me six months to memorize that.
Yeah, and it'll take me six months to forget.
What? You didn't like it.
Christ, I think I'm gonna gag.
It's-- Aw.
Well, here we go now.
# When we played tag in grade school #
# You wanted to be it #
# But chasin' boys was just a fad #
# You crossed your heart, and you quit #
Okay.
No sweat stains.
No sweat stains. Okay. I smell good.
# Now, just like back in grade school #
# You're doing the same old thing #
# Darling, take it slow #
Hi, Brad.
It's Rod.
I mean, I have a rod. I mean, you're Brad.
Uh, uh, hi.
Wow. You look like--
Kyle.
Who's the toe jammer?
Brad is helping us study.
Study?
I told you, Kenny Ashton’s having a rager at
his parents' house tonight. Kegs, lots of kegs.
So let's forget the virgin, and let's jet! Come on.
Put me down, Kyle.
First of all, I am not so much a chattel.
Uh, chattel-- slave, livestock, or any moveable item--
- Shut up.
- Sorry.
I knew that.
And "b," my brain is important to me.
So you are leaving, and
Brad is gonna help me study.
Come in, Brad.
What are you doing?
She did not just do that.
Brooke! Brooke, open the door.
Brooke, this is retarded. I'm-- Big
Papa is not waiting outside all night.
Listen, you're really pissing me off.
Come on, Brooke. Stop kidding around.
Okay, so let me get this straight.
Pollination is the transfer of pollen
from the male reproductive organ stamen
to the female reproductive organ, the pistil?
- That's it, right?
- Huh? Uh, yeah. That's about it.
Wow. I never knew biology was so sensual.
It's, um, it's just like that, um--
that fly you were telling me about. The, uh--
The Tsetse fly?
Yeah. Tsetse fly.
I mean, it hatches, finds its mate,
and then dies within 24 hours.
It's so romantic.
All those steamy glances and taunting kisses.
Smooth sensation of skin against skin.
Incredible mind-bending sex.
Tsetse fly, man-- so intense.
Way intense.
Ahem. Brooke--
do you remember Crayola crayons?
Why? Is that gonna be on the test?
Hello.
You finished playing student yet?
No, Kyle. We're still studying.
Screw that, and let's party! Whoo-hoo!
Kyle, how many times do I have to tell you?
I need to study.
Why bother? You've already got everything you need.
A hot bod and your old man's money, so what time--
Oh, no. Oh, no, no, no.
Please don't cry. No.
What do you-- tissue.
Tissue, tissue. Over here? Over here?
Over on the, the vanity. Right.
Tissue, tissue, tissue.
Ohh!
Tissue.
Thank you.
Are all guys jerks?
Uh-huh.
You're sweet. And you listen to me.
Shh. Not so loud.
You'll give me a bad rep.
What's so hard to get?
All a girl wants is a little romance.
To be swept off her feet.
I mean, is that so much to ask?
You know, I don't know about other guys,
but if we were together--
I would treat you like a queen, a Goddess.
Brad, I know this is gonna sound corny,
but, um, will you give me a hug?
That feels better.
Thanks.
Do you want to--
Oh, God, it feels good to hug you.
Epic.
Brad, breathe.
Oh, God.
You don't know how many times
I've dreamed of this exact moment.
How many times? Tell me.
As many times as there are stars in the sky.
Right answer.
Tell me more.
- You, me, together as one.
- More.
- Running my hands through your golden hair.
- Touching your velvet lips.
- More.
God.
Caressing my supple breasts?
# We played a show, and no one came #
# We played and played it just the same #
Um, Brad, do you have anything?
Not a thing. I'm perfectly healthy.
You know, to be honest, I don't
really get out all that much.
No. Um, no, that's not what I meant.
I mean, do you have, you know, protection?
Ohh.
Yeah. Just give me a couple of seconds.
I'll be right back, in five minutes? Tops.
Big dog.
Hey, mister, mister, wash your windows?
No, thank you.
Wash your windows, two dollars.
Thank you very much, though.
You can't pass up a bargain like that.
You smell like-- I know that smell.
That's a 1972 XKE
It is a '72.
Oh, that's the last best year for these babies.
I would absolutely say go ahead and wash the windows--
Oh. Okay. Uh--
Please, go right ahead,
but if you could just--
I'll get this baby shining like a brand-new dime.
# I saw this girl, and she drove me wild #
# She looked at me, and I looked and smiled #
Come on. Condoms.
Condoms? Condoms?
Where the hell are the condoms?
# I have a date #
# Yeah! #
Condoms, condoms, condoms.
Cones, Papa-Stopper, Jimmy Hats,
Doggy bags, oven mitt, crash helmet, condoms!
Oh, where are they? Where are they?
Holy Sweet Mary, Mother of God.
Trojans.
# I have a date #
Yup. Reservoir-tipped is always a good selection.
Got to use ribbed, kid.
The chicks will appreciate it.
Good evening. How we doing?
Much better now. Thank you.
Uh, Leon, could I get a price check on
a twelve-pack of Trojan prophylactics?
What's a propho-pactic?
Can I have one, too?
No.
I need a propho-pactic!
I have to have a propho-pactic!
Get me a propho-pactic!
Grace, is that jumbo or peewee?
- No, it's just--
- You know, actually,
why don't I just give you a twenty?
Buy something nice for your kids.
I don't have any kids.
There's a shocker.
Go out and buy yourself a couple of mags, okay?
Thank you.
Okay, I left my wallet in the car.
I'll be back in, like, one second.
Hey, Mike, come back!
I am so screwed.
Ohh. I mean really.
I mean, how many people even really want
a silver classic 1972 Jaguar XKE?
The only reason I ask, you know,
it's just, like, my life
we're discussing here!
Don't get your hopes up.
We suspect that gangs are making their way into the area.
Car's probably sawed in half and
on its way to South America by now.
My advice-- go home. Go to your girlfriend's.
Just try not to think about it.
Home.
Go to my girlfriend's.
Brooke.
I'm so dead.
Brooke's gonna kill me.
At least I have Brooke.
Wait a second.
What am I gonna say to her?
Little bit late here. No, you don't have a car.
All right, uh, let's see. You were--
delivering toys, to orphans--
and, and you had to--
save them from a burning building.
Excellent sympathy factor.
Aw.
Oh-- oh, no.
Smudged.
All right, all right, all right.
This is bad. This is real bad.
Odds are it's probably a-- seven.
Brooke?
Hello, and welcome to Movie Phone.
If you know the name of the mov--
Uh--
All right, it's not a seven.
Then it would be a--
Hello?
Ugh. I just scarfed down two burritos.
Oh, hey, Trish. What's up?
Think I have a problem.
We're sorry. Your call cannot be comple--
How do you guys think Brad's doing with old Brookie?
Well, if he's attempting the old sexual-predator,
Kyle-monster thing, he's sunk.
But if he's doing a Brad,
he'll be just fine.
"Doing a Brad"?
Yeah, a Brad.
You know, Brad's a stand-up guy.
You know, Brad's your bud.
Brad's, uh, you know--
Your best friend.
Exactly. Brad's your best friend.
See, chicks totally dig that.
That and good wood.
Hmm. You really think so?
Good wood is very important.
Hello.
Leah, need your help.
Brad? What? What's wrong?
Well, okay, I'm in a bit of a jam here.
I need you to come pick me up now.
Pick you up? Where are you?
Downtown.
Downtown? How in the hell did you get there?
Leah, I don't really have time to explain this now!
If you could just come and pick me up,
I mean, is that such a big thing to ask?!
Uh, pop a stress tab, why don't ya?
I'm begging, okay? I'm here on my knees.
I am actually physically groveling.
Can you hear this?
Please! Come pick me up.
Fine, I'm on my way.
Thank you.
Okay, um--
I'm gonna hop on a bus. I'll meet you halfway.
Like the corner of Fifth and Reseda.
Is that okay? Okay?!
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, I heard you. I'll be there.
Oh, come on, man. You made them too big.
I can't even see her face.
You just don't get it, do you?
Ahh. Ohh, God. What a night.
Uh-- Uh, God. You know what?
Actually, I don't have any money.
Um, see, no, no, no. I had my wallet--
Can I just tell you something?
- Every single day, you kids make me stop.
- This is the first time that I--
- Then you hop on, and you stiff
me out of the fare, huh?
- See, I've never actually been on a--
What's that sign read, huh?
"Exact change only"! Sixty-five cents, right?
Uh, yeah, um--
Sixty-five cents, right?
Not sixty-four. Not sixty-six.
Sixty-five cents!
Do you see a sign anywhere that says,
"Come on, bro, hop on board,
I'll take you anywhere you wanna go"?
Well, I don't think so!
Yiii!
"Exact change only," right?
"Exact change only. "
See, you Gen-X, mocha-sipping,
chain-smoking slackers need to learn to listen!
Whoa!
Ohh! My balls.
Need to learn there's no such thing in life as free rides!
You know, I don't know why I do this.
He can't just expect me to take care of things all the time.
And all for a girlie-girl!
Ugh! God.
Leah!
Hey! Hey!
Leah to the rescue to hump with Brooke.
Ugh.
Hey, Leah!
It's Brad!
So who's gonna be at Kenny Ashton’s?
Kegs. Lots of them.
Well, I'm supposed to be studying, but--
I think he's playing hard to get.
I wanna get off now!
Aah!
Whoa!
Oh.
Next time, maybe you'll remember!
No free rides!
Oh, no. Aw, shit.
This is not good.
Oh, this is so not good. This just isn't right.
Just not--
Bitch!
Oh, this is really not good.
No.
Hi.
Hola.
Wow. What a great place you guys, uh, have here.
Uh, I was actually wondering
if there's a pay phone around somewhere.
Pop in a peso, reach out and touch someone.
Whoops. You dropped something there.
Uh, pay phone somewhere nearby I could use?
Wait a second! Wait a second!
Actually, I know how to say this sentence in Spanish.
What-- you like that? What are the chances-- hi.
What are the chances?
Um, it was, uh, ¿adónde dinero?
No, no, no. I got it! I got it!
What's the matter?
Did I mispronounce it?
Hola, chulo. ¿Como está, mmm?
Me gusta ese hombre.
Está Rico-- Suave.
My sister says that you look like
that guy in Baywatch.
- ¿Como se llama? Es--
- David Hasselhoff.
That's her favorite show, man.
Yeah? Me, too.
Ibaila conmigo, chulo!
My little sister says that she wants
to dance with you the salsa contest.
Hey, that is flattering.
It is, but now's not a great time.
See, there's a girl that I really gotta get back to.
This is her, and--
Get out of here!
Whoo!
Ooh! Mmm. Mmm.
Salsa!
# Moment by moment #
# The fever is starting to rise #
Whoo!
# I feel the heat #
# In my veins #
# From the fire in your eyes #
David Hasselhoff.
# No one makes me feel #
# The way you do #
# No one gets me hot #
# Just like you do #
# You and you alone #
# Can set my soul #
# On fire #
Iputa, es m'ijo!
Isangrona!
Ipendejai
Aah!
# You and you alone #
# That's my #
# Desire #
# You and you alone #
# That's my #
# Desire #
Good boy, eh?
Ey!
Los ganadores son Señorita Roja
y Davíd Hasselhoff.
Eh?
One hundred dollars.
You won, Señor Hasselhoff.
Bésame.
What the hell was that?
Okay. Okay. Okay, quick inventory.
You just won a dance contest,
you're completely lost,
and you're about to become
a chili mama love slave.
Hey, David Hasselhoff! Open up, ese!
My sister loves you, man!
She wants to Macarena with you!
Ipor favor, Señor Hasselhoff!
Ila proxima es la Macarena!
Hey!
Iyo te amo!
Hello!
Imi amor! Imi amor!
Okay, it's official. I am in hell.
Huh?
Hey, that's a Jag!
Stop! Stop!
Whoa! Oof.
I think you guys have my dad's car.
No, it ain't, pinche gringo.
This is my ride, fool.
Puto.
Well, um, I don't know who Pluto is, but, uh--
Okay. Okay, maybe, um--
May-- maybe this will clear everything up.
See, before I got my license
my mom totally freaked out on me,
'cause, you know, her only child
was out driving on the "mean streets."
So before I could drive an inch--
and this is gonna sound totally cheesy, but--
she bought me one of those little troll key chains
with the-- the spiky, orange hair.
And I don't know what trolls have to do with good luck,
but, uh, you know, it's--
it's right here in the glove box.
If you just let me, um--
See?
- Hey, your mom got you one of those, too?
- Yeah.
Right, you and me, caro, we got a lot in common.
You know what I'm saying?
So let's kick it, homey.
Come on. Come chill with the Vatos.
So where do you guys go to school?
Toro Reformatory.
Bet they have a pretty good football team.
Ours kinda sucks
at Dewey Weber. Rah rah.
Dewey? Ah, man, I know that place.
We tagged it up a couple months ago.
Wait. Behind the gym? That was you guys?
That was some really excellent work.
Bold lettering. The choice of fluorescent colors.
It was so jejune.
Yeah, well, art runs in the family, homes.
It's my, uh, it's my passion.
It's a shame the janitor washed it off.
They what?
You-- your-- your graff-- your artwork.
It's-- it's gone.
Chicks, man. I don't get it.
Soon as you think you're giving it to them enough,
they tell you you're giving it to them too much.
Why can't they just be happy
you're giving it to them at all?
I don't know, Kyle. You're pretty
in touch with your feelings, man.
That's 'cause I'm sensitive, ass-wipe.
Well, you must be. I mean, you're letting
Brooke fin-slap that Urkel.
Huh? Hey, isn't that the--
Naw. No way.
Hmm.
Hey, Brad! What you think, homes?
Pretty dope, eh?
Bet you never peeped a honey this fine, homes.
You know, actually, there is this one girl
that-- that I kinda, you know--
Hey, hey.
I saved the final touch for you. Right here.
Go ahead, homes, pop her cherries on.
Oh-- I don't-- you know.
I don't think I could--
Come on, you sissy la-la.
Eh, don't worry, ese.
It's on the down-low.
Don't be shy there, homes. Not mosquito bites.
Silver dollars, homes. Silver dollars!
All right, ese.
You've got some real talent, you know?
Thank you. You guys aren't so bad yourselves.
Think you should've made these bigger, though.
Oh, wait. Dripping here.
I hate that. Drippy nipples.
Wait a sec. Guys!
Guys, that's my dad's car! Hey!
Guys, give me a ride!
Hey! We're chillin' on the down-low! Aw.
What did I do to deserve this?
I mean, all I wanted was one lousy condom! Just one!
Is that really that much to ask?
Just one lousy condom and five minutes!
Just five minutes with Brooke!
I take it all back.
Aah!
Aw, you're kidding.
Mmm.
I, uh, ha.
I knew it. I knew they'd be back.
Goddamned taggers.
Oh, this is so great.
# This is so great #
# It's about time #
Freeze, you punk-ass mouse!
I'll break all your bones
and play marbles with your testicles, boy!
Make a mess out of my school,
I make a mess out of you, fool!
Scumbag!
I knew you filthy maggots would be back.
Only this time, I'm flushing you out.
Oh! Oh, ho!
Aah!
Aah ha ha!
Whoa!
What the hell was that?
Stinky asshole! Come here, you fool!
Ahh.
Maggot!
Oh.
Maggots think you can destroy taxpayer's
property? Well, think again, pal!
I just wanna get laid.
Hyah!
Shouldn't have messed with Mr. Clean, maggot!
Aah! Aah!
Nowhere. I just could not get anywhere.
Ah-choo!
Oh.
Oh, God.
Imi amor! Imi amor!
lallí está mi amor! Imi amori les bonito!
Oh, no.
This is so stupid.
I-- I should just tell him how I feel.
Just say it.
You know, just say--
Brad, you rock, man.
Oh, God. This is stupid, stupid, stupid--
Yeah. Enough. This is bullshit.
- Ino, m'ijo!
- Stop, pendejo!
Hey!
I'm not David Hasselhoff!
Aah!
Hey. Hey, Leah--
Uh--
Ow.
Ohh.
Brad? Oh, my God.
What happened to you? Where have you been?
Oh, I've been just about everywhere.
Oh, it's so good to see you.
Oh, my God. Oh.
Imi amor! Imi amor!
Okay, let's go.
- Have you been eating Mexican?
- Now!
- Imi amor!
- Mr. Hasselhoff! Hey!
Brad, where's your dad's car?
You know, Leah, at some point in the future
we can have this discussion.
But now is really not the time, so if you could
please just get me back to Brooke's.
Fine. Whatever.
So I guess you guys will probably be studying,
you know, too late to be going to Kenny Ashton’s party.
Yeah, gonna be studying real late.
Well, I-- I was thinking about going.
Really? That's great!
You know, you should get out.
Uh, don't be a sissy la-la, you know?
Yeah.
Yeah, well-- kinda thought, um,
maybe we could go together.
Oh. Leah, I can't go anywhere.
I mean, I'm this close to finding true love.
You guys got it on? I can't believe it.
Why? Why can't you believe it?
You can't believe that, what, maybe she found me attractive?
- No.
- What can't you believe?
Just how could you? How cou--
You just don't get it, do you?
You know what? I don't get it.
I don't get how my usually intelligent best friend
could actually think he's in love
with a caricature of every shallow male fantasy--
Whatever. Just drive me there.
Hey, uh, thanks, Leah.
Listen, about what I said back there,
I really-- I-- I really want--
Leah!
Aha.
Brooke.
All right.
Caressing my supple breasts?
Finally.
Ah.
Hey, Brooke.
Brooke!
Sprinklers, man.
All right.
Brooke.
Brookie.
I'm back.
Honey-- daddy's home.
Ah-choo!
Oh.
Ohh.
Where?
Great.
What?
Aah.
Oh!
Wait. Wait.
Oh.
No.
No!
Oh, no!
No, no! Come on!
No!
Oh, no.
Did you see your assailants?
All I know is those kids are maggots!
That's just what I thought.
Gangs.
Seven-Mary-Three. Seven-Mary-Three.
We have a 211 in progress at 741 big wood drive.
10-4, dispatch. I'm rolling.
All right, just hold still.
It'll just take a second.
Oh! Ooh! Oh!
Aah! Aah! Oh!
# How do you know #
# The way to my heart? #
# How do you know? #
Oh. Kenny Ashton’s. Okay, it's--
All right, Vatos. The party's over.
Place is surrounded.
Come out with your hands up.
I'm gonna have your ass, you scum.
Oh. Oh, jeez.
How you gonna explain this?
Oh, wait. I know. You can't.
Come out!
Oh, why couldn't I have just
fallen in love with Becky Chub, huh?
I mean, facial hair's not such a terrible thing on a girl.
Shh. Shh. Shh.
Over here in back! Get him!
I'll cover the front door! Go!
Good doggy! Sit! Sit!
Stay! Heel! Some best friend!
Keep away!
Nice--
doggy!
Okay.
All right.
Oh, God.
Oh.
Oh, shit.
# Burn, baby, burn #
# Disco Inferno #
# Burnin' love now #
# Burnin' #
# To my surprise #
# Listen #
# One-hundred stories high #
Is it just me, or is everybody
acting really weird tonight?
I mean, what was that, disco?
# On the roof here #
Whatever. Doesn't really matter.
Huh?
Uh-oh.
Oh, give me a break.
Whoo!
Oh. Ohh.
It feels good to get down, doesn't it?
Mm-hmm.
Sure beats the hell out of that barn-dancing.
Mmm.
Ben.
Outside.
What's going on?
Hey! Just go way, dog!
It's Friday night, and they're destroying private property.
Probably one of those crack-tagging gangers or something.
I better call the police. Damn kids.
Aah!
Look, Scooby snack!
Go get a Scooby snack!
Stay! Stay!
Heel! Heel!
Go! Shoo!
Shoo!
Get out of here!
Seven-Mary-Three. Seven-Mary-Three.
We have a breaking and entering
at the greenhouse country club.
Uh-oh.
Uhh--
Aah aah aah!
Aah! Oh!
Hey!
You still owe me two dollars.
Oh! That sucks. No.
Maybe it's some sort of--
hormonal imbalance.
Maybe she's possessed.
Know what I think it is?
I think we are witnessing the dreaded PMS beast.
Whoa.
Yeah.
So?
Well, how's it look?
Dude, you have breasts.
Ohh! Your stupid male observations do not apply to me!
- Okay. Leah, let him live.
- Don't touch me!
I'm sorry. It's just that we're not used to
seeing you with, uh-- that way.
- What way?!
- Well, in girlie clothes.
You say the word "girlie" one more time,
I will not hesitate to kick your ass!
You sissy la-las are coming to
Kenny Ashton’s party with me.
Uh-uh. No way.
Josh here is still in training.
He's not yet had the full benefit
of my expert tutelage and guidance.
- He--
- Don't say it.
You think I could just have my old clothes back?
Brooke's not really into vinyl.
Uh, who's Brooke?
Only the greatest girl ever to walk the face of the earth.
Oh, one of those?
No, not one of those. Brooke's--
she's different, you know?
She's the girl of my dreams.
Oh, dreams. Dreams and love.
Dreams and love.
Funny thing about dreams.
When you're dreaming,
your eyes are closed.
So close your eyes. Dream.
Ow! You dick!
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
You gotta look at this world
with eyes wide open.
Wide open.
Now, the advice was free, but the clothes--
the clothes are gonna cost you.
Now, that's sixty-five,
eighty-five for the shirt and the jacket.
It's eight and a half percent street tax.
Now, that's ninety-nine eighteen.
- Ninety-nine dollars for this?
- I'll take it back.
No, no, no. You don't have to take it back.
Hang on. Hang on one second.
Huh? I was dancing in a salsa con-- I--
It's not important.
Now you got a transaction.
You! I thought I told you no free rides!
Wait, wait, wait. I got the money.
Hey! Hey!
Let me in, psychopath! Let me in!
No! No free rides! I told you! No!
Walk places!
- Open the door!
- No!
Huh?
Stop the bus!
You scumbag.
You almost got me killed
for sixty-five lousy cents!
Hey, looky here, pal!
I got your sixty-five cents.
I don't want your stinking free ride, buddy!
Believe me, Mr. Man,
I had to work my slacker butt
a damn-sight harder to earn this money
than just sit behind a steering wheel
on my lazy,
psychotic
ass!
Oh. That's all I wanted.
Please take a seat.
Hey, thank you for conserving fuel
and riding public transportation.
Enjoy your evening.
Okay.
Nothing's changed.
Brooke still wants you.
I mean, uh, all I really need is--
Ohh.
Hey.
Four seventy-five.
Uh, gosh, you know what?
I'm, uh, a little short.
No! I mean, I don't have any money.
Okay, um-- If you could just try
to put yourself in my situation.
Just-- just for a second, please.
Haven't you ever been in love?
I mean-- I mean, so in love
that-- that just the thought of being with that someone
was enough to get you through the day.
Mmm.
Then what if those--  those stupid, stupid things--
could make all of your hopes and dreams come true?
Come on. Haven't you ever dreamed?
Four seventy-five.
Say, do you remember Crayola crayons?
All right, nobody move!
Brad, is that you?
Yo, homeys! Hey, check it out.
What's up, Brad?
Brad, man. Hey.
Scoring some jimmies, or what, homes?
Trying. I'm really trying.
But frankly, she's not helping.
Hey, give me the jimmies with the money.
- They're four seventy-five.
- I got three fifty-seven.
It's on us, homey.
All right, Vatos--
Aw, man!
The pigs, homes!
There's a shocker.
You're surrounded. Come out with your hands up.
Make it easy on yourselves.
I have your ass, you scum.
You know, Brad, don't take this the wrong way,
'cause you and me, we're solid, homes.
But I gotta take you hostage.
- Brad.
- Yeah?
I never really did this before, you know?
You think you could help out?
Yeah. I mean, um--
I'll see what I can do.
Please don't shoot! Please!
They're lunatics, every last one of them!
Your firearms are useless against them!
Please! I just wanna live!
Hold your fire!
Aw. Damn.
Hey, that's pretty good, homes.
Thanks. Drama club, sophomore year.
Tell my mom I love her.
We interrupt this program
with a special news bulletin.
Ben, come in here.
--Suspected gang members
who have been responsible for the
recent rash of local robberies.
Roadblocks are being set up--
God, that's terrible.
God, we are so lucky to be so far away from all this.
Goddamn kids.
Here you go, Brad. Your jimmies, homes.
Oh, yeah, thanks, man.
Yo, Brad, you know, I was wondering.
You think maybe if me and the boys
could hang with you at your party, you know.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The party. Good idea, good idea. Let's go there.
Just please get me back to Brooke, okay?
- Mi casa es su casa. Just get there.
- Right on, Brad.
Look, I know you're waiting for Brad,
so I'm only going to say this once.
Brad is not just a good guy.
He's a great guy.
He's smart, and he's funny.
He's my best friend in the whole world.
And for some stupid reason
he's head-over-feet for you.
I don't get it, but--
he's my friend, and you're the one that he wants.
So treat him right, okay?
Mm-hmm.
Because if you don't, I'll ox-ecute you, your friends,
and your fashion accessories, you tacky bourgeois bitch!
Charming.
Hey, I'm vacating this ritualized, adolescent
display of hedonistic amorality.
- Huh?
- What?
I'm leaving. You guys staying or going?
- Stayin'.
Yeah.
Okay, okay.
Here's how it is. You go for girl, twelve o'clock.
- You're gonna get her.
- Yes.
- Trust me.
- Yeah.
So--
When does your centerfold come out?
Creep.
Brooke, come here.
Oh, joy. The future wife-beater.
No, listen. Are you banging the study hall turd?
Kyle, what are you talking about?
You and the little--
That's Brooke! Brooke!
Brooke!
Brooke! It's Brad!
Hey! Aah! She's talking to Kyle.
Seven-Mary-Three,
suspects are currently headed
northbound on green hill drive,
approximately three hundred yards from your position.
We do have a beam.
Holding for a green light.
Take 'em.
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Yo, Brad. You got insurance?
There is this girl.
This is a girl who's everything and everyone.
This is a girl who can just rock your world.
Man, this girl--
I look like David Hasselhoff.
And I'm doing this crazy lambada song.
Janitor man!
One night-- Hit me dead center in the chest.
One night-- Knocks me--
Scary, scary.
This guy has got the I.Q. of a cheeseburger.
That's before you guys decide to use it for target practice.
That's all I wanted. I wanted one night,
with my one true love.
I didn't know I'd almost have to die for it!
Love sucks!
It's a four-letter word.
It's some bullshit, capitalist conspiracy
made up by greedy florists.
You know what "love" backwards is?
It's e-v-o-l.
Evil! Pure evil!
Granted, it's spelled differently, but it's the same thing.
Well, you're either telling the truth,
or you ought to be locked up
for telling the biggest goddamn lie ever.
Number one-- clean up, change,
'cause vice will just drag your ass back in here.
Number two-- your belongings.
And what's left of your daddy's car.
- Is that it?
- No, it isn't.
Let me tell you something, son.
Love is hard to find.
True love is even harder, damn near impossible.
It took me twenty-two years, one thousand,
four-hundred and ninety-two blind dates from hell.
So you ask yourself, haven't you
come too far just to give up?
Yes.
I'm still not one damn step closer to getting what I need.
You get one phone call, son,
then you get out of here.
Hey, kid.
Make her day.
# I believe in #
# I believe in love #
You look great.
Is that a new outfit or something?
You all dressed up for the party?
I don't need to impress high school boys.
Then again, maybe I should.
Maybe you'd take heed.
Take heed? Of what?
You know, I swear to God, Leah.
Sometimes I think you and I know each other
better than any other two people
on the face of the earth.
This is us, you know?
And other times, I just don't understand
what the hell you're saying.
There's nothing to understand.
Has anybody seen my jacket?
Look, I don't get it. Are you listening to me?
You kick me out for dweeb boy? Why?
Do you hear someone talking?
I could swear I hear someone talking.
You are banging him, aren't you?
I knew it. I knew it.
Oh, Kyle. I wouldn't worry.
All you're going to need to get by
in this life are your muscles
and your teeny-weeny,
little--
brain.
I'm going to kill that little rat turd.
I'm going to kill him big-time!
# He can't get a cab #
# 'Cause he ain't got the money #
Oh. Ooh, baby.
Yeah.
Ha ha. All right?
All right. Let's go get her.
I don't-- I don't want to.
Oh. Trust me. I know.
Let's go. Come on.
# Uh-oh, we're in trouble #
All right.
So, uh--
That's a lovely dress you have on.
Yeah, it matches perfectly with my bedspread.
- Ow.
She must be color blind.
Are you sure you don't want to
just come in for a sec?
No, thanks. Not my scene.
- Hey, Leah, thanks. No, really, for everything.
- Yeah.
Okay.
- Hey, B?
- Yeah?
When you kissed her-- I just want to know.
What was it like?
Was it everything you dreamed of?
Close enough.
- Brad?
- Yeah.
Look, I don't really know the best way to
say this, so I'm just going to say it.
I--
hope you get everything you want.
I hope she makes you really happy.
Thanks, Leah.
# Uh-oh #
# We're in trouble #
Excuse me.
Excuse me, do you own the penis mobile?
I kind of need to get out of here.
It's not mine.
Do you have a penis mobile?
Brooke?
Brooke!
Yeah!
Okay.
You've got to be kidding me.
Imi amor! Excuse me!
Excuse me!
- Brad. Hey.
- Oh. Oh, Seth, Josh.
What do you guys know about Latin women?
Ah. I know Latin women.
Good.
You know nothing!
Imi amor!
I don't know Latin women?
Yeah!
¿Dónde está casa le pepe?
That was me. That was my line.
- ¿Dónde está-- bite me.
- No. ¿Dónde está casa le pepe?
It's the best line ever.
I can't do this.
Trust me. You know.
Hola. Mamacita.
Lamigos!
Hey, my sister thinks you guys look like
Chandler and Ross from "Friends."
- It's her favorite show.
- Sí, sí.
- No way.
- Sí, way.
- Me, too.
Hey. Hey, and you, you know,
she's right. You do look like Chandler.
I mean, chinos and all that stuff.
There you are.
Where have you been?
I was, uh--
delivering burning orphans.
Oh. Come on.
We have some unfinished business.
Hey, you. Peenie mobile?
Excuse me. Peenie mobile?
Peenie--
# Ain't got #
# The measure of mercy #
# Breathe in #
# Nobody could #
# Smile and catch #
# Breathe in #
# Nobody could #
# Smile and catch #
Take me, Brett.
Wait. What?
Take me.
No, that part was good,
but you called me Brett.
My name's Brad.
Not important. Doesn't matter. Doesn't matter.
No.
No, no, wait. No.
Do you want to tell everybody
we're, you know, together?
But I'm going out with Kyle.
Kyle?
Well--
What about-- you and I--
What is this?
Oh. This.
You see, this is your lucky night.
What?
- You don't know me.
- So? It's just sex.
It's not just sex.
I mean, what about the steamy glances,
the taunting kisses?
Hello. I was talking about a fly.
You know, when I finally do this,
I want it to be absolutely perfect.
I want it to be with someone who knows me.
Somebody who's, like, your best
friend in the world, you know?
Somebody like--
# Breathe in #
# Nobody could #
# Smile and catch #
# Breathe in #
# Nobody could #
# Smile and catch #
Do it. Just do it.
I got to go to the bathroom! Open up!
So, wanna rattle?
I got to pee!
# Somebody want a good vibration? #
# Better sit down and hear my sound #
# Ship out, not here, get out #
# That's the burden of the devil's right hand #
# Go! #
Seth! Josh!
Yeah?
Where's Leah?
She just b-bailed.
Oops. Hey.
Not now, Kyle.
No. See, first, you're up in the bedroom.
Oh, yeah.
And then, you're scoring jimmies at the A&P.
- Now--
- You guys are such jerks.
Pssh.
Oh!
I'm going to kick your ass all over this party.
Hey. Good doggy.
Fetch!
Good doggy.
Leah! Leah! Wait!
Finished with Brooke already?
Oh, come on, Leah, please--
No, sorry, stud, but if you're looking for help
in the self-control department,
I can't help you there.
Leah, Leah, nothing happened.
I couldn't.
I mean, you know, I could have.
She was right there on the counter.
Leah, Leah, please. I know you're upset.
No, I am not upset, Brad.
I'm tired.
I'm tired of listening to your childish fantasies.
So please save your fate and Crayola crap for someone else.
Because all you're looking for is heartache and pain.
Trust me, I know.
Leah, Leah.
Stop, stop, stop. Stop.
Please, please. Just listen to me.
I have been looking for something all night long.
And it has caused me nothing but heartache and pain.
But that's only because I was looking for the wrong thing.
You see, I realized that this whole time,
I should've been looking right in front of me.
What?
I should've been looking for you.
Listen. Even I don't know the
best way to say this.
- So I'm just going to say it. Okay?
- Okay.
Was it everything you dreamed of?
Close enough.
# To the crowd #
# To the world #
# You were so dry #
# And with the token bird I made #
# Sent here to fly #
# Right to your side #
# With a broken wing #
# You sailed #
# Oh, like winter #
# It's your life #
# A barren river wide #
# I'll pray for the flood #
# To wash on you #
# It's here #
# I'll be with you #
# Well, if the birds #
# Can reach the sky #
# To this land #
# I'll be with you #
# Till the sun bursts #
# From your sigh #
# With my hands #
# I'll reach to you #
# When you think #
# Your chance is passing by #
# When you blow #
# Your moon away #
# I'll bleed like a reed #
# Fall with your night #
# It's here #
# I'll be with you #
# To the crowd #
# To the world #
# You were so dry #
# And with the token bird I made #
# Sent here to fly #
# Right to your side #
# With a broken wing #
# You sailed #
# Oh, like winter #
# It's your life #
# A barren river wide #
# I'll pray for the flood #
# To wash on you #
# It's here #
# I'll stay with you #
# I'll be with you #
# Oh #
# Oh, oh, oh #
# I'll fall #
# Ah #
# I've got a flair #
# For pulling your hair #
# And making you crazy #
# Oh, yeah #
# It's something I do well #
# I've got a flair #
# For making you care #
# You know you should hate me #
# Oh, yeah #
# It's something I do well #
# And you know I never meant #
# To hurt no one #
# But I've got a knack #
# For getting things undone #
# And I've got a way of ruining your fun #
# All the time #
# I've got a flair #
# For holding a stare #
# And holding you downtown #
# Oh, yeah #
# It's something I can tell #
# And you know I never meant #
# To hurt no one #
# But I've got a knack #
# For getting things undone #
# And I've got a way of ruining your fun #
# All the time #
# I've got a flair #
# For gettin' in your hair #
# And making you crazy #
# Oh, yeah #
# It's something I do well #
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player