Princess_Protection_Program_(2009_TV) ,BR_MKV_H264_AC3[5.1](Disney,Eng) 1280x720
¶ yeah!
¶ do what you wanna do
¶ be what you wanna be
¶ freedom's no mystery
¶ say what you wanna say
¶ tomorrow is another day
¶ but here's the news
¶ nobody's stopping you
¶ do what you wanna do
¶ yeah!
Hey, you just...
Hi, donny.
Hey...
Carter.
Right. How much?
Oh, no, no, no.
No charge.
A deal's a deal.
Free bait in exchange
for never having to
take the bus again.
Great.
Carter, talk to you
for a second?
Yeah.
So, did he ask you
to that homecoming
dance thing yet?
Dad! Don't
embarrass me.
I'm your dad, it's
my job. Come home
right after school.
We got a lot of work
to do around here.
Yeah.
What are you
doing here?
Donny's driving us until
I get my new ride.
Isn't that sweet?
That's sweet.
There's no room for me.
Sure there is.
Come on, climb in.
No, she's right. Brooke's
already wrinkling my
after-lunch outfit.
No, I'm not!
Chelsea, this
is high school,
not Vegas.
You don't need
a costume change.
Right.
But you might wanna
think about it.
(chuckles)
I'm sorry, Carter.
Hey, thanks for the bait.
See you.
Bye.
¶ do what you wanna do
¶ be what you wanna be
¶ freedom's no mystery
¶ say what you wanna say
¶ tomorrow is another day ¶
I can't stand them.
They're such princesses.
You said that like
it's a bad thing.
Carter, they're teenage
girls. They're probably
just jealous.
Yeah, I'm pretty
sure they're not.
(cell phone ringing)
It's Mason. Yes, sir.
No, sir.
Right away.
You're leaving again?
Two days, Max.
It's no big deal.
It's just a routine op.
Yeah, that's what
you always say.
Just be careful. Okay?
Always.
You and me, pal.
You and me, dad.
Dimitri: Her royal highness,
Rosalinda Marie Montoya Fiore.
Princesa de Costa Luna.
And you're walking,
and walking
As your adoring
subjects welcome
you.
Dimitri, my coronation
is one month away.
Why do we have
to practice now?
Ah!
The rehearsal is
so that everything
will be perfect.
Princesa, what a beautiful
coronation dress
you are wearing.
Who, may I ask,
designed it?
You did, Mr. Elegante.
So I did.
I am brilliant, no?
(laughing) yes.
Sophia: Thank you
for coming to help
Rosalinda.
Now that my husband
has passed away,
Only she can become
Queen of Costa Luna.
But it is so much
for someone so young.
And I'm afraid
that general Kane will
take advantage of that.
No, I'll be here,
Sophia. I'll protect
her like she's my own.
I know you will,
major Mason.
I know you will.
(coronation music playing)
Sounds like your music.
(Rosalinda speaking Spanish)
Turn to face your
subjects, Rosalinda.
Honored guests,
family, friends,
I present to you
princesa Rosalinda
Marie Montoya Fiore,
Heir to the throne
of Costa Luna.
She is willing
to be your Queen.
If any person has
a reason to object,
Let them come forward
and be heard!
(all gasping)
I object.
The princesa is too
young to be Queen.
Costa Luna and
Costa Estrella are
two tiny countries
Who must unite
and stand together
against the world.
Therefore, for the good
of both our countries,
I, general magnus Kane,
Declare myself el presidente
de la republica
de las Costas.
(all exclaiming)
Seize them!
(all shouting)
(grunting)
What?
The time is now.
Go now with
major Mason.
Go now!
Archbishop:
Hurry, my Queen,
we must go now.
Who are you?
Where are you
taking me?
I'm here to protect you,
but you need to trust me.
But what about
my mother?
She's going to meet us,
but we need to hurry.
Are you all right, mama?
Yes, yes, darling, yes.
I knew general Kane
would try something
like this,
So I made a plan
to protect you.
You must trust
major Mason. You must
do everything he says.
Do you promise me
you will do that?
Yes, mama, I promise.
Joe: We need to move.
Okay. Come on.
Mama, where are we going?
No, not "we," mija.
You.
The general will
say you abandoned
the country,
But I must stay,
so the people know
That you will return
when it's safe.
No! Not without you.
Here.
So, no matter what
happens, you never
forget you are a Princess.
Don't worry, mi Reina
bonita, we will be
together very soon.
(guards shouting)
We gotta go now.
Let's go.
(helicopter blades whirring)
Joe: Hurry up! Inside!
Go!
You will never find her.
And as long as
she remains free,
There will be hope
in Costa Luna.
I could not agree more.
But the princesa
is only a girl, madam.
She will contact her mother.
And when she does,
I will bring her
back to Costa Luna,
Where she will
rot with her mother
in a tiny dirt cell.
You will both become
a tragic symbol of futility
to those who would defy me.
Take her away!
What is this place?
You'll see.
(birds squawking)
Automated voice:
Door opening.
Door closing.
(machinery whirring)
What... Where am I?
Is this some kind
of prison?
Not prison, protection.
Princess Rosalinda
Marie Montoya Fiore,
You are now in
the safe custody
Of the international
Princess Protection
Program, the PPP.
I've never heard of it.
Nobody ever hears about
us until we're needed.
Good work, major.
Thank you, director.
Automated voice:
Level three. Security.
You'll be safe now,
Princess.
(door closes)
(machinery whirring)
How long am I staying here?
Until you're ready
for stage four.
Stage four?
What is stage one?
Extraction. That is
what brought you here.
Stage two?
Transition.
Transition to what?
Stage three.
Come inside,
why don't you?
And I will
explain everything.
Welcome, Rosalinda,
to the operational heart
Of the Princess
protection program,
A top-secret agency
funded by the world's
royal families.
We are actively
providing protection
to 29 princesses,
All of whom have
been threatened in
one way or another.
(machinery beeping)
Chloe, may I?
Of course, director.
Director:
This is Princess chandra.
Last January,
major Mason rescued her from
a politically-motivated coup.
We have placed her where
no one will find her.
(tapping on keyboard)
Let's just say she's
a little farther north
than she's used to.
She is freezing!
Probably.
But she's safe.
Let's take a walk,
shall we?
Please.
Chloe, report.
"Princess 383 has had
a successful extraction.
"she arrives
at 0100 hours.
"Princess 299 is still
rejecting all attempts
at transformation.
"and Princess 107
is in need of our
services."
Rosalinda: What about me?
Where are you sending me?
Nowhere yet.
First you must go
through stage three,
transformation.
First, we start
with the hair and
then the wardrobe,
Until you are
unrecognizable
as princesses.
(greeting in
foreign language)
No! Stop!
I do not know
any of you people.
I want to speak
with major Mason.
I only trust major Mason.
Is everything
all right?
Take me back
to my country.
Princess, I'm sorry, but
general Kane has taken
control of your country
And assumed command
of its government.
But I must go back.
And you will.
As soon as we find
a legal way to
remove him.
In the meantime,
you have to let
us protect you.
But what about
my mother? Who's
protecting my mother?
You are.
As long as you're in
Princess Protection,
Your mom will
be safe. Please.
General Kane is hoping
you'll contact her
So he'll know
where to find you.
What if he does
find me?
He'll make an example
of you by sending
you to prison
Or a work farm.
And Costa Luna will
become part of his
own personal kingdom,
With its true royal family
nothing but a memory.
Bottom line,
If you care about
your country, and
your mom's safety,
Nobody can know
who you really are.
You may proceed.
Director: Good work.
From now on, you are
no longer Princess.
You are now Rosie Gonzalez,
an average American girl.
What happens now?
Stage four.
Relocation.
Where?
Somewhere where
general Kane
will never think
Of looking for
the Princess
of Costa Luna.
Joe: Welcome to
Louisiana, Rosie.
(car door slams)
(gasps)
Joe: Over here.
Welcome to your new home.
For a while, at least.
Here, let me
get the door.
(all chattering)
Here you go, sweetie.
Thanks, Helen.
Hey, looks like
someone's back
home again.
Carter: See you tomorrow!
Dad?
Hello.
Hey.
Who are you?
Rosa... Rosie.
Are you sure? 'cause
you don't seem sure.
Rosie. I'm sure.
Okay. So, what are
you doing here?
Oh, major Mason
gave me this room.
He did, huh?
Yes, he's been
very lovely.
Lovely?
Of course, the suite
is much smaller than
I'm used to,
But it will feel much
larger once I have
that extra bed removed.
It's not extra,
it's mine.
Will you excuse
me for a second?
Yes. You are excused.
(door slams)
Joe: Hey, pal!
(scoffing) don't "pal" me.
You... You met Rosie?
Yeah. Who is she
and why is she
in my room?
Well, I had to bring
her here. The director
didn't give me a choice.
Okay. Just, you know,
a normal dad
Would go to
a foreign country
on a secret mission
And bring his daughter back
a T-shirt, not a person.
You should have
warned me.
Carter, I didn't have
a choice. She doesn't
trust anybody but me.
Yeah, I know the feeling.
Hey, what I do
is complicated.
But if I
thought for one second
it would hurt our family...
Dad, I get it.
So, you're in?
Do I have a choice?
Good, 'cause I'm gonna
need your help.
She needs to stay here
for a while, undetected.
And in order for
that to happen,
She has to blend in
as a normal American
teenager.
Yeah, no, that's not
gonna happen, dad.
She's a Princess.
Fine. Who do
I say she is?
Your cousin.
(scoffs)
Carter, thank you.
Now, if we do our
job right,
She'll be out of here
and back to her own
country in no time.
Okay, so by Tuesday?
It'll be soon.
I promise.
Still you and me,
pal?
No.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
(giggling) no. No. No.
Is that right?
You're gonna go...
No!
...In the water if
you don't say yes.
Put me down.
All right.
You give me
a headache.
Be nice.
Mmm-hmm.
(door opens)
You have made
other sleeping
arrangements?
Look, the room is not
yours. It's ours.
We share it.
Share?
Share.
I know that's probably
a foreign concept
for a Princess,
But what it
means is that you get
one side of the room
And I get the other.
So stay on your side.
(slams)
Carter: I don't want that.
Joe: That's good.
So I thought princesses
had designer clothes
and stuff.
Well, she had to
leave all that behind.
But I was thinking
you could, you know,
loan her some of your stuff.
(scoffs)
Yeah, sure. Why not?
Thank you.
Now, go try again.
I will after this hand.
No, now.
And don't look
at my cards.
(sighs)
(door opens)
All right, the kitchen's
closing. Last Chance
to eat something.
No, thank you.
I wish to sleep.
Okay.
You may help me
prepare for bed.
I "may"?
Yes.
I need a nightgown.
Preferably silk,
preferably pink.
Pink silk. Let me
see what I've got.
Here.
(speaking in Spanish)
Huh?
May I use your restroom?
Yeah, upstairs,
first door on the right.
(thanking in Spanish)
Okay, whatever.
(sighs)
(screams)
What happened?
Come on!
Do they not have
lizards where
you're from?
Maybe, but I never
see them. That is
why we have Henry.
You have a royal
reptile wrangler?
Yes. And you should
get one, too.
Good night.
She's gonna be okay.
No. She's gonna
be a royal pain.
(door opening)
Good morning.
Hey.
Joe: Hey.
Juice?
Yeah.
All right.
There you go.
Coffee done?
Good.
Don't be shy, Rosie.
Grab whatever looks good.
(car horn honking)
Bus is here.
Sure you don't
want a ride?
Yeah, I'll be fine.
You coming?
Where are we going?
School. You're 16.
You go to school.
School. Of course.
Goodbye.
Morning, honey.
Hey, Helen.
Helen: Whoa!
Who's this, now?
That's just my cousin.
You don't say.
Hello.
Well, aren't you a cutie?
I am Rosie.
And I am late.
Go ahead and grab
a seat, quick as you can.
(kids chattering)
(engine revving)
(machinery beeping)
Automated voice:
Call attempted.
Scrambling signal now.
Ppp link established.
This is the director.
What is your situation
report?
Princess 379 is in position.
Stage four is complete.
She's safe, then?
That's affirmative,
absolutely safe.
¶ the girl can't help it
¶ the girl can't help it ¶
Ed: (in British accent)
could this be the Queen?
Obviously not, ed.
Maybe this is the Queen.
Well, technically, no.
Not yet, anyway.
Nice. Honest.
I like it.
I'm ed, by the way.
And you're...
Rosie.
I'm making a documentary.
Listen, "the Rocky path
from humble peasant
"to homecoming Queen."
The Queen of homecoming?
What is this homecoming?
You don't...
You've never heard
of homecoming?
No. We have
no such thing
where I am from.
Really? Where's that?
Oh, um... That's
from iowa. She's...
What are you doing?
I'm going to school.
Bye, guys.
Yes, and you're
supposed to act like
a normal American girl.
You're supposed
to blend in.
I'm trying.
Well, try harder.
There she is,
Princess Carter.
Sit down.
Ed: Bossy, bossy.
Sit.
I like bossy.
Excuse me,
may I have
this seat?
I'm sorry,
I think it's
school property.
(all laughing)
(both exclaiming)
Yeah, sure.
Rosalinda:
Thank you very much.
What? She's hot.
(bell rings)
(greeting in French)
(class greeting in French)
(speaking French)
(exclaims)
This must be our new student,
Carter Mason's cousin.
(speaking French)
Where are you,
my little princesa?
Ah!
Sophia. Thank you
for joining me.
Any news
from Rosalinda?
No. And there
will never be.
Now, now, now, now.
We must not be
so negative.
Perhaps... Perhaps
we should think happy
thoughts. Shall I begin?
I am picturing
a dashing young general.
(laughs)
And he is...
He's sitting
on a throne.
Royal subjects shower him
with adoration.
And what do you know?
They have crowned
him their king!
(Kane laughing)
You will never be
the king of Costa Luna,
not as long as I'm alive.
You are ruining
my happy thoughts.
Take her away.
¶ what you see is what you get
when you're looking at me
¶ I'm gonna tell it like it is
most definitely
¶ I can tell by the way
you look me in the eyes
¶ that you're not like
the other guys ¶
Girl: Hey, no cutting!
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Hey!
Back of the line.
Pardon?
That's the rules.
No cuts.
Of course.
Then I will not cuts.
Hey, Rosie,
come on up with me.
(woman speaking Spanish)
(speaking Spanish)
Well? You gotta
pick something.
Oh!
(speaking Spanish)
Mystery meat.
Then I will have
one of those.
What is it?
A hamburger?
(thanking in Spanish)
Next.
¶ am I missing something here?
¶ got to say the signs
are clear as mud
True confession.
Are you gonna eat
that nasty food?
¶ when I laugh
I taste the tears
¶ sometimes I wish
I'd just disappear
¶ I'm so confused,
misunderstood
¶ I can't be free
¶ is it just me
who feels this way?
¶ trying to be where I am
so out of place
¶ can't I just wait
to see what's right?
¶ 'cause it looks like
we're all just flying blind ¶
Check her out.
Who does she
think she is?
I know. She thinks
she's Carter's cousin.
Ow!
Oh, was that your leg?
I'm sorry.
She may be a loser
like her cousin,
but she's dangerous.
Really? Why?
Are you serious?
Look at her.
I know.
Totally love the hair.
(kicking)
Ow!
What are you doing?
Eating a hamburger.
Have you ever
tried one?
Yes. And FYI,
they have hamburgers
in iowa.
Oh!
Right.
You're supposed
to be blending in.
I am blending.
Speaking fluent
French in class?
And eating hamburger
like you're having
tea with the Queen?
Well, how else
should it be eaten?
Like this.
The works.
There you go.
Mmm-hmm.
Stop.
Now.
Like this?
It's perfect.
Can I have your
attention, please? I have
an announcement to make.
Can we sit down
and settle down,
please?
On Monday, we'll be
taking nominations
For the homecoming court.
(girls cheering)
These nominees must be girls
of exemplary character.
Kind, intelligent, honest,
charitable members
Of the lake Monroe community.
Now, the three girls
with the most votes
Will become your
homecoming princesses.
(all cheering)
There's more, there's more.
On Friday night,
at our annual dance,
One of these lucky girls
will be crowned
Your homecoming Queen
of lake Monroe high.
Boy: Yeah!
Burkle: Thank you.
You vote for
royalty here?
We're a democracy.
We're into voting.
So then, anyone
can be a Princess?
Even you?
Theoretically.
Excuse me, everyone.
May I have your
attention?
What are you doing?
Sit down!
No, no.
I would like to
nominate my cousin,
Carter Mason,
to be your Queen.
I think that she would
make an excellent ruler.
(sparse laughter)
Boy 1: (whoops) Carter?
Boy 2: Yeah, right.
Carter. Carter!
Girl: Carter?
That's hilarious.
Was that for real?
Wow!
Ed: Oh, man.
Looks like
I'm the Queen.
Rosalinda: Carter!
Carter!
Leave me alone.
I order you to stop.
You order me?
You order me.
I order you to
take a long walk
off a short pier.
You cannot order
me to do anything.
Wanna bet?
You're in my
kingdom now.
Okay, hey, hey, hey.
Whoa, whoa.
Whoa,
what's going on?
Dad, she can't do it.
She can't act normal.
I am normal.
Really? Okay.
So, a normal person
who has never seen
a hamburger before
Can order one
in six languages?
Really? You did that?
I always speak to
my staff in their
native tongue.
They're not your staff.
They're lunch ladies,
okay?
Dad, can't you see
that this isn't
gonna work?
Carter, it's gonna
work, okay?
We just have
to give it a
little time.
(grunts)
It'll work.
(crying)
Man on radio:
It's gonna be
a scorcher again today...
Hey, ernie.
Hi, Carter.
Hello.
Oh, great.
Good morning, Carter.
What are you doing?
Chores.
Chores?
I do not understand.
No, of course not.
Perhaps I could
learn this "chores."
you could teach me.
You know,
that's the best
idea you've had.
What must I do?
We'll start you off
easy. Inventory.
Inventory?
Counting.
You count what's in here,
and put it in here.
Have fun.
Oh! And when you're done,
there's a whole other
shelf, too.
One.
Everything okay?
Yeah. Just peachy.
You got the bow?
Uh-huh.
Stay above that line.
What line?
Right there.
Okay.
(clattering)
Carter, what's
Rosie doing in
the bait shop?
Chores.
(Rosalinda screams)
Dad.
Joe: Rosie!
Carter: Are you okay?
I'm all right.
I think I need to bathe.
Carter, why don't you
go on in and clean
this up, okay?
Why me? She's the
one who did it.
Come on, pal.
I'll help you.
All right, it...
It's not funny.
(giggling) yes. Come on.
You know it's
a little funny.
All right. Here. Go.
You wanna laugh, too.
No, I don't wanna laugh.
Yes, you do.
This is serious.
Come on.
What do you want
for dinner tonight?
Pizza.
Pizza? We had
pizza last night.
How about...
How about burgers?
How about this?
Pizza and burgers.
Yeah. I wanna do both.
One as an appetizer,
or just together?
I don't know.
I didn't know we still
had all that stuff.
What's all this?
A proper dinner.
To thank you for
helping me clean
up the mess
That I made in
your shop of bugs.
It's bait.
I'm aware.
Okay.
Here. Let me.
No, no.
Thank you, but tonight,
I serve you.
Well, I'm not gonna
say no to that.
It is for you.
For me?
Mmm-hmm.
To wear. Okay. Fine.
(snickers)
Come on, Carter.
So, you cook?
I thought you had
servants for that.
Actually, my mother
grew up a peasant.
(mouthing)
So she taught me
many family recipes.
(speaking Spanish)
Wow!
Yeah, that sounds
kind of fancy.
Why don't we just
order pizza?
No, it's chicken
and rice.
Fantastic.
Bring it on, Rosie.
(chuckles)
You know, I haven't had
a real home-cooked
meal since...
Forever.
Right.
Let's dig in!
How do you like it?
That...
That is really, really
good. Gee, I had no
idea you can cook.
Rosalinda: Thank you.
This is terrific.
You're wonderful.
Thank you. Would
you like a roll?
You made rolls, too?
Rosalinda: Yes.
I had no idea.
Yes.
Wow!
Must be nice to play
peasant for a day.
Would you excuse me?
You do not know me,
Carter.
What's the big deal?
You'll be back
with your servants
And your personal chef
and private tutors
soon enough.
How much did your
father tell you
about me?
Other than the obvious,
I think we're on
a need-to-know basis.
I think you need to know
that my name is Rosalinda
Marie Montoya Fiore,
And I am
a royal Princess.
(scoffs) no kidding.
I am from
a small island nation
called Costa Luna.
Never heard of it.
It is not on most maps.
It is very small,
very unimportant
to large countries,
But very important to me.
When my father died,
he left Costa Luna to me.
You don't have
to tell me...
One month
before my coronation,
our palace was attacked.
Your father
was very brave.
He risked his life
for you, I know.
That's his job.
He rescues poor,
oppressed princesses.
Did he tell you
we had to leave
my mother behind?
The man who invaded
Costa Luna now holds
her as a hostage.
I didn't know.
They told me my becoming
Rosie Gonzalez
Was the only way
to keep her safe.
Stop. It's okay.
Carter, whatever I did
to make you dislike me,
I am truly sorry.
I will try to blend in.
I will try to be from iowa.
It is the only way to
save my mother's life.
Let's just start over.
I would like that.
But you need
to lighten up on
this Princess stuff.
It's really annoying.
Absolutely. Please, I only
want to be this typical
American teenager.
You know what?
I think we can
arrange that.
I love this place!
What is it?
It's a bowling alley.
That's bowling.
Just do what I do
And don't draw
any attention to
yourself, please.
Right.
Thank you.
Sure.
Carter! How you doing?
Hi, ed.
Ed: Hi. How you
doing, Rosie?
I'm well, thank you.
What'll it be?
Bowling, please.
(chuckles) no kidding.
Five-and-a-half
coming up.
Thank you.
Sure.
What size?
Excuse me?
Your feet. What size?
(stammering)
I do not know.
All of my shoes
are made for me.
There's a shock.
Just get her
some shoes.
Okay.
Your highness.
Rosalinda:
Why, thank you, Edward.
It's Edwin, actually.
Edwin. That is
a wonderful name.
Thank you.
It's been a pleasure
serving you, milady.
All right.
Thank you, Romeo.
Okay.
You're not blending in.
Pick a ball.
Did you see that?
Yeah. Nobody ever
does that for us.
They do now.
(Chelsea clears throat)
Your shoe's untied.
Don't trip.
Oh!
Careful there.
Donny, you don't have
to carry that for her.
She can do it herself
like a normal person.
So I'll just
take this.
Whatever you say...
Carter.
Right.
So, donny is
your boyfriend?
What? No, no.
He's just a friend.
Rosalinda:
But he is very
special to you.
I see the way
you look at him.
It's the same way
that ed looks at you.
Okay, you're
obviously not from here,
so just bowl. You first.
How do I win?
You win by
knocking down
those white pins.
Okay, I'm ready.
What?
You may fire
at the target.
You may fire it
yourself.
(pins clattering)
Impossible.
Nice shot, Rosie!
You done already,
Carter?
Yeah. Our Lane's
getting a little
crowded.
You don't really
like your cousin,
do you?
No, it's... It's just...
She can be sometimes,
you know, a...
Princess.
She could win it all.
She is getting
really popular.
The vote is
on Monday.
We can't let her
get more popular
than we are.
There's only one
thing to do in a
situation like this.
Excuse me! Excuse me! Roe!
Excuse me! Excuse me! Roe.
You are such
a natural.
Will you show us
how to bowl
like that?
Of course.
But my name is Rosie.
Oh! Roe's our
nickname we
gave you.
We give all of our
friends nicknames.
She's chels.
And she's brookie
and you're roe.
You're one of us now.
Rosalinda: Carter?
Carter: What?
Why do you care so much
for this boy donny?
Who says I care
for him?
Fine. I've been totally
in love with him since,
like, the third grade,
When he kissed me under
the basketball hoop.
Is that what
you want to hear?
He is quite beautiful.
Much like a prince.
I wonder if
he is beautiful on
the inside as well.
Shall we bowl
again tomorrow?
I can't. I'm working
at the bait shack.
I've never worked before.
Is this normal?
Yes. Lots of kids
have jobs.
Then I will help you.
You can't.
Why not?
Because it's mine.
You can't have
everything that's mine!
Well, just...
Want a job so bad?
Just go get one yourself.
All right.
Good night, Carter.
Thank you for
giving me this
job, Chelsea.
No prob, roe. Daddy owns,
like, 17 udderlys
all over the south.
He's the king.
Your father is a king?
Of frozen yogurt.
One more thing.
You have to wear this.
(tinkling)
So these are the
frozen yogurt
machines.
You just pull the lever
and when it comes out
You just put a little
swirly on top and
you're good to go, okay?
Swirly?
This is gonna be great.
And all your friends
will be here to
support you.
We all want you
to succeed at
your first job.
Thank you so much.
Uh-huh.
(both laugh nastily)
Ed!
Ed: Here she is, folks,
A future homecoming Princess
of lake Monroe, Louisiana.
Who is this natural
beauty, you ask?
Will you go away?
I'm working.
This is Carter Mason.
Secret identity?
Bait girl.
So confident of
her innate royalty,
She is completely
unafraid to handle
Whatever
disgusting creature...
Hey!
Isn't that... Not on
my camera, please.
Then turn it off.
No.
Today's my last day
to get the "before"
footage.
The Princess vote
is tomorrow.
Well, then go shoot
Chelsea or Brooke.
Nah. I've got tons
of them already.
They pay me
to film them.
Is that why
you're doing this?
'cause of the money?
Absolutely.
I'm the only senior
guy in lake Monroe
who doesn't have a car.
Figures.
You really hate
this whole Princess
thing, don't you?
I don't hate it exactly.
I just think it's shallow.
Girls like Chelsea
and Brooke, all they
care about is shoes.
Like wearing
the right clothes
makes them superior.
I just want to
do something more
important with my life,
Like my dad.
Yeah, yeah, he does
sell some sick bait.
Right.
So, speaking
of princesses,
where's Rosie?
How should I know?
(cell phone ringing)
I think I just found her.
Girl 1: Hey, I've been
waiting here for, like,
10 minutes.
Boy 1: I haven't
got all day!
Rosalinda: Just a second.
(people grumbling)
Hold on.
Oh, no!
Girl 2:
It's not brain science!
Boy 2: Come on,
what are they
paying you for?
Girl 2: I've been
waiting for,
like, ever!
Come on, chels.
She's dying in
there. Help her out.
You're absolutely right.
Brookie, we should
go in there.
Oh, chels. If only
our pedicures were dry.
Fine.
Bull, will you do me
a huge favor?
Yeah. Yeah.
(whispering)
(softly)
wait. How do I know
it's the right one?
It's big. It's red.
Can't miss it.
Boy 3: I can't believe it.
This is ridiculous!
Boy 4: I want
my yogurt, okay?
Girl 3: You need
some help, or what?
Boy 4: Hello?
Girl 3: I have to go!
(machinery powering up)
(gasping)
Oh, no!
(people squealing)
(screams)
(people laughing)
What are you doing?
Are you okay?
Come here, Rosie.
You said to get a job.
Not this one!
This job's for losers.
Trust me, I've had
this job. The bait
shop is a step up.
(people chattering)
Hey, check it out.
What is happening?
Carter: Chelsea set you up.
She invited all those people
to come watch you make
a fool of yourself.
Carter, it's okay.
I am not a fool.
And she cannot make
something out of me
that I am not.
Rosie, we have
to do something.
I will turn the other
cheek, because that
is what princesses do.
Your father,
the king of yogurts,
Would be very
disappointed in you.
(all gasping)
Yeah, well,
I'm not a Princess.
(exclaiming in disgust)
(all laughing)
She can't be a Princess!
Don't freak,
but she kind of can.
I've just been texted,
like, 10 times.
Everybody thinks
she's pretty cool.
Tomorrow,
when the whole school
votes for three princesses,
She could be
one of them.
And if she gets
enough votes...
Don't say it.
...She could
become Queen.
No, I'm the Queen!
It's my Destiny!
(all murmuring)
That's kind
of iffy now.
I'd rather eat
carbs than see her
wearing my crown.
We have to stop her.
How?
If she never becomes
a Princess, she can't
be the Queen, right?
I'm not sure where
you're going here.
Grab your cell.
We've got a whole
lot of texting to do.
So, it's a skill that
most Americans master
in, like, the third grade,
But it's never
too late to learn.
I am ready to try.
Good luck.
(burps)
(laughs)
Nice.
Okay, next we'll
work on slouching,
Eye-rolling and
talking back
to my dad.
If Mr. Elegante
could see me right now,
he would be so mad at me.
Who's Mr. Elegante?
My royal dress designer.
You're kidding,
right?
No. He is a close
family friend.
If there were
ever an emergency,
He would be the first
I would call.
Must be nice
to be a Queen.
Actually, it's not
all about the dresses
and crowns, Carter.
My mother told me
that my father never
called himself king.
To our people,
he was father,
brother and friend.
I hope to be like him
when I am Queen
of Costa Luna.
Father, brother...
(laughing) no!
I want to make
a difference.
To do something
more important
with your life?
Yes.
You know, you're different
than I thought a Princess
would be.
I hope that is
a good thing.
Yeah, it is.
Thank you for
helping me today.
A Princess is never sure
who her true friend is.
Today, I am sure.
Me, too.
(burping loudly)
I'll give myself
this one and this one,
For bravery and honor.
A thief has no honor.
Sophia! Come in,
come in, come in.
We have a great
deal to discuss.
Do you think
it's too much?
I want to look my
best when I announce
my engagement today.
Who could be so
unfortunate as to
become your bride?
Well, as a matter
of fact,
She is standing
right here in
this room.
(laughing)
That's ridiculous.
I will never marry you.
Ever.
(laughing)
of course you won't.
But Rosalinda
will not know this.
She will see
the announcement,
Assume you are doing
it to protect her,
And come racing back
to her mother's side
Just in time to
join you in exile.
The people of Costa Luna
will never accept that.
The same was said for
the people of Costa
Estrella 20 years ago,
And look what happened.
Hmm.
Take her back
to her cell.
Oh, and bring me
my hair and
makeup team.
We must touch up this gray
before I go on camera.
Yeah.
(shouts in pain)
Sorry.
Carter: Wait, where's
everyone going?
Burkle:
Good morning, students.
The votes for your
three homecoming...
Rosalinda:
We must hurry, Carter.
Carter: Okay, you're
way too into this
Princess thing.
Burkle: Now, I'd like to
announce the winners.
And your princesses
are Chelsea Barnes!
(all cheering)
Thank you! Thank you!
Carter Mason!
(all cheering)
"Carter Mason."
And your third and
final Princess is
Rosie Gonzalez!
(all cheering)
Thank you. Thank you.
What happened?
I don't know!
We texted everyone
in the school.
They were supposed
to vote for Carter
instead of Rosie,
Not Carter and Rosie.
This is all your fault.
How is it my fault?
If you were more popular,
you'd be the Princess,
not her.
I am popular!
This is not good, okay?
Me being a Princess
is not normal.
Hey, there.
Hey, Rosie,
can I talk to you?
Me?
Her?
Yeah.
So, you know there's
the homecoming dance
and everything, and...
Will you go
to the dance
with me, Rosie?
Me?
Her?
Yeah. I want you to be
my date for the dance.
Donny, that is very
kind of you, but no.
Will you excuse me?
Uh...
Sure.
That was the most
humiliating thing that
has ever happened to me.
And I've been
humiliated a lot.
What was I thinking?
A guy like donny would
never go out with me.
Then he is not
worthy of you.
Yeah, you can say
that 'cause you're
all high and royal.
But I'm just
a girl who sells bait.
No.
You are so much more.
You are a Princess now.
Yeah. Trust me,
I am not a Princess.
Yes, you are.
You just do not
feel like one yet.
When I came here,
you taught me how to
act normal, not royal.
Now it is my turn
to teach you.
You think that
being a Princess
is superficial.
Yeah, I guess.
That it is about
what you wear,
and how you look.
Well, it is a little bit
about how you look.
But more importantly,
It is about what you
have to offer the world
and who you are inside.
Come on, Carter.
Let's go find
your inner Princess.
(one and the same playing)
¶ you come from here
I come from there
¶ you rock out in your room
I'd like a world premiere
¶ we're more alike than
anybody could ever tell
¶ ever tell
¶ Friday we're cool
Monday we're freaks
¶ sometimes we rule
sometimes we can't even speak
¶ but we kick it up
let loose and lol
¶ lol
¶ it may seem cliched
for me to want to say
that you're not alone
¶ not alone
¶ and you can call me uncool
but it's a simple fact
I got your back
¶ yeah, yeah, yeah
¶ 'cause we're one
and the same
¶ we're anything but ordinary
¶ one and the same
¶ I think we're
almost legendary
¶ you and me, the perfect team
¶ chasing down the dream
¶ we're one and the same
(inaudible)
¶ one and the same
¶ we're anything but ordinary
¶ I think we're
almost legendary
¶ you and me, the perfect team
¶ shaking up the scene
¶ we're one and the same ¶
You're just so good
with everybody.
Kids, old people,
you're probably
even good with dogs.
That is true.
You're so much
more generous than
I thought you'd be.
It is a Princess's
job to help people.
I guess I never
really thought about
What it really means
to be a Princess.
(both giggling)
Like this.
I can't believe
you actually have
to do this.
Oh, no, you don't.
Wait, then,
why am I doing it?
(laughing)
because it is funny.
What? I hate you!
You do?
No, no, no. No.
No, I didn't mean it that way.
I didn't mean "I hate you"
I hate you.
I meant "I hate you," like,
you're my best friend.
Oh!
Well, then,
I hate you, too.
And that dress is ugly.
It is?
No!
It is beautiful.
And so are you.
Look.
You're becoming
a Princess on
the inside.
And now you look
like one, too.
Excuse me, I have this
lame reading assignment
for Spanish class.
Do you think that
you have something
that's really easy
With lots of pictures?
Oh! Cool.
"Princess Rosalinda"?
No way!
(cell phone ringing)
It's Mason. What's going on?
Director: General Kane's
announcement of
his engagement
To dona Sophia montoya
Has popped up in several
tabloid magazines.
The story is contained so far,
But I would be lying to say
I was not concerned.
She'd never agree
to marry him.
I was not suggesting
she would, major.
General Kane's doing this
to draw Rosalinda out.
He knows she won't
allow her mother to
be forced into marriage.
Absolutely.
So, it is imperative
that we keep this
from Rosalinda.
Yes, ma'am. I agree.
Major, has she made
any enemies?
Anyone who might want
to expose her identity?
Not that I know of.
Let's move that
throne here.
No. No, actually,
there.
Oh, I know.
Up there.
And let's hang some
lights directly on it.
That might be too harsh
on my skin tone.
We should hire
a lighting designer.
The budget's gone,
Chelsea. What you
see is what you get.
Okay, okay. I know!
A follow-spot
just on me.
Maybe light pink,
or golden like the sun.
It's great to be Queen.
You're not Queen yet.
Carter could win,
Or Rosie.
Can it, Muffy.
My name's Margaret.
Not anymore.
Hey, chels.
Don't call me that.
You lost that right when
you lost your Princess
crown to bait girl
And her strangely
formal cousin.
Well, what if we
could get Rosie
To drop out
of homecoming
altogether?
She would never do that.
She might.
She's not who
she says she is.
She's princesa Rosalinda.
Chelsea: It's in Spanish.
What does the article say?
I'm not sure.
What? I'm pretty,
not smart.
Okay, let me try.
It's about Rosie
and her mom.
One of them has
fled the country and
one of them is in prison
Or a paper bag.
I get those
two mixed up.
No biggie.
Good work, brookie.
Thanks, chels.
Chelsea:
I have the perfect plan.
Joe: Hey, girls.
Hi, Mr. Mason.
Is Rosie home?
Maybe. What's up?
Up?
Well, we're planning
a little Princess
surprise for Carter.
To congratulate her.
Yeah. It was
Rosie's idea.
She's in her room.
Go on in.
(chuckles)
(speaking Spanish)
I've never heard
of Costa Luna.
Have you, brookie?
No, chels.
I do not know
what you are
talking about.
We know all about
you and your mother.
And the paper bag.
What?
Poor Princess Rosalinda.
Did you hear
she's in hiding?
You do not understand.
I understand that
you lied to us.
Only to protect
my mother.
From the paper bag?
No.
Look, I will give
you a reward for
keeping my secret.
We know you will.
You do?
And we already
have it picked out.
I don't understand.
Yeah, me either.
You're gonna turn in
your crown, Princess.
You're going to tell
everyone that there is,
and only will be,
One true homecoming Queen,
and that's me.
That's good.
Fine.
You may take my crown,
But you will not
take Carter's.
She's no threat
to you, Chelsea.
Fine.
Let bait girl
play Princess
for one night.
She just won't
look like one.
(honks)
(Chelsea laughing)
Chelsea:
Have fun at the dance!
(both laughing)
(car horn honking)
Look at what
Chelsea and Brooke...
What's wrong?
I have to leave, Carter.
Leave? Leave where?
Back to my country.
(sighs)
General Kane is
forcing my mother
into marriage.
Father's never gonna
let you go back.
He'll never know.
Yeah, but I know.
And I'm not gonna
let you go back, either.
Carter, you have to
stay out of this.
I have a duty
to my people.
And this is something
that you'll never
understand.
I've loved living
here in Louisiana.
And I wish my life
could be like this
every day.
But this is not reality.
I mean, you think
my life as a Princess
is some fairy tale?
This here is a fairy tale!
And I cannot
hide here anymore.
Soon I will be
Queen of Costa Luna.
My country needs me.
You're right.
They do need you.
They need you
to lead them,
and to protect them.
And that's something
you can't do from jail,
Which is exactly where
you'll end up if you
go back to Costa Luna.
No way am I
letting this happen.
(cell phone ringing)
Hola, this is elegante.
Who is this?
That's not important.
All that matters
is I'm a friend of
Princess Rosalinda,
And she's about to make
a very big mistake.
My princesa?
What mistake is this?
Carter:
She wants to come home.
No, no, no, no, no,
she must not.
(speaking Spanish)
It's too dangerous.
I know.
But I have a plan.
And I'm gonna need you
to listen very carefully.
I will do anything
for the princesa.
Anything.
Okay, to start with,
I'm gonna need two
dresses.
You okay?
I'm going to miss
this place.
I'm going to miss you,
Carter.
I can't believe
I'm saying this,
But I'm going to
miss you, too.
Rosie, can you
do me a big favor
before you go?
Anything.
You said it is
a Princess' job
to help others.
It is.
Well, the dance
is on Friday night,
And there's some people
that I want to help.
I want to make this night
special for them,
for all of us.
Will you please
stay until then?
For them, please.
(inaudible)
Margaret: That's it,
keep your chin up.
Joe: What in the...
Margaret: Okay, stay there,
that's perfect. Very good.
Morning, dad.
Morning. What the...
What are you
girls up to?
Just having some friends
over from school.
Is that okay?
Yeah, yeah. It's fine.
What's in the box?
Homecoming stuff.
No biggie.
Hmm.
Kane: And you are sure about
this homecoming dance,
senor elegante?
Absolutely.
I feel, in one way,
I'm betraying my Queen,
But I thought
you should know,
general.
It's for the good
of Costa Luna.
You did the right thing
by coming to me, senor.
Fuel the jet!
Tell the pilot
we will be flying
to Louisiana.
(speaking Spanish)
(laughing)
A lovely color.
Lovely indeed.
Caribbean blue, general.
To complement
Princess Rosalinda's
skin tone.
Well, back to work.
You have a dress
to finish.
Two, actually.
Where did you get them?
Well, you said
to call Mr. Elegante
if I had an emergency.
And I think
that this is
a fashion emergency.
Carter, you are brilliant.
This one is yours.
He says you look
best in pink.
And this one is mine.
It's caribbean blue.
(Rosalinda chuckles)
Thank you, Carter.
This is a night
I'll always remember.
I hope so.
Are you guys ready?
'cause it's getting
kind of late.
Helen: Come on in, girls.
Helen's house of beauty
is open for business.
(all chattering)
Okay.
Oh, this is a great
color on you.
How do I look, dad?
I think we have
a problem.
I may have to stop
calling you "pal."
(cell phone ringing)
All right, I gotta
grab this. You girls
gonna be okay?
Yeah, we'll be fine.
Go ahead.
You sure?
Of course.
We're not kids.
All right. Well,
have a good time.
And be careful.
Helen: Mason.
Helen.
All right,
your highnesses.
Time's a-wasting.
The dance starts
in 10 minutes.
Masks? No one said
anything about masks.
(grunts)
Come on!
(car lock chirps)
Hey! Hey!
I'm stuck!
Open the door,
donny. Hello?
Donny. Donny!
(car lock chirps)
(screams)
(whimpering)
(Chelsea sputtering)
Ed: Come here,
come here.
(whimpering)
You okay?
(exclaims) get off!
(grunts)
(hip-hop music playing)
Okay, freshman,
I think I can
take it from here.
No.
Carter,
what's the problem?
I thought we had,
you know, something.
Actually, we don't.
Okay, what's up?
Isn't this what you've
been waiting for since,
like, third grade?
Before I put on this dress,
you couldn't even
remember my name.
I might be a Princess
tonight, but I'll
always be bait girl.
And I'm proud of that.
Carter, you're making
a big mistake.
No, donny.
I don't think I am.
(sighs contentedly)
You deserve better
than him, Carter.
I know.
Too bad it took this
long to realize it.
Guys!
(grunting)
What happened to you?
Shut up and fix me.
Did you get me a crown?
Who cares?
In a few minutes,
it won't matter anyways.
I'll be named Queen
and this will
all be over.
I thought we were
in this together.
We are. Lip gloss.
No.
What?
I said no.
You can't use my
lip gloss anymore.
But I have to look pretty.
I'm a Princess.
Yeah, a terrible one.
A Princess is supposed
to be a girl of
exemplary character,
A role model. But you,
You're not even kind,
honest or charitable
in any way.
You're not even nice.
I don't think
I want to be your
friend anymore.
Brookie...
Don't call me that.
Carter, Rosie,
I just wanted to
thank you for tonight.
I never thought I
could look beautiful.
Or feel beautiful,
for that matter.
Margaret,
you are beautiful.
(speaking Spanish)
And thanks for not
calling me Muffy.
No problem.
(hip-hop song playing)
I love this song!
Let's go dance!
Well, why don't
you two go ahead?
Be princesses.
Okay!
There you are!
Finally!
You don't understand,
miss.
I'm the...
Security. I know.
You're late.
And what is with
the uniforms?
No one's wearing
berets this year.
Just stay out here
and make sure no one
gets in that dance,
Unless they're students
from lake Monroe. Got it?
Got it.
Enjoy your evening.
Okay, everybody,
he's about to announce
the winner.
Let's put on our masks.
(exclaims in exasperation)
Kane: Princesses everywhere.
(sighs)
Caribbean blue.
Beautiful indeed.
Come with me now,
princesa, and no harm
will come to your friends.
Can I have
your attention, please?
I hold here in my hand
The name of our 2008
lake Monroe homecoming Queen.
And the winner is
Princess Rosie Gonzalez.
(cheering)
Rosie, are you out there?
(whistling)
(applause)
Thank you.
Since I've been here,
I've learned many
wonderful things.
Most importantly,
I've learned about friendship
and loyalty and trust.
And that those are not
things that are just given,
But things we must earn.
So I want to thank
Carter Mason
For teaching me these things.
And for being my friend.
Carter, where are you?
(music playing)
That was so beautiful,
Rosie.
Thank you. But I
need to find Carter.
Hold it right there,
Princess.
My crown.
Hand it over.
Chelsea, please...
You're not going
anywhere
Until I get
that crown.
No!
(screams)
Sorry.
I am so getting
you back for this!
Rosalinda: General Kane!
Well, it appears as
if everyone wants
to be a Princess.
Unfortunately,
it is time for the
masquerade to end.
What are you doing?
The plan was working
perfectly.
This was a very brave plan.
But this is my fight,
not yours.
You don't have
to go with them.
Enough!
As the princesa
so eloquently
pointed out,
This is not your fight.
General Kane.
Good to see you again.
Kane: What is the
meaning of this?
You are interfering
with official business
Of the sovereign
land of Costa Luna.
Maybe this will
fly in your country,
But, here,
it's called kidnapping.
We're turning you over
to the international
authorities.
Get him.
No, let me.
I'm going to enjoy this.
(chuckles)
How does it feel to
be brought to Justice
By a 16-year-old girl,
general?
Not so hot.
(sobbing)
I can't believe you
would do this for me.
That's what princesses do.
They do it for each other.
And you are truly
a Princess now,
Carter Mason.
You rightfully
deserve this.
Hold it! Nobody moves!
Nobody goes anywhere.
I'll take that.
Let her go.
She needs it way
more than I do.
All right. Come on.
Hey, guard.
(grumbling)
You got him?
Oh, I'm in so
much trouble.
(sighs)
What were you thinking,
Carter?
I was thinking
I'd be perfect bait.
Get it? I'm bait girl.
Why didn't you
just come to me?
Dad, you would have
never let me do it.
You're lucky I was here.
I knew you would be.
You're always
there for me.
You rescue princesses.
That's what you do.
You and me, pal.
You and me, dad.
Archbishop: I present to you
Queen Rosalinda Marie
Montoya Fiore
Of Costa Luna!
Long live Queen Rosie!
(shouting in Spanish)
(all shouting in Spanish)
(two worlds collide playing)
¶ you had your dreams,
I had mine
¶ you had your fears,
I was fine
¶ you showed me
what I couldn't find
¶ when two different
worlds collide
worlds collide ¶
Ladies, you're here.
Excellent.
Are you ready
for your next
assignment?
I am.
Me, too.
But can we go somewhere
a little bit warmer?
My feet are still
frozen from that
walk through Helsinki.
Carter, you can be
such a Princess.
Something wrong
with that?
Automated voice:
Door opening.
---the end---