THE BITTER TEARS
OF PETRA VON KANT
A case history
dedicated to the one
who became Marlene here.
With the special participation
of lrm Hermann as Marlene
Marlene...
be more considerate, please.
I've had such awful dreams.
My head is so heavy...
like lead.
The telephone.
Quick.
Mrs. Von Kant, please.
Of course, I'll wait.
Squeeze me some orange juice.
I'm dying of thirst.
Mother?
I couldn't make it yesterday.
My work, you know.
No, I've been up for ages.
It's true.
I haven't had a moment's peace.
But it has its good sides too.
Where are you going?
To Miami?
I'm so happy for you, Mother.
Miami is lovely.
Really, lovely.
And the people.
Wonderful to know.
Just wonderful.
Six months?
Oh, Mother,
I hardly know what to say.
Six months in Miami.
How I envy you.
I could do with that.
Thank you.
Start on the drawing.
The sketch is on the easel.
Yes, Mother. What was that?
Of course I'm listening,
but something's wrong with the line.
I'm sorry.
Don't get offended.
The line really was crackling.
I'm not lying.
Now you're being nasty, Mother.
Yes, I'm listening.
I understand.
How much do you need?
8,000?
That's a lot of money.
I can lend you 5,000, but no more.
What with expenses,
and then Gabriele.
Ask Tatiana, or perhaps -
Yes, Mother.
Marlene.
I want you to write a letter...
to Joseph Mankiewicz.
The address is in the files.
Dear Mankiewicz,
my dear friend,
I'm afraid I shall be unable
to make payment,
period.
There are circumstances
between heaven and earth...
dot, dot, dot...
But who am I talking to?
Question mark.
Hoping you will understand,
I remain your dear friend,
Petra Von Kant.
I'll sign it right away.
Come here.
Take it downstairs,
and be quick.
Well, hurry up.
That drawing must be finished by noon.
Any mail?
Karstadt?
Karstadt wants me
to design for them.
Marlene, did you hear me?
It's the chance of a lifetime.
Karstadt?
Mr. Müller-Freienfels, please.
My name is Petra Von Kant.
Petra Von Kant speaking.
Yes, I did.
But this week is full.
I might manage Friday.
One moment.
Yes, I can squeeze it in on Friday.
When? At 3:00?
Fine, at 3:00.
See you then.
Those rats.
Do you remember when I offered them
my first designs three years ago?
They didn't care.
How times change.
The man was so servile,
when I think about it.
At this hour?
My God, who -
Open the door.
It doesn't matter anyway.
It's 10:30 already.
Darling.
Sidonie.
My dearest!
- Petra.
My God.
How long has it been?
- Three years, my dear.
How time flies.
But you look absolutely stunning.
How do you do it?
I have nothing on you.
Your youth, your beauty.
And Frank?
I read about you two.
In Australia of all places.
And I said to Lester, “Poor dear.
Look what's happened.”
We always warned you
about that man.
We all have to have
our own experiences.
I don't regret it one bit.
No one can take away
the things you learn in life.
On the contrary,
they give you maturity.
I don't know, Petra.
When you can foresee the end
from the start,
is the experience alone worth it?
Make some coffee, Marlene.
Or would you prefer tea?
Coffee would be fine.
- Have you had breakfast?
- Yes.
I flew down from Frankfurt
this morning.
I was anxious to hear
how you were holding up,
whether you were suffering or -
People change.
I was different once, I know.
I wouldn't have known how to cope.
The shame of it alone.
I believed in the goodness
of the man.
But marriage
brings out the worst in people.
- I'm not so sure. With Lester-
- Oh, forgive me.
With all your travels, you never
got to know each other properly.
But Frank and I,
we were inseparable
and in constant fear
that we would fall apart.
That's when you get to know
what the other person is made of.
Sorry, I didn't want
to sound bitter, but...
there would have been
some opportunities,
really wonderful opportunities,
for that man and me.
But it was not meant to be.
- Still dreaming of him?
- No, Sidonie.
I just regret the chances we missed.
They certainly existed.
It's very sad,
believe me...
when you realise
that the distressing things...
by far outweigh
the beautiful things you feel.
Did you quarrel?
Quarrel?
Not in the normal way.
Sometimes there was a coldness.
You could feel it.
Look“.
You're with someone
in a car or in a room,
and you want to say something,
but you're afraid.
You want to be affectionate,
but again you're afraid.
You're afraid of losing points,
of being the weaker one.
It's a terrible moment
when you can no longer go back
and start again.
I think I understand what you mean.
Very vaguely, but -
I know what you're going to say.
“The wise person gives in.”
No, Sidonie.
Once you're in the mire,
who can pull you out again,
in terms of human relations?
It can't have been like that
for the whole three years.
Of course not.
At times,
it was so beautiful that -
There are moments
when you forget everything.
Everything-
Including the fact
that you could resolve the difficulties,
and find common ground to -
But we were stuck in the mire.
Poor thing.
It's easy to pity,
but much harder to understand.
If you understand someone,
there's no need for pity.
You can help change things.
Pity only what you can't understand.
I see.
The whole thing has hardened you.
It's a pity.
I have always been suspicious
of hard women.
I may seem hard,
but it's only because
I'm using my head.
You're evidently not used
to women using their brains.
My poor little dear.
Petra, please.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to offend you.
I just want you
to listen to what I say
and not have a preconceived opinion.
Noted.
I can understand your bitterness.
Did he ask for the divorce?
No, I did.
Not him?
YOU?
Good heavens.
That surprises you, eh?
Poor little Petra,
who couldn't do without her husband,
hopelessly in love,
almost a slave.
And she asks for a divorce.
Terrible, isn't it?
Did he -
No.
He wasn't unfaithful.
Adultery wouldn't have been
a reason for me to separate.
For my part, the relationship
was a healthy one.
We both attached more importance
to pleasure than fidelity.
Fidelity as a duty, that is.
Mentally we were faithful
to each other, no doubt.
There were other reasons
why it didn't work out.
Of course, when things go wrong,
it turns to disgust and hatred.
But that had nothing to do
with what was going on around us
or with other people.
Thank you.
- Yes, thank you.
Go on sketching. it's urgent.
Can we -
Marlene's been with me
for three years.
She hears everything,
sees everything,
knows everything.
Don't take any notice of Marlene.
Well, where were we?
What estranged you both?
What made you so sick?
You see, Petra,
Lester and I went through a time
when it looked as if
everything was over.
We were weary, disgusted and -
You have to be wise,
show understanding and humility.
A woman has her devices.
She just has to know how to use them.
I wasn't interested in “devices”,
especially not female ones.
I had no time for magic tricks.
- Tricks, Petra?
- Yes, they're tricks.
Cheating if you like.
They lead to a loss of freedom.
When I hear words like “humility” -
Don't sneer.
Don't sneer at me.
Lester and I are really happy now.
Humility paid off.
He thinks he's the boss.
I let him think so,
but in the end I get my way.
Listen, darling...
I know what you mean...
and it may be all very well
for you and Lester.
Maybe this sense of compulsion...
is just what you need.
But, you see...
Frank and I...
we wanted
to make our love beautiful.
And for us, “beautiful”...
meant always knowing
what was going on,
in yourself...
and in the other person.
We didn't want a humdrum marriage
with codes of behaviour.
We wanted to decide
everything anew,
always be alert...
always...
free.
I don't understand...
why everything must be so complicated
when it can be simple.
Codes of behaviour exist for us
to use them consciously.
Why keep having to
decide things anew
when we have
tried-and-trusted methods...
and they're good?
We wanted to be happy together.
You understand?
Together.
I don't know of any
tried-and-trusted model for that.
What turned it all into disgust
when there was so much clarity
and understanding?
Success, for example.
The success I had
and that Frank hoped for
and needed so much.
That's how it began.
it was as simple as that.
I'm sorry,
but success is no reason to -
Men...
and their vanity.
He wanted to pamper me,
take care of me.
Of course, he took me seriously
and respected my opinions.
But...
he wanted to be the breadwinner.
And that's how oppression
comes about, quite automatically.
It works like this:
I listen to you
and understand you.
But who slaves away
and earns the money?
One rule for him, another for me.
My dear...
at first, it was,
“Everything you earn, my girl,
will be put aside for later.
A home of our own,
a sports car.”
I agreed, because...
he was so loving, Sidonie.
And sometimes,
the love he lavished on me
just swept me away.
I was breathless for joy.
Then, when he struck a bad patch,
it was almost funny to see
how his ridiculous pride was wounded.
To be honest,
I actually enjoyed it.
Especially as I thought he knew
how ridiculous his behaviour was.
But he didn't.
And later,
when I tried to tell him
that it made no difference to me
whether a man was on top or not...
it was too late.
As soon as I broached the matter...
he was like a wall, Sidonie...
like a wall.
Gradually the honesty began to die.
I thought I'd been mistaken
about him or about myself.
So then I called it a day.
I stopped loving him.
The last six months were excruciating,
believe me, excruciating.
He realised it was all over.
He felt it at least.
But he refused to accept it.
And even then, he wasn't very bright.
He tried to hold onto his wife,
if not wholly,
at least in bed.
That's when it turned to disgust.
He tried a new technique:
violence.
I let him possess me. I bore it.
But...
the man seemed so filthy.
He stank.
He stank of man...
the way men stink.
What had once had its charms
now nauseated me,
brought tears to my eyes.
The way he took me.
Petra, please!
Hear the story out, will you?
He mounted me like a bull
mounting a cow.
Not the slightest respect anymore.
No thought of a woman's pleasure.
The pain, Sidonie.
The pain.
You can't imagine it.
And when I sometimes -
Oh, the shame of it.
I felt so humiliated.
He thought I was crying
for love and gratitude.
How stupid he was.
He was so dumb.
How stupid men are.
You poor thing.
How you must have suffered.
I don't need your pity.
He-
He deserved mine.
Understanding, kindness or pity,
if nothing else were possible.
He aroused no feelings in me.
On the contrary,
it became worse and worse.
When we dined together,
his chewing
sounded like an explosion.
I couldn't stand it
when he swallowed,
the way he cut his meat,
ate his vegetables,
held a cigarette,
a glass of whiskey.
Everything seemed so ridiculous,
so affected.
I felt ashamed for him.
I imagined everyone else
must see him the way I did.
Of course,
it was hysteria, panic.
There was nothing left to save.
All over.
Finished.
The end.
I'm so ashamed.
There's no need.
No need to be ashamed.
You've tried to learn,
tried to understand.
Whereas I -
I think people are made
to need each other.
But they haven't learned
to live together.
That must be Karin.
A delightful girl.
I met her on the boat
from Sydney to Southampton.
She wants to make a start
in Germany.
This is Petra Von Kant.
I told you so much about her.
Take a seat.
Please excuse the mess.
Things are a bit upside down.
It doesn't matter.
Some tea? Or a cognac?
A cognac, please.
Marlene, cognac.
And you, Sidonie?
- No, thanks.
Not this early.
Funny,
I imagined you much older,
more distinguished.
Is that the word?
That is the word, yes.
But why older?
People who are so successful,
so famous,
I don't know,
they're usually older.
It's the exception
that proves the rule.
It's time we were leaving, Karin.
I'll give you a call.
I'm in town longer this time.
Do that, Sidonie.
Take care.
You have a good figure.
You could use it to your advantage.
Get in touch with me some time.
- I'd love to.
Coming.
Let's say
tomorrow evening, at 8:00?
See you tomorrow, then.
Yes, till tomorrow.
You've altered the sleeves?
that's good.
They'll like that better.
That was the bell, Marlene.
And I'm not ready yet.
Open the door.
I'll be down in a moment.
How nice.
Good evening, Mrs. Von Kant.
I've prepared a bite to eat.
Marlene, serve the food.
So here you are.
- Here I am.
Enjoying it here in Germany?
I was only away five years.
Yes, I'm enjoying it.
Nothing's changed much.
Things stay the way they are
in Germany.
Tell me about yourself.
Me?
There's nothing much to tell.
Oh, yes, there is.
What you think,
what you...
dream.
Nothing much.
I just want my little corner
in this world.
Is that asking too much?
On the contrary, Karin.
That's what we live for:
to fight for a place for ourselves.
Do we have to fight?
Of course.
I had to fight too, and hard.
Very hard.
That's life.
I always thought
I was too lazy to fight.
- Too lazy?
- Yes.
I prefer to lie in bed,
reading graphic novels.
Maybe you haven't found
the right incentive to live yet.
You're still young.
- Twenty-three.
- Exactly.
You've so much ahead of you,
good things,
bad, ugly and beautiful things.
Life begins at 23.
- Does it?
Don't you think so?
My God, I have so much
experience already.
I'm married and -
You are?
Yes, my husband
stayed in Australia.
We had -
it's all so complicated.
Nothing is simple.
Nothing at all.
You have to understand...
what humility is.
Humility?
You see,
everyone has his own theory
of the world.
I believe
you have to have humility
to be able to bear what you know.
I have humility in my work
or with respect to the money I earn
or the many things
that are stronger than me.
I think “humility”
is a strange word.
It reminds me of kneeling
and praying.
I don't really know.
Perhaps these...
concepts
are not suitable for young people.
I'd have reacted
the same way at your age.
Thank you.
Help yourself.
Do you think
you'd enjoy working as a model?
I don't know the trade
and what's involved, but why not?
Fine.
We must talk business.
You can't just go down the runway
and think you know everything.
You must be willing to learn.
I am willing to learn.
I want nothing for free.
I could help you, of course.
Later on, when you know the ropes,
you'll easily find work.
You may have difficulties at first.
Financial difficulties, I mean.
You wouldn't earn anything
during training.
- I suppose not.
- I'll help you.
That's an offer.
Money shouldn't be an obstacle.
That's very nice of you.
The nice thing about the job
is that you're often on the road.
I love big foreign cities at night.
Are you fond of travelling?
Depends. Yes, I think so.
It can be marvellous:
travel, new experiences,
foreign cities, music.
Do you like art?
- Art?
I don't know.
- Theatre, concerts, good movies?
Oh, yes,
I love the movies.
Pictures about passion
and sorrow are nice.
We could learn together.
That makes it easier.
I was lucky to have parents
who pointed out to me at an early age
the beautiful things in life.
What were yours like?
My father was a toolmaker.
Very interesting.
We didn't have much.
Lots of work and not much fun.
That's how it was.
They didn't have a good life.
A tiny apartment,
three kids screaming all the time.
But your parents devoted themselves
to you as a child, didn't they?
Devoted themselves to us?
We were in the way,
a nuisance most of the time.
Poor child,
it must have been dreadful.
They meant well.
Besides, they left us in peace.
It's better if parents don't interfere
with all the things you have in your head.
Even so,
leaving children to their own devices?
I'm not so sure.
You know...
I have a daughter myself.
I don't always have time
to look after her
but I know she's at the best
boarding school there is.
It's a reassuring feeling.
I liked school.
Didn't you?
No, I don't think I did.
I know I was glad when it was over.
Although I was a fairly good student.
I'm sure you're very intelligent.
Intelligent? Yes.
But I didn't like learning
in those days.
The things I was interested in,
I found easy.
It was the same with me.
I was unbeatable
at the things I liked.
Funnily enough,
I loved mathematics.
I didn't.
I was always bad at arithmetic.
It was okay at first, but later,
with those letters and so on,
I was lost.
Strange.
Algebra fascinated me tremendously.
Tremendously.
Algebra?
No, it wasn't for me.
Never could understand it.
Why stick a letter onto a number?
I still don't understand.
It's not important.
There are more important things
in the world.
I loved gymnastics
and summer athletics...
or games like handball.
I didn't like using
the exercise equipment.
I always had better grades
in the summer.
Did you?
No, I preferred the exercise equipment.
It requires...
discipline.
Another of those words
young people hate, I suppose?
Discipline's fine
as long as you're having fun.
But discipline for its own sake
or compulsion,
I don't think that's good.
It's funny, but...
I need a push to make me do things.
Like needing money,
or having to keep a promise.
If there were no compulsion...
I'd be totally lost at times.
Yes, I understand.
But it's better
if you can do without it.
My father took us on a bike ride
every Sunday.
The whole family pedalled away.
Him in front, then Mother,
then us three girls behind.
He cycled like mad out in front.
He was a man.
When we came home,
we were worn out,
and he was as fresh as a daisy.
Then he had a fight with Mother
about nothing every Sunday.
Anyway, we all had to come along.
Maybe I'd have chosen
to go along sometimes...
but it was never any fun that way.
The thought of it is amusing, though.
Father, mother,
and us three girls on our bikes.
Isn't it?
Why,yes.
It was brutal of your father.
But that's not
the sort of compulsion I mean.
I'm talking about the constraints
people accept,
that they wish for and need.
How are your parents?
They're both dead.
I'm so sorry for you.
Both of them?
Father beat Mother to death,
then hung himself.
No. How terrible!
Now you see me
in a different light.
It's always the same.
People like me
until they hear my story.
Then it's all over.
No, Karin. On the contrary.
I feel a great affection for you.
Even greater now
that I've heard your story.
We have to do
something good for you.
Let's be real friends.
Sure. It makes things easier.
A bottle of sparkling wine!
She's a good girl.
She does all my work for me.
But tell me,
how did it happen?
My parents, you mean?
Quite simply.
Didn't you read about it
in the papers?
No, I can't remember.
Dad drank like a fish, and -
No, it wasn't like that, because -
One day his firm told him,
“Thimm, we're a competitive firm,
and there's no room
for people of your age.”
I'm not sure exactly.
I wasn't there,
but it was something like that.
He broke down, cried
and began to thrash around.
Somebody from security came
and threw him out.
He went to his regular bar
and got drunk.
What else could he do?
Dad always drank heavily.
Then he went home,
beat Mother to death and hung himself.
He saw no future for himself
and his wife.
It's as simple as that.
I went off to Australia, but...
things are not so rosy there either.
You don't get anywhere
without pushing.
All that's going to change, Karin.
We're both going to do our best
to make something out of your life.
Wouldn't that be great?
I've often given up hope.
I had a bellyful with my husband.
He had me slaving away,
saying he would make a pile of money.
He said it was only a matter of time.
He got on my damned nerves.
Here's to us.
May we use our opportunities.
I can see you now,
striding down the runway.
I'll design a collection
especially for you.
I'll make a top model out of you.
You're beautiful, Karin.
Do you like this kind of music?
They're records from my youth.
They either make me sad
or really happy.
It depends.
They're from the time
I was with my first husband.
What a romance that was.
Someone once said
beautiful things don't last long.
And, you know,
there's some truth in that.
Pierre was killed in an accident.
He was a passionate driver.
Pierre was...
He was a handsome man...
but obsessed.
He thought he was immortal.
But he wasn't.
He'd been dead four months
when our daughter was born.
It wasn't easy for me.
But everything is predestined in life.
I had to put up with it.
People are terrible, Karin.
They can bear anything.
People are hard and brutal.
Everyone is replaceable.
Everyone.
That's something
they have to learn.
Where are you staying?
- At the Hotel Übersee.
In a hotel?
That must be expensive.
- 27 marks, including breakfast.
- Exactly.
Who can afford that for long?
You can move in with me.
It's cheaper and -
Anyway it's nicer.
- I -
- You don't want to?
I'd love to.
I simply meant -
Maybe I'll get on your nerves.
I know myself, Karin.
You won't get on my nerves.
I know what I'm like.
I'm often very lonely.
We'll make it cosy for ourselves.
If you think so...
Yes, I'd love to.
I love you.
I love you, Karin.
We shall conquer the world together.
I want to caress you,
kiss you.
I like you too, Petra.
Very much.
But give me time. Please.
I'll give you time.
We have time enough.
We have so much time.
Time to get to know each other.
We shall love each other.
Bring us the sparkling wine.
Did you cancel the flight?
What?
Why? Sorry, I'm still in bed.
I'll do it myself.
No, I'll do it. Let me get up.
No, why shouldn't I do it?
I booked two seats to Madrid
on the 25th.
For Kant and Thimm.
I'm afraid I have to cancel them.
No, not just now.
It's pointless cancelling flight tickets.
Either you turn up or you don't.
They notice in time.
It's a matter of courtesy, darling.
You'll learn that some day.
- Thanks.
- Don't mention it.
My Shoes!
Hurry up!
I'm beginning to think
she's unhinged.
She's not unhinged.
She loves me.
- Well, have fun.
- Thank you.
You're not going back to school?
Is that final?
Why should I?
I won't learn anything.
We never stop learning.
- You and your pearls of wisdom.
- it's just experience.
Let me phone them
and apologise on your behalf.
Then you can go back.
It's worth finishing something
you've started.
It always pays off.
- If you think so.
I do.
- Fine.
- Exactly.
Fix me a gin and tonic.
You drink too much.
Be careful you don't put on weight.
Go to hell.
Don't forget,
your figure is your fortune.
It's all you have.
- If you think so.
- I don't think so. I know so.
I love you.
- I do too.
Shit! “I do too. I do too.”
Say, “I love you.”
Alright, I like you.
I love you.
You have the loveliest skin
in the world.
Do I?
And the loveliest hair.
The loveliest shoulders.
And the loveliest eyes.
I love you.
Leave me alone.
But Why?
I haven't cleaned my teeth yet.
I don't mind.
But I do.
Stop it.
I want to read.
Please.
I'll leave you in peace
if it disgusts you.
It doesn't disgust me.
We can't play with each other
24 hours a day.
We can.
Oh, Petra.
I could remain forever
in your embrace.
Why do you have to be so cruel?
I haven't done a thing to you.
I'm trying hard.
I'm not being cruel.
That's easily said.
You say you're not cruel,
but when I need you,
you push me away.
May I-
I just want
to sit with you for a while.
Where were you last night?
I went dancing.
Till six in the morning?
- What about it?
- They're not open that late.
Who did you go “dancing” with?
What?
Tell me who you went dancing with.
With a man.
What man?
A big black man
with a big black cock.
I see.
Want another one?
- Yes, make me another one.
“Please.”
Forget it.
No, I won't forget it.
But you could be a little more kind.
Here.
Thank you, dearest.
What was he like?
In bed?
For instance.
Insatiable.
Extremely.
Just imagine his big black hands
on my white skin.
And those lips.
You know, those blacks
all have big, warm lips.
Don't faint, darling.
Stop staring, you silly cow!
Bring me the newspapers!
No need to get hysterical.
The best is still to come.
Don't be so mean.
I'm not being mean.
I'm telling the truth.
We always said we wanted
to be frank with each other.
But you can't stand it.
You want to be told lies.
Lie to me.
Please, lie to me.
All right, it isn't true.
I was walking alone all night,
thinking about us.
Really?
That can't be true.
Of course not.
I did sleep with a man.
But that's not important, is it?
Of course not.
But...
I don't understand.
Really.
Why?
Don't cry, Petra.
Listen, I like you.
I love you, but -
it's obvious.
I need a man from time to time.
That's the way I am.
It doesn't affect us.
I just use men, that's all.
That's all there is to it.
Just a bit of fun.
You were always talking of liberty.
You always said,
“No obligations towards each other.”
Don't cry.
I always come back to you.
How my heart aches!
As if someone
had stabbed it with a knife.
No need for it aching.
That won't help.
No need for it to ache.
He who uses “need” without a “to”
need not use “need” at all.
I know I'm not as clever as you.
I know that.
You're lovely.
I'm so fond of you.
Everything aches with love for you.
Want another one?
I must watch my figure.
- Will you be seeing him again?
- Who? That man?
- Are there so many?
- Come on.
Well?
No, I'm not seeing him again.
I don't even know his name.
Besides,
he said he's being transferred.
Really a black?
Yes. Why?
Just because.
He was really great.
You'd have liked him.
He wasn't really black,
more brown...
with an intelligent face.
Some blacks have European faces,
don't they?
- I wouldn't know.
- They do.
And he was one.
He told me lovely things
about America.
Karin, please.
I'll shut up.
I thought we'd sorted things out.
You don't have to rave about him.
You're hitting the bottle too.
What else do I have?
Come off it.
You're getting hysterical.
I'm not hysterical.
I'm suffering.
You thrive on suffering.
It's easy for you to talk.
“People thrive on suffering.”
It's true.
I'd rather be happy, Karin.
I'd much rather be happy.
All this makes me sick.
What does?
Forget it.
Tell me what makes you sick.
You.
You make me sick.
Because I don't know
why you stay with me.
Whether it's my money, or because
you have a better chance with me...
or because you love me.
Because I love you, of course.
Shit.
Stop it.
- If you won't believe me -
- Believe you?
It has nothing to do with believing you.
Of course I believe you love me.
But I don't know.
I really don't know.
That's what's making me sick.
Listen.
“An outstanding contribution
to next winter's fashion line-up
was made by Petra Von Kant
with her new creations.”
And there's a picture of you.
Show me.
There.
Crazy.
Not bad.
Tell me.
Yes, very nice.
“Very nice, very nice.”
it's fabulous.
The first time
my picture's been in the papers.
I don't believe it.
I love you.
Come here.
Forget it.
I'll take it.
Von Kant here.
It's for you from Zurich.
- Who do you know in Zurich?
- No idea.
Karin Thimm speaking.
Who?
What are you doing in Zurich?
What brings you to Zurich?
When?
3pm in Frankfurt?
Hold on I'll ask.
When's the next flight to Frankfurt?
2.30
The next flight from Bremen's at 2:30.
I'll try to get a seat.
If not, call me from Frankfurt.
I love you.
That was my husband.
Freddy's in Zurich.
He's in Europe.
Book me a flight to Frankfurt, please.
Be a dear.
Petra Von Kant speaking.
I'd like to book a seat
on the 2:25 flight to Frankfurt.
It's full?
There's room in first class?
Fine.
Book the ticket
in the name of Karin Thimm.
I don't believe it.
Freddy's here.
Forty-five minutes before take-off, I know.
I don't believe it.
You told me
you and your husband -
I thought you were through.
That was ages ago.
You might at least
have told me...
you were in touch again.
Freddy's my husband.
Of course I've written to him.
You said you wanted a divorce.
I said maybe we'd divorce one day.
Anyone can change their mind
in six months.
You know what you are?
No, but I'm sure you'll tell me.
You're a rotten little whore.
Mean and rotten.
You think so?
Yes, I do.
A nasty little creature.
When I look at you I could throw up.
You'll be glad I'm leaving, then.
I am.
But it's almost too late.
I wonder why you didn't
work the streets from the beginning.
It was less strenuous with you, darling.
Yes, I see.
My God, how mean you are.
How can you deceive
someone like that,
when you know they love you?
I didn't deceive you, Petra.
Oh, yes, you lied to me.
You weren't straight with me.
That's enough.
I said I love you, Petra.
That wasn't a lie.
I love you...
in my own way.
You must admit that.
I'd have reacted
quite differently if you -
How can anyone be so mean?
You knew how I felt,
what happened to me.
That's not true.
I didn't know what had “happened”
to you for a long time.
At first, you behaved
as if it were just fun.
I can't help loving you.
I can't help it.
I need you. I need you so much.
I'd do anything for you.
I want to exist only for you.
You're all I have.
I'm so alone without you,
so very lonely.
Lonely, without a whore?
Forgive me, please!
Try to understand
what's happening to me.
Don't be so cruel.
Get up. I'm in a hurry.
Oh, you rotten little rat!
You'll pay for that.
You won't forget that, ever.
I don't know what I'm doing anymore.
Please understand.
Give me some money.
For the plane and for Frankfurt.
Freddy never has any money.
I'm good enough for that.
For paying-
Oh, my God.
How much?
Come on.
500.
I'll give you 1,000...
so you won't be short.
500 is enough. Really.
Take the thousand.
What does it matter now?
Drive her to the airport.
I'm too drunk.
You're really leaving me?
No, this isn't Von Kant.
I hate you.
I hate you! I hate you!
If only I could die.
Simply be gone.
I can't bear the pain.
I can't go on.
Oh, God, what a bitch!
The rotten little bitch!
I'll show you one day.
I'll make you suffer.
You'll come crawling back to me,
you little whore!
You'll kiss my feet!
I'm so mixed up.
My God,
what did I do to deserve this?
What did I do?
I still love you.
Don't be so cruel, Karin.
Oh, shit.
I need you so much.
Phone me, at least.
Phone me, please.
Just let me hear your voice.
That's not asking too much.
Just phone me.
That doesn't cost you anything.
No, the bitch wouldn't dream of it.
She has it all worked out.
She just makes me wait because -
it's so sordid.
You nauseate me.
A dirty little slut.
And I love you so much.
I'm mad about you.
If only you knew how it hurts.
I hope you'll feel the same one day,
feel all washed up.
It'll look different then.
You're so damned stupid.
It could be so lovely,
just the two of us.
You'll understand one day.
But it'll be too late then.
Much too late.
Believe me I'll show you -
Happy birthday, Mother,
Gaby!
- Isn't Grandmother here yet?
I've so much to tell you.
Of course, my child.
Marlene, make tea for us.
What a flight.
It was so bumpy I felt sick.
Mother, it's ages since I saw you.
Dearest Mother.
Four months.
Isn't Karin here?
But she's coming later?
I don't think so.
Doesn't matter.
I didn't like her particularly.
Well, you know,
she's rather common, isn't she?
No, she's not.
It's not important anyway.
Mother, I'm so unhappy.
Unhappy?
Actually, I'm terribly happy.
I don't know.
It's all so difficult.
What is, my child?
Mother, I'm in love.
You're -
How funny.
You, in love?
Your reaction is terrible.
Terribly bourgeois.
I'm sorry, my dear.
You were always my little girl.
I must get used to the fact
that you're growing up.
Please do.
Tell me about your boyfriend, Gaby.
That's just it, Mother.
He isn't my boyfriend yet.
He doesn't even know I love him.
He's so obstinate.
For three weeks,
I've been trying to flirt with him,
but he just snubs me,
behaves as if I don't exist.
It's so difficult.
It'll work out, Gaby.
Believe me.
He's so handsome.
You've no idea how handsome he is.
Yes, I do.
He's very tall, slim,
has long fair hair
and looks a bit like Mick Jagger.
How do you know?
I'm not saying-
You're so clever, Mother.
You're the cleverest mother
in the world.
Who was it?
What's the matter?
Say something.
Don't cry.
What's happened?
Nothing, Gaby.
Nothing's happened.
Stop crying-
There's nothing wrong at all.
Get the cake and cream.
Get the hell out of here
and get the cake and cream!
Or are you deaf?
Get lost!
Why do you treat her so badly?
She doesn't deserve any better...
and she likes it that way.
She's happy like that, you see?
- No.
Whatever.
You don't have to worry
about servants.
I don't want to argue with you
on your birthday,
but I want you to know
I don't share your opinion at all.
That's fine.
Children have a right
to develop their own ideas.
Isn't that what they say today?
I'll go.
May I announce
Baroness Sidonie Von Grasenabb.
My dear.
Happy birthday.
With all my heart, Petra.
Open it later.
How's school, Gaby?
- Not bad, Aunt Sidonie.
Satisfactory is satisfactory,
I always say.
Marlene, another cup, quickly.
- I think Mum treats Marlene badly.
- I don't think so.
I don't think you're old enough
to judge your mother's actions.
Okay, then I won't say anything.
How are you, dearest?
What can I say?
I'm well.
Pretty.
- isn't it?
Thanks.
I read about your success in Milan.
Congratulations.
It's a pain in the backside.
- Stop laughing.
- Let her laugh.
Laugh, then.
I'm fed up with my work,
designing things and fearing
they won't succeed.
It's always the same, and for what?
You have to live.
You have to work to earn money.
And you need money to live.
That's just it. Money's everything.
The cake!
She's trying to annoy me.
I don't think so.
- If only she could.
- Don't talk like that.
Any news from Karin?
From Karin?
No, and you?
Yes, I know she's working for Pucci.
Oh, for Pucci?
She's very talented.
She'll go far, I'm sure.
Talented?
That's not talent.
She just knows how to sell herself.
Aren't you being unjust?
Maybe you're too subjective.
She's in Bremen today.
She's -
You're really well informed, my dear.
To tell the truth,
Karin phoned me this morning.
Otherwise I wouldn't have known.
- Did you -
Naturally I told her
it was your birthday.
She said she'd try to drop in.
But she wasn't sure.
She's terribly busy.
She is terribly busy.
I know.
You must get a hold of yourself, Petra.
It's so easy to go downhill.
I'll go.
So sorry,
I just couldn't find a taxi.
Happy birthday.
Sidonie, you're looking younger
every day.
Really, Auntie?
That comes from being happy.
The traffic in this town
will be the death of me.
How's school Gabriele?
- So, so.
- Have you been quarrelling?
- I was forbidden to talk.
- That's not true, Gaby.
- I was forbidden to have an opinion.
Nobody forbade anything.
That's a lie.
- You forbade me to say anything.
- What a terrible child.
Calm down, children.
Let's be nice to each other.
You make me sick, all of you.
- Well, really!
- Stay here, Sidonie.
What's wrong, my child?
You're all so fake.
Dishonest little rats.
You have no idea.
You revolting child.
I hate you. I hate you all!
Don't touch me!
If you only knew
how filthy you are.
A pack of parasites.
- What's the matter with her?
- Poor dear.
I'm not poor.
I see you in a new light.
And what I see
makes me want to throw up!
Stop it!
You'll smash the whole house.
So what?
Did you work for it?
You've not done
a lick of work your whole life.
First you let father keep you,
then me.
Do you know what you are?
A whore, Mother.
A miserable little whore.
What I've earned,
I'll smash as much as I like.
Do I make myself clear?
I don't understand a thing.
What have we done?
It's all because of that girl.
- What girl?
- Karin.
What about Karin?
Everyone knows
Petra is mad about Karin.
Mad?
I'm not mad.
I love her.
I love her as I've never loved
anything before.
You love her?
You love a girl?
Her little finger is worth more
than all of you together.
Mother, please!
Get lost, you little horror!
Marlene, gin!
Ten bottles of gin!
My daughter loves a girl.
How peculiar.
A girl.
My daughter.
Karin!
No, I can't stand it anymore.
I'll smash everything. Everything!
We must calm her down.
What do you want?
You get a kick out of this.
You have enough
to gossip about for a year.
Shut your mouth.
I feel so sick.
Oh God! Oh, God!
I'm going.
I don't have to put up with this.
Go then. Get lost!
Do you think I'm worried about you?
I never want to see you again.
Never again, do you hear?
You'll pay for this, Petra.
You'll live to regret it.
I won't pay for anything.
I've paid for enough.
Anyone else leaving?
The door's open.
Get out!
Get it!
I don't want to see you again!
I've nothing left to give!
I'm all washed up!
Gin, Marlene, gin.
Or are you leaving too?
What are you all crying about?
You're all so happy.
Everyone's happy-
My child, my poor child.
I want to die, Mother.
I really want to die.
There's nothing in the world
worth living for anymore.
In death...
everything's quiet and lovely
and peaceful, Mother.
Everything's peaceful.
I love you so much, Mother.
You take some tablets,
drop them in water,
swallow them
and sleep.
It's so good to sleep.
I haven't slept for so long.
I want to sleep.
A long, long sleep.
Gaby's sleeping.
I'll be my old self again, Mother.
Where there's turmoil,
human beings are so feeble.
It's been thirty-five years since you were born.
Gaby has had a shock.
Mother, I beg you.
This isn't a reproach.
You should simply know.
I visited Father's grave.
Somebody had laid flowers on it.
I don't know who.
It's the second time.
I was afraid you'd despise me
because of Karin.
I know.
Perhaps I do.
It was raining thirty-five years ago.
The rain was beating
on the window panes.
I'm so afraid.
I'm so alone.
I often visit Father's grave.
Much more than I used to.
And I go to church again.
I didn't even enjoy my work
these last six months.
I had the feeling my head
was bursting with pain.
You must have
the courage to believe.
Everyone needs some kind of solace.
And...
one is alone without God.
That's no solace, Mother.
You have to learn to love
without demanding.
It's the same thing, believe me.
I didn't love her.
I just wanted to possess her.
That's all over.
I've learned my lesson...
and it was very painful.
You must be good to Gaby.
Children are so sensitive.
I know.
She cried terribly
before she fell asleep.
Don't torture me, Mother.
What good does it do?
I have to speak my mind.
Petra Von Kant's residence.
Who?
Just a moment.
Yes, of course I minded.
But that's all over.
No, it's -
it's late now and -
No, I can't make it tomorrow.
You're off to Paris?
But we'll see each other sometime.
Of course.
Take care.
You can go now, Mother.
I've calmed down now.
I've made peace with the world.
I'll give you a call.
I have to apologise to you
for many things, Marlene.
In the future, I would really like us
to work together.
You'll have what you're entitled to:
freedom and fun.
Not like that.
Tell me about yourself.