What happened?
(World Entertainment)
(Episode 31)
You're awake.
How are you feeling?
What?
Yes.
Why am I here?
It seems as though you
fell down the stairs.
Fell down the stairs?
You were unconscious in
front of a building,
and people nearby called
an ambulance for you.
In front of a building...
For how long was I unconscious?
For quite a long time.
It seemed you were very tired.
You talked in your sleep too.
Maybe you dreamed about the Olympics,
but you kept saying, "Woo Seung".
I said "Woo Seung" in my sleep?
Am I hurt a lot?
We'll need to go through more checkups,
but fortunately, you don't have
any serious external injuries.
- What is this for?
- There was a minor bruise...
on your head.
Anyway, it's important to get rest,
so do that.
And...
can I get your autograph here?
- What?
- I'm a huge fan of yours.
Why don't you perform anymore?
Nurse Park.
Me first.
Well, my daughter...
is a huge fan of yours.
Here.
Then was it all...
a dream until now?
(Roar, Moo)
Hi, Hyun Jae.
You aren't scheduled for a treatment today.
Are you here for the result of
a checkup you did yesterday?
You'll have to wait a few more days though.
Yesterday?
I came to the hospital yesterday?
Pardon?
Yes. You came to the hospital...
and had a checkup yesterday.
It's my notebook.
(I want to have it!)
I told you not to touch my stuff.
Your stuff? What are you saying?
That's my watch.
What? How is this yours? It's mine.
Why is it yours? It's mine!
Is there another Yoo Hyun Jae here?
I'm sorry, but what date is it today?
It's 17th today.
Do you mean June 17?
Sure, it's June now.
Is it the year 1993 now?
What?
What are you talking about?
It's 1994.
1994?
Hey.
Is Yoo Hyun Jae dead?
Yoo Hyun Jae died on June 17, 1994...
when he was 24 years old.
(The Best Hit)
What?
You shouldn't move around yet.
I'm a bit busy now.
Wait.
Pick up. Please pick up.
Hello?
Gwang Jae, it's me, Hyun Jae.
What's wrong with you?
Why do you keep...
I...
already made it clear...
that I don't want to talk to you like this.
Hey, we made up already.
What?
- When did I?
- So what happened was...
Gosh, I'll explain later. Anyway,
I need your help.
I can't go to where you are now,
so you need to come here.
Gosh, you're upsetting
me after a long time.
Hyun Jae, you...
I only have you whom I
can rely on right now.
Please come to Gom Cafe.
I know I'm being shameless,
but please help me this one last time.
Why would I go there seriously?
Hey, forget it.
Just sleep already if you have
nothing to do. I'm hanging up.
My gosh.
Was that Hyun Jae?
Have you guys been keeping
in touch behind our backs?
That's not it.
Forget it.
Where were we?
What? Well...
This came to my mind as
I was writing a song.
It's not because I can't think of an idea,
but I've never been interested
in dance songs from the start.
What if we release a ballad album?
Are you listening to me?
Hey, Gwang Jae!
What? Yes.
How can you not be interested in me...
regardless of Hyun Jae's existence?
What are you talking about?
You're the star singer...
of World Entertainment now.
You're only saying that because
I'm all you have left.
Whatever. What I'm saying is...
I need to head out for a second.
We're in the middle of an
important conversation here.
Let's talk next time.
You said I'm the star singer.
You're the star singer.
But let's talk later.
I'm pretty sure that
call was from Hyun Jae.
Are they trying to pull something again?
Welcome.
You said you were going
somewhere for a while.
I thought it was somewhere
nice and awesome.
I guess you really went
somewhere for a while.
Hey, it's so nice...
to see you again when I
saw you just a while ago.
What are you saying?
When did we see each other?
There's something.
Goodness, and...
what's wrong with your
hairstyle and clothes?
For goodness' sake.
There's a reason for that too.
Anyway, I'm glad to see you.
I was going to ask you to meet
because I had to talk to you.
Before that, I have to
find someone in a hurry.
Who? Who are you looking for in a hurry?
- Yoo Hyun Jae.
- What?
- I need to find myself.
- What are you talking about?
- Are you drunk?
- No.
Where can I find him now?
- I'm leaving.
- Hey, wait.
I know this sounds weird,
but you know a lot of people.
I know you can find him
quickly if you help me.
What on earth are you saying?
Why are you looking for yourself?
I found you. You're right here.
Sitting here.
No, it's...
Okay, so someone is apparently
pretending to be me.
Someone who looks exactly like me.
- What?
- So find him for me.
Find out where Hyun Jae is. I
know he's out there somewhere.
He's not me, but there is another Hyun Jae.
What are they talking about?
I can't hear them.
What happened? Did you find him?
Like you said, I guess there
is someone like you out there.
Really? Where is he right now?
Well...
It looks like he was
recently in the studio.
He worked there today morning.
And then?
He went to Paju to do something.
Paju? Why?
He apparently had something
to do with his family.
His family?
- I need your car.
- What?
I have no idea why I always
let you have your way.
You're my only friend.
I'm not your friend.
Did you forget something?
Pardon?
Oh, when did I walk out of this room?
- Just now.
- Really?
Then what did I do here?
- Pardon?
- I must've done something.
You wanted to move your parents' grave.
- What?
- You said you can't take care...
- of your parents' grave anymore.
- Did I?
Oh, right. I did.
And did I say where I was going next?
No.
Excuse me, is there a lake nearby?
There is a lake nearby.
There's a rather large
lake named Lake Suryeon.
Lake Suryeon?
We found the last traces of the
popular singer, Yoo Hyun Jae.
Yesterday afternoon, a month
after his disappearance,
a car owned by Yoo Hyun
Jae was found deserted...
near a lake in Paju, Gyeonggi Province.
You can't go to Lake Suryeon.
Thank you.
I don't think I can take
care of you two anymore.
You wanted me to live near you two, right?
I think I'll probably see you very soon,
so don't be disappointed
that I'm doing this.
This is an update on the typhoon.
We can assume that Seoul and
Gyeonggi Province are effected.
Yes, we can.
Many of you must remember the twin
typhoon Kaola from last year.
We have another twin typhoon,
even though it's much smaller.
Who are you?
So there really is another Hyun Jae.
Wow, thumbs up.
Who on earth are you?
Don't be surprised. I'm you.
Wait, should I say that you're me?
What?
I know it's hard to believe,
but I'm Hyun Jae from 1993.
From 1993?
I'm from the night in 1993 which
always wanted to go back to.
I went to the future and came back
because of this weird typhoon.
This is actually pretty huge
if you actually go through it,
but if you say it out loud, it
does sound quite odd, right?
So what I mean is...
Anyway.
I guess you came here because
of our parents' ashes.
In that case, this doesn't seem like...
the worst case scenario which I thought of.
What are you talking about?
It says that you disappeared in this place.
So I wanted to prevent
you from coming here.
But I didn't think I would see you here.
I guess you really can't
change your destiny.
Hey.
Are you saying that you're me?
That's what I'm telling you.
I had no idea what was going on,
but I figured some stuff out from
the note you left in the bank.
A note? What are you talking about?
The money and note which you
left in the safe in the bank.
You were going to give
it to Gwang Jae, right?
Yes, I was thinking about that.
How did you know?
For one thing, I'm you.
And I'm from the future.
No wait, I'm originally from the past.
Anyway, that's that.
So you're saying that you're me from 1993.
I'm from that night in 1993,
when we received the golden cup.
That exact night which you
wanted to go back to.
Right, that's the night...
when I grew apart from everyone.
I thought all of the money was mine,
but I guess it's not.
So,
how do they live?
What?
You said you saw the future.
What about Bo Hee?
How's Gwang Jae?
Oh, right. It's...
Well, it's a long story.
But I am a superb storyteller.
Let's see, how should I begin?
Gwang Jae, Bo Hee, and
Sunday were living together.
Young Jae became a huge success.
Who on earth is that?
He kind of looks like Hyun Jae.
What's with the weather?
What if I get struck by lightning?
Our fans are still the
same even after 20 years.
They are still superb and awesome.
They still remember you, and
they still love our songs.
Really?
(Roar, Moo)
I guess we don't have much time.
- What?
- Nothing.
About Ji Hoon.
Can you tell me a bit more about him?
What?
I told you.
He's a great guy.
He must be superb...
since he's my son.
Yes.
He's superb.
He's just too good.
He's also very smart.
He's pretty good at
dancing and singing too.
Good enough to be on stage.
You'd think he'd be conceited,
but he isn't.
What about school?
Is he a good student?
He went to the best university in Korea.
He must be smart just like me.
I miss them.
Gwang Jae.
Bo Hee.
And Ji Hoon.
Oh, my goodness!
That scared me.
What's up with the lightning?
It's because of the typhoon.
Typhoon?
Is it...
the twin typhoon?
I don't know.
Wait. The radio said it was.
Yes, it's the twin typhoon.
What about it?
What time is it?
I left my watch at home.
How long will it take to
go to World Entertainment?
- Why do you ask?
- I don't know what will happen...
but let's try.
What are you talking about?
I'll explain later.
Start the car first.
What's wrong with this?
I brought a car.
Let's take that. Hurry.
Oh, I don't know.
(The Great Yoo Hyun Jae)
(World Entertainment)
What? The rain stopped.
There isn't much time.
We have three minutes left.
We have to go to the rooftop now.
- Why?
- There might be one more chance.
Quickly.
(World Entertainment)
We've got nothing to lose.
Ride this and slide down.
- What?
- This could...
send us to another world.
What are you saying?
This is how I traveled through time...
on the rooftop.
We don't have time. Hurry.
In the future,
your illness...
can be cured.
No.
What do you mean no?
I don't want that.
What?
This is my time.
Think about it.
I'm Yoo Hyun Jae who's
living in this world.
If the future you're from really exists,
then there's something I should do here.
Whatever I need to finish,
I want to do it here.
There's a reason...
I'm here like this.
If you meet Ji Hoon again,
give this to him.
You're dying.
I'm Yoo Hyun Jae.
I won't go down that easily.
You said there isn't much time left.
Go back to the time you belong.
Hey.
Yoo Hyun Jae.
And...
thanks for coming.
Why you...
Ji Hoon, aren't you ready yet?
Why do you have to go so early?
Public TV makes you do long rehearsals,
so it starts early.
- Gosh.
- What's taking them so long?
Hey. It's your first public TV appearance.
You can't be late.
We were practicing.
Madam, no, mister.
No.
Miss. No!
Sir, I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
I think you look a bit pale.
Yes, I'm okay.
My heart is...
Hey. Where's my heart?
Here.
Hey. Don't be nervous.
Just be yourselves.
Okay.
I'm so jealous. They'll be on public TV.
Sir, you're being so unfair.
You never put us on TV.
They're getting attention. That's why.
Just wait a bit longer.
What are you doing? Get in.
Wait a minute.
There.
My son is so handsome.
Okay. You're ready. Go now.
- Bye.
- Good luck.
- Okay.
- Ji Hoon!
Mal Sook. He's busy. What is it?
(World Entertainment)
What's this? You want my autograph?
No.
If you see Celestial Boys,
- get their autographs.
- What?
You have to get...
every one of their autographs.
Okay?
Okay.
And...
This is my favorite thing.
It'll protect you.
- Thanks.
- Where's mine?
You should protect me.
Where's mine?
Stop it. We have to go. Get in.
- Bye.
- Bye now.
- Go for it.
- Good luck.
- You can do it.
I'm hungry.
Ma'am. There must be something
wrong with my stomach.
Mal Sook.
I told you to call me Mom,
not ma'am.
That's right.
Mom.
Should we go make some delicious noodles?
Okay, Mom!
Let's go.
It feels weird to see them...
debut as singers.
Their song is pretty awesome, right?
Yes. It's pretty high up the music chart.
They need to become a big hit.
That would be nice.
I want to be a big hit too.
Hello. Long time no see.
Well...
- Hello.
Welcome.
Of course they can do variety shows.
- Why did you say welcome?
- I'm not in the office...
- Hello.
- Welcome.
I'll come see you after the show.
Okay.
I guess a lot of producers
think you're great.
This is it.
JB.
(Music Top Ten, JB)
Gosh. Mr. Lee...
came up with a fantastic name.
(Music Top Ten, JB)
Yes, Director.
Sure, hold on.
I can do this.
Don't be nervous.
Old Man.
I didn't expect I'd see you here.
Do you have a shooting today as well?
What are you saying? Our song
is the top one candidate.
Really? But you debuted only recently.
They say we're within the
top five girl groups.
That's not important though. Winning
first place is what's important.
By the way, what's wrong with him?
I think he's nervous. He has stage fright.
Ji Hoon, it's not working. Shall I
go to the toilet one more time?
Are you insane?
- Idiot, be a predator.
- What?
There aren't any place
for herbivore on stage.
Think of my slap if you get distracted.
It'll burn until you come down the stage.
I have to go now. I'll see
you often from now on.
- Bye.
How is it? Is her slap effective?
Not at all! It's just the pain on my back.
JB.
It's time for you to go on stage.
- Okay.
Drill, are you ready?
Ji Hoon, I'll rely on you.
Let's go.
Hello, it's World Entertainment.
The CEO isn't here at the moment.
I think he's out of reach
because of JB's schedule.
Sure, I'll make sure to send the message.
Hi, Ms. Choi.
Are you back from your workout?
Yes, because I'm on break.
I thought you were writing songs.
Shouldn't you be busy then?
That's... I'm working on it,
but I get distracted often
and it's not going well.
Can you stop calling me Ms. Choi?
We have no other employees anyway.
Still, you're the team manager.
But I'm the only employee this company has.
It's says you're a team manager
on your business card.
The CEO made it, not me.
Whatever.
Don't you have any songs you wrote?
Why would I write songs?
I already know. I heard
you're studying composition.
Show me if you have any.
If I show them to you,
will you copy them?
Gosh, seriously. You just hit my weak spot.
I'm going to have some food. I
can't think since I'm hungry.
- Tell the CEO that I was here.
- Okay.
Oh, right. Did you get
any calls from Master?
What?
No.