Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
"Welcome to Corporate Jeffers.
The largest, the most friendly
the corporation more profitable
the history of mankind. "
"Level 3"
Good morning, Mr. Jeffers!
"Visionary"
- Good morning Jeffers, George!
- Jeffers Morning!
Jeffers Morning Todd!
"V I S I O N E E R S"
"Today is Thursday.
Rest 10 200 minutes of
productivity
before the weekend. "
Jeffers Morning.
Visionary level three.
George Washington
Winsterhammerman talking.
"Jeffers Morning George!
Speech Charisma, level four. "
Good morning!
"I wanted to talk to you.
I noticed that you arrive early. "
Ah. Yes, I know.
Work early ...
or whatever.
I arrived early too.
George.
Walk around a rumor
upon thy servant Mike. "
"Tell you'll know more when
something else. "
"I send you now
work for today. "
Goodbye, George.
Well Bye. Bye.
Was Charisma, level four.
"Resta 1199 minutes
productivity
for the weekend. "
Jeffers Morning
Visionary level three.
George Washington Winst --
- "Hello, George! Speech Charisma."
Hello!
"George. I just called the
level five to warn that Mike
not be here today.
Apparently he
He exploded last night. "
He blew?
"They found it in the garage.
There will be a statement. Goodbye George. "
Okay. Bye.
Charisma was level four.
Mike will not be here today.
What happened?
Apparently, according to
Charisma of Level Four, à exploded Thursday night.
They found him in his garage.
It seemed that it was those that do not explode.
"Jeffers Morning levels
two, three and four.
Jeffers greets everyone.
This is the level five, with
Morning Report
direct office
Mr. Jeffers.
An ad sad
Jeffersonians, this morning
tunt, a level three,
a dedicated employee named Mike
no longer with us.
Take place
a brief ceremony
tunt in the cafeteria,
level three, Rs 10 hours
for the three levels
interested in participating.
Jeffers Tip of the Day:
What is good for the company,
is good for us all. "
"Restar 1 198 minute
productivity
for the weekend. "
Good morning! George speaks.
"Good morning Jeffers, George."
The level five said they would
have a new employee. "
A new employee.
"To replace
Mike. Goodbye George. "
Well Bye.
We
a new employee.
With us?
To replace Mike.
It's a girl?
I do not know.
I said that Mike was not
the type of burst
but I knew that would happen.
He said he was tired.
It is one of the signs.
Most people are
tired and perfectly well.
My therapist told me that if I did not
pull the trigger of
my gun all the time
I can explode.
Everything is ready
to explode, George.
Of course not!
I hope the new person
is a woman.
Well Back to work.
Do you know someone who
already blown?
A friend of mine has exploded.
Mike?
- Ted.
Rs Sometimes I think I will explode.
Sorry. For every
world is very excited
on the new employee
and everything is a distraction, but
still have much to do.
and ... this ... need
do our work
because if we do
chaos will be complete.
Hello!
"It's the George Washington
Winsterhammerman level three? "
Yes
"This is the fifth level.
Something happened
level three sector two.
Mr. Jeffers wants
maintain productivity. "
Ah, yes.
"Mr. Jeffers?
"Yes"
Of course! Yes!
There is a situation
at level three.
Mr. Jeffers wants
maintain productivity.
Mr. Jeffers?
Hello!
"This is the fifth level.
Mr. Jeffers thanks. "
Himself?
"Sure."
Mr. Jeffers thanked.
Himself?
Of course!
"Need 1 197 minutes
productivity for the weekend. "
"I created a form of
be with everyone.
From now on now
are just you and me.
Close your eyes.
I want
to hear
Happiness is ... "
Happiness is ...
"It is now Laura Huhn,
author of a brilliant, excellent,
tremendous work:
"Ten thousand things to be happy."
"I love helping others."
"Because you can not
be happy enough. "
"You are right, Sarah."
If you want to be happy and
have many friends
eat fried chicken.
Fried chicken makes a difference.
And if you want to have fun
without flying to pieces
Eat fried chicken.
Fried chicken is delicious!
Hey, love!
"ice cream too.
"That's interesting."
"A 12-gauge shotgun."
"My name is Louise."
"Hello Louise!"
Hello!
Good chicken.
"I note that there is a new
type of butter:
Apple butter.
Butter Pear.
Butter
Butter sheep.
Ah The butter is very versatile. "
I'll be in ...
"Butter edition.
"This butter is used
as a vaginal lubricant. "
"Vaginal, nothing more?"
"Well, you know ..."
"For the butter
does not discriminate.
No, that is. "
"As you can imagine -"
Howard!
"living with wolves can be
you - "
Howard!
Howard, is your father.
"We will discuss these factors
and dominance, which provides - "
This chicken, Howard.
It is delicious.
Howard!
I need to buy this book.
Sounds like fun.
"As I said, turning left à
and run it from behind --
No, no, please do not.
Remember what happened
the last time. "
I do not know.
Questionair me if
was a short time or not.
hearing on the Oscar.
"Honey, if she says so ..."
"Thanks!"
Is not it beautiful?
Howard did not leave the room
since joining the school.
Your brother called,
do not know why.
My brother called?
They called from your work
and told not to ires tomorrow.
Are you going to the doctor?
You'll see TV?
Yes
Lowers the volume.
Home?
I can still feel the
electricity from the screen.
... you have to ...
please ...
... is ...
"Updating the explosion:
The death toll is 100 001. "
The victims had dreams. "
Look ahead.
Smile please.
Lift the arm.
Lift your right arm.
Raise your left arm.
Download them. Yes, download them.
Turn right Distributor.
Faster.
A little faster.
À Turn left.
Smile please.
Mr. Winsterhammerman.
You are a person
following orders,
you want to obey,
is calm, friendly.
It's the kind of friend
we all want.
I see a good look
in your eyes ...
... classifies it was going to a
average intelligence.
All this is good.
The problem is that
brain scanner
was negative.
And that makes my diagnosis.
... because, as you know, normally
passive men like you
not the kind of man
suffering from dreams.
When they dreams?
About a month ago,
more or less.
What you see when you dream?
Been there?
I'm living ... long
time the same dream, you know?
I, George Washington.
"George Washington?
Does'll explode?
Woodrow Norman had
success in the past
with this product for dreams.
I'll send it immediately.
However, for
à answer your question:
However,
no link between
dream and explode.
Without taking into account that your
dream is a bad sign.
Dreams are dangerous because
instability and pain
and so do not talk about them.
But remember that
most important, is
that in this world, our world,
dreams are never real.
"Historical Viajens of Mimi"
Hello friends. It's here.
the property of Mr. Winsterhammerman.
From the land and house of George
Washington, Mr. Winsterhammerman.
Hey!
There it is!
You see, unlike your
ancestors, Mr. George Washington
Winsterhammerman chose
a common decoration.
Hey! Hello!
How are you ...
... your day?
How are you?
Number 435 of my book.
I made food, right?
Dress your new clothes.
Howard.
Your mother prepared dinner.
"Are you constipated?"
"I can win 15 000 ..."
"There's a tunt?
Want to become one? "
"The CDC has issued this
updated list
symptoms explosion
after careful review
growth of
epidemic explosion:
Problems of sexual desire.
Difficulty sleeping.
Mistake.
Do you feel that your life
is meaningless.
Suffocation, as if the
chest was pressed.
Rs often fantasize
as
in another place or time.
Costumes always ... "
Mack Luster
PD, MD
My name is Luster.
The last line of defense between
our lifestyle and
chaos.
Who are you?
Only one man
trying to prevent chaos.
Who?
Look at me! Lucy-Bel.
Say what you know!
I just want
go home.
I know.
Sorry.
Man.
A mission
stop these explosions. "
Did you bring protection?
Me too.
Want to try?
I bought some aid.
Man Shop
said this was your favorite.
He said with his words.
Betty also said.
Betty?
Betty Castor.
Betty Castor is
crazy for a trunk.
Sorry.
Why?
I do not know.
Please,
you will not explode.
Nobody is going to explode.
Tomorrow will be better
myself.
Sounds like fun.
Best squash.
Best karma.
Good weekend.
Best audience. Better
acorns. Best lamb.
Just relax!
Best corn.
Corn in a taxi.
Relax.
What are you doing this weekend?
The usual, I suppose.
"There was a time of darkness
when suffering
reigned in the land.
but à as man
wrote the story,
man was solving
their problems. "
This situation
was a man.
An ordinary man
with a simple plan.
And the name
his name was
Jeffers Lord "
Ah Hi If we are
view means that you are
one of thousands, millions
fortunate citizens
which joined à
Jeffers Corporation.
and let me be
the first to say:
Are you like!
Not so, Netty?
That is, Mr. Jeffers!
Here, the corporation
Jeffers
believe in hard work
and productivity.
But we also believe
teams.
Super work.
Because it was the corporation
Jeffers
the first to recognize
as profitable
may be the company
if we forget
ourselves
and work-hands together.
Working as a team provided us
jobs and happiness.
A world governed by peace
and plastic.
Where everything is wonderful
and especially
magic.
Good work, Mr. Jeffers!
We have great things
reserved for the future.
Because the style Jeffers, is the style.
But do not believe me.
Listen to this man:
Style Jeffers, is the style.
Thanks
Mr. Jeffers!
Ok
Jeffers Corporation
not supported by
activities gospel
or the belief in dreams. "
Have a question?
This is your desk.
Welcome to level three.
"Extermination standard 31-B.
Mike. Tunt.
"Remain 3 054 minutos
productivity
for the weekend. "
George.
Hello!
- Hello!
Not want to be ...
Never question again.
But ... Are you sure that is
appropriate for the level three?
They did the test
primary productivity, Cindy.
He proved to be infallible.
I think you are eating a
Burger embryo.
Problem boss?
No. None.
At what level is that
for us to eat?
Level Two.
In the test colococaram me
the second level
before going to jail.
I returned last week
I made a new test
and wrote me to tunt!
Prison!
Said a tunt
is sociable;
but introspective.
They want a team environment.
... BOOM ...
Tunt.
Here we eat?
I see no problem
that.
"Faltam 3 055 minutos
productivity
for the weekend. "
George Washington Winsterhammerman.
Visionary level three.
"Hi George.
Charisma level four. "
Hello Hello
"How was your weekend?
Tives you chance to relax? "
Yes
"George. Fifth level called
to get you to call and ask about
the performance of the new tunt. "
We have just the contract.
"The level George, five
I also called
to see if everything went
well with the doctor. "
Well, I think it is
everything works fine.
"I just wanted to confirm."
"A newly placed
never mind, but
às times can
be difficult
accept its position. "
"Goodbye George."
What is the secret ingredient
to an explosion in real life? "
"It's called dihidrodicloro
and this wonderful substance
is in one place:
Las Vegas. "
Hello! love.
Come and join us, brother.
What we are discussing how
Satan works today.
Hear voices?
Voices of the path.
Society is
before us.
Well that may be
Satan say
to explode the brother.
Is the number 700.
"Stay away."
You are reading books
wolves, Howard?
Howard. I can not tolerate
this chaos in my house.
Howard!
Julian!
Brother!
... escaped.
I got home, my brother.
You receive up to my call?
No, I ...
George. I was at level five.
I was a king.
A king among men.
And one day, I was in my
office and fell asleep.
And I was walking.
He was sleeping, but I
Walked down the road
and people laughed at me.
and when I looked down
I saw that I was missing the penis.
And in its place was
logo of Jeffers.
I do not care to try
remove it, it
he fall to wash it.
Then I realized that
had to flee
before the explosion
caught it all.
- I was in South America,
I lived in Ecuador.
Then one night
after drinking too much beer
maize and guinea pig
I found myself free.
Like when I was young.
Only louder.
And I knew that when he came to
house was capable of doing something.
George, I came home
to live with our family.
Came home
recover our heritage.
to live
in the pool house.
To find the force.
And with the hope
to find it.
I know, my brother, I know.
"Keep phones
playing. I like this sound.
Ring, ring, ring, ring.
People know, as I appreciate it!
When I said I would do a marathon
to increase awareness
all these explosions
that has been happening
everything about this great nation,
Televisions
saw me live
and said, Berne, You're crazy.
You're a fool.
No one will want
see a show like this.
But I think
Estmos to prove that
they were wrong!
We checked
wrong.
Now, Joe is with us.
Yes, Joe!
Joe wanted to walk again.
His psychiatrist
said he would live only
two weeks before it exploded.
But thanks to hard work
to understand
beauty of this position
you can see,
Joe is still with us.
How are you, Joe?
Ble bl bl bl Bln BLR.
We love Thee, Joe!
Let's give an applause to Joe!
You know, ladies and gentlemen
there are people like Joe
supporting pain
wherever
and learn to accept that the beauty
Distributor is us. "
General!
We have problems, sir!
"Hello George.
Speech Cindy. "
Hi Cindy
Where are you?
"I'm at level four, George.
I knew last night that
we had a new job.
I am now a goop
instead of Charisma.
You're a good tunt, George.
While you've been
a tunt long.
It must be hard to accept
that you have been exceeded
an employee
younger and capable.
I hope not take it badly
for being a woman.
Are you gonna bother with that, George? "
No.
He has a good
relationship with Charisma.
Relations which I hope to develop.
The new tunt should work with
harder now.
And I do not want
problem between us.
Understood?
Shipping rules and would like to
get back after lunch. "
Jeffers Morning!, Level two,
three and four. A sad announcement:
After showing a low
gradual productivity
Charisma, a goop level four
Jeffers left the corporation.
The good news is that
Cindy, a level three tunt
was promoted
is now a goop.
Congratulations Cindy!
Jeffers: Word of the Day:
"Be productivity or say goodbye.
Hello love!
Rodger.
Come.
Yes!
Get off me.
I'm beginning to lose it?
George.
It's getting difficult.
George!
What is it?
It Rodge.
Hello
George. How are you?
Hello Rodger.
I was with this
girl the other night.
She was to contact you.
In my package.
Right? Right?
Really ...
Tensions are high.
Let's see what we can work.
Two more times!
Just calm down.
Relax.
This is a friend.
That's it.
It feels like work?
We are well, tiger?
The doctor still thinks
will you explode?
Well Well This means that
treatment is working.
Remove the cream in dermatological
softening and exfoliating.
Sleep well?
Can not say. My choice is ...
What about sex?
Want to be happy, George?
Are you sure you did not return
want to resign?
Because I'm feeling
'm not feeling
I am not
feel that energy.
You know what I'm
feel in this room?
M.E.R.D.A. George.
Know what
M.E.R.D.A. means?
M.E.R.D.A. means
someone
not feel lucky
live in
great country
and that makes all the
difference for us.
Who do not have any luck
work for Jeffers coorporação.
Sort of having a woman
is able and willing.
The luck of having a home.
Driving a car,
boat.
Golf.
A lucky to have wonderful conversations
with people like me.
You know why I feel that there M.E.R.D.A. George?
Because someone is not struggling enough!
When I came assured
that wouldn 't explode.
And is your life, friend,
your career
and this is my job.
You will need a
little faith?
An effort?
No?
gui blrr bl
You will take a bit of blu blu bl?
Give it the old coach?
Faith
Good! Let me, to end,
give you a little advice
to close this session.
It is quite natural desire
sex, George.
The man who does not want sex
is a man who does not believe
the world you live.
He does not believe in the future.
A man who does not want sex
is a man without hope.
Without faith.
A man without sex is ...
He is not a man Complect.
He is not a man Complect, George.
Is.
Well
Rodger, the crazy, wasted
the patient still, is it?
I want you to do something for me.
Promise me you'll try.
Today à night when you go out, I
I want you to go to the fourth
want to grab your wife
and I want you ...
I want to do that.
Sara!
I promise to do it!
That's what I like to hear.
"Uder Norman"
"Sonhoauta"
"Instructions"
Outer space is empty
all thoughts and desires.
As your life is
empty and meaningless.
You can enjoy it only
has a
special connection with the universe.
Using the hat 12 hours a day.
See DVD manual washing.
"Welcome à corporation Jeffers."
"The biggest, most friendly and more
profitable enterprise of mankind. "
Jeffers Morning!
I have this bad boy all night.
It is assumed that reduces the
stres and the bad energy
by 15 percent.
Comes with white arms.
George Washington Winsterhammerman
Visionary speech level three.
"George, is Cindy. Goop level four."
"I want the standards
until lunch. "
Standards settlement Charisma "
Jeffers Morning!
"Jeffers Morning, levels two and three.
Are trying to find
things about the visitors
that are in my office this morning.
We are pleased to report that
the corporation will distribute Jeffers
gang huggable
a little later.
Mr.. Jeffers is excited
with this product.
He is convinced that the
strategy to alleviate stress
Huggable reduce gang
significantly
the risk of explosion.
We want each of you
spend as much time as possible
with its Member
gang huggable.
Later, we will evaluate whether
this product has changed their lives.
Can collect their bears now
and tighten the ears
find a pleasant surprise. "
How old are you?
Grapes and blackberries.
Today, it is a beautiful day?
General!
We have problems, sir.
- Can you tell me ...?
- Yes, sir!
.
There are two possible
breaks in the position here
in the field.
The Big Boss was maintained.
General Putnam were appointed
but those damn Tuntas.
Convicted Tuntas!
Are facing the enemy
on the battlefield, Lord.
I want Hamilton.
I want the Hamilton and Jefferson.
We need a speech
as soon as possible.
- Come on! Come!
- Yes, sir.
General! We have a problem
with men, sir.
The men are stopped, sir.
He was working
with a unit which could not
move out of Boston, sir.
Not pass! No!
Let's sing and dance
Queen forever, sir.
Tell the men who have faith!
Not too aware that victory ...
... conscience, Mr.
Tell the men
General has a plan.
to defeat the English
before sunrise
tomorrow.
Flat!
Go.!
The future is good. No way out.
Defeated and crying.
Now, I write
this wonder.
- George!
Listen George. Look.
Hey George!
You'll be okay?
By Berne.
A race to happiness
did not return to health.
Hello!
Of course. I confirm that more
300 people died.
I repeat: Berne Goodman
comedian, actor and fish
exploded this afternoon live.
The dead included Billy Mood.
Another man named Joe
and Rodger
famous coach.
They told me that reached us
video of the last moments of Berne.
Ready John? Well
Stop, stop.
Give me -.
Hang, turn off the phone now.
I tell you,
pinheads
who sit
at home in your living room.
Turn off the TV! Now.
Go!
- Easy!
Get off me!
You know how I spent the money?
I had sent.
Want to know?
Spent with prostitutes.
In pills
In gaming machines.
And there as the spent
end
day
Is that --
I mean, only
Damn!
I do not know how they got here.
I think
somewhere
within you
part of you
asks to hear.
I've done this before ...
a dream.
George.
Hear George. Look.
Mary. How are you?
- Okay!
Are you sad?
- Nao. No.
You are in pain?
Cut what you were hurt?
Standards of extermination of Charisma
It is enough, enough.
Good girl!
Are seeing the inhibitor
recently developed.
Remove all the pain,
thought and emotion
and will gain instant happiness.
Feel they can
be in danger of exploding,
please, please
contact with your supervisor.
Maria was not happy
before loading.
But now:
Inhibitors Jeffers REM
comes in three great colors:
"Charisma. 213 River Street,
Lot 37 "
Orange, blue and red.
"AM 1440
music of the past. "
"To push
your soul and help you to see. "
Lot 37. "
"Hi George. Hello
Charisma, level four. "
"I tried to talk to you before.
I noticed that you arrive early. "
"Ah. Yes, I ..."
I have a new job.
Goodbye George.
Hello! What do you want?
Here it is.
- Sorry.
Well Anything else?
Good! Return later.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
George?
George Washington Winsterhamerman?
... I did not want to bother you.
We --
Wait, wait a second.
This is the business of my father.
You are as I imagined.
and I?
Probably not think
would be in a place like this.
Perhaps a more sophisticated site.
Something suitable for a
goop level 4.
What I'm saying?
I did not want to bother you?
Were spying on me. Right?
Sitting there.
Trying to decide to go or not.
Should be angry with you?
How you doing, George?
Todd exploded.
Cindy was promoted.
and
I dreamed you.
In my dream
levavas me to a place.
Sorry. I should not say that.
I must be crazy.
I do not know.
It has a ring on his finger and ...
Task number 9 000
place an order by phone.
"There will be a hysteria
total country, in this city.
Exactly where you live.
This is the answer: no ... "
Jeffers Morning.
Employees Jeffers Morning.
I am here to make an announcement,
in relation to speech
presidential à last night.
After assessing the tragic
Goodman death Bern
and the resulting chaos, our
President declared that the explosions
a threat
to our way of life
and approved the implementation
inhibitor.
In the following areas chaotic.
"Area 37"
We here at Corporation
Jeffers, we
fully measure.
Using
inhibitors mark Jeffers
in underdeveloped areas
will dramatically improve
the dangerous passions.
And more importantly,
show us the vision
of a happy future that awaits us.
And in accordance with
the president's agenda,
advert to my own initiative.
An official of the corporation
Jeffers demonstrating behaviors
explosives or potentially problematic --
ticos will be expelled immediately. "
"The right to information
the underdeveloped areas. "
I can not wait to see
the vision of our leader
on an explosive life and freedom. "
"Happiness is being happy.
"Happiness is to be happy?"
"What the hell, how
I do this? "
This is nonsense.
"I, Agena. So much butter."
...
"Happiness is to be happy?"
"That crazy as this?"
"What the devil ..."
Task number 800 with butter.
Care.
Want to sit?
The FBI is in the forest.
I think it will make a
incursion here.
They have been coming.
Since the president made
a notice of the inhibitors
someone spread the word
there was a party
or revolution taking place here.
It is the policy.
At least I have
the right to name it.
Even without know are
to do the same as the others.
Only with a different name.
Entertain.
Losing lying.
Nobody cares
the defect, or dreams.
He used them as models.
You know, the toy soldiers.
I did a re -
When Washington crossed the Delaware.
The night of the passage, Washington
had a vision.
The other night I had this dream.
I was in your store à
night, before I cross
appeared a woman,
whom he worked.
And try to show me something.
And the next day I went to see it.
There was a time
the restaurant
hands
were near the mine.
And I thought
would play into the hands
How to get a
pool of deep water.
She is the woman with whom I worked.
At four goop.
But when she said she felt.
Well, I know.
I'm not sure if
she has not touched his hand.
And if there was some promise
in the dream, I did not.
I saw it, but saw nothing more.
"See, with the
recently developed inhibitor
eliminates all
thought, pain or emotion
to take it to farms --
Joe Ryder!
Oh, George! How could
thought I could beat us?
I bleed!
Did not I tell?
Dreams are not real.
I never wanted
Inhibitors Jeffers ...
comes in three great colors:
orange, blue and red.
In my dream,
waves me to a place.
The use of new inhibitors.
Sorry
I should not say that.
It does not matter.
I thought if I came here,
show me.
Well, what you see?
George. George.
Where you going?
Employee: George Washington Winterhammerman "
"Level: Tunte"
"Test 101 C"
"Please describe the characteristic
you love. "
"Describe your sexual relationship."
"Please draw a
his vision of the future. "
George --
- "George, says Cindy, goop level 4.
"- Mark is there?"
- Mark?
It is a level 5.
Hey. Hold on.
Hold on! I bought this chair.
"Please draw a
his vision of the future. "
Hey George!
Hey!
Need 1 776 minutes of productivity
for the weekend.
"News 1440 AM, bad news
my soul mate
from tomorrow AM 1440
will stop playing music.
The producers asked me
to read as follows:
The president raised
the risk of explosion
from dark brown to magenta.
We do not want someone explode
in underdeveloped areas
where there are castles
Breaded old
and women in bikinis.
Howard!
Of course we want our
women die as rats
in the basement and our
men like wolves in the mountains.
She's dead.
He put the gun in his mouth,
apologized, pressed the trigger
opened the brain.
So I put the gun in my mouth,
I apologized and pressed the trigger.
As in the book.
Love ...
Shut up!
I've been sitting all
the afternoon trying to explode.
But I can not. I can not
Do it because there is nothing in me.
Nothing more.
And I realized.
Nobody says
people who are
explode are not sick
are not cursed
or dangerous.
They are better than us, because
I still feel something,
still dream of something.
Something that does not go out
a haircut,
with coffee
milk, with this kind of ...
and then back
grow
and a husband who did not return
can get an erection.
See? Nothing.
There is nothing left.
Damn. I lost it!
Want to hear the worst?
The last time I felt
alive was the day we met.
At this meeting, the meeting of 30.
I was drunk.
I walked around drunk every day
this month.
You know?
And it asks you to
your degree
and finger
mean on your shirt
and talking about
George Washington Winsterhammerman.
And I thought, because
did not return venture.
So desperate sat
my room
with a gun in his hand
I wanted to kill me!
I've been there long enough.
George Washington Winsterhammerman?
Level Three?
It's amazing.
I'm proud of the
My concentration
the ability
focus my mind
and my body
in any subject
without touching anything
without seeing or
that is outside
my vision.
Make sense?
Now
I am looking for man
Mr. Jeffers
saw a tunt.
And I ...
I do not.
And I worry, because
there is a shit
war approaching, tunt.
A war that will decide whether
Company Profile - Look at me!
- Continue to follow the course
given by Mr. Jeffers
or otherwise maneirao gives
resulted in a huge mess.
So far we have
good looking men
to help us in this process.
We have not thought much about you.
We did not even
existed, but
but then
Gave us that.
"Please draw a
image of his vision of the future. "
Mr. Jeffers
very much enjoyed this design.
She is out there waiting Distributor.
Pretty, is not it?
Do not be afraid.
My muscles are big.
But only exercise I sweat.
Want something?
Soda? Alcohol?
Normally I do not
I show my staff.
In the past, had effects
negative impact on productivity.
But times are changing.
Now show me
my staff.
Like now.
Employees who I can trust.
As you approach a fight
to save our way of life.
As much as I believe
of inhibitors
and some laws,
that would stop the chaos
all studies show
the war has begun.
Many confused
and many stupid people,
out there, and began to question
began to think!
Thank you.
In analyzing the learned
and what others know
and that is a
fundamental truth
that there is a union in the world,
where men have evolved
beyond the emotions,
become enthusiastic
opponents of our system,
where there
dreams or explosions,
because there are no actions or
independent thinking.
Of course, the real
peace can exist.
What you thought
when designing this to you?
Dreams of death.
Suffers pain?
Yes
Part of you is angry.
I like you, tuntia.
I'll show you how
can have the peace you want,
and live in the world
know is coming.
Do this and your pain will stop.
It will not have another dream
for the rest of your life.
"Shoot what you love."
"Month of TunT"
Hello! Welcome to Isadora.
I would like to eat something?
Please. Here
no place to sit.
Thank you. Not a good night?
Be right back.
Wait. Do not you remember?
It was a weird before?
Yes
- Great!
I wonder if I
to take a walk.
I like walks.
What kind of ride?
A boat trip.
Want something to drink?
Do not know if I'll understand.
But, of all places in the world
I'd rather be here in the boat. Water.
I met her in
restaurant of his father.
Was sitting in
table like this.
With our hand
next, as now.
I'll take it. Now, let's see.
I'll put it again
to stop the pain of both.
Charisma.
Want something to drink?
"AM 1440 music of the past. Well,
my friends, I'm saying goodbye. "
Nothing. Nothing more.
"Tomorrow I have come to be the Lord
Happiness, at the hour of comedy Slap.
Now say goodbye.
We will miss the wonderful ...
Now listen.
Return when ... "
George.
A translation "        ".
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org