This film was restored by PATHE m 2014
WAITER!
Water.
Andouillette for madam.
And your lamb.
A Gamay!
The John Dory?
Schnitzel for the young man.
Michel...
A half-bottle of Pouilly.
Philippe...
- Table 11.
- Right away.
Bill for tables 5 and 11!
A half of Pouilly.
Roger, still roasting that coffee?
Goodbye.
Gangway!
2 chickens! Ready?
Take 'em away! Where's Dominique?
One rare steak! Take it!
I have  turbot and kebab waiting!
One buss. One lamb chop!
Let's have them!
Announce your orders!
I'm not part of the decor!
Alex needs two more chickens!
Where's my marrow?
ls that lamb still here?
Gone? Glad to hear it!
Someone take the sausages!
Speak up!
One fillet, one ray!
So soy so!
Roger, your scallops.
- Rare or medium?
- Rare!
So say "rare fillet"!
Alex, take these away!
Whose supremes are these?
Gilbert's! He's not here.
- I'll take them.
- No!
Chop it up.
Garnish it with cress.
Meat on this side.
Watch that, not me.
Veggies for my guinea fowl!
Where's my order got to?
Don't fret, pal! It's on its way!
Made to order.
Finally!
How are you, Mr Gilbert?
- A party of 6...
- Let's hear it.
Say it's best lukewarm.
One ribs, one pork, two supremes,
one chicken and one steak!
6 dishes for 1 table!
- Got it in for me?
- They insisted...
Because they saw
you were a pushover!
Get going!
I need veggies for the guinea fowl!
One guinea fowl...
How's the chicken done?
Grilled
with a sauce of tomatoes, shallots,
cognac and white wine.
It's a bit spicy.
- Can you hold the sauce?
- It comes separately.
Would you prefer fish?
Maybe... I'm not sure.
We have brill with basil sauce.
It's steamed. Very light.
Where is it?
In the daily specials.
- Bye, Alex.
- Goodbye, Mr Gachet. Sir...
But it's with basil.
Maybe I'll have meat.
Meat...
Grilled or with sauce.
No sauce.
I'm holding you up...
It's all right.
Excuse me.
- Two calvados.
- Right away! Maurice!
The chicken, plain chicken.
One chicken.
The guinea fowl, sir?
- Yes.
- Very good.
Thank you.
l'll send the wine list.
- Thank you.
- Enjoy your meal.
You make me so happy, Sylvia.
Especially now.
Excuse me.
The wine list.
- Met Maurice?
- No.
Meet Coline.
Hello.
See you at half past?
She's a bit shy.
You hadn't met?
- No.
- I thought you knew her.
That's fine!
Those who are staying
can work with Dick and Jaia.
How was it?
Dynamite!
Well?
- Did you "dig" it?
- My feet hurt!
Try to memorize the steps.
Can you take over?
I'm waiting for Coline.
- I'll try to find Bob.
- Good idea.
Simon was a great dancer.
As good us any American.
What about you?
I kept up but his legs were
like machine guns!
Our trio became a duo.
The last guy quit
at the London Palladium.
Then it was my turn...
But there's still some life
in the old boy yet!
- I'm off.
- See you later.
I've kept you waiting.
How are you?
Are things that bud?
Alex,
I don't know how to tell you this...
I can't see you anymore.
You can't?
Richard wants me all to himself.
Only natural.
He's fond of me,
so we've decided to live together.
That's good.
I always said he was a nice guy.
He's young...
much smarter than I am...
A go-getter.
A little aggressive maybe...
That's no sin.
That's what I'm saying!
And he's handsome, in a way.
What way?
I'm saying that because...
I'm jealous.
You're not.
You're too old for that.
Betting's off
on 3, 7, 8,11,14 and 21.
- Who's with me?
- Me.
- William?
- 100 francs for me. Thanks.
Same for me.
You should thank the horses.
You never bet...
But Mrs Paulin does!
She's got looks... and luck!
Be careful; the horses
slow down when they spot Alex!
Not all of them.
This is stone cold!
50 francs for me.
Your perfume drives me wild!
Smell it?
I sure do!
Stop it...
How about Urbain?
No, Urbain can't afford it.
He makes as much as we do.
Sure, but he has 6 mouths to feed.
Dinner's over.
Hurry, we're running late.
We're not fussy but this is cold.
Two of my burners are out.
Any veal stew left?
Here, this should be hot enough
for them.
Thank you.
Cigars, Monique!
Two pork, one rabbit,
one medium steak!
Who forgot their hum and parsley?
Whose scallops?
Take them away!
Yes, Mr Gilbert?
Your daily special?
Here you go!
Bastard!
Change jobs, stupid!
- It was red hot!
- So use your napkin!
You keep bringing food buck!
"Dry", "too salty"...
Now it's my fault you drop it?
Enough, Francis.
Stay out of it!
Whose mushrooms are these?
I'm quitting.
Good riddance!
One less jerk here.
Apologize!
Shut up!
- Shut up yourself!
- This is my turf!
I'm the boss here!
This is no sideshow!
Get moving!
- Whose schnitzels are these?
- Mine.
It's not over?
No, it's not.
Take the chicken away!
We're out of pork and lentils.
What's with Gilbert?
He's quitting. If he goes, I go.
I've got better things to do!
Don't just stand there!
Bill for table 4!
3n coffees for table 5!
Here, boss.
Thanks.
Who'll set up tomorrow?
It was Gilbert's turn.
Well then...
I hear the revolution's begun!
You're abandoning ship!
A quick word...
Hold on!
I reckon I need to apologize.
- I apologize, Alex.
- Not to me...
OK. To Gilbert, then.
I admit the plate was red hot.
So was l.
I hereby apologize. Publicly. OK?
Drinks are on me!
Maxime, start pouring!
- Champagne for everybody!
- No, wait!
This is on me.
Maxime, Perrier-Jouét!
In that case, make it a '55!
- Shake, Gilbert!
- Bravo, Francis!
Where's the photographer?
I'm no fool:
it's happened to others.
With Charlie, it was
"I don't like queers."
With Rico, it was dagos...
I couldn't refuse
to shake his hand...
But I know I have to leave.
Don't get curried away.
If you lose your job...
what'll your wives and kids do?
When I said I'd quit,
I realized I was skating on thin ice.
What's that?
A map.
A map of what?
Some land.
Your father's land?
And?
Nothing.
Stop the machine!
It's the red button.
Francis has always been like that.
Seven of diamonds.
I need a card
and can't draw it!
I draw 'em all!
I knew Francis
when he was in short punts!
He fought with the cashier.
- Play, Armand.
- He got kicked out right away.
Your turn, Jeannette.
- I don't believe it...
- Oh, what a beauty!
What's she up to now?
Who was that?
She won't answer.
Take these.
- Whose turn?
- Yours, Jeannette.
Drinking won't help.
I don't care!
What did he play?
- Queen of clubs.
- Just what I needed.
I'm gin.
What a woman!
All I needed was a jack!
I've been holding one cord forever!
Right!
See you, Armand.
- It's not polite to leave.
- I know.
It's because he's losing.
Always cut your losses!
Right!
- You leaving, Jeannette?
- No.
He loves your visits.
- Bye, Jeannette dear.
- Bye.
Alex?
I remember you...
I'm Claire.
We met at my father's wedding,
on the bout.
- In Toulon.
- Orthez...
The violinist!
How is he?
He died three years ago.
How about you?
Still tap-dancing?
That's behind me now.
I have to run!
I've got a taxi waiting...
See you again maybe.
This is my favourite.
It's beautiful!
To set the colours,
wash it in cold water...
- With salt and vinegar.
- Hung it on the wall.
- You said I was wrong!
- I did not!
Don't tell him I came.
I'm in a hurry.
I don't want to hear about it!
Calm down!
I um calm!
I'll fetch some water.
And the other night?
He apologized.
Then he started again.
He can't sleep at night
and he panics if I'm not here.
Off you go.
I won't see you out.
- Thanks.
- Don't give up your job!
Don't worry.
Off you go.
I sent it away.
The taxi...
You're going back to Paris too.
And I've got a car.
Wonderful!
- Where to?
- The 20th district.
I take the Porte de Bagnolet?
I think so.
What was I going to say...
How long has it been?
17 years.
I was 17 at the time.
17 years...
Sorry!
How's your wife?
My wife?
All water under the bridge.
She's remarried.
To our divorce lawyer.
It was my fault: I screwed up.
I made her sell her restaurant.
Know why?
To buy a music hall.
I wanted to take up dancing again.
Goodbye, Fred Astaire!
She wanted a hotel,
so we bought a complex.
Hotel, nightclub, pool: the works.
I got in over my head.
The whole thing folded after a year.
She'd had enough of old Alex.
I'm still paying off my share.
And now?
I work in a brasserie.
Head waiter.
For the time being.
Are you going home?
No, an intensive English class.
You're a teacher?
I guess so.
It's only been 2 months.
I've never seen you at Jeannette's.
Jeannette more or less raised me.
I didn't see her much
after my marriage, until last year.
What does your husband do?
No idea.
I left him for another man.
A little less than a year ago.
But that affair's over now too.
Already?
So I guess you're...
ls he crazy?
It's a one-way street.
Sorry! I'll move!
I'll backup.
You're going wrong way,
you moron!
I know, I know.
Can't argue with a doctor.
- Are you late?
- Right on time!
Bye!
Just a second...
They've nearly finished.
Ashtray, table 5.
Mussel soup...
And the herring.
Then the duck confit...
Duck, red mullet and 2 soufflés.
- Orange ones.
- Very good. Enjoy your meal.
- Taste!
- No, thanks.
Be u good boy and taste!
3 coffees, 1 cognac!
2 espressos, 1 decaf.
Look who's sitting at table 14.
Our beloved Gloria
with her husband in tow.
In a London pub,
a guy asks the barman
for something tall and cold.
The barman says, "Take my wife!"
Marie-Pierre has invited us
to dinner Thursday night.
What a woman!
Little Paul gushed his chin
the other day.
Ambulance, hospital, 2 stitches...
She only told me today,
so I wouldn't worry.
Seen Gloria?
Pick me up at the Bel Air
at 3:30 sharp.
Make up a story, anything.
- Are you tired?
- No.
I hate seeing you like this...
So overworked.
Listen: work is exhausting
for everyone.
But a man of your intelligence
could somehow...
Victor wasn't always successful.
But he rose to the challenge.
If I could get you a position
in his firm,
you'd earn more, have greater
responsibilities... and more freedom.
Ready-to-wear isn't bud.
Maybe, but I'm not interested!
Do you understand?
I'm so tactless.
Sorry I made you angry.
Forget it.
I'm thinking of myself, us well.
I see you so rarely.
I thought...
if you had a job
that allowed you to travel...
I could come along.
We could sleep together
without hiding.
I have nothing against ready-to-wear
but leave me be.
Don't come to the brasserie...
Victor insisted!
He loves eating there!
What could I say?
Nothing.
You shouldn't.
Button-downs.
I noticed you didn't have any.
Any what?
Button-down collars.
We make them.
- Sorry, but...
- What?
We have to go!
Where?
You know where.
Hello.
It completely slipped my mind!
Will I see you Saturday?
Alex!
Thank you.
- I was tongue-tied.
- I noticed!
Maurice Palazzi.
That's me.
That cubicle.
German police!
All right!
I'm coming.
How's your blood pressure?
180 over 110.
Pretty high!
Watch those carbs!
Want to know my count?
Sure. What is it?
140 over 90.
The engine's in perfect running order.
So I asked about the old ticker.
A jewel!
- See you later, Urbain.
- See you.
Hi, pal.
Hi, Gilbert.
Don't let them take too much blood!
It's illegal.
They take blood now?
Coming to the bank?
Today's my lust installment.
I've paid it all off.
I'm free!
Congratulations. But I can't...
Bariollet's opening a new restaurant.
A classy place.
I'm going to apply.
The problem will be
the two days off.
Should I bring it up right away?
You're not listening!
- I um.
- No you're not!
I got the idea when I dropped you off
the other day.
In this world, it's the survival
of the fittest.
In every line of work,
the polyglot beats the bilingual,
who beats... the monoglot?
- Who knows?
- Anyway, that's how I got the idea.
It's tiring, the first lesson.
You should've called me.
How could I?
Jeannette and Armand
have gone away.
They're in Menton at her sister's.
- My car's over here.
- I already have a ride.
- Goodbye.
- OK, goodbye.
Sorry!
I wasn't paying attention!
There you go.
Got your braces?
Fetch them!
- Braces?
- For his teeth.
That's Marianne.
They want a story.
It won't be long.
Let them in.
Hurry it up.
Everybody tucked in?
Yes!
Once upon a time
there was u beautiful princess
with two lovely eyes...
Especially the left one.
Such style!
He does that so naturally!
I've had enough, thanks.
There must be days...
I couldn't do it.
It's hard on the legs,
always standing.
Standing but bowing.
What do you mean?
Bowing to serve others.
- Flunkeys!
- I didn't say that!
But it's what you meant.
Cigarette ash...
What's it called in your job?
When your boss calls you
into his office
and says, "Bring me
that motorway feeder file,"
it's, "Right away, sir!"
If you bring him the wrong file,
it's back to the kitchen.
Gilbert...
Marie-Pierre picked it.
I feel its bouquet
"throughout the body".
He's learning English.
It may come in handy.
Sounds fishy to me.
The warm tart...
It's the oven again.
Repaired just yesterday...
- Flip the switch!
- Where is it?
Take the tart out of the oven.
There's a warm tart?
Gilbert couldn't find the fuse box!
He doesn't live here.
He doesn't?
If Suzanne found out
we had 2 kids
and were living together,
imagine the scandal!
Think of poor Suzanne.
What would she say?
- Sorry!
- Thanks a lot.
Keep it.
For seven years now,
he keeps on fretting;
has Suzanne committed suicide?
He left her
when I had my second baby
but he stays at Alex's
to be on the safe side.
He has it easy.
It's his home away from home.
This is delicious.
Maybe when we're grandparents,
he'll tell her about us.
That's enough!
All right.
She's right, you know.
You only see your side of it.
In her shoes,
how would you feel?
Think of the children.
Do you have kids?
Yes.
I really shut that guy up.
What's his name again?
Jean-Jacques.
You shut everybody up!
What's wrong?
Let me ask you something.
When I left my wife
and you invited me to stay...
For 2 weeks! Not forever!
You just hate living alone.
It wasn't for my charm!
You didn't think of Marie-Pierre
or the kids at the time.
You know why?
You don't give a damn about people.
Marie-Pierre, Suzanne, Gloria,
me, the Pope...
You couldn't care less!
You just put on an act.
You show off.
The rest doesn't mutter.
You've got a son you never see,
yet you criticize me!
You're too much!
Hold on a second! My son's been
in Canada for nearly 20 years!
I don't even know him!
That suits you fine!
- How can you say that?
- I believe it!
If I said my mother had died...
you'd say: "Oh, really?"
When I told you about Poul,
you didn't listen!
You don't cure about my new job!
Yet I asked for your opinion
three times!
You don't care about
anybody or anything!
You're still angry?
It's partly true, isn't it?
Some of it.
But I'm not that bad.
Don't bow too low as you come in!
Hello! How are you?
I followed you because you weren't
at class on Tuesday.
I saw you as I arrived today...
But you were leaving!
So, right away,
I did a U-turn and almost had
an accident. I tried to follow
but those buses go fast!
I'm in a new classroom now.
That explains it.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Since you didn't answer my letter...
What letter?
You didn't get it?
No.
You wrote to me?
Yes.
Well...
What did you say?
It's hard to explain here...
I said that I'd like to see you...
more often than every 17 years.
Because I'm really...
attracted to you.
It's easier to write about
than to say...
Mind if I walk with you?
Not at all. I have to pick up
some things at home.
My former home, that is.
I'm divorcing. It's my fault.
He said he'd be out.
The other day at the school,
someone picked you up.
That was him. He came to say
he'd be away 3 days
and that I was wicked.
I already knew that.
You're here?
Yeah,
I didn't go away after all.
This is my friend Alex.
Alex, this is Francois.
Her husband.
I'll only be a minute...
The Reynolds are back from the USA.
They've invited us to dinner.
I guess they haven't heard.
- What shall I say?
- Whatever you like.
- Taking those, too?
- What?
My dad's books.
He gave them to me.
Can you lend me a hand, Alex?
Goodbye.
Bye.
Give me that!
Give it back!
Stop it!
If you wont the books, take them!
He makes prefab homes?
I saw the plans.
Yes, for the time being.
He's in good shape.
That's quite a right hook he has...
I tried a classic party but...
What's a classic party?
You don't know?
You dodge and turn...
But it's tough with a suitcase.
He got me.
Not hard, but it hurts.
You're bleeding.
Here.
- This is...
- To stop the bleeding.
Leave it on 5 minutes.
- When do you start work?
- Now!
Fancy a drink?
No, thank you.
Upper Volta
Wells in the desert
Is this him?
Who?
The divorce by your fault...
ls he your fault?
I don't mean to pry.
Yes, he's the one.
I feel like a drink.
Where is that?
In Upper Volta.
Yes, it says so.
An important guy...
I read the article.
They go over there...
to improve the land.
I wish I could too...
Not that I'd be able to...
That's Margot. This is her place.
You've met her.
The English teacher. Hello.
I picked up the laundry.
Did you bring the car back?
No. The cops had clamped it.
I don't believe it!
I'm late. You know
you're on the list for England?
Yes, I know.
Did Jean call?
What a bastard!
I have to run.
Your coat?
No coat.
What's the list for England?
We rotate:
2 days there, 3 days here.
You never wrote me that letter.
I tried
but it was difficult.
Shall I cull you or...
l'll call you.
The sausage was for table 8!
I got it all wrong!
You wanteda salad!
I'll be right back.
The sausage for the lady.
Enjoy your meal.
Don't forget my Saumur!
- Telephone.
- Right away.
The salad for table 1!
Claire...
No, not at all!
I finish in about 2 hours.
Are the coffees ready?
- Alex!
- Coming.
Where's my Saumur?
It's right here!
What's Francis doing?
He's resting while Coco takes over.
I'm training Coco as night chef.
He's temperamental but he's the best.
Bravo! Keep it up!
It's your fault, Mr. Mazet!
I know. Maxime, that's 8 coffees!
I need a clean shirt.
There's one in my locker...
I know it's not your neck size.
I'll wear it open.
The problem's the sleeves.
Use rubber bands.
How's it going with Marie-Pierre?
What about her?
Since the other day,
I'm afraid you'll bite my head off
if I mention her!
We're heading for the rocks.
But don't worry.
But I do worry.
Damn! No rubber bands!
I've got some.
Why not sleep at her place?
When?
One night... Tonight, say!
Tonight?
I didn't let her know.
That's just it. If you go tonight,
you'll surprise her.
If she's surprised, she'll worry.
If she's worried,
she'll feel reassured.
- What are you looking for?
- Women.
Do many come here?
Here? No, never!
Am I the first?
Yes.
My father!
Yes, at the wedding.
What were you doing there?
My job: entertaining.
Here's Jeannette, in slacks.
And Armand...
And the guy you had a fight with.
I had a fight?
Gilbert.
How's Monsieur Gilbert today?
It's pouring outside.
We just had a big fight.
On account of her sister.
Not the one you know.
The bossy one.
At first, Marie-Pierre was delighted.
But I forgot; no school today,
so the kids were in our bed.
What a madhouse!
You didn't give me time.
Hello!
Come and say hello.
Gilbert.
So this is Gilbert.
Claire.
Sit down.
I can't.
I've got to make a phone call.
Is it ruining?
Take my coffee.
I'll make some more.
I see you're using the...
Yes. I shouldn't have?
Sure, it's all right.
- The what?
- Never mind.
I want to know!
These cups are...
They're a gift from his mother.
We never use them.
It's the first time...
You should hurry up
and make your call.
Excuse me.
You left your light on.
- I didn't.
- You did.
Finish my coffee now.
How big is this plot? An acre?
A little over an acre.
I checked the land register.
Your land starts at the fence
and goes to those trees.
My neighbour's built on his land.
He's in a different zoning district.
You should've sold it long ago.
You can't build,
so why hold onto a patch of sand?
I know. But no thanks.
Going back to Paris?
Shall I tell them you'll rent it?
No thanks, Mr Gallois.
Can't I say you're not sure?
If you want. It's just us easy.
It was more like a fun park.
- My brother run it.
- Where is he now?
No idea. I'll give you
Sangali's address. He's the expert.
He's got the equipment
and the know-how.
Maurice, bring me my address book.
Never mind! I've got it.
Got u pen?
Sangali's a big shot now.
He's with Vassard in Brussels.
Telephone: 288-80-09.
Over here, the wobble bridge.
Impossible to stand up!
It's hilarious!
There, the magic house.
In between, the swings
and next to them...
the trampoline.
Next, a slide and super-slide.
And by the road,
rental of tandems, tridems
and even a bike for five.
A bicycle with square wheels
for solos!
You said they were oval.
I did? Well, oval or "crazy wheels".
And you end up at the magic house.
There's Sangali.
- Are you Alex?
- That's me!
Weren't you in Brussels?
No, I was in the area.
Did you get the catalogue?
- Well?
- This is the plot. It's small...
But that fence can be pushed buck.
My neighbour miscalculated.
It's my land up to those trees.
It's a long story.
The first 2 years,
he wouldn't tell his wife.
It drove me mud.
So I took another lover on the side.
I was happy.
It made me feel special.
That went on for a year.
Did Gilbert know?
Yes, he knew.
What got me was when I broke oft
with the other guy...
I was pregnant.
Do you have kids?
No.
Why not?
Maybe no one cured enough.
Anyhow, I told Gilbert,
"I'm sure it's yours.
I know it is."
He was wonderful.
He never doubted me.
He asked no questions and yet...
You're nuts,
taking your socks off in winter.
Know what winter is?
You don't know, do you?
Paul!
I don't believe it...
Crazy kid!
You're gonna get it!
What are you doing, Gilbert?
I'm fishing!
I'll give you what for!
We open July 1
and close August 31: 2 months.
Before and after, zilch!
We need a permit to stay open
after 10 pm for adults.
The bar's the real money-maker.
Sandwiches, hotdogs, etc.
The problem is the neighbour
because of the noise.
But since he's encroaching on
my land, there's a solution.
We'll trade:
I get my permit and he keeps
his rhododendrons.
- What does he want?
- Your sandwich.
Don't provoke him!
I'm not provoking him.
Stray dogs can be dangerous.
Surely we can talk?
When do you open?
I don't know.
Not this summer but the next.
Why not this summer?
It's 3 months away.
The construction work takes time.
I'll need help.
You can't get that?
I don't know...
I can't think with this dog.
Can't someone call him off?
Here kitty, kitty...
Come on.
Nice kitty... Come here.
- How's things?
- Hi, Francis.
I saw Armand.
Why don't you visit him?
He knocks it back,
with his diabetes...
I know.
- Your call, Alex!
- Thanks. Michel! Finish up.
Maxime, an espresso!
Another?
Hello, Sangali? Alex.
I'm calling to tell you...
We're all set to go!
We open this summer.
In July.
You can't mean that!
Why not?
It's up to you.
I'm ready right now!
About that first installment...
How much?
Is that negotiable?
Good. Call me back soon.
That's fine. Goodbye.
What a surprise!
How are you?
And Richard?
It's over.
Was it you or him?
Him.
How about that...
He must be nuts!
I'm broke. I need to find a job.
So I'm looking around.
I heard Monique was about
to quit the checkroom.
So I got my hopes up...
She changed her mind.
Her modeling career fizzled out.
What about Clovis?
He won't be back till Wednesday.
Coming!
I've got to run.
So long...
See you soon.
There's a hitch.
I just spoke to Sangali.
We can get the equipment.
We'll use the demo models
from a trade show.
The trouble is...
they want money.
A lot of it...
- An oil bottle's broken.
- Tell Denis.
Aren't you eating?
I am...
I can accept the fact
that you dumped me.
But why didn't you tell me?
It's not that hard.
It is.
I should have figured it out.
You never came by, didn't answer
my letters or phone calls.
And when I called Maxime,
he said you were at the sea.
But I was!
Anyway, I'm grateful to you
for coming by.
- Don't you want your beer?
- Sure.
You have another woman?
Yes.
Younger than me?
That's not the reason.
- Do I know her?
- Let's not discuss her!
Why not,
since we can't talk about us?
And I was about to get a divorce...
A divorce?
Did I hear you right?
Divorce Victor?
Did you tell him?
Not yet.
You were always praising
his devotion, his kindness...
Victor, compared to...
even to me...
And you're going to destroy him
after 25 years?
I can't believe
what I'm hearing, Gloria.
I must be mistaken.
How do you mean?
This can't be you.
Not my Gloria.
That's not the Gloria I knew...
It can't be.
I'm sorry.
Right now, I've got problems.
Well, everybody's got problems!
I can't sleep.
So I'm tense, I'm jittery.
You've got problems?
Yes.
Not vital problems,
just money problems.
But they really get you down.
I'll be going.
No, tell me.
Do you know about my fun pork?
No.
That's why
I was out of town.
I have to find 100,000 francs
or else.
I know, it's u tidy sum...
I can lend you that much.
What? You?
- Why you?
- I can afford it.
Think about it.
Just when we're splitting up...
Never mind, I want to.
Be quiet.
I'll sign for it.
- No need to.
- I insist.
I, the undersigned...
I'll pay interest.
Or else I refuse. I mean it!
- Shall we go?
- I'm ready.
- Your bug?
- It's behind you.
- When's the plane?
- AT 6:30.
- Are you OK?
- Great!
My banker lent me the money.
- How much?
- Ten!
- With surety?
- No surety. After you...
What a businessman!
A barracuda!
Mind you,
these little London trips...
2 days here, 3 days there...
Sometimes, I wonder.
You wonder what?
If you're meeting him there.
He's not always in Upper Volta.
I could meet him here too.
That's true.
Him or someone else.
As they say...
If it's not him, it's his brother.
But that's a vicious circle.
What a joke!
But I don't feel like laughing.
Our life here is absurd.
- Are you cold?
- No.
Yes, you are!
I'm not!
I need some air.
I stifle when she's not home.
She never is.
Poor Jeannette!
Poor thing!
She rushes to work before I wake!
She dashes buck at noon.
We bolt down our lunch!
When she visits those flats,
she forgets I'm alive!
Though I don't mind her
helping out a friend.
Afternoons, she's busy
with Pierre, Poul and whoever.
It's as if I had no wife!
You've got me.
What an idiot...
Wait.
She said she'd see you at noon.
It is noon. Raymond.
So long.
I won't see you out.
- You don't deserve it.
- Bye, Gilbert.
Gilbert, I rely on you
to make him come here.
He's a lousy friend!
I promise.
Nice place!
Two small rooms,
with a communicating door...
I've got the key somewhere.
Looks nice.
It's up to Marie-Pierre.
I didn't tell you.
My divorce is set.
Suzanne's a new woman.
She's being cooperative.
- I didn't know.
- Now you do!
Here we are.
I can show you 2 more places...
Without me. I have to be
in Brussels by 3 pm.
One in this building
and a smaller one next door.
Personally, I prefer it.
And this is the monkey barrel.
You'll see.
No! 45% isn't 50%...
It's second-hand stuff.
At 50%, our margin is really small.
What do you say, Mme Pierreux?
To be honest, we never deal that way.
I've got to run now.
Frank will pay.
We'll go for 50%,
but in two payments instead of three.
And cash, us agreed.
You can have the cash right now...
I wont to go home
with a signed contract.
That's fine
but all the papers are at my place.
Will you excuse me?
Certainly.
Goodbye, Jacques.
Goodbye, Madame Pierreux.
Are you related to the Pierreux
of the Pacra Concerts?
You have nice hands.
A drink?
Let's have one at my place.
Fine.
Do you live alone?
For now, I do.
In fact, I'm scared.
Of what? Of wolves?
Some wolves!
It depends which ones.
Calm down, guys!
That's enough.
I didn't go home last night.
The cur broke down.
It's the clutch.
I gave them notice.
I quit tonight.
Already?
I'm going to Bariollet's.
Starting tomorrow.
Don't read over my shoulder.
I can't concentrate.
Don't forget...
The mayor and town council!
The "Bordelaise"...
For the gentleman.
- André!
- Sorry.
- Enjoy your meal.
- Thank you.
"Awaiting your approval
"and the agreement
of the town council for my permit..."
ls that ok?
- Fine.
- Wait, I'm not finished.
What's this I hear?
Gilbert is leaving?
Tonight?
I don't get it.
Bariollet's offering me a job
as maitre d'.
- A toast?
- Not now...
Tonight, before dinner.
Do you mind chatting someplace else?
Bariollet has women chefs.
You'll miss your pal Francis.
I yell but I don't shriek!
Hello.
There was a strike.
A plane strike?
No, I flew back.
At the school.
- You're on holiday then?
- Yes.
How did it go?
Just great!
I'll spare you the boring details
but I'm all set to go.
Aren't you cold?
You got back late?
I called at midnight.
No answer.
Same thing at 2 am and 3 um.
I was at Sangali's.
We dined there - the whole family...
father, mother, kids...
an endless dinner...
Coffee, liqueurs...
It was so late, I slept there.
I left early this morning.
I should've called you.
It was thoughtless of me.
Were you worried?
What could have happened to me?
Another woman.
She left you a message.
I don't understand.
That's impossible.
Claire, it's Margot.
Call me when you get back.
Hello, Claire. Ronnie Sharp.
Thursday's meeting
is pushed back to 8:30 pm.
Alex, it's me.
It's Gloria!
Just to tell you...
I told Victor everything.
Even the cheque.
I feel better and so does he.
We're inking u trip.
I won't write.
Take care.
It was Gloria.
She's a friend.
A woman friend. Before you...
When you live alone,
you flutter around.
Do you miss that?
What's she like?
A brunette...
She used to be very beautiful.
She's been married 25 years.
Very dynamic.
What else can I say?
You still see her?
I saw her recently.
She lent me that money.
She was the banker.
But I hadn't called her since.
Not since you.
She asked me to explain
and I explained.
What?
That I was in love.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I feel tired all of a sudden.
To our friend, the maitre d' to be!
As the actress said to the bishop,
"It depends where you put it!"
You'll be married this year,
Gilbert!
It's Jeannette.
Hello, Jeannette?
We're all eating with Jeannette.
How did it happen?
He was alone when he died.
He had an attack.
He needed medicine,
so Jeannette run out to get some.
By the time she got buck...
No, back up.
No, he has to pull instead.
There's no talking to him.
Come on!
Is that ok?
Down there, Maurice!
Walk straight, Martel.
I thought...
We got here last night.
Seen all this?
By tonight, the slides will be up.
You're back from London?
I never left.
Is he back?
He called several times.
I didn't want to see him again.
This time, I called him.
I lied to you.
You didn't,
since you're telling me.
You're leaving with him?
Yes.
I knew it would happen one day but...
I'm not stupid, you know.
I've always been aware
of the difference between us.
I'm nothing.
You mustn't say that, Alex.
I never thought that.
You're you!
You didn't take me.
I wanted you and I took you.
Because of what you are,
who you are.
It's not your fault.
It's him.
He's back from Upper Volta.
How did you know?
I took the trouble to find out.
I thought: even if we go
to the end of the world,
he'll be there
digging those wells.
I'm going to make a phone cull.
Is that his wife?
No idea.
Remember to ship
the crane tomorrow!
Are you going to work
with him over there?
I don't know.
I don't want to talk about it now.
I'll see.
- Where's Alex?
- Over there.
We'll do it without him then.
Did you take your things yet?
I'll pick them up tonight.
Maybe l'll make u play for Margot.
I don't recommend it.
Can you lunch with us?
Sure.
Careful: 1, 2, 3!
We can't find the bolts!
What's up?
We can't find the swing bolts.
- What bolts?
- For the axles.
Just ask Sangali.
Where is he?
He's gone.
- Where?
- To find a phone.
- To call who?
- I don't know.
Here are the bolts!
Use your eyeglasses.
What about the swings?
We'll finish them.
When will you be finished?
Just remember, I paid cash!
- Excuse me.
- Thank you.
Enjoy it!
Did you hear the racing results?
- No.
- Can you read?
In the right order.
Patience triumphs over confusion.
I'd like to invite you
to dine on my winnings.
Monday, at Lasserre.
Just us two, Francis,
Gilbert, Urbain and Maurice.
About 675 square feet.
2 rooms and a bathroom.
I need about half that.
Yes, for instance.
Excuse me, I'll be right back.
I came for my lamp and the table.
- You told me to stop by.
- Come in.
See? It's all there.
You've lost weight.
Think so?
Are you ok?
Yes.
Don't you miss me?
A little.
Are you settled in?
Hello? I'm sorry.
Come by anytime.
The janitor has the key.
Were you passing by?
Yes.
Why didn't you come up?
I'm on my own now.
I know.
You're in a bad way?
I'm broke, I'm out of work,
I'm pregnant and I'm alone.
I'm just fine!
I've been drinking.
I don't know where to go.
What do you mean?
What about my place?
Take Gilbert's room.
You'll keep me company.
But I'm moving in September.
When's the baby due?
In three months.
I'll have to evict you both then!
I'll be merciless!
Here. In the meantime...
Let me in.
I don't have a spare.
Have this gentleman taste it.
I already tasted the label.
Words fail me...
I'll stick to champagne.
It's not exactly
a neighbourhood bistro.
The atmosphere’s in the dish.
Nutmeg...
And the scallops?
I can't analyze each mouthful.
We're hereto enjoy this.
To appreciate it.
That's a sin!
That's why it's so good.
Light it for him.
How cold is the champagne here?
5.5° C.
- How do you know?
- I'm a regular.
It's magnificent, Maxime!
I'm not much good at speeches
but thanks for being my friends.
- What a crowd!
- It' might rain later.
Hello.
Sorry, I won't shake your hand...
She's my sister.
Can you mind the kids?
Sure. Going for a swim?
But no more than an hour.
Watch out!
Does it hurt?
We'll put a big bandage on.
Take him.
If they amputate, call me.
Damn it!
Get off my back!
What's wrong with them?
Can't you see I'm fixing it!
Just wait. Go away, get off!
- Can we help?
- No!
Alex?
I want to kiss you goodbye.
Already?
Yes. Maurice is driving me buck.
We have to get going.
I start early tomorrow.
You'll learn to swim?
I take my lesson every day.
Cull me when you get there.
Be careful! She's fragile!
Francis, the tarps!
I declare this a disaster urea!
Lights! Lights!
A restoration carried our
by Eclair Group on the image
and by LE. Diapason on the sound
with the support of the (NC