In lane 7,
Suzuki, of Tadano
Boys High School.
In lane 8, Tsuchiya
of Kitahara Academy.
On your mark!
No way!
Hurry up and get out!
Huh?
The next routine.
It has already started!
WATERBOYS
Suzuki
You monster!
See for yourself, our swim team's so
pathetic, it's been this way awhile.
We're down to one last senior,
a wimp named Suzuki.
But it's time for him to quit.
If nobody new comes along,
we won't have a swim team.
Good morning.
I'm Sakuma Megumi.
I'll be joining the staff today.
I'm a newcomer here, and I look
forward to your cooperation.
I know Tadano High is really
serious about sports.
My own...
My own training...
Excuse me.
My own training is that
I swam through college,
so I'll be coaching the swim team.
Unfortunately, it's a one-man
show right now,
so if any of you are interested...
Suzuki! Eliminated in the preliminaries?
Weren't you gonna quit?
Shut up, you just got hurt and
quit basketball, right?
I can't play in games anymore,
so of course I chose swimming.
Ikeuchi from Karate,
Sakamoto from Gymnastics.
Even Mochizuki from Track.
All quitters with
nothing better to do.
And that skinny nerd is Ota Yuichi
Guess why he signed up...
And the kid drowning over there...
is Kanazawa Takashi.
Just decided to learn how to swim!
And that's Saotome.
Hey, he's got the hots for you.
Cut it out, it makes me sick.
We're really scraping
the bottom of the barrel, huh?
Sniffing around like hyenas.
What the hell!
I heard that!
Wow, look how many
of you turned up.
Her skin's so delicate.
She's damn cute.
Aren't you going to get in?
Show us something.
What's your favorite stroke?
Let me rub your back.
One thing we do
have is muscles!
Yes... but...
But what but?
You wouldn't be interested.
Because I...
Miss Sakuma san!
What's wrong?
What'd they do to you?
I wouldn't get
too near those guys.
I'm sorry.
I knew it, I just can't
teach at this school.
Why not?
I didn't...
know they were sending me
to an all-boys school.
Don't say that.
Girls, boys, who cares.
That's right, miss!
We're all beginners here anyway.
Tell us anything.
You can count on us.
We want you to teach us, right?
Yeah!
Really?
Real synchronized swimmers perform
in deep pools, but we'll manage.
I can't believe I got
stuck on that tiny detail.
All that chlorine must
have gone to my brain.
The truth is, I got super depressed
when I heard this was a boys school.
I've always dreamed of
coaching my own team.
Why can't boys do it?
OK, I've made up my mind.
Let's all go for it.
Synchro swim!
Man, can you believe
the mess we're in?
Don't start!
I just wanted regular swimming...
Liar, you don't care
if you swim or not.
I do too! I have to
learn to stay afloat.
Wow, scary! What are you
so pissed about, you geek!
Don't call me a geek!
Hey, stop it!
Wait.
How come you want to swim so bad?
Because the math doesn't work.
The relative human weight is less
than the volume of water,
which has to create buoyancy.
Besides,
the logic of fluid mechanics suggests
stroking water will propel one forward...
And a 1, 2, 3, 4
5, 6, 7, 8
2, 2, 3, 4
Those fools are
really gonna do it.
Bunch of idiots!
Synchro Swim Team, yes.
Yes, yes, my Synchro
Swim Team.
And a 1, 2, 3, 4
5, 6, 7, 8
Hey, Pavlov! Quiet.
What's that?
We premier at the
Tadano High School Festival.
What!
If we're going to practice,
might as well have an audience.
I've left the date open
intentionally.
And those letters should
be bolder, brighter.
But leave the details for later.
All right, here we go!
Yup, we can do plenty
even with just 5 of you.
I'm so happy I could just...
My heart is pounding.
I'm... ill...
Must be the thrill.
I mean, I thought
my period was late...
And my stomach,
I thought I was bloated...
Never dreamed I was 8 months!
Oh, this is my husband.
Hello.
I'm so sorry, but I have
to take a little maternity leave.
You've got to ace
that Tadano Fest, OK?
Our annual Tadano Fest
is on the second weekend
after summer vacation.
It's the only time we ever
get girls from Sakuragi
and the other all-girls
high schools to visit,
so you guys better come up
with good ideas.
This year, we want to nab
300 Sakuragi girls!
Let's see...
Early on, the swim team
put in a bid to perform
their synchronized swim.
If you're still good for it,
I'll put it on the program.
The basketball team gets the
pool for fly fishing.
But, um...
It's too late now, right?
Late for what?
We're stuck with the
synchronized thing, right?
No, not at all.
The program's totally open.
Oh, really?
In that case, we'll bow out.
OK then, the basketball
team gets the pool as usual.
Damn, check out those
Sakuragi High girls.
That was a close call.
We almost got stuck
synchro swimming.
Besides, who the hell wants to
watch guys synchro swim?
It only makes you barf.
But what do we tell Sakuma...
No sweat, man.
She's busy havin' that baby.
She'll forget.
What are we gonna do now?
Let's study,
we still have to get into college.
Oh, right.
We gotta study.
Listen, I guess...
Excellent!
Full panty sighting!
I guess we can't really
synchro swim...
Totally impossible, and besides,
they were never serious.
Just a bunch of horny geeks.
And then she takes maternity leave.
The worst.
You know they're gonna flake out.
They're hopeless no matter what
they do, just hopeless.
Let's bet whether they do it or not.
Sure, 1,000 yen they won't.
3,000 yen.
Somebody bet on them
or we're not betting at all.
What a shock.
What?
What the...
Hey wait! We're gonna
use the pool after all.
Too late, the fish guy already
put all the fish in.
Don't be that way, man.
We're old basketball buddies.
Basketball, huh!
You're such a total flake,
you never made the team.
Now your teacher's run out on you!
You didn't get injured in a game?
The way he cut practice?
Never.
Don't ever mention
our team again!
Well, I don't know what
all the flap is about,
but if you get all the fish out,
I can just take 'em home again.
Go ahead.
No way we can do that!
Cool! If you guys catch all
the fish, the pool is yours.
You swear!
Goddammit!
It's never gonna work.
Stop.
Quit yakking and help.
Some swim team!
Emptying the pool is OK, but whose
gonna pay for the fresh water?
No, I watched 'em do it before.
This water meter's busted.
You can rig it.
Get in, Sato.
No way, you go!
Better hurry or they'll die.
Goddammit!
Bunch of idiots.
I'm going home.
Man, you're a downer.
If you just did it,
it'd be over.
If you're gonna fart around,
you don't need me.
What are you doing!
Wait!
Don't run!
Look.
Guess it's time we
called your parents.
Oh, no, please.
So, what are you
gonna do about it!
Pay you back out of our
synchro take at the Festival.
How can I count on that!
Synchro? You mean
synchronized swimming?
You guys?
No, no, that's a matter of...
Yes we are!
For real? Are you guys good
enough to charge admission?
We'll start practicing.
Well, let's have a look, then.
And then we'll decide.
You're on!
We'll show you in a week.
Hey, Sato!
A week, then.
But the water.
You guys emptied it.
I don't know how serious you are,
but if you are,
figure it out yourselves.
Sir.
Yeah.
How high's the water bill?
About like that.
Um, actually, your
math's a little off.
25 meters long
by 13 meters wide,
by 1.3 deep, so
Actually, it's more.
Synchronized Swim Tickets
-500 Yen
Who's swimming?
We are.
Oh, I'm sorry, I really am.
Can't sell one lousy ticket!
Oh, I know, maybe you should
try selling them at that place.
What!
Huh...
You could just buy one ticket.
Just enough for the water bill.
Otherwise, we can't even practice.
Will one of you promise
to come work here
after you graduate?
Why not start today.
Just joking!
Say ladies, these boys are
synchro artists for the Tadano Fest.
You boys are so cute,
I'll buy 10.
I run a host club, I'll buy
a stack, a whole stack.
Thank goodness!
He's so cute!
Oh dear, he's crying.
What are you crying about?
Here goes.
What are we
supposed to do?
Bent knee pose
Bend one leg, and
tuck the toes of the bent leg
behind the opposite knee.
That's easy.
Next, then, Ballet leg pose.
Straighten the leg into the air.
Raise your hips and bend the
opposite leg for the Flamingo pose.
Hey, easy, easy!
Bent knee, Ballet leg,
Flamingo.
Bent knee, Ballet leg, Flamin...
Hey, wait!
Bent knee, Ballet...
I got a cramp!
Huh?
Outta the way!
How's the synchro coming?
Who knows, I sure don't.
Are they serious, or what?
What's the...
Are you sure?
Huh?
Yeah.
What's up with that?
Let's check 'em out.
I don't see 'em.
Oh, no, they're here.
What are they doing here!
Oh, shit.
We gotta do it.
Already?
Oh, shit, time out, time out.
Dammit to hell!
What, what happened!
How do I look?
Who gives a damn!
What the hell are you doing!
Why do you always flake out!
Can it! You use this stupid thing
but you can't pose!
What was that! You jerk!
Don't blame me!
You weren't supposed
to jump in!
But my string broke.
Your wave crashed into me!
Stop wearing
that dumb thing!
Stop crying!
You queen!
What the hell are you guys doing!
You can't do this at the Festival!
As of today, the pool's off limits!
So you'll pay my damages...
I'm calling your parents now!
Buncha losers!
Stupid idiots!
Your summer vacation
starts tomorrow,
so take care of yourselves
and practice moderation.
The Tadano Festival's
coming up after vacation,
and I'm sure some of you will
come to school to prepare.
However...
For you seniors, it's
time to give up sports
and study for
your college exams.
For those of you planning
to take the Standardized Exam,
as you see on the board, for
English, it's Standardized English,
and for math, we recommend
Standardized Math.
And as for Japanese...
What is this!
Bam!
That's the trick.
Here.
Oh, um, thank you...
Oh, that...
Here.
Indirect kiss!
I'm Shizuko from
Sakuragi High.
Oh, I'm...
You're Suzuki from
Tadano, right?
What? How'd you...
I've always had a crush on you.
Will you go out with me?
What!
Oh, um... okay.
You guys are
getting all steamy.
Busting the air conditioner.
Ditch that weirdo,
come play with us.
Don't!
Let her go.
She's upset.
Will you marry me?
You're Suzuki
from Tadano, right?
What? How'd you...
Suzuki - Tadano High
Karate!
Nice!
My brothers took me,
ever since I was little.
I assumed all families
had tile cracking contests.
But not likely, right?
And you?
Oh, synchro.
What?
Oh, synchro-songwriter club.
That's so cool!
Just keep walking.
What?
There's a really weird guy
behind us who's been staring.
It is you, Suzuki.
What?
Don't recognize me out of drag?
Oh, Mama san from the bar...
You know him?
Sort of.
I see you're not wasting any time.
How are ticket sales?
Oh, yes, well, so.
Looking forward to
that Tadano Fest, take care.
And who was that?
Just someone I know.
Huh.
What are you doing at the Festival?
I wanna watch, can I come see?
No, it's not really
set yet or anything.
We might not even do it.
Make up your mind.
Like I said, I don't know...
I myself plan
to try really hard, but...
Like you're a guy and all,
but you synchro?
I told you I quit!
How way, way, uncool.
Join our band for the Festival.
It's the best way to get girls.
That's right, even
this jerk got a girlfriend.
What was that!
You don't like aquariums?
Why didn't you tell me?
No, it's not really that...
It's always something with you!
Make up your mind!
I do have a tendency
to get carried away...
It's no big deal, OK?
Giddiyup.
Giddiyup, Giddyup.
Thank you.
Thank you, thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls.
Grandpas or grandmas.
Today's show is now over.
Dolphins are so cool!
Ouch! Ouch, ouch, ouch.
Um, excuse me.
Huh?
Oh, you're that synchro squirt.
This area's closed to spectators.
Please, teach us! How can
we put on a show like that!
Are you crazy?
I use dolphins.
Whole different universe from synchro.
But I want to move like that.
Ridiculous.
I'll do anything!
I'll practice anything!
The way we are...
is so pathetic.
Moving freely in the
water is no mean feat.
You got what it takes!?
Yes...
Probably.
No probablys.
Then promise you'll
do anything I say.
Ota.
Is that your best!
You can do better, I know it.
Now your deltoids.
Push yourself harder.
30 more seconds.
Muscles! OK, let's go!
Good, nice work-out.!
Sato! Sato!
Hey, man!
What are you doing here!
Let's swim, man.
Are you nuts? There's no way.
The pool's off limits.
We hijack the pool on Festival day.
We train at the aquarium.
Aquarium?
That fish guy's going to
teach us stuff.
Our finest days of high school.
It's so dorky, just give it up.
You'll wind up looking dumb.
You really are the worst.
I hate myself, too.
Driver! Please!
So you made it.
You synchro squirts!
You make them leap?
Of course not,
are you nuts?
They get all excited when they
see me 'cause I mean food.
There you go, there.
Leave your stuff and come down.
Move it!
Thank you for visiting
Sea World today.
What is this?
Dunno... ouch.
What's this fish called?
I'm sorry, I'm not sure.
Idiot!
What are you doing!
Hurry or we'll leave you here.
Idiot! Idiot! Idiot!
Polish the plate glass till it gleams.
And I mean spotless!
You've got until morning,
when we open again.
Um...
"Anything I say," remember?
What the hell's going on, Suzuki?
Not me! I came here to practice
synchro, not wash windows!
Wow, look at those eels.
They sure look tasty.
Don't eat them.
I won't.
There's squid over here!
And crab over there.
This aquarium's just like a sushi bar.
Yeah.
Seafood Buffet
All you can eat
Odllayee odllayee hee hoo
Tuna belly, abalone, squid
All you can eat
Ark shell, mackerel, salmon roe
and shrimp, All you can eat
We did it! We really did it!
Thanks squirts.
Looks good.
Tomorrow you'll hit that tank.
What?
Finally...
We did it...
We did it! We did it!
Good morning
Welcome to Sea World.
Outta here!
Hey, hey.
What's this weird fish called?
An Elephant Nose.
And that one?
Tiger Oatfish.
A Nautilus.
A Dragonfish.
Trinecties Maculatus, Melanotaenia.
Need a tour guide?
Oh, no, that's alright.
Something odd about those kids.
It's already been two weeks.
How long do we have to do this?
Summer vacation'll be over.
Maybe he tricked us.
Oops, I'm sorry, sorry.
Dammit!
This pool's for the dolphins!
You said you'd coach us,
so we came.
But it's hard labor everyday.
You're just a slave driver!
Shut up! You cleaned all the tanks?
Yes.
What? All of 'em?
Even the fresh water fish?
Yes, we're finished.
You've got to tell
us what's going on.
Do we just stare at fish and polish
tanks or are you going to teach us?
Show me your arms.
OK, next.
OK, try the Bottle Nose Dolphin.
Huh?
Move like a dolphin.
In the water, dammit!
Scull with your hands to stay in place.
If you can't do that, all
your training's been wasted!
You call that training!
Shut up! You don't like it, you
hustle your butts outta here!
Damn.
That doesn't even count as basic!
OK, next!
After Bottle Nose Dolphin, do
Sea Otter, Squid and Flamingo.
Finally, do the Nautilus Roll!
Bottle Nose Dolphin.
Sea Otter.
Squid.
Flamingo.
Nautilus.
You can swim!
You did it!
Yeah.
We really were learning.
What do we practice next?
Huh? Lots of stuff.
What do you know?
OK, here we are.
Get out.
Slept like a log.
Where are we?
My butt hurts.