Wait!
Somebody told me,
love is like waiting for a bus.
The one that arrives isn't
the one you expected.
And when the one
you expected arrives,
there will be obstacles blocking
the way to get on it.
This happens all the time.
I've had a crush on Ohm
since elementary school.
This love seems impossible,
but I still had hope,
no matter how many years pass by.
However, our story finally ended,
because Ohm went out with Pam.
They decided to study abroad together.
But my life has to go on.
I later moved to study in Bangkok,
Hoping that I could fall in love
with someone.
But I don't have any feeling toward any.
Maybe,
I'm still waiting for Ohm.
Jane
Get out of your meditation.
Our shop is crowded.
What's going on, you two creatures?
While you were meditating,
did you see that
the executive presiding
at the party tonight
is damn...
hot.
Stop it.
I'm in hibernate mode,
on "male" diet.
Here he comes.
He's cool!
Ohm.
I know this is ridiculous,
but it's not anymore.
Now, he comes back to my life again.
I've never imagined this moment before,
but now it's real.
Sa, right?
I thought you still live in London.
After I finished BA from Harvard.
I went for MA at Oxford.
Then I came back to Thailand.
Urgent,
- and...
- And you're alone?
Yes. I'm alone.
I've just come back and
too busy to make new friend.
I just arrived.
Can I have your number?
If love is like waiting for a bus
I think it's worth every minute.
It may takes years,
but my bus arrives now.
I'll get on this bus and begin my journey.
"First Kiss"
Focus on your work,
I'll call you later.
Yes.
Bye-bye.
There is dog hair on your shirt.
I told you this dog is losing hair
and you still wanted to hold it.
Where?
Over there.
Let me help.
Kiss?
Concentrate on your work.
I'll give you a call.
Go to work.
When he dropped you off,
I saw everything.
Guilty as charged!
Bitch! Slut!
You seduced him.
True.
But I like it.
You slutty!
You know first kiss is very important.
It foresees the future
between you and your lover.
I broke up with my ex-boyfriend
because of the first kiss.
His tongue is so big.
When I pressed my lips with his,
his saliva was all over my mouth.
It made me feels like
kissing a bulldog.
The point is if your first kiss is good,
it's possible that
your relation would went well.
That's right.
Good luck.
Let's go to work.
I'm glad you're with me here
at Phu Thab Berg.
I'd love to be with you anywhere.
Sa...
I love you.
Accident!
I gave a signal.
Don't you see?
You ruined my Phu Thab Berg.
What Phu Thab Berg, auntie?
What's wrong with you?
Pull over, I'll get off here.
We need to talk.
You punk.
Hope I never see your face again, psycho!
Stop, please!
I'll get off this stop.
No passenger allow to leave
outside bus stop, auntie.
What did you?!
What did you call me?
A psycho?
Do I really look psycho to you?
You are the one who...
Hey, stop it!
Shut up, you punk!
...Kiss me.
I didn't intend to kiss you.
I'm sorry.
You didn't intend to?
Then, why do you say sorry?
I don't know.
OK. That's my bad.
But I didn't intend to do that.
I did nothing.
Nothing?
Obviously, you kissed me.
Quiet!
We did have a kiss.
What else could I say?
You kissed me.
Kissed me. Kissed...
Hi.
Excuse me.
Did you have my cellphone?
Well...
Why did you kiss me?
Why did you steal my phone?
Why did you steal my cellphone,
you rascal?
You threw it to me, remember?
And then you ran away.
How could I give it back to you?
Whatever.
You better give it back to me now.
No!
You can't keep it.
It's mine!
Yes, I can.
I'll keep it as a compensation,
for you stole kiss me.
You have to pay me a lot more,
if there were any compensation.
Because you stole my first kiss.
What?
Am I really your first kiss?
How old are you?
You asshole.
If you won't give my phone back,
I'll meet you at you school and we'll see!
Anytime.
If you can find out where I study,
then, see me there.
Paramee with whatever surnames,
Please come to the disciplinary office.
What did you do?
Trouble.
Paramee Jindanin
Paramee Yiam ngamkul
Paramee Un Ruean
Paramee Opanunt
What am I doing wrong?
I've never been to the disciplinary office.
I always submit my homework.
What are you mourning for?
Huh?
That's him!
Paramee...
Do you steal her cellphone?
Yes, ma'am.
I caught him but
he refused to give it back.
Why did you do that?
Indeed.
I can't believe this kid dare stealing.
You must give her phone back now.
I got to say sorry for my student.
Never mind.
Paramee, for what you have done,
you have to be punished.
Come here.
Ma'am.
I don't think you have to do this.
I already get my phone back.
Everything's intact.
No.
He should be punished
for what he has done,
so he won't do it again.
Well...
Just sit and still hurt?
Haven't you been punished
when you were young?
Oh... you can't remember, right
because it's a long long time ago.
Cut it off!
I'm not that old.
Here.
What is it?
Herbal drug for old maid?
You dog breath!
Use it.
Auntie, how do you know my name?
And where I study?
Do you think I'm blind?
I just couldn't catch your last name.
By the way, stop calling me auntie!
Then, what do you want me to call?
Call me sister Sa.
Why I have to call you sister?
Can I call you Miss Sa?
No!
Call me sister.
I don't want to.
Between auntie Sa and Miss Sa,
what do you prefer?
All right! Miss Sa then!
- You're unbelievable, stupido!
- Bass.
My name is Bass.
Hello, Ohm.
Tomorrow?
I'm available.
The Chinese restaurant on Sukhumvit?
Yes, I remember that place.
What are you doing here?
What a small world?
Are you sure?
Such a coincidence.
I'll come and get it. Punk!
Yes,
I'll take care of it.
Thank you.
Sorry. It was my customer calling.
What is this, Bass?
Why this restaurant?
Don't you think it's too old?
But I think it fits your face.
How is it?
Why you call us to this restaurant?
I want to celebrate.
I've just realized that luck is on my side.
Peanut tastes great
if you pick it with love.
Thank you very much.
Sa...
I'm so glad that we've met again.
Garland?
Do you want it or not?
I think you should go to your room.
And I'll call you later.
All right.
- Thanks, Ohm.
- Yes.
Hey!
Garland, ma'am?
It's you?
Why you keep getting on my nerve?!
- How much do you want?!
- Stop!
Someone like me money can't buy.
So, what do you want?
Tomorrow, meet me here at ten.
And dress beautifully.
You'll go to the cinema with me because...
Are you crazy?
What kind of dress?
I said dress beautifully, didn't I?
This is the best I can.
The best dress for dating with you.
Look at that!
He's so cute.
Is he with his mom?
No way.
They don't look alike.
I don't think they're relative.
What do you think?
His girlfriend?
Gosh!
I'm sure she is his mother.
- They might have been Art & Craft Center.
- I guess.
That's why I told you to dress properly.
Do you wanna change?
You'd better dress appropriate next time.
Next time? There is no next time.
This is the only last time with you.
- So cute!
- Shouldn't have come with his mom.
What? What are you doing, huh?
I want to show you the trailer
before we enter a theater.
Wait, darling.
- This is better?
- Well, yes, it looks all right.
- Let me help.
- Let's go.
Pam?
What's wrong?
Nothing
I know Pam.
I see you date with her boyfriend,
So I brought you here to see it by yourself.
They are getting married.
Married?
Ohm is getting married?
I can't believe.
He seems really love you, Sa.
Have you talked to him?
Someone brings you this, Sa.
Who sent it?
Damn cheesy.
It's me.
Who are you?
- Go to lunch with me?
- Yes, sure!
Follow me.
Hey!
Make sure that
they won't catch you, all right?
You sneaky...
Bitch
I've just seen you cry for Ohm,
in a blink,
you get a new one.
- Food will be served at your table.
- Thank you.
- Evil!
- Slut!
Devil!
- Thank you.
Lady first.
Here you are.
Strong coffee.
Hey, you!
Why don't you introduce your friends?
This is Jane and Mham.
- Hello.
- Good to see you.
My colleagues
This is Bass.
Bass?
He is just a friend.
See him near by.
Why didn't I discover him first?
- You're Bass?
- Yes.
Can I play?
Well, yes.
Stop it.
Excuse me.
Give it to me. Over here.
Big wings indeed.
Cock-a-hoop.
- Let's eat!
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Please.
I want some.
Wicked!
He doesn't let her pick up the phone.
Great!
Don't even let her read his message.
Can I ask?
Is that my phone?
What are you doing?
Nothing.
It's not necessary to get that.
It's nonsense.
Was that Ohm?
She really makes me envy.
Why nobody fight for me?
Look at you face...
and decide why men would fight for you?
Just ignore it.
Finish your food, okay?
I gotta go now.
Have something to do.
Hey!
My cellphone is with him.
Yes.
He's gone.
Don't act innocent,
I know you lure him.
So deep.
Her scheme.
Out of my league.
They are just girls.
I'll hit on a woman like Khru Dao.
Who is she?
A new intern teacher.
She resembles my mom.
That's my type.
How come are you here?
Hello. I'm Sa.
I'm a senior in high school.
Oh I mean grade 12/4
What did you say?
Senior?
Se... Se... See you there!
Is she study at our school?
She doesn't look familiar.
She looks too old.
Look who's talking.
I've nurtured my skin
since I was a kid.
Damn!
By the way,
I'm not familiar with her.
How can you familiar?
She's not studying in our school.
Actually, she's already got a job.
But I'm hitting on her.
That's why she follows me here.
You the man.
See?
She's shy.
You pretty face boy!
Anyway, let me introduce,
Here is Sa.
This is Win and Art, my friends.
Hello.
Is he your uncle?
Why is he here?
Does he help you steal things?
How long have you been here?
What?
What long?
Pre-class assembly!
Go! Hurry!
- Yes.
- Hurry.
Run!
Hey!
Get it back to me.
Don't be so hurry.
Since you are here,
Let's have some fun.
Back in high school,
have you ever broken school's rule?
Do you wanna try?
Well...
Let's start from bulling you.
All right!
Let see then.
Sa... I'm sorry.
You... die!
Why did you hit me?
Have you ever skipped class?
What are you two doing?
Why don't you go to class?
Where you think you're going?
This way!
Where are you going?
I loved to spend time
in science lab during free class.
Why?
I don't think
it's a good place for relax.
- You're not afraid now?
- Acting.
Where do you love to go
when you skip class?
Mostly, I spent my time at music room.
Practicing with my band.
I don't wanna brag,
but I'm a member of school band.
Are there any band's fans?
No, I just play for fun.
Is that what you want to hear?
Oh... poor little boy.
If there's no one listen
to your song, tell me
I'll go listen to it.
Really?
Oh, by the way...
you haven't told me
why you liked a science lab
I loved a science lab...
because at my school,
if you looked down from the lab's window,
you saw the whole basketball court clearly.
Paramee!
Don't let me catch you.
Are you hiding?
You hiding from me?
Where are they?
Let's go!
Paramee, don't let me catch you!
Should be somewhere in there.
Your wallet...
you better look for it yourself.
I'll wait here.
Hey, wait.
Will you come with me?
No, I won't.
You go find it by yourself.
Here.
No matter what happens, don't call me.
At this moment you better call an exorcist.
Did you find it?
If you want me to find it quickly,
come and help.
I thought you said you like science lab.
I like watching view from my science lab,
not here.
Don't you want to know
looking from this lab's window,
what will you see?
Would you love me
if you don't have anyone?
Please open your heart for me
I promise you with my life that
I won't let you down.
Would you love me, please?
I don't want to see anyone have you.
How do I live without you beside me?
I don't want to compare myself with Ohm.
I just want you to forget him.
Is that it?
I want to be your boyfriend.
I just want a chance to take care of you.
Friend can take care of friend.
I don't want to be just friend.
Have I told you love is
like waiting for a bus?
I've found that...
it's not just about waiting.
Also, I've learned that,
once the bus arrives,
you have to decide if you get on it.
You looks very blossom
since you were in love.
Putting on makeup,
do you want to compete
the beauty with me?
She can't.
You are way ahead of.
- Who is it?
- Ohm.
Give me.
Don't talk to him.
Coffee, ma'am.
Here it is!
"Love you"
"Tutorial School"
Drop off your younger brother?
That's sweet.
Would you love me, please?
He forgets to bring his wallet.
Ouch!
My eyelash!
"Love me?"
Sa... You old crone.
I know everything now.
Bass's friend is my facebook's friend.
I thought it's his old photo.
Bass?
Are you serious with this relation?
Well.
He's good in everything.
What important is you two like him.
No high school boy would
take any love seriously.
This is serious.
Though you don't care anything,
at least you think about moral.
We're 26.
We should think about marriage.
It takes many years
before your boyfriend graduates.
Don't you think
he might meet a younger,
and prettier woman than you.
It might takes 10 years
before he's ready for marriage.
And 10 years from now,
you womb might be
dysfunctional by then.
Come on. Let me help.
Fine, if you don't need my help.
Now my friends know that
you are high school boy.
So?
They told me that,
I should have thought more
about future and reality.
What do you mean?
Our age gap is too wide.
We think differently.
How do we feel to each other,
I don't think
it's enough to carry our relationship.
Since you might not even,
think about our future.
I guess we could make it together.
I've thought about our future for a while.
Our future is,
when I graduate,
I will take over my dad's business.
Then we'll getting married.
We'll have two children.
By that time, I will be 28.
You will be 36.
But nobody will care about that
when the time's comes.
Sa.
Do you know, in my life,
I've chosen everything by myself.
It's just a few thing that I couldn't.
I couldn't choose my birthday.
But now I've chosen that,
for the rest of my life,
I will be with you forever.
Every morning, before I go to work,
I want you to tie a tie for me.
Why you crying?
You don't like my planned future.
Hey, Sa...
Do you want to come in
and wash your face?
Come on.
Come.
Stop!
What are you doing?
- Want me to hit his head? Let go of me!
- Stop!
Sa... this is my father.
Hello, sir.
I'm sorry...
for that extreme greeting.
Who is this woman?
She's my friend.
Look all you have done!
Someone called me
you went to practice with your band.
Did I order you not to play music?
You should stop misbehave
and hang out late.
I won't live forever to teach you.
- Go upstairs!
- I will but let me send my friend back home first.
I'm all right.
By the way, you were great.
If nobody had stopped you,
my father should have been knocked down.
Come on, let's go home.
And don't bother to give me a ride back.
Wait a minute.
Don't tell me that your?
No need.
I'll get some more when I go back.
I'm going to do it once at a time.
Why did your dad do this to you?
He always mad at me since my mom died.
Every activities I can do
when my mom's alive,
I couldn't do any now.
My dad only wants me to stay home.
But while I was there,
he always be with another woman.
That's why I go out
and practice music with my band.
Somebody had asked
my band to play in the pub.
Can you?
I think you are underage for such place.
Well...
What about your dad?
Age is not a problem.
But my dad...
Forget it.
For him, I always do things wrong.
I have to go.
He has been waiting for too long.
Bass!
Nice place.
Who are they?!
My brothers.
Tle and Tik,
The turbulence twin.
They do nothing but arguing
who was born before.
Sit here.
I'll give you bandage.
Live by yourself, aren't you feel lonely?
How can you go to school in this condition?
I think you'd better rest here.
If you are hungry,
there are foods in the fridge.
And in the evening,
I'll cook for you.
Here.
Is it good?
Do you want a lie or a truth?
Listen...
You ran away from home like this.
Where will you stay?
Can I stay here?
Please... just for a while.
I'll move out when
I can find a new place.
- Please, please, please.
- All right.
Then...
Go take a shower,
I'll prepare the bed for you.
Hey, go to bed.
- You have to go to school tomorrow.
- I haven't done my homework yet.
What?
Pervert!
What's pervert?
I meant homework as a school assignment.
What do you think it is?
Well... homework as it is.
All right. Forget it.
Come on. What subject?
Let me help.
What is that?
Not so smart now?
It's the 'Diff'
Diff?
What's Diff?
Is it like 'Dib Boyscout' the singer?
Who's he?
It's Diff Integration.
It's Calculus.
It goes like this.
Get it?
How could you be this stupid?
I studied language arts, not maths.
Don't make an excuse.
Stupid! Stupid! Stupid!
You're just a kid!
Show me some respect!
How could you mess up my head?
You should go sleep in your bed.
What key did you give to the boy?
My room's key
You did it with the boy, didn't you?
You're now immortal!
Are you nuts? Huh?
He's running away from home.
You invite him to stay with you?
You're such a big bad bitch!
You're ruining his future.
Nonsense!
I'm not ruining his future.
We are actually planning
our future together.
When he graduates...
He'll take over the family business.
Then, we'll get married.
- Come here.
- Wait!
If he's going to take over
the family business,
how come he's staying
in your apartment?
What's your logic?
Sa, I think you should reconcile with Ohm.
He's a married man.
Not that he can't get divorced.
But the age gap of almost 10 years...
can't be reduced to a couple of years
Can't you just keep
your feet on the ground?
A high school kid dreams
as big as he can.
You guys live in two different worlds.
Whoa, I'm starving.
Are you all right?
How's your work today?
Meeting with the client today
made me so exhausted.
They changed the plan
again and again.
When I said I couldn't finish it
by the last quarter.
My boss simply told me
find a subcontract to beat the deadline.
If I can't carry out this project,
I won't get bonus this year.
What should I do?
Seriously...
What is 'the last quarter'?
Well, now that you're escaping home...
What did your dad say?
He doesn't know it yet.
For how long do you expect?
- I'm not going back.
- What?
But don't worry about my future plan,
I have plan B.
I'll work as a pub musician.
Totally, 5,000-6,000 baht a month.
I'll be able to feed you well.
Right.
Yes, meeting is set
at 10 o'clock tomorrow.
Wait a sec. Sorry.
Hello?
Yes. Wait a moment please.
Excuse me?
All right, I've found it.
Of course, I can do it.
How can I possibly finish all the work?
Hire some freelance to do the work.
I think subcontracting is worth investment.
And you'd be able to wrap up the project
before last quarter deadline.
What would you say?
Want me to find you a contact list?
Ohm
I already solved my problem.
From now on, I can take care of you.
You've come back to me...
Wouldn't Pam mind at all?
She doesn't care about me.
We get married
because she's pregnant and left alone.
We don't really love each other.
The one I do love...
...is you.
Although I'm with Pam,
I always think about you.
Pam and I don't get along well
I think we fit together so well.
Don't you think so?
"Ohm is back"
Can I stay with you for a while?
All right.
But don't let your dad know
where you are.
I saw your dad's henchmen the other day.
They looked like bandits.
I'm scared for you.
I don't think you can escape this time, Bass.
My dad is forcing me to study abroad.
You'd better keep a low profile.
Don't wander off for a while.
Got your fake ID card yet?
I've got mine.
So that we can play a gig at that pub.
Got yours?
They told me I didn't need one.
Believe me, you can blend in easily.
- With a face like me?
- It'll be a breeze.
I look so young.
How could I pass?
Are you crazy?
Ohm is back.
I knew it!
By the way, who's Ohm?
Right.
He's my girlfriend's ex-boyfriend.
And he's her first love.
So?
You're a hotshot.
Although your dad...
constantly beats you up.
- How come is he better than you?
- Right.
He's got a house...
a car...
and a high paying permanent job.
I'll go for Ohm.
Come on. Come on.
"Incoming Call - Bass"
Oh, god!
The clash of boyfriends!
The doomsday is falling on us, Mham.
We should flee right now.
Let's go.
Hey, Jane... Mham
- Hi, Ohm.
- Hi there.
Is Sa here?
I've been calling her several times.
She doesn't answer the phone.
She said she'd be out running
some errands.
- She might not come back today.
- That's right.
You shouldn't wait.
It's a waste of time.
I'm bringing her the freelance contact list.
Here it is.
Please give it to her.
Sure.
Splendid.
She's using her ex-boyfriend.
You have any plans
for your next vacation?
No, we haven't.
Good.
I've booked a hotel package in Phuket.
I'm taking Sa and
her family on a vacation.
If you don't have any plan, join us.
Well, I...
Thank you.
I think you'd better go.
Or rush into the emergency room.
Be smacked by the boy.
You'd better go.
Please handle that for me.
- I will.
- Sure.
- Thank you very much.
- Bye bye.
That's it.
There he goes.
We'll bring you a sympathy gift basket, Ohm.
Thank you.
Hey, Bass.
She couldn't find you at the school.
So she's been waiting for you here.
Why didn't you go to school?
You could be expelled for skipping school.
Hey...
Hey, look.
I bought a maths books today.
So you would stop calling me stupid.
Let's see what it's all about.
Here!
Calculus... Integration.
Probability... Oh?
Do you have a lot of free time?
You don't have to try this hard.
No need to understand what you don't.
I won't try to understand...
what 'last quarter' is either.
But I...
I finished the first chapter.
And now I can solve this kind of equation.
- Hey!
- Huh? What?
What song are we going to play?
Ah... well...
I told you that the rich boy...
...is damn self-willed.
You'd better go back.
"You are my love - Ohm"
Ohm?
Wise choice that you are now dating Ohm.
Sorry, I'm late.
I have an urgent thing to do.
She doesn't care about her baby.
I took pity on this little one.
So I'm taking care of him for now.
Well, you're such a good guy.
So much love for women,
children, and everyone.
So much, very much!
You two might have a long conversation.
We will take care of your baby.
- It'd be better.
- Come with me, sweety.
Please take care of her.
How cute!
Here.
Sa...
You wouldn't mind, would you?
Not at all.
Ohm...
Pam
Where are you?
You sound so drunk.
Park right there.
Don't drive.
I'll pick you up in an hour.
Just park right there.
Sa, let's order some food.
- Don't you have to pick...
- Order some food.
Well... I'd like to...
thank you for bringing me the contact list.
Pardon me?
I said...
thank you for bringing me the contact list.
Jen and Mham would love
to join our trip to Phuket.
That's all right.
Good. Good.
The more, the merrier.
You'd better go seeing Pam.
Sa, today is all about you.
But all
You are thinking of is Pam, right?
Sa...
I understand.
It happens to me as well.
I'm trying to be with you.
But what really happens is that...
All the time that we're sitting here,
my mind is on someone else.
I think we feel the same thing.
We thought it's wiser
to be with someone in a league of our own.
But what really happens...
What we are doing is against our hearts.
Sa...
Thank you.
Hey, Sa.
Are you going to work?
- I'll give you a ride.
- That's OK. I can go to work myself.
Come on, Sa.
Think of it as a ride with a brother.
I want to thank you for understanding me.
You made me realize
what I really need to do.
To show you how grateful I am,
I'll take you out for a treat tonight.
Invite as many friends as you'd like.
All right?
Hello, everyone!
All single ladies, put your hands up!
Did anyone here sneak out from boyfriend?
All single and not-so-single ladies,
On this special night, we'll have a fun activity.
We're gonna have...
An auction for a kiss with our hot singer!
Give me some noise!
Even a frog like him
can make girls scream.
If they put my kiss on an auction,
girls will go gaga over it.
Right.
I can't imagine that day.
Whoo!
Look yummy!
Watch me.
His kiss must be mine.
First bid... 500 baht!
Wow, haven't started bidding yet
but we already got 500.
Do I hear a higher bid?
800!
1,000!
2,000!
Jane, don't you think 2,000 baht
is too expensive?
- C'mon.
- Just sit there.
I want him.
5,000!
Ready to drop the hammer
and announce that I win?
Sa, can I borrow your money?
Jane...
Take this.
Thank you, Ohm.
5,500 baht!
5,500 baht, going once.
5,500 baht, going twice.
And...
5,500 baht... Sold!
To Table R3!
Well, excuse me.
I have my own rule to kiss only real girls.
We won the auction.
If I don't get the kiss,
One of the girls at my table must get it.
Sa, it's you.
Go on.
- Hurry up, otherwise it'll be our lost.
- Yes, it's you.
May the winner come up here.
- Hurry up!
- Go on.
Hurry up.
It's your chance. So cute.
Go on.
- Wow, if you're ready...
- Go on.
Prepare to be kissed.
- You guys!
- Sa!
Have you ever cared to ask me first?
Don't play hard to get.
Here's your chance.
Come on!
Look, he's so handsome.
Cute!
Kiss! Kiss! Kiss! Kiss!
Bass
- Let me kiss you instead.
- No, thank you.
Bass! Bass!
Ohm
That kid...
His father is Mr. Kriengkrai?
Do you know Bass's father?
Kriengkrai...
is the father of Pam's baby.
- I've got him.
- Get off me! Let me go!
Get ready to go to the airport.
All you care about is music
and your girlfriend.
You need to learn a lesson.
You need to stop acting like a lunatic.
You don't want to see
your girl in trouble, do you?
Sa... good luck.
You too, Ohm.
If love is like waiting for a bus.
Sometimes even we catch the right one,
it doesn't mean
we'd always have a smooth ride.
- Pam!
- I used to feel reluctant to get on a bus.
- But from now on, I won't be afraid of it.
- Leave me alone!
Pam!
And if that bus is going to run away from me,
I'll run after it. Bass!
Bass! Bass!
Bass!
Are you out of your mind?
Why are you running after me?
You told me once...
You wanted to see me tying
your tie every morning.
Don't you want to see it anymore?
Bass!
5 years later.
Yes, Mom.
Still have a headache, Mom.
I'll go to bed soon.
Tle and Tik?
You don't have to send them over here.
I can take care of myself.
I'm fine.
I'm going to bed now.
Bye bye.
Yes, Mom.
Have Tle and Tik arrived there yet?
Tle and Tik?
Yes, I send them to check you
out last night.
Sa
Do you hear me?
Yes, Mom.
Call me if you need anything.
Thank you.
Yes, dear.
Please sign here, Mr. Janepob.
Thank you.
Wait.
Yes?
You're fired.
My name is Jeannie.
Dare to show off.
Have you tucked and taped yet?