Didn't you see the man ahead?
Speed up, full gear
Stop the car!
You can't do this!
I am talking to you
stop right now!
God, I was shot
Damn, I am so stupid!
Am I still going to live?
You won't die, it's not gonna hurt
I said this is not gonna hurt
But my blood is running out
Damn, let me have a look
Let me take a look!
You can hold on a little longer, it's not too severe
The bullet is not deep inside
You can't stay here
No no, I want to go back to the prison
Don't you forget, you will stay there for
the rest of your life if you ever go back
Are you named Gilbert?
Two friends of us have died
for this single matter
No matter what
I don't believe
I think we'd better divide from here
I'll go first, see you
Why are you going that way?
Got a plan? MG! Wait for me!
It hurts, it hurts!
Mama!
Hey, MG!
MG!
How did you get into this?
Didn't you put on any isinglass cream?
You've got blood on the clothes
God, how did I get it on the shirt
It's still new
I brought it out just to have it basked
Look at what your father did
He always put his razors everywhere
and said he will tidy them up
That's just to help you,
he thought he could do it well
That's right
Don't forget he is going to celebrate
the Mother's day for you
Yeah
But now what shall I put on?
This is so unexpected!
Look at that!
Oh! Those glair almond cookies!
Hurry up, Magali, turn off the oven!
Look, I've got my finger cut
and only shed a few dropes of blood
How could this happen?
It seems that someone else had got into our home
I swear
This reminds people of woods of Autumn in Paris
There are many orange trees on the roadside
This alcohol is about 13 degrees
and it's easy to get drunk
Alcohol from 98 is not so crusted for me
Believe me,
the longer the alcohol is stocked
the more exalted it becomes
It's exactly the opposite to me
How much is it?
Tax not included, 7.6
Such a delicious alcohol rarely
sells for price like this
I hope so
It's okay
Make it a little cheaper
Give me a reasonable price tag
Price?
If you insist to compare
Ah, you are so lucky
Daniel
It's very obvious, she's a terpsichorean
People can tell from her upright waistline
She wanted to be a star in her childhood
Perhaps in one or two years
Shit, what's wrong?
So stupid!
Hurry up!
Do you want to be like this?
Got any plan?
What kind of luck this is!
I didn't get in the way of nobody!
Shut up! Come on!
Don't you be quick!
I wanna pick the lock
I am an expert
Expert?
You wanna get caught?
Wait, I can't walk
I can walk no more
You try breaking your leg! Try it!
I really can't walk
Cannot walk
You are right
We can't be like this any more
Go, it must be after us
You have brains, you have intelligence
MG, aren't you smart?
Then get me out of here!
In conditions like this
Can I think of what to do?
With handcuffs!
But this doesn't prevent you from thinking!
We need to find a quiet place to have a break
Let's play to the score when we settle down a bit
Is this your plan?
The geckos here remind me of my grandfather
The owners of this home must be as kind as him
Geckos are guardians of homes
Let's go
Wait, wait for me
This door is not automatic
Look, just as I said
Geckos are bring us good luck
Come and help me a bit
Come on
Mama!
Hey! MG!
We can hold them as hostage
What's the point to take this household hostage?
I don't know either
We can negotiate with the daughter
In the past
You ask the hostages to get downstairs one by one
You ought to do this
I never did that
They will cooperate with you
You also need to find an empty room
and make them stay there
Which way are you going
for your wound's sake
Door, door!
Seems that somebody had been here
Then I need to find this thing out
You go look at the glair almond cookies
What are you looking for?
No, excuse us, we were going the wrong way
He was hit by a car
accidentally
Is there such a person?
Yes, actually we are looking for a doctor
We heard that the number is 15
and we went in
But we don't know how we ended up here
Excuse us, madam
Never mind
But this is 3, not 15
And that is his house, but it's not a clinic
Please come in, I'll find some
No, don't bother
Okay, okay
Please come in, you can't stay like this forever
Please
Monsieur
If you are very painful, please have a seat first
No, Magali
Bring the chair from the dining room for this gentleman
Are we causing any trouble to you?
Your are too courteous to think this way
I'll call a doctor
Doctor Buwaik is very warmhearted
It's an emergency, madam
I think you'd better not call a doctor
How can I not do that?
This is nothing
No
Don't make this happen in my wedding anniversary
We won't bother you for too long
You have nothing to worry about
We just need some rest
Do you have anything to bind up a wound?
Like isinglass cream or bandage
Shall we? Borrow some
The glair almond cookies are baked ready
Yes?
Are you going to
rape and kill us?
Right?
We just want to take breath here
Everything here is yours to take
And then please go
Smells good
It's my specialty
Twenty years of marriage, do you understand?
There are guests tonight
And I need to get the supper ready
And my husband and son will be back in a while
I also need to change
It's not that your are not welcome
I very much understand your problem
But it's for sure that you can't have supper here
Don't worry
We won't face you to do anything
May I watch television?
There are no interesting programs now
They are all for children
Do you like watch cartoons?
No
We want to know whether our breakout is be talked about
Ah, sure
Did you break out of prison?
You can say that
How come I can find anything
If you don't mind
I want to go on with preparing the supper
Otherwise I wouldn't be able to make it
Don't worry, it's the automatic door to the garage
Okay, the door is open
Hi, Daniel
Hi
Do you have anything on your mind?
Yeah
Did you see my dog in your garage?
No
It's lost again
Probably it ran from that end of the fence
The fence needs to be fixed
We talked about this
but we haven't set any date
You decide the time
You just approve a refit plan
I'll see to the rest
I have a catalog, how about a little chat?
I will be right there
Freeze there
Let me go
Papa
I am really sorry
The garage door was blocked
Excuse me
There's something
My mother is preparing for the wedding anniversary
Oh, you are such a lucky guy
It's all right
I'll be back later
Are there many guests already?
No, only two
Just breakout prisoners
No matter who they are
My dear
The supper is not ready yet
We have something unexpected
What is that?
Did he shoot you?
Where did you hurt? Where?
I did this to myself
Relax
They agreed to not having supper here
I think he's even kinder than us
They are not ferocious at all
Two dangerous prisoners escaped during their transfer
Us? They are talking about us
The incident happened at 3 or 4 o'clock in the afternoon
It's on the interprovincial highway crossing the Flurhay-Prizans Forest
According to several witnesses
It's estimated that this breakout has neither complicity
nor premeditation
One of the prisoner, Gilbert
for involving in a small lawsuit
was sentenced to two years in prison.
His term of imprisonment is nearing its end
You are so foolish
And another one
Michel Garmay
is an unexcused prisoner
His nickname is MG
Possibly referring to intelligence
To me, MG always refer to edible oil
He was the ringleader
of the notorious armed robbery 9 years ago
They robbed a bank in Saint Bursan that provides loans for growing grapes
During the course there are hostages hold
And the case ended up with the death of an employee
Mr. Garmay was sentenced to 20 years in prison
His confession in the courtroom didn't convince the jury
because he woundn't plead guilty
That's not my fault
You tell them
That's not my fault!
You are an reporter
Tell them I was not wrong!
Above is the office statement
Since I am not the reporter investigating this case
I don't know if you would be satisfied with this report
Mr. Garmay
In fact, you were only an accomplice
You were an employee of the robbed bank
You only provided the criminals with
some information on the security monitoring system
in the robbed bank
Right, right, that's the truth
The reward was three months of salary
Mr. Sharl Greynach
Are you the lawyer for Mr. Garmay?
Yes
At that time
The real ringleader of that case contacted Mr. Garmay
Is that true?
Yes, but I didn't ever know who he was
Yes
As to me
We investigated his identity
not for any professional secrets
The reason is very simple
We wanted to understand this person
It's him who instigated me to do those things
He also promised to save me if I got into trouble
Therefore we can't turn our back upon this
Someone saw the two escaped criminals
in and around the Flurhay-Prizans Forest
From now on
Every trunk road in this region is under police' control
Now I know the whole thing
No matter how
If you'd like to stay for supper
I'll prepare some more dishes
Which dishes do you prefer?
Got any plans? We are doomed to death
Surely you have, right, Mr. MG?
Very sorry
I am very sorry to bother you in your weeding anniversary
This reminds me of the time when my wife and I were together
Pull yourself together
You haven't lost anything
Look
At least you need to take away all the telephones
excluding the one in the living room
We'll give our cellphones to you also
Yes, yes
I insist to do so
No one would know what's gonna happen
Try it
And cellphones are not as valuable as wedding rings
Magali
Put the cellphones upstairs with Mr. Gilbert
Is you name Gilbert?
Bring all of them upstairs?
Right
Oh, what about those guests?
Louis Dovick is returning from school soon
Can I make a phone call to him?
I will find an excuse
and ask him to stay over night at his schoolmates'
In the meantime
You can cancel the invitations to our friends
I'll try
But this is so tricky
Let me explain this to you
I work in a daytime hospital for psychopathic children
as a part-time social welfare personnel
Do you know hysteria?
Hysteria, yes, I know that
Great!
Those children are very mysterious and arresting
The Mearlow's
are both supervisor to the hospital
and psychiatrist there
We are friends, very good friends
But it's still hard to explain to him
Don't worry
He will understand
Dr. Mearlow
This is the Bermariyan Hospital
What can I do for you
Béatrice, wait a second
Yeah, excuse me
I have been studying the case of Alexander Jr.
Now he has entered the phase of self-controlled mutilation
At one time he broke his head
At the other time he thrashed his arms
In the last two days he struggled to
bump his back against everywhere
How about you, Béatrice
Are you okay?
Damn flies!
Ah, yes
Your twentieth wedding anniversary
Does your daughter suffer from mental stress?
Since a long time ago
She is good, very good
People like to stay together with her
Frankly speaking
Probably some kind of blasphemy
make her go down with such a psychological disease
I treated her with psychotherapies
But this is too slow
She strongly opposed it
She felt that she still belonged to Satan
Now it worked
thanks to Mr. President
When Louis Dovick came to attend the chastenment committee yesterday
mentioned to us your fondness for poems
Can we have our poem club now?
Yes
Please wait
Hello?
Papa!
I will be right back, don't worry
Yeah
The meeting was longer than expected
But don't be afraid
It's your wedding anniversary, I won't
Ah? Yes?
It's up to you
Okay
Yes
Say hello to mama
Enjoy your time in Leedur
Do you wanna come to my home to learn some art?
No, damn you
Give me a break
Give me the stuff
What are you talking about
There's a beautiful girl, are you not going for her?
Got something to do today
I'll leave her alone for now
Stop that
I don't wanna go at all
I am scared
I think I will feel uneasy all over
If you find them to be old-fashioned
it's not too late to leave at that time
Magali is a very good friend of mine
You understand that, don't you?
She wouldn't wanna see me drinking with her uncle all the time
You can have a lot of decious food there
especially sweets
Mrs. Roze makes first-class glair almond cookies
You choose
me or those cookies
Okay, okay
I give up to go there
But we'd better say hello to her family
There are still many things to do
Yeah, your are right
That's the reason why I ask you to choose
Don't be curmudgeonly, I am only staying there for two minutes
Yes
But when Magali sees me together with you
she will ask you what's going on
No, I don't want it, you have to hide me
Where?
I don't know either, anywhere
Only two minutes
Say yes, dear uncle!
We have no way to contact him
He is not taking his cellphone
He must be on his way
He is always early
When he arrives
you go out
find an excuse and ask him to leave
You don't know him
He's as stubborn as a mule
There's absolutely no way to persuade him
You know
He's always like that
Look, here he is
Ask him to leave
This is good for everybody
He won't listen to me, never
I think Magali can give it a try
He likes you
As to me, he knows too much
He can tell immediately that I am lying
Hello, uncle
Ah, Magali, how are you?
There's a small incident, sorry
Do you want to say something?
No, No please
You tell your parents that I am sorry
Please tell them I can't be their guest today
I have to something unexpected to deal with
Sometimes it happens
There's something wrong with the cultural center
I have to be there
Is it for your next performance?
Yeah
Is there an 18-year-old girl?
I will like her
Really
Get in
This is my home!
What are you going to do?
You are so unsympathetic
He just came home
This is the point
Someone self-invited goes everywhere
Is this normal?
And he found such a pretext to reject an invitation
You can check if he has a cellphone with him
Don't kill me
Please
Don't kill me, I am a patient
Anybody? I can't stand any more
She will suffocate in the trunk
I don't care
May I go?
She looks quiet
It would be a pity if she dies
Don't you know that in a time like this
there are things more important than the girl?
What else do you like?
Shotgun?
No no, I guarantee to you that
it's gardenia
My wife loves gardenia a lot
Please let me go, please
I will give you anything you want
I have a heart problem and have to take medicines on schedule
I'll tell you the names of those medicines
I need anti-heart-failures drugs
I need anti-convulsion drugs, anti
This fellow needs anti-everything drugs
Be patient
It'll be better, uncle
Think for him
He wants to release you also
But he can't
You know
They are having a hard time too
Come and try my glair almond cookies
It happened so sudden today
that I didn't have time to prepare some little cakes
Never mind, madam
Thank you
They look very delicious
This is all natural
Authentic glair almond cookies are all natural
They are only made from almond powder
If you don't mind
I'll go change upstairs
Hold it
Help yourself
It's my pleasure
What do you two want to drink?
Here I have champagne
But in this kind of situation
probably you would prefer
I just want to think it over
How about your wound?
What suprised me is
Perhaps it's stupid to think this way
But aren't you going to be set free soon?
Yeah
It can be even more unrestricted than home
Why did you still want to escape?
Is the prison that unbearable?
Right
That is the most unbearable place
I didn't want to escape
This was an accident
Magali, your question might get people bored
And you've also interrupted Mr. MG's thoughts
In this way he won't be able to find a solution
Look, we've brought trouble to others
There is someone in the garage
It's police!
God, we are finished!
They have found here
They are so fast
The worst moment is coming
We could only fight!
We are dying
I am telling you!
We are dying without even any belongings
It's so ridiculous
Madam, it's me
We totally forgot there is she
It's Marsanne, Marsanne
I'll talk to her
Are you sure?
Yeah, she came just to help me prepare the supper
She always comes in through the garage
Don't worry
I know how to send her away
Gugu, Marsanne!
I have to come in here
The door is blocked
Look at my clothes
It became so dirty
Damn!
You can wash it clean with ease
Washing the clothes is even more expensive
than buying a new one!
You always exaggerate, Marsanne
It's gonna be fine
There's something wrong with the door, I admit
I am feeling better
I will tidy it up
and you don't have to work here tonight
As compensation
I will make this clear to the guests
I will tell them
You mean I came here and had nothing to do?
That's true
But I will pay you as I promised
Did I ride one hour of bus for nothing?
I'll say it again
I will compensate you for all your time
and dry clean your clothes
plus the fare for the public traffic
Yes, yes
I left my daughter with 49 degrees fever for here
You are exaggerating again
Such a young child would have already died of 49 degrees
Yeah, she is dying
but I came here for nothing?
Frankly speaking, Marsanne
Okay, I am willing to pay the medical treatment as goodwill
Please don't demand for more
Pay, pay
I am fed up with that
Do you think this is the panacea for everything?
Do you think by paying me you will live in peace?
Narcissism
Do you know what narcissism is?
You are so darkminded!
Marsanne
Don't bring me any more trouble!
Do you think I have no trouble at all?
I came to prepare the supper
and I will do that
No
Let's see
Marsanne
We have enough maids already
Mrs. Roze
It's you who likes to exaggerate
You are fired!
Great
But after the supper
Get out of my home! Get out!
Shut up! Stupid woman!
Stupid woman!
I will throw this immediately!
I think we can't bring her through
No matter how
it's me who wanted to get rid of her
She never knows where he is
I told her one hundred times
to put the vacuum under the bed
One hundred times!
Do you have a plan?
What are we going to do?
Magali, please go back to your room
In fact
this is not a big deal
If you hadn't come here
it wouldn't have happened
I think you killed a number of people
including the two policemen died recently
It shouldn't be a problem if adding one more
I didn't do nothing
I never killed anyone
If you set me free
I'd like to testify for you
How I admire your family value!
Jean-Louis
I am telling the truth
Daniel
Daniel is right
If you do not hesitate to betray your family
it's hard to ensure you don't spread the word
I can't take this risk
I just wanted to live the 6 months quietly
I don't know what you are going to do, MG
But I am going
I'd rahter go elsewhere to find opportunities
Very sorry to disturb you
Thank you for your cookies, madam
Too hotheaded, Gilbert
And it's too late to go now
Think about it
Look at Mr. MG
He knows how to think
and he's a smart guy
He knows that he shouldn't be caught
after escaping five hunred meters
The moment when you step out of this doorsill
it's likely that you are recognized
And what Jean-Louis did
have made us closer to this family
He's my only uncle
a little flabby
but we still love him very much
Is Mr. Roze there?
I am his neighbour
My name is Flaunsova Clavih
Ah, he's right there
Hello, this is a surprise
What surprise?
Didn't your wife give you a surprise?
I will be out explaining this to you
Is he your cousin from Chile?
Is he coming for your wedding anniversary?
I know there is a kind of soft alcohol in Chile
Sorry, Flaunsova
You won't be interested here
Go that way
I'll leave the catalog behind
Cross the one you are satisfied with
Does tomorrow night work?
If you would agree
Is there a room in the house with no windows?
And can be locked with a key?
There is a darkroom
There is only a louver window inside for ventilation
It can be locked from inside
That sounds good
I am sure you have a plan already
Gilbert
Go find that girl upstairs
You go to the darkroom
Madam will be there soon
You keep the key
I need to make a phone call
If you don't mind
I want to stay here
I have claustrophobia
and I have rheumatism, no humidity
I didn't have anti-rheumatism drugs with me
But I won't wreck your plan
Don't you think you have baffled others?
Leave him alone, he's always up with something
Jean-Louis!
Hold this
It can be locked inside
This doesn't look so good
I gotta tell you probably I can't stay long
Sorry to bother you
But you don't have to stay very long
This is nothing
This is good for everyone
We can have a rest
You stay reassured
We won't escape
There are no exits here
You can do a check
Since you said it, I believe
Don't worry about us
No matter how
I still have a washing machine here
If you have any needs
Give us your pants
We'll put it in the machine and wash it
Thank you, I can put up with it
I don't wanna bother you
She is right
You can't dress this way
And there's a spot that needs to be sewn
since I am here
We are not gonna run away
Go to my son's room
His pants might fit you
Listen, no matter what you did has nothing to do with me
Michel
it's not necessary
I don't care
This I don't care at all
Don't you think so?
Let's forget everything in the past
I remarried
and have a son
You have a child?
That's great
You decided not to write me because of these?
Eight years, Sophia
Eight years
No see for eight years
No call
Nothing at all
I won't die
You can tell them
I will wait for you
Sophia! Sophia!
Hello, is Mr. Gilbert speaking?
I'm Michelle.Game
Do you remember me?
Remember our trade?
No, after that
Is half an hour ok?
I don't think you can conquer me
Today I have no taste to see you
Come
Come to see what's this
Two murderer ran away
It happened when changing the prison this afternoon
I have only six months
don't know where to go
I'm Gilbert
Next crossing
otherwise it's easy to jam
Necessary?
We need to produce ID card in the crossing of highway
It's routine
Are you MG?
What's your crime?
Is it serious?
I lacerated finger
I intended
Sometimes you can get a conditional freedom by doing this
Sometimes can't
We don't go our planed route
I'm nervous
We pass through Fleury woods
so we can save time
And road conditions there is much better
I will take advantage of curing my hand
to cut my foreskin
Too tight
I felt pain at that time
I don't like not to go according to planed route
I never do this
Don't quarrel, listen
I am very familiar with this district
We go through this province road
At least we should inform jail, shouldn't we?
No need, don't doubt me
It's legal
I decide
Aren't you punished enough by jail?
Go that way, I said
Turn left
Seems you are right
The road is more comfortable
Stop!
It's cozy driving here
But what's matter with you?
Stop! I said!
Ok, ok
Don't be silly, guy
they quarrel
Don't you know why I do like that?
I think I know, but
I listen!
Alright
I kissed your wife
Say it again!
You kissed her many times!
Alright, yes, many times
How could I don't know like a stupid pig!
Don't be like that, it will mess up
What's on earth the problem?
How bold are you
Even offend my wife!
This will change nothing
Do you think that will be alright killing me?
Your wife will accompany you?
It's you who leave me the chance!
Get off, you are free!
I said you are free!
Go quickly!
Goodbye, good luck to you
I can't run away, only 6 months left
Don't blather! I will shoot!
He is so stupid! Fool! Fool!
It's murder for love?
Don't be staleness
You will struggle out
If you will
I can negotiate with police
as a social welfare people
I usually negotiate with manage department
If hand in the materials to them honestly
they will allow for you
No one will believe
It's a 30 year trial to kill two supercargos
no including your handmaid
If another 7 year trial
I can't be out
It's headache
I can't believe
Are you a tough guy?
Yes, yes
All the people said so
My husband won't know
I clearly understand what attracts you
Ardour, something you want to do but can't do
It's part of human nature
People can only do sometimes all his life
Do you know I never see your heartthrob in the prison
It's only agony accompaning me
Feel me
Please allow me to conciliate you
Till tonight, I feel what a wonderful time
MG is
Do you know M,G
are just the acronyms of my name
no other meaning
Michelle.Game
When they beat prisoner running away
I lacerated my wrist
I try to suicide
Ok, I have to go back to dark room
I have to see the washing machine
I accompany you
Alright, ok
No, no
I won't tell you address
It will bring them trouble
No, no, it's alright
They admitted, mine is true
thank you, sir, thanks
Your plan is nothing to me
What?
Can you find another way to wash his clothes
She is busy
Why should I run away?
Just now you implored them to let you go
Now you don't want to go?
I don't want to be utterly isolated
It's my only chance
Jean-Louis
I have to stay to look after my family
Any good news?
Very good news
Aren't you care about me?
You'd better go to have a look
Oh, no, do what?
I can't hear the sound of washing machine
Maybe it's finished
All these will be over soon
You have plan finnally?
After 11 tomorrow morning
only bad memory left
no bad
Anyway, that's it
Do you have local wine?
Yes, but
I don't want to dinner ourselvies
Should prepare for them
It's a pity to say goodbye
There are many good wines
It was my job
I was keeping bodega
Quick
You two can drink one cup
Isn't it, Jean-Louis ?
So see you later
Ok, ok, see you later
So you can enjoy the wine here quietly
Aren't you really hungry?
I never ate such a wonderful food
I usually think of my home town
Many friends gathered in a house like yours
Gilbert,
We are going
I have got a plan
Say it tomorrow,
Now is resting time
can't you leave your stomach empty
I want to drink a small cup
You got the right place
I go to choose several bottles of good wine
Let you full of human kindness
Pity can't go to have a look
It's by nose tasting the wine, not liver
It makes me think of the scent in the dyewoods
a scent with violet
aftertaste is filbert
The child is talent
have a good smell
You are totally right
We should taste wine like that
keeping a kind of rhythm
Otherwise we will confuse the taste of wine
Isn't it our first wine tasted?
Only
a bit thick
Maybe deposited more 5 years
How could you guess?
Just feeling, of course experience, too
The thicker woods's scent
the harder to fidget
It's too suprised
How striking the child is!
Wonder child!
What if my customers like you
This wine comes from
Chile
My cousin brought to me there
If I'm not wrong, It's famous
I'm pleased not to worry about child's study
Come, quickly
Daniel is keeping there
Don't you want to go?
We should be away from crime, especially for youth
Good luck, uncle
No!
Stay here will be hapless
Shit! Don't be lah-de-dah
I don't
Quickly!
What's wrong?
Could you please turn on the lamp of hallway?
No
Are you mixing things up?
It's too dark
I will drop downstairs
Then I go first
You take care of yourselvies
Go quickly!
Come
Enjoy the poetic wine
Enjoy it
Poet Beaudelaire!
My son complied a poem about wine
He likes poem
Politics is like a wine
on changing the world
If fancy even in an old age
it's the thing I mostly want
beside wife
Do you see her ass?
Don't be like that
It's normal to say that
I was mad for it
Round, stout, smooth
Lure me like a forbidden fruit
Even after 20's marriage
I still love
Look, so strange
Light outside are on
Maybe some birds fly through
I must keep the door clean
You are not fool, come in
Don't force me to shoot
Not me, I didn't want to, it's
Damn!
How to do?
Let's show our hands
He will trouble us sooner or later
This guy is too selfish
Never think of others
But can't kill for this reason
Only you say that
If he bring the police
Who will say you don't kill anybody in my home
You are right
Whatever we can't let police come
I think he has been after handmaid
maybe it's the sound of fireworks
Nothing, sleep, dear
Before morning today
I never see the dead man
Ah, drag his leg
drag him in
To an actor
It's a beautiful way
Think creeper stems, you will be better
I never meet lucky
Meet one thing like this
will suffer from it
I just want to protect family
What you protected is yours
It's from my mother
This room and store are both my uncle's
We take charge of his aged
Now he is dead, need nothing
That's what I just said
I'm protecting my family
You are too young to understand
How is your leg?
Fine, thanks
Go upstairs, child
It's what you premediate, too?
What have you done to my daughter?
She became so treasonable
Forgive her
She is too excited celebrating our marriage anniversaty
Now we can talk
All will be the same soon
Now, listen to Mr. MG to tell his plan
If you do as I say
After tomorrow noon
You can do whatever you want
All are arranged well
It's he who planed!
He owe me
Great
An hour later
You go to receive our false passports
and our merited money
Then your wife will take you to the exit of the city
Let's bet
Police will only check two men
won't pay attention to a couple
You let him alight first
then come back to see us
bring me
I can go with you any place you want
Which car?
Uncle's
It's because of you
he needn't the car any more
Don't say like that
My honey
Aren't these all because of me?
If you could listen to my suggestion
I wouldn't not say a word
I have encountered your jugglery one year before
pity! Child
When did you become so capable?
If nothing else, dad, I go upstairs
I can't endure any more
Look at you
Hold forth
Clear and logical on educating me
And hug me smarmy
I hate this kind of life
You no heart!
We are come from this age
It's youth at 18
If I can't go with you
I'll suicide
Go, Bring something to me to eat
Enough
I don't want to stay here without doing anything
Look, so interesting!
Don't be mistake, impossible!
It's all true!
But it's meaningless of realistic things
Hasn't Picasso a realistic attitude?
Say true thing to a dog
To a flea which makes it scratchy
maybe it's not true
Ah, is it?
Can't you see
it will become worse?
I can't manage too much
Do you decorate room to red?
I'm here waiting for you
But you needn't wait outside
You can have a look
I'm not feeling galling
On the contrary
I think show my body to you
like show insider a paint
What do you think of me?
Closer
I even write a word
Do you want me?
I will disappoint you
It's my first time
No real
Although have, I don't know
To be honest, I really don't know
When I know my chaperon is prostitute
I left her
She asked me to do
That's all
But now
all are finished
Since then
I never touch other girl
Do you like boy?
If you will
let me lean you like this
no
What I want to do now is to be a gardener
Better own a garden somewhere
But far away from here
Don't you?
I think we are far away, far away
I'm afraid of myself, I want to die
I hate myself
Do you know?
How I hate myself!
I always think that I'm competent for anything
even fly to the sky
It's you
Daniel
Where do you go with that dress?
Fishing
Me, too
To some extent
I'm fishing, a big fish
Don't you see any person doubtful in the street?
Don't you hear any news?
Don't you know anything?
There is something around
I am busy with 20 anniversary
Two persons killed their two colleagues with their weapons
It deserves consideration
If you see
somebody doubtful
Don't forget to inform me
After making contribution, I can enjoy my life
It's difficult to be a police.
Can I go?
Goodbye
What can I do now?
There is a vacant for a fisher
There is a stool there
Cloth bag
and fishing rod, for sea fish
This person is Nobel whom you are looking for
I knew nothing
You go closer,and will see a basket in the water
There is a big crab inside
You should check whether there is or not
Remember, don't  be mistake
It's so complicated
But can get effect instantly
You exchange the cloth bags
Then leave
Somebody nearby will inspect you
Ensure that you have done what you need to
He will leave
It's your mobile phone
Phone me after finishing
Do you fish many fishes?
Many, many
Hello?
Is that Mrs. Roze
Yes
For two years
My son can't go to school for children of psychosis
Two years
This is delayed from your first meeting to now
Shall we talk about this in my office
How about the day after tomorrow
It's just a misunderstanding
You won't have any loss
I know you won't solve the problem
Bad woman!
I curse you! Damn it!
Who gives you my mobile phone number?
Such trivias bother me too much
I hear her complain because we are friend
Just nearby
Retired soon
And I think these words are not blithering
there was a child
Chance is so small, isn't it
My cousin got the similiar disease
Sorry, I forget
I have to phone him agian
What happened to him?
He won't come back
I know him, real
He must be go away with money
It's the best gift in the marriage anniversary
He leaves daughter and you alone?
He have been waiting for the day for a long time
Me, too
You won't kill me, will you?
There is any kind of person in your family
It's normal, normal
Gilbert said right, shouldn't let him go
He is back
Hi
It's for you
Please sigh in
Ok
Ah, ba careful, don't fall over yourself
Wish you happy
Stupid pig!
I told him to take the passport, but cheated by him
Shit!
It's from elder brother's wife
I guess is a gift for our marriage anniversary
can I take apart it?
I hate her all the time, too jealous
Go, go to find my husband
Don't worry
I don't intent to do that
My his mistress occupies his money,
it's too abnormal
Do you know where is he?
20 year's marriage
I know him clearly
Let's go
You husband went like this?
He is cozy
From now on
He keep the money without going out
No one will know
Who will say it out?
Better not stay in the frame house alone
Don't you thank me?
What did I do recently?
Attracted by a girl and neglect MG?
Thank you for your trust on me
You should wear a neckcloth
but it's ok
We have no other choice
It's our last chance
I will come back to find you
Quickly
If he has arrive in his mistress's home
We are late
Can you be here?
Can
see you later, dear
Magali, forgive me
I know you hate me
I never want to hurt you
It's all for you
Close the water pipe
If Daniel came back, give me a call
MG! Take care!
He did something silly
Drive Jean-Louis 's car?
No, that will be attention-getting and troublesome
Frive my car
Cheat me
They all cheat me
Believe my mother
She is a dirty woman, too
She must find my father, and money
Especially money
Without me, MG will lose
I can't understand
Why does he risk to be here?
My mother won't let him fiddle
Let's see, I will protect my family when he comes
I won't refuse you
I will share all these with you
Like your chaperon
Let his brains down to the blanket
Pong!
Many prisoner will do anything for running away
Are you forced?
I, I don't want to run away
I just don't know what should I do
How can I run away
How can I killed two policemen
You should know clearly
If I tell them, they will understand
But I'm not your princess yet
If I said, nothing good to me
Protect me, it's a fair trade, too
Shut up!
I think
Before going to his mistress, we come here to have a look
I think he will take away the money in the shop counter first
You will sleep well here
It's for you
What wine?
A kind of black tea wine
You make me happy, dear
His only lover is me
We are still sweet like first love
Do yo understand?
Do you want to not be found by police when urgent?
Stay there
Oh, no,he took my bag away
Don't you lock the door?
Don't be dumbstruck
Dear, hurry up
Anyway, he can't go far
and wounded
Don't you think I destroy the thing?
No, dear
We can live in luxury hotel for two weeks with the money
I'm proud of you
I want, Sophia
You are the strongest
You are the most powerful
Don't touch me!
Stupid pig!
Stop! Cheat!
I know no one respects on you
Stupid! Cheat!
You are nothing
Like a shit!
What the use of you
Dally woman?
Leave her alone
You can do whatever you want
No one will pay attention to you!
I'm leaving
Run wild yourself
Louis! Jean-Louis !
Am I mistake, I
Jean-Louis !
Ah, there is somebody in the backup box
No, how could it be true
There is somebody in the backup box!
Someone?
How could I do?
Let me out!
Ok,ok
Wait a minute, I look around
Who are you?
I ask you to let me out! Please!
Don't speak!
Better not speak if don't want to die
Daniel!
Even no one here!
Are you here?
Daniel, it's me, Francois
Oh, sorry
Marsanne!
Bad
I'm sorry
That's alright, sorry
I come to find a thing
you know my dog
You dog always relieve itself in our garden
Yes, right
Because there is gap in the fense, so it can be there
I come for this
Some materials are on sale
Maybe
I don't know, either
I remembered some
But maybe we souldn't talk about this
Then talk later, I come several days later
Kill him, dear
Shoot
Shoot for me
Please do it for me
Do you know
You are nothing
We have no responsibility at all
really
Mr. Roze
Why you changed to this
Gilbert, where are you
All are over
Hello?
I'm locked in the backup box of Jean-Louis's car
Do you have anything?
No, I'm coming, I'm coming
Keep for the cleaning of the room
What we did?
We did?
Nothing, dear
nothing
We love each other, that's important
I can't endure
You look out, I go to the toilet
I think they lose many things
It's me, let's go
Let me go first
Not now, after go out of the city
How can
I have to keep in touch with you
How can in the backup box
You are good at talking
Wait a minute, sorry
What happened
I have a better way
Hello, yes
I'm beside a garage of Floricans(pronunciation)
You know, Daniel won't do anything
Look, dear
All are coming
All neighbours are coming
It will be a beautiful memory
All are kind
Yes, they are kind
kind really
I'm grateful
Don't worry, that's only a mistake
We'll be back soon
Now it's time to go
Don't let them wait
The earlier we go, the earlier we return
See you later!
Sorry, daniel
Don't you forget to turn off the hydrant
Béatrice is my wife's friend
Alter ego
my cooperative fellow, too
I observed early
Feel of frustration mentally probably
disturb people's attitude on things
As for hostage
I want to say
Those who captured hostage need status identity
Then they will release hostage
Of course, hostage problem is a social problem deserve consideration
Need further analysis
Now
A publisher has negotiated with us
to publish a scribble corpus about this problem
Is there a fly on it?
No, I don't want to talk things about Mr. Roze in public
He is good businessman
Loves family, especially his daughter
When I get them out of the dark room
She is dowdy, tried to suicide once, I think
Web address is:
www.two-rozes.com
two means Secondary_two in english
It's about this family's video archive on the site
remember the address
www.two-rozes.com
Are you clear? Welcome
Is there any problem between neighbourhood?
Two escaped criminal now is still away
Magali Rozes's best friend:
Agnes disappeared from yesterday
It is said that the last time people saw her
She is with Magali's uncle
who is one of the casualties of the case
Where shall we go now?
MG?
Don't call me that way
I'm not wise
I don't care where to go
because I 'm free already
How do you spend the money?
Buy your uncle's house?
I have no home
but will buy it at last
Alright
Jump out of the car here
Look, she is really so unlucky
Do you plan to open a garden?
I studied the problem carefully
However fragrant the flower is, it will fade at last
What about your friend Béatrice?
You can help him!
He is dealing in other places
It's said seedlings of flowers and woods are not expensive
You can look for his brother-in-law
He is looking for investor
Look, you are not silly