Will you have dinner with me tomorrow?
I'd like to dine with you for
the last time before I go.
It's the last time for the 3 of
us to meet before I disappear.
I wan't to change it into a nice memory.
I don't want this time to
become a scar to Da Hye.
Lee Hae Joon and Han Gi
Tak know each other.
The one person who knows
about Han Gi Tak's death.
I won't get ruined so easily.
Are you alright?
Excuse me, are you sure you're alright?
Are you okay?
Wait just a bit long... I'll be there soon.
I'm going.
Be happy, Ahjumma.
Ajhumma.
Ahjumma, you're still there, right?
I'm almost there. You're
going to wait for me, right?
I'm a little late, right?
They got soaked in the rain.
Will you still take them?
Episode 15
Did something happen?
I ran because I was running late.
You could have taken your time.
This time I didn't want to be late.
Over here.
Yes customer.
I placed an order in advance.
Is that alright?
The chef's special is
available for old times sake.
Of course.
See, the color will be distinct.
Such a nag.
Hey treat them well.
Yes, chef.
Please enjoy.
Thank you.
Let's start.
I heard the food was good here but
I've never experienced it properly.
Here.
♪ They must be somewhere ♪
You can leave it. I can do it myself.
I wanted to do this for you. Enjoy.
♪ Inside our memory. The time we
have been avoiding. Those memories ♪
How is it? Is it good?
Yes.
♪ Maybe they're hidden by the sun ♪
♪ Once again ♪
♪ I let go of those
memories from long ago ♪
♪ I might be too late ♪
♪ Maybe in a place that I
can’t even go back to ♪
♪ My whole love is alive and breathing. ♪
Aren't you eating?
Eat.
But...
why did you want to meet here?
♪ I realize ♪
The food you made for me
was so warm and I'm so thankful.
I wanted to invite you in a
delicious meal just once.
This is nothing in comparison to what
you've done for me during this time.
Also for becoming a family to me
I'm very thankful.
I wanted to say those words to you.
That feels good.
This time I kept my promise.
Excuse me.
You are very beautiful today.
Hae Joon! Hae Joon!
Hey honey, pull yourself together.
Hong Nan, what should we do?
Call 911 immediately!
Yes!
The blood is...
What?
It was good to have...
Will he be alright?
Patient are you alright?
Doctor!
What's the matter with this patient?
He was in a hit and run.
Let's examine him first.
Please stay here.
He never said a word.
He'll be alright.
Why is he like that? Why did
have to do it to this extent?
Release the kids are look for the car's
license plate. It's urgent so quickly.
Contact me as soon as you find it. Alright.
Are you going to kill him like this?
Unfortunately, I guess precious time
of Kim Yeong Soo's will be shortened.
What the heck nonsense is that? - It will
be difficult for him to over come today.
Perhaps, is he's dying again?
There's nothing we can do since it's a
self-inflicted injury after he came back here.
So he's dying again like this?
You're the one who made him Lee Hae Joon!
Save him right now!
It is not my authority to save someone.
You need to let them say
good bye to each other.
Save him.
What do I have to do?
I can't let him go like that!
There is a way.
What is it? I'll do anything.
Han Gi Tak, could you share
your remaining time with him?
Please. Please wake up.
If you don't wake up I'm going to be angry.
You said you were going tobe
like the wind that passes by.
You can't do this.
Wake up immediately and leave
from my house with a smile.
Let go home.
Are you alright?
I want to go home.
I want to lay on my bed and listen to
Han Na babbling in the back round.
I want to eat the food you make me.
Let's go.
Where did this patient go?
He was discharged.
He has a brain hemorrhage!
What kind of accident is this
person responsible for this time?
You're here.-Yes.
He's starting to get me all worried!
What now?-Cha Jae Gook
is who I'm taking about.
He asks to eat together. He doesn't
laugh or talk in front of the kid.
Something seems off.
Is that so?
Oh my!
Isn't this me?
Hey how long has it been?
It's an interview from 10 years ago.
Hey, your brother saved
the weirdest things.
I don't know who it is but she's pretty.
Now and 16 years ago.
Am I not pretty?
You are.
Seriously, it's really been a long time.
I was so young.
Aigoo, Director Cha.
Meeting you like this is refreshing.
What a welcoming.
Your face really suits the
scene under this bridge.
It must be difficult being wanted?
It's time for you to save me now.
Give me what you've got.
This thing?
Kill those bastards.
Oh my so frightening.
It's time for you to verify the money.
The amount should be right.
Yes, this is the right amount.
Oh my.
You've made some new friends already.
I can't leave a rabid dog
that bites his owner alone.
A rabid dog.
Oh yea, I wonder if you've already heard.
Lurking around where a rabid dog lives so,
I completely ran him over with the car.
Your rival Lee Hae Joon.
What? Lee Hae Joon?
Why did I run over Lee Hae Joon over?
That was because you told me to.
Just like you ordered
me to do to Han Gi Tak.
You killed him and want
to put the blame on me?
I need at least this amount of insurance
while cleaning up behind you.
You ordered me to kill Han Gi Tak.
You also ordered me to Lee Hae Joon.
This was all ordered by you.
Because you and I are one body.
This son of a b*tch.
How dare you frame me!
You're laughing?
Oh that hurts.
You think I would have come, bringing
that, with no backup plan in mind?
Surprise.
Wait for it.
Find him!
Go inside. Find him quickly!
This lurch individual! Find him quickly.
Find him!
♪ When I see your eyes, I feel uneasy ♪
♪ I start feeling lonely next to you ♪
♪ In my heart, it's just you ♪
♪ Don't turn around like you
don't know me anymore ♪
♪ I love you, you're in my heart ♪
♪ Don't hide in front of me ♪
♪ Alone, I dream about
you and wait for you ♪
♪ It seems like I love you ♪
It'll be bad if it leaves a scar.
Good morning, Ahjumma.
Are you feeling better now?
Yes, I'm feeling like a
really healthy person now.
That's good, let's go down and eat.
In my dream, it seemed like
somebody was caring for me.
Here.
Thank you.
Did I ask for the grape sticker?
Oh, Maya. I think the clock is broken. The
remaining time has decreased drastically.
It's not that it's broken.
What? What are you saying?
I'll just tell you that your time
not decreased but has increased.
You should be clearer so I can understand!
When you return, you'll find out.
Please, take good care
of the family matter.
This amount of time is impossible for me!
Just like everyone else.
Why until now you pretended not to
know, I am curious as to your plan.
It was good enough to make me wonder
if you were the Lee Hae Joon I knew.
That's because I couldn't
completely trust you.
I think you've said the same thing before.
It's not that simple for
me to trust people.
Sunjin Group's first member of international
support department, Lee Hae Joon.
Although Chairman was an official sponsor,
helping out a person who had lost his mother.
That person is the ex-secretary
of the Chairman, my father.
That is something I did not expect coming.
I wanted to confirm of the work you were
going to put in to Sunjin Group's future.
Currently, there is a fight going on
that is disadvantageous to Lee Hae Joon.
Now, can I help you?
Okay, the only way to block the sale of the
store is to become the real Lee Hae Joon.
- Hello. - Hello.
Hello!
Hi friend!
I came to raise the sales!
Hello.
Hong Nan was at the pub. Is
she not your manager anymore?
That restaurant was
originally her brother's.
I've heard that before.
She taught me how to box, saying her
brother taught her when she was younger.
Her brother was originally the chef there.
He also boxed on the side.
It seems like you're
close to Hong Nan, too.
Han Gi Tak...
This person's name...
is Han Gi Tak.
Han Gi Tak?
I liked him a lot.
This person died...
Now, his younger brothers
are protecting me.
This person appeared
like it was meant to be.
Miss Da Hye, are you okay?
Yes, I'm okay.
That's strange. What's happening?
Branch Manager!
Have you seen this?
Oh my world!
The preparation for the temporary share
holder's meeting is going well, right?
So that we can secure the decision to
sell, make sure you manage the Directors.
The audio file that was
posted on the internet,
- Was it your voice that was recorded?
- What are you saying?
The one person who said
he killed Han Gi Tak,
It's spreading fast that it's your voice.
Tell them to stop saying nonsense.
As I am sensitive, facing the sale of
the store, who is trying to mess it up?
There is also movement from
the prosecutor's side.
CEO, there's a big problem!
If it's the truth, I can't
consider you as the CEO anymore.
What's wrong? Is there a problem?
Well... Are you okay?
I think this is talk about Gi Tak Hyung.
What should I do CEO?
You dirty bastards.
Then according to the plan, Han Gi Tak...
Kill them! Those filthy rats!
Then I will follow along with the plan
I saw that too, but is
that this mall's chairman?
No way...
Die, you filthy rats!
So, as planned, Han Gi Tak...
Han Gi Tak...
Die, you filthy rats!
Cha Jae Gook.
Da Hye... I'm sorry, looks
like I have to leave.
Miss Yi Yeon, are you okay?
Of course! I'll see you next time.
Die! You filthy rats!
You killed Han Gi Tak.
Who in the world told you this nonsense?!
Did yo order the killing of Han Gi Tak?
I'm Cha Jae Gook. How would, killing
a thug like him, benefit me?
I will kill everyone
that's been saying that.
Alright,
It can't be you.
If it is you, I will demolish you.
Right, you're finally showing
your actual self, Lee Hae Joon.
The people's misery that
you've stepped on...
I will help you feel that misery soon, too.
No...
Song Yi Yeon...
No matter how mean that person is...
He would never go this far.
Hong Nan, I'm sorry. I have things
to do so I'll be leaving first.
Did you hear that?
Cha Jae Gook, Na Seuk Chul...
They killed Hyungnim.
Follow Song Yi Yeon.
Is she the problem right now?
Your brother was killed!
- I'm asking you.- Han Hong Nan!
Think about what Han Gi Tak wants.
Miss Hong Nan, are you okay?
This is what I wanted to say.
Here.
Are you okay?
I'm not.
I'm not okay whatsoever.
I didn't live that nicely.
But it makes me wonder if I lived mean
enough to make someone want to kill me.
What are you saying?
Throwing away my family,
hurting the person I love.
I wonder if this is the punishment
I'm receiving for those things.
Stop saying this!
I will definitely, 100% find
out who made you like this!
In that time, just stay
next to Hong Nan's side.
She asked me if I was okay.
Even though I am feeling so
guilty because I died that way.
Since I can't stay by her side,
in my place,
stay by her side and protect her.
Even if it's just for the
remainder of your time.
I promise. I will dedicate
all of the time I have left.
And I'll stay by her side.
Han Gi Tak. That person's
name is Han Gi Tak.
I told you if you cry everywhere, you're
the Ugly One. You're so cool, my sister.
Where are you going?
Da Hye... Da Hye?
Did you have a bad dream?
May be it's because I feel worried
but something feels strange.
I'm uneasy, I feel like
something bad will happen.
Can I ask for a favor?
You can ask me anything.
Even if you leave,
don't leave without telling me.
At least let us do our
farewells before you leave.
I understand. I promise.
You finally showed up.
Did you really do it?
You... You ordered for
Han Gi Tak to be killed?
The first thing you say after years
of not coming in here, is that?
It's not true right? It's not, right?
Say something! It's not right?
Tell me that it wasn't you!!
You have to not done it! You didn't do it!
No!! No no no!!
Yeah, I killed him. I
tried to kill that punk.
I told them to rip him to pieces and leave no
trace of him and kill him, is that enough?!
Please tell me it wasn't you.
No! Nope!
I killed him! Why? It's
because of you, Song Yi Yeon.
It was because of you.
Timing and Subtitles brought to
you by The Possessed Team @ Viki
Where are you? I don't have much time left.
Are you going into the
prosecutor's office?-Yes.
CEO, don't you think a humble
looking clothing will be better?
Why should I? Did I commit a crime?
Welcome.
What is all of this?
Cha Jae Gook is currently denying the charge that
he ordered the killing at the Prosecutor's office.
But Jeong Ji Hoon and Choi Seung Jae said,
that there were lots of
questionable aspects to your case.
So I looked into it again.
The truth behind Han Gi Tak's death.
Spill what you have.
Here, first, the whereabouts of the black
box that should've been at the site.
Second, the paparazzi and the driver,
both of their whereabouts are unknown.
Third, in the site where there
are no CCTVs to be found.
They made the accident happen in a
place where there are no CCTVs.
-So what?-So! What do you think we need?
Brain. We will find out what
happened through your memories.
Oh, Seung Jae. Let's talk later.
What happened, Boss? The police
came to the restaurant too.
- What?-They're looking for you. What
did they mean by a case of violence?
Exactly what happened—
So you wanna go, huh? Alright
then, let's go to the end.
Han Gi Tak was in the midst of following the
paparazzi to show that Song Yi Yeon was innocent.
He found about the Yoo Hyuk's assult
and assumed that he fell into a
trap that was set up by somebody.
From following the paparazzi,
you got in the first accident.
The second accident was when the
truck came at Han Gi Tak's car.
That's when he officially died.
Do you remember anything regarding
the accident? Anything strange?
I'm not sure.
Now that I think about it...What's this?
Outer limit?
There was a cigarette in my pocket.
What's with this?
It's been quite a long
time since I quit smoking.
Are you alright, Ahjusshi?
Are you dead or alive?
Ahjusshi!
Seems like he's dead.
I took care of the driver.
Go then.
What should I do, Chairman?
These dirty scumbags.
- Then as contract, Han
Gi Tak... Kill that trash!
Just do it as planned. And
make sure there's no trace.
At the Prosecutor, he said that the statement
he made about killing him was just a metaphor.
The original plan was to lock Song Yi
Yeon in the house with the scandal.
Yes, I will clean up Han
Gi Tak without a mess.
You worked hard. Now just rest.
Na Seok Cheol, you punk...
He used Cha Jae Gook to kill Han Gi Tak.
How sad. He should fall into hell's pit.
The person to commit your hit
and run was also Na Seok Cheul.
Na Seok Cheol, that guy...
What is his motive?
The person that was like
his parent, Big Hyungnim.
Killing his friends and only
following the line of the money.
Now, he has nothing to lose.
Now that Cha Jae Gook is like that. The
remaining hope for Na Seok Cheol is...
The secret account number?
Until Na Seok Chul dies,
I have to be Han Gi Tak's sister.
It has to be.
Will it be alright? After we pass on,
Da Hye and Yi Yeon... Will they be alright?
I have to hurry and catch Na Seok
Cheol while I'm still around.
What's this? Why is yours so different from
mine? How come you have so little time left?
What's different!?
What did you do?
It's not that Kim Yeong Soo's time got shorter.
I'll just tell you that it got longer.
Could it be... You have
some of your time to me?
They said you can't pass two days.
It's for the sake of my younger sibling.
This person, in this time, I told
you to do well to your wife.
Really pathetic.
- Pathetic?- Pathetic?
What am I supposed to do when
I want to forget but I can't?
I want to take it out of this
heart, but it doesn't work.
They're in front of my eyes and it
makes me want to pull my eyes out.
Is that being pathetic?
I'm the most pathetic
person on this planet.
How nice would it be if he was there?
To see how pretty and energetic
your sister grew up...
That would've been so nice it together.
Oppa?
Oh my! How can that be?
My wish came true.
I wanted to have a picture with you.
♪ Are we not destiny now? ♪
I'm sorry.
♪ Now are we strangers? ♪
Turning around because
I wanted to so meanly.
Because I couldn't hold
in how much I missed you.
Trying to find you in any way I
could because I'm a selfish wench.
I'm sorry.
Even though I knew that you were a person
who had hard time forgetting about me,
And I kept telling you to forget me.
♪ Because I love you too much ♪
For constantly telling you to go away.
For telling you to blow off.
I'm sorry.
♪ Always being greedy ♪
Because I...
Love you, Oppa.
♪ For once ♪
I'm sorry.
♪ I have never regretted it ♪
♪ The fact that I love you ♪
♪ And ♪
Song Yi Yeon...
No, no need to be sorry.
Cha Jae Gook isn't the one that
made Han Gi Tak like that.
You don't have to feel guilty.
Cha Jae Gook is probably very
worn out by what's been going on.
So you have to take care
of Young Chan, right?
I came to say that.
Then, I'm going to go.
Show me your face. I have to leave soon.
Since I finished everything
I had to do here.
Sunjin
15 th Sunjin department store
Extraordinary Directors Meeting
CEO!
Long time no see, Directors.
I heard something odd. I heard
something has been added.
(1) Dismissal of the CEO.
(2) Putting the mall up for sale
Number one, do you think this will pass?
But, who's idea would this have been?
Was it you? Did you do it?
What kind of bastard
would dare to fire me?!
It was me.
Lee Hae Joon, with what
authority you dare to...
That's because I'm the
majority shareholder.
What?
Until now, I was buying it up a bit by bit, thanks
to you who make the stock price drop significantly.
It's enough if it's 4.9%, right?
The image of Sunjin Mall is being shaken by the
continuous deteriorating image of the Chairman.
To move in the direction
that the company wants and
to withstand the adverse wind where our roots
don't shake, we have to make Sunjin like that.
For those reasons, I request that
we dismiss the CEO Cha Chae Gook..
Father, you raised a son well.
You must be happy. Since you
got one out of the two right.
The voting for the dismissal
of Cha Jae Gook has started.
We will vote now.
Everyone who wishes this to
pass, please raise your hands.
Cha Jae Gook's dismissal has
passed with everyone in favor.
For now, Lee Hae Joon, you
take over as the CEO.
It is a great decision you made.
It was for the company.
Are you trying to comfort me?
I know that you weren't
trying to kill Han Gi Tak.
Get lost.
You finally got the company.
Yeah.
But why are we seeing each other here?
It's awkward.
I decided to meet with Da Hye?
What?
Sit down. You know you've
been wanting to see her.
She's the one that said she
wanted to meet you first.
What?
Hong Nan!
This... I found it when I
was cleaning your room.
The kid on this picture is me.
I don't know why it was there.
Tell me, how did get have this?
Truthfully...
I found your brother.
But I can't tell you about his
name, his age and his whereabouts.
It's something the person doesn't want.
Although he can't can't show himself to
you, but one thing I am sure about is
that they love you very much and let you
go because they wanted to protect you.
My brother... is Han Gi Tak?
It's too far.
What are you doing? You have no guts?
Wait. They saw us!
Hey!
Father!
♪ I never, not once ♪