New Tales of Gisaeng
Episode 51
Soon Deok...
Yes.
Come to our place.
Together with Director Geum.
Did Master Jeong contact you?
It's not that, but it's important.
All right,
If I'm to come with
Director, then the evening.
It's fine with me.
Yes.
Did Master Jeong contact her?
It's not that, but Hwa Ran
unnie says to come by.
Please come check this, to
see if it's done right.
Yep.
Yes, Madame Oh.
Are you busy?!
No.
Can you stop by here today?
By myself?
Yes, yourself for now.
I got it. I'll come by before five.
Okay.
Dear, when are we going
to make winter kimchi?
We have to wait until it's cooler.
If we pickle them now, they'll get ripen too soon.
Our in-law's home... it's really so great.
Starting from the front garden, it's enormous.
Wish I could take a look around.
I'm sure they'll invite us soon.
Dear, how do you feel?
Am I strange?
No.
My mind feels refreshed, and
I think it's gone for good.
That's a relief
I should be good enough to
go to the company, right?
How many hours can you actually
work though, if you go now?
Just go on a stroll with Andre instead.
Then you come too, Dear.
Me too?!
Yep.
Andre, let's go.
Um, could we go somewhere far?
Enjoy a drive too.
Oh, how did it go?
It went well.
Are all his symptoms gone?
Yes.
Oh, that's good.
Please tell the madame I said thank you.
I didn't tell her it was Chairman Ah and
made it sound like it was someone else.
I see.
Is Sa Ran okay during all this?
She was quite startled and
worried, but I think she's fine.
Alright, then call me again
if someone else happens.
Yes, please hang up.
I keep wanting to eat.
Then you should be eating
a proper meal with rice.
Not really feel up to rice yet.
I'll run an errand and come back.
Oh, it's hot, after walking around.
Yep.
Kid.
Now I know what true happiness is.
What is that?
Being together with family,
without any issues.
That's right.
Earlier, at the temple, I prayed.
That if they would pull away the
ghost, I would live diligently...
even more diligently than I have until now.
Working diligently, you mean?
Work diligently too, but put
my best into my family too.
Up until now, to be honest,
the company was priority.
Really?
Can I count on that from now on?
Wait and see. I won't change.
There will be guests coming.
Have it so that they don't look for me.
Yes.
Yes?!
You said you'd be coming in the evening.
I think it'll be hard for Director
to come, because of the patients.
And I was curious too.
Does it have to be both of us?
Master Jeong...
there's nothing wrong, right?
He hasn't contacted us.
I said not to look for me. Who is it?
You have a guest here.
- Omo. -Hello!
I thought you couldn't come.
I had a patient who was in a bad
condition, but his condition improved.
Do you want some tea?
I already drank a lot today.
Today is a very happy day for me.
That's why I asked to meet.
Are you getting married?
No.
Director will probably understand
this by looking at it.
Genetic test result.
I'll tell you the conclusion first.
Soon Deok's daughter's been found.
You did?
Is she living well?
Very.
Where?!
Please don't be startled. It's actually...
It's Sa Ran
Sa Ran?!
Really?!
That's what the test result shows.
What did you test with?
Blood test. Last time, you
had a nosebleed, right?
How can it be Sa Ran?
It was an ahjumma who worked at
our house who took the child.
I thought it was a possibility too.
So, I asked my mother-in-law and she said no.
She said she went to check and
Sa Ran's mom isn't that ahjumma.
Why did she go check?
Because Sa Ran resembles my
mother-in-law so much from her youth.
It's for sure.
Sa Ran said this to me when
she was getting married...
that she was a foundling.
Her current mom is her step-mom
and her real mom passed away
when she was in high school.
But she later found out that
wasn't her real mom either,
but the mom who raised her.
How could it be?
It's probably the case that her deceased mom
was the ahjumma who worked
at Director Geum's house.
Are you sure?
Last week,
after I heard the whole story from Soon
Deok, and I was about to go to sleep.
Sa Ran's story came to my thoughts.
For it to be just a coincidence...
the circumstances are too similar,
so even though I still had doubt...
I called Sa Ran to come the next day.
I said she looked like she was
indigested and I pricked her fingers.
Then, I asked Doctor Kim Woo Jin of Daekyung
Hospital to run a DNA test for blood relations.
The result came out today,
and I was told it's a 99. 9% match.
Blood relations without a doubt.
Soon, Ah Da Mo will be coming here.
I was afraid it would startle her too much.
Since she's with child, I don't
want to startle her and the fetus.
So I called her husband to come first.
Sa Ran is?
Sa Ran is?!
But... the test couldn't be wrong...
it couldn't be wrong.
The blood from both were submitted
properly, and the result is this.
What are we to do... our Sa Ranee...
our pitiful daughter.
Because of this foolish mom of hers...
she had to become a gisaeng too.
All the food for the
hair-raising ceremony...
I made them with these hands of mine!
How could it happened?
What do I do?
She grew up thinking they
were her real parents.
But after the remarriage, her
current step-mom told her.
And that's how she ended
up becoming a gisaeng.
The first day she came, saying
she wanted to become a gisaeng.
The girl came in a daze.
Her wounds appeared to be so grave to me.
So I sent her away, telling
her to reconsider.
Da Mo... is he coming here without knowing?
Yes,
He said he'd be here by five.
She went through that kind of neglect...
that kind of pain.
Regardless, the end result is good.
How can I face Sa Ran now? With what right?
I asked her last time, and she said she was trying
hard to force herself not to think about it.
Since she didn't have a
way to find her parents.
Think of it as fate.
Regardless of what...
you've found her now, so it's good now.
A good thing for you both.
Omo, she's bleeding again.
She needs to lay down and stabilize a bit.
Go to the room next door and lay down.
I want to see her now.
After Da Mo gets here,
we'll discuss with him.
Get ahold of yourself.
I'm all right, I am all right.
Here.
Hello.
Have you been well?
I heard you'll be a dad next year.
Who said that?
Please go in
Did something unpleasant happen?
I've shed some rare tears.
I think we need to go.
Her nosebleeding won't stop.
You came.
Oh, you're!...
I'll call you later.
Yes.
Did he come with Kitchen Head?
Yep,
I think you'll need to
change how you address them.
And I will lower my speech
to you too, from now on.
Yes,
I should be calling her Madame, but I've
gotten too used to calling her Kitchen Head.
Not Kitchen Head, and not Madame either.
Actually, she's your mother-in-law.
Since Han Soon Deok and Director
Geum are Sa Ran's real parents.
You also knew, Chief Madame?
That Sa Ran was left outside Ra Ra's house?
You already knew?
Yes.
How?
Father-in-law knew which house they took Sa
Ran from, all these years, as it turns out.
Even though, previously he said he didn't know,
when I had my sister-in-law ask him about it.
I followed the address he gave and went to see
the house, and it was actually Ra Ra's house.
Director Geum's house.
But then?
Then, you should've revealed the truth.
Sa Ran didn't want that.
She said it would make her feel too
wretched and awkward to her friend.
On the off-chance that it's true,
I went behind Sa Ran's back
and hired an acting ahjumma.
But then?
They told her no one came
to look for the foundling.
Came to look for the child?
Yes.
Who said that?
Who said no one looked for it?
Since she said it was a middle-aged
madame, it must have been Kitchen Head.
It's somebody else.
It might be Ra Ra's real mother
Did you hear this from my mother-in-law?
Gong Joo's mother?!
Yes.
Han Soon Deok and...
Sa Ran's genetic test... I applied for it.
And today it came out as them being
biologically mother and daughter.
How could that be?
Director Geum knew Han Soon
Deok before he was married,
and that's when Sa Ran was conceived.
For many reasons, Soon Deok found
herself unsuitable for him,
so she didn't go meet him as promised.
And a few months later is when
she found out she was pregnant.
When Director Geum met with the woman
the families matched together,
he married Ra Ra's mother.
So what could she do?
She had the baby and left
it outside the Geum's.
But he sent his own child
away to a stranger?
Without knowing.
Soon Deok, she...
She's too innocent, like her name says.
She thought he would know and didn't say
it was his daughter on a piece of paper.
That family never imagined
it was their bloodline.
And, the deceased grandfather
said they wouldn't raise her.
Why?
Because his second daughter-in-law
was about to give birth very soon.
And that's how the ahjumma who worked there
ended up taking Sa Ran away to raise.
This is all really true?
The fact that Soon Deok had a baby...
she only told me that last week.
The part about the child taken
by the working ahjumma.
Concurred with Sa Ran's story.
And that's why I submitted
a test to be done.
With what?
Soon Deok...
she was so upset that day,
she had a nosebleed.
So, with that,
and with the blood from pricks I did on
Sa Ran, saying she looked indigested...
And the result...
came out today, saying
they are blood-related.
I was so shocked and joyful.
Soon Deok...
she just found out the truth not long ago
and went into a deep weeping session.
And suffered another round of nosebleed.
I hope nothing is wrong with her.
She couldn't even walk properly.
It's true, without any mistakes, right?
The blood test, and all
the circumstances concur.
Since she's pregnant.
I didn't want her to get too startled.
Soon Deok is quite startled right now.
Thank you.
I am so happy too, beyond
anything I can express.
If I tell her, she
probably won't believe me.
Please tell her yourself.
You think she'll be okay?
It's a joyful event. It won't go wrong.
Sa Ran longs for them so
much, quietly by herself.
Subtitles brought to you
by NTOTG team @ viki.com
Hello?
Busy?
I was making cheese.
Make cheese?
Cottage cheese.
Never heard of it.
You are something. Is it good?
It's light, but rich in taste.
I want to eat some.
It's easy. I'll teach you.
You don't even call, you brat.
You heard about me, right?
Yep, congratulations!
Actually I was going to call you.
No need for words.
I'll eat that cottage cheese instead.
Yep, so come tomorrow.
This needs to rest for a day.
My father-in-law isn't fond
of me leaving the home.
So he told me to call my
friends to come to the house.
Oh, look how you're bragging so much now.
I have a future father-in-law
too, I'll have you know.
In the U. S.?
No treasure is a real treasure
until you can wear it.
It's so good.
I might be late. You sleep first.
Alright.
Wow, this scent...
Maybe we should've called
first before coming?
Yes.
Omo.
Welcome.
Father and mother-in-law are eating out.
Okay.
You haven't had dinner yet, right?
I don't have any appetite to eat.
I ate lunch late.
Let's go to our room.
Chief Madame has something to tell you.
Should I set the dinner table?
You'll at least have some tea, right?
No.
What is the matter?
It's nothing bad.
Get your heart prepared
calmly and don't be startled.
Are you ready?
Go ahead.
Honey... we found your parents.
Rea... lly?
They are people you already know.
None other than Director Geum and his wife.
Don't joke.
It's not a joke.
Last time... the day I gave you a bracelet.
I said you looked indigested
on purpose to draw your blood.
So I could do a DNA test.
I had one done with Soon Deok's.
And today the result came out,
saying you two are blood-related.
Soon Deok was startled too and she was
so traumatized she had nose-bleeding.
She's laying at Geum Hospital right now.
It's really true?
Kitchen Head is...
Then, none other than Ra Ra's dad is...
Your real dad.
How?
Soon Deok thought Ra Ra was,
for twenty-five years...
She lived thinking Ra Ra was her daughter.
By the time she gave birth, the
director was already married.
And that's why she left the
baby on the doorsteps.
Thinking they would raise the baby for sure.
For just in case,
since she didn't know
who'd discover the baby.
Since she was afraid of causing
distress to the family.
She left the child without writing a line.
That the child was the director's child.
She thought the director
would know for sure.
But how was he supposed to know?
Since your grandfather said
they would not raise it.
The mom who raised you...
She happened to work
there, and she took you.
That's how things happened.
The important thing is that they
didn't abandon you on purpose.
Kitchen Head took you to your dad's house.
But Director Geum had no idea.
That was what happened.
Last week, Soon Deok
came to my house crying.
That she actually had given
birth to a daughter.
And that daughter...
She lived thinking that was Ra Ra.
But when she met Director Geum and heard
the story, it turned out she wasn't.
So, she had to find her child.
But her mother-in-law said they had gotten
no response, after putting out so many ads.
So they should just...
give up.
They put out ads before, looking for
the ahjumma who worked at the house.
She asked me what she was supposed to do.
Without finding the child,
she had no confidence she could endure life.
This is really true, right?
It's without a doubt.
Don't cry too much. For the baby's sake.
Then...
Ra Ra is my younger sister (by cousin)?
Yup.
And Ja is your cousin too, and so is
Yeon Sang, who you haven't met yet.
This feels like a dream.
I was so curious about them
and longed for them so much.
Meet tomorrow.
Soon Deok needs to be stable today.
She's not ill with a disease, is she?
It's not that.
All these years...
I've never seen her nosebleed before.
Last time...
when she talked about you,
and today, just twice.
I'll try and call her.
Yes.
How is Soon Deok?
She's getting an injection
of Ringer's right now.
I'm here at Sa Ran's home.
Did you tell her?
Yes.
What does she say?
She's crying, of course.
She's not resenting us?
No.
Meet her tomorrow.
It's late today.
If I could...
I know how you must feel.
Later.
I'll call Da Mo.
Yes. Hang up then.
He's too choked up to talk.
Feed her something.
Yes.
Alright.
Madame's been admitted to the hospital?
She had a sudden bout of severe nosebleed,
so she's at the hospital,
getting a Ringer's IV.
This is all that's left of
the sweet bean porridge.
So this is actually made
for you, by your mother.
She attended our wedding too.
And they walked you in, for
the bridal entrance as well.
They put in their parental
duties, as I see it.
Subtitles brought to you
by NTOTG team @ viki.com
Over here.
But I'm not late.
Just got here early somehow.
Coffee?
What are you two?
My wife.
I heard a lot about you.
Like what?
That you two live without
a lot of affection.
So what?
Just... that.
Do you like my husband?
Yes.
Oh yeah?
Give me your address.
Why?
I'll send him to you.
So you can live with him.
Dongho Apartment, building 605, number 103.
Are you that Ae Rin?
Yup. Hwang Ae Rin.
Dongho Apartment, building 605, number 103?
You live in a nice place, I see.
You escort her home well?
No, just a few times.
She's the one who likes me. Right?
You suit each other well.
Hey, Gong Joo.
The plan is a success?
Yeah, I think so.
You should go in my car!
You can come right away, right?
I'll pay you double.
Mother and father would be
so shocked and happy too.
Since you never know about
things, tell them tomorrow.
Just in case. I feel uneasy.
Why do you feel uneasy?
I feel like things will
change, after I sleep.
And they'll tell me there's
been a mistake or something.
Should we bet?
To me...
Not anyone else,
but those two...
that they are my real parents who bore me,
I can't believe it.
But I feel sure, without a doubt, now that
I've throught through all the situations.
What is it?
The fortune cooking! That day!
"Enjoy a happy day with your child."
It's true.
That was accurate like a ghost.
And we thought it was only accurate for us.
Could it really be true?
A normal blood test is one thing,
but a DNA test is without a doubt.
I think our Starling is our fortune baby.
I don't think I can sleep tonight.
Hello.
Ja's moving his stuff.
This way.
What is she talking about?
These books here, and
the stuff on this side.
No clothes?
In the closet over there.
Where are you moving these to?
Dongho Apartment, building 605, number 103.
Why?
I'll tell you later.
Ahjussi, you come here, please.
What brings you here?
Grandma told me to come
and see how sick she was.
Her migrane is a bit severe.
Shouldn't she get a CT scan or something?
Let's go and talk in my room.
Is it a very serious illness?
No.
Today,
something startled her.
What is it?
To you...
I feel bad and such.
What is it about?
Before I married...
I met your current aunt.
I told you that, right?
Yes, on an island.
She conceived a baby back then,
and I didn't know.
Without telling me,
she left the baby outside our house.
And we didn't now,
so we let the ahjumma who worked
for us take it to raise it.
Oh my gosh.
Your aunt had thought you were
her child for twenty-five years,
since your ages are similar.
How in the...
Then you have to find the child.
We found her today.
However...
She grew up under misfortune?
She's actually Sa Ran.
Sa Ran?
Yeah.
I was so startled and your aunt
was so startled as well...
And that's why she's in
that condition right now.
For real?
Chief Oh Hwa Ran of Buyonggak had a
DNA test done and told us the result.
I was on the phone with Sa Ran earlier
and I didn't sense that at all.
It was before she found out then.
This is outrageous.
The, it means Sa Ran's mom
used to work in our house.
But we saw her on the graduation.
How come you and everyone
else didn't recognize her?
Her current mom is a stepmom.
The deceased mom.
I can barely believe it myself.
Madame Oh said the blood
test was done perfectly.
But before I meet her tomorrow
and hear it myself...
It's probably not true.
I never heard from her that
her mom was her stepmom.
She told Madame Oh,
right before she married Da
Mo, that she was a foundling.
It looks like Da Mo's
family knew all this time.
When they were opposing her...
Now I remember.
Chairman Ah said,
other than being a gisaeng, Sa Ran...
She had another reason to be disqualifed,
but since it was her privacy, he
had no reason to talk about it.
So that was it.
All due to our fault.
But she and Gong Joo get along so well?
Because they are both good-hearted.
If it's all true,
then what do we do about Sa
Ran who is so pitiful...
From now on...
We need to treat her well.
Treating her well...
can that compensate for 25 years?
She had to enter Buyonggak too.
She suffered so much to get married.
You don't know.
How could you have done that?
How could you not recognize your
own child and give her away?
Grandpa...
If I were Sa Ran,
I wouldn't be able to forgive you.
Ra Ra is suppose to come over tomorrow.
Should I give her a call?
To say what?
Say you're not feeling well,
or that something came up.
I'll just deal with it head-on.
It's going to be another wound to Ra Ra.
What if she comes to resent and hate me too?
She wouldn't.
What wrong did you ever do?
Why do you have your phone off?
The battery went out.
Sorry.
There was a small wreck
right in front of me.
What is this talk about you
moving to Dongho Apartment?
Dongho Apartment?
She says you're moving
and the men are packing.
It's nearly done.
What's that?
I'll give you the divorce,
so you go live with her.
Divorce?
Actually. Honey, don't misunderstand.
Misunderstand?
100% misunderstand.
I'm back.
Then what did I see with my eyes?
Dear, these two are divorcing.
What are you talking about?
Geum Ja is having an affair.
I caught him today.
What?
Is this the truth?
No, what happened was...
She kept sending texts to Geum Ja, and he went out
with his hair done, so I followed him in a taxi.
And I caught him meeting a
girl named Hwang Ae Rin.
She said they were dating.
This rascal!
Dear!
I didn't do it! She...
Regardless, it's true you strayed one eye.
It's not that! Ra Ra noona...
she's her junior alum.
You heard yourself that
she said she liked you.
Dongho Apartment, building
605, number 103, right?
Yes.
AJUSHI! NO!
I'll pay for your service. How much is it?
Go now.
I already paid you.
Now, hurry and move these.
It's not!
Why are you moving my stuff
without my permission?
Call Ra Ra noona.
It was just a show.
She suggested we should put on a double act.
Just go along for now, and leave the stuff.
Yes, please go.
Please go.
Say something that makes sense.
You think I'm a dummy?
Just give her a call first!
Yeah, do.
Maybe her battery's out,
but she's not answering.
Noona said I needed to
make you feel jealous.
Write a novel, why don't you?
I guess she'll take your side though,
since blood is thicker than water?
Noona!
Ae Rin. Explain to her.
You stay still.
What is his relationship with
that girl named Hwang Ae Rin?
I'm not in any mood to
talk about that right now.
Why?
I'm about to be kicked out.
She says to divorce.
It was your idea.
What's wrong with her?
What does Ra Ra say?
She said Sa Ran was so pitiful.
Are you able to meet her tomorrow?
My headache's pretty much dissipated.
However,
I feel so happy,
and my heart is ready to burst.
I can only make time in the afternoon.
I have to go home and
prepare some things too.
Yes, go ahead and hang up please.
He says to meet around three
tomorrow, your father.
He wants to meet quickly, but he has
some patients with morning appointments.
Where?
He says to come to the house.
Then, I should just go alone?
Why? How can I not go?
But how can you vacate your job?
They'll be fine.
They are coming in.
Was the movie good?
Yup, very much.
It was chaotic and complicated.
It is, isn't it?
You look like you've been crying.
I haven't.
Did you upset her?
Ah, no!
Why the alcohol table?
It's something I need to
tell you after a drink.
What?
You want to tell me to leave?
Nope.
It's about Director Geum...
and Han Soon Deok.
They're separating?
They had a child together, as it turns out.
I only found out a few days ago too.
And, that child is none other than...
Sa Ran.
It's Sa Ran?
Chairman Ah's daughter-in-law?
How did this happen?
Say something that makes sense.
It's a very long story.
Really?
None other than Sa Ran ssi?
Then the child our ahjumma
took is none other than...
It's dumb-founding, isn't it?
How could he not know his own child?
She didn't write any word that the
baby was the director's child,
in case it would trouble your marriage.
Then she should've at least
met with him to tell him.
She was afraid if they met, they
wouldn't be able to part and rekindle.
By then, Director Geum was
already a married man.
But still.
What crime did the child ever commit?
Sa Ran is the one who ended
up suffering everything.
Wow! It's really coming to an end. Thank you so
much Team Gisaeng! That's 26 weeks of hard work.
We all like to specially thank DramaDramaOK for
subbing 32,000+ lines for Gisaeng. That's dedication.
Our Gisaeng subbers are just as great: Jane316, Leekrn2011,
DaracyCollie, Q_park, PoshSlng, Tutixiu, Xnabi queen0flove16, Boshitang
Thank you seggers for waiting around for the uploads: Faraz3500, Shamsimadahi,
Allieg8ter, PoshSlng, Agatha, Sukig, Queenofl0ve16, serenasf95, Leoscorpion, Coatzin
Thank you Auntie Mame for all that editing. Thank you Nounoune,
Allieg8ter, Serenasf95for uploading the videos. Ahoxan for the srt files.
Thank you Everyone else for contributing
to New Tales of the Gisaeng!!
I love you.
Imagine how desperate I was
for your love to do that?
Are you down with bodyaches or what?
Mother.
I found our child.
You found the child, you said?
Yes.
Where does she live? And how?
It was Sa Ran.
I told you, it's not her.
We already went and checked.
The current mom is a stepmom.
The mom who raised her...
She passed from an illness, while
Sa Ran was in high school.
And the deceased mom is the
ahjumma who worked here.
Sa Ran said that?
I heard it from Hwa Ran unnie.
Before her wedding,
she told Unnie only.
That she was abandoned outside a front door.
That she was a foundling.
But still, it might not be her.
Maybe not our house, but another house.
Hwa Ran unnie had a DNA
test done with blood.
And called us to come. So she could tell us.
It's without a doubt.
How could this be?
It's Sa Ran? If only we had known.
Then, the old man wouldn't have had to died.
My husband.
Your mother-in-law?
She went to a gathering.
We love you Team Gisaeng!!
Thank you for every minute of it! ^_^
It looks delicious.
After I heard it.
I was so shocked.
And heartbroken.
How did you endure through it?
You were my unnie all this time?
Mother,
Sa Ran should be coming now.
If you cry like that,
you'll wipe yourself out.
How can I not cry?
All the suffering she went through...
we know about it.
Is that her?
It's probably your son.
How do you feel?
I can't begin to explain it.
And I still feel uneasy too.
But Ra Ra accepted it quite well.
She actually feels
heartbroken for me instead.
Since she knows all that you went through.
She's here?
Yes.
Together?
Son-in-law Ah was the one who rang.
I'm sorry, Sa Ran.
Your mom is such a fool.
I went to the temple because of you.
To pray that you'd grow up well.
To pray that I could find you.
I didn't even know that... and...
I resented you every now and then,
because things were so hard and
I wanted to see you so badly.
Did you really give birth to me?
If you are the foundling,
then it's without a doubt.
You really are a foundling?
Yes.
My deceased mom took me from
the house she worked at.
How are we to do with this? It's for sure~!
Oh my... my granddaughter.
Your grandpa looked for you and he got sick from
it and passed away because of it, my child.
He thought you could be the one.
So, we made up an excuse
and went to your house.
But she wasn't the woman.
And after that he couldn't rile
up enough energy to get up.
My dear...
Let me have a look.
Your grandpa was right.
You said your birthday was June 14th, right?
Yes.
That's the day you were
left outside the door.
You were actually born on the 8th.
Mother, please get ahold of yourself.
She also cried too much yesterday and ended up...
How can I be calm right now?
We went to your house, but she wasn't
the ahjumma who worked for us.
Imagine the despair.
After that, your grandpa
took to his sickbed.
He still couldn't give up and
wanted to do a DNA test.
He did?
Saying she clearly seemed
like our offspring.
But I stopped him and told him no.
How could I have imagined it?
Hair.
Your head hurts?
Which one should I give you?
Grandfather.
That day, he...
as he was passing away.
He put his hand out saying "hair"...
I thought he meant his head was aching, so I
was trying to give him the pill envelope.
Today, I spent some money
to keep up an appearance.
What appearance money?
The broads told me I should buy
since I have a rich son-in-law now.
So I couldn't just behave
as if I was poor either.
They say if a person starts to think they are
poor, then, they really will become poor.
You did great!
When we were little, the moms would squeeze
our noses to let the snots out, right?
That was meant for us to live big.
Really?
Yes.
I'm out right now.
When I said I broke up with Da Mo ssi.
She told me to go be a gisaeng.
I said no, and she began to torment me.
She knew I drank milk every morning,
but she would empty the cartons.
Why, that...
And put only my shoes out in the
balcony where sun comes in.
My world...
It was quite difficult.
But I still endured through.
So one day, she...
Told me about that.
That you were a foundling?
Since they fed and educated me...
If the marriage is a dead issue...
It's my duty to, at least,
earn money to pay them back.
Oh my, and her face didn't look so evil.
It's all my fault.
Because I was so pathetic.
I couldn't tell anyone about it.
And this is my first time mentioning it.
What else?
Now that I've talked about it.
I feel a bit less burdened.
How broken-hearted you must have felt.
To go through that...
It's all in the past.
Regardless, I entered Buyonggak and
that led to marrying Da Mo ssi.
And thanks to Madame Oh, we meet like this.
I don't want to resent you.
You should resent.
I feel so happy.
And thankful.
How did you ever...
How did our daughter get
to grow up so beautifully.
Who is it?
Oh, our daughter... without calling first?
What happened to son-in-law Geum?
He didn't come.
Did you and Ja fight?
No.
Unnie found her real parents.
Sa Ran did?
How?
It's none other than Ja's uncle and aunt.
Uncle and aunt... then Ra Ra's?
Yes.
So this means Unnie walked down the aisle
holding her real dad's hand, at her wedding.
You little brat. What joke is this?
Then call Unnie and see if it's a joke.
Ra Ra unnie said they
even did a DNA test too.
Mom, what are you going to do now?
What?
About forcing her to become a gisaeng?
What are you doing?
I'm playing with Andre.
Don't you want to see some Grand
Prince, since it's been a long time?
Shark fin, you mean?
Yes.
Come out with Sa Ran to Beijing House.
Sa Ran went out and isn't home.
But she's with child. Where?
Da Mo came home during the
day and took her out.
Did they go to the hospital or something?
Nothing like that.
I suppose they have some
business to tend to.
What business to tend to,
during his work hour?
Just bat an eye.
I'm sure they'll tell us later.
You should receive our greeting.
On what right?
It wasn't your choice either.
Do that.
Is this a dream or is this reality?
Do one for Grandpa too, though
it's not his memorial day.
Yes.
If he were alive, how happy would he be.
As you know, I made a lot of mistakes.
Please forgive me and accept me fondly.
I will do well in the future.
We share the same sentiment.
They should actually be grateful to us.
Grateful for what?
For raising her. And putting her through school.
And feeding her. And clothing her.
Did you feed and clothe her?
And educate her?
Spouses are two hearts in one body, girl.
If your father did, then we did it together.
Then you shouldn't have made her a gisaeng.
Why are you nitpicking about it?
Because I feel shameful to face them.
No need to feel ashamed.
We're not the one who kicked
out our own bloodline.
All we ever did was a great deed, of raising
her like she was our own child, you know.
Don't you sigh.
I'll eat it well.
Yes. Yes.
I'm not in any mind to cook.
Oh, of course.
Next time, I'll make you
something delicious.
Is this a dream or is this reality?
That's what I want to say.
Would that be enough, eating like that?
Yes.
I can only eat things that are refreshing.
This is your first meal
at your parent's house.
Will it do that you're only
eating rice and cucumbers?
It's yummy.
You don't have ice cream, do you?
We do.
Your mother-in-law likes walnut ice cream.
Really?
Sa Ran's been living on ice cream
and sweet bean porridge these days.
You two mother and daughter are alike.
The issue is with son-in-law Ah's.
Would they treat us like in-laws now?
They won't even look at us.
They'll just be chummy with Ra Ra's.
Aren't you hungry?
You're hungry under the situation now?
These kids... not even calling.
Just leave them be.
So they can enjoy a date.
Yesterday, we did.
The house feels like a temple building.
But we have Andre.
Andre is just Andre.
Are you really fine?
If you ever sense that I'm
strange, even a little,
tell me right away.
Yes.
Do you remember the fortune cookie?
It was accurate exactly on that day.
To have a happy day with your child.
It was, indeed.
And Master Jeong was so
accurate like a ghost too.
He said if you marry, you
will find your child.
That's why they rushed to marry.
I can't believe this.
Want me to pinch you?
But Mother-in-law, you are so young, you
must feel wronged to be called "grandma"...
No
I am so happy.
And joyful beyond words can express.
What about you, Father-in-law?
I am the same, of course.
Did you, by chance, have a
conception dream of me?
Of course.
My... she still doubts?
Didn't she even dream your
conception dream for you?
Yes.
The sky had a very full moon so I was
looking at it completely enraptured.
And in just a little bit, from that big moon,
small moons were popping out like popcorn.
They all popped out and fell into my skirt.
It's a great dream.
Of course.
It's a dream that means the
child will live well in luxury.
Your mom barely hung on
in life, with that dream.
Because she had such a sturdy dream.
And now all the dregs are gone.
A beautiful Sa Ran like you...
is my daughter.
Not just beautiful.
She's so good-hearted as well.
It's father.
Hello?
Why aren't you guys coming home?
We're about to leave.
Where are you?
I'll tell you after I get home.
You sure it's not because Sa Ran is ill?
It's not.
Alright.
Yes.
Tell your father I'd like to meet him first.
When would be good?
Tomorrow works too.
So, anytime that works with
your father's schedule.
Yes.
I wish I could talk to you
throughout the night.
I'll come again tomorrow, Grandma.
Alright.
Sa Ran.
You should live with us too.
Of course.
Yes.
What about me?
The thread won't follow the needle?
What expression do you suppose
my father would have?
It's all done.
Yes. I was going to wash my hands.
You haven't heard, right?
About what?
Miss Dan is Kitchen Head Han
Soon Deok's real daughter.
What?!
And the real dad is Director Geum.
So you mean, Eun Sung's
daughter-in-law, Dan Sa Ran is...?
Yes.
Oh my world.
Manager. Manager!
Where did you guys go for the whole day?
It wasn't a whole day.
Maybe you went to the villa?
To see the fallen leaves?
No.
Father...
Sa Ran found her real parents who bore her.
What?!
How?!
Through blood test.
Where do they live? In Seoul?
Yes.
We went to see them and had dinner.
They called you?
We only found out yesterday, but...
Father, don't be startled.
Those two who were seated at Sa Ran's
presiding seats, at the wedding.
Those two who sat at the
presiding seats were...
Hospital director Geum Eo San?
Yes!