[ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
[ VEHICLE APPROACHING ]
[ RUMBLING ]
[ RUMBLING INTENSIFIES ]
[ GURGLES, SPUTTERS ]
[ BIRD CAWING ]
I HAD A FEELING
IT WAS A DUSTER.
YOU GOT THE ONLY THREE DRY WELLS
IN PARADISE BASIN, HENRY,
AND TWO LEASES
EXPIRING NEXT WEEK.
WHAT ABOUT
THE BAILEY FIVE?
LOOKS BAD, HENRY.
DROPPED THE BID AT 6-5.
WE'RE FISHING FOR IT NOW.
WELL, YOU CAN'T SELL DUST,
HENRY,
SO YOU GOT TO HIGHTAIL IT
UP TO THE BIG CITY
AND GET YOURSELF
SOME SHOPPING MONEY QUICK, YES.
BILLY JOE, IS MONEY
ALL YOU EVER THINK ABOUT?
HENRY,
I AM AN ACCOUNTANT.
I'M SUPPOSED TO THINK
ABOUT MONEY.
SO YOU GO ON UP NORTH AND RAISE
$1.2 MILLION STARTING RIGHT NOW,
OR YOU'RE BROKE, YES.
HENRY, YOU'RE A RICH MAN,
AND A RICH MAN
CAN'T AFFORD TO GO BROKE.
[ UP-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYS ]
♪ HERE COME THE ♪
♪ WHEELER DEALERS ♪
♪ HIGHFALUTIN LOCAL YOKELS ♪
♪ DIAMONDS IN THE ROUGH ♪
♪ FANCY-DANCING CITY SLICKERS ♪
♪ THAT'S WHAT I CALL
WHEELER DEALERS ♪
♪ YEAH, LONG AS WE GOT MONEY,
THAT'S ENOUGH, YEAH ♪
♪ NOW, WE'RE JUST
ORDINARY PEOPLE ♪
♪ BUT WHEN WE GO TO TOWN ♪
♪ EVERYWHERE WE GO, WE'RE GONNA
LAY THAT MONEY DOWN ♪
♪ YOU KNOW YOU GOT TO
SPEND A DOLLAR ♪
♪ IF YOU WANT TO MAKE A DIME ♪
♪ JUST KEEP ON SPENDING MONEY
ALL THE TIME ♪
♪ THEY CALL US ♪
♪ WHEELER DEALERS ♪
♪ HIGHFALUTIN LOCAL YOKELS ♪
♪ DIAMONDS IN THE ROUGH ♪
♪ FANCY-DANCING CITY SLICKERS ♪
♪ JUST SOME KIND OF
WHEELER DEALERS ♪
♪ YEAH, LONG AS WE GOT MONEY,
THAT'S ENOUGH ♪
♪ FROM VERMONT TO CALIFORNIA ♪
♪ IT'S VERY MUCH THE SAME ♪
♪ THEY'LL TELL YOU
WE'RE THE KIND OF FOLKS ♪
♪ THEY'RE PROUD
TO KNOW BY NAME ♪
♪ WITH A QUAINT
NEW ENGLAND ACCENT ♪
♪ OR A GOOD OLD
TEXAS DRAWL ♪
HELLO, J.R.!
GOOD DAY, R.J.
HI AND HOW ARE Y'ALL?
♪ NOW, IF I EVER GET TO HEAVEN ♪
♪ I'M GOING THERE WHEN I DIE ♪
♪ GONNA MEET WITH
THE BOARD OF DIRECTORS ♪
♪ OF THAT COMPANY IN THE SKY ♪
♪ AND IF THEY GOT
A PLACE UP THERE ♪
♪ WHERE WEALTH
IS BOUGHT AND SOLD ♪
♪ SAINT PETER BETTER WATCH
HIS PEARLY GATES ♪
♪ AND GUARD THEM STREETS OF GOLD ♪
♪ HERE COME THE ♪
♪ WHEELER DEALERS ♪
♪ HIGHFALUTIN LOCAL YOKELS ♪
♪ DIAMONDS IN THE ROUGH ♪
♪ FANCY-DANCING CITY SLICKERS ♪
♪ AIN'T THAT
A BIG DEAL? ♪
♪ YEAH, LONG AS WE GOT MONEY,
THAT'S ENOUGH, YEAH ♪
SAVE YOUR
CONFEDERATE MONEY, BOYS.
WIDGETS IS COMING BACK
IN STYLE.
♪ DA, DA, DA, DA-A-A-A-A ♪
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ HORNS HONKING ]
TAXI.
TAXI!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING, LADY?
THERE, YOUNG MAN.
MAYBE THAT'LL TEACH YOU
SOME MANNERS.
OH.
YOU CAN'T GET A CAB
IN THE AIRPORT.
WHEN IT RAINS.
YOU CAN'T GET A CAB
UNLESS YOU DON'T WANT ONE.
ANY OTHER CITY,
YOU CAN PHONE FOR A CAB.
NOT NEW YORK.
YOU'RE JUST LIKE MY WIFE, MISTER.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND
THE ECONOMICS OF THE SITUATION.
THEN TEACH ME.
I'M INTERESTED IN THE ECONOMICS
OF ABOUT EVERY SITUATION.
WELL, THERE ARE 11,000 CABS
IN THE CITY
AND NO NEW PERMITS
FOR THE NEXT 25 YEARS.
NOW, SUPPOSE YOU WANT TO
BUY A CAB AND START HACKING.
YOU GOT TO GET
A NEW PERMIT, TOO.
NOW, THE TAB
ON A NEW PERMIT
IS $18,500
ON THE OPEN MARKET.
MM-HMM.
AND HOW MUCH
DID YOUR CAB COST, MR., UH...
FEINBERG?
$3,300. NEW.
MM-HMM.
AND THAT MAKES YOUR INVESTMENT,
UH, WITH THE PERMIT
COME TO ABOUT $22,000?
YEAH.
BUT DON'T TELL MY WIFE.
SHE'LL THINK I'M RICH.
[ BOTH CHUCKLE ]
MM-HMM.
MR. FEINBERG,
I'LL GIVE YOU $24,000
FOR YOUR CAB AND PERMIT.
YOU WANT TO BUY THE CAB?
RIGHT, BUT YOU
COME ALONG WITH IT.
I'LL NEED YOUR SERVICES
FOR A WEEK, MAYBE TWO.
NO, LOOK, MISTER.
I CAN'T SELL THE CAB.
I NEED IT.
WELL, I FIGURED THAT.
SO, WHEN I LEAVE,
I'LL SELL IT BACK TO YOU
FOR $22,000.
YOU WANT TO LOSE 2 GRAND
JUST TO KEEP YOUR FEET DRY
WHEN IT STARTS TO RAIN?
I DON'T LOSE, MR. FEINBERG.
YOU SEE,
I BORROW THE MONEY,
AND THEN I GET A DEDUCTION
ON THE LOAN INTEREST
AND ANOTHER
ON THE DEPRECIATION
AND ANOTHER ON THE LOSS
WHEN I SELL IT BACK TO YOU,
AND YOU MAKE
A NICE PROFIT.
YOU WIN AND I WIN.
UNH-UNH.
THERE GOT TO BE A LOSER
SOMEWHERE.
TAX MAN LOSES.
HE USUALLY DOES
ON A HENRY TYROON DEAL.
MISTER, YOU JUST
GOT YOURSELF A TAXI.
[ TELEPHONE BEEPS ]
YEAH?
HE DID?
HENRY'S NOT IN MIDLAND.
THEY SAID HE WENT UP TO NEW YORK.
NEW YORK?
YEAH, I BET OLD HENRY'S UP THERE
LOOKING FOR SOME LOOSE CHANGE.
THEY TELL ME HE HIT
NOTHING BUT DUST IN THE BASIN.
NOTHING BUT DUST.
THIS YEAR THERE'S A REAL JINX
ON HIM WHEN IT COMES TO OIL.
WELL, IF HE'S LOOKING
FOR MULLET IN NEW YORK,
IT LOOKS LIKE THAT'S WHERE
WE'LL FIND THE ACTION.
I RECKON WE BETTER SWING BY
FOR A LOOK-SEE.
WE BETTER SASHAY
UP TO NEW YORK.
YEAH.
RIGHT NOW, CHARLIE.
OH.
I CAN'T TELL
WHETHER I'M HUNG OVER
OR WHETHER I'VE GOT
SINUS TROUBLE.
WELL, SINCE YOU'VE GOT THE CHOICE,
WHY NOT MAKE IT SINUS TROUBLE.
OH, THANKS A LOT.
UH, THE FUZZ ON THAT TOUNGUE.
MY SINUSES DON'T REACH THAT FAR.
WHERE'D YOU PICK UP THE FUZZ?
I CAUGHT IT
AT A COCKTAIL PARTY.
I DON'T THINK
I ATE ENOUGH.
BET YOU ATE
ENOUGH OLIVES.
AND WHERE DID YOU
SPEND THE NIGHT?
ON THE GOOD SHIP
LOLLIPOP?
NO. WENT TO A GALLERY
WITH LEONARD.
A NEW ARTIST HE THINKS
IS THE COMING THING.
LEONARD STILL HAVING
HIS PROBLEMS?
STILL SEEING
THAT PSYCHIATRIST?
YOU'D HAVE PROBLEMS, TOO,
IF YOU WERE MARRIED TO THAT
WOMAN HE WAS MARRIED TO.
WELL, I'VE HAVE PROBLEMS
MARRIED TO ANY WOMAN.
OH, ISN'T IT AMAZING HOW I
SPARKLE SO EARLY IN THE MORNING?
WHY BOTHER SPARKLING?
WHEN A GIRL SPARKLES
DOWN ON WALL STREET,
SHE'S A THREAT.
WHEN SHE SPARKLES UPTOWN,
IN MY TERRITORY,
SHE'S A PROMISE.
I'LL STAY DOWNTOWN,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU BETTER QUIT SPARKLING
FOR LEONARD.
YOU WON'T GET ANYWHERE
WITH HIM.
A HEADSHRINKER'S
TOO MUCH COMPETITION.
IT PUTS A THIRD PARTY
IN THE ACTION.
LEONARD'S A PASTIME,
NOT A PROJECT.
IT'S COMFORTABLE
TO HAVE HIM AROUND.
HE HELPS ME WARD OFF
THE GRABBERS.
I'VE GOT TO RUN,
SO I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
NOW, YOU SEE, IF YOU WORKED
UPTOWN INSTEAD OF DOWN,
YOU WOULDN'T HAVE TO BOLT
SO EARLY.
WE COULD SHOP AT BONWITS
AT LUNCHTIME.
OH, UPTOWN IS JUST
A STATE OF MIND.
ME?
PUT UP ANOTHER $100,000?
HENRY, YOU MUST BE
OUT OF YOUR MIND.
YOU SURPRISE ME, LEN.
YOU'RE HESITATING.
WE WENT DOWN THE LINE
WITH YOU THIS YEAR,
AND WHAT DID IT GET US?
PART OWNERSHIP IN SIX OF THE
DEEPEST, DRIEST HOLES IN TEXAS.
YOU BOYS SURE GOT SHORT MEMORIES.
HOW ABOUT THE SEVEN WELLS
WE BROUGHT IN TWO YEARS AGO?
I DON'T BELIEVE IN LIVING
IN THE PAST.
YOU'RE SLOWING DOWN, HENRY.
MAYBE YOU'RE LOOSING YOUR TOUCH.
YOU USED TO HAVE
UNDERCURRENTS, HENRY.
I DON'T FEEL THE
UNDERCURRENTS ANYMORE.
LEN, A FEW YEARS AGO,
WHEN YOU HAD ALL THOSE SURPLUS
AIRPLANES YOU COULDN'T UNLOAD,
- YOU SAID, "SEND THEM TO
THE JUNKMAN," RIGHT?
- RIGHT.
WELL, JUST WHO WAS IT THAT SOLD
THEM AS AN AIR FORCE
TO A CERTAIN UNNAMED PARTY
IN CENTRAL AMERICA?
BUT WE GOT PAID
IN BANANAS.
YEAH, AND YOU FERRIED
THOSE BANANAS ON YOUR AIRLINE
AND CLEARED HALF A MILLION
DOLLARS, RIGHT?
AND YOU, FLINK.
WHO WAS IT THAT PUT YOU
ONTO THOSE 40,000
OBSOLETE JAPANESE CAMERAS?
YOU DID, HENRY,
BUT I --
I MADE YOU THE FIRST
AMERICAN IN HISTORY
TO EXPORT JAPANESE CAMERAS
TO JAPAN.
I DIDN'T MAKE BEANS
ON THAT DEAL.
OH, BUT WHEN WE IMPORTED THEM
AGAIN, YOU MADE A KILLING, HUH?
AND YOU, ACHILLES.
OF ALL PEOPLE TO HOLD OUT ON ME.
WHEN WE HAD
THOSE TANKER CHARTERS
AND THEY BOTTLED OUR SHIPS UP
IN THE SUEZ,
WHO WAS IT THAT SWAPPED
ALL THAT NAIL-POLISH REMOVER
FOR SIX MORE TANKERS
TO MEET OUR COMMITMENTS?
THAT I LIKED.
THAT WAS COMPLICATED.
YEAH.
JUST REMEMBER, BOYS.
NOBODY WHO HAS EVER
SOLD ME SHORT
HAS COME OUT
AHEAD OF THE GAME YET.
NOW, I WANT $100,000 FROM EACH
OF YOU, AND I WANT IT NOW.
Len: WELL...
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN
A PERCENTAGE PLAYER, HENRY.
COUNT ME IN.
I'LL GO ALONG
FOR THE RIDE.
IT'S AGAINST
MY BETTER JUDGMENT...
BUT I MADE A LOT OF MONEY
AGAINST MY BETTER JUDGMENT.
THANK YOU, GENTLEMEN.
- OKAY, BOY.
- RIGHTO.
Bear: LET'S GET TO
THAT LIST, WHITBY.
HERE IT IS RIGHT HERE.
IT'S EVERY STOCK THAT OSGOOD
BOUGHT BEFORE HE PASSED ON.
UM, MEGLO MANITOBA
IRON ORE.
HE BOUGHT IT IN 1951
FOR $3 A SHARE.
WHERE IS IT NOW?
A 61-CENT BID.
GREAT EASTERN OFFSHORE OIL,
COST $14...
SIX-CENT BID.
YOU MEAN WE HAVEN'T UNLOADED
THAT YET?
WELL, IT TAKE'S A WHILE TO
UNLOAD THE REAL DOGS, BULLARD.
MY BOY, SOMEWHERE IN
THIS VAST, VERDANT,
EVER-GROWING NATION OF OURS
MUST BE SOME PEOPLE
STUPID ENOUGH
TO BUY GREAT EASTERN
OFFSHORE OIL.
FIND THEM.
YES, SIR.
HERE'S ANOTHER REAL DOG,
BULLARD --
UNIVERSAL WIDGET.
DOESN'T SAY WHEN OSGOOD
BOUGHT IT.
DOESN'T SAY FOR HOW MUCH.
WE'VE HAD IT FOR A LONG TIME.
I-I CAN'T SEEM TO FIND OUT
ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
WELL, WRITE IT UP
IN OUR NEXT STOCK LETTER.
POINT OUT THAT INDUSTRY
IS GROWING
INCREASINGLY
WIDGET-CONSCIOUS.
WHAT IS A WIDGET, BULLARD?
I DON'T KNOW.
ASK INDUSTRY.
HERE'S A HAPPIER ITEM.
REACTOR ENGINES.
HE BOUGHT IT FOR FIVE CENTS
SIX YEARS AGO,
SOLD IT YESTERDAY
FOR $61.
[ CHUCKLES ] $61, EH?
THAT SHREWD OLD FOX.
WELL, THAT'S THE LIST.
WE'RE STILL IN THE RED WHILE
EVERYONE ELSE IS CLEANING UP.
ECONOMY --
THAT'S THE ANSWER.
WE JUST GOT TO TRIM OFF
SOME OF THE FAT.
NO MORE LONG-DISTANCE
PHONE CALLS.
TELL YOUR PALS AT THE CLUB
TO PICK UP SOME LUNCHEON CHECKS.
LAST MAN OUT AT NIGHT
HAS TO MAKE SURE
THAT HE TURNS OUT
ALL THE LIGHTS.
CANCEL THE LINEN SERVICE.
WE'LL GET PAPER TOWELS --
YOU KNOW, THE KIND THAT COME OUT
ONE SHEET AT A TIME.
TELL THE MEN TO BLOT,
NOT RUB.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF IT,
BULLARD.
AND WE'VE GOT TO
LET SOMEBODY GO.
BUT WE NEED EVERYBODY,
BULLARD.
YOU NEVER NEED EVERYBODY.
BUT IF WE LET ANY OF THE BOYS
GO, THERE'LL BE TALK.
RIGHT, IF WE LET
ANY OF THE BOYS GO.
BUT, UH,
WHAT ABOUT OUR GIRL?
WELL, THE GIRL SEEMS TO BE
DOING PRETTY WELL --
A LOT OF BRIGHT IDEAS,
A LOT OF ENERGY.
IT'S KIND OF UNUSUAL
AROUND HERE.
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE?
THAT'S ONE WAY WE CAN CUT
EXPENSES WITHOUT CAUSING TALK.
BESIDES, EVERYBODY KNOWS
THAT TAKING ON THAT GIRL
WAS JUST AN EXPERIMENT.
WE'VE GOT TO HAVE A REASON.
LET HER TRY MOVING
ONE OF THOSE DOGS,
LIKE THAT WIDGET THING,
FOR INSTANCE.
THERE'S YOUR REASON.
WHERE'S SHE GOING?
HER LUNCH CLUB, I THINK.
WOMEN SHOULDN'T BE ALLOWED
TO HAVE LUNCH CLUB.
WE GOT TO KEEP THEM OFF BALANCE,
DISORGANIZED,
CLAWING AND SCRATCHING
AT EACH OTHER.
OTHERWISE, THEY MIGHT TURN ON US
LIKE MAD DOGS.
AND SO YOU SEE, LADIES,
MANY THINGS ARE MADE OF STEEL --
BRIGHT, SHINING, FAITHFUL STEEL
THAT YOU USE IN YOUR KITCHENS
AT HOME.
[ CHUCKLES ]
NOW, I WANT TO LEAVE YOU
WITH AN INTERESTING STATISTIC
CONCERNING A SMALL THING OF
SPECIAL IMPORTANCE TO WOMEN --
THE BOBBY PIN.
[ LAUGHS ]
[ GROANING ]
NOW, THE VALUE
OF THE AMOUNT OF STEEL
THAT GOES INTO
ONE YEAR'S PRODUCTION
OF THE AMERICAN BOBBY PIN
IS GREATER
THAN THE NATIONAL INCOME
OF MANY FAR EASTERN
AND SOUTH AMERICAN NATIONS.
[ CHUCKLES ]
SO IS IT ANY WONDER, THEN,
THAT WE OF THE INDUSTRY
ARE PROUD?
THANK YOU, LADIES,
FOR YOUR ATTENTION.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
ARE THERE ANY QUESTIONS?
MR. WILSON,
IT WAS VERY NICE OF YOU
TO EXPLAIN TO US
HOW SHINY STEEL IS,
BUT WE WOULD LIKE
SOME HARD FACTS AND FIGURES.
FOR INSTANCE,
HOW WILL EARNINGS PER SHARE
BE AFFECTED
BY THE FRINGE BENEFITS
IN SECTION 17
OF THE RECENT UNION CONTRACT?
WELL, YOUNG LADY, WE'D HAVE TO
TAKE OUT OUR PENCILS
AND SHARPEN THEM
TO ANSWER THAT ONE, WOULDN'T WE?
[ CHUCKLES ]
SAY YOU RAISED
IRON BILLET PRICES 5%.
WHAT EFFECT WOULD
FOREIGN COMPETITION HAVE
CONSIDERING
FREIGHT COSTS?
WELL, THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT WOULD HAVE TO BE DETERMINED
COOLLY, LOGICALLY,
AND WITH THE BEST INTEREST OF
THE AMERICAN CONSUMER AT HEART.
BUT WHAT WOULD
THE FIGURES BE?
OH, BUT I SEE THAT I'M OVERDUE
AT MY OFFICE NOW,
SO I MUST BID ALL YOU
CHARMING LADIES ADIEU.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR COMING,
MR. WILSON.
JERUSALEM STEEL HAS BEEN
DELIGHTED TO MEET YOU LADIES.
YOU'RE UPPERMOST
IN OUR THOUGHTS.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
OH, WHAT'S THE USE?
THEY TREAT US LIKE SECRETARIES
AND HOUSEWIVES --
JUST WOMEN.
INSULTING.
ABSOLUTELY INSULTING.
DID YOU GET THAT BIT
ABOUT THE KITCHEN?
AND THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO BE
SMARTER THAN WE ARE.
THAT'S A LAUGH.
WHY DOESN'T ANYONE
TAKE US SERIOUSLY?
I'LL TELL YOU WHY.
BECAUSE THEY DON'T THINK WOMEN
HAVE A PLACE ON WALL STREET,
AND WE HAVE.
THEY WON'T LET US JOIN THE
SOCIETY OF SECURITY ANALYSTS.
THE NEXT THING YOU KNOW,
THEY WON'T LET US ON THE FLOOR
OF THE STOCK EXCHANGE.
THEY SAY WE'RE TOO EMOTIONAL
FOR SECURITIES,
WE HAVE NO HEAD FOR FIGURES,
BUT OUR DAY IS COMING!
WE'LL SHOW THEM!
WE HAVE RIGHTS!
AND WE'RE NOT EMOTIONAL,
AND WE'RE NOT EXCITABLE!
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING,
SILVERWARE CLINKING ]
YOU DESERVE A SHOT AT SOMETHING
REALLY BIG, THATCHER.
OF COURSE, I'LL ADMIT
I WAS A LITTLE NERVOUS
WHEN YOU FIRST
CAME WITH US.
BUT NOW WE'VE ALL COME TO THINK
OF YOU AS ONE OF THE BOYS.
WELL, THANK YOU,
MR. BEAR.
AND NOW WE'RE GOING TO
GIVE YOU A CHANCE
TO SHOW YOUR REAL STUFF,
REAL SALESMANSHIP.
WE'VE ACQUIRED A LITTLE GEM
CALLED UNIVERSAL WIDGET,
AND WE THINK THE PUBLIC
OUGHT TO SHARE
IN THIS GREAT OPPORTUNITY.
OF COURSE, YOU UNDERSTAND
THE EVER-INCREASINGLY
DOMINANT ROLE
THAT WIDGETS PLAY
IN OUR NATIONAL ECONOMY.
OH, CERTAINLY, MR. BEAR.
I'LL START ON IT RIGHT AWAY.
THAT'S MY BOY.
WIDGETS... WIDGETS...
WIDGETS.
AH! HERE WE ARE.
UNIVERSAL WIDGET,
WHIPPLETON, MASSACHUSETTS.
FOUNDED 1844.
THE PRESIDENT,
THADDEUS WHIPPLE.
DIRECTORS LEMUEL WHIPPLE,
NEAHMIAH WHIPPLE, ISAAC WHIPPLE.
NO ANNUAL MEETING
AND NO FIGURES REPORTED
SINCE 1894.
OH, BOY.
IT'S WORSE THAN I THOUGHT.
Henry: EXCUSE ME, MA'AM.
I'D APPRECIATE IT
IF YOU COULD DIRECT ME
TO THE OFFICE
OF MR. BULLARD BEAR.
OH, UH...
THATAWAY?
FIRST DOOR THERE.
MUCH OBLIGED.
I HOPE YOU'LL EXCUSE ME
FOR THE FORWARDNESS OF THE
REMARK I'M ABOUT TO MAKE, MA'AM,
BUT SURPRISE BECOMES YOU.
MAKES YOUR EYES
REAL PRETTY BLUE,
LIKE A PRAIRIE FLOWER,
SORT OF.
[ SIGHS ]
DID I HEAR WRONG, OR DID THAT
MAN ACTUALLY SAY "THATAWAY"?
THATAWAY?
THATAWAY.
Henry: NOW, WITH ALL THE MONEY
THAT THIS OFFICE
MUST HAVE MADE LAST YEAR,
YOU HAVE GOT TO DRILL OFF
SOME OF THAT INCOME, MR. BEAR.
NOW, I'VE GOT SOME
PARTICIPATIONS OPEN
DOWN IN SCURRY COUNTY
THAT'LL GIVE YOU
THE KIND OF TAX SHELTER
THAT AN OUTFIT IN YOUR BRACKET
REALLY NEEDS.
THE DEPLETION ALLOWANCE --
MR. TYROON, THIS YEAR
I DON'T EVEN HAVE A BRACKET.
MAYBE WE CAN GET TOGETHER
ON SOMETHING ELSE, THOUGH.
YOU KNOW THE OIL BUSINESS.
YOU KNOW
GREAT EASTERN OFFSHORE OIL?
OH, YEAH.
NICE -- VERY NICE PEOPLE, YEAH.
SORRY TO HEAR ABOUT THEIR RIG
LAST NIGHT.
RIG? LAST NIGHT?
THE VERY LAST RIG JUST,
YOU KNOW,
GOT HIT BY A GALE DOWN IN THE
GULF AND TOPPLED OVER AND SANK.
THEY GOT EVERYBODY OFF IN TIME,
THOUGH, THANK GOODNESS.
THANK GOODNESS.
EXCUSE ME JUST A MINUTE.
DR. PFEIFFER? CHARLIE RALEIGH
AT BEAR, OSGOOD, AND WHITBY.
WE JUST GOT A FLASH
ON GREAT EASTERN OFFSHORE OIL.
IT LOOKS LIKE THEY'VE FINALLY
SUNK SOMETHING --
SOMETHING BIG
DOWN IN THE GULF.
THIS MAY BE
YOUR LAST CHANCE
TO BUY GREAT EASTERN
AT THIS PRICE.
I'D NEVER FORGIVE MYSELF IF
I DIDN'T LET YOU KNOW IN TIME.
UH, I DIDN'T KNOW YOU HAD WOMEN
WORKING ON WALL STREET NOW.
OH, THAT'S MOLLY THATCHER,
ONE OF OUR TOP ANALYSTS,
SPECIALIZING
IN THE WIDGET INDUSTRY.
WIDGETS, HUH?
QUITE A BOOM NOW,
SHE TELLS ME.
WELL, I'M CERTAINLY INTERESTED
IN BOOMING INDUSTRIES.
I GATHER YOU MIGHT CONSIDER
OPENING AN ACCOUNT WITH US.
I CERTAINLY MIGHT.
I'VE HAD MY EYES ON WIDGET
FOR QUITE SOME TIME NOW.
LET'S SEE IF WE CAN GET
OUR MISS THATCHER FOR YOU.
WELL, MR. TYROON,
ACTUALLY, I'VE JUST STARTED
ON WIDGET,
BUT ONE THING
I KNOW ALREADY --
IT'S A VITAL COMPANY,
BUT A SMALL ONE.
AND ONCE IT STARTS GROWING,
WHICH IT HAS TO...
IT SURE HAS TO.
...THEN THE STOCK COULD MOVE
VERY RAPIDLY.
IT'S AN OLD COMPANY
AND SECURE.
IT WAS STARTED IN 1844.
AND ITS STRATEGIC POSITION IN
THE NEW ENGLAND AREA MAKES IT --
MR. TYROON, PLEASE.
OH, I'M SORRY, MA'AM.
I DIDN'T WANT TO INTERRUPT,
AND I DIDN'T THINK YOU'D NOTICE.
HAVE YOU BEEN LISTENING TO
ANYTHING I'VE SAID ABOUT WIDGET?
ESTABLISHED 1844,
OLD AND SECURE,
STRATEGIC POSITION
IN THE NEW ENGLAND AREA,
AND YOU SURE GOT
MIGHTY PRETTY HAIR.
UM, THE COMPANY'S
MANAGEMENT
APPEARS TO BE ABLE
AND EXPERIENCED.
[ TELEPHONE RINGING ]
EXCUSE ME.
MOLLY THATCHER SPEAKING.
OH, HI, LEONARD.
NO, THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'M ALMOST FINISHED.
WHAT TIME IS IT NOW?
OH, IT IS?
WELL, I WON'T BE MUCH LONGER.
WELL, LOOK, WHY DON'T YOU
GO ON UP TO THE APARTMENT,
AND I'LL STOP BY THE MARKET
AND PICK US UP SOME CHIANTI,
AND THEN I'LL WHIP US UP
SOME SCALLOPINI, ALL RIGHT?
THEN WE CAN LISTEN TO MUSIC
AND WATCH THE LATE SHOW
UNTIL YOUR NERVES
ARE SOOTHED, OKAY?
FINE. BYE-BYE.
NOW, THEN, MR. TYROON.
UH, MR. TYROON.
WHOO-HOO.
HMM?
OH, EXCUSE ME.
I'M AFRAID YOU WERE
A MILLION MILES AWAY JUST THEN.
YES.
WELL, I-I'M SORRY.
I-I DIDN'T KNOW I WAS IN THE WAY
OF YOUR PLANS.
I GUESS WE BETTER TAKE THIS UP
ANOTHER TIME, HUH?
OH, NO. I'M AT YOUR DISPOSAL,
MR. TYROON.
WELL, NOW,
I REALLY WOULD
LIKE TO KNOW MORE
ABOUT THESE WIDGETS,
EXCEPT THE ONLY FREE TIME I HAVE
IS, UH, DINNER TONIGHT.
OH, I'M TERRIBLY SORRY.
I HAVE A DATE.
COULDN'T YOU ASK LEONARD
FOR THE NIGHT OFF?
I DON'T HAVE TO ASK LEONARD
FOR ANYTHING.
NOW, ARE YOU SURE YOU CAN'T
MAKE IT ANY OTHER TIME?
CROSS MY HEART.
WELL...
ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, THEN -- 7:30.
I WAS JUST GONNA TAKE
A CAB UPTOWN.
COULD I GIVE YOU A LIFT?
OH, MR. TYROON,
YOU DON'T KNOW THIS TOWN.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO GET A CAB
AT THIS TIME OF DAY.
I'LL SHOW YOU
TO THE SUBWAY.
[ HORNS HONKING ]
THE EAST SIDE SUBWAY
IS THIS WAY.
HOWDY, PARTNER.
HOWDY.
WELL, BILLY JOE, HOLD HIM OFF
SOME OTHER WAY, THEN.
WELL, WRITE A BOSTON CHECK
ON OUR MIAMI BANK,
COVER THAT WITH A CHECK
FROM THE L.A. BANK,
FROM THE DALLAS BANK.
BY THE TIME THEY RUN
THE FIRST CHECK DOWN,
I'LL HAVE US THE MONEY.
I AM NOT FOOLING AROUND,
BILLY JOE.
I'M MEETING ALL KINDS
OF MONEY TOMORROW.
YEAH.
WELL, SAME TO YOU, FELLA.
HI.
HI, MOLLY.
OH, YOU HAVING COMPANY?
NOPE. JUST ME.
YOU GOT LEONARD
ON THE DOCKET AGAIN?
NO, NOT TONIGHT.
THIS TIME IT'S DINNER
WITH A CLIENT -- A TEXAN.
OOH.
HOW DOES HE SHAPE UP?
OH, YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE HIM,
MY DEAR.
HE'S REALLY TOO MUCH.
BOOTS AND ALL.
BET HE WALKS IN HERE
WITH TWO DOZEN FLOWERS.
YOU CAN FIND A BETTER REASON
THAN THAT TO HATE HIM.
MY BOSS SAYS THIS IS
SOME SORT OF A CHALLENGE,
BUT I THINK THAT TEXAS
IS JUST ANOTHER GUY ON THE MAKE.
THAT'S THE WAY PEOPLE
ARE CONSTRUCTED.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T LIKE WHAT'S
BEEN GOING ON IN THE OFFICE.
I KEEP TELLING YOU --
DOWNTOWN A GIRL HAS TO BE TWICE
AS SMART TO GET HALF AS FAR.
I THINK MR. BEAR'S PUT ME
ON THIS FOR SOME SORT OF REASON.
ON WALL STREET,
YOU'RE EVERY MAN'S RIVAL.
UPTOWN, I SMILE,
AND I GET A $5 RAISE.
OH, AN UPTOWN JOB
IS JUST THE WAY
A GIRL KILLS TIME
TILL THE EVENING DATE.
ANYWAY,
I LIKE WALL STREET.
I LIKE MY JOB,
AND I'M GOOD AT IT.
BESIDES, THE MAN I MARRY
IS GOING TO HAVE TO WANT
SOMETHING MORE THAN A CHIEF COOK
AND BOTTLE WASHER.
SOONER OR LATER, FATE, IN
THE FORM OF THE DIAPER SERVICE,
MUST COME KNOCKING
AT THE DOOR.
I'LL TAKE LATER.
I'LL TAKE SOONER.
- MMM.
- OOH.
NOW, WHY DO YOU SUPPOSE
MR. BEAR WANTS ME
TO FIGHT OFF A LARGE TEXAN?
YOU THINK HE'S GOT MORE
THAN BUSINESS ON HIS MIND?
EVERY MAN
HAS SEX ON THE BRAIN
LIKE IT'S SOME SORT
OF WONDER DRUG,
A CURE-ALL FOR EVERYTHING --
COLDS, PLEURISY, ARTHRITIS.
I EVEN HAD A GUY ONCE TELL ME
THAT SEX PREVENTS CAVITIES.
CAVITIES?
IN YOUR TEETH?
SURE.
WHEN YOU'RE TENSE, YOU HAVE
MORE ACIDS IN YOUR MOUTH,
AND ACIDS EAT ENAMEL.
WHEN YOU GET RID OF THE TENSION,
YOU GET RID OF THE ACIDS,
AND THE BEST WAY
TO GET RID OF TENSION --
DON'T TELL ME.
LET ME GUESS.
SAY, WHY DON'T YOU EVER UNDRESS
IN THE BATHROOM?
BECAUSE I CAN'T HEAR YOU
FROM THE BATHROOM.
OH.
WELL, AT LEAST LEONARD SPARES ME
ALL THAT JAZZ.
SAY, WHERE ARE YOU AND THIS
COWBOY GONNA CHOW DOWN?
I DON'T KNOW.
SOMEPLACE WHERE HE CAN'T
PUT HIS BOOTS ON THE TABLE
AND ORDER A BURNT STEAK.
TRY LE COCHON TRèS CHER.
IT IS SO SWANK.
YOU'RE NOT EVEN ALLOWED
TO USE YOUR TEETH.
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]
YOU JUST GUM THE FOOD.
THAT'S ABOUT THE BEST IDEA
YOU'VE HAD ALL DAY.
- OH, LEONARD.
- EVENING.
I'VE BEEN TRYING TO REACH YOU
FOR THE PAST HOUR.
YOU KNOW DR. PFEIFFER
WILL NEVER ANSWER THE PHONE
DURING MY SESSIONS.
WELL, I KNOW, LEONARD,
BUT I'M SORRY.
I'M GONNA HAVE TO BREAK OUR
DINNER DATE,
BECAUSE I HAVE A VERY URGENT
BUSINESS APPOINTMENT.
I'LL-I'LL MAKE IT UP TO YOU
ANOTHER NIGHT.  I PROMISE.
NO VEAL SCALLOPINI?
NO SOFT MUSIC?
I JUST TOLD YOU I CAN'T.
I HAVE TO HAVE DINNER
WITH A CLIENT.
HOW DID YOU RATIONALIZE
THIS REJECTION OF ME?
WHAT EXCUSE
DID YOU GIVE YOURSELF?
IT'S NOT A REJECTION.
IT'S A CLIENT.
BUT THE REAL REASON,
THE SUBCONSCIOUS REASON
YOU'RE REJECTING ME,
HAS TO DO WITH THE AMBIGUOUS
MASCULINE-FEMININE ROLE
WHICH YOU HAVE --
IT HAS TO DO WITH
TRYING TO SELL SOME STOCK.
STOCK. MONEY.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT FREUD SAID
ABOUT MONEY?
IT'S REFUSE, DIRT.
I'M JUST TRYING TO TURN
A FAST MUD PIE.
NOW, GOOD NIGHT, LEONARD.
MY CLIENT'S COMING TO GET ME
PRETTY SOON.
I'LL TALK TO YOU LATER.
I'LL BE AT SONIA'S.
WELL, HOWDY, LEONARD.
EVENING, MA'AM.
BROUGHT YOU SOME FLOWERS.
OH. [ CHUCKLES ]
HOWDY, MA'AM.
THAT'S MY ROOMMATE,
ELOISE COTT.
HOLY COW.
UH, I, UH, GUESS I BETTER
PUT MY SHOES ON.
I FEEL A LITTLE SHORT
IN THE SADDLE.
YOU KNOW, YOU REALLY
DIDN'T HAVE TO DO THIS.
WELL, I ALWAYS FIGURED
THAT FLOWERS AND LADIES
KIND OF GO TOGETHER.
WHERE WE GONNA CHOW DOWN
TONIGHT, MA'AM?
WELL, THERE'S A LITTLE PLACE
WHERE WE USUALLY DROP IN,
SORT OF A NEIGHBORHOOD
ATMOSPHERE.
IT'S CALLED
LE COCHON TRèS CHER.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
WELL, IN FRENCH, IT MEANS
"THE VERY DEAR PIG,"
BUT THAT'S NOT
WHAT IT MEANS.
THANK YOU.
[ MID-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYING ]
WE SHOULD HAVE MADE
A RESERVATION.
WE'LL NEVER GET A TABLE.
OH, SURE.
EXCUSE ME.
WE'D LIKE TO GET A TABLE
AND SOMETHING TO EAT, PLEASE.
[ French accent ] IF YOU WILL
WAIT AT THE BAR, MONSIEUR,
I WILL CALL YOU --
PERHAPS TWO, THREE HOURS.
OH, BUT I'M TOO HUNGRY
TO WAIT THAT LONG.
AH! MONSIEUR DUGLACE,
MADAME, BONSOIR!
LE NUMERAL QUATRE POUR
MSSR. DUGLACE ET DAME.
MERCI.
YES.
EXCUSE ME.
UH, CLYDE, I DON'T THINK
YOU UNDERSTOOD THE LADY.
YOU GOT
ALL THOSE EMPTY TABLES,
AND WE'D LIKE TO EAT THERE
RIGHT NOW.
MONSIEUR, WHEN I SAY
THREE HOURS,
I MEAN THREE HOURS.
YOU LISTEN TO ME, MERLE.
PASADO UNO PARA EL OFICIAL
DE IMIGRACIóN, ¿EH?
PARA UNO PICCOLO
DE TU QUOTA.
UN GRANDE AMIGO
DE ELIOT NESS.
CERTAMENTE, SIGNORE.
CERTAMENTE.
IL TRADIRE DIECI
PER SIGNORE QUEEN.
AVANTI.
THANK YOU.
MONSIEUR.
WAS THAT ITALIAN?
I FIND THAT IN NEW YORK,
MOST FRENCH HEADWAITERS
ARE ITALIAN.
CAN YOU SPEAK ITALIAN?
NO, MA'AM.
THAT'S JUST A LITTLE
WETBACK SPANISH.
IT SOUNDS THE SAME.
OH.
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
YOU, UH, REALLY DO
LIKE THIS PLACE, HUH?
OH, YES. I COULD EAT HERE...
EVERY NIGHT OF MY LIFE.
MADAME, MONSIEUR, MAY I SUGGEST
A SPECIALTY OF THE HOUSE?
FILET DE SOLE MONACO.
OH, EXCUSE ME, FRIEND.
YES, SIR?
WHAT'S THAT KEY FOR?
THAT'S THE KEY
TO THE WINE CELLAR, SIR.
WELL, IF THAT'S THE KEY,
THE DOOR MUST BE 50 FEET HIGH.
MAY I SUGGEST THE SPECIALTY
OF THE HOUSE?
FILET DE SOLE MONACO.
OH, WELL,
I THINK I'LL HAVE
THE POULET FLAMBé
SAINT BERNARD DU VIN.
EXCELLENT.
EXCELLENT CHOICE.
YOU, MONSIEUR?
UH...
WHAT WAS THAT YOU HAD?
OH, THAT'S CHICKEN
WITH MUSHROOMS AND ONIONS
AND MARINATED IN WINE
AND TOPPED WITH BRANDY.
UH, CHUCK-WAGON STEW
WITH A DASH OF RED-EYE, HUH?
UH, WAITER,
BRING ME A BURNT STEAK
AND A MESS OF GREENS, PLEASE.
YES. OF COURSE.
I'LL BET YOU A SHAVE
THAT OLD HENRY'S ON TO SOMETHING
REAL GOOD.
OKAY, I'LL SEE
YOUR SEE YOUR SHAVE
AND RAISE YOU
TWO SHOESHINES.
I'LL SEE YOUR TWO SHOESHINES,
RAISE YOU A SHAVE,
AND LOAN YOU
MY HELICOPTER.
- OH, THAT'S GOOD WINE.
- MM-HMM.
AND AREN'T YOU GLAD I MADE YOU
CHANGE YOUR ORDER TO CHICKEN?
I SURE AM.
THAT CHICKEN'S THE MOST
I'VE HAD TO DRINK
IN QUITE SOME TIME.
NOW, MR. TYROON,
LET'S GET BACK TO BUSINESS,
BECAUSE I KNOW YOU WANT TO HEAR
ABOUT WIDGETS.
I SURE DO.
HOW DID A GIRL LIKE YOU
EVER GET MIXED UP WITH WIDGETS?
YOU MEAN WHAT AM I DOING
ON WALL STREET,
AND HOW COME
I'M NOT MARRIED?
WELL, NOW, I WASN'T GONNA GET TO
THAT FOR ANOTHER HOUR OR SO.
I'M IMPRESSED
BY YOUR DIRECTNESS.
MR. TYROON,
GETTING MARRIED
IS NOT THE ONLY THING
A GIRL CAN DO.
AND I LIKE WALL STREET,
AND I WANT TO SEE GIRLS
ACCEPTED THERE.
WELL, YOU MEAN
THEM FELLAS DOWNTOWN
ARE GIVING YOU
A HARD TIME?
UH-HUH, AND IF I CAN PUT WIDGET
OVER, I'M ON MY WAY.
I MAY EVEN BE THE NEXT PRESIDENT
OF THE WOMEN SECURITY ANALYSTS.
WELL, SINCE WE'RE DOING
ALL THIS SO SPEEDY-LIKE,
THIS LEONARD,
IS HE YOUR STEADY FELLA?
OH, NO, NO. NO.
NO. I-I SEE A LOT OF HIM.
HE'S AN ART CRITIC
AND VERY INTELLIGENT.
AND YOUR NEXT QUESTION
IS GOING TO BE
HOW LONG
HAVE I KNOWN HIM.
WHOO-EE.
THERE'S NO POINT
IN MESSING WITH YOU.
YOU'RE AHEAD OF ME
ALL THE WAY.
I'M JUST NOT USED TO
BRIGHT GIRLS.
OH, YOU REALLY THINK
I'M BRIGHT?
MM-HMM.
OH, SO DO I,
AND NOBODY EVER TELLS ME THAT.
WHENEVER ANYBODY
WANTS TO SCORE POINTS WITH ME,
THEY TELL ME I'M PRETTY.
AND I GET SO TIRED
OF THAT WHEN --
WHEN ACTUALLY,
I-I'VE DONE S-SOME VERY...
INTELLIGENT...
THOUGHTFUL WORK.
Wilson:
HEY! HEY, GOOD BUDDY!
EVERYTHING'S
GONNA BE ALL RIGHT.
OH, NOW GET OFF THE ROAD,
LITTLE PUPPY,
AND LET US BIG DOGS ROLL.
WELL, HOWDY, HENRY.
EVENING, MA'AM.
Both: EVENING, MA'AM.
HOWDY, HENRY.
HOWDY, BOYS.
OH, UH, MISS MOLLY THATCHER,
I'D LIKE YOU TO MEET
JAY RAY SPENALBEE,
RAY JAY POTTS, AND J.R. WILSON.
- HI.
THE BOYS ARE FROM TEXAS.
NO. HELLO.
IT'S A PLEASURE, MA'AM,
AND IF I'M NOT TOO BOLD,
I'D JUST LIKE TO SAY THAT YOUR
HAIR'S PRETTY AS CORN SILK.
PRETTIER.
[ LAUGHS ]
SAY, NOW, HENRY,
WHATEVER IT IS YOU'RE ON TO,
I'LL TAKE A FOURTH OF IT.
AND I'LL TAKE
AN EIGHTH.
I'LL SEE YOUR EIGHTH
AND I'LL RAISE YOU A FOURTH.
WELL, UH,
I'LL TELL YOU, BOYS,
I HAVEN'T GOT ANYTHING
GOING JUST NOW.
THESE GENTLEMEN HAVE BEEN
ASSOCIATED WITH ME
IN A COUPLE
OF MY VENTURES.
OH, COME ON, NOW, HENRY.
YOU CAN TELL US.
NOW, WHAT ARE WE
GETTING INTO THIS TIME?
HONEST, BOYS, I'M JUST OUT
FOR A NICE SOCIABLE DINNER.
IS THAT TRUE, MA'AM?
YES, THAT'S TRUE.
WHERE CAN A MAN GET A BOWL
OF CHILI IN HERE?
HOW IS THE CHOW, MA'AM?
WELL, IT'S JUST ABOUT
THE BEST IN THE WORLD --
WHEN YOU GET A CHANCE
TO ENJOY IT.
YOU, UH, REALLY LIKE
THIS PLACE, HUH?
UNDER CERTAIN CIRCUMSTANCES,
IT CAN BE HEAVEN.
WELL, PEOPLE HAVE
A DIFFERENT IDEA ABOUT HEAVEN.
WELL, LET'S SEE.
THERE'S A FEW INTERESTING PRINCIPLES.
I MEAN, IT'S GOT
A HIGH MARGIN.
YOU KEEP THE PEOPLE
PACKED IN THERE.
AT A DOLLAR AND A HALF A SHOT,
THEY'RE CRYING TO GET IN.
BY THE TIME THEY HAVE
FOUR OR FIVE WHISKEYS,
THEY DON'T KNOW WHAT THE WINE
TASTES LIKE ANYWAY.
OH, YEAH, THEY GOT THEM
LITTLE PULLEY CARTS.
FIRE INSURANCE.
YOU, UH, REALLY, REALLY
LIKE IT HERE?
YES.
WELL, WHEN HE'S NOT BUSY,
WOULD YOU HAVE HIM CALL ME BACK?
Bear: Miss Thatcher?
YES, MR. BEAR?
What's new
with that widget thing
we gave you
several days ago?
WELL, I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO DO THE RESEARCH,
BUT THE COMPANY
DOESN'T ANSWER ITS PHONE.
What about that Texan
we set you up with?
I-I HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE
TO REACH HIM.
Well, don't let him get away,
Miss Thatcher.
Speed things up. We've got to
get on to other things.
[ CLICK ]
[ SIGHS ]
GIVE HER ANOTHER MONTH.
OTHERWISE,
IT WILL LOOK TOO OBVIOUS.
ONE MONTH,
AND WE TRIM THE FAT.
OUT SHE GOES.
LEONARD, I SYMPATHIZE,
BUT I CAN'T LISTEN
TO YOUR TROUBLES NOW.
I HAVE TOO MANY
OF MY OWN.
[ TELEPHONE BUZZES ]
LISTEN, I'LL SEE YOU AT
THE OPENING TONIGHT, ALL RIGHT?
I HAVE ANOTHER CALL NOW.
MOLLY THATCHER.
Henry: Oh, I'm not
disturbing you, am I?
OH, HI!
NO, NO.
YOU'RE NOT DISTURBING ME
ONE BIT.
I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO REACH YOU FOR DAYS.
I was afraid I wouldn't get
the chance to talk to you again.
WELL, I'VE BEEN WORKING
ON A LITTLE CRASH PROJECT.
I GOT A SURPRISE FOR YOU.
I'D LIKE TO SHOW IT TO YOU
TONIGHT ABOUT, UH, 7:30?
OH.
OH, I DO WANT
TO TALK TO YOU.
UH, I HAVE TO GO
TO AN ART GALLERY TONIGHT,
A RECEPTION
FOR A NEW ARTIST,
THE FIRST TIME HIS PAINTINGS
HAVE BEEN HUNG.
IF YOU WOULDN'T MIND
EATING EARLY,
maybe you'd like to come
to the gallery with me.
IT'S THE FIRST TIME
I EVER TOOK A GIRL TO A HANGING.
[ CHUCKLES ]
BYE-BYE.
EVENING, MA'AM.
GOOD EVENING, SIR.
WELL, GOOD EVENING THERE,
BONAPARTE.
WE'LL BE OUT IN A COUPLE HOURS,
FEINBERG.
[ MID-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYING ]
GOOD EVENING, MR. TYROON.
IT'S NICE TO SEE YOU
THIS EVENING.
WELL, THANK YOU.
COMMENDATORE, BUONASERA.
QUELL'ONORE.
SIGNORINA, BELLISSIMA.
[ SPEAKING ITALIAN ]
MOLTA CARINA, BELLISSIMA,
SIGNORINA.
WAKE UP.
ONE OF YOUR FAVORITE CIGARS,
MR. TYROON.
FAVORITE CIGARS.
[ CHUCKLES ]
GRAZIE, GRAZIE.
THANK YOU, ZELDA.
THEY CERTAINLY HAVE CHANGED
THIS PLACE, HAVEN'T THEY?
AND THAT HEADWAITER --
DID HE TURN OUT TO BE YOUR
LONG-LOST FATHER OR SOMETHING?
WELL I FIGURED IF THE BAR IS MORE
PROFITABLE THAN THE DINING AREA
AND PEOPLE LIKE TO BE
SHOVED AROUND,
WELL, THEN, YOU DOUBLE THE SIZE
OF THE BAR
AND SHOVE THEM
A LITTLE HARDER.
GOOD EVENING, MR. TYROON.
GOOD EVENING, MADEMOISELLE.
GOOD EVENING, CLYDE.
NOW WE HAVE A 100-FOOT DOOR
ON THE WINE CELLAR.
THEN I FIGURED,
WHO WOULD LOAN ME ENOUGH MONEY
TO BUY THIS PLACE?
SIMPLE.
A FIRE-INSURANCE COMPANY.
MR. TYROON,
Y-YOU BOUGHT THIS PLACE?
CHEZ-HENRI.
"HENRI" IS THE SAME AS "HENRY,"
AND HENRY IS ME.
- MR. TYROON --
- NO, NO, NO.
YOU CAN CALL ME HENRI,
LIKE IT SAYS ON THE MENU.
YOU BOUGHT THIS PLACE.
WELL, YOU SAID YOU'D LIKE TO
EAT HERE EVERY NIGHT.
WELL, NOW YOU CAN.
SEE WHAT WE GOT TONIGHT.
NARDO! NARDO?!
WAIT FOR CHUCK!
POTTSFIELD IS SUCH
AN ANTISEPTIC PAINTER.
AT FIRST GLANCE,
BUT THAT'S BECAUSE HE USES
ONLY WHITE PAINT.
WELL, HIS PAINTINGS
ARE GERM-FREE.
BUT THEN WHEN YOU'VE SAID THAT,
YOU'VE SAID EVERYTHING.
[ LAUGHS ]
PERSONALLY,
I LIKE HORSE PAINTINGS.
HENRY, ABSTRACTS ARE ALWAYS
HARD AT FIRST.
IT'S AN ACQUIRED TASTE.
NOW, YOU HAVE TO TRY
TO UNDERSTAND,
WHAT IS THE ARTIST
TRYING TO COMMUNICATE?
A FEELING,
BUT HE AIN'T MAKING IT.
BUT I CAN'T
THIS SATURDAY, SPIKE.
I'M GOING TO THE CAPE
TO EXPAND.
FOR THE WHOLE WEEKEND?!
Man: NARDO!
NARDO, THERE YOU ARE!
OH, HIS WORK IS GHASTLY,
BUT IT DOES HAVE
A CERTAIN OBSCENE POWER.
COMMUNICATION IS VERY DIFFICULT
AT FIRST, HENRY.
MM-HMM.
WELL, I AIN'T HAVING
ANY DIFFICULTY.
HE IS.
I DON'T THINK WHAT TED IS DOING
IS AWFUL AT ALL.
AFTER ALL,
DEE DEE AND SALLY ARE TWINS.
YOU'RE NOT TRYING, HENRY.
WELL, I'M WILLING TO TRY,
BUT HE'S GOT TO TRY, TOO.
OH, EXCUSE ME, HENRY.
$500?
I THINK I GET THE MESSAGE.
NARDO!
NARDO, YOU DEAR, DEAR BOY!
I READ YOUR BRILLIANT
LITTLE PIECE IN ART WORLD.
OH, SO ACRID,
SO DELICIOUSLY NASTY!
NOBODY ELSE
COULD DO IT!
NARDO, YOU MUST COME
AND HAVE TEA WITH ME.
THERE'S THE MOST EXCITING
NEOREALIST PAINTER
I WANT YOU TO MEET.
HE'S A SLOB, DARLING,
BUT HE'S A GENIUS.
LET US IN ON IT, NARDO.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO SAY
ABOUT THE EXHIBITION?
YES.
THIS EXHIBITION
IS GOING TO MAKE HISTORY.
THAT'S WHAT I'LL SAY.
WHAT STANISLAS
HAS ACHIEVED HERE
IS ESSENCE
RATHER THAN APPEARANCE
BY USING SPACE ON LIGHT
INSTEAD OF LIGHT ON SPACE,
AND THAT, OF COURSE,
IS THE WHOLE MYSTIQUE
OR GEIST, IF YOU WILL,
OF THE STANISLAS METHOD.
HE'S BROUGHT MYSTICISM
TO PAINTING,
BUT HE HASN'T FALLEN
INTO THE TRAP
OF BRINGING PAINTING
TO MYSTICISM.
OH, MY DEAR.
HE'S A GENIUS.
ONE THINKS OF BAUDELAIRE AND
THE OTHER FIN-DE-SIèCLE POETS,
BECAUSE, WELL,
ONE JUST DOES THINK OF
BAUDELAIRE SO OFTEN THESE DAYS.
OH.
[ SOBBING ]
OH, I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T WANT TO MAKE
A SCENE.
SEEMS THIS PICTURE
BROKE THAT YOUNG FELLA UP.
OH, DON'T WORRY
ABOUT HIM.
HE'S A PAID WEEPER,
ONE OF THE BEST.
UH, YOU KNOW
THIS FELLA STANISLAS?
I AM STANISLAS.
SEEMS TO ME THAT, UH,
YOU USE SPACE ON LIGHT
INSTEAD OF LIGHT ON SPACE.
SIX OF ONE...
YOU'RE BRINGING MYSTICISM
TO PAINTING,
BUT YOU AIN'T BRINGING PAINTING
TO MYSTICISM.
WHAT ARE YOU,
SOME KIND OF RELIGIOUS NUT?
TELL ME, STANISLAS,
IS THIS AN ASKING PRICE,
OR IS THAT FIRM?
FIRM.
SOLD FOUR ALREADY TONIGHT.
OF COURSE,
IF YOU'RE A TEXAS COLLECTOR,
I MIGHT WORK SOMETHING OUT
ON A JOB LOT.
AFRAID I CAN'T AFFORD
A HOBBY LIKE COLLECTING.
OH, IT'S NOT A HOBBY.
IT'S AN INVESTMENT.
REMEMBER THAT REMBRANDT
THAT SOLD FOR $2 MILLION
A BIT AGO?
YEAH, I HEARD ABOUT IT.
YOU KNOW YOU COULD HAVE BOUGHT
THAT ONCE FOR 20 BUCKS?
FROM WHOM?
FROM REMBRANDT
WHEN HE PAINTED IT.
NOW, MY STUFF
GOES FOR 500 CLAMS,
BUT IT'S GOT
1,000% PROFIT POTENTIAL.
YEAH, BUT REMBRANDT
AND THAT BUNCH,
YOU KNOW,
THEY'RE OLD MASTERS.
THEY'VE ALL BEEN BID UP.
THIS NEW STUFF,
IT'S LIKE WILDCATTING.
IT MAY GO UP,
BUT THE ODDS ARE AGAINST IT.
IF I READ YOU RIGHT,
YOU GO FOR WILDCATS.
I ALWAYS LIKE SOMETHING
ON THE OUTSKIRTS OF A PRODUCER
WHERE NOBODY'S
BROUGHT ONE IN --
NOT TOO EXPENSIVE,
BUT THEN, NOT TOO LEFT-FIELD.
I BELIEVE I KNOW
OF JUST SUCH A FIELD.
NOW, WHEN THE COLLECTION
NEEDS A CURATOR --
A CURATOR?
A FOREMAN.
SOMEONE TO RIDE THE HERD
AND ALL THAT BEAUTY.
WELL, I ALWAYS
GIVE MY ASSOCIATES
A PIECE OF THE ACTION.
LET ME LAY THIS ON YOU.
THE COMING FIELD
IS GERMAN EXPRESSIONISTS.
[ VACUUM WHIRRING ]
Molly: I HAVE THE AWFUL FEELING
THAT THE AX
IS ABOUT TO FALL.
"HOW ARE THINGS GOING,
MISS THATCHER?
WE CAN'T KEEP ON GIVING
YOU CHANCES, NOW, CAN WE?"
LET THE AX FALL.
WORK UPTOWN
AND BE A GIRL AGAIN.
HOW CAN SOMEBODY
JUST DISAPPEAR FOR DAYS?
HENRY?
WHO ELSE?
WELL, HE COULDN'T GO AROUND
IN PUBLIC FOREVER.
[ TELEPHONE RINGING ]
ANSWER THAT, WOULD YOU?
MY HANDS ARE WET.
[ VACUUM SHUTS OFF ]
YES?
FINE, THANKS,
BUT MY HEAD'S HOT.
HOLD ON.
HELLO?
HELLO, HENRY.
OH, I'M FINE.
OH, NO.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'VE BEEN
TERRIBLY BUSY, TOO.
I-I TRIED TO REACH YOU,
BUT YOU CHECKED OUT.
HENRY, I NEVER DID GET
A CHANCE
TO EXPLAIN TO YOU
ALL ABOUT WIDGET AND...
HALF AN HOUR?
WELL, I'M REALLY
AWFULLY BUSY,
BUT, UM, I GUESS I COULD MAKE IT
IN A HALF AN HOUR.
ALL RIGHT.
OH, I-I'VE GOT TO GET IN
SOME CLOTHES.
WOULD YOU RINSE
THOSE THINGS OUT FOR ME?
SURE. RUN ALONG.
DOES MY HAIR LOOK
ALL RIGHT?
FOR A DOWNTOWN GIRL,
THAT'S AN UPTOWN QUESTION.
BETTER NOT
LOOK AT THIS ONE.
IT'S A SHATTERING EXPERIENCE.
LOOSENS YOUR TEETH.
YOU KNOW, WE'RE SOPPING UP
THE FLOKES, FLACK,
AND 'DINSKYS, ALL RIGHT.
ABOUT TO GET
THE NOLDES CORNERED.
HOW WE DOING
ON THEM GORKYS?
WELL, IF YOU CAN EXTEND
YOUR BANK CREDIT,
I CAN GRAB THE TWO GORKYS
IN THE ROTHSCHILD COLLECTION.
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]
[ WOMAN CRYING ]
OH, NOW,
THERE, THERE, HONEY.
DON'T CRY. NO.
OH, I THOUGHT
YOU WERE GONE FOREVER.
OH, ME AND MY BOY
STANISLAS,
WE'VE BEEN WILDCATTING
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
WE WENT TO EUROPE
ON TUESDAY.
YOUR B--
W-WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
MOTHER, YOU'RE TALKING
TO THE HEAD WRANGLER
OF THE HENRY TYROON
COLLECTION.
THIS IS
MISS CATHY MADISON.
SHE WORKS FOR THE SAME MAGAZINE
YOUR BOY LEONARD WORKS FOR.
ART WORLD?
SUCH A MOVING COLLECTION.
SUCH MARVELOUS TASTE.
THAT -- THAT NOLDE.
YEAH. HOW ABOUT THIS CUTE
LITTLE YELLER ONE RIGHT HERE?
AIN'T THAT A BEAUTY?
ARE THEY REAL?
THEY BETTER BE.
BUT THAT ONE OVER THERE --
THAT'S IN THE TATE GALLERY
IN LONDON.
WELL, IT WAS
IN THE TATE GALLERY.
WE JUST ABOUT GOT THIS
EXPRESSIONIST FIELD
- STAKED OUT, HUH?
- THEY ARE REAL.
MR. TYROON, I HOPE
YOU'LL SHOW THEM ALL TOGETHER
IN YOUR EXHIBITION.
YOUR PERSONAL TASTE
MAKES IT ALL A...
AN ENTITY.
UM, HENRY, HAVE YOU LOOKED
AT ANYTHING YOU'VE BOUGHT?
LOOKED?
MY POOR EYES
ABOUT BUGGED OUT.
NOW, IF YOU
COULD JUST TELL ME
WHAT YOU CONSIDER THE KEY
TO YOUR COLLECTION,
I'LL HAVE PLENTY
FOR MY INTERVIEW.
YES.
WELL, THE, UH, THE KEY
TO MY COLLECTION IS, UH, THIS.
I IMMERSE MYSELF
IN WHATEVER THE PAINTER
IS TRYING TO COMMUNICATE.
THIS SCHOOL, IF I MAY
CALL IT SUCH IS, UH,
IS NOT DECORATIVE.
IT DEALS WITH...
HUMAN PROBLEMS.
AND... I LEARN FROM IT.
MR. TYROON, THANK YOU.
YOU HAVE DONE
A BEAUTIFUL THING.
THE ART WORLD OWES YOU
A DEBT OF GRATITUDE.
Stanislas: LET ME GO DOWN
AND HELP YOU GRAB A CAB.
GOOD DAY, MA'AM.
[ SOBS ]
HENRY, YOU DON'T
LOVE THEM.
YOU HAVE NO RIGHT
TO OWN THEM.
WELL, NOW, I AIN'T GONNA
HIDE THEM AWAY.
I'VE JUST GOTTEN INVOLVED IN
A LITTLE WHEELIN' AND DEALIN'.
DOESN'T ANYTHING
GIVE YOU ANY PLEASURE
UNLESS IT MAKES MONEY
FOR YOU?
OH, MOLLY,
YOU GOT ME ALL WRONG.
YOU DON'T GO WHEELIN'
AND DEALIN' FOR MONEY.
YOU DO IT FOR FUN.
MONEY'S JUST THE WAY
YOU KEEP SCORE.
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]
YOU SEE, I FIGURE IF THERE'S
A STRIKE ANYWHERE,
THIS WHOLE FIELD
IS GONNA GO STRAIGHT UP.
NOW, ANYTIME YOU FEEL LIKE
COMMUNICATING WITH THESE FELLAS,
YOU JUST COME RIGHT ON UP,
YOU HEAR?
All: HOWDY, HENRY.
BOYS.
All: EVENING, MISS THATCHER.
EVENING, JAY RAY,
R.J., JAY RAY.
WE SURE HATE TO BUST IN.
WE ASK YOUR FORGIVENESS.
WE DIDN'T WANT TO INTERRUPT.
OH, THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE NOT INTERRUPTING A THING.
All: THANK YOU, MA'AM.
NOW, HENRY, YOU REMEMBER
THE TIME I LET YOU HAVE MY CREW
SO YOU COULD MEET
AN EXPIRATION DATE.
I SURE DO, J.R.
AND REMEMBER, HENRY, WHEN WE
DRILLED ALL THEM DUSTERS,
WE DIDN'T WHIMPER.
I DID APPRECIATE THAT.
WELL, THEN, HENRY,
NOW, WE HEAR YOU'RE
ONTO SOMETHING HOT.
WHERE'S THE ACTION, HENRY?
- CANADA?
- VENEZUELA?
WELL, NOW, HOLD ON, BOYS.
YOU CAUGHT ME OUT PREMATURELY.
I'M NOT READY YET.
All: BUT, HENRY,
WE'RE YOUR BUDDIES HERE.
WELL, SINCE I CAN'T PAY
FOR WHAT I BOUGHT,
I WOULD BE GLAD TO EXTEND
OF A LITTLE PARTICIPATION.
HENRY, WE HEAR TELL
YOU'RE MESSING AROUND
WITH THEM ELECTRONICS.
NO, NO, NO.
OIL.
OH, NO.
HEAVEN FORFEND.
NOT THIS YEAR.
ANYTHING BUT OIL.
OIL IT IS.
AND IT'S RIGHT HERE --
ON CANVAS.
- CANVAS?
HENRY, ARE YOU
ALL RIGHT, SON?
YOU FEELING A MIGHT BIT
PEAKED, SON?
MOLLY, I WONDER IF YOU COULD
GET THESE GENTLEMEN
SOMETHING FOR THEIR
PARCHED THROATS?
All: WELL, JUST A LITTLE
BRANCH WATER, MA'AM.
BOYS, DID YOU EVER HEAR
OF A FELLA NAMED RENOIR?
OF COURSE YOU HAVE.
ONCE UPON A TIME,
THIS FELLA RENOIR,
HE PAINTED PICTURES.
AND HE COULDN'T SELL THEM
TO SAVE HIS LIFE.
HE GAVE THEM AWAY
FOR HIS SUPPER.
SOLD SOME FOR 50 CENTS.
WHY?
THAT'S 'CAUSE THEY WAS ALL
KIND OF FUZZY.
AND PEOPLE LAUGHED.
PEOPLE WEREN'T READY
FOR FUZZY PICTURES.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT ONE OF THOSE
FUZZY OLD RENOIRS
WILL BRING TODAY?
MNH-MNH.
$1 MILLION.
[ WHISTLES ]
NOW, I KNOW.
YOU'RE GONNA SAY THAT THESE
PICTURES DON'T LOOK FUZZY.
THEY LOOK SCRATCHY.
WELL, I MAY BE WRONG,
BUT WHEN PEOPLE GET READY
FOR SCRATCHY PICTURES,
THESE ARE GONNA GO UP,
RIGHT THROUGH THE CEILING.
LOOK AT THE FUSELAGE
ON THIS WOMAN.
WHAT'S THE ACREAGE
ON THIS RUN, HENRY?
OH, I'D SAY, UH, $60 MILLION
AN ACRE, COUNTING THE FRAMES.
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
WHAT'S THE DEPLETION ALLOWANCE?
WELL, I'LL TELL YOU, J.R.,
IT'S NOT DEPLETION,
BUT IT WORKS OUT THE SAME.
YOU BUY THE PAINTINGS,
YOU GIVE THEM TO THE MUSEUM,
AND THEN YOU TAKE A DEDUCTION
ON THE APPRAISED VALUE,
WHICH IS GOING UP.
I FIGURE I CAN SAVE YOU,
OH, SAY, 10 CENTS
ON THE DOLLAR OFF INCOME.
RAY JAY.
JUST A MINUTE.
LOOK, RAY JAY,
YOU THE ART MAN.
- WE COULD BUY A LITTLE...
- THEY LOOK PRETTY GOOD.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
I'LL GO.
ALL RIGHT.
AHH.
HENRY, WE'VE MADE
A DECISION.
NOW, WE REALIZE THAT A DEAL
LIKE THIS IS RISKY,
BUT THERE'S A RISK
IN ALL GOOD THINGS.
SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE
HALF THE KANDINSKY
AND ONE-FOURTH OF THIS PILE
OVER HERE --
IF WE GET A ONE-EIGHTH OVERRIDE
ON THE PRODUCERS
OF THIS BATCH HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
SOUNDS FAIR.
YOU GOT YOURSELF A DEAL.
YES, SIR, IT'S A DEAL,
J.R., RAY JAY.
All: EVENING, MISS THATCHER.
EVENING, HENRY.
EVENING BOYS.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
WELL, NOW,
THAT WASN'T HARD, WAS IT?
HENRY, YOU'RE QUITE
AN OPERATOR.
IN SOME FIELDS.
IN OTHERS, I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHERE TO START.
WELL, YOU COULD START
WITH UNIVERSAL WIDGET.
ALTHOUGH MAYBE
THAT'S NOT EXCITING ENOUGH --
NOT ENOUGH ROOM
FOR WHEELING AND DEALING.
YOU WANT ACTION?
MM-HMM.
OKAY.
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING,
YOU AND I WILL HOP IN A CAR
AND RUN UP TO MASSACHUSETTS
AND TAKE A LOOK
AT THIS UNIVERSAL WIDGET.
THEN YOU CAN PREPARE
TO HOLD ON TO YOUR HAT.
WHAT HAPPENED TO FEINBERG
AND YOUR TAXI?
WE COULDN'T GET THE TOP DOWN
ON THAT ONE.
[ WHIRRING ]
LEFT IS SCOTCH
AND RIGHT IS BOURBON.
[ ICE CLINKING ]
LEFT IS SODA,
AND RIGHT IS BRANCH WATER.
ALL I WANTED WAS A LIGHT.
UH, TRY THAT ONE.
[ WHIRRING ]
OH!
HENRY, THIS IS NOT THE WAY
I LIGHT MY CIGARETTES.
[ BELL TOLLING ]
EXCUSE ME.
COULD YOU TELL US WHERE
THE UNIVERSAL WIDGET PLANT IS?
PLANT IS
RIGHT DOWN THERE.
BURNED TO THE GROUND
AFTER THE WAR.
SPRING OF '99.
DON'T LET ON ANY MORE
THAN YOU HAVE TO, ZEKE.
IS THAT THE ONLY PLANT?
YOU SURE?
ONLY ONE.
FIRST LEFT,
SECOND RIGHT.
DOWN THE HILL.
OLD NEW ENGLAND COMPANY.
STRATEGICALLY LOCATED.
AND IT SURE HAS
LOTS OF ROOM FOR GROWTH.
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
COME IN.
GOOD AFTERNOON,
MR. WHIPPLE.
MIGHT BE.
MIGHT NOT BE.
MY NAME IS HENRY TYROON.
THIS YOUNG LADY
IS MISS MOLLY THATCHER
FROM THE WALL STREET FIRM
OF BEAR, OSGOOD, AND WHITBY.
WOMEN ON WALL STREET NOW,
HUH? HMM.
UH, MR. WHIPPLE, WE WON'T
TAKE UP MUCH OF YOUR TIME.
WE -- WE JUST WANT TO ASK YOU
A FEW QUESTIONS.
MIGHT AS WELL ASK THEM
SITTING DOWN.
UH, MR. WHIPPLE,
WHERE DID YOU BUILD
THE NEW PLANT
WHEN THE NORTH ADAMS STREET
PLANT BURNED DOWN?
NEVER DID BUILD
A NEW PLANT.
UM, YOU ARE THE PRESIDENT
OF UNIVERSAL WIDGET?
SAYS SO ON THE DOOR, DON'T IT?
DON'T THINK I'D PAINT
A FALSEHOOD ON MY DOOR, DO YOU?
WELL, THEN WHERE DO YOU MAKE
THE WIDGETS?
YOUNG LADY, I DON'T KNOW
WHY YOU'RE UP HERE
FUSSING ABOUT OUR STOCK.
WE WHIPPLES CONTROL IT ANYWAY.
WE HAVEN'T MADE A WIDGET
SINCE 1854.
ANY FOOL KNOWS THAT.
FLYING CLIPPERS WENT OUT
YEARS AGO.
BUT YOU MUST MAKE
SOMETHING.
WHY?
WELL, IT SEEMS TO ME,
IF YOU DON'T MAKE SOMETHING,
YOU GOT NO CALL
TO STAY IN BUSINESS.
I'M A BUSY MAN,
AND I'D LIKE THIS TO BE
THE LAST WORD ON THIS SUBJECT.
OUR COMPANY OWNS
JUST TWO THINGS --
THAT BOG OUT THERE
AND SOME STOCK WE BOUGHT.
ONLY THING THAT KEEPS US
FROM DISSOLVING THE CORPORATION
IS MY BROTHER LEMUEL SAYS WE'D
HAVE TO PAY A TAX ON THE STOCK.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WELL, WHAT MR. WHIPPLE
IS SAYING
IS THAT WHEN THEY WENT OUT
OF WIDGET PRODUCTION,
THEY TOOK WHATEVER WAS LEFT
IN THE TREASURY
AND INVESTED IT
IN ANOTHER STOCK.
AND THAT'S
WHERE IT IS NOW.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE BOUGHT AMERICAN TELEPHONE
AND TELEGRAPH
JUST BEFORE THE WAR.
BACK IN THE '30s?
THE DAY BEFORE THEY SUNK
THE LUSITANIA.
YOU BOUGHT AT&T IN 1915?
YOU HAVE A FORTUNE
IN HIDDEN ASSETS!
YOUNG LADY, DON'T YOU FUSS
WITH OUR STOCK.
IT'S SELLING NOW
JUST ABOUT THE WAY IT OUGHT TO.
YOU'D BETTER GO ON HOME
AND GET YOURSELF A HUSBAND.
AND A COOKBOOK.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
DOES MY FACE LOOK PUFFY?
I'M A GENTLEMAN, AND I REFUSE
TO ANSWER THAT QUESTION.
I'M SORRY I BURST OUT
LIKE THAT.
I HAVEN'T DONE THAT
IN YEARS.
YOU WEREN'T CRYING OVER
A LITTLE OLD BURNED-OUT FACTORY,
NOW, WERE YOU?
NO.
IT'S THE WHOLE SITUATION.
I MEAN, IF I CAN'T
PUT WIDGET OVER,
THEN IT'S GONNA MAKE IT
THAT MUCH HARDER
FOR EVERY GIRL
ON WALL STREET,
AND THEY'RE DEPENDING
ON ME.
ANYWAY, THIS IS
A WILD-GOOSE CHASE,
AND MY BOSS KNOWS IT.
WELL, THERE'S NOTHING WRONG
WITH A WILD-GOOSE CHASE,
PROVIDED YOU CATCH
THE GEESE.
ANYWAY, HOW CAN I SELL
WIDGET STOCK?
I MEAN, ANYBODY
IN HIS RIGHT MIND
WOULD GO AND BUY AT&T
DIRECT FROM HIS BROKER.
[ SIGHS ]
WELL, I GUESS THERE'S NOTHING
FOR ME TO DO
BUT GO BACK
TO PHILADELPHIA
AND PUSH LITTLE MONSTERS AROUND
IN SUPERMARKET CARTS.
YOU REALLY WANT TO STAY OUT
OF PHILADELPHIA?
EXCUSE ME.
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL MAKE YOU A DEAL.
UH, THIS STEAK
IS ALL PINK INSIDE.
YES, SIR.
YEAH, I WONDER IF YOU'D
TAKE IT BACK TO COOKY
AND TELL HIM TO BURN IT
FOR ME, PLEASE.
- YES, SIR.
- THANK YOU.
DON'T WAIT FOR ME.
TURKEY WILL GET COLD.
NOW, ABOUT THAT DEAL.
WHAT ABOUT IT?
ALL RIGHT.
HERE ARE THE TERMS.
IF I HELP YOU PUT OVER
THIS STOCK DEAL,
YOU COME DOWN TO TEXAS WITH ME
AS MY ASSISTANT
FOR SIX MONTHS.
IF I DON'T HELP YOU,
NO DEAL.
ME IN TEXAS?
THERE'S PLENTY OF ROOM.
HENRY, YOU'RE AN OPERATOR,
BUT DO YOU KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT THE STOCK MARKET?
I KNOW THE STOCK MARKET
IS MONEY AND EMOTION.
THERE'S...
HOPE WHEN YOU START OUT,
GREED ON THE WAY UP,
AND FEAR ON THE WAY DOWN.
I KNOW THAT THE
STOCK MARKET IS PEOPLE,
AND IF THERE'S ANYTHING
YOU CAN'T SELL PEOPLE,
I HAVE YET TO FIND OUT
WHAT IT IS.
THESE PEOPLE NEED
A REASON TO BUY.
THE BEAUTY OF IT IS, THE REASON
DOESN'T HAVE TO MAKE SENSE.
YOU'RE NOT THINKING
OF ANYTHING ILLEGAL, ARE YOU?
I'M NEVER ILLEGAL.
I'M JUST CLOSE TO IT.
HMM.
TEXAS.
PHILADELPHIA.
OH, MR. TYROON,
YOU'VE GOT YOURSELF A DEAL.
ALL RIGHT.
FIRST OFF, WE GO SEE WHIPPLE
IN THE MORNING.
OH, NOW,
WAIT A MINUTE THERE.
STAYING OVERNIGHT
IS NOT PART OF THE DEAL.
WELL, WE'VE GOT TO TAKE
ADVANTAGE WHILE WE'RE HERE.
ADVANTAGE OF WHOM?
CIRCUMSTANCES, THAT'S ALL.
HENRY, I MAY NOT BE
THE DRIVEN-SNOW TYPE,
BUT I DON'T GO IN
FOR ONE-NIGHT STANDS.
I NEVER THOUGHT
YOU DID, MOLLY.
SEPARATE ROOMS OKAY?
SEPARATE FLOORS
IF YOU LIKE.
I REALLY DO HAVE TO CHECK
SOMETHING IN THE MORNING.
WE MAY HAVE AN EXTRA ASSET
IN THAT WIDGET WEED PATCH.
SEPARATE FLOORS.
OKAY.
[ CRUNCHING ]
MMM.
MY COMPLIMENTS
TO THE CHEF.
HENRY, WHY DON'T YOU BUY A
COUPLE OF NEW ENGLAND MOUNTAINS
AND SEND THEM DOWN
TO TEXAS?
WELL, NOW,
I'D PURELY LIKE TO DO THAT.
BUT I JUST DON'T THINK
I COULD SWING IT.
YOU DON'T MEAN TO SAY
YOU FINALLY DISCOVERED SOMETHING
YOU CAN'T BUY.
NO, I COULD BUY THE MOUNTAINS,
ALL RIGHT.
THE PROBLEM
IS MOVING THEM.
[ CHUCKLES ]
MY FACE STILL PUFFY?
IT'S STILL PUFFED
A LITTLE RIGHT HERE.
AND IT'S A LITTLE SWOLLEN
RIGHT HERE,
AND IT --
IT'S ALL MESSED UP HERE,
AND...
IT'S STILL ABOUT THE PRETTIEST
FACE I EVER DID SEE.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
WHEN I FIRST MET YOU, I DIDN'T
BELIEVE YOU WERE FOR REAL.
I MEAN, THE TEXAS ACCENT
AND THE HAT AND THOSE BOOTS.
WELL, IT WAS ALL
A LITTLE TOO MUCH.
WELL, SUPPOSING
WHEN I MET YOU
THAT I WAS WEARING
ONE OF THEM WALL STREET SUITS
AND A SHORT-BRIMMED HAT
AND I'D SAID, UH...
[ Boston accent]
"I FIND IT HARD TO BE HAPPY
NOW THAT I'VE LEFT
HARVARD."
[ Normal voice ] WOULD I HAVE
BEEN ANY MORE REAL?
[ Texas accent ]
WELL, MAYBE JUST A LITTLE BIT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
REAL IS WHAT YOU'RE USED TO
OR WHAT YOU GET USED TO.
THE BOOTS AND THE HAT
AND THE TEXAS ACCENT
ARE JUST TRIMMINGS,
THAT'S ALL.
THEY DON'T REALLY HAVE
AN AWFUL LOT TO DO WITH ME.
WELL, YOU'RE REAL TO ME NOW,
TRIMMINGS AND ALL.
OH?
AND I THINK IT'S TIME
WE GO BACK TO THE HOTEL.
YEAH.
OH.
[ LAUGHS ]
HENRY?
HMM?
NOTHING, JUST...
HENRY.
HEY, UH, YOU MADE ME
ALL KIND OF WIDE AWAKE.
WANT TO JOIN ME
FOR A NIGHTCAP?
NO, THANKS, HENRY.
I'M KIND OF TIRED.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU CALL ME THE MINUTE
YOU WAKE UP.
I'M ON THE SECOND FLOOR,
ROOM 23.
OKAY. IF YOU WAKE UP FIRST,
YOU CALL ME.
I'M IN, UH, 32.
ALL RIGHT.
SEE YOU AT BREAKFAST?
OKAY.
- GOOD NIGHT.
THANK YOU, SIR.
UH, MR. TYROON?
THE PARTY IN 23 CALLED UP
TO SAY THEY AIN'T
CHECKING OUT.
BUT THERE'S ANOTHER VACANCY
IN ROOM 31.
- 31?
- UH-HUH.
THAT'S RIGHT NEXT TO 32.
YOU SHARE A BATH.
IS THAT THE ONLY OTHER ROOM
YOU GOT?
WE AIN'T GOT ANOTHER VACANCY
IN THE HOTEL.
TOUGH LUCK, MR. TYROON.
YEAH.
I, UH, ASKED
FOR ANOTHER ROOM, BUT --
BUT THEY DIDN'T HAVE
ANY STANDARD MODELS LEFT.
PARTY IN 23
DIDN'T CHECK OUT.
THIS WAS THE ONLY ROOM
I COULD GET.
AND THE AUTOMOBILE
WITH THE SCOTCH AND THE BOURBON
AND THE NEW
"TUCK ME IN" LOOK,
THAT WAS THE ONLY THING
YOU COULD GET, TOO, HMM?
I DIDN'T THINK
YOU'D BELIEVE ME.
I DON'T. AND THE WARM-UP
ON THE MOUNTAINTOP --
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG
WITH YOUR TIMING, IS THERE?
I CROSS MY HEART, MOLLY.
AND THE NIGHTCAP THAT WAS
SUPPOSED TO SET ME UP.
WHAT DID YOU HAVE IN MIND --
A-A TRIPLE BOURBON?
I SWEAR TO YOU,
MOLLY, I --
NOW, LOOK, CLYDE. I TOLD YOU --
NO ONE-NIGHT STANDS.
NOW, AS FAR
AS I'M CONCERNED,
ROOMS 31 AND 32
ARE JUST ONE ROOM,
AND THEY HAVE
JUST ONE TENANT.
YOU?
MM-HMM.
HENRY?
HENRY, YOU ALL RIGHT?
YEAH, I'M ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE STILL PARTNERS,
AREN'T WE?
WE'RE STILL PARTNERS.
GOOD NIGHT, PARTNER.
GOOD NIGHT.
HELLO. OPERATOR?
YEAH, COULD YOU GET ME
MIDLAND, TEXAS,
EXCELSIOR 3-6-2-2-1,
PLEASE?
UH, MY NUMBER
IS W-1-H-K-K.
HELLO, PATRICIA.
HOW ARE YOU?
SAY, PAT, COULD YOU GET ME
BO BLUEDOG
ON THE OTHER RADIO PHONE
AND HAVE HIM CALL ME
AT W-1-H-K-K?
UH...
CONNECTICUT, I'D SAY,
HEADING SOUTH.
[ TELEPHONE BUZZES ]
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU, PAT.
HENRY TYROON'S OFFICE.
YES, HE IS.
OH, JUST ONE MOMENT.
IT'S SOMEBODY
CALLED BILLY JOE.
THANK YOU.
HI, BILLY JOE.
HOW ARE YOU?
YEAH, YEAH.
BILLY JOE, I TOLD YOU
I'D HAVE THE MONEY ON SCHEDULE.
I FIGURE TO SWING A BIG PIECE
OF CHANGE ON A RESTAURANT.
YEAH, AND I ALSO GOT A PIECE OF
THE ACTION WITH SOME PAINTERS.
YOU HEARD ME RIGHT.
PAINTERS.
WELL, I HAVEN'T GOT
THE WHOLE $1.2 MILLION,
BUT I'M MOVING, BILLY JOE.
I'LL GET IT SOMEHOW.
YOU JUST RELAX
AND HAVE BO CALL ME
WHEN HE GETS BACK FROM
HIS COFFEE BREAK, YOU HEAR?
THANK YOU, BILLY.
I HAD A TALK WITH
THADDEUS WHIPPLE THIS MORNING.
I WANT BO BLUEDOG TO GET
HIS DRILLING CREW TOGETHER.
DON'T BE SO MYSTERIOUS, HENRY.
WE'RE PARTNERS, REMEMBER?
YOU KNOW
THAT LITTLE WEED PATCH
- WHERE THE FACTORY BURNED DOWN?
- MM-HMM.
WELL, I MADE A DEAL WITH WIDGET
FOR THE SUBSOIL RIGHTS.
THE DRILLING RIGHTS?
YOU MEAN TO SAY
YOU THINK THERE'S OIL
THERE IN MASSACHUSETTS?
[ TELEPHONE BUZZES ]
HENRY TYROON'S OFFICE.
JUST ONE MOMENT.
I'LL SEE IF HE'S IN.
ARE YOU IN?
IT'S FOR YOU.
HELLO?
OH, HI, JACK.
HOW ARE YOU?
JACK? NOT BO?
IT'S JACK GRAHAM.
HE HEARD I WAS AT THIS NUMBER.
JUST A SOCIABLE CALL.
WHAT'S THAT, JACK?
OH, WELL,
IT'S KIND OF PARTLY CLOUDY.
IT'S A NICE DAY, THOUGH.
NICE DAY YESTERDAY, TOO.
HOW IS IT DOWN THERE,
HOT AND DRY?
JACK SAYS IT'S HOT AND DRY
DOWN IN TEXAS.
OH, THAT'S A LOAD OFF MY MIND.
[ TELEPHONE BUZZES ]
HENRY TYROON'S OFFICE.
YES, HE IS, BUT HE'S BUSY
ON THE OTHER LINE JUST NOW.
WILL YOU HOLD, OR SHALL I
HAVE HIM CALL YOU BACK?
WELL, THAT'S RIGHT NICE
OF YOU, JACK.
JACK'S FLYING SOME PEOPLE
TO SUN VALLEY.
WANTS TO KNOW
IF WE WANT TO GO SKIING.
IT'S FOR YOU.
OH, HEY, JACK,
I GOT ANOTHER CALL.
I GUESS WE'LL HAVE TO PASS
THIS TIME.
RIGHTO.
THANK YOU, JACK.
HELLO?
OH, HI, BO!
HOW ARE YOU?
WELL, IT'S KIND OF PARTLY
CLOUDY, BUT IT'S A NICE DAY.
I HEAR IT'S HOT AND DRY
DOWN THERE.
TERRIFIC WEATHER REPORT.
COSTS ONLY $300 AN HOUR.
BO, GOT A LITTLE PROJECT
FOR YOU.
YEP. WHIPPLETON,
MASSACHUSETTS.
NO, I'M NOT KIDDING.
THE UNIVERSAL WIDGET SITE.
WE'LL DRILL RIGHT THROUGH
THE ROCK TO THE EOSINE.
LET ME KNOW
WHEN YOU GET THERE, BO.
BO, SKIP THE QUESTIONS.
I GOT A REASON.
YOU JUST CALL ME
WHEN YOU GET TO THE HOTEL.
RIGHTO.
NOW, WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
THAT THERE'S ANY OIL
WITHIN 1,000 MILES
OF MASSACHUSETTS?
MOLLY, YOU GOT
A LITTLE OLD COMPANY
THAT'S GOT A LITTLE OLD
WEEDY PIECE OF LAND.
IT NEVER HURTS
THE STOCK IN IT
TO SET UP A DRILLING RIG
AND DRILL FOR OIL.
[ TELEPHONE BUZZES ]
HELLO?
NO, THIS IS W-1-H-K-K.
YEAH.
YOU BETTER HURRY
IF YOU'RE GONNA GET DOWNTOWN
BEFORE THE STOCK MARKET
CLOSES.
YOU CAN HAVE A HAIRDO
OR A RIDE IN A CONVERTIBLE,
BUT YOU CAN'T HAVE BOTH.
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]
COME IN!
DOOR'S OPEN!
All: AFTERNOON, MA'AM.
HOWDY, HENRY.
WE JUST GOT IN.
HI, JAY RAY,
RAY JAY, J.R.
HENRY, THEY REALLY GOT
OIL IN MASSACHUSETTS?
WELL...
A MAN CAN'T EVEN USE
A RADIO PHONE ANYMORE.
YOU GONNA BE ABLE TO DRILL
THROUGH THAT HARD ROCK
TO THE EOSINE, SON?
WHAT'S THAT MASSACHUSETTS
ACTION, HENRY?
NOW, YOU BOYS
ARE A WEE BIT EARLY.
THIS IS
AN INVESTMENT SITUATION.
I'LL KEEP YOU INFORMED.
HENRY, COULDN'T I
SELL THEM SOME?
I'LL TAKE AN EIGHTH,
WHATEVER IT IS.
WAIT A MINUTE.
I'LL TAKE AN EIGHTH.
TAKE AN EIGHTH OF YOUR EIGHTH,
RAY JAY.
FOR THE EIGHTH OF THE EIGHTH,
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT I'LL DO --
GIVE YOU A RIG I GOT STACKED
AND THROW IN A HELICOPTER.
I DON'T NEED NO RIG.
I'LL SWAP YOU TWO
OF MY EXPRESSIONIST PICTURES.
RAISE YOU AN EXPRESSIONIST
AND THROW IN ANOTHER HELICOPTER.
WELL, NOW, SIR,
I'LL JUST SEE YOUR RAISE,
AND I'LL RAISE YOU TWO MORE
OF MY EXPRESSIONIST PICTURES.
NOW, WHOA, WHOA.
HOLD ON, BOYS.
THERE'S NOTHING
TO SELL YET.
WELL, HENRY, IF WE'RE EARLY,
DON'T YOU FORGET ONE THING.
WE STILL BUDDIES.
- YOU BETTER BELIEVE IT.
- YEAH.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
HOW CAN YOU BUY SOMETHING WHEN
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW WHAT IT IS?
WELL, YOU SEE, MA'AM, HENRY HERE
IS A REAL WHEELER DEALER.
AND A WHEELER DEALER
IS SOMEBODY
THAT LOVES TO FIND PLACES
FOR MONEY TO GO.
IT'S LIKE HITCHING
ONTO A STAR.
YOU MAY ZOOM UP TO THE SKIES
ON A MIGHTY PRETTY RIDE.
AND IF THE STAR FALLS?
WELL, THEN I FIND SOME WAY
FOR THE GOVERNMENT
TO TAKE THREE-QUARTERS
OF THE LOSS.
YOU SEE, MISS THATCHER,
THAT'S THE MARK
OF A REAL WHEELER DEALER.
YEAH.
AAH!
INVESTORS!
THAT STREET
IS FULL OF INVESTORS!
[ GROWLING ]
Man:
OH, STOP IT, VANSON.
LOOK AT THEM
DOWN THERE, BOSS.
MONEY, MONEY, MONEY --
THAT'S ALL THEY WANT.
RELAX, VANSON.
RELAX?
HOW CAN I RELAX?
I DOUBLE-CHECKED
THE CONSOLIDATED SILICON
STOCK TRANSFER.
IT'S ALL PERFECTLY LEGAL, BOSS.
THE COMPANY'S IN THE CLEAR.
BE PATIENT.
SOMETHING OUTRAGEOUS
IS BOUND TO COME ALONG.
WE HAVEN'T HAD
A REALLY GOOD VICTIM
SINCE WE SMASHED
ZIRCON AVIATION PRODUCTS.
[ CHUCKLES ]
TOO BAD YOU WEREN'T AROUND
FOR THE CRASH OF '29.
IT WAS HEAVEN.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YEAH. YEAH.
I'VE GOT LOTS OF STATISTICS,
LIKE LABOR SUPPLY
AND POWER CONSUMPTION
IN THE AREA
AND THINGS LIKE THAT.
THAT WON'T DO IT,
SWEETHEART.
WE NEED ROMANCE --
WAVES OF THE FUTURE,
RIBBONS OF CONCRETE
ACROSS THE LAND,
THE COUNTRY GROWING,
GROWING, GROWING.
WE GOT TO BUILD A BANDWAGON
FOR THESE PEOPLE TO JUMP ON.
I SURE HOPE
YOU LIKE GARLIC.
WE HAVE GOT TO FIGURE, WHO ARE
THE BIG INVESTORS TODAY?
NOT THE MORGANS
AND THE ROCKEFELLERS ANYMORE.
NO, IT'S THE PENSION FUNDS AND
UNION FUNDS AND MUTUAL FUNDS.
RIGHT. NOW, YOU TAKE
ONE OF THESE MUTUAL-FUND FELLAS.
MAILMAN BRINGS HIM $20 MILLION
EVERY DAY TO INVEST.
HE CAN'T GO SPECULATING
ON NO WILDCATS.
NO, HE GOT TO
PLAY IT CAUTIOUS.
HE HAS GOT TO INVEST
JUST LIKE
ALL THE OTHER MANAGERS DO.
NOW, WE'VE GOT TO CONVINCE
EACH ONE OF THEM
THAT THE OTHER
IS BUYING WIDGET.
[ LAUGHS ]
WHAT ARE YOU LAUGHING AT?
YOUR SOCKS.
I NEVER SAW THOSE BEFORE.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH MY SOCKS?
WELL...
YOU LOOK LIKE A BUNNY.
I LOOK LIKE A BUNNY?
MM-HMM.
I CAN JUST SEE YOU
AS A LITTLE BOY.
LITTLE TINY WHEELER DEALER
TRADING A RED WAGON
FOR A BICYCLE.
AND YOU LOOK SO MUCH
LIKE A BUNNY,
NOBODY COULD GET MAD.
IT'S TIME FOR BUNNY'S
EVENING NIBBLE.
[ SIZZLING ]
MM! MM!
SCALLOPINI'S BURNING.
I APPRECIATE THE JOB YOU BOYS
DID PUBLICIZING MY RESTAURANT.
- IT WAS GREAT.
- HA! GREAT!
DID HE SAY GREAT?
LISTEN TO HIM, BUSTER.
HE CALLS IT ONLY GREAT.
ONLY GREAT, MR. TYROON?
THE JOB WE DID
WAS ONLY MAGNIFICENT!
- ONLY STUPENDOUS!
- ONLY FABULOUS!
THAT'S ALL IT WA--
GET THE BOOK. GET THE BOOK.
YOU'LL READ THE BOOK.
YOU'LL LOOK IN THE BOOK.
YOU'LL SEE.
LOOK. EVERY PAGE HAS GOT A PLUG
FOR CHEZ-HENRI.
OKAY, OKAY.
I AGREE.
NOW I'VE GOT SOMETHING ELSE
FOR YOU TO TAKE ON.
YOU NAME IT, WE'LL MAKE IT
A HOUSEHOLD WORD.
UNIVERSAL WIDGET.
IT'S A LITTLE STOCK
NOBODY EVER HEARD OF.
WIDGET.
- WIDGET.
WID-GET.
WIDGET.
I CAN HEAR IT NOW, BUSTER.
IT STARTS AS A WHISPER.
THEN IT RISES TO A MURMUR.
Both: UNTIL IT BECOMES
A TRIUMPHANT SHOUT
IN THE THROATS
OF ALL AMERICA!
WHAT'S A WIDGET?
THE COMPANY HAS SOMETHING
TO DO WITH COMMUNICATIONS.
DON'T --
DON'T TELL US MORE.
WE DON'T BELIEVE
IN OVERRESEARCHING A PRODUCT.
BOYS, THERE ARE LAWS
ABOUT THIS SORT OF THING.
NOW, I WANT
A FIRST-CLASS JOB.
I WANT IT RESTRAINED, DIGNIFIED,
BUT HARD-HITTING.
SAY NO MORE.
THERE ARE DIFFERENCES BETWEEN
THIS CAMPAIGN AND THE --
HOLD IT. HOLD IT, MR. TYROON.
BUDDY'S THINKING.
[ THUMPING ]
I GOT IT! I GOT IT!
I GO--
WE LAUNCH A CAMPAIGN
TO GIVE AMERICA THE LEAD
IN INTERNATIONAL WIDGETRY!
YOU'VE GOT TO GIVE ME TIME,
MR. BEAR.
NOW, IN A WEEK, I GUARANTEE YOU
ACTION, OR I'LL RESIGN.
BUT, MISS THATCHER, THIS THING
KEEPS DRAGGING ON AND ON AND ON.
NOW, LOOK, MR. BEAR.
YOU PROMISED ME A MONTH,
AND THAT MONTH ISN'T UP YET.
NOW, IS YOUR WORD WORTH ANYTHING
OR ISN'T IT?
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
WELL, IT VARIES.
IT -- [ SIGHS ]
MOLLY THATCHER?
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU,
MISS THATCHER.
MAYBE I DID SAY ONE MONTH,
BUT THAT WAS --
NOW, LOOK.
LOOK AT THIS.
TEXAS MUTUAL
COOPERATIVE FUNDS.
RIGHT, AND IT'S A VERY SIZABLE
INVESTMENT IN WIDGET.
NOW I'VE GOT THE MUTUAL FUNDS
INTERESTED,
AND THIS IS
JUST THE BEGINNING.
MISS THATCHER,
I OWE YOU AN APOLOGY.
TAKE A WEEK, TAKE A MONTH --
TAKE ALL THE TIME THAT YOU LIKE.
FROM THE VERY FIRST DAY THAT YOU
SET FOOT IN THIS OFFICE,
I SAID TO MYSELF,
"THAT BOY IS GOING PLACES!"
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
SURE, SWEETHEART.
YOU DID?
WELL, NOW, THAT'S WHAT I CALL
REAL WONDERFUL.
BUT HOW DID A TEXAS MUTUAL-FUND
OUTFIT EVER GET WIND OF IT?
WELL, RAY JAY AND JAY RAY
AND J.R. WANTED PARTICIPATION,
BUT I WANTED THEM
TO PARTICIPATE MY WAY.
You see,
the three of them are
the Texas Mutual
Cooperative Fund.
THEY ACT MORE LIKE SPECULATORS
THAN MUTUAL-FUND OPERATORS.
NO, NO, SWEETHEART.
THEY'RE NOT
A MUTUAL-FUNDS COMPANY.
IT'S A CATTLE SYNDICATE.
I MIGHT HAVE KNOWN
THERE'D BE A CATCH SOMEPLACE.
WHY ARE YOU
SO DISAPPOINTED?
SOUNDS LIKE A MUTUAL FUND,
DOESN'T IT?
[ Chuckles ]
Man:
SEE WHERE TEXAS MUTUAL
IS ADDING UNIVERSAL WIDGET
TO THEIR PORTFOLIO.
IT'S GOOD TO SEE AN INTEREST
IN WIDGET.
AND HIGH TIME.
IF WE DON'T WATCH OUT,
THE SOVIET UNION
WILL OUTPRODUCE US IN WIDGETS.
YOU WON'T BE THE FIRST MAN
IN THIS TOWN
WHO TURNED DOWN
A GOOD THING
BECAUSE A WOMAN BROUGHT IT
TO HIS ATTENTION,
BUT WHEN TEXAS MUTUAL
COOPERATIVE FUND
MOVES ON AN ISSUE, IT'S TIME
YOU TOOK A LOOK FOR YOURSELF.
Man: LOOK.
IT'S ONLY ABOUT 7/8
OF AN INCH LONG.
THE PRODUCTION OF WIDGETS
IS A MASTERPIECE OF TOOLING.
ANY WIDGET WITH A TOLERANCE
OF MORE THAN 1/10,000 OF AN INCH
IS REJECTED.
Man #2: I GUESS THAT'S
WHAT MAKES THEM SO VITAL
TO TRANSISTORIZED
COMMUNICATIONS.
EXACTLY.
AIN'T NO OIL
IN MASSACHUSETTS.
I WON'T SAY THERE IS,
AND I WON'T SAY
THERE AIN'T.
WE MADE WENDELL'S COLUMN
THIS MORNING.
LISTEN TO THIS.
"DID THE SECRETARY
OF DEFENSE
"MAKE A SECRET TRIP
TO NEW ENGLAND YESTERDAY
FOR A QUICKIE INSPECTION
OF UNIVERSAL WIDGET?"
Henry:
NOT BAD. NOT BAD AT ALL.
YEAH, BUT WE'VE GOT TO ASK
MORE QUESTIONS.
THAT'S RIGHT. QUESTIONS ARE VERY
IMPORTANT, MR. TYROON.
YOU ASK ANY QUESTION,
AND THE PUBLIC ANSWERS YES.
YOU MEAN LIKE, "IS UNIVERSAL
WIDGET STEPPING UP PRODUCTION
"TO MEET THE DEMANDS
OF RADIO STAR,
THE NEW COMMUNICATIONS
SATELLITE?"
BUSTER,
HE'S GIVING OFF SPARKS.
NOT BAD. NOT BAD.
"IS TEXAS MUTUAL FUNDS
PULLING OUT OF RAILS
"TO CONCENTRATE
ON COMMUNICATIONS ISSUES
SUCH AS UNIVERSAL WIDGET?"
HE EFFERVESCES!
HE BUBBLES!
"ARE UNION LEADERS WORRIED
AS AUTOMATION STEPS UP
WIDGET PRODUCTION OVERNIGHT?"
EVERY WORD
IS MOTHER'S MILK.
GENTLEMEN, YOU'RE GREAT.
YOU HAVE DONE IT AGAIN.
[ UP-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYS ]
MY OFFICE CABLED
YESTERDAY.
THERE'S A HOT RUMOR
GOING AROUND --
A MERGER BETWEEN RCA
AND UNIVERSAL WIDGET.
WHERE THERE'S SMOKE,
THERE'S FIRE.
HONEY, WE'VE GOT IT.
WHAT? WHAT? WHAT?
WHAT DO WE HAVE?
HERE IT IS.
THIS IS THE LATEST ISSUE
OF MODERN TECHNIQUES
AND COMMUNICATIONS.
IT'S THE TECHNICAL JOURNAL
OF THE COMMUNICATIONS INDUSTRY.
NOW, LISTEN TO THIS.
"THE MANUFACTURERS
OF RADIO STAR,
"THE NEW COMMUNICATIONS
SATELLITE,
"HAVE STATED THAT THEY NEED
ALL THE WIDGETS
"THEY CAN POSSIBLY
ROUND UP,
"BECAUSE THEY CONSIDER THEM
ESSENTIAL
TO EFFICIENT PRODUCTION."
THEN THERE REALLY ARE WIDGETS.
THEY REALLY USE THEM?
[ Imitating Whipple ]
ANY FOOL KNOWS
THAT WIDGETS WENT OUT
WITH FLYING CLIPPERS.
OH, WELL, THEN THAT PARAGRAPH
DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
I ONLY READ ONE PARAGRAPH.
THE WHOLE ARTICLE
IS ABOUT RADIO STAR,
THE NEW COMMUNICATIONS
SATELLITE.
NOW, INSIDE THE SATELLITE,
THEY CAN'T AFFORD TO WASTE
ONE INCH OF SPACE,
BECAUSE IT'S GOT
UMPTEEN INSTRUMENTS.
NOW, MEN HAVE TO MOUNT
THESE INSTRUMENTS
INSIDE THE SATELLITE
IN SOME PRETTY CLOSE QUARTERS.
ORDINARY MEN ARE HAVING
AN AWFUL LOT OF TROUBLE
SQUEEZING IN THERE
AND DOING ALL THIS WORK
IN THOSE ITTY-BITTY PLACES.
SO THEY'RE HIRING MIDGETS
TO DO THE WORK.
WELL, THEN WHAT'S THIS ABOUT?
A-A MISPRINT?
I SUPPOSE SO.
THEY SAID "WIDGETS,"
AND THEY MEANT "MIDGETS."
SO WHY DON'T YOU JUST GET OVER
ON THAT LITTLE OLD PHONE
AND YOU READ
THAT LITTLE OLD PARAGRAPH
TO ALL THE PEOPLE
ON YOUR LITTLE OLD LIST.
HENRY, DO YOU REALLY
THINK THAT --
HONEY, I DON'T WANT YOU
TO TELL A LIE.
I WANT YOU TO TELL
THE TRUTH,
AND THE TRUTH IS THAT MODERN
TECHNIQUES AND COMMUNICATIONS
PRINTED THE STATEMENT
THAT YOU ARE ABOUT TO READ.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YEAH.
[ UP-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYS ]
45. I'LL BET WIDGET MAKES 60
BY THE FIRST OF THE MONTH.
OUR GIRL PICKED A WINNER.
WELL, NOT EXACTLY.
I PICKED IT.
BUT SHE DID A PRETTY GOOD JOB
WITH IT.
HEY, LOOK AT THAT.
47.
WHITBY, IF IT HITS 50,
TAKE OUT THE PAPER TOWELS
AND BRING BACK
THE LINEN SERVICE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ BELL CHIMES ]
[ UP-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYS ]
WILL YOU
LOOK AT THIS, BOSS?!
"WIDGET TO ENTER
MIRACLE DRUG FIELD."
YEAH.
WELL, VANSON, YOU MAY BE
ON TO SOMETHING.
WELL, THE WAY THAT STOCK'S
BEEN GOING UP
IS LITTLE TOO SPECTACULAR
FOR ME.
[ LAUGHS ]
- ALL RIGHT.
PUT THE SURVEILLANCE SQUAD ON IT
AND GIVE ME A DAY-BY-DAY REPORT.
RIGHT, BOSS.
I'LL LAY ODDS
SOMEBODY'S KITING THAT STOCK.
YOU KNOW,
THAT DEDUCTION WE GOT
FROM THE APPRAISED VALUE
OF THEM EXPRESSIONISTS
IS GONNA RUN OVER 10 CENTS
TO THE DOLLAR.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I FIGURED IT CLOSER TO 12.
OH, HENRY'S BEEN A REAL GOOD
BUDDY TO US THIS YEAR.
HE EVEN MADE US MONEY
ON THAT RESTAURANT, TOO.
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT
I'VE BEEN THINKING.
OLD HENRY'S DONE WELL BY US,
AND WE OUGHT TO DO SOMETHING
FOR HIM.
WELL, YOU CAN'T
GIVE HIM ANYTHING.
HE DON'T WANT TO OWN
A THING.
LEASES EVERYTHING
SO HE CAN DEDUCT IT.
MUST BE SOMETHING OLD HENRY
WANTS THAT WE CAN HELP HIM WITH.
WELL, I NEVER
HEARD OF ANYTHING HENRY WANTED
HE COULDN'T GET
FOR HISSELF.
EXCEPT, WELL, MAYBE THAT
LITTLE OLD GIRL UP IN NEW YORK.
- YEAH!
- MAYBE.
NAH.
THAT LITTLE OLD GIRL'S TOO STUCK
ON THE STOCK MARKET
TO HAVE ANY TIME
FOR HENRY --
ANY REAL TIME.
I THINK I KNOW A WAY
WE CAN HELP OLD HENRY OUT.
HOW?
LET'S HIGHBALL IT TO NEW YORK.
YEE-HA!
THANK YOU.
I WANT YOU TO KNOW
THAT I CONSIDER THE PRESIDENCY
OF THIS ORGANIZATION
THE HIGHEST HONOR ANY GIRL
ON WALL STREET CAN RECEIVE.
AND I PROMISE TO USE
MY TERM OF OFFICE
TO OPEN MORE AND MORE DOORS
TO WOMEN SECURITY ANALYSTS.
AND IN TIME, NO ONE WILL DARE
STAND IN THE WAY
OF WOMEN TAKING THEIR RIGHTFUL
PLACE IN WALL STREET,
AND BETWEEN YOU AND ME,
IT WON'T BE LONG
BEFORE I AM NO LONGER
THE ONLY WOMAN
IN THE INNER OFFICES
OF BEAR, OSGOOD, AND WHITBY.
YOU WANT ME TO FIRE
MY TOP ANALYST?
A WOMAN'S PLACE
IS IN THE HOME,
BUT MOST WOMEN
DON'T KNOW IT.
YOU GOT TO PUSH 'EM.
TEXAS IS GONNA MAKE MOLLY
MIGHTY HAPPY, TOO,
EVEN IF SHE
DON'T KNOW IT YET.
YOU WANT HER TO BE HAPPY,
DON'T YOU?
CAN'T POSSIBLY LET HER GO.
SHE'S MY NUMBER-ONE BOY.
WELL, WE THINK YOUR NUMBER-ONE
BOY'S READY FOR MOTHERHOOD.
JUST NOW, WHEN WIDGET
IS REALLY STARTING TO FLY?
WE HAPPEN TO KNOW
YOU TOOK A REAL WHOPPING
IN GREAT EASTERN
OFFSHORE OIL.
I CAN'T DO IT.
IT'S, UH, IT'S MORALLY WRONG.
SUPPOSE WE WAS TO GET YOU
OFF THE HOOK WITH GREAT EASTERN.
YOU MEAN YOU'D TAKE
MY WHOLE POSITION?
FOR HENRY AND MOLLY,
WE'LL TAKE THE WHOLE THING.
GENTLEMEN, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO SAY.
EXCEPT YOU MAKE ME FEEL HUMBLE.
TRULY HUMBLE.
OUT SHE GOES.
OH, HENRY, IF YOU KNEW HOW MUCH
I WANTED TO BE PRESIDENT.
WELL, THAT'S VERY NICE,
BUT IT DOES MAKE FOR SOME
DIFFICULTIES, DOESN'T IT?
And, Henry, I want you to come
to Philadelphia this weekend
to meet my parents.
They'll adore you.
I hope.
WELL, CAN WE, UH,
LEAVE FOR TEXAS FROM THERE?
TEXAS?
As I remember,
we got a deal.
OH, THAT.
UM, WELL, HENRY,
I KNOW I MADE THAT DEAL,
BUT, WELL, MY TERM OF OFFICE
IS SIX MONTHS,
AND I JUST CAN'T LEAVE NOW.
You can wait six months,
can't you?
YOU MADE A PROMISE, MOLLY.
YOU GAVE ME YOUR WORD ON IT.
Please, Henry, how did I ever
know I'd really be president?
A PROMISE IS A PROMISE.
WELL, I KNOW I PROMISED,
BUT...
HENRY, COULDN'T WE
TALK IT OVER TONIGHT?
WELL, UH, COULD YOU
DROP UP HERE, MOLLY?
IF YOU'D LIKE ME TO, HENRY.
I COULD ORDER US A LITTLE,
UH, LATE SUPPER.
That would be nice.
I'm tired of restaurants,
even Chez-Henri.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
A LITTLE CHAMPAGNE
WOULDN'T HURT, WOULD IT?
NEVER HURT ANYBODY.
BYE.
[ SMOOCHES ]
[ SIGHS ]
YOU WERE A GREAT TALENT,
STANISLAS.
AND LOOK AT YOU NOW.
DON'T YOU LIKE
THE WAY I RIDE?
IT'S PEOPLE LIKE YOU
WHO GIVE THE NORTH MEDITERRANEAN
NEOREALIST MOVEMENT A BAD NAME.
THE BRUSH IS OUTMODED
AS A TOOL OF ART.
MODERN TECHNOLOGY DEMANDS NEW
MEANS OF ARTISTIC PRODUCTION.
ANYWAY, BUSTER, IT'S NOT ME
THAT'S BOTHERING YOU.
YOU'RE SUFFERING
FROM ACUTE LACK OF MOLLY.
MAYBE YOU'RE RIGHT.
I'VE LOST HER,
AND IT COULDN'T HAPPEN
AT A WORSE TIME.
MY PSYCHIATRIST WON'T SPEAK
TO ME WHEN SHE HEARS ABOUT THIS.
YOU COULDN'T
HELP IT, MAN.
TELL YOUR SHRINK THAT'S THE WAY
THE POPSICLE MELTS.
BROTHER, YOU DIDN'T
MAKE THE SCENE AT ALL.
I WAS DEFEATED BY MONEY.
PLAIN, COMMON, ORDINARY,
FILTHY MONEY.
WELL, THAT'S NOT TRUE.
PUTTING THE STOCK OVER
HELPED.
BUT THE REAL THING
IS EXCITEMENT,
WIN, LOSE, OR DRAW.
THAT GUY ALWAYS HAS
A GOOD TIME.
HE LOVES THE GAME,
ANY OLD GAME.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT --
MOLLY WITH A HALF-EDUCATED,
SUN-DRIED PRAIRIE MARSHAL.
YOU'VE BEEN TUNED IN
TO THE WRONG WAVELENGTH, NARDO.
MEANING WHAT?
UNDERNEATH
ALL THAT COWBOY JAZZ,
THE OVERSIZE HAT,
AND THE BOOT BIT,
HE'S STRICTLY A YALE TYPE
FROM BOSTON.
BOSTON?
HE'S NOT FROM TEXAS?
LOOK, MAN, LONG AGO,
HE FIGURED
THE BEST WAY TO RUB UP AGAINST
MONEY WAS TO BE A TEXAN.
NOW HE'S BEEN THERE SO LONG,
HE'S CAUGHT THE ACCENT.
BUT THAT ITALIAN
HE SPEAKS SO WELL.
MAJORED
IN ROMANCE LANGUAGES
IN A LITTLE OLD TEXAS
SCHOOLHOUSE BY THE NAME OF YALE.
YALE? BUT --
BUT MOLLY DOESN'T KNOW
ABOUT THIS DECEPTION, DOES SHE?
WHAT IF SHE DOESN'T?
LOOK, MAN, IF YOU'RE GONNA WALK
ON MY CANVAS,
THE LEAST YOU CAN DO IS PUT
A LITTLE CRIMSON ON YOUR SOLES.
DID YOU SEE WIDGET
THIS MORNING, MR. B--
SIT DOWN, MISS THATCHER.
THANK YOU.
DID YOU SEE WIDGET THIS MORNING?
IT BROKE THROUGH ITS UPSIDE
RESISTANCE LEVEL -- 59.
YES. WELL, EVERYBODY HITS
A LUCKY FLUKE NOW AND THEN.
A LUCKY FLUKE?!
MISS THATCHER, I'VE BEEN WANTING
TO TALK TO YOU FOR SOME TIME,
LIKE A FATHER TO A DAUGHTER.
I'VE BEEN WATCHING
WHAT'S BEEN HAPPENING TO YOU.
YOU'VE GROWN HARD.
THAT TENDER, LOVELY LOOK
YOU USED TO HAVE IN YOUR EYES
IS GONE.
NOW THEY GLINT.
NO, I HAVE TO COME RIGHT OUT
AND SAY IT.
THIS CRASS COMMERCIAL WORLD
HAS COARSENED YOU.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
NO, MISS THATCHER, I WOULDN'T
WANT IT ON MY CONSCIENCE
THAT I TOOK
A LOVELY YOUNG GIRL
AND LET HER WORK
TRANSFORM HER
INTO A HEARTLESS, GRASPING
DEALER IN THE MARKETPLACE.
I-I CAN'T JUST BEAR SITTING BY
AND WATCHING
WHILE I SEE ALL THAT IS
WONDERFUL AND TENDER IN YOU
RUN OUT AND CAST ASIDE.
YOU CAN CLEAN OUT
YOUR DESK.
BUT YOU SAID --
I HAVE A DAUGHTER YOUR AGE, MOLLY.
AND NOW THAT I'M FIRING YOU,
I MAY CALL YOU MOLLY, MAY I NOT?
YOU GAVE ME YOUR WORD.
BUT REALLY,
YOU'LL BE MUCH HAPPIER IN TEXAS.
TEXAS?
DID YOU SAY TEXAS?
THAT'S RIGHT --
I UNDERSTAND YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
A TICKER TAPE
IN THE KITCHEN AND --
OOH, THAT DOUBLE-CROSSING
SIDEWINDER!
OOH, I WAS READY TO LIVE UP
TO MY PART OF THE DEAL,
BUT IF HE THINKS HE CAN
GUARANTEE IT THIS WAY...
NOW, MOLLY,
THERE'S NO NEED --
NOW, LOOK, MR. BEAR,
I'M NOT PART OF ANY DEALS,
AND I'M STAYING HERE
ON WALL STREET.
WITH MY RECORD IN WIDGET,
I CAN GET ANOTHER JOB
IN THREE MINUTES.
OH, BY THE WAY...
WE REVOKED YOUR
SECURITY DEALER'S REGISTRATION.
THE PAPERS SHOULD BE
IN WASHINGTON BY NOW.
[ TELEPHONE RINGS ]
HELLO?
HELLO. HENRY?
LISTEN, HENRY,
I PHONED TO ASK YOU,
HOW LONG DO YOU WANT US TO KEEP
DRILLING HOLES IN MASSACHUSETTS?
You know, this is gonna
run you into money.
WELL, FINISH OUT THE DAY
AND PACK UP,
AND I'LL SEE YOU
DOWN IN TEXAS.
SEE YA.
TEXAS.
HE EVEN WENT SO FAR AS TO HAVE
MR. BEAR REVOKE MY REGISTRATION.
OOH, I USED TO WONDER HOW LOW
A MAN COULD GET, AND NOW I KNOW.
I DON'T GET IT.
A FEW HOURS AGO,
YOU WERE MOONING OVER HIM.
YOU WERE READY TO PLAY
THE PAJAMA GAME.
A FEW HOURS AGO, I THOUGHT
HE WAS A MAN, NOT A SNAKE.
[ TELEPHONE RINGS ]
HELLO? YES.
OH, LEONARD,
I DON'T WANT TO TALK NOW.
ALL RIGHT.
MAKE IT QUICK.
HE WHAT?!
ARE YOU SURE?!
OH, THAT FRAUD!
DO YOU REMEMBER THE FIRST TIME
I TOLD YOU ABOUT HENRY TYROON?
I SAID HE WAS A $3 BILL
IF I EVER SAW ONE.
THEN YOU WENT THROUGH
A PERIOD OF INFLATION.
I WAS RIGHT.
HIM WITH HIS TEXAS BOOTIES.
WHY, THAT PHONY WAS BORN
AND BRED IN BOSTON.
HE WENT TO YALE!
NOBODY'S PERFECT.
AND THE ACT HE PUT ON.
HE EVEN MOVED HIS LIPS
WHEN HE READ!
SO HE LED YOU
UP THE GARDEN PATH.
HE SURE DID.
BUT NOW HE CAN JUST COOL
HIS HEELS AND WAIT FOR ME,
BECAUSE I'LL JUST GO BACK
TO PHILADELPHIA
WHERE THE MEN MAY BE DULL,
BUT AT LEAST THEY'RE NOT
BACKBITING FRAUDS!
AS LONG AS HE'S WAITING
FOR YOU,
WHY NOT GIVE HIM
SOME OF THE SAME?
THE SAME WHAT?
A STROLL
UP THE GARDEN PATH.
WAIT RIGHT THERE.
I WAS SAVING THIS
FOR A RAINY DAY.
GIVE ME
THAT SHORTY NIGHTIE.
WELL, DO YOU HAVE TO TALK
RIGHT NOW, BO?
I'M EXPECTING A VERY IMPORTANT
VISITOR UP HERE ANY MINUTE.
I'VE GOT TO TALK NOW!
HENRY!
HENRY, YOU READY?!
ALL RIGHT. GO AHEAD, BO.
WHAT IS IT?
HENRY, I DON'T KNOW,
BUT MAYBE WE'RE BOTH CRAZY,
BUT I'M WATCHING IT
COME UP!
IT'S COMING UP!
THE PUREST OIL I EVER SAW!
OIL IN MASSACHUSETTS?
WHAT ARE YOU TAKING,
HAPPY PILLS?
HENRY, WE WON'T EVEN
HAVE TO REFINE IT!
[ LAUGHS ]
[ RECEIVER CLICKS ]
OIL IN MASSACHUSETTS.
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]
OH, THE ROOM
LOOKS WONDERFUL, HENRY.
YOU SURE HAVE GOOD TASTE
FOR A TEXAN.
I GOT YOUR VERY FAVORITE DINNER
COMING UP IN A LITTLE WHILE,
AND I GOT
THAT CHAMPAGNEY WINE
COOLING IN ITS OWN
LITTLE OLD BUCKET.
OH, THAT'S TERRIFIC.
I SURE COULD USE
SOME CHAMPAGNEY WINE.
SAY NO MORE.
HEY, WHAT YOU GOT
IN THE LITTLE POKE, HUH?
OH, THIS?
MY NIGHT THINGS.
WHERE'S THE OTHER HALF?
OH, THAT'S ALL THERE IS.
THERE ISN'T ANY MORE.
[ BOTH CHUCKLE ]
BETTER GIVE ME THAT COAT,
OR YOU'LL BE STANDING AROUND
WITH IT ALL NIGHT LONG.
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]
AH, COME IN, GENTLEMEN.
OH, RIGHT OVER HERE.
RIGHT THERE.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
THAT WILL BE ALL.
OH, EVERYTHING LOOKS
JUST WONDERFUL.
HENRY, WHAT'S IT REALLY LIKE
IN TEXAS?
OH, MOLLY, YOU MEAN...
OH, YES. I MEAN.
MOLLY...
WELL, WHAT ABOUT
THE PRESIDENCY?
OH, NO, NO, NO, HENRY.
I'VE DECIDED THAT A WOMAN'S
PLACE IS IN THE HOME,
SO I'M GOING TO
GIVE UP WALL STREET
FOR A COOKBOOK
AND A HUSBAND.
AND IF YOUR HOME
IS IN TEXAS,
THEN THAT'S WHERE
MY HOME IS, TOO.
MOLLY.
SHALL WE CHOW DOWN?
WHY NOT? THEN WE'LL HAVE THAT
OUT OF THE WAY.
[ SIGHS ]
EVERYTHING
WAS JUST PERFECT.
IT MIGHT BE JUST THE MOST
PERFECT EVENING OF MY LIFE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU KNOW, SWEETHEART,
WE CAN GET MARRIED
IN MIDLAND,
AND THEN YOU CAN REDO THE HOUSE
ANY WAY YOU WANT IT.
WELL, IF IT'S YOUR HOUSE,
I'M SURE I'LL LIKE IT
JUST THE WAY IT IS.
UH, DARLING, UM...
WHY DON'T YOU JUST LEAVE ME
ALONE IN HERE FOR A FEW MINUTES,
AND YOU GO IN AND SLIP INTO
SOMETHING MORE COMFORTABLE.
MORE COMFORTABLE?
MM-HMM.
ALL RIGHT, SWEETHEART.
YOU'LL SAY WHEN.
OH, OF COURSE, DARLING.
[ CLICKS TONGUE ]
OH, HENRY.
WHEN, HENRY.
MOLLY!
YOU WANT TO TALK ABOUT DEALS,
HENRY TYROON?!
YOU WANT TO TALK
ABOUT TEXAS?!
MOLLY!
WHAT'S THIS ALL ABOUT?!
OH, DON'T PLAY INNOCENT
WITH ME!
MOLLY!
I WAS READY TO GIVE UP
MY PRESIDENCY FOR YOU,
BUT YOU HAD TO WRAP IT UP,
DIDN'T YOU?!
NO! MOLLY!
YOU HAD TO GET ME FIRED!
YOU HAD TO GET
MY REGISTRATION REVOKED!
WELL, NOBODY GETS ME
BY DOUBLE-DEAL--
DON'T!
NOBODY GETS ME THAT WAY.
YOU LIKE THIS THING SO MUCH,
YOU WEAR IT YOURSELF.
MOLLY, I DIDN'T GET YOU FIRED!
I DIDN'T DO ANY OF THOSE THINGS!
- I SUPPOSE YOU'D SWEAR IT ON
THE STATE OF TEXAS!
- THE WHOLE STATE!
WELL, YOU CAN DROP
THAT LITTLE ACT, TOO,
BECAUSE YOU'RE A BOSTON BOY
WITH A YALE DEGREE,
AND I THINK YOU GOT IT
IN DOUBLE-DEALING.
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
IT'S AN ACT TO TRY TO WEASEL OUT
OF YOUR BARGAIN!
ME WEASEL MY WAY --
OH! OH!
MOLLY! MOLLY!
MOLLY!
[ DOOR OPENS ]
- HI, MOLLY.
- HI.
MMM. MARTINI.
IN THE KITCHEN, ALL MADE.
WHAT'S WITH THE PHONE?
HENRY'S BEEN CALLING ME
ALL DAY.
I HAVE A SORE ARM
FROM HANGING UP.
ELOISE GETS TELEPHONE ACTION,
TOO, REMEMBER?
[ TELEPHONE RINGS ]
HELLO?
HOLD ON.
I'LL SEE.
IT'S HENRY TYROON.
WHAT SHALL I TELL HIM?
TELL HIM
TO GO SOAK HIS HEAD.
MOLLY SAYS YOU SHOULD
GO SOAK YOUR HEAD.
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ TELEPHONE RINGS ]
HELLO?
OH, YES, MR. TYROON.
HE SAYS HE'S DRYING OFF
HIS HEAD.
[ CHUCKLES ]
WHAT WAS THAT?
WELL, I'LL TRY.
MOLLY?
HMM?
I LOVE YOU.
WHAT?
WELL, THAT'S WHAT HE TOLD ME
TO TELL YOU.
TELL HIM
I'LL GET HIM ARRESTED
AS SOON AS I CAN THINK UP
A CHARGE.
SHE SAYS SHE'S GOING TO
HAVE YOU ARRESTED
AS SOON AS SHE CAN
THINK UP A CHARGE.
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]
COME IN.
MR. HENRY TYROON?
THAT'S ME.
WHAT'S THAT?
- SUBPOENA.
- FOR WHAT?
FRAUD -- IN THE MATTER
OF UNIVERSAL WIDGET.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
MOLLY!
Man: DEFENDANTS ARE CHARGED
WITH VIOLATIONS
IN THE INVESTMENT COMPANY ACT,
THE ERIE CANAL ACT,
SECTIONS 14 THROUGH 23
OF THE INTERSTATE COMMERCE ACT,
CONSPIRACY TO LURK,
ENTAILMENT...
MR. VANSON, THIS INDICTMENT
SEEMS TO BE
A LITTLE ENTHUSIASTIC.
WELL, THEY'RE A PRETTY SLIPPERY
BUNCH, YOUR HONOR.
I HAD TO THROW THE BOOK
AT THEM.
MR. VANSON, THIS COURT INTENDS
TO WHITTLE DOWN --
WHITTLE DOWN, YOU UNDERSTAND? --
THE RELEVANT EVIDENCE.
THE LAST SECURITY CASE I SAT ON
TOOK FIVE YEARS.
I DON'T INTEND
TO SPEND FIVE YEARS
ON THIS ONE, YOU UNDERSTAND?
NOW, WE'LL STICK
TO THE BARE BONES.
THE BARE BONES,
YOU UNDERSTAND?
WE'LL GET OUT OF HERE
BY LUNCHTIME, YOU UNDERSTAND?
LUNCHTIME.
NOW GO AHEAD. GO AHEAD.
PROCEED.
ALL I DID WAS READ TO THEM
EXACTLY WHAT WAS WRITTEN
IN THE MAGAZINE.
AHA!
AND YOU CONSIDER THAT
PERFECTLY ETHICAL?
WELL, I WAS DESPERATE.
MY BOSS WANTED TO FIRE ME,
AND I WANTED TO KEEP MY JOB.
AH, THEN IT WAS
A LITTLE UNETHICAL.
NOW, I CAN'T LET HER TAKE
THE RAP FOR THAT, YOUR HONOR.
SHE NEVER WOULD HAVE
THOUGHT OF IT
IF I HADN'T
TOLD HER ABOUT IT.
NOW, HOLD ON, MR. TYROON.
YOUR ATTORNEY WILL GIVE YOU AMPLE
OPPORTUNITY TO SPEAK
AT THE PROPER TIME.
PROCEED, MR. VANSON.
NOW, MISS THATCHER,
YOU TOOK THIS WEEKEND TRIP
TO MASSACHUSETTS
WITH MR. TYROON.
WHAT WERE YOUR RELATIONS
WITH HIM?
WE WERE BUSINESS ASSOCIATES --
THAT AND NOTHING ELSE.
YOU WERE BUSINESS ASSOCIATES --
THANK YOU, MISS THATCHER.
I NOW CALL TO THE STAND
MR. HORACE PILLSBURY.
YOU ARE HORACE PILLSBURY,
NIGHT CLERK IN THE
COTTON MATHER INN, ARE YOU NOT?
I AM, AND THERE AIN'T MUCH
ESCAPES ME.
[ LAUGHTER ]
MR. PILLSBURY,
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN
THESE TWO
BUSINESS ASSOCIATES BEFORE?
YES, SIR.
THEY CHECKED INTO
THE COTTON MATHER INN
ON, UH, TUESDAY NIGHT,
JULY 16th.
THERE AIN'T MUCH
ESCAPES ME.
[ LAUGHTER ]
CAN YOU DESCRIBE THE NATURE
OF THE ACCOMMODATIONS
THESE BUSINESS ASSOCIATES TOOK?
YOUR HONOR!
YOUR HONOR, THAT QUESTION'S
IMPROPER AND IRRELEVANT.
YOUR HONOR, WE SUBMIT
THAT THIS LINE OF QUESTIONING
HAS ABSOLUTELY NOTHING
TO DO WITH THIS CASE.
NO, NO, NO, NO.
IT HAS EVERYTHING
TO DO WITH THE CHARGES.
MUCH OF THIS CASE DEPENDS
UPON THE CREDIBILITY
OF THE WITNESSES.
I PLAN TO PROVE TO THE COURT
THAT THEIR TESTIMONY
IS UNRELIABLE.
IF THAT'S THE PURPOSE OF THE
QUESTIONING, YOU MAY PROCEED.
THANK YOU, SIR!
NOW, MR. PILLSBURY,
WILL YOU PLEASE
ANSWER THE QUESTION?
WELL, THAT
BUSINESS ASSOCIATE
TOOK ONE ROOM
WITH A DOUBLE BED,
AND THAT BUSINESS ASSOCIATE
TOOK THE ADJOINING ROOM.
AND THEY SHARED
THE CONNECTING BATH.
AHA!
SO MUCH
FOR THE WITNESS'S CLAIM
THAT THE DEFENDANTS
WERE BUSINESS ASSOCIATES
AND NOTHING ELSE.
NEXT WITNESS, PLEASE.
Man: MR. THADDEUS WHIPPLE.
NOW, MR. WHIPPLE,
DID YOU LEASE THE SUBSOIL RIGHTS
TO MR. TYROON?
Whipple: YOU MEAN THAT CRAZY
FELLOW OVER THERE? I SURE DID.
HE PAID GOOD MONEY FOR THEM,
AND HE CAN HAVE THEM.
AIN'T NO OIL
IN MASSACHUSETTS.
WHAT ABOUT THE OIL MR. TYROON
CLAIMS TO HAVE DISCOVERED THERE?
HE STRUCK OIL, ALL RIGHT.
HE STRUCK A PIPELINE RUNS RIGHT
UNDERNEATH OUR PROPERTY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
PIPELINE?
PURE DIESEL.
DID, UH, HE KNOW
THERE WAS A PIPELINE THERE?
CAN'T SAY HE DID,
CAN'T SAY HE DIDN'T.
DID YOU TELL HIM
THERE WAS A PIPELINE THERE?
OF COURSE NOT.
HE DIDN'T ASK ME.
MR. WHIPPLE,
DOES THE PIPELINE COMPANY KNOW
ITS OIL IS BEING DIVERTED?
THEY OUGHT TO.
MY BROTHER LEMUEL'S
THEIR LAWYER,
AND HE FILED SUIT
THIS MORNING.
HE CHARGES TRESPASSING,
DAMAGE TO PROPERTY,
AND A LOT OF OTHER THINGS.
YOUR BROTHER'S SUING YOU?
NOT ME.
SUING THEM CRAZY TEXANS.
THEY OWN THE SUBSOIL RIGHTS,
NOT ME.
NOW, MR. TYROON,
SUPPOSE YOU TELL THE COURT
THE REAL REASON
FOR YOUR TRIP
TO MASSACHUSETTS.
LIKE I SAID,
A SORT OF PICNIC.
SEE, I'D MET THIS PRETTY GIRL
WHO FOR ONCE HAD SOME BRAINS,
AND SHE WAS HAVING A LITTLE
TROUBLE WITH A STOCK REPORT,
SO I FIGURED I'D COMBINE A
LITTLE BUSINESS WITH PLEASURE.
WELL, IT WAS A WAY
OF COURTING HER.
I OPENED MY BATHROOM DOOR,
AND THERE YOU ARE,
BRUSHING YOUR TEETH
IN YOUR UNDERWEAR!
[ LAUGHTER ]
NO OUTBURSTS, MISS THATCHER.
I SLEPT IN THE CAR, YOUR HONOR,
AND LET ME TELL YOU.
IT WAS COLD OUT THERE.
WILL THE WITNESSES
PLEASE CONFINE THEMSELVES
TO THE PURPOSES
OF THIS HEARING?
THEN THE REAL REASON
FOR YOUR TRIP
WAS YOUR INTEREST
IN THAT YOUNG LADY?
WELL, YOU MIGHT SAY SO.
AND I'M STILL INTERESTED.
OH, I SUPPOSE
THAT'S WHY YOU GOT ME FIRED.
I DIDN'T GET --
AGAIN, I MUST ASK
THE WITNESSES THAT --
PLEASE, YOUR HONOR,
I JUST HAVE TO SPEAK.
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW
SHE GOT FIRED.
NOW, I'M WILLING TO TAKE
HALF THE BLAME.
- I'LL TAKE A QUARTER.
- I'LL TAKE AN EIGHTH.
LET'S TAKE 5/16ths
AND SPLIT IT THREE WAYS.
I'M ONLY THE JUDGE HERE,
BUT WILL SOMEBODY LET ME IN
ON THE SIGNIFICANCE
OF THIS TESTIMONY?
WHAT HENRY SAYS IS TRUE,
YOUR HONOR.
WE GOT MISS THATCHER LET GO
IN TRADE FOR SOME STOCK,
BUT WE MEANT WELL.
OH, HENRY.
HENRY!
[ SPECTATORS MURMURING ]
WITNESSES WILL REFRAIN
FROM HUGGING AND KISSING.
OH, Y-YOUR HONOR, MR. TYROON
SHOULDN'T BE A DEFENDANT.
I WAS THE ONE
WHO WANTED TO SELL WIDGET,
AND I DIDN'T MUCH CARE
HOW I DID IT.
PRESUMABLY NOT, YOUNG LADY.
TRADING IN THIS STOCK STOPPED
WHEN IT REACHED ITS PEAK.
EVERYONE HAS SOLD IT SO FAR
AS A PROFIT.
WHAT ABOUT THE INNOCENT PEOPLE
WHO ARE STILL HOLDING IT?
WE WHIPPLES HOLD 48%.
ALWAYS HAVE
AND ALWAYS WILL.
WE HOLD ANOTHER 48%,
YOUR HONOR.
WE FIGURED AS LONG
AS HENRY WAS INTERESTED,
- THERE JUST HAD TO BE A REASON.
- YES, SIR.
YOU BOUGHT THIS STOCK
FROM EVERYBODY?
THAT'S RIGHT, YOUR HONOR.
GUESS OUR 48% AND MR. WHIPPLE'S
48% MAKES US PARTNERS.
HOWDY, PARTNER.
NOW, YOU STOP THAT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
THERE'S STILL
4% STOCK OUTSTANDING.
SOON AS I GET IT,
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR NO TALK
ABOUT PARTNERSHIPS FROM YOU,
Y-YOU... COWBOY!
[ LAUGHTER ]
WELL, NOW, THE FACT IS,
YOUR HONOR,
I HAVE THE OTHER 4%.
NOW, IF MR. WHIPPLE THERE
IS INTERESTED IN PURCHASING
MY PERCENTAGE,
WHICH REPRESENTS
THE BALANCE OF POWER --
LET ME SEE NOW.
$1.2 MILLION, PAINTINGS,
THE RESTAURANT...
I DON'T THINK
A HALF A MILLION DOLLARS
IS ASKING TOO MUCH, IS IT?
SINCE THIS SITUATION HAS REMOVED
THE STOCK FROM PUBLIC OWNERSHIP,
THIS COURT NOW CONSIDERS
THAT THE CASE
IS BEYOND THE JURISDICTION
OF THE FEDERAL SECURITIES
COMMISSION.
CASE DISMISSED.
[ SPECTATORS MURMURING ]
KISS NOW.
THANK YOU, YOUR HONOR.
AFTERNOON, MISS THATCHER.
HOWDY, PARTNER.
TAKE GOOD CARE OF MY BOY.
THANK YOU, MR. BEAR.
HENRY, I'LL TAKE
A FOURTH OF THE ACTION.
AND I'LL TAKE THREE-FOURTHS
OF HIS FOURTH.
FIGURE ME IN FOR A FIFTH,
AND I'LL LOAN YOU MY HELICOPTER.
NO DICE, BOYS.
THIS IS A PRIVATE CORPORATION.
♪ HERE COME THE ♪
♪ WHEELER DEALERS ♪
♪ HIGHFALUTIN LOCAL YOKELS ♪
♪ DIAMONDS IN THE ROUGH ♪
♪ FANCY-DANCING CITY SLICKERS ♪
♪ AIN'T THAT A BIG DEAL? ♪
♪ YEAH, LONG AS WE GOT MONEY,
THAT'S ENOUGH ♪