Cut it off. Please.
Please!
Cut it off.
Please.
- Aren't you full of surprises?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Yes.
You're beautiful.
Open your eyes so I know
you hear me.
Beautiful.
What about birth control?
Menopause.
Who's the lucky boy?
Okay. Okay.
I think we should take
your blood pressure.
- My blood pressure?
- I think it's irresponsible not to.
- Nobody but you would stop...
- Yeah, so you're lucky.
Oh, God, I can't...
I can't see.
- My glasses.
- Okay.
120l80! Oh, baby!
Oh, my God.
I do like sex.
- You certainly do.
- Wow!
Oh, God.
So this is what you're supposed to do
on a rainy afternoon, huh?
I really thought I was...
...sort of closed up for business.
I never expected this.
Nothing's ever surprised me more.
This is crazy.
I can't remember
the last time I cried. I...
I think I'm overwhelmed.
Me too.
That's the perfect word.
Baby, I had sex three days
after a heart attack, and I didn't die.
That's gotta be some kind of a record.
Yeah.
Let's just not brag about this
to your doctor, okay?
Honey.
I may not be many things,
but one thing I am is discreet.
Yeah.
Erica?
Erica.
Yeah?
Erica?
You know I'm not good
at being monogamous, right?
Monogamous?
Please. I hardly know you.
But why Paris?
I just always wanted to
write a play that ended there.
People need that romance, and if
someone like me doesn't write it...
...where will they get it? Real life?
- Excuse me?
What do you call this?
Eating eggs by candlelight,
in our robes...
...after...
Sorry.
So where do you like to eat in Paris?
I love this bistro called
The Grand Colbert.
It's behind the Palais-Royal. It's the
best roast chicken in the universe.
You'd be fun to go to Paris with.
It is the best city
to stay up all night in.
Hey, when is your birthday?
- February.
- Well, mine's January.
So how about if we still know
each other by then, we go to Paris...
...for our birthdays, huh?
Maybe.
You just said... You know something,
I have no idea how to do this.
I don't know how to be intimate
but not intimate.
The color is draining from your face.
Okay, I'm gonna pee, take one of
your blood-pressure pills...
...and when I get back,
let's not talk anymore.
Erica.
You're the funniest girl
I ever had sex with.
Well, that's something.
Honey.
I think I should go back to my room.
- Let you get some sleep.
- Let me sleep?
Yeah.
Right.
You usually send the girls home.
But I am home.
- Okay.
- Well, I'm an old dog, you know?
Hey.
It's perfectly... Whatever.
This was...
...a great night...
...for me.
Me too.
Yeah?
At one point...
...I even thought...
...soul mates.
Good night.
I'd like to try sleeping with you.
Oh, my God!
Hi.
What time do you think it is?
Can you see this?
Not really. It looks like it says...
...11?
- It is 11.
- It is?
No way. It can't be.
Oh, my God, that would mean
we slept eight hours?
- Impossible.
- Yeah.
Oh, Nellie.
A little dizzy.
Oh, no. Okay, now, you just...
You just stay still.
There you go. Here's the clicker.
You have a doctor's appointment
in an hour.
I'll make us some coffee,
get you your pills...
...whip us up some french toast.
I have the best maple syrup ever.
Erica.
You are a woman to love.
"You are..."
"You are a woman to love."
What the hell does that mean?
Okay, buddy, your echo
looks real good.
I'm sending you back to the city.
Past few days
have done wonders for you.
Yeah, I've been working on
that stair thing.
I can do it, by the way.
Do what?
Climb a flight of stairs.
Several times, actually.
Way to go.
So how's Erica?
Erica, as it turns out...
...is an amazing woman.
- She's just...
- Well, that's wonderful.
I think she's wonderful.
I think she's wonderful too.
Give her my best.
Julian?
Thank you...
...for everything.
You're gonna be okay.
I am?
This is the second time
I've done this.
I get overcome or something.
It's so out of the blue.
It's common to become emotional
after having an episode like you had.
Everything takes on a new meaning.
So it's not crazy for a guy
to do something...
...so totally out of character
after having a heart attack.
You mean like crying?
Yeah.
And completely changing their taste.
Like, suddenly...
...really liking something that you
never thought you could ever like.
Ever.
- It's unnerving.
- You can expect anything right now.
People have done some wild things
after having a heart attack.
But most people go back to
being themselves, right?
I'm gonna go back to being me...
...aren't I?
We'll see.
Here you go.
You can have these back now.
I confiscated them
on your first night here.
- Thank you, darling.
- Try not to smoke them.
And I packed you a sandwich,
just in case your blood sugar got low...
...and some of that iced tea you like,
a low-cholesterol cookie and a peach.
What a doll.
Got something else?
Something to remember me by.
- There is that.
- And, hey...
...we'll always have Paris.
Bad joke.
- Honey?
- Yeah?
No words can ever
express my gratitude...
...for taking me in...
...and taking care of me and...
- Hey. Your heart attack...
...could be the best thing
that ever happened to me.
- I love ya.
- I love you too.
If that's what you said.
I don't know if it ends in a "ya"
if it's an official "I love you," but...
You're not like anybody.
- I knew you'd call.
- Who? It's me.
- What's wrong?
- Had breakfast with Dad.
We're talking, and he starts
looking weird and tells me...
...he met someone three weeks ago,
that it's really something.
And then he...
He tells me he's getting married.
Why am I reacting this way?
I'm almost 30 years old.
- Wait, wait. Who is he marrying?
- I don't know.
Some chick he met three weeks ago.
She's two years older than me.
She's an ear, nose and throat
doctor. Has he lost his mind?
- Honey...
- I have a huge auction tonight...
...and I'm really upset.
My shrink's away for two weeks.
Can you come in? I know
you're working, but just, please?
I get that he has a right to get
remarried, but he doesn't know her.
She's my age.
Do you know what that's like?
That's, like, beyond creepy.
It's not like I think he's
replacing me. I know he isn't.
I know I'm too old
to act like this, it's nuts.
First of all, please don't smoke.
If he is replacing anyone, it's me,
not you. And all the statistics say...
...divorced men always remarry.
It's how they're built.
Wanna know why I'm always
with the wrong guy?
This is why. Because the wrong guy
can't do this to you.
This is my big fear,
that some guy can get me...
...unglued like this.
And this is just Dad!
We know this about me. I am just
not cut out for this kind of drama.
I think it's the drama in
life that makes you strong.
You always say things to me like this.
You never understand
that everyone isn't like you.
If I were you, and my ex-husband,
the man I allow to direct my plays...
...were getting remarried
to some 33-year-old...
...ear, nose and throat babe,
I'd be bonkers. And look at you.
- You never looked better, by the way.
- Oh, well...
Marin, we're all set.
I gotta go sell $40 million
worth of art.
Can you do one other big thing
for me? Just say yes, just...
- Please?
- Anything, bubby.
I need you to come out to dinner
with me, Dad and the fiancée.
- Absolutely not. No.
- Mom, you have to.
Hey. You have to.
Yes, because he wants me
to meet her. I can't go alone.
I asked them if you could come,
and they said it was fine.
You're gonna have to meet her too,
so we should do it together.
Come on. Please?
You know you can handle it.
Well...
Okay, that's it. You see that
look on your face?
That's the gene I didn't get.
Welcome to Christie's and tonight's
sale of impressionist and modern art.
The auctioneer may open bidding
on any lot below the reserve...
...by bidding on behalf of the seller.
Let's start with lot number one...
...the Renard, showing here.
$80,000 is bid with my absent bidder.
$85,000, gentleman's bid.
$90,000, still with me.
$ 100,000. $ 110,000.
$ 140,000, gentleman's bid.
And fair warning.
Guess I got stood up.
Would you like to order or...?
Why not? I put the tie on
and everything.
Can you bring me another?
Your drink, ma'am.
Oh, good. Thank you so much.
So delicious.
- Thirsty?
- I've had a very big week.
I forgot how these slip right down.
I'm fine.
So, Kristen, where did you
go to medical...
...school? Oh, I'm so sorry.
University of Pennsylvania.
Well, actually, I went to school
in Philadelphia too.
- Bryn Mawr girl.
- You're kidding.
- My mom went to Bryn Mawr.
- Wow!
Not only are you marrying my dad,
our moms went to the same college.
- Shall we order?
- Absolutely.
Erica? Do I like duck?
Yes, it's rabbit you hate.
I'll give you a list of his likes
and dislikes.
Let her figure things out for herself.
I'm not talking about that, Dave.
After all, she did go to medical school.
Hey, hey, hey.
Not in front of the kids.
So, what do you see that you like?
- What are you having?
- I don't know.
You know,
I'm looking at the grilled salmon...
- Who would like what?
- Mom, are you okay?
- Sure you're okay?
- Yeah, no, I'm fine. I'm...
- I'm fine.
- You sure?
- Oh, yes.
- Good.
If we wanted pasta,
we could get the fresh rigatoni.
Grilled free-range chicken teriyaki...
I'm not sure. What about you?
I'm sorry.
Maybe I need a little air.
- Are you okay?
- Fine. I'll be right back.
- Excuse me.
- I'm sorry.
I...
- Hey!
- Hello, Harry.
Hi.
- Hi.
- I don't know if you know...
God, I'm so stupid.
- What?
- Erica!
- Harry, I gotta go.
- Slow down!
You wanna kill me?
Taxi.
Erica.
- She's just a friend.
- Oh, yeah.
- She looks like a buddy kind of girl.
- Come on.
- Just a dinner.
- Harry, look.
Here's the problem.
I really like you.
- I really like you.
- Yeah, but I "love you" like you.
I do, I love you.
I think that we should consider...
...maybe we're getting
ahead of ourselves.
- Do you?
- Yeah.
I am like the dumb girl
who doesn't get it.
I've never been the dumb girl before.
It ain't great.
Let's just calm down.
I had these plans
before I even met you.
- I mean, I do like seeing you. I do.
- Yeah.
- I'm always surprised by it.
- Surprised by it?
What was I thinking?
I have never lied to you.
I have always told you
some version of the truth.
The truth doesn't have versions, okay?
Will you cut me a little slack?
- My life has been turned upside down.
- Mine too!
Well, then let's just each
get our bearings.
I don't want my bearings.
I've had my bearings
my whole goddamn life.
I felt something with you
that I never really knew existed.
Do you know what that's like,
after a 20-year marriage...
...to feel something
for another person that is so...?
That...
Right. Right. Not your problem.
God. Do you know that
I've written this, but I never...
...really got it.
Do you know what this is?
No.
This is heartbroken.
How's that for impervious?
You're killing me.
I just wish that it had lasted
more than a week.
Me too.
That is a terrible thing to say.
You know, the life
I had before you...
...I knew how to do that.
I could do that forever.
But now look at me.
What am I gonna do?
What am I gonna do with all this?
Taxi.
Erica. Can you wait just a second?
The truth is, I...
I just...
I don't know how to be a boyfriend.
That's what you have to say?
That you don't know how to be
a boyfriend?
That's not a small thing.
Are we done?
I don't know.
Oh, my God.
Ouch.
Came in via cab.
Vital signs are stable.
Respiratory is on its way.
Chest pain, hospitalized
a week ago with an MI.
- Switch over to monitors.
- Hang a nitro drip.
You can't.
I took Viagra.
You have been through this before.
Let's run a 12-lead EKG.
You having chest pain right now?
No. And the pain
I was having was sharp...
...not like before.
- Good.
"Not like before"
is what we like to hear.
I was really out of breath...
...like I couldn't catch it.
Okay. Give him an aspirin,
and let's run a blood gas.
Mr. Sanborn, what were you doing
at the onset of the pain?
Having a fight with someone.
A woman.
- Can a woman give you chest pains?
- Are you kidding?
- Love hurts, haven't you heard?
- I've heard.
I just never personally experienced it.
- Well, you've been lucky.
- Yeah. Lucky.
All right. Your EKG
looks perfectly normal.
Your heart rate's good.
The pain you described...
...is not the kind we worry about.
I think what you experienced
was hyperventilation...
...brought on by stress.
- Stress?
- And in case you haven't heard...
...stress can give you
a heart attack.
I have no idea what you're up to,
gallivanting out at this hour...
...one week after
having a heart attack...
...but if you were my dad,
I would have you home in bed...
...recuperating.
"If you were my dad..."
Hi, it's Erica. I'm not here,
so leave me a message.
Ouch.
You have one new message.
Message one.
Erica, hi, it's Julian.
I'm in the restaurant...
...and I'm just wondering if you're
on your way. It's about 8:20.
It's a lovely night out here.
It's a nice...
Oh, my...
Go figure.
Zoe!
- Hey, Mom, we're going into town.
- Okay.
Are you crying?
Yeah.
It's my new thing.
- I've gotten abnormally brilliant at it.
- Why? What is it?
I'm in love.
Ain't it great?
Seems like I gotta learn
how to do that...
...Iove-them-and-leave-them stuff,
you know?
Oh, Mom, I hate this.
Now do you get my theory about
all this? You gotta self-protect.
You don't really buy this stuff
you say, do you?
You don't actually think that you
can outsmart getting hurt?
- I think it's worth trying.
- Listen to me.
You can't hide from love
for the rest of your life...
...because maybe
it won't work out...
...maybe you'll become unglued?
It's just not a way to live.
Are you telling me this is good?
I think you should consider
the possibility...
...that you and I are more alike
than you realize.
I let someone in,
and I had the time of my life.
I've never had the time of my life.
I know, baby.
And I say this...
...from the deepest part
of my heart.
What are you waiting for?
- Hey!
- Great party.
Thank you. My pleasure.
- Hey.
- Hey, good to see you.
You having fun?
Not quite.
I got you something great
at the farm stand.
These are for you to give me
when you apologize.
Julian, I hope you know how mortified
I am by my behavior.
I was gonna get in touch
or send a note.
- A note?
- A note.
- That's a little chilly.
- Well...
...I'm embarrassed.
I just haven't been myself lately.
What can I say?
Just tell me you're sorry.
I am sorry.
Then you could kiss me.
Kiss you?
You're gonna forgive me
if I kiss you?
I think so.
No one on earth would forgive
you for that kiss.
May I?
I forgive you.
Yes!
- It's the best thing you've ever written.
- It is?
- It's wonderful.
Yes, it's sweet,
it's smart, it's funny...
How great is it for you that I'm not
intimidated by your brilliance?
Must we go through this every time?
Come here. Come here.
Good. That's very good.
Anyway, you know
what I'm gonna do?
Oh. Oh, my God!
Oh, I gotta tell you.
I'm totally excited
about this audition.
It's such a great part. Supporting,
but she's a really funny character.
There's this totally hilarious scene
where she's dating this older...
...chauvinistic guy.
Just as they're
about to do it, he moans.
And so she's just thinking that he's,
like, really into her...
...except he's having a
heart attack.
She's, like, totally creeped out...
...and her mom, who basically
despises the guy, rushes in...
...and gives him CPR
and saves his life.
Are you okay?
Isn't that funny?
Hold on, hold on.
Let's not get so dramatic here.
What are we, four teenagers?
We're all sophisticated people.
Why can't we all stay
for the weekend?
Your mother has work to do,
I've got papers to grade.
You do what you're going to do,
whatever that might be...
I need to talk to you.
- Together, and if we don't,
we don't.
Got a minute?
So your play is about us?
- No, it's about me.
- Am I in it?
Well, a guy like you is in it,
but he's not you.
What happens
to this guy who's not me?
I haven't totally decided.
He can...
He can live, or he can die.
- What are you leaning towards?
- Death.
- It's funnier.
- Fine.
He dies of a funny heart attack.
He's a schmuck, who screwed around
with our heroine, so it won't be sad.
Schmucks are people too, you know?
Death doesn't seem
a little harsh to you?
I went where the story took me. It's a
work of fiction, stuff that I made up.
They're ready to do the hospital
"Do you take Viagra?" scene.
- Should we wait for you?
- Yeah. That's good. That's fine.
So I'm gonna be
the laughing stock of Broadway?
Harry, he's not you.
He's a version of the truth
of you, so to speak.
Dave wants to know
when Henry says, "I love ya"...
...you want that to be "ya,"
not "you," right?
Right.
Well, you look really nice.
Thank you.
- Are you feeling all right?
- You know...
...it isn't like I wanted
to stop seeing you.
We could've carried on
a fun thing for a while.
Why is it that you broads
want all or nothing?
I don't know.
We're just goofy
when it comes to love.
Harry, if it's all right with you...
...I'd like to be friends.
I'm not ready to be your friend.
How's that?
Fine. I understand.
Anyway, do you actually
buy that horseshit?
That men and women can be friends
once they've had sex?
I'm friends with my ex-husband,
but we didn't just have sex.
We didn't just have sex either.
Then what was it? I'd love to know.
Can I e-mail it to you
when I figure it out?
Okay. Okay.
Just moving into another phase
with this thing. I'm mad at you.
- I think I'm mad at you too.
- Excellent!
Because I don't like thinking
about you so much...
...and worrying about how you are
and if I ruined your life.
- You've worried about me?
- Yes, honey.
The schmuck...
...who deserves to die...
...worries about you.
Sometimes worrying about you
feels like a full-time job.
Well, doll, I'm doing great.
So you don't have
to work that shift anymore.
Erica? They want you to look at
the costumes for the dancing Henrys.
Are these gonna work for you?
- Mr. Sanborn, back so soon?
- This is it, I'm dying.
I've had 20 minutes of severe chest
pains, nausea, shortness of breath...
...my blood pressure's
gotta be 170l100.
Give me the nitro,
I didn't take Viagra.
Plug me into an EKG.
I'm taking two beta-blockers...
...blood thinners, Lipitor, Procardia.
If I were you,
I'd pound on my chest.
Mr. Sanborn. Your diagnosis, although
fascinating, was entirely incorrect.
- Impossible!
- Do you realize...
...that a severe anxiety attack
can masquerade as a heart attack?
So I'm nuts.
Perfect. The one thing
I'm not taking pills for.
If you don't wanna
be here every week...
...I suggest you do whatever it takes
to decompress. Now lie down.
Just try something with me.
Come on.
Give me your hand.
Relax, relax.
All right, close your eyes.
Okay, good. I want you
to give yourself a visual...
Both eyes.
I want you to give yourself
a visual image...
...of something that gives you
a feeling of peace and serenity.
I don't know. What?
- A hammock.
- Good.
- What else?
- Palm trees.
Clear, blue water.
What else do you see? Feel?
Taste?
A peach margarita.
A Cuban cigar.
Miles...
...of soft beach.
I couldn't believe you were calling
from downstairs. You have a beard!
- It's great to see you.
- You couldn't look better.
Thank you. Well, come on in.
No, no. I just wanted
to stop by and say hi...
...and tell you I'm sorry if I ever did
anything that wasn't on the up and up.
What do you mean?
You were great to me.
- I was?
- Always.
That's refreshing. Good.
Well, I don't know what
you've done to yourself...
...but you look absolutely radiant.
I'm three months pregnant. That
might have something to do with it.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Who's the lucky guy?
- My husband.
Hold on because he really wants
to meet you. Danny.
Harry Sanborn,
this is my husband, Danny Benjamin.
- Heard so much about you.
- I bet.
Well, you know,
with the play and all.
- I'm famous, huh?
- Hey, just to us.
In every interview my mom does,
she always says she made you up.
So the guy in the play
doesn't make it, does he?
He basically dies
at the end of the second act.
But it gets a huge laugh.
I was hoping
she'd give me a reprieve.
Yeah, well...
Okay.
- Good seeing you. Congratulations.
- Thanks.
- How is she?
- She's really good.
Up to her old tricks. Learning Italian,
remodeling her apartment in the city...
Now, if I wanted to see her,
how would that go over?
Only one way to find out.
Except she's out of town right now.
Oh, yeah? Where is she?
Paris. She left two days ago
for her birthday.
But she'll be back next week.
Paris.
Showtime.
- I knew you'd be here.
- You did?
At first I thought I had the wrong
restaurant, but here you are.
- Just like I imagined.
- You mean...
...we're not bumping into each other?
You came here to see me?
I'm aware it was a bold move...
...one of those impulses that grabs
you, but so far we're okay.
Right?
- I mean... I kind of...
- It would be great...
...if you'd let me take that as a yes.
- Would you like a glass of wine?
- Yeah. I would.
I would love one.
I was just gonna give you a kiss hello.
- Okay.
- Whoa.
Awkward.
You remember how you said
if we still knew each other...
...we should go to Paris
for our birthdays?
Well, we still know each other.
That's true. But, Harry, I haven't
heard from you in six months.
Yeah.
After I saw you in the theater,
with the dancing Henrys...
- Yes. Sorry...
- No, it's very funny, by the way.
- I had another episode.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Well, as it turned out, I was fine...
...but I was sure I was dying, and
the doctor in the ER said I needed...
...to decompress. So I did.
I walked out of there
and changed my life.
Sold most of my businesses,
packed my bags...
...moved to an island in the Caribbean.
That is where you've been
all this time? The Caribbean?
Actually, no.
I was there about six hours...
...when it occurred to me
that wasting away on an island...
...couldn't possibly cure
what was ailing me.
So I decided
to take another kind of trip...
...into, let's call it, my past.
- Your past?
I thought if I visited some
of the women I've known...
...that maybe I could figure
out how I arrived at being me.
- Wow.
- Wow, yeah, it was quite a journey.
Hi, Louise. Remember me?
Hi, how are...?
Some of the ladies, I admit,
weren't too interested in seeing me...
...or even speaking to me,
but one day, my losing streak ended.
One of them opened up to me.
Hearing what she had to say was no
picnic, but I stuck it out and I listened.
And then I listened harder.
And one of the things I realized...
...was I was actually giving closure
to generations of women.
When you hear the same story
about yourself...
...over and over,
your life begins to add up.
Took me months to find them all.
Visited a dozen different states.
But I traveled the farthest to see you.
I don't believe it.
Me either.
- Doc. How are you?
- I'm good.
- Nice to see you.
- You too.
I should have told
you he was coming...
...but I was so engrossed
in your story. I just...
Sorry I'm late.
- What story?
- Oh, maybe another time.
So I guess I should've seen your play.
Would've known how this ended.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, big twist, huh?
Yeah.
So, what are you doing
over here, man?
Just a vacation.
I've never been to Paris in January.
It's amazing to run into you.
You look good.
- You look great.
- I haven't been on a gurney...
...in six months, so that's something.
Well, I've just been
to every store in the city.
- What?
- This woman's impossible to buy for...
...but I think I finally found
the right gift.
Happy birthday, baby.
- I'll open it in a bit.
- No, no, no, no. You know what?
- I'm gonna let you two celebrate.
- Harry, no, please.
Stay. Join us for dinner.
We'd love to...
- I can't. I can't. Really.
- Why? You have somewhere to go?
I've spent a lot of time in hospitals.
It doesn't matter, right?
- Went to see a... What was it?
- No, it was a wheaten terrier.
So beautiful. So beautiful.
Make a wish.
To the forces of destiny
that brought us together.
Forces of destiny. Beautiful.
- You don't smoke.
- I'm in Paris.
Secondhand smoke
will kill you anyway.
She's very brilliant,
but the woman cannot hold her liquor.
- I like that about me.
- Me too.
If I were writing this,
this is where I would write:
"An awkward moment."
Honey, if you were writing this,
I'd be dead.
Never fails to amuse her.
- No. Let us.
- Oh, no.
- Please, let us.
- Doc, I insist. I crashed your party.
- No.
- Let me buy you dinner...
...on your birthday.
Thank you.
What time does that say?
- Oh, God, I have no idea.
- Oh, wait a minute, l...
Me too. Me too.
You think you look
so handsome in mine?
You know how long I have been
looking for those?
Yes, I do.
Thank you very much.
Excuse me. Thank you.
Once again, closure.
- Well, here we are.
- Harry, why don't you take it.
No, no. I think I'm gonna walk.
You two take it.
Well.
- Harry.
- Doc. Thanks for everything.
- Stay well.
- Well, this was fun.
And it was so great to see you.
Honest. So...
It was great to see you.
Look...
...Erica, if you ever...
- No.
- Take care of yourself, Harry.
- Yeah, I will. You too.
It's cold, huh?
Look who gets to be the girl.
Anything else?
- Where's Julian?
- He's back at the hotel.
He said when he saw me with you...
...he knew that I was still
in love with you.
What do you have to say about that?
If it's true, my life just got made.
Why'd you come here, Harry?
Turns out the heart attack
was easy to get over.
You...
...were something else.
I finally get what it's all about.
I'm 63 years old,
and I'm in love...
...for the first time in my life.
That's what I came here to say.
Harry.
- Sanborn.
- Mr. Sanborn.
Four and a half.
Got your table waiting.