SCENES FROM A MARRIAGE
- Nice!
- An ideaI famiIy portrait...
Look into the camera, pIease.
Great!
How about giving us a smile?
Let's see some happy faces.
You too, Mother... Great!
Mind your hair! There we have it.
- That should do it, right?
- Yes, l think so.
- We've finished with the girls.
- You've been so good!
- Bye-bye!
- They were good as gold...
How about some shots
of the parents on the sofa?
Lean forward, you're sliding
too far back. That's it!
- l'll try and make myself small.
- Talk to each other.
Marianne, turn your eyes
slightly towards us...
Look as if you were fond
of each other... There, like that.
Hold that pose! Great....
- That's it. Thank you very much.
- Good!
We'll need some portraits later.
Well then, let's start, shall we?
l always begin with a standard
question, to soothe the nerves.
- l'm not particularly nervous.
- Good. The question is:
How would you describe
yourselves in a few words?
- That's not an easy one.
- Not all that difficult, surely?
- l may be misunderstood.
- Really?
lt may sound conceited to say
l'm highly intelligent, youthful,
successful, sensible, sexy and
l care about the world we live in.
l'm educated, well-read
and a good mixer. Let's see...
l'm a good friend even to people
who are worse off than myself.
l'm good at sports.
l'm a good husband and a good son.
l have no debts and l pay my taxes.
l respect our government,
no matter what it does.
l love our royal family.
l've left the state church.
- Shall l go on?
- Please.
- l'm a splendid lover.
- Perhaps we can skip that question.
What about you, Marianne?
Well, what shall l say?
l'm married to Johan
and l have two daughters...
- That's all l can think of...
- Come on, think harder.
- l think Johan is awfully nice...
- How kind of you.
- We've been married for 10 years.
- We've just renewed our contract.
Unlike Johan, l lack the ability
to see myself in such glowing terms,
but in all honesty, l'm glad
l'm able to lead the life l do.
lt's a good life,
if you know what l mean.
What else? My, this is difficult...
- She has a nice figure.
- l'm trying to be serious.
- l have two girls, Karin and Eva.
- You've already said that.
How about some personal data?
Let's start with your ages.
- l'm 42, but l don't look it.
- l'm 35.
Both of us come from
obscenely middle-class homes.
- Johan's father is a doctor.
- And my mother is the motherly type.
My father is a lawyer.
lt was decided from the outset
that l was to be a lawyer too.
l'm the youngest of seven children.
Mother ran a big household.
- Nowadays, she takes it easy.
- Oh, does she?
Oddly enough, we get on with our
parents. We see a lot of each other.
There's never been
any friction to speak of.
Let's talk about your professions.
Mine is a bit unusual.
l'm an associate professor
at the lnstitute of Psychotechnology.
Family law is my specialty. l belong
to a large firm of solicitors.
Most of my work concerns divorce,
but the interesting thing is...
Hold that pose!
Take a picture, l want
to capture that expression. Good!
- My, l feel so...
- lt will pass.
- Tell me, how did you meet?
- l'll leave that to Johan.
- Lord, that is interesting!
- lt wasn't love at first sight.
We both had a large circle of friends
and ran into each other often.
We were also both involved
in politics for several years
and we went in for amateur
dramatics quite a lot as students.
Well, l can't say we made any
deeper impression on each other.
Marianne thought l was stuck-up.
Johan had a rather highly publicized
affair with a pop singer...
..which gave him a certain image
and made him insufferable.
Marianne was 19.
She was married to a fool whose
only saving grace was a rich father.
He was very kind
and l was madly in love with him.
Besides, l got pregnant
early on in the relationship.
- But how was it that...
- That the two of us joined forces?
That was actually Marianne's idea.
My baby died soon after birth
and my husband and l divorced,
to our mutual relief.
And Johan's singer
had given him his walking papers.
We were both a bit hurt and lonely,
so l suggested making a go of it.
We weren't in love at all,
but we were both downhearted.
And then we found out
that we got along very well
and we really
buckled down to our studies.
We moved in together, a situation
our mothers actually took in their stride.
ln fact, they became good friends.
We were accepted
as Johan and Marianne.
After six months we got married.
- By then we were in love as well.
- Very much so!
- We were seen as an ideal couple.
- And that's still the case.
- No complications?
- We've never had material worries.
We're on good terms with friends
and relations on both sides.
We have good jobs that we enjoy.
We're healthy.
And so on, to an almost vulgar
degree. Security, order, loyalty...
We're almost indecently lucky.
Naturally, we have our differences,
just like other people.
But we agree on all the key issues.
- Don't you ever quarrel?
- Marianne does.
Johan is very slow to anger,
so l run out of steam.
This all sounds wonderful. All of it.
Only last night someone was saying
that the very lack of problems
is a serious problem.
We are well aware that
a life like ours can be dangerous.
How do you mean, dangerous?
The world is going to hell. l claim
the right to mind my own business.
Live and let live, that's my motto.
lt sickens me
to hear about the latest panacea.
- l don't agree with Johan.
- So, what's your opinion?
- l believe in compassion.
- Please elaborate on that.
lf people learned to care
about each other in childhood,
the world
would be a different place.
Hold that pose!
Look into the camera, please.
Listen to this:
"Marianne's eyes, blue as an old
folk song, are lit up from within.
When asked how she copes
with a job and a household,
she smiles with shy delight
and replies that she and Johan
help each other." That's true.
"'We understand each other,'
she says,
brightening as Johan sits down
beside her on their heirloom sofa.
He puts a protective arm around her
and she snuggles up to him."
- Hey!
- This is the best bit!
"So l leave, noticing that they
seem pleased at the prospect
that they can once more
be alone together.
Two people who have matured:
strong, happy and positive.
People who have never forgotten
to give love pride of place."
- We almost died when we read it.
- l was going to file a complaint.
But our mothers and our daughters
simply loved the article.
What really riles me is that
it says nothing about my eyes.
- lsn't there a secret glow in them?
- They're more like dark pools.
- Very sexy, actually.
- Katarina has a crush on you.
- Johan, will you elope with me?
- A change would do Johan good.
He's been so good for 10 years
and has never been unfaithful.
Are you sure?
l believe everything Johan says.
- Did you hear that, Katarina?
- Johan is a better liar than you.
- But l have no imagination.
- That's just it.
- lt makes you a better liar.
- Peter tarts up his stories.
At times l really find it touching.
l read your article in TechnicaI Times.
Even l could understand it.
- Actually, Katarina wrote it.
- Are you that clever?
You see, l was in Germany and
they wanted an article on the spot.
So Katarina wrote it
and read it to me on the phone.
- But why did it have your by-line?
- lt's not discrimination.
- We collaborate.
- That's admirable.
You wouldn't say that
if you knew the details.
Things are rotten between us.
Cheers, Katarina, my poppet!
Cheers...
Does it bother you that l speak
freely to Johan and Marianne?
- What is it, Katarina?
- Nothing. Nothing at all.
Only Peter can be
so damn clumsy sometimes.
Clumsy is the right word...
l take pride in being clumsy...
and imaginative.
The funny thing
is that according to Katarina,
l am nothing
but a spineless jellyfish.
- Jellyfish? Now you're talking.
- Let's try to enjoy ourselves now.
Exactly, because we mustn't forget...
l'm making a thank-you speech now.
Bearing in mind
that fabulous magazine article
reminding us
that we are in a happy home
that we must not soil
with emotional rubbish.
Cheers, Marianne!
l may not envy your domestic bliss...
..but l envy
your talent as a cook.
No, l really mean that.
l wish Katarina
would learn to cook like that.
Katarina is a much better cook.
- Peter says l poison the food.
- lt's a standing joke in our house.
- Right, it's obviously a joke.
- One that's seen better days.
Well, let's go into
the drawing room and have coffee.
Well, Johan, what am l to do?
l've put my foot in it again.
The girls will clear the table.
- lt's all too bloody touching.
- What is?
Your marriage.
Johan and Marianne...
lt can move a person to tears.
ln fact, it makes you want to stick
a pin into your beautiful balloon.
- So would you?
- Cheers to you both!
- lt's been 10 years, right?
- We just had our 10th anniversary.
- No skeletons in the cupboard?
- You never know.
- Both Johan and l like tidying up.
- You hear that, Katarina?
That's where you and l have been
remiss... We never clean things up.
But next week l'll call Marianne
and make an appointment,
so she can get started
on our divorce.
Peter will have changed his mind
by the time he's sober.
That's when the calculator
starts running.
This is what he says:
"l'll agree to a divorce,
if Katarina gives up her claim
to our assets in Switzerland."
And my reply is:
"But it's my money, l've earned it."
Then Peter
will say he has multiplied it
and l can have the whole factory.
Then l say, "that's nice of you
to let me have a factory in ltaly -
that gets more risky
with every rise in labour costs."
- But Katarina, l've said...
- "Take the whole set-up in Sweden.
The apartment, the country house,
the boat, the car,
the shares and the premium
bonds." lsn't that nice?
l get all the taxable stuff!
Excuse me for going on
about such trivial matters,
but when Peter gets started on
assets, l know how drunk he is.
- And the insults aren't far off.
- That's what l've said all along.
Katarina is a businessman,
with equal stress on both words.
A businessman...
ln addition to which,
she's a brilliant artist
and she has
an lQ of l don't know what.
She's attractive as well.
She's a paragon,
and gift-wrapped to boot.
How l ever got lucky with that
monster of perfection is a mystery.
l really think we'll ring for a taxi
and go home now.
This can't be pleasant
for Johan and Marianne...
No... Johan and Marianne?
They're candy figurines
decorated with red ribbons.
Just like the marzipan pigs
of our childhood.
lt's good for their moral fibre,
to gaze
into the bottomless pits of hell.
August Strindberg
once wrote:
"ls there anything more fearsome
than a husband and wife
who hate each other?"
What do you say?
Maybe child abuse is even worse.
But then Katarina and l are children.
Deep down, Katarina
is a little girl who is crying
because she has fallen down
and no one comforts her.
And l haven't grown up either.
l cry
because Katarina can't love me,
in spite of my bad behaviour.
There's one thing to be grateful for.
That there is nothing
more hellish than this.
That's why we're ready for a divorce.
Provided you listen to reason.
Provided we simultaneously,
in each other's presence
and in front of reliable witnesses,
sign all the papers.
So no one can stiff the other.
- We'll call you up this week.
- We have a great business lawyer.
Borglund can help you
with the financial arrangements.
What do you say?
Even if we agree on money matters,
you'll never let me go.
l'm convinced of that.
You think you're that bloody
indispensable, my dear Katarina?
Whatever gave you that idea?
Do tell me... Tell us.
You force me to have sex,
since you can't get it up
with other women.
Your need of a guilty conscience
knows no bounds.
Now that it's all over with Jan
l expect you're in a panic.
You're stuck with old Peter.
He has the right patience.
So you think
you're the only one, do you?
How touching...
You think there are no others.
Let me tell you one thing, Peter...
Please excuse me
if l'm rather outspoken,
but Peter is asking for it
and he needs to be enlightened.
l'll tell you this, Peter...
You nauseate me so much...
..in a physical sense...
that l'd buy myself a lay just
to wash you out of my sex organs.
"Abide with me,
fast falls the eventide
The darkness deepens,
Lord with me abide..."
You son of a bitch!
"When other helpers fail
and comforts flee
Help of the helpless,
Oh, abide with me."
Whatever
that's supposed to mean...
l hope there won't
be any stains on the carpet.
l don't know about liqueur...
Why don't you bill me?
Do as l say!
Would you mind
pouring me a cup of coffee?
l'm pretty sloshed.
Forgive us.
We don't usually behave like this.
But you're our best friends.
You're our only friends.
Forgive me... Forgive us.
lf you ring for a cab,
l'll take my bacchante home
and we'll finish our little scene.
The finale is usually
not suitable for an audience.
- What's the time?
- Ten past twelve.
- Thank goodness we got rid of them.
- Yes, things got a bit out of hand.
Do you believe it's possible
for a couple to be partners for life?
lt's an absurd convention.
Marriage should
be a five-year contract.
- Or be subject to annual renewal.
- What about us?
No, we're the exception
that proves the rule.
- So you think we'll stay together?
- What a funny question.
Are you ever sorry
you can't sleep with anyone else?
- No, are you?
- At times.
- Well, l'll be damned!
- lt's a purely theoretical longing.
l wonder if there's something wrong
with me, l never feel like that.
- l'm content.
- So am l. Now l've got it!
Katarina and Peter go through hell
because they don't communicate.
They have to translate everything
they mean into a common language.
- l think it's simpler than that.
- We understand each other instantly.
We speak the same language,
that's why we're doing fine.
l think it's the money.
lf you speak the same language,
money is not an issue.
- You and your languages.
- l see it all the time at work.
Sometimes it's as if the couple
are talking on bad telephone lines.
Sometimes it's like listening to
two pre-programmed tape recorders
and sometimes it's
the utter silence of outer space.
- l don't know which is the worst.
- l don't know...
Supposing the kids went to day care
while we worked shifts at a factory?
- lt wouldn't matter.
- l think it would.
lf you speak the same language,
it doesn't matter where you are.
That's a romantic view.
Do you think our relationship would
suffer if we lived that kind of life?
- Yes, l do. Seriously.
- lt would diminish our relationship?
Regardless of our language.
lsn't the danger of estrangement
just as great in the life we lead?
Definitely not.
Hard, tedious labour exposes
people to much greater strain.
You're sillier than l thought
and you're taking the romantic view.
- We'll see.
- What? What will we see?
- l don't know, do you?
- Are you teasing me?
- Aren't you hungry?
- Yes, terribly.
How about
some beer and sandwiches?
Sounds marvellous.
THE ART OF SWEEPING
MATTERS UNDER THE RUG
- Good morning.
- Did you sleep well?
- Like a log and you?
Well, l woke up at 5 o'clock
and couldn't get back to sleep again.
- Why not?
- l got all worked up.
- Should l feel guilty?
- No.
For once you're not to blame, dear.
l lay fuming about
that wretched Sunday dinner.
We always have Sunday dinner
with your parents or mine.
- lt's absurd.
- lt's for their sake.
- l'm going to cancel dinner.
- Cancel it?
- What will your mother say?
- Whatever she damned well likes.
l want to spend Sunday
with you and the kids.
- Well, if you can swing that...!
- l certainly can!
l'm fed up...
- ls it the curse?
- You always say that!
Even if my period's due on Monday,
that may not be why l'm edgy.
- What's wrong?
- Has it ever struck you
that our life is mapped out and
every last second is accounted for?
- But we have our vacations.
- They're even more scheduled.
- Aren't you going to wake the girls?
- They're sleeping in today.
Karin has the day off from school
and Eva has a sore throat.
She needs to come along on Sunday
to spare us from nagging!
- You were going to cancel dinner.
- l'd rather you did it.
Oh no, l'm not making
excuses to your mother!
Aren't you going to call your mother?
She's an early bird.
- Didn't we agree you would call?
- No, dear.
l'll hold your hand in moral support.
All right, l'll do it...
- My, my heart's pounding!
- The first sign of the great revolt.
No answer? What a relief!
Hello. Miss Alm? ls my mother in?
May l have a word with her?
How is your knee, by the way?
Oh, it's not any better?
lt's worse? That's too bad...
What does the doctor say?
He's not sympathetic, you say?
lt's a sign of the times.
Hello, Mother. How are you?
Now isn't that nice.
Has Dad left yet?
Right, he was going to the country.
So you let him go off
on his own like that?
Oh, Erik is with him. That's good.
l'm sorry, but there's
something l have to tell you...
Exactly, how did you guess?
What reasons do we have?
l simply want to spend Sunday
with Johan and the girls.
No, we're not going anywhere.
We just don't
want to come over for dinner.
l don't think for a moment that dad
was looking forward to Sunday.
lt should be a pleasure
and not a duty, right?
Yes, l see. l see.
You hadn't told me that bit of news.
Bored stiff, to be quite honest.
No, forget all about it, Mother.
We'll be there.
Yes, we'll manage. lt's fine.
We're looking forward to it.
Bye for now, Mother dear.
The revolution
was smothered at birth.
Aunt Elsa is coming
and she was so
looking forward to seeing us.
- She has a present for you.
- And Mrs Danielsson is cooking.
- And your dad longed to see us.
- Damnation!
l admire your courage all the same.
We'll say no another time.
Don't be upset.
- Will you be home for dinner?
- No, meet me at the theatre.
Don't you like
coming home any more?
My, aren't we in a fine mood today?
l'd love to stay in bed for a week,
so we could just hold each other.
- And we'd both have a good cry.
- That's not the life we chose.
lf only l could be sure
we chose it and not our mothers.
You're suffering from
a maternal persecution complex.
- Did you want a life like this?
- No.
What if we started
cheating on each other?
What would you do then?
Kill you, of course.
- Sometimes l wish...
- What?
Nothing...
- Wait a second, l'll come with you.
- Why not take your own car?
We can go home together
after the play.
- What about the girls?
- l'll ask Miss Andersson to cook.
She makes fabulous pancakes.
l'll go wake the girls.
- But l'm in a hurry.
- lt'll only take a minute.
While l remember it,
please pay your parking tickets.
- There's a whole pile here.
- Yes, sir.
l'll see you tonight at the theatre.
Hello? Yes, speaking.
Hello, Mother. The line is bad,
l didn't recognise your voice.
l'm fine, how are you?
You're worried. Now, why is that?
Marianne's mother called
and she's worried as well, you say.
Good Lord...
No, Marianne and l are doing fine.
We're healthy and cheerful
and ecstatically happy.
Nothing's wrong, l swear!
Don't worry, Mother dear.
Your intuition? lt's led you astray.
Marianne and l are happier than ever.
Tell Marianne's mother
that you should do something
more constructive than gossip.
l'm pressed for time, Mother dear.
Yes, l'll see you soon.
We'll pop in on Friday, just like
we said. Say hello to dad.
Hell and damnation!
Am l disturbing you?
l just had to see what you're up to.
A lot of rumours are floating around.
What is all this mysterious stuff?
- Shouldn't you be in Lund?
- That's right.
However the students are demonstrating.
The lectures were cancelled.
- What's this going to be?
- Take a look.
- What am l supposed to do?
- Hold this pen.
When l put the lights out
you'll see a bright dot on the wall.
Try and touch it with the pen.
lf you miss, draw a line to it.
The TV camera
will register your efforts.
- But it's dark.
- There's infra light.
l'll watch on the monitor outside.
l'll put the lights out now.
Off you go.
Get to it.
- Are you pulling my leg?
- No, please continue.
But... lt keeps moving.
lt's not a trick, it's quite still.
l've had enough of this.
Turn the lights on.
Well, aren't you cross?
- That was unpleasant...
- Yes, it makes people nervous.
Look how you've wandered,
getting more and more irritated.
- What does that prove?
- That remains to be seen.
- l'd like a cigarette.
- Sure. Have a seat.
l gave up smoking six days ago.
lt's awful.
- Having withdrawal symptoms?
- Stefan is away...
My friends avoid me,
but l'll try and stick it out.
Go on, have one.
That spy Bromeus left some here.
Oh, that's heaven!
- Lord, what bliss!
- Well?
Right...
l spent the day reading
your poems yesterday. Very carefully.
- They baffled me.
- Were they so strange?
That's not it.
Well, l might be wrong...
- Has Marianne read them?
- No, she's not interested in poetry.
- She ought to be interested in you.
- She is, but not in that way.
Really?
You and l are old friends.
We've never been sexually involved.
You can provide an objective opinion
before l try the publishers.
- l shouldn't bother.
- Are they that bad?
lt's not that they're bad...
..if only that was the case.
You mean they're mediocre?
They're insipid, neat, and puerile?
That l'm indulging
in spiritual masturbation?
Several of us in our set believed
you were destined for greatness.
We admired you.
You left us all behind.
We even envied you.
- Does that affect my poetry?
- No.
- You read it while craving nicotine.
- That's true...
l intend to show them around.
Naturally...
l'll wait until
some publishers tell me they're bad.
- You feel offended.
- You bet l do!
l'm sorry.
Well, l know
someone who likes them...
- Who would that be?
- Curious, are you?
My dear little Johan...
Pay no attention to what l said.
lt was just my craving talking.
Well, l must go.
l'll leave the poems at your door.
Give my love to Marianne.
l'll stick to you
through thick and thin.
Bye!
l'll see you around 12:30, then. Bye.
l'm sorry to have kept you waiting.
During this first encounter,
we customarily establish the problem.
l want a divorce.
- How long have you been married?
- More than 20 years.
- Do you have a profession?
- No, l'm a housewife.
Why do you want a divorce?
lt's a loveless marriage.
- ls that your reason?
- Yes.
- Has it always been like this?
- Yes, for the full 20 years.
But now you want to break away.
Yes.
My husband is a responsible man.
He's kind and conscientious.
He's been an excellent father.
We've never quarrelled.
We have a nice apartment
and a house in the country.
We're both fond of music.
We belong
to a chamber music society.
- lt all sounds ideal.
- Yes, doesn't it?
But there's no love between us,
there never has been.
Forgive me for asking,
but have you met someone?
No, l haven't.
What about your husband?
Not as far as l know.
Won't it be lonely for you?
l guess so...
But that's better
than living in a loveless marriage.
Have you informed
your husband of this?
Naturally.
15 years ago, l told him
l didn't want to live with him.
He asked me to wait
until the children had grown up.
Now that they've left home,
l can get my divorce.
And what does he say?
He keeps asking me
what is wrong with our marriage.
l tell him l can't go on
in a relationship that lacks love.
Then he asks what this love
is supposed to consist of.
But l can't describe
something that doesn't exist.
Have you been on good terms
with your children?
l've never loved my children.
l know that now...
l used to think l did. People do.
But l know now
that l never loved them.
l've been a good mother
to them all the same.
l've done all l could, even though
l've never felt anything for them.
l know just what you're thinking:
"She's been overindulged
and has no sense of humour."
She has all she could ever want,
but still she moans about love.
There are other qualities:
"friendship, loyalty, security..."
Something like that, yes.
Let me tell you something.
l have a mental image of myself,
which doesn't correspond
to reality.
Forgive a personal question...
lsn't it so that love...
What were you going to ask?
l'm not sure. Forgive me.
l have the capacity to love.
But it's all been... bottled up.
The life l've led
has stifled my potential.
The time has come to change that.
The first step is divorce.
My husband and l
block each other
in some deadly way.
That sounds frightening.
lt is frightening.
Something peculiar is happening.
My senses, sight, hearing, touch
are starting to fail me.
This table, for instance,
l can see it and touch it...
But the sensation
is diminished and dry.
Do you understand?
l think l do.
lt's the same with everything -
music, scents, faces and voices.
Everything seems...
puny, grey and undignified.
Now for a drink and some food.
Sitting through lbsen
on an empty stomach is deadly.
Remember when we joined
the May Day procession?
You were
the more fervent believer.
You told me l neglected our home.
That was the winter, we all
came down with the Asian flu.
- We believed in the future then.
- lt's nice to believe in something.
And we had the pleasure
of annoying our parents.
- You were a hothead.
- So was your dad.
A pretty hothead. You were
very attractive as a socialist.
Aren't l now? Very attractive?
But married people
lose interest in each other.
We haven't.
We're just too busy. When evening
comes around, we're exhausted.
That wasn't a reproach, l promise.
- We like each other.
- Not in that way.
- Oh yes, we do.
- Our life is full of evasions.
l can't help not enjoying it
as much as l used to.
There's a natural explanation.
You shouldn't reproach me.
- Don't get upset.
- We have a fine sex life.
We're not as passionate nowadays,
but it could be worse.
Sex isn't everything.
lf you're not satisfied
you'd better find a mistress
who is more exciting sexually.
- l assure you, l do my best!
- Right...
You've got that look again.
Tell me what you're brooding about.
- You'll only get angry.
- No, l'm listening.
Why make sex so complicated?
lt's pretty elementary stuff.
lt's become such a sore spot.
lt's all your mother's fault.
- You're so superficial.
- You're a sourpuss!
You put all the blame on me.
- You said you do your best.
- l do!
That's preposterous!
Are you calling me a liar?
Then what are you talking about?
Let's drop this and go to bed.
lt's just like you
to get me so worked up
and then yawn and say it's bedtime.
You suffer from ferocious ambition.
lt's something we often joke about,
but can't
our poor sex life be spared?
Why won't you leave me alone?
First you attack me for not trying
and later for making the effort.
Now look what l've done!
Yes, indeed, you have.
Couldn't you be kind instead?
There, there... Don't be upset.
l'm sorry.
lt's possible to talk too much
about these matters, you know.
l know you shouldn't keep secrets,
but in this case the rule is wrong.
There are some things
you shouldn't pry into.
We hurt each other to no end
and the barbs still remain
when we go to bed.
lt's like lying on a bed of nails.
- What are you laughing at?
- The bed of nails.
- lt's all very well to laugh.
- Let's go to bed.
You've been unbelievably tactless.
l apologise.
Don't l give you enough affection?
Affection takes time.
- Then you don't get enough.
- We don't, or give enough either.
That's why l wanted us
to go away this summer.
Affection shouldn't
be kept for vacations.
You're nice,
even if you are a moron.
Lucky l'm married to you.
You're mediocre, but you have
your moments of greatness.
At our age, thousands
of brain cells burn out every day.
- Never to be replaced...
- You must lose a million!
You're awfully sweet anyway,
even if you do scold and fuss.
l'm nearly asleep already.
- l'll just go check on the children.
- l'm nearly asleep, so don't worry.
Aren't you going to set the alarm?
You may make love to me
now if you like.
Thanks for the offer,
but l'm too tired.
Here already? l wasn't
expecting you until tomorrow.
What a lovely surprise!
Are you hungry?
We all went to bed early.
We thought we'd have an early night.
The girls and l have been dieting.
- Would you like some sandwiches?
- Sounds good to me.
Or shall l fry you some eggs
and ham, or fix some soup?
No, sandwiches
and beer will do fine.
By the way, Peter and Katarina
will call you on Monday.
What an ordeal they're having!
They don't seem able
to decide about their divorce.
l told them to get a lawyer each,
but they won't.
Listen, change into your pyjamas
and l'll bring in a tray.
Sounds nice...
l was afraid you were angry with me.
- Why should l be?
- l was beastly on the phone.
l called back,
but you'd pulled out the plug.
l was tired last night.
l'd been with
that numbskull from the ministry.
Those bureaucratic idiots
in charge of our well-being...
- l still think l behaved badly.
- Let's drop the subject.
You never want
to finish talking about anything,
but this won't take long, dear.
l just wanted to say
that you were right, but so am l.
lf you don't want to wear a tuxedo,
that's your business.
- But l've a right to my own opinion.
- l hate wearing a tux.
lt's a ridiculous outfit.
l feel like a dressed-up chimp.
Let's not start quarrelling.
Tux or no tux, l love you.
A tuxedo is hardly
essential to our marriage.
- lt seemed like that last night.
- l said l was wrong.
Watching you eat
makes me hungry...
l need a sandwich.
l'm so hungry, l feel light-headed.
l've lost nearly two kilos this week.
Does it show?
l can feel it, though.
But it seems pointless at times...
Why should we grudge ourselves
the good things in life?
Why can't we be fat and cheerful?
Remember
Aunt Miriam and Uncle David?
They were big, fat and cheerful.
They slept in that double bed
of theirs, holding hands.
Content with each other
the way they were.
Why can't we be like them,
brimming with contentment?
What's the matter?
Are you upset?
Has something happened?
What's wrong?
Tell me.
l came here to tell you something.
l've gone and fallen in love.
lt's quite absurd
and probably all wrong...
l met her at that congress in June.
She was an interpreter.
She's a student of Slavic languages.
She's nothing much to look at.
You might even think she's ugly.
l've no idea what this will lead to.
l don't know a thing. l'm bewildered.
On some level l'm happy,
but l have one hell of a guilty
conscience about you and the girls.
We've always got along so well.
Things have been
no better or no worse
than in most families.
Say something, for Christ's sake.
l don't know what to say.
lt was wrong not to tell you sooner,
but l figured l'd get over it.
l didn't want to worry you.
lt's funny...
..that l haven't noticed anything.
Everything's been like usual.
Better, in fact.
You've been so sweet.
l've been a silly blind fool.
l didn't understand...
- How mortifying.
- No, you haven't understood a thing.
You've never been
particularly observant.
- Where do we go from here?
- l don't know.
Do you want a divorce?
Are you going to marry her?
Why tell me now? What's the rush?
We're leaving for Paris tomorrow.
l want to get away from it all.
l was going this autumn anyway.
Paula has this scholarship...
..and l want to be with her.
l can't make it without her.
So we're leaving tomorrow.
Now that l'm talking to you,
l want to ditch the whole damn thing.
l feel tired and scared.
Nothing could be more ridiculous.
l know just what you're thinking.
How could you know that?
l'm trying not to feel guilty,
which has rather affected me.
Facts are facts,
there's nothing to be done.
Let's go to bed. l expect
you need to make an early start.
l have a meeting at nine.
Then we should get some sleep.
Aren't you going to undress?
You have marks on your chest.
How tactless of you.
ls my grey suit here or in town?
- lt's at the cleaners.
- What a shame.
Did you want to bring it along?
Can't you go and pick it up?
l won't have the time.
l'm busy right up to 3 o'clock.
l can pick it up for you.
l'll do your packing, too.
You're no good at such things.
- No, thank you.
- Don't be silly...
l'm a bit conventional.
l think you have all you need here.
There are clean shirts
and underwear.
Why don't you travel
in your jacket and flannels?
- They give you a youthful air.
- Whatever you say...
- How long will you be away?
- lt depends.
What do you mean?
l've taken leave of absence
for at least six months.
l'll probably stay away for
at least seven or eight months.
l want to make a clean break.
- And if l'm not here?
- l couldn't care less.
Do you know how long
l've wanted to leave?
How long
l've thought about leaving you?
- Don't tell me!
- Four years!
- l can't take this!
- Empty words...
What are you going to live on?
You'll have to pay child support.
Don't worry, l'll manage.
You must have assets
l'm not aware of.
That is correct, Marianne.
- How is that possible?
- Listen, damn it!
Even though it's none
of your damn business,
l've sold the boat
and l've raised a loan.
The bank will pay you and the girls
1,600 krona a month.
We'll make some other arrangement
when l return.
Get advice from your colleagues,
l don't care.
Name your price!
l'm not taking a thing
apart from my books.
l'll just vanish.
l'll dematerialize.
l'll pay all l can to support you.
All that interests me
is to end this.
Do you know
what l'm most fed up with?
All this carping about
what we're expected to do
and the people
we must accommodate.
What will your mother think?
Hadn't we better ask
so-and-so to dinner?
We have to go here,
we have to go there...
We must celebrate
Christmas, Easter, birthdays...
Every single damn occasion!
- My poor darling...
- l don't want your sympathy!
Stop pawing me!
This is pure affectation,
my running on like this.
l can't get at the truth about us.
There isn't any one truth.
Whichever way we turn, it hurts.
Please don't go!
- l beg you.
- lt's no use.
Postpone your trip.
l believe we can save our marriage.
We could make a fresh start.
You must give me a chance!
Perhaps Paula would understand me.
l should meet her and talk to her...
Let us face this together.
Let me have a chance!
You're facing me
with a fait accompli.
You're forcing me
into an intolerable situation.
You mean:
What are our parents going to say!
What will our friends think?
Jesus, how tongues will wag!
How will it affect the girls?
What about the dinner parties?
What will you tell Peter
and Katarina? Who cares?
lt feels good to be a cad!
That wasn't what l meant.
Forget it...
l forgot to set the alarm.
- When do you need to leave?
- Please set it for 5:30.
l need to pack
and l have a conference at nine.
l've been meaning
to get a new alarm clock.
This one's so noisy
and it's not very reliable.
There, it's set for 5:30.
l'll wake up on my own anyway,
so you needn't worry.
- Tell me about Paula.
- Please... What's the point?
- Why torment yourself?
- l want to know what she's like.
lt's much worse
picturing some faceless threat.
- Do you have a picture of her?
- Can't we be spared this ordeal?
Please help me with this.
Well, you asked for it...
Where's my wallet?
l guess it's in my jacket...
Here are two photos.
That was taken
two years ago, on holiday.
That is her passport photo.
lt's a good likeness.
She has a nice figure.
- And lovely breasts, right?
- Yes, she does...
- Does she dye her hair?
- lt's possible.
- Her smile is nice. How old is she?
- 23.
She hasn't been lucky in love.
She's been engaged twice
and has had lots of affairs.
- Does that bother you?
- Yes, it does...
Her frankness is quite unpleasant.
She insists on giving me
the details of her erotic past.
l suffer from retrospective jealousy.
She has no illusions
and she has no great hopes
for the two of us.
She knows l'll go back to you.
lt all sounds like
a hackneyed old melodrama.
Are you compatible in bed?
Yes, we are, actually.
At first it was all wrong.
l wasn't used to it -
being with other women, l mean.
We've spoiled each other, you and l,
living in a bubble of our own.
Everything's gone like clockwork.
- The lack of oxygen smothered us.
- And Paula will revive you?
l have little self-awareness.
l know little of reality, regardless
of all the books l've read,
but this may be an opportunity
for you and l to really live.
Has Paula filled your head
with rubbish like that?
- Just how naive can you get?
- We can do without your taunts.
- Forgive me.
- l'm trying...
l'm trying to be honest
and it's not easy!
We've never talked like this before.
ls it any wonder we're naive?
What else can we expect?
You're in a tight spot.
Come and lie down beside me.
Come...
l want you to make love to me.
Please?
For old time's sake.
Lie here in my arms
and we'll both go to sleep together.
l don't think l can sleep.
l'd better leave at once.
Close your eyes.
We both need the rest.
Tomorrow will be a busy day.
l'm so damned ashamed.
We'll talk about that later.
Right now, it's just the two of us.
We still have a few hours left.
Just you and l...
- Are you going to pack first or eat?
- You decide.
- Tea or coffee?
- Tea, please.
- What about your mail?
- l'll send you my address.
You can send the letters on,
pay the bills in the usual way.
The plumber was scheduled
to come to fix the bathroom.
Shall l call him?
l figured it might
have slipped your mind.
l've phoned him dozens of times,
l haven't forgotten it.
What about your car?
l've asked Paula's sister
to take care of it.
She needs a car.
l see.
Would you please
cancel my dentist's appointment?
lt's your father's birthday on
Friday, we're supposed to dine there.
Are you planning to phone him?
That's tricky...
Maybe l can write him a letter.
As long as you don't forget.
Dealing with our parents
will be tough.
- What should l tell the girls?
- Say whatever you like.
- That you walked out on us?
- You couldn't have put it better.
l don't expect you to understand me.
l have to leave now,
to avoid traffic.
Goodbye, Marianne. Take care.
- l may be home in a week's time.
- l wish...
We'd make a fresh start.
We'd throw out stale old routines.
We'd talk about the past.
We'd try and find out
where we went wrong.
You'd never hear me blame you.
Johan, it's all so unreal...
l don't know what to do.
You're shutting me out.
Any solution
would be better than this.
Couldn't you promise to come back?
Then l'd have something, at least.
You can't leave me without hope.
Even if you don't intend to return,
tell me you will.
l have to go now.
Fredrik? lt's Marianne.
Sorry to wake you.
ls Birgit there? No, let her sleep.
So, how are you doing?
Oh, you're an early riser, are you?
l won't keep you long.
lt's cloudy... That sounds lovely.
There's something
l need to talk to you about.
l really need to talk...
You and Birgit are friends of ours.
l have to...
lt's all so unreal, Fredrik.
You see...
l'm on the verge of tears
and crying only makes things worse.