- Come on.
- I'm sorry.
Yearbooks are forever. Look serious.
- Okay, all right.
- Hold it.
Janey, keep your arms down.
Come on. Pump them!
All right, mean.
Tell me I'll coach girls' track
for the rest of my life.
Come on, this gag photo
for the yearbook was your idea.
What the hell is going on?
Who let you use my uniform?
- Hi, Dan.
- Moll.
Sorry, babe. Didn't know it was you.
No problem.
Anytime you wanna get into my pants,
just ask.
I never had sisters before. So long.
What a guy.
Come on, girls. Keep your stride
nice and easy. Let's go.
Get your arms down!
Moll, our fearless leader has returned.
- Who?
- Walker.
Go ask him now before somebody
else does. Go get him, tiger!
Dr. Walker!
Miss McGrath!
For a second
I thought you were Bubba Smith.
They look fine. You look fine, girls.
Get those arms up.
How was the principals' conference?
- Very stimulating.
- Good.
Dr. Walker, an interesting thing happened
when you were away...
Nick Martinelli went in for a double hernia.
I don't think he's gonna be able
to coach JV football this year...
and I'd like the job.
I tell you what, run it by Dan Darwell.
If he doesn't have any objections,
it's fine with me.
Young lady, keep those knees pumping!
Knees and arms, girls.
- I got to ask Dan.
- The worst he could do is say no.
He could say, "No, babes."
You wanna know the best way to do this?
Don't talk to him about it now.
- Not now? I like that.
- Tell him you want to meet him later.
- Later. Good.
- Sort of a date.
I'm not going on a date with him.
I already did.
Tell him you want to meet him.
Maybe play a game of racquetball.
I mean, the guy is disgusting.
- I'm not going on a date.
- How badly do you wanna coach football?
- I can't. I have to pick the kids up.
- I'll pick the kids up.
I'm warmed up.
Okay. Ready?
- I need to talk to you, Dan.
- Sure, babes. How about over dinner?
- How about over racquetball?
- Okay. A quick set, then dinner.
We'll play to five. Ladies first. You serve.
I want to coach the JV, Dan.
Molly, a girl can't coach boys' football.
You know that.
- No, I don't.
- My serve.
- Dan, I can handle this. Believe me.
- Heads up!
One-zip. Supposed to hit the ball,
not the wall, babes.
I was raised on football. I know more
about it than anybody else you could get.
- I mean, coaching to me is like...
- Heads up!
You know I'm qualified, Dan. I've known
you and Dr. Walker a long time now.
You wouldn't discriminate against me
because I'm a woman.
You know me, babes, I'm a modern guy...
but Walker, I don't know.
Let's see what he says.
- We'll meet with him on Monday.
- Thanks, Dan.
- What's the score?
- Two-one, mine.
It's three-one, yours.
Dan, I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
Are you okay?
I'm fine. Good game. We'll play again
when I don't have a headache.
- See you later.
- You're not sore at me, are you?
No, everything's fine.
- We're still going to meet with Walker?
- Yeah, first thing Monday morning.
- Okay. You're not upset?
- I'm fine.
- Get out of here, you knucklehead.
- Okay.
Yeah. Go team. Throw the ball!
- Mom, I lost my sneaker.
- Put on your sandals.
- Verna, I found Dad's playbooks.
- Then I'm not going.
- Alice!
- What?
- Help your sister find her shoe.
- Why do I have to?
Because she's 6. You're 13.
As you get older, life gets tougher.
Look how Dad blocked the sweep series.
He was way ahead of his time.
I love this play.
Hey, Mom, I found Marian's shoe.
President Muffley had it.
Little son of a bitch also
ate my Duran Duran album.
What'd you say?
Verna said it's okay to call a dog
a son of a bitch, because that's what he is.
I can't believe I said that,
but it is linguistically correct.
I got it.
- Hey, Frank.
- Hey, Verna.
How you doing?
- My lips are above the water line.
- That's very funny.
- Hey, Moll. What's happening?
- Hi.
What's with all that? Finally getting
around to throwing that stuff out?
Yeah, I'm just throwing that out.
Daddy!
Hi, sweetie. Muffinhead.
- Kids!
- We're going shopping!
Guys, call me every night, okay?
- It's just the weekend.
- Well, humor me.
'Bye, baby.
'Bye, Mom. See you Sunday. I love you.
- 'Bye, honey. I love you. 'Bye.
- 'Bye, Mom.
By the way, Stephanie's parents
are having a cocktail party Sunday night...
so I'll drop the kids off earlier than usual,
like 2:30 p.m. Okay? Thanks.
Why didn't you tell him
about the coaching?
'Cause I know him. He'd put it down,
try to talk me out of it.
So I decided to get tough,
stand up to him, and deny it.
Anyway, I'll tell him Monday
after I get the job.
I'm really very sorry.
If the position has been filled,
there's nothing I can do about it.
Coach Darwell is within his rights
to select Mr. Remo as his JV Coach.
- But he's the Home Ec teacher.
- And a darn good one, too!
Mr. Remo, do you know
what a nickel defense is...
or an open set formation,
or when to use a safety blitz?
I can't say I do.
How about penetration? Do you know
how to get good penetration?
Miss McGrath, please.
We're drifting off the subject here.
Sorry I'm late. What did I miss?
Dr. Walker was explaining to me
why you picked someone...
no disrespect, Mr. Remo, who
doesn't know diddlysquat about football.
Hey, you really wanna coach football?
Fine, you got it.
What are you talking about?
You said I could coach JV.
Because, she's going to coach varsity.
The big "V."
- What?
- Jesus, Dan, don't...
At Central High.
Oh, my God.
I spoke to their principal this morning.
If she is willing to take no bonus
over her pay, they'd love to have her.
Here's his number. Ben Edwards.
Dan, I don't think Central
is the right place for a woman.
She can handle it. Can't you, Moll?
Besides, maybe a woman's touch
is just what they need.
After she teaches them to sit,
she can take the thorns out of their paws.
- You think that's real funny, don't you?
- Yes.
Okay, laughing boy.
I'm going to take that job.
You think a woman
can't be tough enough?
I'll show you tough.
Watch me.
I forgot my purse.
Help!
Mr. Edwards?
Hey, come on, stop all that noise.
You damned dogs.
- Hey, how are you?
- Fine.
I bet you're Molly McGrath.
- Ben Edwards.
- Molly McGrath.
Right. Come on in.
I want to apologize for the puppies.
I went out...
to chain them up before you came,
but they got away from me.
- Are those puppies always here?
- No, just when the armed guards are off.
I have some stats here
that you might be interested in.
Great!
It's play diagrams from
our touchdown plays from last year...
players' reports, things you might need.
Great! I just wanna thank you.
I appreciate this so much,
you taking this chance on me.
Right. How about some peanut brittle?
We have a little left
from last year's fund-raising drive.
No, thanks. I'm too fired up to eat.
You got some real talent here.
Raw, perhaps. I think with the help
of my assistant coaches...
- No assistant coaches?
- Right.
School starts in a week,
so we better start practice right away...
No practice?
I wouldn't even know
how to round the guys up.
But if it's any consolation to you...
a number of our players are returning
from last year, so...
maybe it wouldn't take much coaching.
Your team only won one game last year,
'cause the other team's bus broke down.
Yeah, that victory party
was something to see.
Mr. Edwards...
let's second-think this for a bit.
Are you sure
I'm the right person for this job?
Hey, Dan Darwell told me
that you were eminently qualified.
He also tells me that
it's your lifetime dream to coach football.
- Is that right?
- That's right.
If word got around
that you chickened out on this job...
you think anybody
would ever offer you another chance?
Yes?
- No.
- Right.
- Coach, aren't you late for practice?
- I was just going.
- Are you nervous?
- No.
- Well, a little.
- I don't blame you.
Hey, what are you guys doing?
Wait a minute. You guys want to fight?
Go ahead. Punch each other's head off.
Doesn't make any difference.
Only tell your mother
you don't have a principal anymore.
You got a parole officer. Understood?
Suited up and ready to play, coach.
Be on the five in field minutes.
Oh, God!
All right, listen up!
If you're not here to play football,
clean out your lockers and leave now.
I like her tits.
You. You're in training as of right now.
Put that out.
All right. I don't intend to coach
a bunch of losers.
Now, if you're not willing to work hard...
She has a really cute ass,
you know what I'm saying?
Guys, look...
I was raised on this sport. It's part of me.
I know that I can help you
learn the game and win.
I think that with...
If we just learn to trust each other,
there's nothing we can't do.
I mean, I'll help you. I'll be there.
I just need for you to give me a chance.
Now, what do you say?
Line up for calisthenics!
Do you guys want to play football or not?
Man, come on. Listen to her.
Come on!
We start out by stretching our hams.
Right foot over left, and hang.
What is this?
You said we were gonna play football.
- What's up with that?
- You can't play if you get hurt.
- lf you're not properly conditioned...
- Zip that shit.
Tell us when you want us
to play football, sweetheart.
- What's happening, fellas?
- What you doing here, Bird? Are you lost?
So, you're the coach.
I am. Who are you?
Ain't no thing, baby. I'm just a football fan.
Don't be too rough on these girls,
'cause they really ain't got the stomachs...
for all that physical activity.
Hey, Bird. You got a Walkman?
I'm out of Walkmans, but I got Casios.
Who wants a watch? Come see the Bird.
- Are they coming back?
- lf there's a scrimmage here tomorrow.
There will be a scrimmage here
tomorrow at 4:00.
Do you want to show them up
at scrimmage tomorrow?
- He's our quarterback.
- They're the best guys we got.
All the more reason to run rings around
them. Do you want to play football?
I can't hear you!
Do you wanna play football?
Don't wear yourselves out.
I can't go back there tomorrow,
it's a disaster.
I'll call Edwards tonight
and tell him I can't do this.
- Darwell has a pool.
- Darwell bought a pool?
No, he's got everybody betting
on how long you'll last.
- Oh, God!
- Is Wednesday a safe bet?
I want to forget this day.
All right, sweetie. Thanks for the lift.
- What's this?
- Just a little something.
Thanks.
Mr. Edwards? Molly McGrath.
Not so good.
Actually, I wanted to tell you that...
I don't think that I'm...
That's not fair.
That it's not fair that I should be so lucky.
I just wanted to say
thanks again for picking me.
Okay. See you tomorrow.
God, I even quit when I'm trying to quit.
15, 16...
17, 18...
19, 20. All right.
- What are you guys doing here?
- You said there's a scrimmage today.
So take the field.
Yeah. Let's go, man.
All right, my guys, let's huddle up.
I can break his damn face.
Don't do that, man.
Let him play.
Stay in strong, right.
Remember our first wrinkle, Peanut?
- I think so.
- What are they doing?
Kissing her ass, most likely.
All right. Let's fire them up.
Watch this.
Break!
Look at Peanut. That twerp!
Yeah! Sure!
That shit's pretty good.
- Let's show them what football's all about.
- Kill them.
Marvel, go deep. Phillips, run a post.
Let's take care of them. On you. Ready?
All right, let's go.
Blue. 22. Crush you.
Come on. Stop those wimps!
I'm getting tired of this shit, man.
I'm going in.
- What are we going to run now?
- Double reverse. I'll take it.
Why don't you just play quarterback?
I ain't seen you do no end-zone dancing.
Hey, come on. Somebody think
of a good play. Let's go.
Run anything, but just stay out of my way.
All right. Left formation,
double reverse on bean.
Try not to get me sacked this time,
bumblehead.
Ready. Let's break!
That's on the chicken shit side.
Sorry about that, Coach.
I was running my blocking assignment.
- I guess practice is over, Miss Coach?
- Let's get out of here.
Hi, guys. Hi, Jeannie.
- Nice day at school, Mom?
- Terrible.
- But I got it all figured out.
- Yeah?
I'm gonna get my old job back at Prescott.
I'll be at the right place at the right time.
Remo won't last long with the JV, so,
when he bombs out, Molly takes the field.
Don't look at me like that.
Going back to coaching girls' track
is not exactly the same as quitting.
- Darwell hired somebody else for it today.
- I'll kill him.
The problem with killing him though,
is that it goes on your record.
It follows you everywhere.
Well, I can stick it out.
I'll bet she's getting in her van now,
tears streaming down her face.
She's too stupid to know when to quit.
But I hope she stays.
I only got a few more days
before I get my hands on her.
You're full of shit, Trumaine.
What's the problem, man? She knows I got
10 pounds of dangling fury waiting for her.
I know she wants it.
I can tell by the way she looks at me.
Put your pants on and listen up!
Baby, we were just talking about you.
Don't call me baby.
What did he say?
He says, "Yes, ma'am."
My name is Coach McGrath.
If that's too much for you to remember,
then just call me "Coach."
- Hey, Coach?
- Yes.
Why don't you quit,
so we can get us a real coach?
Amen.
You don't get it.
I'm the only one who'll take this job.
You ain't good enough.
You want to get rid of me?
- You really want to get rid of me?
- Yeah.
Absolutely.
Step outside.
If I drop before any one of you...
- you can tell me to go to hell.
- We sure as hell will!
We'll help you pack your bags.
But...
if you quit before I do...
then from here on out, I call the shots.
- Got you!
- We're coming up on you.
- We're gaining!
- All right!
I'll bet you $50 the coach outruns them.
She's crazy if she thinks
she can beat Trumaine or Cerulo.
They're fast.
I love it!
Call me and let me know who won.
What, you all leaving?
I'll see you all at the bank.
Here we go.
It's raining. Let's call it a draw, okay?
You quit, you lose.
I forgot to tell you.
- I ran the Boston Marathon.
- Oh, shit.
Twice.
You owe me a new stopwatch!
You pussies!
Fuck you!
Fuck you, what?
Fuck you...
Coach McGrath.
Better!
Frank!
I'm sorry to barge in like this,
but I heard about the little job change.
Would you mind getting out of here?
What is that on your eye?
Cheap mascara. Now get out of here.
Seriously, Molly, we have to talk.
- Give me a towel.
- I'm not offended by nudity.
Give me a towel. A big towel, Frank.
So how are you doing in school?
- Fine.
- Good.
Great.
Listen, I think it's terrific
you care about this coaching job...
and it's great that the kids will benefit
from your experience and expertise.
You called, I wasn't home,
the school's in the ghetto...
and you started thinking about
terrible things that could happen...
thereby causing you inconvenience.
So, you're here to tell me
that you don't like me coaching at Central.
- I hate you coaching at Central.
- Tough.
Excuse me? What did you just say?
I said, "Tough."
So, school is fine, right?
That's terrific. That's just great.
You don't care about my opinion?
For the 10 years we were married,
your opinion was my opinion!
For the four years we were divorced,
your opinion was still my opinion.
- That's not true.
- Now I want my opinion to be my opinion!
You don't even know what you're saying.
I always gave you your own way.
- What?
- That's right. You wanted a van, right?
- No, I didn't want a van!
- Wait a second...
You wanted the van.
You wanted a van, we got a van!
I didn't want a van, you wanted it.
- So, are you getting ready for Halloween?
- It's only September.
Oh, of course.
...go out and trade in that
great little Valiant for that stupid van!
And now I have a van
and I wish I had a Valiant!
That isn't polite.
I was just on my way to the kitchen
to get some more water.
The kitchen is that way.
Stephanie?
Stephanie, hello.
Hello. Where's Frank?
- He left.
- Oh, he left.
- What are you doing, Stephanie?
- I was just waiting for you, Frank.
Come on, we're late. Let's go.
See you, Molly.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
I'm sorry, are you all right?
This is last year's schedule.
It's gone. Forget it.
You guys are better now.
Much better.
Now, tomorrow's our first game.
Forget the past.
Concentrate on tomorrow...
and don't be nervous tonight.
- You okay, Mommy?
- I'm fine, sweetie. Thank you.
You can sleep in my bed with me
if you're scared, Mommy.
I'm all right, sweetie.
Good night.
Let's rock, let's rock
come on and boogie
Boogie down, boogie down
Wildcats are the best around
we'll run those Cougars out of town
Boogie down
Let's rock!
Okay, listen up.
Listen up. How can we concentrate
if they keep ringing that fucking bell!
If they're the Cougars,
how come they got a goat?
What are we bitching about?
We got a dog dressed like a cat.
Can we talk about the game for a minute?
Okay. Jet, red right. 29-Z reverse.
Speak English. Nobody understands
that code shit except you.
Marvel, you go ahead, come back.
I'll give it to you.
You give it to Trumaine.
Trumaine, you run upfield, okay?
- On "whore." Ready?
- Break!
Black. 24. Black. 24.
Your mother's a whore!
When we go with the veer...
you've got to hand off to the fullback...
unless the tackle commits to the inside.
Their tackles have been forcing the play.
So you've got to read
the outside linebacker.
If he commits to you,
then pitch to Marvel around the end.
We're four points behind.
We can push right past them, right?
You don't sound very convinced.
Don't you guys have any pride?
- Yeah!
- Don't you have any guts at all?
- All right, then. Get out and get tough!
- Yeah!
- Get mean!
Those Cougars will be furballs
when we're finished.
Let's go eat some pussy!
Red. 26. Red. 26.
The Cougars are dicks!
All right, come on, guys. Good game.
Central, y'all still some rookies.
Good game, Cerulo.
Way to go, Kru.
Hey, you guys played a great game!
All right, we'll do better next week.
Give it up, Central!
- Nice game.
- Yeah, right.
Congratulations. Good luck.
Good game, Coach.
- You'd better watch some more pros play!
- Hey, Mom!
So we lost yesterday.
The important thing is,
you played a good game.
- Don't blow smoke up our ass.
- I wouldn't do that.
Especially not up yours, Cerulo.
You guys have to remember, we've got
nine more games before the season's over.
So we've got to get more disciplined,
work harder and get more organized.
Cerulo, cut it out.
- What's this?
- These are your playbooks.
I'll put a play up there,
you'll write it in your books.
I want you to memorize it, take it,
because you'll be tested on it.
- Cerulo, okay?
- It ain't me, Coach. I'm innocent.
You stole the Cougars' goat?
- Edwards.
- Edwards? His name's Edwards?
Principal Edwards.
- Welcome to our locker room.
- Right.
I thought you all played
a fairly decent game yesterday.
Make that about 200 percent
more decent...
and we can start having
some victory parties around here.
We're working on it, aren't we boys?
Thanks for coming down.
I got a call from the principal
over at Jackson High.
It seems they're missing their goat.
I don't suppose anybody around here
would know about that, would they?
What did you say, Coach?
My guys wouldn't know
anything about that, would we?
Good...
because if it's not returned today...
any person remotely connected
with the disappearance of that goat...
will be summarily expelled.
That gets me steamed.
Right.
I'm sorry I interrupted your meeting.
A joke's a joke.
You guys are old enough
to be responsible for your own actions.
I want a volunteer right now
on who will take that goat back, okay?
Who's it going to be?
Good goat.
Good little goat.
Stay here, baby.
- Hi, Mom.
- Hi, baby. What's this?
I got hungry, so I fixed myself dinner.
Chocolate chip is not what I call dinner.
Where's Alice?
I'll fix you dinner in a minute.
- Hi, Molly.
- Jeannie! New hairdo?
- Yeah, do you hate it?
- No, but I think it really looks terrible.
Great, no old person has liked it yet.
We're going to the library.
- I'll take you.
- You don't have to.
We got sick of waiting around,
so I called my mom. She'll pick us up.
I'm not that late. I can still drive you.
Jeannie's mom will take us.
I'll take you.
First I have to fix you something to eat.
I can't believe she didn't say
anything about it.
She must really hate it.
She just doesn't care.
I'm going to fix you a nice dinner
before you leave.
I don't want a nice dinner.
That's my mom.
Mom, I don't want to eat.
I just want to go to the library, okay?
I'll take you after you eat.
- We're going.
- No, you're not.
Jeannie, you may go.
Alice, you'll stay here and eat your dinner.
See you tomorrow.
You don't even care if I do bad at school.
It's all your fault you came home late
and we didn't have any supper.
All you care about are those stupid boys.
You don't even care about my hair.
You didn't even notice it.
I hate you.
Alice, open the door.
Okay, I hate your hair.
I really, really hate your hair.
I didn't want to be one of those mothers
who doesn't understand.
But I didn't.
So I guess I am.
What?
I wanted to be able
to talk calmly about your hair.
Marian, come here, honey.
You are the most important people
in my life.
Much more important
than any football team.
If that's true, why do you play with them
instead of making us dinner?
I was late because
I had to do the shopping.
I am now a football coach...
and I want to be the best one
I can possibly be...
just like I want you to be the best
at whatever you decide to do.
I want to be a helicopter pilot.
Don't be stupid, Marian,
you can't be a helicopter pilot.
Of course she can. She can be anything
she wants to be, if she works at it.
So can you.
So can I.
Daddy says you're going to quit.
He did, huh?
Well, he's wrong.
I'm not going to quit.
I'm going to see this through...
but I need you to help me.
- Can you do that?
- Okay.
Alice?
Okay, sweetie.
- Principal Edwards.
- Coach McGrath.
The goat showed up at Jackson High.
Must have been catting around, I guess.
I thought you'd be pleased to hear it.
You don't look pleased.
Krushinski told me about last year's
quarterback, Lavender Williams.
- Levander.
- Yes, the accent's on the second syllable.
- You know him?
- We have this hate/hate relationship.
You didn't show me his stats.
I'd like to see them.
I figured no sense
in having your mouth water...
for food you'll never get your fork into.
- Are you saying I can't get him to play?
- I think that's what he's saying, Coach.
- Right.
- I'd like to see his stats anyway.
Just for the heck of it.
Okay, I'll dig them out for you.
Let's see here. Say, Krushinski...
are you stepping down as quarterback?
It's like I can run good and throw good.
I just can't...
run and throw good.
- I'm thinking I want the team to win.
- Right.
- Wow.
- I told you he was good.
He's also a criminal and chronically truant.
I didn't know he was sick.
What class would he be in about now?
About now, he'd be in 11-A English.
However, I seriously doubt
if he's in 11-A English.
- Could I have his address?
- You don't want to go there.
- Is Levander Williams here?
- No.
- Where is he?
- At Maurice's.
Where's Maurice's?
Yeah, he's here a lot.
He's one of my suppliers.
But he ain't here now.
Say, lady, is that your van outside?
You ought to consider stepping up
to some genuine wire-wheeled hubcaps.
No, thanks. I don't care for any...
I was wondering if you know
where Levander Williams is?
These beauties would cost you $400
anywhere else in town.
But since you're a friend of Levander's...
they're yours, installed, $80.
If you could just tell me
where I might find Levander...
$65.
That's below wholesale, lady.
- Whose ball?
- It's mine.
I didn't mean to interrupt.
Please, just continue doing
what you were doing.
I was told that I would find
a Levander Williams here.
I'm Levander Williams.
No, I'm Levander Williams.
What?
All right. All kidding aside...
I really need to find Levander.
- He's about 18...
- I can show you about 18.
- Ain't no thing, let's go.
- Bird.
Man, what are you doing in here, lady?
You're Levander, aren't you?
- I got an appointment to get to.
- Wait, Bird. I have to talk to you.
I've been chasing after you for two hours.
- At least give me five minutes.
- My playing days are over, lady.
What's up, man?
- Three minutes.
- No.
- I really need to talk to you.
- Bird, step into my office.
Let me handle this.
Look here, our car won't start.
We were wondering
if you could give us a ride...
- to my mother's house.
- You and Levander can chat on the way.
All right.
Nice hubcaps.
- How much did you pay for them?
- $65.
You were robbed.
I ain't got time for football.
I'm working on another career.
Take the next right.
If you're as good as your stats say...
then we could attract college scouts.
That could mean a scholarship.
- Yeah, over here.
- Is this where his mother lives?
Yeah, she got sick of the suburbs.
We play Dearborn next week.
All I need to beat them is a passer.
Give me the keys. Come on!
Shit!
- He said that key would work.
- Did you see me try it? Did the door open?
You can't trust Jimmy. He's a criminal.
I got sick of losing every week.
Last year you didn't have
a decent coach. Now you've got me...
and I'm good!
Excuse me, what are you doing?
The key my mother gave me doesn't work.
So we've got to go through a window.
Yeah, wait a minute.
He can't walk around on my van.
He's going to cave it in.
Can you wait till
your mother comes home?
His mother's in the hospital and needs her
nightgown or she won't let them operate.
It's her lucky nightgown.
I can't let him walk on my van.
He's too heavy.
I'm not playing football,
so we have something in common.
Look, if you get down...
- I'll get up, okay?
- That's fresh!
- That's cool, man.
- Not cool.
Get her down. We'll do this later.
We do this now, Bird.
It'll take just a minute.
I said we'll come back later. Without her.
Oh, my God!
Come on, man, let's go!
You better come down, lady.
Hold on, man.
- Drop.
- I can't!
Lady, come on. I'll catch you. Now, drop!
Oh, my God! What's happening?
- Bird, I'm in a trash can!
- Be quiet.
You want me to be quiet?
I'll tell you what.
- You get my van back.
- No problem. Now, shut up.
- Get back what I paid for those hubcaps.
- I'll talk to Maurice. Be quiet.
And you play for Central
or I start screaming.
Now, lady, look, that place belonged
to the biggest fence in town.
The stuff was all stolen. I just wanted
to return it to the rightful owners.
- We're in here!
- Are you crazy?
Shut up.
If you play football...
my lips are sealed.
You know what this is, don't you?
This is extortion.
That's an ugly charge, Bird.
True, but ugly.
Right!
Left!