(PR Video Production, Make me Viral)
(Are they really here together? They're like a father and a son.)
(Heung Kook came to Make me Viral.)
(Feeling confident)
(The office becomes full of laughter with him.)
(And Taeyang with an amazing voice...)
(shows his burning ambition for a variety show.)
(Heung Kook's shocking suggestion, "Taeyang Swallowtail")
(It's something you've never seen before.)
(Heung Kook and Taeyang's special collaboration)
(Join us now.)
(Make me Viral, Episode 15)
(It's a cool Monday morning.)
(The phone rings in the semi-basement office.)
Hello? Make me Viral, PR Headquarters.
You want to talk to Sol Bi?
(Sol Bi?)
Unfortunately, she's not with us anymore.
I'll work harder.
- Okay. - What does he want with her?
Hello?
Cao Lu? Cao Lu...
She's not here. Sorry.
Would I get fired soon too?
I wouldn't say you'd get fired.
I'd rather say...
you'd be gone.
- With the wind? - I guess so.
Eun Hyuk, is your seat comfortable?
It feels like sitting on pins and needles.
I'm just enduring it.
(Hang in there. We will get you with a soft cushion soon.)
- What? - Wait.
- Someone's here. - I'll get the door.
(Hesitant)
Who is it?
Who's coming today?
(Screaming)
(Who are today's clients that electrify the employees?)
(The global star, Taeyang of BigBang)
(And...)
(Variety Cheat Code, Kim Heung Kook)
(She's excited to see them.)
(Welcome.)
It's "Eyes, Nose, Lips"!
(They greet the clients feeling thrilled.)
(He's a spirited man born in 1959.)
(He has generated many catchphrases.)
(He's a Variety Cheat Code, Kim Heung Kook.)
(He's the voice of BigBang.)
(His talent for music has been proven with his solo singles.)
(He is a spirited man Young Bae and the best artist Taeyang.)
It's so exciting to see them in Make me Viral.
- It's quite rare... - To see them together.
It's something you can only see in Make me Viral.
I guess...
Taeyang didn't even know who'd be here with him.
No one told him about it.
Again, they are...
Kim Heung Kook and Taeyang. Nice to meet you.
(Welcome.)
I'm so excited that they're here.
It's rare to see them together.
In fact, I decided to come here...
because of Heung Kook.
Every time I see Heung Kook on TV,
- I find him hilarious. - Of course.
He is the Variety Cheat Code.
Since he'll be on the show too,
I thought that I'd learn some pointers from him.
I see.
The lyrics to "Tiger Swallowtail" include "hide above clouds".
- Yes. - That's right.
I've been above the clouds for all this time,
but now I've met the sun.
(He met the sun.)
I bet you came prepared to say that today.
- Just get at it. - Get at it.
(The lesson has already started.)
"Just get at it."
I think you are perfect for our show...
because you've been going viral these days.
Hasn't he changed a bit?
You have more hair on your head.
That's right.
I got myself a fur hat.
- Good choice. - You can't tell.
- Isn't it perfect? - You really can't tell.
Why do you have those sunglasses on though?
- They look like goggles. - They don't mean anything.
- I see. - I thought I'd protect...
my eyes from Taeyang.
(Taeyang's learning a lot.)
You know how UV rays can sting.
(It's another lesson learned.)
You really came prepared today.
Everything you say is worth writing down.
(They're all addicted to Heung Kook's puns.)
Taeyang released a new single,
and G-Dragon's been avidly promoting it.
- That's right. - Via social media, of course.
So since it's a new single, we should definitely hear it.
What's it called?
It's called "Darling".
- "Darling"? - Yes, "Darling".
This'll be the first time singing it live.
- The first time. - We're the first ones to hear it.
- That's right. - So here's "Darling".
(He's singing "Darling" live for the first time.)
It's his first time.
(He's nervous.)
This is unbelievable.
I'm so glad I joined this company.
We should record this.
("Darling" by Taeyang)
(His sorrowful voice touches our hearts.)
(Amazed)
(It's like hearing the song from a CD.)
Are you sure this is live?
(We need to record this on our phones.)
(He pretends to play the piano.)
(It's as if we're at his concert.)
(They're all absorbed in his song.)
(You're the only one for me)
(Taeyang has a dominant voice.)
- Darling! - You sounded just like the CD.
Didn't you hear me ask if this was a live performance?
Was this really the first time?
- Was this really the first time? - I couldn't believe it.
He's never sang it live before.
- He wasn't even warmed up. - Darling!
(Darling!)
Sorry?
- What? - Say that again.
Darling! Isn't that how you sang?
The artists who sings like that is Jeon In Gwon.
Kyung Hwan, just read a book.
No wonder people say he's the best.
Thank you for that.
He practically only sang to a piano accompaniment.
Now it's Heung Kook's turn.
I haven't released a new song though.
I'm finding confidence, I'm finding confidence.
- Right. - Can you sing...
"Tiger Swallowtail" to a piano accompaniment?
Play it for me then.
I'm afraid we don't have one ready.
- Gosh. - Call Kim Gun Mo instead then.
(If that's not an option...)
(Did you say, Kim Gun Mo?)
You want Gun Mo to play the piano for you?
Yes.
- Why not? - Now that's absurd.
Why would he even come?
We sing together after a few drinks.
(Like this?)
(The collaboration of a legendary singer and...)
(the Director of the Korea Singers Association)
(We'd love to see it too.)
You just heard Taeyang...
sing his song just to a piano.
- Were you amazed? - He sounded like...
a globally acclaimed artist.
- Thank you. - It was fantastic.
Yes, I agree.
To be honest, you two...
are already known by almost everyone in Korea.
So why is there a need to film a new PR video?
A what?
(What are you talking about?)
He doesn't know what he's doing here.
PR videos are...
On this show, we come up with PR videos...
that'll help you be more popular than you are.
Can we sing "Taeyang Swallowtail" then?
- "Taeyang Swallowtail"? - Yes.
- Hold on. - "Taeyang Swallowtail"?
He just gave me a great idea.
Will Taeyang join you...
when you perform "Tiger Swallowtail"?
Taeyang swallowtail
(Heung Kook and Taeyang are already partying.)
A single butterfly
At a field of flowers
Nice!
(This is perfect for a PR video.)
Go, Taeyang swallowtail
I'd like that idea for myself.
- "Taeyang Swallowtail". - I'll be the one to work on that.
Then...
Our team will take that idea.
- But... - Why is it yours?
We called dibs on it.
Kyu Han said so first.
Since when have we allowed dibs?
Dibs!
(Here.)
I call dibs!
- Hold on. - This is unbelievable.
- The clients... - Speed is of the essence.
Whomever claims the idea faster...
- will have the right to... - I'm sorry,
- but Team Two is right. - Why?
- They responded quicker. - It was such a good idea.
They snatched up the idea immediately.
The team that makes it work better should take the idea.
- That's only fair. - Our team has Eun Hyuk.
Bring me some noodles first.
All of a sudden?
We'll make sure that Gun Mo plays the piano...
while you sing "Taeyang Swallowtail".
Eun Hyuk, can you be responsible for your words?
- No, I can't. - This can't be a joke.
Gosh, I'm sorry.
("Taeyang Swallowtail" belongs to Team Two.)
Before we make the PR videos,
- we'll first do some research. - Sure.
Let's start with Heung Kook's memes.
In order to see them, you have to say a command.
A command?
You can't command people around these days.
- What? - I'm sorry.
- Did you hear that? - We...
(They burst into laughter.)
We end up explaining this every week.
Since that's the case,
let's just bring in our next clients.
- You did great today. - Can I go already?
- Thank you for coming. - Thanks, Taeyang.
- He might go for real. - Stop him.
- He might leave. - Thank you, Taeyang.
Memes are what we call short videos.
"What's my meme?" Just say that adorably.
Fine.
(Does he understand the rules?)
Heung Kook...
is five and a half.
(He still doesn't understand.)
He didn't get it at all.
- He's clueless. - It's still good though.
(Kim Heung Kook on variety shows)
(He wanted to be on "Top 10 Artist Award".)
I'd be the sole master of the stage.
What if you're not nominated?
I'll pluck out my mustache.
(Laughing)
(He revealed that his wife is pregnant.)
It's been three months. I'll be a father next year.
Unlike other ordinary babies,
- your baby will cry in a funny way. - Then how?
(Yes, I'm wailing!)
(This is how the legendary catchphrase came to.)
So that's how the catchphrase came to.
(It wasn't just that though.)
(He had many other catchphrases too.)
Yes, I'm a baby!
A baby.
(Grunting)
(The legend of variety shows)
When was that?
- It was back in 1990. - 1990?
You look like a different man.
People ate up everything I said back then.
It's been a while though. Taeyang, have you seen that?
No, I haven't.
How old were you back then?
- I was 2. - 2?
You have become a different man.
You're able to sit still now, but you couldn't back then.
- I know. - This is how you were like.
It's like you didn't know what to do with your body.
I was there as a singer, not a comedian.
Was it because you were nervous?
To survive in the industry,
I had to do something to grab attention.
"I'd be the sole master of the stage."
You're not a comedian,
but you still have many catchphrases.
What else do you have apart from what we saw?
- "Just get at it." - Right.
- "I'm finding confidence." - That too.
- It's from "Reggae Party". - It goes like this.
- You have to roll your tongue. - She's quite good.
Like this.
This is how you do it.
That's right. My gosh.
(While the others are enjoying themselves...)
Could you perhaps say them in the form of a medley?
If you do, we'll use that to...
Is he the police or something?
(Flustered)
It's a good source for your PR video.
Look at him blush.
I didn't come here to be interrogated.
- He's flustered. - How can I be the police?
Don't corner him or he'll cry.
- Really? - Yes, he might cry.
(Sniffing)
He's really crying!
(Fascinating)
Don't make fun of me.
- Kyung Hwan. - Yes?
You know, shows must be fun.
Did you hear that?
I have a lot of catchphrases.
- Ask me to say them all together. - He told a comedian to be funny.
You sounded like you were investigating him.
- Right. Be more like Eun Hyuk. - Okay, I got it.
- Let me give this a shot. - Okay.
- I'm about to lose my part. - Great job.
- Great. - Heung Kook.
- You have a lot of catchphrases. - I do.
- We all want a catchphrase. - That's right.
- He's good. - It's hard to get one.
- It's not easy. - Can we have a relay of them?
(Perfect)
Look how friendly he was.
- He's good. - You liked his version more?
- Kyung Hwan. - Wait.
- What are you doing? He's good. - Hold on a second.
I can do it well too.
I was just getting to that, Heung Kook.
Why don't you show us all of your catchphrases at once?
- Is this how should I say it? - Look at him sweating.
I can see sweat on his nose from here.
- Okay, I got it. - He's sweating?
Why don't you do what Eun Hyuk asked you to do?
- Then your catchphrases... - At that time,
I used the word, "almost" very often.
- "Almost"? - "Almost"?
It's almost my solo performance.
Solo performance.
- It's almost a work of art. - Almost?
- Almost. - I used this word often.
With the song, "Tiger Swallowtail", I managed to perform in the US.
You went to the US?
At that time,
- only I ruled Southeast Asia. - That's true.
When he was popular, I was in elementary school.
When we had a talent show, 9 out of 10 students...
- sang "Tiger Swallowtail". - That's so true.
- Everyone did his dance. - At that time,
the word, "butterfly effect" was derived.
- Butterfly effect? That's right. - Yes.
(Eun Hyuk is getting used to this futuristic, variety show.)
Butterfly effect?
Actually, when I was young, my mom would watch the TV...
and see Heung Kook dancing to the song.
- And she'd copy his dance. - Your mom did my dance?
- Then she's an amazing person. - Your mom danced to his song?
- Your mom copied his dance? - Your mom danced to his song?
No, I copied his dance. I did his dance.
It wasn't your mom.
(He's unpredictable.)
Anyway, I went to the US to perform for the first time.
Other singers go to the US with at least 2 or 3 hit songs.
At that time, I only had one hit song.
- I couldn't sing an encore. - You had no song to sing.
So I sang "Tiger Swallowtail" twice.
- This is history. - Goodness, it is indeed.
After the show in the US, I returned to Korea. When I was on a show,
the host asked how my show was in the US.
I said it was almost like a solo performance.
That's when I used the line for the first time.
- That's how the line came about. - That's how you used the line.
- "Almost like a solo performance". - What other catchphrases are there?
If we waste this much time just to listen to his catchphrases...
When we are done listening to his catchphrases, our show will be over.
It's because he has stories behind those catchphrases.
We heard stories about the wailing and solo performance.
How did "I'm feeling confident" come about?
- I'm feeling confident? - Yes.
- He has a lot. - Of course.
- How was the line created? - I'm sorry.
I'm sorry to interrupt, but this isn't yours.
You're supposed to share them.
Why are you making such a big deal out of this?
(Why are you making such a big deal out of this?)
- Please share them. - Is your show struggling?
- Is our show struggling? - We are struggling.
Your catchphrases aren't the only things that you are famous for.
I hear that you have a license that gets you off work early.
He does have a license for that.
I got off work early a lot last year.
From what I've heard, when you starred on "Sunday Night"...
with Choi Jin Sil,
you left the shoot early because it was...
- too boring. - How do you know that?
- You guys researched thoroughly. - Yes, we did.
- This story is hard to believe. - This really happened?
It was when Jin Sil was really popular.
She and Joo Byung Jin was talking,
but they kept talking about boring stuff, so I left.
I let them talk to each other.
I went thinking who would watch a boring show like that.
- But... - Don't you usually get fired...
- or banned from starring on shows? - That's right.
They don't ban me as long as I'm an asset.
(They don't ban me as long as I'm an asset.)
(Heung Kook is at another level.)
- You're so cool. - You're confident.
What do you think is the secret to your popularity?
- It's my innocence and honesty. - Sorry?
- You're innocent? - He's honest and down-to-earth.
- I don't play mind games. - He's innocent.
I present myself as I am.
- He doesn't hide his feelings. - That's right.
- He gives his honest opinions. - Yes.
You know Taeyang just released a new song?
- How is the song? - When I heard it,
if I didn't like it, I would've said, "I enjoyed it."
- I would only say that to him. - But?
When he sang the song,
the song got me hooked. It was the best.
- Goodness. - He's so honest.
- Then... - I can feel that you're sincere.
- Right! I ought to be sincere. - We...
- I see. - Jae Hoon, be sincere on TV.
(Jae Hoon, be sincere on TV.)
- Me? - Didn't that surprise you?
- He wants you to be sincere. - Why is he calling me out?
(His charms are innocence and sincerity.)
Putting that aside, on the shows,
- you’ve made many funny mistakes. - There are tons.
- There are countless mistakes. - Mistakes made some people popular.
Cho Sae Ho is an example.
Didn't you make him into a man who never attends ceremonies?
(It was during his appearance on "3 Wheels" in 2015.)
(Sae Ho said how he always attended ceremonies.)
Why didn't you come to Ahn Jae Wook's wedding?
- Whose wedding? - Jae Wook's wedding.
I don't know him. How can I attend his wedding?
(I don't know him. How can I attend his wedding?)
(It's hilarious.)
You don't know him?
(Flustered)
(In 2016, this clip had become quite famous.)
- It was his turning point in life. - I bet.
To be honest,
that wasn't your intention. You just made a mistake.
- It was done on purpose. - Exactly.
Be honest and answer this.
That's a good question.
What actually happened was that Kim Gu Ra wanted me...
- to help him since he's struggling. - He wanted you to help Sae Ho.
- Gu Ra asked you for a favor. - I didn't know this happened.
I said, "Why are you not popular?"
- You work hard. - "Why are you not popular"?
I asked him how he wasn't popular already.
He should've met Taeyang. He would've been popular quickly.
He should've met him.
- He's taking care of Taeyang. - He's talking about everything.
So I asked him why he didn't come to Jae Wook's wedding.
He told me he didn't know Jae Took.
Let me tell you how big of an impact of Sae Ho's new character left.
- It was impactful. - On his social media account,
the comments for the posts Sae Ho uploads were...
asking why he didn't come to their birthday.
- There were tons of comments. - That's true.
- I agree. - It was funny. I wrote a comment.
- On which post? What did you write? - What did you write?
Our group had a fan meet, but he didn't come.
(He didn't come to what?)
He probably wasn't invited.
(Why didn't you come to our fan meet in Japan?)
(It's the comment Taeyang wrote.)
- He didn't go. - He should've gone to the meet.
- It would be disappointing. - "Why didn't you come"?
- Really? - I really left the comment.
Where should Sae Ho go then?
- I'm so curious. - I got a lot of offers for ads.
We only filmed one commercial together.
I think without me knowing, he filmed about 10 commercials.
(Sae Ho had the commercials to himself.)
- That must've hurt your feelings. - Gook Ju, when you see him,
tell him not to shoot commercials alone.
Heung Kook, but the thing is that he's not famous for that anymore.
I don't think you'll get offers. You should've done that earlier.
- That fad is over. - That's true.
- You'll get another one. - Now, you should make a new one.
- Make one on our show. - Please do it for us.
It was hard enough to make one character famous. How can I...
- He also makes slips of the tongue. - He makes a lot of them.
The title of Gummy's song was "We Should've Been Friends".
He said it was "We Should've Been Spiders" by Friends.
- This is a famous example. - He made the mistake on the radio.
He said, "BT Vest" instead of "BTS".
(List of his mistakes)
That was just terrible.
- The title was "Childish Wife". - What was his mistake?
He said, "Hairless Wife".
- These are the mistakes he made. - That's right.
This is my first time telling you this.
I'll say this for the sake of your show.
One time, I introduced BigBang's song on the radio show.
- Okay. - It's the first time hearing it.
- I made a mistake at first. - What did you say?
I said it was BakBing's song.
(I said it was BakBing's song.)
(Laughing)
BakBing?
- This is BakBing! - Here is BakBing!
- BakBing. - I'm sorry. I said it wrong once.
I said the wrong name for their group.
But you just read the script wrong, didn't you?
- You didn't do it on purpose. - No, it wasn't intentional.
I didn't plan on it.
Right now, they can type the screen on computer screens,
but at that time, the producer wrote the script by hand.
That's why I mispronounced Turbo's song, "Cyber Lover".
He's right.
- You mispronounced UCLA too. - Sorry?
- I mispronounced UCLA too. - UCLA?
The biggest mistake was...
when I read one of the letters wrong.
- The producer wrote it sloppily. - "Hairless Wife".
But you should've questioned if you read it correctly at least once.
Had I read the script in advance, I'd have been okay, but I didn't.
- I don't read scripts. - That's my point.
How did "BT Vest" come about?
- That was... - He only read up to BT.
It was when my daughter was in the US.
She's very interested in K-Pop.
She told me that lately she liked BTS.
I told her I'd play their song on my radio show in Korea.
- But I couldn't memorize the name. - BTS?
- You remembered BT though. - He only knew BT.
- I memorized up to BT. - It was BTS.
My daughter requested this song.
It's by BT Vest. Wait, no. That's not it.
Shall we listen to "I Need You" by BTS?
How can a vest sing a song?
I'd like to ask you this.
There was a program called "I Am a Singer".
I heard the show tried to cast you,
but why did you turn it down?
I didn't turn it down.
When they contacted me,
I told them that I was already a singer.
(I told them that I was already a singer.)
- It was a simple thought. - That was why.
I told them I was already a singer.
You didn't star on it because the title was "I Am a Singer", right?
- That's right. - You were already a singer.
I already became a singer.
- I've never thought it like that. - Me neither.
You're so cool.
Aren't I right?
- See? He acknowledged me. - Taeyang is awesome.
You are so cool.
What if the title was, "Are You a Singer"?
- "Are You a Singer"? - Yes.
- "Are You Still a Singer"? - That sounds a bit insulting.
- Since they are questioning me, - Will you star to prove yourself?
- I should show them I'm a singer. - You will star for that?
- When they look down on you... - I'm the Top 10 artist.
- "Am I a Singer"? - I would've never thought that.
Heung Kook has a lot of pride...
and self-respect as a singer.
Since we're on the subject, let me tell you this.
You know how comedians...
get together and support each other?
I really like how united they are.
But singers work individually.
We perform by ourselves, and there's no opportunities for us to meet.
That's true.
So when singers are trying to do something,
I'd like to help them unconditionally. That's my point.
- I see. - Did I make sense to you?
- Yes. - Taeyang is very loyal too.
When he heard you'd be starring, he accepted the offer to star together.
- He's so loyal. - He is indeed.
- We... - Anyway.
must be grateful to him and realize how lucky we are.
You mean the real sun, the meaning of Taeyang's name?
Imagine it rains all the time.
- If it rains every day, - He literally means the sun.
- you'll get depressed. - Right.
- Heung Kook... - I don't want a world without days.
literally means the sun, not Taeyang himself.
Right. He's talking about the sun.
I think he means that we should be grateful to the sun.
Then shall we move on to Taeyang's meme naturally?
- Since we're at it. - Since we're already at it.
- I can't wait. - Let's watch the first one...
of his best memes now.
You know what to say.
What's my meme?
(He's got the swag.)
(Taeyang sounds like he swallowed his CD.)
("Eyes, Nose, Lips" by Taeyang)
(This song describes Taeyang's style very well.)
(Copying Taeyang)
He has a great body.
It's such a nice music video.
(Singing live without instrumental accompaniment in Japan Dome Tour)
It's a video clip of his singing live.
He sounds the same.
He sounds the same as the CD.
(He sounds just like the CD.)
(He sings perfectly well even in a huge venue.)
(Immersed in Taeyang's song)
(Feeling shy)
(Amazed)
Taeyang! Taeyang!
- That was awesome. - But...
doesn't he have any funny clips?
- No. That is all we got. - Really?
- That's it? - Yes. He is just cool.
You also monitor your videos,
- don't you? - Yes.
- Then I bet there are funny clips. - Sure.
Are there any funny clips you remember?
When I decided to shoot Make me Viral, I wanted to find some too.
But because I had not been on variety shows for quite a long time,
I couldn't remember funny videos.
I couldn't remember any particular clip.
So did you want to find some funny clips or...
the ones where you make mistakes?
- Yes. - You mean you wish you had them?
- Yes, I do. - There must be some.
Are you usually quiet?
Or do you like being funny?
Usually, I like being funny and playful.
- You do? - I know he likes playing jokes.
- You are lively and humorous? - Yes.
He plays jokes on the other members a lot.
When I hang out with my friends in private,
they say I play dad jokes a lot.
- I'm the one who started dad jokes. - Yes.
That's why I like Heung Kook very much.
He is hilarious.
People don't like my dad jokes a lot though.
But do you keep playing jokes?
Yes, I do.
If you keep doing it, they'll eventually like it.
- Sure. - You've got to keep going.
Who likes your jokes the most among your members?
They think they lose when they laugh at my jokes.
- They don't laugh. - On purpose.
- They think it hurts their pride. - They try not to laugh.
- Right. - They laugh at my joke and say,
- "Gosh. I lost." - Then...
who laughs the most among the members...
- when you say that? - G-Dragon laughs the most.
Then do two of you have the same taste?
No, we don't.
But he giggles and then regrets a lot.
It's a project we need to work hard on.
It is a long-term project.
- So... - We have long intestines too.
(Laughing)
(Seung Ri skips the joke and keeps on talking.)
(Why don't we play chess for a long time after this?)
Then how does she react...
to your jokes?
In fact, her reactions are quite cold.
- Quite cold? - Yes.
(They're asking about Hyo Rin.)
But that makes me want to say even more jokes.
- You don't want to give up. - I want to get recognition.
- I see. - So I keep telling jokes,
but she doesn't acknowledge them.
- You don't need to care about that. - Okay.
- You should keep telling jokes. - I should?
Then after a while, cold people...
- will also laugh in the end. - In the end.
A moment ago, you said...
that you don't have any funny videos, right?
- Yes. - Then do you remember any mistakes?
Mistakes on stage? Oh, I remember one.
We had a concert and performed a lot at the end of the year.
Maybe because I overexerted myself,
my throat was not in good condition.
It's possible at the end of the year.
While I was encouraging the audience to cheer,
my voice got out of tune drastically.
- Drastically. - Yes.
- While you were encouraging people? - Yes.
When I gave that exclamation,
the other members laughed a lot because it sounded funny.
It was "Day by Day" and they started to laugh while dancing.
It was a lyrical and serious song.
- You were not supposed to laugh. - Right.
But they burst into laughter, so I still remember that.
(While singing the lyrical song, "Day by Day",)
(Taeyang's exclamation got out of tune.)
(Seung Ri looks at Taeyang.)
(When they look at each other, they burst into laughter.)
(Laughing)
(Their eyes meet.)
(G-Dragon comes out to the center with a big smile on his face.)
- Then... - Let's check out his funny...
videos later on the show.
For now, let's see how cool he is.
- Like what? - A medley of his solo songs.
You will be able to listen to his great songs.
Really?
Just one of his songs would make my heart flutter but is it a medley?
That sounds great.
- He picked up his mic. - It's almost like a concert today.
You need a female partner in your solo songs.
Do you remember the time?
- Yes. The award ceremony. - Right.
- Have you performed together? - Cho Sae Ho...
sang "Eyes, Nose, Lips"...
and I played a role of a female.
I said I played a role of a female when I'm already a female.
I performed it back then.
- If you need me, I'll be there. - All right.
(Taeyang's mini concert)
He just turned back and he's already cool.
(Looking so cool)
(It's time to fall for Taeyang's swagger.)
("Only Look at Me" by Taeyang)
(Immersed)
(Though I may forget you)
(You shouldn't forget me)
(Taeyang's unrivaled groove)
(Letting out his cool vibes)
(Screaming)
(Exclaiming)
("I Need a Girl" by Taeyang)
(They're all falling for Taeyang's songs.)
(Here comes the female partner.)
(He doesn't get flustered and looks natural.)
(Fatally attractive)
Gook Ju must be so happy.
(After the fatally attractive girl left,)
("Eyes, Nose, Lips" by Taeyang)
(a man misses her.)
(So sorrowful)
(She suddenly acts while he is singing.)
(She is totally into the role.)
(But his great singing skills are not affected at all.)
(Gently looking at her.)
(It was Taeyang's mini concert full of soul music.)
Great job.
I'm so honored.
- It's an honor. - It sure is.
- I wish we could see some more. - I'm really honored.
Such a cool man was singing for you...
but why did you keep pushing him away?
So that he can focus on singing, I tried not to show my face.
I was worried he might burst into laughter.
- In fact... - That was the reason.
When I appear in the middle of songs, accidents usually happen.
He didn't get flustered at all but embraced me.
So I feel so grateful.
(While he was singing,)
(Gook Ju approached him.)
(And he collaborated with her smoothly.)
Gook Ju made Taeyang's performance even better.
- Thank you. - He doesn't make mistakes at all.
- Right. - He's a professional.
Sometimes, there are a few fans who break into stages.
- Yes. - Were there some naughty fans?
I think there was no one in Korea.
But there are some overseas fans...
- Right. - that are more enthusiastic.
Some of them really...
- try to come up... - They do.
on the stage.
Once a fan came up on the stage and we danced with him...
as if it were a part of the performance.
- Looking natural? - Yes.
- Really? - It was "Fantastic Baby."
He came up and danced with us.
The security guard were about to come up to stop him...
- but we asked them not to come up. - You mean the security guards?
He just came up because he was so excited and wanted to dance.
So we danced together to "Fantastic Baby"...
and let him get down safely.
As a part of the performance.
There is a famous video..
where someone comes up and does a flying kick on the stage.
To the singer?
Yes. He was an ordinary man.
- Who was the singer? - He did that to the singer.
But there is a part even funnier. While the singer was singing,
the man jumped and literally did a flying kick...
but the singer ducked it very smoothly.
He ducked the kick.
- Really? - Yes. He was a real singer.
- He didn't seem to be startled. - I can't remember who it was.
(While Wheesung was singing on stage,)
(a man suddenly did a flying kick.)
He must be crazy.
(The police officer takes him away.)
(Wheesung keeps on singing as if nothing had happened)
Ducking the flying kick,
- he kept on singing. - Without stopping.
I think Taeyang is as good as him.
It was nice to see you get along with everyone.
I was surprised.
Taeyang says he wants to come out on entertainment shows,
but the show he watches the most...
is Choi Bool Am's "Korean Food Table".
- I love it. - It's addictive.
- I like it a lot. - I like it too.
- Do you catch it on air? - If I...
miss the air time, I watch a rerun.
I watch it while I eat.
- Do you like to eat? - Yes, I do.
- Do you search for good eats? - Yes.
There are a lot of food based shows.
Is there a reason why you like "Korean Food Table"?
On other food shows,
you can easily find the restaurant and go there to eat.
- Yes. - For "Korean Food Table",
you can't eat it unless you go to that person's house.
- That's right. - "Korean Food Table".
Taeyang, if you love food so much,
are you a good cook? Do you cook often?
- Yes, I cook... - Is it a hobby?
I'm not very good at it, but I enjoy cooking.
When I'm home alone, I make kimchi jjigae often.
- There are various kinds. - What do you like the most?
- The pork kimchi jjigae. - Of course.
You need pork in it.
- You need pork shoulder. - Of course.
Taeyang cooks?
Do you also drink?
- I'm not a good drinker. - No?
Someone could teach you.
Teach him?
- Who could teach him? - Why?
Maybe his body just doesn't like taking it.
You can't be a good drinker from the start.
I stopped drinking.
After I stopped,
I felt my body change.
Didn't you stop because of your debt?
(Didn't you stop because of your debt?)
(Sweating)
Actually,
Psy found out...
that I'm not a good drinker.
I don't enjoy drinking, so I don't know my limit.
You can only know if you drank before.
When I told him I didn't know,
that's what I meant.
I told him I never got drunk before.
Then Psy thought it was great and invited me to his house.
He thought you were a good drinker.
When I came to my senses,
we drank eight bottles of wine.
- He's good. He drank wine. - You're heavyweight.
You're a good drinker.
You're not a bad drinker. You just never drink.
He knows how to drink wine.
Eight bottles can kill you.
After that, I got sick of drinking.
- How many days were you out? - It was too much.
For about 2 to 3 days.
Do you turn red when you drink?
I don't turn red.
It's hard to tell for me.
What do you like to snack on?
I like Korean food.
Fruits?
Hello?
He just said he likes Korean food.
- Hello? Are you on the phone? - I like fruits too.
Hello? Hello?
Jae Hoon, it's me.
- Yes, hello. - He's taking it.
You got the snacks wrong.
(Why are you bringing up fruits?)
(Whimpering)
I'm glad you brought it up.
He's really good at cutting fruits.
- Really? - Great timing.
Today's timing is amazing.
- He must be good with his hands. - It was smooth.
We want to see you cut apples,
but just watching you won't be fun. We’ve prepared a little skit.
Team Two prepared it.
It's about three daughters of an orchard farmer.
Three daughters.
- That's a scary setting. - Yes.
The three daughters compete to cut apples...
in order to inherit the orchard.
- Then... - They want the orchard.
they should officially apologize.
(He's just saying anything.)
Can Team Two take Kim Heung Kook?
(Please take him away.)
Hey, are you throwing me away?
It's too late to ask me.
Then this will be Taeyang's apology show.
(That's it.)
This is because none of you apologized on a show before.
That was good.
You guys.
Let me apologize.
(Taeyang ends it off.)
He's good.
We have to call the secret stage...
- in order to start the skit. - Okay.
Can you do any impersonations?
The stage will transform if you show us something.
What should I say?
It doesn't matter. You can do anything.
(What will Taeyang show off first?)
(I'm praying)
He did it.
I'm praying
(Motion scanner on)
(Recognizing talent)
- Is it turning? - Is Yong Pil coming?
Great! It's turning.
Hey, is Yong Pil coming?
No, no.
Wow, trees.
(They can smell the apples.)
Everyone, it's an apple show.
It's an apologetic show.
It's here.
- It's a huge orchard farm. - Amazing.
(Dumbfounded)
I'll tell you your roles.
Heung Kook,
you're the orchard owner and father of three daughters.
- Jae Hoon, you're the mom. - Mom.
- Why am I the mom? - Is he my wife?
Yes, he is.
- You look good together. - Why would I marry him?
They look like a couple of 50 years.
Honey.
Honey?
(Singing)
- Honey - What is it?
Please, Heung Kook.
- Stop doing this to me. - You followed him.
- I'm trying to work here. - You did it too.
Kyu Han is the eldest daughter.
- Gook Ju is the middle child. - I'm glad.
Taeyang is the youngest.
If you're a woman,
please get your makeup on.
- Let's go. Mom, - No.
you have to get makeup on.
(Changing)
I don't get why I have to dress up when I'm already a woman.
Look at the youngest daughter.
(He has pigtails.)
- Do I look cute? - You look good.
(The youngest daughter is so cheerful.)
She's so cute.
(The eldest is sassy.)
He wanted to be more funny.
I don't think it'll be funny.
No.
I think this is better.
It suits me.
- The makeup... - It looks like mine.
- Good. - It's cute.
(The pigtails reflect his free will.)
- Okay. - No wonder I wanted...
to wear velvet today.
We should get off stage for now.
- The eldest daughter. - You can enter first.
Ready.
Action.
Honey.
(That feels good.)
- Honey. - Yes?
Today is the day. We have to settle it.
- We must get the orchard. - It's ours.
We have to take it.
Kyu Han likes dressing up.
He likes dressing as a woman.
- Kids. - Mom, we're here.
Hello. Welcome.
- Hello, Father. - Welcome.
Mom, Dad, we're here for a reason today.
Stop hesitating and hand the orchard to us.
Our kids are growing up.
They're going to start elementary school soon.
We're going to need a lot of money.
Honey, today is important.
I thought of a business plan. We have to pay off our debt.
There are green tea pork and wine pork.
What about apple pork?
I heard everything you said.
- Mother. I mean, Mom. - Mother.
If you're here, you should come in. Why are you talking outside?
- Are you here? - Sir.
Yes, we're here.
Good.
- My son-in-law is so handsome. - Mother.
Why are you guys here?
Why are you picking a fight?
- Why did you come? - What about you?
I know you're living well.
Stop fighting.
(They're ready to join the war.)
- Father. - Take care of your husband's debt.
- Father. - What's that?
Is that the youngest?
Our youngest is here.
What a show.
We're in so much love.
- Are you here? - Dad.
- I'm glad you're here. - We're here.
- Sit down. - Sit.
- Mom, sit down. - I'm okay.
Why are you all here?
Don't you know the orchard will be given to us?
- Come on. - It's ours.
- What are you talking about? - Don't say that.
All you have to do is sign on the waiver.
We're not giving it up.
I'm the eldest, so I should get it.
Your youngest daughter...
says she'll dance her heart out if she can get the orchard.
What kind of dance was it? Show us.
- Show us, honey. - If I can get the orchard...
If we can get it?
(This is the youngest daughter's dance.)
Look at how great her dance is.
That's not a dance.
Honey, show them. You show them.
You show them.
- This is what you call a dance. - Show them.
- This is how you do it. - Honey, don't let them win.
- You should dance like this. - Honey, go.
This is a real dance.
(This 45-year-old is trying his best.)
- Dancing. Dancing. - Good job.
- Father. - You're so good.
I'll explain to you why...
we deserve the orchard.
I sang a song called "Sorry, Sorry".
It's an apologetic song.
That's right.
(He's doing the dance right away.)
You're right.
Apple, apple, apple, apple
- Come on. - Apple, apple
Even before "Sorry, Sorry"...
I'm so sorry but I love you
(I did it before him.)
Do you have anything?
I'm so apple, I'm so apple
Apple, apple
(It's suddenly an apologetic song.)
What are you doing, honey?
What did you do?
- I didn't even notice. - It's okay.
I raised our kids well.
- Sit down. - Father.
- We understand... - Give it to us.
We know how you feel.
Your father will make an important announcement.
I can't farm anymore.
It was such hard work tending to a huge orchard farm.
Honey, you need a break.
Are you planning to die?
He's almost talking in his grave.
The air feels so heavy.
It's not that.
I want to travel with your mother.
- Yes, that's good. - Good.
You should take a break.
I want to split it fairly between you three.
Let's take this apple.
Try to peel it as long as possible.
- Peel it long. - Make it long.
- We have to measure it. - That's a wise decision.
The couple...
will get this orchard which is all my fortune.
This apple orchard.
All right. Hold an apple in your hand.
- Let's begin. - What should I do?
- Okay. - Hold this.
He's good at this.
Honey, have a seat.
- All right. - I'll do it standing up.
- You should do it sitting down. - Sit down.
Honey, have a seat.
I'll eat an apple while you guys are peeling them. This is for you.
My husband still has a strong grip.
Ready.
(Who'll get the orchard as the best apple peeler?)
Start.
Take your time.
Do it slowly.
- In fact... - Peel it thinly.
Taeyang has been good at peeling apples since he was young.
You're off to a good start.
(The two ladies are peeling an apple smoothly.)
- Isn't it too thick? - I think it's too thick.
- Taeyang is good at this. - Oh no!
It's almost 5cm wide.
Oh, no!
- You should... - Wait.
- Gosh. - We don't know it yet.
Dad!
- You'll get the orchard. - I have a crick in my hand.
I have pins and needles in my legs. What should I do?
She always liked to eat it but has done nothing like this before.
(It looks like he's getting lessons for married life.)
(Taeyang is peeling an apple with deliberation and elaboration.)
Honey, I'll get the orchard!
(Screaming)
It's cut off. It's over.
That's it.
- All right. - It's done.
- You did a good job. - Gosh.
- Okay. - He's done too.
- Okay. - My legs.
My wife just finished it perfectly.
(That's tiresome.)
I'll spread it.
You should be careful.
It has a very thin part in the middle.
Do you have...
- Do you have a tapeline? - Spread it.
(The immature husband just made a mess.)
He made a mess.
You can cut it now.
Be careful.
Cut it here.
I was so nervous doing this.
(Taeyang finally finishes it.)
Wait.
That was so close.
It didn't snap.
- All right. - Look at that.
- Look at Gook Ju's. - How do we measure it?
- It's long. - She really wants the orchard.
- We worked hard for the orchard. - I can see that.
Mine is 120cm long.
It's very long.
Gook Ju's is 94cm long.
Taeyang's is 98cm.
- 98cm? - What?
(Kyu Han wins.)
Being insensitive, Kyu Han won the game.
- She's the eldest daughter. - The eldest.
(It's for Taeyang's PR Video. Why did you win the game?)
(He feels embarrassed and uncomfortable.)
She feels very uncomfortable.
- All right. - Congratulations!
(Such an insensitive move)
- You did a good job. - Honey.
You must be very happy.
- Let's go. - I apologize.
(We all apologize.)
Being insensitive, I inherited the orchard.
- Right. - I got it.
He's mean. He's so greedy.
I become very greedy when it comes to land.
Kyu Han, you sound really down.
That's because he feels guilty.
- Why would he feel guilty? - He's sorry about the orchard.
Maybe he won’t be here next week.
We should hold him responsible for it. Taeyang.
Why did you suggest it when you're not good at peeling an apple?
(Why did you suggest it when you're not good at peeling an apple?)
(He shifts responsibility onto Taeyang all of a sudden.)
The whole thing happened because Taeyang said he's good at it.
Should I apologize?
(He's witty.)
You should definitely apologize for this.
(We all apologize again.)
- All right. - Let's move on to Heung Kook.
- Heung Kook. - Meme.
Heung Kook's 17 years old.
- Hang on. - What was that?
(Kim Heung Kook's legendary performances)
What's that?
That's it.
He was very slim back then.
I know.
It was his best days.
I was slim, and I had a good head of hair back then.
(Staggering)
There he goes!
All the backup dancers lied down.
(The point is the reeling steps.)
- Look at that. - He's likely to fall down.
- Have you fell dancing to the song? - Yes.
He just fell.
(He fell on the stage.)
(It's the legendary dance which got him arthritis in his knee joints.)
("Reggae Party" in 1994)
It's "Reggae Party".
(It's a reggae song which has Heung Kook's freewheeling style.)
(I'm feeling confident)
(Giggling)
(The highlight of this song is this exclamation.)
What's that?
("Shaking" in 1992)
It's "Shaking".
Is this "Gag Concert"?
Is he a comedian?
(He dances like a primitive man.)
This song was quite popular.
Right. It's "Shaking".
(Heung Kook's PR point is his freewheeling musical style.)
It's something people still can't even try.
How did you come up with the dance moves? I'm so curious.
I was in a vocal group.
I was an obscure singer for about 10 years.
Then I released the single, "Tiger Swallowtail".
I got a call from a TV show for the first time ...
- with that song. - I see.
So I had a rehearsal there in the afternoon.
There were no choir or backup dancers for me.
They wanted me to sing alone.
- While others got all those things. - I see.
- So I got an idea. - You had a plan?
I decided to dance like that during the shooting.
Tiger Swallowtail, fly
When the part began,
I thought I had to do something about flying.
So you were describing a butterfly?
That's right.
- Was it a butterfly? - Yes.
- A butterfly? - A butterfly coming out of a pupa.
From a larva...
- The metamorphosis of a butterfly? - That's right.
(The metamorphosis?)
The metamorphosis?
The metamorphosis of a butterfly.
It doesn't mean I'm a pervert.
From a larva to a butterfly.
That's right.
It's called metamorphosis.
Really?
(He didn't know the word.)
Have you injured or sprained your ankles dancing to the song?
I got a lot of calls from oriental medical clinics.
They said I could visit their clinic if I had any problem.
A lot of people fell and got injured...
imitating my dance moves back then.
- Right. - Imitating your dance moves?
- Yes, while they were imitating me. - You were very popular back then.
He's right.
Who do you think was more popular? Heung Kook of the time or Taeyang?
- Of course it's Taeyang. - Taeyang?
- He's BigBang. - Compared to you of that time?
Back then, to be honest with you,
I had no rival.
Of course there were many popular dance singers...
like Sobangcha, Park Nam Jung, or Kim Wan sun.
But "Tiger Swallowtail" overpowered them.
- It turned the game around. - I heard...
you settled all your debts with this song.
- It was a big hit. - In fact,
my parents are all dead.
Before they died, my family was very poor.
But only with the song, "Tiger Swallowtail",
I paid off all my mother's debts.
She was very happy about it.
The song, "Tiger Swallowtail" completely changed a person's life.
Then I believe you have...
all the detailed knowledge about tiger swallowtail.
Can you tell us about a tiger swallowtail then?
There are various kinds of butterflies.
(He answers immediately.)
But a swallowtail is the best.
- Is it the best? - It's the best butterfly.
I still see swallowtails when I go to the mountains and fields.
- You see swallowtails? - Other people can't recognize it.
But the butterflies recognize me.
- The butterflies recognize you? - Are you sure they recognize you?
He's the most popular singer in the butterfly's world.
(He's the most popular singer with butterflies.)
When I go to the mountains and fields,
others can't see them. But I...
- Look at him. - Taeyang.
I've never lied in my life.
- He looks so serious. - Other butterflies don't do that?
Cabbage butterflies and sulfur butterflies just fly past by me.
- They fly past by you? - They don't like you.
But tiger swallowtails come to me to say hello.
(What a coincidence!)
- Are you serious? - It's unbelievable.
You should go to the mountains and fields with me.
To the mountains and fields?
- To see the truth? - He's like a poet.
I can't help it wonder...
how Taeyang liked the Tiger Swallowtail dance.
I watched the performance when I was very young.
I seriously think that...
it was a revolutionary performance.
It was very cool.
I think the song is sophisticated enough to be released now.
(BigBang always show flashy performances.)
(Taeyang is an outstanding artist.)
(One thing they have in common is that they show shocking performances.)
He's right. So I thought about this meme.
I was thinking it'd be great if Taeyang danced to the song.
- To "Tiger Swallowtail"? - "Tiger Swallowtail".
- It's a good idea. - What do you think?
- It must be cool. - Can I sing the song?
(He politely asks it.)
- That'd be great. - Did you see that?
What?
Can I sing the song?
He's so cool.
He's amazing.
- This is the best meme. - It's something...
we can never see from Jae Hoon.
- What did I do? - It's...
Is it something you can't see from me?
I've never seen him being so polite.
I think Sang Min is a smooth talker.
(He's a smooth talker.)
- He's good. - It's discrimination.
Let's watch him sing "Tiger Swallowtail". Here's the microphone.
(He wants to be the Variety Cheat Code like Heung Kook.)
(Nervous)
- It must be cool. - I'm so excited.
It'll be a big hit.
The song would top the chart again.
(PR Video by Lee Kyu Han)
("Tiger Swallowtail" by Taeyang)
(Dancing waves)
(He gets into a groove.)
This is exciting.
He's just like Heung Kook.
Yes! There it goes.
This is amazing.
(A tiger swallowtail)
(One butterfly)
That's it!
(Taeyang adds a cooler style to it.)
- Look. - It's so much cooler.
Nice!
(Taeyang remakes the immortal butterfly song.)
(Good!)
(The two with similar lives sing together.)
- Yes. - This is nice.
(A tasty song with a cooler style)
(A butterfly's wings flapping made BigBang possible.)
Join in when you can.
- It sounds trendy. - I know.
That's Taeyang's song!
Taeyang swallowtail.
(How upsetting is this?)
Please don't be upset.
(I'm upset)
Please don't.
Here we go.
(Here comes the highlight.)
(Let's see Taeyang flap his wings.)
(Flapping)
(Swagger)
(He's dizzy.)
(Butterflies are everywhere in the basement.)
(Taeyang wants to party.)
(He pulls off the original's staggering dance steps.)
(Hopping)
(Taeyang has rubbed off on him.)
("Taeyang Swallowtail" rewrote history.)
That was perfect.
- That was amazing. - It truly was.
- I love "Taeyang Swallowtail". - Me too.
(Taeyang knows how to party.)
Since Taeyang sang "Tiger Swallowtail" today,
the digital sales will go up.
- You're right. - I know.
It'll roam up the charts.
Why don't you sing...
"Tiger Swallowtail's Eyes, Nose, Lips"?
(They find it absurd.)
You don't have to if you don't want to.
(What?)
So let's go back to Heung Kook.
While we were watching his memes, we saw...
- "I'm feeling confident". - Right.
(In 1994, "Reggae Party" brought on the reggae craze.)
Those who did reggae music called him...
the King of Reggae.
I heard that "Reggae Party"...
was written after witnessing...
the success of Kim Gun Mo's "Excuse".
I don't do things I need to make excuses for.
(His puns catches the comedian off guard.)
- Taeyang likes it. - That was unexpected.
- Look at Taeyang. - You can respond to anything.
You're actually making our jobs harder here.
Do you know that?
That's how it is for some.
(So what?)
He's completely trouble-free.
It's as if he doesn't care at all.
Did you know that Sang Min...
worked with me on "Reggae Party"?
Did you rap for him?
Yes, I rapped in the song.
Could we hear it live?
- Do you remember the lyrics? - Well...
I only sang it when we recorded the song.
- I see. - Really?
Have you performed it together before?
- No. - This'll be the first time.
This would instantly be a meme.
This I should do.
I think that this'll be legendary.
(Will a legendary meme be born?)
(It's been 23 years...)
(since they brought us the Jamaican rhythm.)
(How will they look on stage?)
(Startled)
Looks perfect.
(They're wearing appropriate outfits.)
This is nice.
They look more like Pakistani men.
(This is what Heung Kook wore for his album cover.)
- We can't make a mistake. - The hats look like...
the candy baskets at the cashier counter...
of a barbecue restaurant.
(They involuntarily look sweet too.)
(Music starts.)
("Reggae Party" by Kim Heung Kook)
(With Chief Director Lee)
(Please welcome the band from Jamaica.)
(She plays 2 instruments.)
(We're in Jamaica now.)
(The world is big)
(There are many things to do)
(Dreams are not far from reality)
(Yes!)
(Now it's time for the hook.)
(His other selves are invited to the party too.)
(Look at that.)
(Their presence makes him more confident.)
(Witness his confidence!)
(He ends the first verse with his unique laugh.)
He'll now rap.
(He's off beat.)
(The way you look for behind)
(Swagger)
Lee Sang Min!
(Don't wake me up if this is a dream)
(I can't take how thrilling this is)
(The Jamaican rhythm fills the basement.)
(I'm feeling confident, I'm feeling confident)
(Tongue rolling)
(That'll even shake Bob Marley's confidence.)
(The reggae brothers were a success.)
That was awesome.
No wonder Heung Kook is known as a legend.
He's so cool.
Now that we've seen Heung Kook's,
- it's now time to see Taeyang's. - That's right.
Could you look more adorable this time?
Sure, I'll try.
What's my meme?
(Adorable)
(Look at Taeyang party.)
(Here is Taeyang after his concert in the US.)
- Is he in the US? - Yes.
It's after his concert.
Is that his bodyguard?
- Did this happen in the US? - Was it with an American?
Where on earth is he?
It's where he had his concert in the US.
Is he behind the stage?
I think it's the parking lot.
(Taeyang can't hide his excitement.)
You really must like to party.
Are you sure that this wasn't a fight?
(They look cool even when saying goodbye.)
(Sistar won 1st place on a TV music show.)
(BigBang seems three times happier.)
You're happier than Sistar is.
(Taeyang seems to be the most excited.)
This is during Sistar's acceptance speech.
(He's embarrassed.)
Please tell me that I saw wrong.
(During the ending scene...)
We'll see someone jump. See?
Some flew past the screen again.
Were you drunk that day?
- Of course not. - I think he was.
Did you have wine?
That's a live show.
I do admit that I wasn't myself that day.
- Do you admit it? - Yes.
There are times when I can't help myself...
when I feel the urge to party.
Why were you so happy that day?
As you all saw, we didn't win first place.
I know. We all saw that.
We had released an album after a long hiatus.
- That's why you were happy. - That day,
I felt like nothing could go wrong.
- Everything was a joy. - That's right.
Did Sistar say something to you that day?
They never said anything to us,
but I'm still sorry about it.
It wasn't us who won first place,
but I acted like...
- a crazy guy. - Like you had won.
You're being too kind about this.
It doesn't matter who's the senior artist.
You were helping them in a way.
You were happy that they had...
- won first place. - Exactly.
- Junior artists were behind you. - That's right.
Did you see their expressions?
(What's wrong with him?)
(IU and Koo Ha Ra)
I could read that on their faces.
So why did you dance with the bodyguard off stage?
That happened after we successfully...
wrapped up our concert.
A security guard...
who saw me dance on stage asked if we could dance together.
Really?
- He's a skilled dancer too. - I know.
- Really? - He was talented.
Who won the dance-off?
(Flustered)
- Who won? - Was it you?
- It's important. - We need to know.
I'm sure he felt a certain way afterwards.
- He knows who won. - Right.
As you saw on the video,
I was the better dancer.
Of course.
- That's right. - I agree.
The reason you came to us today...
is because you're not funny enough.
You wanted us to bring that side out of you.
So to know how you really are,
we'll see a video of someone close to you.
We asked a few questions.
Let's see how your close friends see you.
I'm dying to know.
(Under the Microscope)
Taeyang has never been drunk before.
What is he like after a few drinks though?
- It's not pretty. - What?
I've seen him drunk many times.
That's his habit.
(He always says that he isn't drunk.)
Taeyang claims that he's funny in person.
What's your opinion on that?
That's what he says when he's drunk.
- Really? - He's not funny at all.
It's proof that he's drunk.
Who are you to Taeyang?
- Do you know who it is? - He doesn't have many friends.
I'm like his only friend.
- Who can it be? - I think I know who.
It's G-Dragon!
(Surprised)
Is there anything you'd like to say to him?
(Taeyang looks forward to it.)
I'd like to point out that my single was released too.
- He's talking about his own song. - Anyway,
he's like an older brother even though we're the same age.
I could tell that he was stressed out...
with this new album of his.
As his friend, I'm glad...
that he was satisfied with it at the end.
I wish him nothing but the best.
Think of Make me Viral on Monday,
and think of me on the other days of the week.
We must've forced him to say that.
I'm sure it was on a script.
He probably didn't want to say that.
Think of me on the other days of the week.
(He tries not to smile.)
Then think of Taeyang on Sunday.
- G-Dragon. - He delivered that in style.
He was threatened into saying that.
"Think of Make me Viral on Monday."
So you have many drinking habits.
G-Dragon's currently on a world tour.
I guess he's exhausted. During the interview...
seeing how he said they were just drinking habits.
As I mentioned earlier,
he always just smiles and says that he lost.
Now, he will think that I'm boring.
Then which one of you is funnier? You or G-Dragon?
Then who is funnier? You or G-Dragon?
I believe I'm funnier.
He takes pride in being funny.
He does. He definitely does.
Do you really not have any friends?
I...
Well, I like staying at home.
I don't go out often to meet my friends.
People whom I can call my friends are the members of my group.
When I was young, I had more friends.
After I started my career in the entertainment business,
- You didn't have time to meet up. - I didn't have time to meet them.
- Even if you called, you can't see. - When we meet,
- we don't understand each other. - You are different.
- My members are my closest fiends. - I can see that.
Shouldn't there be people from Mars or Venus...
among your friends, Taeyang?
(He can't believe what he just heard.)
- Shouldn't this be a problem? - Goodness.
- Chief Director. - You can't act like him.
(He's taking after someone.)
You can't be like this.
G-Dragon said that in the video that you are...
like an older brother.
Then what about you? What kind of a friend is G-Dragon?
To me,
he can't be a kind of friend I have.
- He's the only friend. - The only friend?
Yes, we met at the age of 13.
- When you were 13? - Until now,
I spent more than half of my life with him.
- Do you plan to live with him? - Of course.
- Wait, what? Live together? - Yes.
I can't see that far out.
- He's living with his parents now. - Really?
You can go to his house and live together.
- Me? - That'd be funny.
Taeyang has his own parents.
(Stop it.)
From my observation,
I can see that Taeyang is a good dancer and singer.
He's perfect, but among his talents,
I think he's the best when it comes to having fun.
I also uploaded the dance cover...
of Blackpink's "As If It's Your Last" on my social media account.
Why did you do that?
I posted it because I was bored.
There were a lot for me to memorize. I wanted someone to take a look.
But my video got more than 480,000 hits.
So I think if Taeyang dances to the song,
- I wonder if people will watch it. - He'll get a few millions easy.
Exactly. This will gain a lot of attention from the public.
- Gook Ju. - Isn't this for your personal gain?
After hearing that he doesn't have any friends,
I think you're trying to be his friend rather quickly.
- I can do both. - If you try to dance with him...
Then Gook Ju, why don't you dance here?
And Taeyang can look at her dance and copy her.
I think Gook Ju can be his dance instructor and dance in the front.
(Gook Ju's dance lesson)
Turn your arms and lift them up. Do it like this.
I never imagined Taeyang would learn dance moves from you.
- Me neither. I'm so nervous. - No one imagined this before.
- I don't know if I should teach. - You'll memorize this right away?
- You can just feel the song. - Sure.
I think she's teaching him the wrong moves.
- How is this? - I don't want to hear her sing.
Let's see now. This is good enough.
("As If It's Your Last" by Blackpink)
(With Gook Ju's gestures,)
(Taeyang's journey to dance female idol group's choreography begins.)
(Dancing)
(Since it's his first time, he looks a bit sloppy.)
(However)
(Getting the hang of it)
He catches on quickly.
(The beginner catches up to her quite quickly.)
(Fancy)
(He even shows some freestyle dance moves.)
(1, 2.)
(He's a dance prodigy.)
We'll do this move now.
(He delivers perfect dance moves which is hard to believe.)
(Their moves are in synch.)
(It's her last dancing lesson that will never happen again in the future.)
- He learned them so quickly. - He's so good.
- He does. - When I watched, he danced well.
- I agree. - Gook Ju taught him well.
- Really? Was that good? - We should...
- listen to his opinion. - That's right.
- Taeyang is too nice. - That's true.
What's the biggest rebellion you ever had?
This is so sudden.
- There's none. - I bet.
I think he rebels...
- through having various hairstyles. - It's true.
They are all unique.
(The transition of Taeyang's hairstyles)
- Mohican. - He did many different hairstyles.
Since he always has a unique hairstyle,
his current hairstyle looks normal.
- It is an ordinary hairstyle. - I like his hair though.
I like it too.
I realized after some time had passed.
- What did you realize? - A lot of people didn't like...
those hairstyles.
I learned that especially the ladies weren't fond of them.
Of course they aren't.
I found that out now.
You should do it together.
Is there something that inspires you to have those hairstyles?
When I watched National Geographic...
and channels like this,
I thought that I'd look cool after seeing some animals.
That makes sense. One time, your hair looked like a scorpion.
It did.
You had a hairstyle that resembled the mane of a lion.
- It catches people's eyes. - What's the one on the end?
- What is it? - It's a buffalo.
Did you get that hair done with your own hair?
Inside my hair,
- they put hair rolls. - They used hair rolls.
After I got my hair done for that,
- I thought it was revolutionary. - You thought it was amazing.
- Really? - Yes.
I thought no one ever had a hairstyle like mine.
So I got that hairstyle.
After my music video was released,
my fans photoshopped a roll of gimbap in it.
That did happen. I saw it.
I thought I should keep the hairstyle.
So I couldn't perform with that hairstyle.
- It appeared only in the video? - Yes, only in the music video.
It just looked like you put a pair of telescope on top of you.
- He put it there after using it? - He can place it there for a while.
The person behind him can do this without realizing it.
(Let me see.)
Just like Mount Nam.
(They demonstrate perfect teamwork when they tease people.)
I know that you are preparing to go on tours all around the world.
Can I ask you to show us a sampler of your concert?
You have a competent friend.
This is the most practical one.
Team One got a promising employee.
- Could you do it for me? - Of course.
(Taeyang never says no.)
I think he does everything he's asked of.
You can't see this anywhere.
Can you lend me money?
- How much do you need? - "How much"?
"How much"?
I can't ask him for favors because he never says no.
- He'll do everything. - Exactly.
Jae Hoon, if you're close to someone, don't get money involved.
(Looking serious)
Heung Kook, did I really borrow money from him?
I got a feeling that you might.
(Feeling guilty)
(PR Video by Eun Hyuk)
- This is the world tour. - They'll join in the middle?
(They are his back-up dancers.)
- They look so cool. - Hold up.
We're filming here. Get out of here.
(They go along with him.)
(They are funnier than me.)
Let's go.
("Ringa Linga" by Taeyang)
(He's the best vocalist who has a world tour to attend to.)
(The performance of a world-class singer)
(The performance is about to unfold in the basement.)
(Raise your hands as if you're liberated)
(Jump like you have a sprained ankle)
(He starts rapping first.)
(His intense rapping...)
(is as good as his singing skill.)
(A good dancing skill is a bonus.)
(And)
(Taeyang is known for his impressive voice.)
(His rapping, dancing, and singing are all perfect.)
(I'm Taeyang.)
(The whole country is pumped up by his song.)
(His song also awakens their inner instinct to dance.)
Sing it now.
(Everyone, sing it together.)
Sweet!
Gosh, that's so cool.
("Ringa" is an irresistible magic spell.)
(And)
(For the excitement they couldn't unleash,)
(he starts counting again.)
(This is Taeyang's ritual calling for people's excitement.)
(Everyone, wake up to have fun.)
(His ritual is over.)
(Pump up the volume now.)
(Here we go.)
(Let's sing it one more time.)
(Thanks to Taeyang's unyielding magic spell...)
(Everyone learned how to have fun.)
(You'd better do something about my heart.)
- I went crazy. - That was awesome.
What moved me was that during the song,
his dancers came here and drummed the desk.
I thought that his concerts had to be successful.
(It was when the song was reaching its climax.)
(This is nice.)
Let's give a round of applause for him.
- Thank you. - Thank you so much.
We saw numerous PR videos today.
Right.
Both of you can choose the video...
that you liked the most.
I think today, "Taeyang Swallowtail" has to be the winner.
That's your choice, Taeyang?
Taeyang chose "Taeyang Swallowtail".
I think even when we wrap up,
I'd like to finish the shooting while we sing "Taeyang Swallowtail".
Goodness!
(Really?)
He's such a nice colleague.
- I mean it. - He's so cool.
In my opinion, it'd be better if you chose "Taeyang Swallowtail".
- It must be "Taeyang Swallowtail". - Exactly.
Today, we will go with only "Taeyang Swallowtail".
- We'll sing "Taeyang Swallowtail". - They both chose that.
We'll finish up as we sing the song.
- Let's wrap up. - It's "Taeyang Swallowtail".
I think "Taeyang Swallowtail" might be popular.
This might climb up the chart.
Director.
(They finish off the excitement with the song.)
You should sing it together.
(Because it's an encore, the prelude sounds even more exciting.)
(Holding his breath)
(Tiger swallowtail)
(As Heung Kook sings a measure,)
(these tiger swallowtails are gathering around him.)
(On the flowerbed)
(Sang Min joins them.)
(Chief Director Lee can sing.)
Here comes Taeyang!
(Showing off a technique)
(Get ready,)
(and fly.)
("Taeyang Swallowtail" is about to soar successfully again.)
Let's hide.
(Hiding)
(Feeling great)
- Awesome. - Tiger swallowtail.
Just get at it!
Hi. It's me, Taeyang.
I had such a great time.
Anyway, you should go to bed.
Sleep tight. Good night.
(Wanna One, an idol group loved by the nation will be on the show.)
(A variety show hazing to show off their charms)
(I am the best at being funny on variety shows.)
(Attracted to their tough and powerful sides)
(Also attracted to the provocative words)
(From the wake-up calls which are sweet to your ears...)
(to the ones that make your eyes pop.)
(They don't care about their images and give it all.)
(Wanna One is full of charms.)
(Make me Viral)