[Episode 15]
Of course I remember!
When everything's resolved,
let's go there again.
You were putting on a show until now?
You came, Soo In.
This...
It's not yours.
Joon Hyun.
It's not that...
There must be some misunderstanding.
It's not me.
Misunderstanding?
What misunderstanding?
Destroying Chun Hee's stage dress?
Causing an accident to hurt Chun Hee?
Lying about being my fiancee
and covering up the accident?
But...
we saw each other back then.
Is that a misunderstanding, too?
Why?
Did you think I still fell for it?
Joon Hyun...
How did you turn out this way?
You weren't like this before.
Joon Hyun... I really
didn't mean to hurt you.
Then was it Choi Chun Hee?
Why the heck would you
do that to Chun Hee?
Is it because of the new boss?
Is it because he likes
Choi Chun Hee, not you?
No, it's not like that!
Yes, I hated Choi Chun Hee!
Who is she? Who the heck is she
to steal away everything I have?
Why is she the one enjoying everything
that I should be enjoying?
Soo In...
You know I've liked you for
a long time, don't you?
For that long training period...
you never slacked off.
I really liked you... for
putting in your honest work.
That's how Park Soo In exists now.
You're not the type
to know about tricks.
I'll tell you for the last time.
Turn yourself in, Soo In.
I can't do that, Joon Hyun!
Like you said, it took so
much for me to get here!
I've never breathed easily
since I was fourteen.
Every time I went up on stage
I was always so nervous,
I would clench my feet.
I bled because my toenails
went through my skin!
I still went up to sing.
Joon Hyun...
I can never step down
from the stage on my own!
You made... the choice.
Joon Hyun... Joon Hyun!
Joon Hyun... Joon Hyun...
Where are you going right now?
Are you going to report me?
You wouldn't do that, would you?
Wait wait, just wait for me!
Joon Hyun, you told
me to turn myself in.
Okay, I'll turn myself in.
But please, give me some time.
Time for me to wrap things up.
You can do that much for me, can't you?
Joon Hyun, please!
I need to tell you something.
Everything you said on stage...
is recorded here.
What?
I'll give you three days.
First, apologize to Choi Chun Hee
from the bottom of your heart.
Chun Hee!
What are you doing here...
Joon Hyun called you so
that you and I can meet.
Have a seat, Chun Hee.
Why would Jang Joon Hyun do that...
I apologize.
Everything was my fault.
To be honest... the accident
on stage was also my fault.
- You did that?
- I must've been blinded by jealousy.
I just hated you at the time...
so I only wished that you'd disappear.
I'm sorry.
You mean... you did it to
me because you hated me.
But Jang Joon Hyun got
hurt instead of me?
Chun Hee, I'm sorry.
I don't know why I did that either.
I'm sorry.
I can never forgive you.
Jang Joon Hyun almost died from it.
You know that, don't you?
I'll turn myself in. I will, but...
just give me a little bit of time.
You said you became a singer
because of your father, right?
Just like you have your precious father
I have my mom. Her only hope is me.
But if I go straight to the police
station, my mom might faint.
Please, I'm begging you, Chun Hee.
Give me a little time to
wrap things up, will you?
It's my fault.
Yes... I need time.
Time to wrap things up.
Why didn't you tell me?
Why did you hold it
in all by yourself...
If I told you...
would you have been okay
with the temper you have?
You'd have run over there
and made a ruckus!
You don't know how they
would have reacted...
You could've even been in trouble.
You had no evidence other
than my statement.
Look at me.
Well done!
You knew how to embrace a secret
and you carefully secured evidence.
Good job!
You did a better job.
You trusted me and waited for me.
Good job.
- Dad, I'm going out.
- Where are you going?
Yes, I'm going to a
homeless shelter to sing.
Isn't that hard?
Dad, I think things have
been going to easy for me.
I got recognized by people quickly...
If I compare it to marathon, I
haven't even run one kilometer yet.
Even if things go well again, I
plan to continue volunteer work.
It's rewarding to sing for the homeless
and they like my singing.
But more than that, I like it.
I feel like I'm learning
more from them.
Don't forget to eat!
- See you later.
- Okay.
Hello?
My Chun Hee wouldn't do that.
I trust my daughter, Joo Hee.
Myung Shik, I watched
the CCTV recording!
Are you saying you can't trust me?
It's not that I can't trust you.
I just trust my daughter.
And about the clip that you saw...
something must've gone wrong with it.
I heard things like that can
be manipulated these days.
After what you said last time,
I did my own investigation...
And it looks like Director
Yang stole the CCTV recording.
I thought you were
just sitting as
president, but you
actually do some work.
I got a great father.
Oh, and...
that picture of Choi Chun Hee
and you living together...
I think Director Yang did that, too.
Can I meet with that paparazzi?
Dresses are really pretty.
- Mother...
- Yes?
How do you like this?
It's so luxurious and pretty.
Take this one.
Really?
Thank you.
By the way... that wench didn't
just have a crush on Joon Hyun?
My Joon Hyun was in on it, too?
Please help me, Mother.
The evidence that they cheated
is in Joon Hyun's room.
My Joon Hyun wouldn't do that...
Anyway, I'll help you this time...
but going forward, you should do
better so that it won't happen again.
Yes, Mother.
Father...
how far do you think those two will go?
The whole time I've been in business,
there is one principle I stood by.
It's people.
Even with bad thoughts
or wrong behavior
I recognize their efforts and talents.
You and I both, if we had recognized
their efforts and talents...
maybe things wouldn't
have gotten this far.
That's tough.
I can't stand anything complicated!
This job really doesn't suit me!
You punk! You have a long way to go.
You really have a long way to go.
Really, you're such a headache.
Father, have some watermelon.
Have it all by yourself!
- Senior, good morning.
- Good morning!
Hi.
That red pants are really annoying.
Wow, it's so cool.
- Chun Hee is on a program today?
- Huh? I don't think so.
- Isn't she doing an opening act?
- Opening?
- Getting the audience excited?
- Yeah.
Still, how can they leave her
standing up in the hallway?
It's a hot day, but the
air conditioning is not even on.
Tell her to come in, it's too hot.
- Just Chun Hee?
- Yeah.
No, I can't. There are
so many people watching.
Really?
Tell everyone to come in!
- Everyone!
- Everyone?
- Even the red pants?
I don't like her.
Everyone...
Joon Hyun says...
everyone should come in.
It's cool in the room with food to eat.
So come in and relax in the room.
Yes, I'll be right there.
You can't do that.
Chun Hee, you have to come.
- You said you're on a diet.
- Don't push me.
- You should lose weight.
- I'm not eating!
It's so loud in here.
Just hang on. That's why I
said no to the red pants.
What kind of trainee is she?
- She must be good at singing.
- She must be amazingly good.
Is it good?
Hey! Drop that right now!
Drop it right now!
I knew the red pants
would cause trouble.
Get out, everyone!
So he's a star...
He invited us in! Is he pulling a joke?
Seriously...
She touched my bellflower tea!
You brought it for me.
I understand how you feel...
But it hurts me to hear other
people talk bad about you.
Can you treat other
people nicely for me?
Can you do that for me?
- Hello, Mother.
- Soo In...
I just sent a messenger to give you
something that looks like a pen.
I just received it.
Yes, thank you.
Who ordered you to follow Choi Chun
Hee and take a picture of her?
It's Director Yang Joo
Hee of Shine Star.
Has this happen before?
Yes, it happened several times.
I took a picture of Choi Chun Hee
sleeping in front of her house.
Everyone has something if
you shake them enough.
Something's supposed to come out.
I kept the CCTV recording...
and the recorder you're
looking for is here.
Joon Hyun!
Let's stop now.
Joon Hyun, you didn't
send this, did you?
It's over, Soo In.
Turn yourself in before it's on TV.
This is still your last chance.
Are you crazy?
- What are you doing?
- Let go! It's over now!
- Park Soo In!
- Let go!
What am I supposed to do now?
Let go! Let go of me!
Park Soo In!
Get a hold of yourself.
Will I be able to sing again?
Let's go.
Why did we come here?
Why isn't my invitation
getting accepted?
This man...
Sir...
Wait, I have to get
to the next level.
'Sir!'
Get it!
Got it! I leveled up!
Level up.
Round of applause!
Let's clap together!
One hand!
Cheer up, it's only once.
Life doesn't come back
once it's passed.
Even if love doesn't tell me
it doesn't change just
like the tree for you.
I can give everything I have for you.
What did you think?
I've only heard about it.
I saw it for the first time today.
It was really nice.
Were you ever happy like that
when you sang?
It looks like you've lost it.
If you lost it, you
should find it again.
Don't be touched.
I'm telling you as the
President of Shine Star.
I really don't like you these days.
I really liked it when you were
popular and made a lot of money.
Sir...
Hurry up and come back to your place.
So that I can make some money!
I'll wait for you.
This...
What's this?
It's your first love that
you were looking for.
Goodness, when did you...
He might be your first love...
but to me, you're my last love.
Ji Sook, please be happy.
Bro!
You should have this!
I had a commercial shooting,
and I got so much chocolate.
Enjoy.
Senior!
My niece is your fan. She
asked for your autograph...
I guess the answer is no?
- Why would I say no? Let me see.
- Really?
- Should we take a picture, too?
- Choi Chun Hee!
- Yes?
Why don't you take a picture of us?
Me?
Okay, I'm taking a picture.
One, two, three!
Close, close.
We should take one close together.
Here. Let's take one standing close.
One, two, three.
- Here you go.
- Thank you so much!
What?
Did you eat something bad?
I'm doing well, right?
- Pat my head please.
- Pat your head?
What the?
Is moderation so difficult for you?
- You told me to be nice.
- What a joke.
Place Choi Chun Hee on
a different program?
I think it'll be tough to ask
given the things going on now.
If you're willing to be a DJ for a day,
I'll ask Producer Kim.
I looked everywhere
that she would go...
- And?
- But I couldn't find her.
Should I file a missing
person's report?
You call yourself a manager...
By the way, did something
happen between
Soo In and Jang
Joon Hyun recently?
Soo In doesn't talk about
things like that...
Got it. You can leave now.
Yes?
Jang Joon Hyun!
Congratulate me.
I'm on a radio program!
Really?
I'll be a guest and I'll
be singing a song, too.
- Are you climbing up?
- Am I?
Get inside.
I'll come by later to cheer you on.
To give you this.
Get inside.
Mom, don't look for me for a while.
Fighting!
I want to do well.
Joon Hyun!
Are you the DJ?
The DJ had an emergency,
so I'm filling in.
- Emergency? Natural disaster?
- Emergency?
Hello?
Can you give me water?
I have it ready.
- Let's do well.
- Yes.
For sure.
Now, it's time for 'Decide for My
Heart, ' stories from the listeners.
Our guests of the day
Mr. Shin Hyo Yeol and
Miss Choi Chun Hee
will read the stories.
- Yes.
Hello, I'm a woman in my 20's who can't
decide between two very different men.
One is a guy from my neighborhood
that I've known since my childhood.
He has a temper, so I've never
considered him as a man.
But the owner of the
cafe that I work
part-time is showing
his interest in me.
Seon Joo, what are you
doing after work today?
I want to give you a ride
and have dinner together.
I'm a good cook.
Hyo Yeol, you should
use the mic in front
of you to get the
sound out properly.
- I see.
- Please.
- Really?
- Please continue.
He's cool and capable, enough to
make other employees jealous.
I couldn't believe someone
like that likes me.
It's a happy concern between the
neighborhood guy and the cafe owner.
Don't add meaningless ad-lib.
- Please follow the direction.
- Yes. Follow the direction.
And I can't say I didn't like the owner
who had money, and was also nice.
Then one day, the cafe
owner gave me a ride
and kissed me suddenly
in front of my house.
Seon Joo... you know how I feel, right?
You do...
Stop!
"Stop," that's what the
neighborhood guy said.
And everything ended there. Stop!
Miss Choi Chun Hee, you're
very good at reading stories.
You're really awesome, too.
Joon Hyun...
You want to die?
Why would I want to die? I'm sorry.
I wonder why I was like that back then.
I didn't even see my parents then.
I had no friends...
If I didn't stop you, you were really
going to kiss her, weren't you?
You really went overboard.
Try that one more time, I'm going
to stop you from going on air!
What do you mean 'stop'?
Why would you be so upset?
Do you have high blood pressure?
Okay, Joon Hyun... I mean, sir...
I'm really sorry about everything, sir.
I'm very sorry.
So please, get me on the
program again next time.
You can talk to Producer Kim.
I'm working to death for this program.
See? Choi Chun Hee looks like this,
but still I'm putting my best effort.
Her face... I can't
connect my feelings...
Kneel.
So, please tell Producer Kim...
What? You can't bring up your feelings?
What's wrong with Choi Chun Hee?
What's wrong with my Chun Hee!
You know, we all know...
faces like that...
What's with you?
You... I'll talk to
Producer Kim, but...
Watch what you say. Seriously, you...
Thank you for today.
About what? For cheering you on?
You think I'm stupid?
You put me on the program.
I didn't.
I went on a program for the
first time in a million years.
And the program DJ is Jang Joon Hyun.
Wow, you think I'd believe
that coincidence?
How did you know?
Don't do that again.
I want to come back on my own.
Please.
But thank you so much
for your thoughts.
Really?
Then pat my head.
Pat your head?
Good night.
Father!
Father, shouldn't you
get surgery soon?
I don't want to be away
from my children and
spend my remaining
time in the hospital.
Please keep it a secret from Chun Hee
and Byul to the end.
Okay?
I understand.
And...
can I ask you for one more favor?
I know it's a lot to ask...
but can you be with my Chun Hee?
Of course I will.
I don't mean it that way...
Before I leave, if I can see you two
living together under the same roof
I think I'll feel at ease.
'Before I leave'?
Why would you say that?
Please.
Tae Song...
What's going on?
Well, Tae Song entered
'Voice of Trot' this time...
If he passed this round,
he could've been
on the monthly competition.
What a waste!
There was something like that?
Well, even professional
singers enter it too...
Of course I wouldn't pass...
Don't say that. You're
a trot god, Tae Song.
Yes, Tae Song. I'm your number one fan.
Don't ever give up!
You have to cheer up!
Hey, Jang Joon Hyun...
Tell me honestly. You're
the god of music.
If you tell me there is no
future for me, I will stop.
I have... no future, do I?
When you think about it,
do you honestly think...
There is.
You have a future.
- I do?
- Set a good concept and shoot a demo.
That sounds good!
Yes, yes, that's what you should do!
Joon Hyun can help, right?
Really? I was going to stop.
But I'm doing this
again because of you.
- Can I say hello now?
- Wait, wait.
- Go!
- Hello.
Playing hard to get with trot!
Playing hard to get
with trot, the man!
The woman!
You're my partner.
My partner forever.
- Tae Song.
- The best gift in my life.
You and I were strangers.
Living a good or bad life
depends on the fate
But I only love you!
My partner forever!
Let's hear from MJ, the 11th
participant in 'Voice of Trot.'
What, what, what is it?
Who, who, who are you?
Please don't leave me alone.
What, what, what is it?
I might lose weight.
Please don't leave me alone.
By the way, what's your reason for
entering our 'Voice of Trot, ' MJ?
To be honest, I became a
singer before I knew it.
When I thought about it, it was too
easy for me to become a singer.
I wanted to return
to the beginning and
restart, so I challenged
myself to this corner.
Choi Chun Hee...
Hello, MJ!
President...
- What?
- MJ!
You're MJ.
Anyone would know from
listening to the radio
- that you're MJ.
- You listen to the radio, too?
Of course.
If I pass this blind audition, I
can go on to the final round.
Until then, please
keep it a secret...
Well... I'll see how you do.
I'll keep that secret.
Thank you.
What secret?
No comment.
That punk...
Oh, Mr. Jang Joon Hyun,
what's going on?
You have a nice tie today.
- What?
- Your hairstyle is nice, too.
I've had the same style for six years.
Shine Star stock price has gone up
a lot because of me, hasn't it?
A very little.
What is it that you want to say?
Well...
What's the secret that you talked
about with Choi Chun Hee?
She didn't tell you?
My goodness, you really don't know?
This is embarrassing...
Are you really going out with her?
You really suck. If you don't
want to tell me, then don't.
That's really immature.
Jang Joon Hyun...
If you win the game, I'll tell you.
What?
Rock, paper, scissors!
Paper, paper, paper, paper!
Wait, wait.
- Wait.
- Now, start.
Go, go, go!
Come here, Jang Joon Hyun.
Now...
Go, go, go.
Here!
This is cheating!
What's with your hand?
Come here. I'm going to start.
Go, go, go!
Really, as president...
You have a mark.
What? Are you saying that the
culprit is Miss Choi Chun Hee?
Yes, it is Choi Chun Hee.
You're saying that this
was an intentional
accident from a love triangle.
This will become a big
issue once it gets on TV.
I can't just put it on TV
based on your words alone.
Unless you have some evidence.
This... would at least prove
that the two cheated.
I really want them to pay
for lying to my Soo In.
Dad... what Director Yang
said earlier is not true.
You know that, right?
Wouldn't I know my own daughter?
You would never do such a thing.
Director Yang doesn't seem to know
that I have the recording.
Father, I'll take care of this matter.
Please don't worry.
Jang Joon Hyun...
what do you plan to do?
I really didn't mean to hurt you.
Then was it Choi Chun Hee? Why would
you do that to Choi Chun Hee?
Is it because of the new boss?
Is it because he likes
Choi Chun Hee, not you?
No, it's not like that!
Yes, I hated Choi Chun Hee!
Who is she? Who the heck is she
to steals away everything I have?
Why is she enjoying everything
that I should be enjoying?
Is this the voice of Park Soo In?
Yes it is.
So the culprit is not Choi Chun Hee.
Mr. Jang Joon Hyun,
what's the reason you
decided to hold a
press conference now?
I had lost my memory after the accident.
So I couldn't even remember
the woman I loved.
The woman I love is... Choi
Chun Hee, not Park Soo In.
I hope the woman I love doesn't go
through anymore pain because of me.
It's Yang Joo Hee!
You said that Choi Chun Hee caused
the accident of Jang Joon Hyun.
Did you lie to protect your daughter?
Please tell us the
truth, Ms. Yang Joo Hee.
- Please move.
- Please tell us.
Jang Joon Hyun, Jang Joon Hyun!
Why do you bring up the
name of my precious son?
What brings you here?
I thought you were smart, but
you're not good after all.
How can you raise your
daughter like that?
My Joon Hyun could've been in
big trouble because of Soo In.
Attempted murder for a man?
Shouldn't you send your daughter to
a psychiatrist to get some help?
You'd better not provoke me.
You're not so clean and
innocent yourself either.
What? What do you mean?
Go!
We'll begin the blind audition
of 'Voice of Trot' now.
They're legends of trot.
We have Ms. Hwang
Geum Ja and Mr. Byun
Hee Bong as judges.
Participants, please enter.
The judges will hear the
singing while blind-folded
and select the number
of the best singer.
We'll begin now.
I want to put my face on
your chest and cry today.
I can't come close to you
because I'm short of a word.
Every time I stand before you
why do I become small?
When I stand behind your back
my eyes become wet.
Wow, everyone is amazing!
We'll be right back
after this commercial break.
Participants, please leave
the room for a minute.
Judges, you can take
off your blindfold.
We'll hear your short comments now.
Since I've been a singer so long...
I can figure out someone by her voice.
The echo from the participant number
three comes from her truthfulness.
She's born with the
gift of her voice, too.
The winner is number three.
Congratulations! The winner
Miss MJ, please come in.
You...
Hello, Teacher!
I'll never be a judge again.
- Teacher, thank you for your comment!
- Number three...
Just because I told you a few
words today, don't get cocky.
- This is the beginning.
- Yes, I'll keep that in mind.
Thank you, Teacher! I'll do my best!
The top three must-to-dos
when I get a girlfriend
What? Is this why you made
such a scene just now?
Of course. What else could be
more important for a couple?
I'll show you what a
real date is today.
Let's go!
First, walk on a busy
street holding hands.
You even prepared matching t-shirts?
Of course! It's me!
Second, eat delicious street food.
Please give me a plate of that.
- Did you want to eat spicy rice cake?
- Yes, fish cake, too.
Is it good?
Wow, my Chun Hee really
knows how to eat.
- It's good.
- Chun Hee.
- Yeah?
- You look like you gained weight.
Third, watch a movie together.
I've really wanted to do this.
Really? Me too.
One for you...
one for me.
Having fun?
- I think I'm thirsty.
- Here... one sip for you...
one sip for me.
To be honest, the
movie is not important.
What's important?
- Being intimate.
- What a joke.
You scared me!
What did you buy so much of?
Things to eat.
- Please have this.
- Oh my.
Do you want to play badminton with me?
I let you off easy last time.
It's hard for me because
you're not good.
- I let you off easy last time.
- Look at you...
I'm going to play
badminton with Dad now.
He's really good.
What? Byul... is your father back?
Yes!
Cheers!
We're still on a date, but
that is ruining the mood...
There is a mood for eating chicken?
Here.
You're eating well.
We have to get back in the mood!
- There is a mood for eating chicken?
- Yes there is, you idiot!
No there isn't, you idiot!
Your eyes are not pretty,
your nose is not pretty
so how did I come to love you?
Did my heart melt watching you smile?
I like you, the one with her own style.
When I was in your arms
all my hardships were erased.
Like a lie...
I missed your warm,
comforting embrace so much.
I think only about you all day.
I think only about you all day. I do.
It's nice.
Of course. God of music Jang Joon
Hyun composed it thinking of someone.
Thank you.
When I send you something,
you should send me something back.
You should make my wish come true.
I'm feeling good.
Tell me everything. I'll make
everything happen for you.
Let's get married.
What?
I thought about this...
I don't think I can
make it without you.
This necklace finally found its owner.
It looks good on you.
Don't lose it. Keep it safe.
You lost me altogether.
As long as you keep your mouth
shut, there is no problem.
I don't care... It's all in the past.
What? Getting married
to Choi Chun Hee?
Are you crazy?
I have more than enough
of a headache...
When you got married to David...
did you ask for my approval?
What?
Recently, I saw the person who caused
the accident to your mother.
The hit-and-run?
Yes.
Who was it? Is it someone you know?
She was a colleague who used to
sing with your mom.
I have to find her.
I want to find her and resolve
it with my own hands.
That's the first thing I have to do.
And the second thing is...
to marry you off.
Dad...
I hope... you'll tie the
knot with Joon Hyun.
A career in singing has
a lot of ups and downs.
If Joon Hyun is by your side...
I'll feel more at ease.
Are you going somewhere?
Why are you talking like
someone who's leaving?
You're making me nervous.
Hey...
I have to see you live a happy life...
for me to feel at ease.
I heard the reservation
is under Choi Chun Hee.
Please wait.
This way please.
What will you bring as
a wedding gift?
A house with big windows is nice.
A house?
To take a husband like Joon Hyun...
of course a house is in order.
Soo In said she'd get a house...
- Mom, please!
- Stop calling 'mom'!
My ears are hurting!
By the way, where is the restroom here?
Don't worry.
There is nothing I like about her.
This is the room.
Myung Shik...
Hwa Soon...
You're Hwa Soon, aren't you?
Myung Shik...
By any chance...
Is Jang Joon Hyun your son?
Maybe Dad can't find this place.
Wait a minute.
You call yourself a human being?
How could you run over
Sung Joo and run away?
After what you did to Sung Joo,
were you able to sleep comfortably?
Myung Shik...
Since you ran away to the U.S.
after the accident,
you didn't think I'd
be able to find you?
I've waited for this day all my life.
I wanted to find you and
ask you before I was dead.
Why did you do that?
Why did you do that to Sung Joo? Why?
I'm sorry, Myung Shik.
It was my car, but...
But my car was stolen at the time.
I'm telling you the truth!
You did nothing wrong, but
you ran away to the U.S.?
- Does that make sense?
- But it does.
Congressman Park bought me that car,
so I was afraid of a scandal...
Will you keep lying to me?
Sung Joo didn't know
anything but singing.
Do you know how much she
suffered after that?
It's all your fault!
How... How could you leave Sung Joo
on a cold street and run away?
No, no! It wasn't me, Myung Shik!
It wasn't me!
If Sung Joo was taken
to a hospital a little
bit sooner, she wouldn't
have lost her life!
Myung Shik, please believe me!
I didn't know!
- I didn't know, Myung Shik.
- Let's go.
Let's go to the police. You
should pay for your crime. Let's go!
Myung Shik! Please listen
to me, Myung Shik!
Myung Shik, please
consider my Joon Hyun...
Joon Hyun is a singer.
If his mother ends up at the police
station, it's over for Joon Hyun!
Myung Shik... please... please...
Please...