Hae Joo.
- Say something.
- Mom.
How could you?
How could you sell our company's design...
to a counterfeiter?
- Hae Joo.
- And you're Wid Group's madam?
I'm very disappointed in you.
Koo Do Chi lost his position
and is awaiting assignment,
and Son Yuh Ri from the
design team was fired.
Do Young.
It's been a while since you did as I say.
I guess he was afraid...
of the company being prosecuted.
Did you hire workers and have
them wait outside as I asked?
- I did.
- Okay. Wait outside.
Do Chi and Yuh Ri, stumbling blocks...
to Hae Joo's success have been removed.
It's Ji Won's next.
I just need to remove her now.
Hae Joo. How could you do this to me?
Anyone who damages the
company's reputation...
cannot be forgiven.
Even if it is you.
I'm done talking.
Get out of my sight!
Don't do this to me based
just on Do Chi's words.
That recording could've been faked!
We knew you'd keep denying it,
so we brought the witness.
Come in!
This man...
circulated our design in Dongdaemun.
Who's the one who gave you our design?
Who ordered you to sell
our dress at the market?
Tell me. Who is the one...
who gave you our design?
This woman.
What? What did you say?
Hey, you. Do you know me?
Have you seen me before?
When? Where?
I've never seen you before!
Who is it? Who told you to blame me?
Tell me!
That's enough! Shut your mouth.
Stop denying it.
We have a witness.
Denying won't accomplish anything.
I've never met this man before!
Now that we found the culprit,
please cancel Yuh Ri's and
my termination and transfer.
That's not right.
The thief isn't the only one at fault.
You're also at fault for being careless.
Hae Joo.
It's a premeditated crime.
Don't try to blame the victim!
Uncle. Accept the result.
Dad. You can't cancel Yuh
and Uncle Do Chi's...
termination and transfer.
Dad. Mr. Chairman.
That's enough!
For now, the termination
and transfer are on hold.
Now everyone get out!
Ji Won! You stay!
Look. Who are you?
Who told you to frame me?
Stop it!
Just how low will you go?
Is your head filled only
with conspiracies, schemes,
and dirty tricks?
What is this mess?
Hae Joo and Do Chi...
were competing to succeed the
chairman to run Wid Group.
Ji Won gave that man our team's design...
in order to eliminate Do Chi and me.
She made counterfeits of our
dress to fill the market,
in order to hurt Do Chi and me.
Ji Won did something like that?
I can't believe it.
I told you.
Ji Won is a frightening woman.
Don't see her again.
Who knows what she'll do to you?
But why were you at the office?
What?
This is it.
Where I left my baby.
Here?
What's wrong?
Do you remember something?
The thing is...
It's obvious.
You'll say...
you wanted to get rid of
Do Chi and help Hae Joo.
Even if you did it for Hae Joo,
I can't forgive you!
It wasn't my plan.
- Believe me.
- If not you? Then who?
It was...
You've tried my patience.
You've crossed the point of no return.
I was patient with you for
Hae Joo's sake until now,
but no more.
Pack your things and get out of my house!
No! Why should I?
If it's about the damage the company
incurred, I'll compensate you.
I'll take responsibility for
the products discarded,
and I'll sell the land in my name...
- and compensate...
- This isn't about the money!
I can't let someone like you
remain in our house. Get out.
- Honey.
- If you don't leave,
I'll drag you out.
How could you?
How could you sell our company's design...
to a counterfeiter?
- Hae Joo.
- And you're Wid Group's madam?
I'm very disappointed in you.
Why did Hae Joo suddenly
throw me under the bus?
I did all of this because she asked me to.
Ji Won.
I'm very disappointed.
Do you see only Hae Joo
and not the company?
How could you ruin the company to help her?
I never saw that man before.
And he didn't know what I looked like.
He didn't know what you looked like.
As in, you never met him,
but you admit to giving him
the design, is that it?
I did no such thing.
You must have schemed this
in order to get rid of me.
Dream on.
Once Wid Group becomes Hae Joo's,
she'll kick the two of
you out without fail.
That's right. Let's see the
mother and daughter fight.
Both of you...
will be kicked out of the company...
and the house. I'll make sure of it.
Did you get to the house?
Okay. I'm busy too.
Hae Joo told you that I was coming, right?
- Yes.
- Where's Ji Won's room?
She's staying in that room.
Go in and remove all of her things.
Right now.
Yes, ma'am.
How did it go? Did you catch the culprit?
- We did.
- Yes.
Then the termination and
transfer were canceled, right?
Just because we caught the culprit
doesn't excuse us from all fault.
Regardless, we were
careless with the design.
We must change the chairman's
mind about basing his decision...
- on who should succeed him on this.
- Of course.
We couldn't compete fairly
because Ji Won cheated.
But wasn't Hae Joo acting strange?
Ji Won clearly did it for her,
but she shunned her,
and turned her back to her.
Ji Won could not have acted alone.
She couldn't have gotten our
design without Hae Joo's help.
Have you reached Yul Mae yet?
She turned off her phone and
has completely disappeared.
What will you do about Angela
Choi pressing charges...
against the two of you?
Now that we found the culprit, we
should explain what happened...
and ask her not to press charges.
Let's go see her now.
She must be in her apartment.
Ji Won.
Were you living...
in this tiny study in
this palace of a house?
You poor thing.
I'm sorry.
Wait.
Is this Do Young's and Ji Won's son?
It's Ji Won when she was young.
Who's this?
It isn't Hae Joo.
Is this the baby that she abandoned?
What are you doing?
What are you doing in my house?
It'll be my house starting tomorrow,
so I came to look around.
What are you talking about? Your house?
The furniture lacks any sense of style.
But then again, you need to
have seen them growing up...
to develop a taste for them.
I'll have to change them all.
Why are you complaining about the
furniture after trespassing?
I heard you stole my design.
Your design?
The design you circulated in Dongdaemun.
It was a collaboration I did with Do Chi...
and Yuh Ri.
I'm the designer Angela Choi!
Angela Choi was you?
While I was gone,
you stole my husband Do Young, and now,
you steal my design too?
It must be because you grew up poor.
Stealing is ingrained in you.
You won't be Wid Group's madam much longer,
so enjoy it all you can today.
I'll see you off nicely when you step down.
Ms. Ahn!
Yes, madam.
Who let this woman in?
Why are you...
letting random people in as you please?
Kick her out right now!
I told her to let her in.
- Hae Joo.
- I called her here.
I called my real mom into my house.
Hae... Hae Joo.
Angela Cho still isn't picking up.
Maybe she's avoiding us because
of the charges against us.
- Hello?
- This is terrible.
What is it?
Madam is about to get
kicked out of the house.
I can't reach the chairman,
so I'm calling you instead.
Let's go home first.
Ji Won must be fighting with someone.
Hae Joo.
You were like this earlier too.
Why are you doing this to me?
Is it...
because of Ga Ya?
That's right.
You know, since you've lost a child too.
Just as you can't forgive
Yuh Ri because of Hae Sung,
I can never forgive you.
It's a completely different
situation than with Yuh Ri.
I did my best to save Ga Ya.
There was nothing I wouldn't do.
Had I known...
that Mee Hee was a match with Ga Ya,
I would've looked for her first.
Who would believe you?
Regardless, the results are the same.
You're the one who killed Ga Ya.
If you hadn't stopped my
birth mom from meeting me,
Ga Ya would've lived.
I never knew you'd think that way.
I had faith that you'd
know how I truly felt.
If you understand my pain
even in the slightest,
leave this house quietly.
If you care at all about me,
don't torment me by
making me see your face.
Fine.
If that's what you want,
I'll leave for a while.
But...
I was sincere about everything
I've done for you and Ga Ya.
Please believe me.
Hae Joo.
Do you see this?
- What is that?
- Give that back!
The picture of the real daughter...
of the woman you call "Mom."
He had been hiding it very well.
She was cherishing this photo...
and probably looked at it all the time...
as she longed for her real daughter.
You were nothing but a substitute...
for the daughter she lost.
That's not true! I never considered
Hae Joo to be her replacement.
Don't try to tear us apart!
You lost that child, right?
If she finds this child,
she'll discard you like yesterday's trash.
You acted like you cared so
much about me to my face,
but you were...
longing for your daughter behind my back?
Hae Joo. That's not true.
Get out.
Drag her out of here.
Hae Joo! Don't fall for her lies.
You were all I had!
Hae Joo! It isn't true!
Hae Joo!
It's Ji Won.
Angela Choi is with her.
- Hae Joo.
- Why is Angela Choi here?
Is she fighting with Ji Won?
Hae Joo. Please listen to your mom.
- You have to believe me.
- I don't want to hear it.
Hae Joo.
Put this all over Dongdaemun.
It's a women's clothing design.
Did you...
ask me to circulate the design...
in order to get rid of me?
That's right. I'll be honest,
given the circumstances.
I can't bear to look at you any longer.
It pains me.
Seeing you reminds me of Ga
Ya, and it drives me crazy.
That's why I want to get
you out of my sight.
I'll send you the rest of your things.
Please leave quietly.
Okay.
If that's how you feel,
I should leave your sight.
But don't believe that woman Mee Hee.
She left you.
Who's to say she won't abandon you again?
I'll take care of that.
Good job.
You have to be prepared to bleed
this much to get what you want.
We kicked Do Chi and Yuh
Ri out of the company,
and Ji Won from the house.
Leaking my design...
was detrimental to me,
but I'll gladly accept it for you.
Let's go in.
Angela Choi is Hae Joo's birth mom.
It was all Hae Joo's doing.
She used Ji Won to leak our design,
and used Angela Choi to
press charges against us...
to kick us out of the company.
Ji Won was just a pawn.
Hae Joo was the one controlling her.
She used both of her moms
to achieve her goal.
(Love Orphanage)
No.
Yuh Ri couldn't be the daughter
that Ji Won abandoned.
Grandpa.
Hi, Bom. What is it?
I drew you.
Wow. Bom.
You're a good artist, just like your mom.
I'm lucky that I take after Mom.
I think it's because I
had my lucky birthmark.
Lucky birthmark?
I had a birthmark the shape
of a four-leaf clover...
on my waist before.
Although we had it removed,
so all I have is a scar now.
A scar?
Let's get surgery once you start college.
It looks bad.
It wasn't bad enough...
that she gave that baby a burn scar.
She left the baby on the cold
floor in the dead of winter...
which killed the baby.
So she wailed, punching
herself in the chest.
No.
It couldn't be.
Not Yuh Ri.
- We're home.
- Where is everyone?
Bom. Mommy and Great-uncle are home.
Bom.
- Welcome home.
- My baby.
Father. Is something bothering you?
You look concerned.
Is it because of what happened
earlier at the office?
Yuh Ri.
If I remember correctly,
you had a burn scar on your shoulder.
That's right.
I had a burn scar on my shoulder
ever since I was a child.
But not anymore.
I got surgery to remove it.
Why do you ask?
No, nothing. Never mind.
Yuh Ri couldn't be Ji Won's daughter.
There's no way.
Why are you coming from there?
I was looking at the empty room.
Where's your mom?
She left.
Mother left? What do you mean?
I'm tired. I'm going to bed.
What happened?
Why did your mother suddenly move out?
I kicked her out.
Seeing her face drove me crazy
because it made me think of Ga Ya.
If it weren't for her,
Ga Ya would've lived.
What? Even still,
she raised you as her
own for over 30 years.
How could you turn your back
on her so coldly like this?
What is it? Tell me.
This isn't just about Ga Ya.
You're hiding something
from her, aren't you?
I am not. Stop imagining things.
- Hello?
- I've found him.
The man who was watching
Son Joo Ho for Ms. Koo.
I want to meet him tomorrow.
Hae Joo.
There's definitely something there
between you and your mother.
Otherwise,
you couldn't do this to her.
Yul Mae?
I haven't heard from her yet.
Okay. Bye.
What is it? Was it Yuh Ri again?
Yes.
She begged me to call her
if I hear from Yul Mae.
I think something serious is up.
What did she do?
Forget this.
The phone has been turned off.
That brat. I can't reach her.
Where is she?
I haven't slept in my own bed for days.
My body feels so stiff.
Should I ask Hae Joo to send me money?
Wait. Over there.
That girl walking with her
behind swaying side by side...
looks like Yul Mae.
Yul Mae! Kim Yul Mae!
Mom!
We found Yul Mae.
We're taking her to Ae Nok's store now.
Oliver just texted. They found Yul Mae.
- Okay. Let's go.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
Have a nice day.
The public loves it.
The other locations said your design...
is flying off the shelves too.
This is enough to show what
I'm capable of, right?
Of course.
You'll win for sure.
Once I get back to the office,
I'm going to tell my dad...
to make me his successor.
Okay. I'll head there now.
I need to stop by somewhere.
See you back at the office.
I'll get to the point.
You're the one who was
watching Son Joo Ho...
- at Haneul Hospital, correct?
- That's right.
Koo Hae Joo, the person who hired you,
is my wife.
And I called you here
because I wanted to know...
what you've done for my wife.
This should be enough.
Well,
I had to watch Son Joo Ho,
and she had me run some DNA tests.
DNA tests?
Whose DNA did you test?
The names were Son Joo Ho, Son Yuh Ri,
and Hong Ji Won.
Who? Hong Ji Won?
Why did she run a DNA test
on Ji Won and Yuh Ri?
For what?
Can you get another copy...
of the DNA test results?
(Human DNA Testing Center)
Yuh Ri and Ji Won are mother and child?
How?
That's why...
Hae Joo turned her back on her mother?
Is there a chance that Yuh Ri...
is Ji Won's daughter?
It's me.
Hi. I'm glad you called.
I wanted to meet and ask you something.
Okay. I'll come to you.
Here.
It's the famous Yoon Ki Dong
brand cold bean soup noodles.
Did you remember the hot peppers?
Naturally. I got the hottest ones,
just as you like them.
- Here they are.
- Great job.
My husband is the absolute best.
Are you going somewhere?
I need some air.
I thought I'd walk around
again like yesterday.
Why don't you eat first? I
just pulled the noodles.
I'm fine. I'll eat when I get back.
Also,
I think...
I may get my memory back soon.
Something very important.
If I do, I'll tell you everything.
Enjoy your lunch.
Ms. Koo.
Here are the sales figures...
and the contracts with buyers abroad...
that you asked for.
This is more than enough to make up...
for the loss Yuh Ri's
team caused the company.
- Good job.
- Thank you.
Did you see that?
Yuh Ri. You can't beat me.
- I'm going to see the chairman.
- Yes, ma'am.
I'm going to my dad.
I'll show him how well our team is doing,
and ask that he make me his successor.
- Go with me.
- We need to talk first.
What is it?
Let's talk later.
- I want to...
- Is Yuh Ri...
your mother's daughter?
- Is Yuh Ri your mother's daughter?
- Keep it down.
Do you want the whole world to know?
Answer me.
She is.
Yuh Ri is Mom's daughter.
The daughter Mom abandoned.
The daughter Mom thought has died.
Yuh Ri is that daughter.
She isn't related...
to Mr. Joo Ho at all.
Honey.
Is that why you kicked your
mother out so cruelly?
That's right.
I can never forgive my mom.
Once I found out that she was
Yuh Ri's mom, she made me sick.
I had a hard enough time
holding it in until now.
Don't tell me...
you plan to tell Yuh Ri or my mom, do you?
Tell me. Whose side are you on?
I told you.
I'm always on your side.
Good.
The two of them must never find out. Ever.
If you and I keep our mouths shut...
Mr. Joo Ho.
He knows too.
What if he gets his memory back?
I have to do whatever it
takes to silence him.
Whatever it takes.
I'll make my mom and Yuh
Ri, who killed Ga Ya,
pay for their sins.
The mother and child...
will end up killing each other.
I'll make sure of it.
These are the sales figures of Team A,
and the contracts with buyers abroad.
As you can see,
Wid Fashion's stock price
has gone up thanks to that.
I've seen the report.
Father. Don't you think it's time...
to name Hae Joo your successor?
Hae Joo. Are you confident?
Naturally.
I know I can grow Wid Group
much better than Uncle can.
Mr. Kim. Call in Koo Do Chi...
and Son Yuh Ri...
to my office right now.
Shut it! Get over here!
You'll pull my ear off, Mom.
How could you stab Yuh Ri
in the back of all people?
If you want to stab someone in
the back so badly, do it to me.
I had no choice.
Hae Joo said she'd divorce Moo
Yul if I didn't help her.
They had nothing keeping them
together after Ga Ya died.
I couldn't let him get kicked out.
Still, how could you be a mole?
Were you happy doing that?
You can't hide from Yuh Ri forever.
That's right. Confess and
ask for forgiveness.
She wouldn't kill you.
Kill me? No.
I don't want to die. I'm not even married.
I'd rather run away again.
- Yul Mae.
Yuh Ri.
Yul Mae. It isn't true, right?
You didn't do something
that frightening, right?
Yuh Ri.
I'm sorry.
Please forgive me.
Hae Joo threatened to divorce
Moo Yul if I didn't do it.
Hello?
The chairman? Now?
Last year,
Choi Mee Hee was engaged to the
French Ambassador in the US,
and recently called it off.
People close to her said she
took a trip for five weeks...
to recover from the broken engagement.
She came to Korea after
the broken engagement?
- Okay. You may go now.
- Yes, ma'am.
Come in, Joo Ho.
What's wrong?
Did you remember something?
I need to confirm something...
about your missing child.
You do? What is it?
Sit down.
Koo Hae Joo's new product is
making groundbreaking sales.
Thanks to that, Wid Fashion's stock...
that had hit bottom, are halfway back up.
The company's image is being restored too.
Congrats, Ms. Koo.
Congratulations.
I don't need your lip service.
It's true that there were
some shameful things,
but a competition is a competition.
The results are what matters.
The winner of this mission...
is Hae Joo.
The two of you promised...
to accept whatever the result may be.
Hae Joo is the successor now.
Please give me another chance.
This wasn't a fair competition.
We may have been partly at
fault for the design leak,
but Ji Won cheated.
And behind Ji Won...
was Hae Joo.
What do you mean?
Uncle. Don't make things up.
Mom worked alone on leaking your design.
- I wasn't involved.
- That isn't true.
The designer Angela Choi,
who worked with us,
was Ms. Koo Hae Joo's birth mother.
Yesterday, we witnessed
their secret meeting.
Ms. Koo is the one who pressured
Angela Choi to press charges...
against us.
To kick Do Chi out...
and become the successor.
Don't try to frame me.
Angela Choi is a professional.
She pressed charges
because she was outraged.
I didn't pressure her!
If you don't believe us,
we'll prove it.
Prove? Whatever.
How could you prove that I was
involved with the design leak?
Yul Mae. Come in.
Yul Mae.
What is it? What's your question?
Did that child...
have a unique mark or anything on her body?
Like a birthmark...
- or...
- A scar.
She had a burn scar.
A burn... A burn scar?
She should have a clear burn
scar on her right shoulder.
I spilled water on her by
mistake while making formula,
and gave her a scar.
Then Yuh Ri...
What's wrong?
Joo Ho. Did you recall something?
Do you remember something
about my daughter?