Hey, Bastard. How can you kill her off, Bastard
Stop here.
Do you think, I killed Kim Ae-kyung?
Is that what this is?
i said i'd take her back.
When did i say i'll kill her?
I'm a Businessman, and no longer a mobster.
You know, businessmen
Don't do murder. They make business.
Let's now get to the hearing.
Kim Ae-kyung, please enter
Today's the hearing, remember?
Min- soo, do you like this?
Wow, thank you.
When is mom coming?
Please stand for your oath.
uh...
I solemnly swear
the testimony about to be given
shall be nothing but the truth.
huh? It's mom. She's on TV.
congressman, please take turns
to ask your questions.
Kim Ae-kyung. Did mayor Bae Sang-do
take bribes from chairman  Cho Young-gook?
Prosecutor, those above the law...
We don't fall to the gutter.
Do you now realize
who you've been up against?
No. He hasn't .
Just you wait.
I'll make it exactly like
three years ago.
There is circumstantial evidence
that you were involved in their act of bribery.
Do you deny it?
That's not the truth.
Don't make false statements.
I'm not.
Aren't you well acquainted with Chairman Cho and Mayor Bae?
I'ev never met Mayor Bae.
The people are watching.
Why do you think you are here?
I'm not sure.
Woo Jae-moon, that bastard.
(Bad Guys : Vile City) Subscene@Whimsical
While there were arguments on why Kim Ae-kyung
hadn't shown up to the hearings as a witness,
her appearance today give us
a great deal of implications on this case.
Wouldn't this throw of prosecution's stance?
The prosecution claimed
Chairman Cho Young-gook was keeping Kim Ae-kyung
from talking on the stand.
But now, She's come to attend.
She testified that nothing out of the ordinary
took place to the tender process.
So this means...
Yes, that's right.
The figures show a swing in public opinion.
Ever since Kim Ae-Kyung came to the hearing,
public support for Mayor Bae's administration
has increased by six percentage point.
And HS's Group's shares climbed 24 percent to...
Seong-cheol.
Yeah.
You're taking that too often. You holding up?
What if i'm not?
Rest. After this case.
Rest? What rest?
Don't worry. I got Pil-soon.
She takes care of me.
Yes?
What will you do now?
How will you make Kim Ae-kyung talk?
Do you have a plan?
I'm still thinking.
So there's no plan.
Phew.
Why did you lose Kim Ae-kyung?
To Cho Young-gook's guys?
If things backfire, that'll be the end of us.
You even get that?
Let's handle this the old way. The way we do best.
(Kim Ae-kyung's Tax Account Office)
We're from the prosecution.
Hey, go through everything
Kim Ae-kyung?
What's your business here?
We're from the prosecution.
Here's a warrant to search and seize.
Grab that laptop.
Slowly choke her to death. Or we'd be no more.
She works is dough, so there must be something.
Zero in on that woman
and run through her all her bank statements.
Ma'am.  -Check the drawers.
Rummage through. -Min-soo.
Whoever transacted with her,
bring them in for questioning.
Come on, be careful.
With consent or with an arrest warrant,
bring them all in tomorrow.
-And.. -Hello?
Ae-kyung. People just rushed in.
They say they're from the prosecution.
They say the money you gave me
is from some mobster's money laundering.
I'll be on my way.
Min-soo, stay at nanny's place.
Don't complain it's dirty play.
Just do it. Please takecare of him.
The police may give way,
but not us.
Chaebols may come apart, but not us.
The regime may go under,
but not us.
Dad.
Ae-kyung. Why are you here?
Nothing bad will happen, so don't worry.
Your Mom.... -Let's go.
Dad.
In this country, we're power.
We're the truth.
We're the justice.
If we come to nothing,
that'll be the end of our country.
Ae-kyung.
What the hell is going on...?
Hello?
Our business clients have called,
asking what to do with the prosecution at them.
On how they know you?
And about your money dealings.
What should we tell them?
Hello? Hello?
They've nothing to do with Cho Young-gook.
It doesn't have to be like this.
We're after Cho Young-gook,
not his accounted, Kim Ae-kyung.
This will causetl trouble later.
Of you worry about implications, you'll regret ever having them.
Who's the prosecutor behind this arrest warrant?
Of Cho Young-gook Slips us again, we go nowhere.
You want to grieve again? Like three years ago?
You said you're bitter.
That you're up for anything. As long as you get Cho.
Then show me.
How sharper your knife is since three years ago.
What did i do wrong...?
That was way back...
I've done nothing wrong.
Why bring me in? What did i do?
I'm rich, so what?
Tell me.
Money laundering? Never!
Chief.
No.
Don't say anything. I Know.
This...
This isn't you, right?
Take it easy.
Where do I need to go?
Uh, this way.
Subscene@Whimsical
One sundaeguk and soju.
No sundae tonight. I'm out.
Just give me anything you got.
How long has he been there?
Two hours.
Jae-moon, what brings  you here?
You're not the only regular.
What's happened to you face?
And where's your wig?
I lost it, busy with work.
I'll get a new one tomorrow.
Hey, I'm all for civil-rights lawyer stuff,
but also think of your rights.
Who did you fight for this time?
Evictees of Inseo-dong redevelopment district.
I decided to take their lawsuit.
I got in a few punches myself.
You know me, I still got my fighting skills.
That's nothing to barg about, Save the fighting for court.
And don't get yourself beat up.
Think of your safety.
well, It first needs yo get to court to fight.
Back when I was prosecutor, I was at the courthouse
more often when I was home.
That,s how it was.
Why is it hard to reach for it now?
Having left since then
Why do you live like that?
Be like our other colleagues.
Make money off divorce clients.
Get yourself a good wig.
Why pass the bar? For this?
You call this doing well?
Then what is exactly is doing well?
You tell me.
I'll make the most of that.
Sigh.
Jae-moon.
You know.
I want seowon, the city we live in,
to turn out like this.
Good judgement prevails, not absurdity.
Rule of law prevails, not expediency.
Coexistence prevails, not survival instincts.
Kind heart prevails, not indifference.
Nonviolence prevails, not violence.
To become such a place,
the people here shouldn't be hurt,
and to protect them from such pains.
this is the only way.
I may lose all the time get beat up and cry.
I know nothing about it.
I've never seen that.
Do you know Oh Kwang-seon?
No, I don't
Come on, back in 2016...
You may tell me I'm a fool,
not getting how the world works.
But living like this,
trying  to change  something,
makes me free of conscience.
Don't you think every town needs a fool like me?
A few more would do better.
Yes, Chief.
Let those people  go.
Let's start over.
And not bark up the wrong tree.
Yes, Sir.
Sigh.
Investigator.
Let them all go.
What are you waiting for? Send them home.
Thanks for your cooperation .
We'll get in touch with you.
You can go home now.
I'll receive you like a prosecutor next time.
(prosecution)
Having Kim Ae-Kyung at the hearing,
was that you idea?
Why side  with the likes of Cho Young-gook and Bae Sang-do?
You weren't that kind of guy.
Don't you know who they are?
How could i not?
I know them well.
Then why back them up?
Mayor Bae Sang-do was elected to office .
We should respect the decision of our people.
What if the people are wrong?
What makes us the judge of that?
We're prosecutors.
Does  that give us power?
Is that why you became one? Is that it, ji-soo?
Senior.
Remember when we we're student activists?
You were amazing then.
On a podium, you spoke to hundreds of students.
That was really impressive.
Do you know what I thought then?
So that's power.
That guy, Ban Joon-hyuk, has power over us.
That came to mind.
What are you trying to say?
Where there are people, there is power.
If you don't take it, someone will.
You may argue otherwise,
but the prosecution is packed with authority.
And we have prosecution power.
That's the very reason we exist.
Stop your shenanigans.
When we're through, it won't look good
that a prosecutor has their back.
Get that, Ban Joon-hyuk.
Well, I don't know.
We'd have to wait and see
whichever way this works out.
I mean, you've no hand to play.
Aren't you cornered, District Chief?
Many are suspicious now.
Think about it.
If the knives you dealt until now
point at your own neck.
and they see what you've done
and concealed all this time,
who would be better off?
Senior, Are you threatening him?
No need.
Joon-hyuk.
Are you that ambitious?
Even striking against your own?
Not everyone is like you, sir.
It's time you know that.
Sigh.
And?
Where is Woo Jae-moon now?
Subscene@Whimsical
Chief Woo Jae-moon.
The District Chief doesn't look too happy.
Is something wrong?
Why did you let them go?
Taking her family as hostage,
so she'll say what we want?
Isn't that a bit humiliating?
That's not how prosecutors work.
Not how prosecutors work?
Then tell me, how do we work?
I hope we don't cross that line.
We're not thugs.
They had no business here.
What was with that?!
Does that make you a true prosecutor?
That's your problem, you fool.
While your junior associates climb the ladder,
wonder why you're still stuck?
That line you won't cross!
Everyone else did.
So just grab at Kim Ae-kyung?
Not enough with her parents,
but also lock up her kid?
Is that what I should?
Cho Young-gook said this last time.
Not to wield a knife at who
I'm fond of or who I'd like to last.
That I could be the one to die.
So do you know what I did?
You. I called you.
To wield a knife against Cho Young-gook.
Call them back in.
And break them.
Then who knows?
Maybe I won't ask for you again.
I can't do that.
I can do anything to get at Cho Young-gook or Dongbang Gang.
I'll do anything you order.
But let's not torment innocent folks.
We're prosecutors.
Then kill him.
Go kill Cho Young-gook.
You said you'd do anything I order.
What's wrong?
Can't do it?
You don't have guts.
That's your very problem.
Which got you divorced, bastard.
(Prosecution/South Gate)
Yes, Chairman.
How are you?
The prosecutors called you in?
I owe you one.
So nothing happened?
No. Nothing particular.
I see. Are you sure?
You know, Kim.
You're not hiding stuff, are you?
Of course not.
I got nothing to hide.
All right.
I'll take you on that.
Come by when you have the time.
I'll treat you dinner.
Sure. take care.
Yeah.
Sang-mo, clear up what you can.
How relaxing.
that took long.
You didn't eat yet right?
You didn't tell my mom, right?
About what?
That thing. I'm dead if she finds out.
So why did you?
If You're worried about her, stay away from such a place.
Who says I'm concerned for her? It's me I'm worried about.
I told you, she'd kill me.
Anyways, keep your promise.
Or I'd make you pay.
If you tell her, I mean.
Kids these days.
Eat, before it gets cold.
It's good.
I'm sorry.
Eat first.
You might choke on it.
To Survive.
I was trying to survive.
(Medical Institution)
If you can't bear it any longer,
if you've had quite enough,
leave them.
That would do.
And end up like you?
Lose everything and get hurt?
Run a restaurant? In a place like this?
I can't live like that.
No.
I won't let Min-soo live that way.
I'll have to bear it.
If I can bear it, then my son, Min-soo...
I just need to put up with it.
Then everyone is happy.
Sigh.
Remember what you said?
Asking if we're in our right time?
This comes to mind.
For you, yes.
But for me, no.
This damn world.
Are you her new doctor?
Excuse me.
That bastard.
Subscene@Whimsical
No drug was injected.
She's the same state.
Joo-myeong. -Yes?
Get some of our guys here.
Sharp ones.
Sure.
It's Cho Young-gook.
That bastard's behind this.
No, ne. We're not sure yet...
Don't give me your crap.
What's not sure?
Who else wants my sister dead?
He's washing his dirty dishes.
Things seem over,
so he's trying to get her
and keep her dead this time.
Those bastards.
Is there no way to catch them?
Come on, say something!
Go, before my sister returns.
Shouldn't we stop Han Kang-joo?
He may be a hazard.
Are you kidding me? Huh?
Han Kang-joo could kill Cho Young-gook.
You know that, Chief.
just let him be.
Whatever he pulls.
Sigh.
Honestly, Chief.
I'm not sure I know who you really are.
You let those people go, but now...
Good grief.
Abetting murder is a crime. Do you hear me?
Hey. There's no black and white.
You think people are that obvious?
Not so.
This bloody world?
It's all gray.
you should know that now.
Yeah, but...
what are you trying to do here?
Just don't do anything, you bastard.
Whether Han Kang-joo kills Cho Young-gook or not,
Shut your eyes, turn a deaf ear
and just sit there quietly.
Is that so hard to do?
Chief.
Hey.
Noh Jin-pyeong.
You don't get...
why I'm trying to bust Cho Young-gook, do you?
The prosecution had claimed
Chairman Cho Young-gook was purposely keeping
Kim Ae-kyung from the stand.
But she appeared to testify. So Inseo-dong's...
Get me Cho Young-gook's schedule.
Yeah, It's me.
Starting tomorrow,
can you keep tabs on Han Kang-joo?
Things look pretty quite.
But what is this all about?
Why should I keep watch on Han Kang-joo?
Nothing particular.
It's just...
What I mean is...
It depend on the situation.
What is that supposed to mean?
Did Chief give the order?
No, he didn't.
This is on my authority.
And so...
Don't breathe a word
to Chief Woo about it, got it.
I'll take the burn and flame.
So just tell me
If Han Kang-joo makes his move.
No harm will come to you.
Can you fo that for me?
Just Answer me this.
No one gets hurt by doing this?
It's so we can live.
Sigh. Yeah, so we can...
It's so we can all live.
Please trust me on this.
All right.
When Han Kang-joo moves, I'll let you know.
Yeah, thank you.
Sure, take care.
Hang on.
Hey, Han Kang-joo.
Kid..
What are you trying to do?
Is that knife in your hand?
Hey, Han Kang-joo
Kid..
What are you trying to do?
Is that knife in your hand?
Uh, uh!.. Hey.
Kang-joo took off.
He even got himself a weapon.
I'm not sure where to.
What the hell is going on? huh?
wow.
What a big crowd.
Hello, I'm HS Group's Cho Young-gook.
In a little while, my staff here
will talk you through details.
Honestly, I don't get their papers.
They use too many big words.
Damn it.
What I got to say to everyone here
is just this one thing.
Inseo-dong is where destitute people flock to.
They're bums who live off our taxes.
Those Inseo-dong blokes. I've heard such talks.
How close are the Inseo-dong bastards?
They're almost here.
You've come here to see a business profit.
Damn, They're like plague.
How about we call the guys?
Despite It's poor state...
Tell the bodyguards to come.
It won't take long.
(Seowon Stadium)
Bundang was a tumble of shacks.
Seocho was a field. Haeundae was just water.
But how are the people there now?
They're now quite well-off.
Why do you think that is?
People.
It's because of new people.
With new people, the surroundings change.
And with such a makeover...
there is...
a difference in land value.
That's my plan for Inseo-dong.
You live in Inseo-dong.
Then everyone will be envious.
I'll make that for you.
I'm good as my word, right?
Yeah.
Should we block the entrance?
Get the bodyguards back on the chairman.
what? -Get them back. Damn
I took long enough.
You can enjoy the details.
We object to Inseo-dong redevelopment!
We object, We object!
Arrest Cho Young-gook!
Arrest him, Arrest him! Arrest him, Arrest him!
Telling lies of best to come!
Telling lies, Telling lies!
Chairman, talk to us!
Let's not go that far.
kill that bastard, kill him.
Bastard.
Chairman!
Hey.
Noh Jin-pyeong.
You don't get...
Why I'm trying to bust Cho Young-gook, do you?
That bastard messes with people.
Power or Money, either you have it or you don't.
The haves are on my side, they have-not are not.
The poor tries to take what's ours.
Fight with me, so that won't happen.
That's how they bastard starts up fights.
While hiding himself in the back.
Isn't that the worst kind of person? Huh?
The worlds turns that way.
The poor will stay poor no matter what they do.
That make people anxious.
They get restless, dissatisfied.
So they turn unhappy.
That's why people murder.
Whoever kills or get kills,
they both end up miserable.
Hey, why should we live like that?
Fighting all the time?
Can't we help and share?
Isn't that what makes us human?
Shouldn't we live like that?
Yeah...
I get what you're saying.
But now, Han Kang-joo is your chess piece.
What make you any different from Cho Young-gook?
What's that?
This isn't...
This isn't right.
Kang-joo was there? Today?
Yes, Sir.
I trusted my instincts.
and was able to stop him.
Ugh!
I'm sure those bastards will come at you again.
Those prosecutors got the nerve to...
Those guys...
They were there to snuff me out?
Yes, I think so.
If that's what you saw, so it is.
What do you think we should do?
How do we get them back?
Any ideas?
To be honest,
I didn't expect to see you there.
What do you mean?
I thought you'd let Han Kang-joo stir things up.
Hey, I'm prosecutor.
I know. But I didn't realize
until today.
You're walking all over me again.
It's because I like you, Chief.
You're a prosecutor. And I'm an investigator.
When people like us get to work,
they we're exercising public authority.
So we shouldn't forget about laws
and kill people straight up.
I mean, people like us
shouldn't get used to the taste of blood.
Blood tastes horrible.
Rule of law is more appetizing.
We should keep to that. Don't you agree?
That bastard Ha Sang-mo.
I think he recognized Kang-joo.
Keep him safe, Joo-myeong.
They can also stike back, so be ready.
Yup. Sure. Will do.
What's with that laughter?
You're excited today.
What's got you in a good mood?
Is your wife not at home?
Hey, why did you tell me about Jin-pyeong's order?
How is that being loyal?
I'm always your man.
I may be in tatters from all sorts of beatings,
but I'm your investigator, Chief.
I always will be.
What's with the smooth talk?
You say this to everyone, huh?
That's my sales secret.
I need to take a leak.
My bladder isn't working. I keep wanting to go.
Oops.
Subscene@Whimsical
Yes?
Ah, yeah. It's alright.
...due to rising suspicious,
conflict of interest concerning
Inseo-dong's redevelopment project
is getting worse.
Seo-won's Inseo-dong....
Does it hurt a lot?
I'm okay.
Gosh...
I'll bring you some.
Sigh.
Hey.
Get yourself treated.
Oh man.
What'd you do without me?
You'll die like that.
Whatever.
Don't worry and hurry back.
The sick belongs to hospitals.
This won't help...
Stop that nonsense.
Let's talk afterwards.
oh man.
Damn it.
There has been a brawl
over Inseo-dong's redevelopment issue.
This morning protestor crashed the briefing
where supporters of the redevelopment attended,
leaving five people hurt.
Picket- holders burst into on scene
and threw rotten eggs towards
Hello.
HS Group Chairman Cho Young-gook.
It's an ambitious project for Seowon City and HS Group.
I'd like some kimichi-stew.
Inseo-dong's redevelopment project is expected to face challenges.
Reporter Park Dong-joo, what's your take on this?
The redevelopment briefing
in Inseo-dong, Seowon was cut short.
Protesters filled the halls,
resulting in brawls with those attenting
to become nightmare.
The supporters of...
What?
Come on Why isn't it working.
Excuse me..
My daughter's feverish.
I don't have a car to take her to the hospital.
Can't you give us a ride?
Why are there fewer pills?
I just pass on what i get.
You should've asked for more.
What's wrong? Huh?
-What? -Why are you sweating?
Are you sick?
No, its nothing like that.
Here, the drugs.
You know... this can't be helped.
Huh? can't be helped?
Are you doped?
What's taking her?
Damn it.
That bastard.
You'd better not be pocketing the pills
No, It's not.... It's not like that.
I, Uh...
I'm sorry.
I'm really... really sorry.
Don't stammer, but talk straight.
I'm sorry.
Sorry for what?
What?
Yeah, take care.
Here you go.
Who are you?
-Joo-myeong. -Chief...
Subscene@Whimsical
What's taking you?
Don't come here.
Pil-soon!
Don't you think every town needs a fool like me?
A few more would do better.
Hey.
Sorry to burst your bubble.
But that won't happen.
If good judgement ever prevailed,
things wouldn't be this way.
If the rule of law ever prevailed,
we wouldn't have come this far
and you wouldn't be in this state.
They made me call you out.
Pil-soon.
Look at you.
How can you live like this?
Our City,
it doesn't work that way.
Or it'd already be what you said.
You live in your dreams.
I'll go clean out the feces.
So.
Spit it out.
I have a favor to ask.
What is it?
Whether cops or our guys,
get me 20 men.
That bastard Cho Young-gook...
I'll go break his neck.
You'll go all-out?
It'd be hard to clear the mess.
I don't care for that.
I'll quit if i have to,
or get myself in prison.
just let me break
Cho Young-gook's neck.
Hey.
Can you send me ten guys?
Hang on.
-yes, sir. -Team up,
10 guys from each side.
Woo Jae-moon.
Any particular guys?
Younger the better? Who fight well?
It doesn't matter.
Just mad dogs.
Mad dogs will do.
Yeah. No, no.
just go ahead and talk.
Huh? Just keep talking.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, all right. On my way.
Heard that?
Get me 10 mad dogs.
Damn it.
-Do we have wipes? -Yeah.
-We do? -Yeah.
We got backing up to do. Let's go.
Who is it for?
-Prosecutor Woo Jae-moon? -Woo Jae-moon?
I almost forgot. Did you get that thing?
Yeah, I got it here.
Did you check it?
Yes, I did just before.
-Satisfied? -Hey, let's hurry.
That Cho Young-gook...
Get him.
And kill him.
Bear this in mind.
If you give out.
This country will be no more
Subscene
Uploaded By Whimsical