Episode 20.
Why are you giving this to me?
Starting immediately,
quit your job at the company.
Really, what are you afraid of
that you're even giving me money.
Afraid of what?
Anyway, what's there to be afraid of?
My Joo Ri,
because of you, she going crazy
She told me she couldn't work at the company.
That's why I'm giving you the money.
Who is that?
Isn't that Joo-ri's Mother?
It seems like you want to shut me up with this money.
I'm sorry, but this won't do.
Have you even counted carefully how many zeros there are?
It's not 5,000 won. It's 500 million won, 500 million.
Merely 500 million?
So you're trying to keep my mouth shut with the mere 500 million.
It might be different if it's 5 billion!
This won't do.
I'll never quit my job!
You are Joo Ri's mother, right?
Is something wrong?
They say you should not take care of someone else's child.
In the end, I get this kind of treatment.
Why are you being like this? Who was that woman?
She's my daughter-in-law. To be precise,
she was my daughter-in-law.
Daughter-in-law?
Aioo... Aioo... Aioo...
Do you feel a little calmer now?
Aioo... Since I had something refreshing...
I can think a little clearly.
If you don't mind, may I ask what it was about?
You saw everything, so there's nothing to hide.
I told you Joo Ri has an older brother, right?
He's so kind and innocent. Really, in this world,
-there is no one like him.
-I see...
But, he met the wrong woman.
She's very vain, and she has a complicated history with men.
They parted after 3 years of marriage.
Then, that... woman...
Yes. You're right.
But, what made you to...
Aigoo... Really, I don't know what kind of unfortunate fate this is...
She got divorced and found a job... out of all places
My company, isn't it?
My Joo Ri is so calm and gentle
The difference in their style is so great
Even when living with her brother
Joo Ri used to despised her sister-in-law.
So,
it seems like she is very uncomfortable to work at the same company.
Of course. So,
I asked if she could move to a different company
I asked so nicely, yet
she asked for 5 billion.
Oh my God!
What kind of department
is she in, and what is her name?
No, it's fine.
I do business, too, but
Important people shouldn't
Be involved in private matters like this.
Please act like you didn't hear a word I said today.
Ice water!
What's the reason why you didn't take the money?
I already told your mother.
That I'll quit if I get 5 billion.
How are you so confident?
Is there any reason why I shouldn't be confident?
To be honest, aren't the unconfident ones you and your mother?
What's the real reason why you won't quit?
You think you found our weaknesses, right?
Because you were wrongfully treated at our house,
do you want to take revenge now?
I have no such interest, so just go and do your work
Can you leave your work like this during your duty hours?
It's not because he's my son-in-law
But this type of man is hard to find nowadays.
He is kind, hard working, good provider, and healthy.
If only he gets married, as the kids say these days, you got a real catch!
Please stop, mother-in-law.
I will guarantee about my son-in-law by stamping with a seal.
Don't worry too much, okay?
Let's leave these two to talk.
Yes, of course! I know when to leave, too.
You youngsters should enjoy yourselves.
Son-in-law Min, have a good time.
And I'll pay for the coffee.
I have money, too, mother-in-law.
I'm not giving it to you because you don't have it.
Then I'll see you soon.
Let's get going.
Aigoo, they're filming a movie.
This is what you call a nice-looking man and woman.
It seems like you get on well with your mother-in-law
Ah, yes.
When i heard that you lived with her for almost 30 years after your wife's death
I was really touched
I really wanted to meet you.
I'm flattered.
I have to go to the toilet, excuse me.
Chun...chunhee ssi
Bad guy
Chunhee ssi, this is a misunderstanding
Chunhee, chunhee!
Hyodong ssi!
Chunhee ssi!
Let's talk somewhere else. Please don't misunderstand.
Misunderstanding? I saw it with my own eyes
I understand that it could be misunderstood.
I had the blind date today because...
What are you doing?
I was a fool to trust a guy like you
I'm a fool
Chunhee, listen to what i have to say!
Lunch time already has passed and she isn't here yet
I'm going crazy
Isn't this too much?
How could you take care of a patient like this?
I'm not in the mood right now, so don't talk to me
CAN'T YOU STOP THERE?
Who are you telling to stop?! Who are you to give me an order?
Without hearing about my situation, why did you hit me first?
I have my reasons
What reasons? Looked like you really liked her
It's nothing like that. For now, apologize first.
Apologize?
For hitting me!
If i hit you it was because you deserved it. Why should i apologize?
There's no reason for hitting me!
I never knew you were this kind of person
You met that woman in front of my eyes... and there's no reason to get hit?
Utility Pole! Did you have a blind date?!
How it was arranged, why I had to go,
you didn't even hear my reasons, and you just slapped me!
Weren't you too rash?!
Madam Yang, did you slap him?
That's enough. Starting today, I stopped having feelings for you, so
let's live our lives pretending not to know each other from now on.
Fine. Women who are violent with hot temper like you...
I'm sick of them too!
Why are you guys being like this, really?! Aren't you too uncivilized?
Okay! That's the end of the story then!
Let's finish our relationship with this!
Fine with me!
Oh, these people. No matter how mad you are
How could you break up so easily? Let's calm down and talk it over.
The time we spent together was very pleasant. Good bye, Min Hyo Dong-ssi.
Hey, Madam Yang! Madam Yang! Won't you go after her?
It was pleasant for me, as well. Good bye, Yang Chun Hee-ssi!
This is wrong. No matter how angry you're, this is wrong.
You have feelings for each other, you shouldn't talk about breaking up that easily!
MOVE!
What kind of situation is this? Why are you like this?
Instead of pork, let's go to eat duck meat
But we already told Nutritionist Min we were going to the pork restaurant
You guys are going out tonight?
Omo...
Hello
Yes. We have a new employee and since we've been busy we've not gone out in a while.
don't say that. It just makes me feel hungry
Where should we go for dinner tonight?
How about pork rinds?
Pork rinds?
You don't like them?
No, no, no
You know how to eat that kind of stuff?
I really like them a lot.
Let's go.
Yes
Cheers!
I really didn't know you'd like pork rinds?
This is really strange right?
Honestly, this is my first time.
Before you said you really like them a lot.
The meeting was not too comfortable. Instead of being too formal,
I thought eating comfortably at a place like this would be nice.
This is acceptable, right?
It's alright by me.
Why don't you order?
Yes
I'm sorry I'm late.
We already had a round of drinks.
Here.
In one shot, drink all of it.
One shot. One shot.
Woah!
Here, why don't you have a drink?
I'm sorry, but I don't think I should drink tonight.
What might be the issue?
Ah,
It's that I have an appointment. Here, why don't I pour you a drink?
Wow, you drink well
Drinking almost at the speed of light.
Yes!
Dinner is ready
My mouth is very bitter..
Ahjumma, make some nurungji
Yes
Aioo... Push your lips back. You're pouting too much.
I can't live because of you!
that's right. it's all my fault
What're you going to do now?
Now that zero said she won't quit the company!
Even if it wasn't for her,
It's only a matter of time before the truth comes out.
Then why did you do that?
Did i know this would happen?
What're you going to do now?
First, his mother...
I'll take care of her
Her mother already acknowledges you as her Daughter-in-law. Now, just get married.
Sunbae looks like a mama boy?
What?
Sunbae is not like that.
He's far from being a mama boy.
Hey, perhaps...
your sunbae...
with "that thing"...
Are they in that kind of realationship?
"that thing"?...
Are you talking about "Zero"?
It's just that I did everything I can
to bring those two together.
Don't talk no sense
Sunbae has such high standards. Someone like her...?
Mom, do you have dementia?!
Who do you think you're shouting to?
You drive me crazy.
Hey!
Don't tell anything to your brother
He'll make this bigger
Do you think I'm stupid?!
That..that
I can endure my father and my brothers looking down on me
But I can't put up with my mom, who gave me birth, being like that.
Anyway, I'm like a curse in my mom's forehead.
Please, take me out of there. I need your help.
You must have been lonely like me.
Your life is really pitiful too.
eat up guys
How come the meal tables are not full of people?
Chaewon said she had a meeting so she'll be late today.
It seems like Brother-in-law is doing well with his blind date.
Since he's not home yet.
She looked as kind as Buddha.
I could tell right away she is the mate for your brother-in-law.
It's already too late.
What do you mean?
Mom, really, would he leave a beautiful person like Madam Yang alone, and
get interested in someone who looks like Buddha?
I really don't know why Madam Yang, whatever,
is so pretty.
That's what I'd say. Maybe she would look pretty for 3 seconds.
You would get tired of her if you were to look at her constantly.
If I were a man, if I had a truck load of women like Madam Yang, I still wouldn't like it.
The worst nauseating style.
Right. She has the face for bad fortune.
Hello?
Yes.
One moment please.
They want to talk you, Grandma.
Me?
I'm on the phone.
yes yeah min jung omma
son in law min hasn't come home yet
what do you mean by that?
Huh?
He left in the middle of his arranged date and didn't return?
Yes.
Ok, I understand.
When my son-in-law returns, I'll find out what happened and will give you a call.
So let's wait a little and see.
Ok.
Brother-in-law disappeared while he was on his blind date, Mom?
That's what they said. I really don't know what's going on.
What else can it be?
He went out because of you.
But in his heart, he only has Madame Yang only.
Bo Reum's mother...
Go and bring me a needle and thread.
Why do you need a needle and thread, while we're eating dinner?
I want to sew your husbands's mouth shut. Why?
I'm so upset, really...
Where are you going while we're eating?
Obviously, he'd be at the cafe or whatever, so I have to bring him back.
I'll come with you, mom.
Me too.
I'm home.
Where did you just come from?
I'm a bit tired, so I'll go in and rest.
But, what's up with him...?
Let him go.
He probably has a headache, so let him rest.
from today on I will forget you
From now on, let's pretend that we don't know each other.
That's fine! Women who are
violent and have hot temper like you... I'm sick of them!
Even if all the men in the world change,
I thought Utility Pole Oppa would never change.
He's not that great.
man are all the same
Shit.
I mean,
it's not I'm caught between two fires,
so they were fine before why the fighting now?
I'm so starving.
Hey!
Lesson teacher.
Why're you here?
I've been solving my dinner these last few days.I can't cook with my hand like this.
But what about you?
My nephew wants to eat crackers.
Hello.
My second older brother's son.
You look exactly like your dad.
Pick out something you want to eat.
Yes, aunt.
Is your brother-in-law at home right now?
Yes, he came a little while ago.
Wait.
Don't call him.
Completely low right now.
Madame Yang has her shop closed too.
What is with those two?
Do they really love each other?
Why are you ticking your tongue?
A prune like you will never understand it.
What do you think I am?
I'd have a son as old as Bo Reum had I not failed at my first love.
First love?
You even have something like that?
Of course I do!
The time, 20 years ago.
I was playing Mozart's sonata at the competition.
I forgot the notes by mistake.
He handed me a handkerchief,
"student, your recital,
is sincere."
"What matters more than technique is the heart of the musician."
"Student, you have that sincerity."
He was a vocalist who was sitting among the judges.
But he followed me because he was worried about me.
Isn't he someone so tender?
And romantic.
He was a new talent who received international awards.
He'd reply back now and then when I wrote him fan-letters.
But he started to keep his location hidden.
And my letters came back undelivered.
Where did he go when I was talking here?
He has no tear-drop of manner!
Aunt, I'm all done.
Okay, let's go.
Add the cup ramen and two triangle seaweed rolls, it's $5 dollars total.
Cup ramen and triangle seaweed roll?
The person you were with said you would pay together.
I beg your pardon!
I'll enjoy it !
That man has no consicience!
You have to pay, customer!
This is really pissing me off.
I thought you wouldn't drink and be all coy.
You are different than you look.
Coy?
That's definitely not it.
You seem drunk, will you be okay?
This is my welcome party to the company.
The protagonist can't sit out.
I will accept fully.
You are such a breeze.
Manager, don't hate me now.
I know I still need to work on stuff but I will work hard! Allegience pledged.
When did I ever say I hated her?
Since we're in the same direction,
we can just get in one taxi.
What about Chae Won though?
No worries.
I can get home fine.
Please go first.
You seem really drunk.
We'll go after you leave.
Yeah, let's do that.
You can't!
I'm the newest hire so in no way can I go first.
That's mutiny.
You go first, seniors.
Are you sure you're going to be alright?
I'm fine.
No problem!
Taxi!
Taxi, taxi.
Hurry and get in, seniors.
Are you sure you'll be alright?
I'm fine. No problems!
Go safely!
Yes.
See you tomorrow morning.
Go safely.
Go home safely, seniors.
I should go home too.
This is too good to watch by myself.
Who are you again?
You drank everything they offered you.
I see that your wits are out.
Captain Hong!
Who's Captain Hong?
You didn't see the movie? "No matter what happens to who and where or when."
The one who will appear, Captain Hong.
You always appear whenever I'm in trouble.
Oh, you're not Captain Hong.
You're Captain Lee!
Enough drunk drama. I'll send you home so get in.
Yes, Captain Lee!
I am okay!
No problem.
What no problem?
You look full of problems.
Joori.
Hello?
She's doing all sorts of stuff.
Dad, I just finished the party and I'm coming home.
I got in the cab so I should be home soon.
Don't worry and sleep well.
A formidable foe.
I'll hold the flashlight up,
so you switch our noodles with your brother's.
Ack,
this is robbery.
You didnt' see it in the movies and dramas?
People do more extreme stuff than this to win.
We're talking 10 million here!
I got it.
I got it, I said!
Anyone home?
Oh my.
Who's this?
Se Yoon, right?
It's me, Aunt Dohee.
Oh, hello.
Yup.
Director Kim.
Hello.
But what are you doing here?
I'm Chae Won's aunt, and he's her uncle.
You are?
But why is she so wasted?
How come you're taking our Chae Won home?
We had a company dinner party tonight.
Miss Min Chae Won drank a lot.
I had an errand to run around here so it was on my way.
Everyone fine with your family? Your mom?
Of course.
You came all the way here, so come in for some tea.
No, it's alright. It's late so I'll be going.
Then, goodnight.
That smells.
What smells?
Not like they're in the same department and Chae Won just started. For him to drive her home already?
Something definitely smells a bit here.
There you go again with the nonsense. Come on.
Is it still too early?
What's that?
"Thank you for driving me home yesterday."
"Enjoy this soup. Min Chae won."
Sunbae took her home?
Are they in that kind of relationship?
What's this?
As mom said, is she trying to seduce him?
You came early.
Have this coffee for a hangover.
I thought you might had a drink with people from work last night.
Thank you.
From now, the judging starts.
Starting from Uhm Gi Ok
Yes, father.
You chose well the flour, but not the salt.
The flavor's weak and you used refined salt that is not good for the health.
The shape did not form well either.
The noodle's missing a pure taste.
40 points.
40 points? Aren't you being unfair father?
Conclude.
It's our turn, father
"Uhm Gi Chun"
What happens, father?
These are your noodles?
Obviously! My name is there, father.
It's ours, father-in-law!
Although the flour wasn't the right one.
Your combination of hard and soft flour was good.
And the taste wasn't bad.
It was good that you used sea salt
that is full of minerals.
Above everything, your noodles had a good chew.
Thought not perfect, among the three ...
These are the best noddles.
Yay
Thanks, father-in-law!
Their noodles scored highest?
This is someone screwing us.
I know.
They were the worst before.
Father, are you sure you didn't make a mistake?
What do you mean by that?
You're disregarding father-in-law's capability?
We'll work harder, father-in-law!
Thank you
Noddles are like your childs.
If the parents are going to change their child just because he's ugly
what parents,
would just sit and let their children be stolen?
On that, eldest child, Um Gi Moon, who stole the noodles,
is kicked out of this round and disqualifies for next round of competition as well.
What are you saying, father-in-law?
You should know what I'm saying better than anybody.
And second son, Um Gi Joon, who doesn't even realize he was robbed,
gets zero points.
So what is this?
You swtiched our noodles?
What the hell?
I know people steal from each other in this world,
but your own brother? How could you?
You can't give us zero points for it! We're victims.
Conclude.
Wait.
So I'm first place.
Hyung!
Isn't this too much?
I'm sorry.
I told you not to do it.
Father-in-law is so sharp.
Sorry about it.
Sorry, sister-in-law.
How can you switch them even if you have no conscience?
Don't you think you are playing too dirty?
Sorry, sister-in-law.
I have no justfication.
Getting zero ponits for doing nothing wrong!
This is so unfair!
We cant' win.
Geesh!
I was harsh yesterday.
Forgive me for hurting your feelings.
Flowers to make up.
Let's make up now.
Leasing out?
Isn't that too extreme?
I can empty out the store by the end of the week.
So if you like it, you should sign the lease.
We're leasing it out cheap because she has to leave for the U.S. suddenly.
It's hard to find a shop like this at this price.
U.S.?
Going?
We'll come back after thinking about it a little.
Then, please come by when you've thought about it.
Bye now.
Didn't you see the notice?
I am not in business anymore.
You're going back to America?
Without a word with me? How could you?
How funny. Why would I discuss with you about leaving?
No matter how hurt and disappointed you are with me,
don't you think this is too extreme?
Forget it.
I made up my mind without any concern to you.
So don't try to involve yourself.
I got it.
Go to America or to China.
Do as you please.
What? He should be begging me not to go.
But "do as you please" he says?
Seriously?! Isn't he being too much!
Utility Pole, you should back down first.
Kneel and put your hands together and beg.
Forget it. She will do as she pleases.
I have no wish for a woman like her!
It's not the time to think of your pride!
Forget everything!
This is bloody.
Geesh.
What do I do about my lunch?
A madame newly moving in?
Killer style.
For lease.
What is it now?
Choon-hee!
Oh, unnie!
What brings you here with a call?
The help made seafood kimchi and I thought of you so I brought you some.
Wow.
You don't need to.
Thank you.
First, sit down.
As I was coming in,
I saw the for lease sign.
This is a good alley and the deposit is low so I think it will be leased out soon.
You've made up your mind to go back then?
Yup.
There's nothing good for me here.
So I plan to leave as soon as the shop gets leased.
Is there anything I can help you with?
Just seeing your face again after 30 years is plenty.
What more would I wish for?
I'm sorry Choon-hee
I'm really sorry.
Why are you always sorry to me?
Just.
Everything. About everything.
No, unnie.
30 years ago,
when I was roaming around like a crazy woman.
If you weren't by my side then,
I wouldn't be able to be here right now.
I would've died then.
I'm only alive now because of you.
That only
makes you my life's savior.
For getting mad at you when I didn't mean to,
I'm sorry, Unni.
Forgive me, okay?
What forgive.
Why do you say such a thing?
Hello!
Isn't this too much?
What?
I dropped you at home when you were drunk
Then shouldn't you at least send a 'thank you' text message?
Anyway, I heard from my aunt that you dropped me off.
Thank you.
That's why I left a note and pollock soup in the morning.
Pollock soup?
In a thermos, I left it on your desk. You didn't see it?
I didn't see it.
Did assistant yoon take it?
So Lee Seyoon ssi, i mean, Director Lee
did you also have a get-together at the pork rind place?
Yes...
I guess that place is our company's get-together spot.
Did I perhaps make any mistake yesterday?
As I take after my dad, i'm not good at at drinking
Why are you laughing?
Did I make a mistake somewhere?
No, you didn't.
If I didn't, why are you laughing?
What is it? Oh, I did make a mistake.
There isn't anything like that.
You created a website?
Yes.
I can put out the menu early and get requests and reviews on tastes.
That's a good idea.
'Idea Bank' has always been my nickname.
Drunk drama and now, self-flattering.
A formidable foe.
Drunk drama?
What..
I did something while I was drunk right?
What are those two doing?
That 'ding' ...
I seriously can't just leave her be.
You were probably shocked to hear me talking about setting the wedding date so soon.
Well a wedding is a life's big event.
It's not like picking out beans to eat.
I thought maybe we're rushing it.
To have the bride's side rush the wedding,
may have people wondering if the bride's got a flaw.
No!
What do you mean flaw? Not at all.
That's right...
Who'd dare to say such a thing about the precious daughter of one of the greatest families of Korea.
Well,
not quite 'dare' though.
You probably heard from Mz. Go,
my father-in-law's very ill.
The hospital also said to prepare our hearts.
That was quite a while ago too.
Yes.
We are a family who respects traditions and conventions.
So if he passes away, our daughter can't marry for 3 years.
As the mother of a daughter of some age, I'm in a rush.
Yes that must be..
I understand.
My mom should be
meeting your mom, trying to rush the wedding using my grandpa as excuse.
I wonder if her scheme's working out well.
You talk like it's about someone else.
I don't get along with my mom.
I'm not exactly on great terms with my mom either.
The rumors have you as a devoted son though.
Not devoted son, but a mamaboy, I bet.
Yup.
The biggest mamaboy of the century.
That's what they say.
I like your honesty.
My mom's no easy cake.
She's going to bully you if you ever marry me.
You will marry me?
I'll answer you after I asked someone about it.
Who are you going to ask about your own marriage?
Do you believe in fortune tellers?
A great couple.
Oh my.
The weather's still cold. Aren't your hands chilly?
I'm fine.
Oh my. See how demure and graceful you are.
You're not like the other misses of these days.
It looks like you really like your daughter-in-law-to-be.
Of course.
What took you so long to come to us finally?
Oh my see how pretty her smile is too.
Don't be my daughter-in-law. Be my daughter instead.
Long time no see
What again?
Let's talk.
I've told you. I don't have anything to talk about with you.
Today is really the last time.
For the last time. A real final time,
I have to decide something after meeting you so I came.
Just give me 10 minutes to talk with you.
Quickly say it If you have anything to say
My family's waiting for me at home.
They're all good, right? Father-in-law too.
He's not your father-in-law anymore.
You don't need to be so precise.
I know.
What did you need to say?
A few days ago, I went on a marriage meeting.
My mom really likes the woman.
That's good.
The parents are the two sides are rushing the wedding.
So they're saying to set a wedding date soon.
Congrats!
I wanted...
to ask you something for the last time.
What do you want to ask?
We...
Can't we start again?
Are we really over?
I already told you.
We are over.
You may have ended it
But i didn't.
If there's a thread of hope left.
I want to grab onto it.
I want to start again.
I really can't send you away.
Our fate's finished.
It's over now.
You did all you could.
You begged, you threatened, and you clang on pitifully.
But still, I won't ever come back to you.
I'm sorry, but the more you're like this, the scarier to me.
I see.
Now that you met a new woman, start again.
Luckily, your mother likes her.
So you'll be able to live happily
So, this is really the end?
It's the end.
Okay.
I won't look for you again.
Then please leave.
Wait a minute.
Because it's the last time.
Really the last time.
You have to live well.
Go!
I'm leaving.
What did I tell you?!
Changing the noodles is stealing!
Only if you had chosen well the materials...
I wouldn't have thought of doing this.
So it's all my fault?
No matter how much i think about it...
it's like that
I'd rather come in last than lose the right to participate in the next competition.
I told that Seul Rong to come back to the country so long ago. But where the heck is he?
Would that shape us any better anyway?
It's be better to have an extra brain.
Yo whats up mom
HEY!
COME HOME RIGHT NOW!
I think this is to unfair father-in-law
Give us at least 20 points
We worked really hard on those noodles and we got 0 points.
And frankly, we weren't the ones who stole the noodles.
But what can we do when someone steals them?
The old saying goes, 10 people can't fight 1 robber.
No need to waste time talking about what's already done.
Just prepare for the next challenge.
Then Father-in-law, given this situation
Give us a hint please
I'm hungry. Are you almost done getting it ready?
Father-in-law, father-in-law!
He's screwing with us!
Why did sister-in-law pull us down too?
Calm down
Let's calm down
Uhm...
Dad, are you hurt anywhere?
No, I'm okay.
Grandma told me you were in your room all day.
Oh, i think you have fever.
Fever? What fever? I'm okay
Eat dinner now.
Because I was in bed all day
I haven't digested the lunch yet.
I have no appetite so you go out and eat first.
It's really weird.
Are you really not hurt anywhere?
I'm fine
Don't worry about me
And have dinner now, my princess.
Go to eat!
You're returning to America?
How can you do this?
I can decide this on my own
so, don't get in my way
How can she make that decision without telling me?
So that means that our love...
didn't mean anything
This is too much. If i'm telling him i'm going back to America
At least he should try to stop me
During all this time, did he really love me?
How can he be so cruel?
So were you with daughter-in-law all this time?
No.
Then if you didn't and you don't smell like alcohol...
Where were you till now?
I just had some things to think over.
So i went on a drive
What did you have to think?
Why don't you answer?
I'll do it
What thing?
Marriage.
I'll do it.
Really?
Yes.
Aigoo, finally
Do you like it that much?
Of course I do!
Manse manse!
Why are you so noisy?
Your brother says he's made a decision!
Decision?
He's marrying with Taesan Group's youngest daughter!
Really oppa?
Yes.
Aigoo, my Cheol Gyu
Yay
This is a dream come true
Joori, pinch me.
It's real life!
My mom is really excited, huh?
This is like winning the lottery.
My biggest lottery in my life.
Hurray!
Did something good happen?
I just received my pay.
Today must be pay day.
Congrats.
I can't remember the last paycheck I got from working.
It's like I accomplished something big and I feel full already without eating.
I feel like I became rich.
And when I think about how my dad's going to be happy, I feel so great, you know.
I have had him worried this whole time but now he can relax finally.
This is all thanks to you.
Are you only going to thank me in words?
I can't just say it in words.
Buy me something then.
My dinner appointment has been cancelled, you can buy me dinner
Oh, what can i do? I have a nutritionalists' meeting in Crystal hotel today
What? Aren't you making an excuse?
I can't today, but next time, I will treat you a grand,
no, two meals!
Sorry for today.
Wow!
There's nobody like you.
Thank you.
Did you have a nice dream last night?
What... what's that?
It's my dog Coco.
Why is this here?
He's a family member
Coco, say hi!
I..I don't like it.
It's okay.
Aigoo, aigoo.
Coco, where're you going?
Coco, where are you?
That girl, what is she doing?
Her mother-in-law fell and she goes after that dog?
Is she in her right mind or what?
Chae-won.
Coco, Coco where are you?
Cheol gyu ssi!
Subtitles brought to you by The Inheritance Team @Viki.com