(The truth has risen to the surface.)
(When the truth opens its eyes, every story begins.)
Pushing the gates.
(The private jet of Legend Entertainment crashes.)
(The disappeared plane and hidden secrets)
(Nine survivors drift to a deserted island.)
My gosh.
You know where you're going, right?
He takes better care of others when he should be taking care of us.
If you want to die, die alone.
If you want to go, go by yourself. You jerk.
I killed someone.
That jerk killed others to save himself.
(Only one survivor makes it out of the deserted island.)
- What happened? - Tell us what you've been through.
Are they alive?
(But she loses all of her memory.)
(They have to get her memory back to find the truth.)
Medically speaking, she is supposed to remember.
She remembers, but she's pretending not to.
Is that what you're saying?
(A man tries to discover the truth.)
My sister...
died. To be specific,
she was murdered in that island.
Let's look around.
(Everything feels unfamiliar.)
There it is.
You keep saying we're almost there.
(What happened to the nine people who went missing?)
(Missing9, the records of the 9 people's survival)
(The door to the shocking truth opens now.)
(Missing9, The Beginning)
- Now, you all came back alive. - Yes.
- Please say hello to the viewers. - Let them know you're alive.
Hello. I'm Choung Kyung Ho. I play Seo Joon Oh. It's good to see you.
- All right. - It's Choung Kyung Ho.
Hello. I'm Baek Jin Hee. I play Ra Bong Hee.
I want to go missing with her.
Hello. I'm Choi Tae Joon. I play Choi Tae Ho in Missing9.
- He's handsome. - He is.
Hello. I'm Lee Sun Bin. I play Ha Ji Ah in Missing9.
- Ha Ji Ah. I see. - She's very popular these days.
(Character Analysis)
Nine missing people.
(A man is tracking the nine missing people.)
(From the plane crash to the present)
I wonder what happened...
during those four months.
(He has been continuously chasing the nine missing people.)
(Character Relationships Chart)
(Who is this man that feels somehow familiar?)
Hello.
I'm Kwon Hyuk Soo. I play Prosecutor Cho...
in Missing9.
That woman named Ra Bong Hee lost all of her memories.
Should I look into it further?
Isn't it boring to investigate one target?
Okay. I got it.
(He plays a crucial role in finding the truth.)
In Missing9, you'll see 9 people who disappear.
What on earth happened to them?
To solve that mystery,
I investigated the identity of those nine people...
very secretly.
First of all, after the plane crash,
they were stuck in a deserted island for four months.
During that time, someone was at the center of every incident.
It's Ra Bong Hee.
It was her.
They've found a survivor from the plane crash.
(They find Legend Entertainment's private jet in four months.)
- They've found that plane. - They've found it.
She's the only survivor.
She's also the only witness who knows everything...
that happened on the deserted island.
(Ra Bong Hee, a 26-year-old stylist, is the only survivor and witness.)
(Her life as a diver ends.)
After leaving her mom who dives for a living,
Ra Bong Hee moves to Seoul to follow her dream.
Today is my first day of work.
I'm Mr. Seo Joon Oh's stylist.
- Who are you? - Hello, I'm Ra Bong Hee. I'm new.
- It's a damp material, and... - It's too ordinary.
After a long search, she finds a job...
working as a stylist for a former star Seo Joon Oh.
(She's a stylist for Seo Joon Oh.)
As it's her first business trip abroad on her first job,
Bong Hee is very excited.
This is incredible.
Gosh, it's huge in here.
However, the excitement doesn't last.
After a sudden plane crash, she finds herself in a deserted island.
What should I do?
However, she doesn't lose hope.
She's strong enough and has skills to survive on a deserted island.
I can't let myself starve to death. I survived the plane crash.
(Bong Hee is always positive.)
It looks delicious.
After many dangerous situations and mysterious incidents,
she's rescued from the deserted island.
What secrets does she know after being rescued?
Ra Bong Hee came back as the only survivor.
She was on...
Legend Entertainment's private jet.
There's another character we must take a careful look at.
Seo Joon Oh.
(Seo Joon Oh)
(A former leader of Dreamers, Joon Oh has the key to the mystery.)
What should we do when I dislike all the outfit?
(He's immature.)
Remove the splinter.
(He gets scared easily.)
Joon Oh used to be a big star.
I had been drinking, but I didn't drink and drive.
However, he makes a big mistake and completely ruins his career.
I made many new songs.
Let's take a look at other songs.
The president of his agency looks down on him.
In the end, he starts to do everything to make a living.
(He's willing to do anything.)
Open your mouth wide.
Hoping to make a comeback, he travels abroad for a concert.
After a sudden plane crash,
he lands on a deserted island.
(He lands on a deserted island after a sudden plane crash.)
While Joon Oh is devastated,
Bong Hee approaches first and takes care of him.
- Come here for a minute. - What is it?
(He gets his strength back.)
Thanks to Bong Hee, he gets his strength back.
They start their life with many ups and downs on a deserted island.
I think this is better.
(They argue a lot.)
They often get into arguments.
On a deserted island,
they start to open up...
little by little by depending on each other.
(They open up to each other.)
It's okay. Stop crying.
Don't cry.
(Joon Oh comforts Bong Hee.)
What will be their destiny?
(What will be their destiny?)
- What is it? - I play the leading role after all.
Please get me a new stylist, Mr. Hwang.
Sure I will. That's not difficult to do.
(Choi Tae Ho enjoys the prime of his career.)
(A top actor, he's a selfish, cold-hearted troublemaker.)
As we continue working together...
What do you want to say?
We'll get jealous of each other.
Why do you think we disbanded?
We'll worry.
(They start to worry.)
We'll also fight.
Don't bring other people down with you.
If you're leaving, leave by yourself.
We'll resent each other.
(They resent each other.)
Let's trust each other.
Okay?
(They used to trust each other.)
They were close at one point.
Now, they became each other's enemy.
What created a distance between them?
- Why should we do that for them? - If you want to...
Tae Ho is utterly cold-hearted.
He's the most selfish of the selfish.
(His cold-heartedness becomes more obvious.)
If you want to survive,
you must listen to me.
(He provokes division and confusion.)
It's Ha Ji Ah, Tae Ho's girlfriend.
(Ha Ji Ah is a 26-year-old actress with an incurable disease.)
With arrogant looks,
Ji Ah is unfriendly and straightforward.
- Did you take the photos? - No, I didn't.
Gosh, your skin looks so old. You need to get some facial.
See you.
With her boyish charms,
she's very popular.
Do your fans know how mean you are?
They beg me to curse at them because it's sexy.
She has a secret that she couldn't tell anyone.
It's a mysterious disease she has.
Don't look at me like that. I won't die.
With an incurable disease, she's trapped on a deserted island.
Her life starts to be at risk.
Jeong Ki Joon is a character who helps people in secret.
(As Joon Oh's manager, he secretly takes care of Ji Ah.)
I caught it!
(He stays positive even in the worst situation.)
As you keep grilling it...
Even if the only food they have is coconuts,
he remains very positive.
Let's continue the shoot since I always listen to you.
All I have to do is shake that thing at the camera 2 or 3 times.
He put up with Joon Oh's demanding personality with patience...
and guides him.
We have to cancel the shoot. I don't like any of the outfits.
Though we're less popular, we're still Dreamers.
Ki Joon is a loyal person whose goal in life...
is to make Joon Oh a top star again.
The way Ki Joon looks at the couple...
is very suspicious.
I should go and look for them.
Aren't you worried about your girlfriend, Ji Ah?
(Ki Joon is unhappy with Tae Ho.)
The two men find Ji Ah in a dangerous situation,
and they run up to her at the same time.
(The two men run up to Ji Ah whose life is at stake.)
Ji Ah finally wakes up after overcoming difficult moments.
(Ji Ah overcomes difficult moments.)
She finds Tae Ho next to her.
Did you save me?
However, she could wake up...
because of Ki Joon's devoted care.
My boyfriend is amazing.
(Tae Ho doesn't tell her the truth.)
Gosh, you're so clumsy. Don't get hurt again, okay?
Stay tuned to find out how their love triangle...
will turn out.
A spectacular mystery drama, Missing9.
It's a whirlwind of shocking events...
that takes place around the nine missing people.
What will be their fate?
Was there a scene like that?
- Yes, there was. - That was great.
We just watched the whole drama.
Is that everything?
- We only shot until then. - You watched everything.
Kyung Ho.
What do you think makes your character charming?
I play an actor who doesn't know how to do...
anything for himself.
After the plane crash,
he learns a lot of things...
in the process of surviving.
He matures as a person.
On the other hand, Baek Jin Hee...
plays the stylist of a former star.
- She plays his stylist. - She plays Ra Bong Hee.
However, you only worked...
as his stylist for a day.
I was his stylist for one day.
I went in the water the most to catch fish...
and shellfish.
I did many things including building a hut.
- You worked as his manager, too. - You did everything.
I played many roles.
When you land on a deserted island,
- no stylist is necessary. - That's true.
You're too busy trying to survive.
In the beginning,
Bong Hee is very hopeful about being rescued.
- We will survive. - We will survive.
(We will survive, won't we?)
She plays a positive character.
However, including...
"Empress Ki" and "My Daughter, Geum Sa Wol",
every drama...
Baek Jin Hee appeared was very popular.
Do you feel pressured about this drama?
I don't feel pressured so much,
but we had a difficult time during the shoot.
All staff members and the cast...
went in the water despite the cold weather.
The weather was a big factor.
I hope the difficult times turn out worthwhile.
- Choi Tae Joon. - Choi Tae Joon.
His work has been impressive.
He's working on many things including variety shows.
I heard you play a malicious villain in this drama.
I feel at ease playing a villain.
As I play this character,
I can say everything I want.
Without hesitating, right?
When we land on the island, I'm the only one...
not carrying any luggage.
It was convenient during the shoot.
Everyone else was carrying water bottles.
Even Kim Sang Ho was carrying something.
(He's at ease in front of a senior actor.)
Why isn't he carrying anything when I am?
- What? - I think it's this way.
(The rest of the actors are having a hard time.)
Be quiet.
Joon Oh!
(The rest of the actors are having a hard time.)
Tae Ho.
(He's very comfortable.)
(While others are working, he stays seated and thinks.)
We received an emergency report.
- What is it? - If it's real,
it's shocking news.
According to this information I received,
Tae Joon and Sun Bin kissed as soon as they met.
(They're lovers in the drama.)
When are you going to kiss Tae Ho?
(The first scene they're shooting is a heated kissing scene.)
- Timing is important. - It shouldn't be too...
(The shoot began suddenly while they're still feeling all awkward.)
I'm very honored...
that Sun Bin shot her very first...
kissing scene in dramas with me.
- Aren't I right? - Yes.
- Really? - Yes. It'll be remembered...
as a good memory...
- That sounds weird. - "Good memory".
- No, I mean... - You made good memories?
- That's not what I meant. - You're saying it was memorable.
I tried my best to be considerate of her feelings...
and to make it less awkward.
- We were all over the place. - Yes, we were.
All of us were there.
- That's right. - We were peeping at them.
Sun Bin. When you were saying that you were all over the place,
- you gave him the thumbs up. - No, I didn't.
We were all over the place.
(She gave him the thumbs up.)
(Let's take a sneak peek at their kissing scene.)
(You can watch the full scene next Wednesday.)
- So the four of you came back. - Yes.
I want to know what happened to those who went missing with you.
- Here's Reporter Lee Teuk. - Do you know something?
Sadly, Chan Yeol...
couldn't get rescued. That's why...
he couldn't make it here today.
But since I'm so resourceful,
I managed to get a hold of him...
- who's on the deserted island now. - I see.
Let's talk to Chan Yeol now.
- Right now? - Yes. Chan Yeol?
Will he come out?
(She looks around.)
- What is going on? - Is he here?
Hello. I'm Chan Yeol, and I'll be playing Lee Yeol in Missing9.
Kyung Ho, Jin Hee,
- I miss him. - Tae Joon, and Sun Bin.
- I know, right? - Can you guys see me?
- He's cute. - Hello.
I haven't been rescued,
so I wasn't able to join the special today.
I'll be rescued soon, so don't worry about me too much.
The drama will make you...
sit at the edge of your seat the whole time you're watching it...
because it'll be filled with so many interesting and thrilling incidents,
so please look forward to it.
Also, please watch the drama...
and find out how I'll manage to return...
from the deserted island safe and sound.
If you want to rescue me from the island,
please make sure to watch Missing9 every Wednesday and Thursday.
Bye!
(Lee Yeol, age 23, former member of Dreamers and solo artist)
My character, Lee Yeol,
was the youngest member...
of the famous group, Dreamers. After the group disbanded,
he became a popular solo artist.
- You have to top the music charts. - I'll do my best.
- Mr. Hwang, the song is ready. - Okay! Let me hear it.
As a solo artist, he inherited Dreamers' style of music.
He also continues to respect Joon Oh even after the disbandment.
Joon Oh, are you okay? Did you get hurt?
(He's the only member who trusts Joon Oh.)
I'm going to do what Joon Oh says.
(I'm going to do what Joon Oh says.)
He's our leader, you know.
(President)
Hello, I'm Kim Sang Ho.
In Missing9,
I'll be playing the president of Legend Entertainment,
Hwang Jae Gook.
He doesn't lose his sense of humor even on the deserted island,
and he's so down-to-earth.
Hwang Jae Gook is like a big brother to everyone in Missing9.
Gather here, everyone. Let's lift our spirits up.
We should be grateful that we're alive. Wait, hold on a second.
(His quirky charms stand out even more on the island.)
I couldn't even sleep.
Then there's this guy who follows the big boss like his shadow...
while charming us with his presence.
In the drama, I'm Mr. Hwang Jae Gook's secretary...
as well as the director of Legend Entertainment,
Tae Ho Hang. I'm actor Tae Hang Ho.
My character tends to blow things out of proportion.
- Gosh, my goodness! - That's how his personality is.
(He's a timid guy.)
I won't make it. Just go.
Stop talking nonsense!
(They bicker at each other, yet they have the best teamwork.)
The mysterious last missing person...
is the top actress of Legend Entertainment, Yoon So Hee.
(Top actress of Legend Entertainment, Yoon So Hee)
Hello.
I'm Ryu Won, and I'll be playing Yoon So Hee.
She's a top actress of Korea.
She's very sensitive...
and tender-hearted. She also has a rich sensibility.
Hey, Yoon So Hee!
(She's unpredictable.)
I saw it. All of us will die here.
Someone is going to kill everyone so that they can survive.
And these two characters will add weight to the drama.
The person who is trying to conceal the truth.
I'm Cho Hee Kyung from the special investigation commission.
I'm Yoon Tae Young from the Western Seoul Prosecutors' Office.
(Yoon Tae Young is after the truth.)
The psychological warfare surrounding the truth.
Trying to unravel the mysterious relationships...
among the nine missing people...
makes the incident become more of an unsolvable riddle.
(Things get more mysterious.)
How will the truth about the mystery...
come to light?
I really want to know whom all of you were most excited...
about working with before the filming began.
- I'm curious, too. - In my case...
I've known Jin Hee for a while.
- I'd say it was Oh Jung Se. - I see, Oh Jung Se.
I've always been a fan of him.
I thought that I'd be able to learn a lot from him...
and that we'd have a lot of fun together, so I was very excited.
- I had to jump through hoops. - Stop it already.
I'm full. Why did you say that?
Are you all right? No! Don't do that.
(We look forward to their teamwork.)
I'm so glad that you're alive.
In my case, it was Kwon Hyuk Soo.
- He's usually seen as a funny guy, - That's right.
But he plays a prosecutor in our drama.
Tell him that his sister is the only one.
Ms. Ra Bong Hee.
(He'll surprise us with a side of him that we've never seen before.)
(We'll look forward to the teamwork between the two of you.)
We have to go in there. When you're there, you'll see...
I haven't shot any scenes with him yet,
but I was so excited about working with Yang Dong Geun. I'm a big fan.
I really want to see his acting...
and shoot with him soon.
(I'm a huge fan of yours.)
(Tae Joon is waiting for the drama to air to see Dong Geun's acting.)
But this layout is...
- In my case, it was Kim Sang Ho. - I see.
- I'm a fan of his. - Me, too.
He has been in so many dramas,
and he has played so many fun characters.
I'll teach you a lesson!
(Let's watch him on set.)
(He sure looks like a big boss.)
(Sun Bin looks so happy.)
I heard that you guys did a success-wishing ritual recently.
- What kind of wishes did you make? - Tell us what you wished for.
- I wished for my success. - There are always people like him.
In Kyung Ho's prayer,
he said, "I only care about my success."
- I'll answer again. - It's too late.
- Is it? - Yes.
Wish something else when you're starting a new drama.
(At the ritual)
We did a ritual to celebrate the first day of filming.
I hope that all of us can power up and do a good job together.
I'm really excited, and I think...
that I should do my very best. We can do this!
I hope Missing9 becomes a big hit.
I hope that we can finish filming the drama without any issues.
Please look forward to it.
- In 1, 2, 3. Let's go! - Let's go!
(Best of luck, Missing9!)
I heard that Reporter Lee Teuk has another exclusive story.
Is it my turn again?
Hello, I'm Reporter Lee Teuk.
- My gosh. - With Chan Yeol's help,
we got an up-close-and-personal look at how the top stars are...
- surviving on the deserted island. - I see.
Seeing how desperate they are to survive will break your heart.
We'll reveal their survival stories...
to you now.
Part 1 of the in-depth coverage of Missing9.
"Tough Life on the Deserted Island".
(We'll reveal it now.)
Gosh, everyone looks so awesome.
Our team raided their shelter...
which is their home base on the island.
(What exactly is the shelter?)
Well... We initially live together...
on the beach,
but we soon feel danger and end up finding...
this shelter.
As you can see, it looks like it used to be inhabited by people.
Also, it's very spacious.
I think that it's a perfect place...
for the nine of us to live together.
- It's very well made. - The set looks amazing.
I must say, it's better than living right on the beach.
It has walls which block the wind.
It looks like a house, so I feel at peace here.
(The shelter is the survivors' only sanctuary on the island.)
- Did you know this was here? - Let's go in.
The color scheme is very nice.
- This is nice enough. - You guys must have bonded.
(Find out more in Missing9!)
And they shot the poster the next day.
It rained a lot that day.
- Oh, that day? - Yes. It rained so much.
The photo shoot is put on a quick pause,
and we spot these two engrossed in a serious conversation.
Our team went up to them.
What are you talking about?
(What's the topic of your conversation?)
We were talking about food.
(We were talking about food.)
- Eggs are rare in Jeju Island. - I'm hungry.
- I've been up since 4am. - It's a very serious topic.
I feel as if I've been living on tuna ever since arriving here.
Rice and tuna.
I've been eating all flavors of canned tuna.
(All flavors of canned tuna)
- I thought it was fresh tuna. - I thought she caught the fish.
- I thought she ate raw tuna. - She was talking about canned tuna.
Food is so precious here.
They're trying to simulate what it'd be like on a deserted island.
Is that why they don't give us food?
- They want us to experience it. - Exactly.
(He's shocked.)
I'm hungry!
(He's screaming that he's hungry so emotionally.)
(It's obvious that he really means it.)
- That's real acting. - He really meant it.
It wasn't even on the script.
I mean we weren't shooting.
When you're hungry, just talking about food helps.
Even the props become precious meals for them.
The best food of the deserted island is...
kimchi they found in the suitcase.
(She even licks her fingers.)
I have to go.
- Don't eat it all. - Gosh.
There is a scene where we eat kimchi in a small pack.
- I see. - I remember it was so delicious.
- It was actually delicious. - Kimchi in a small pack.
They are too hungry that they start to eat...
the snacks which were prepared as props.
It's so tasty.
I didn't open it to eat it.
I just opened it to act.
- Sure. - I'll just eat it to act.
Gosh. I feel too bad to watch them.
Should I send some sweet potatoes to the island?
"Sweet potatoes!"
Sweet potatoes!
(We'll definitely send you some.)
Aside from the food,
they have another difficulty.
When they're in the sea,
when they're in the rain,
and even when they eat food,
there's a disturbing fact that they always wear the same clothes.
We asked them how they feel about wearing the same clothes.
- You changed into these clothes. - Yes.
- Which ones feel more comfortable? - These.
I can sit on anywhere in these.
I now feel awkward to have pretty things.
No, Joon Oh. Wake up!
(Interestingly, all of their clothes are in beige.)
When they're in reality, they wear clothes in...
achromatic colors, including beige.
It's something we're consciously controlling.
When they drift to the island, they wear clothes in vivid colors.
I think you'll find out...
the reason when you watch the show.
You always wear the same clothes.
We can't even wash them for the consistency.
Didn't they smell bad?
Around the time they start to smell, we go into the sea,
or get in the rain. It's just like washing them.
(They get washed automatically.)
I actually realized something today.
- They even smell like flowers. - I didn't know...
the clothes actresses wear smell so great.
When we came here earlier today,
- I said, "You smell like a woman." - "Smell like a woman"?
- They smelled good. - Yes.
I didn't know they were so fragrant.
(We're fragrant women.)
What should I do?
The 1st difficulty that the actors of Missing9 had with water.
(Jumping into the sea in midwinter)
It looks so cold.
- It's literally a struggle. - Right.
(They do warm-up exercises before going into the sea.)
(In freezing weather, they go into the sea.)
- People normally do it to be funny. - That's right.
(It uses up a lot of their energy.)
- You have to finish it in one take. - That's right.
But the shivering people...
suddenly start to laugh.
This is the new trend of 2016.
Gosh, it was so funny. I had fun.
They go into the cold sea,
run hard on the sandy beach,
and go into the sea again.
Chan Yeol became a trendier sweater ghost.
- "Rubber..." - "Spear!"
(Su Geun notices something.)
There were ships.
Why didn't you ask for a rescue?
- I saw two big ships. - That's true.
I think you're mistaken.
- You're mistaken. - There's a boat, too.
Are those all computer graphics?
- You're mistaken. - I even saw the breakwater.
I think ships come to this island.
They had the second difficulty with water...
when they shot the plane crash.
(They pour water on her without mercy.)
(He's startled.)
Gosh. This is how you do it. I didn't know.
- This is how you shoot it. - Yes.
Let's do it again.
(They didn't pour it on the right timing.)
They keep retaking the scene because the timing is off.
- You were too fast. - It was too fast.
(They're practicing outside.)
We did it!
- Let's go. - Are we rolling?
- Yes, we are. Ready, - Ready,
- action. - action.
(They fire the water bomb.)
This is how they created the close-up shots of the plane crash.
The secret of this scene with a larger scale will be...
revealed later.
They were closely connected to water while they were on the location,
but the hardest thing was the underwater shooting.
I'm actually a little scared of water.
I have a trauma, and I don't know how to swim.
- I guess you don't like water. - I'm scared of water.
- I see. - Yes. I had a hard time at first.
To play Ra Bong Hee who used to be a diver,
Jin Hee spent long hours to fight with the water.
There was a scene where I go into the water...
upside down and get hurt...
and a scene where I rescue people. I had to shoot them all.
It was hard. My first underwater shooting lasted over 12 hours.
When I was done, I was really exhausted.
She overcame her trauma and attained a great underwater scene.
I'll show you a little bit of it.
- Gosh. Let's give her a big hand. - Goodness.
As we just saw on the video,
there were many scenes that looked so hard to shoot.
You jumped into the sea...
- and ran around in the rain. - You also got water poured on you.
You didn't even run around in an ordinary place.
- You ran in the dense woods. - Yes.
I think it was very hard for you to shoot such scenes.
Which scene was the hardest to shoot?
Do you remember any particular scenes?
For me,
- it was hard to go into the sea. - I suppose.
Is it because of your phobia?
I'm very scared of water.
But more than that, the water was so cold.
No matter how warm the weather was,
shooting the scene where I go into the sea or get in the rain was hard.
I was curious about something.
On the scene of the plane crash,
- they poured water on you. - That's right.
- They used a very special tool. - Yes.
How did you feel then?
After the first take, I was okay with it.
After the 2nd take, I thought we'll only have 3 takes.
But as we went on our 4th and 5th take,
I thought maybe they're mad at me or something.
Let me tell you something. When they pour water on you,
it gets into your ears and nose.
- It hurts so much. - I guess it stings.
They started it with a small bucket. I guess it wasn't enough.
- Even the director wanted more. - They switched it to a basin.
That's right.
Part 2 of the in-depth coverage of Missing9.
Checking the actors' charms.
(The first one to be checked out is...)
(Chan Yeol.)
Joon Oh. Joon Oh!
(You can describe his charm in one word.)
- Joon Oh! - He laughs a lot.
(Why do you keep calling names?)
When you were being funny, you called out names. Why did you?
It's because I call other people's name a lot in the drama.
I always call someone's name even when I'm sick, happy,
or sad.
To see if it's true, we analyzed the videos.
Tae Ho!
I'm sorry, Joon Oh.
Tae Ho. Let's stop, Tae Ho.
Joon Oh. Joon Oh.
Joon Oh. Joon Oh! Are you okay, Joon Oh? Are you hurt?
He really does that a lot.
- He really calls us often. - It's better than calling girls.
It's better to call the guys' names.
(He's cute.)
- I'm going to call them in vibrato. - Vibrato?
- "Joon Oh." - Joon Oh.
Check out his different ways of...
calling their names on the show.
The second person to be checked out is...
this man who makes everyone laugh with his witty words.
(Oh Jung Se, who makes everyone laugh)
We approached him to see what kind of charms he has.
(They approach Jung Se to see his charms.)
- He ran away. - He ran away.
(Whenever the camera goes near him, )
(he only shows his back.)
- He knows. - He knows it when...
- Really. - the camera approaches him.
He's a shy person.
It almost looks like he's one of the staff.
He rarely...
passes by in front of the camera, showing off his nonchalant charms.
I hope you could enjoy it on the show.
(We'll see your face on the show.)
Another man who lightens up the mood is Kim Sang Ho.
The word that he yells out the most often is...
Shoes! Shoes! Shoes!
They're shoes!
(Sang Ho heartily shouts out "shoes".)
I lost my shoes in the crash.
(It's because he lost them.)
(Barefoot Sang Ho's struggle is hard to watch.)
(Even while waiting for the shoot, he walks around barefoot.)
He plays a pitiful role,
but I hope you'll watch his cute charms closely.
The next one is Choi Tae Joon, who is kind of a simpleton.
(Tae Joon is charming in a silly way.)
Action.
Some clothes disappeared, too.
(He speaks the line correctly.)
(The line reads, "It's clear now.")
Now it's clear.
(He makes a mistake.)
It's clear now.
(Correct)
There is...
someone else in the...
What is it? My gosh.
It's because of Jung Se.
He's showing his back,
- but he makes a certain face. - To tease you?
I think I know what it is.
(Tae Joon keeps tripping over his tongue.)
(We went to ask him about it.)
I'm sorry.
Say it again.
Why did you keep making mistakes?
It's because it was so funny.
I made mistakes because I was laughing.
Who made you laugh?
- The one who made me laugh was... - I finally get to see his face.
(He's obviously the culprit.)
It was you.
Was it me?
We nominate Tae Joon...
as the king of bloopers for laughing too much.
(At the press conference room)
The mood of the scene...
We meet Kyung Ho getting ready for a scene...
of a press conference.
What's the next scene?
It's a press conference scene where Dreamers' breakup is announced.
It's set up.
You try to hug me.
Then I say, "No, no."
Ready, action.
I'd like to thank...
(He announces the disbandment of Dreamers.)
the reporters who are here today.
I'd like to apologize...
to our fans in China.
(He says something to the fans in China.)
(He speaks in Chinese.)
What was that?
Goodness.
(Chan Yeol laughs while Kyung Ho is serious.)
(The unexpected ad-lib makes him laugh.)
I apologize to all the fans abroad.
I said I drank but didn't drink and drive.
All of these are Kyung Ho's crazy ad-lib.
Cut.
I couldn't stop laughing.
Seriously, Kyung Ho.
You started speaking Chinese.
I can't do this. It's too funny.
(He personalizes the scene.)
You said you drank but didn't drink and drive.
That's the part I laughed at.
(What's the story behind the ad-lib?)
Actually,
this scene takes less than a page in the script.
It's a short scene.
However, Joon Oh turned it into an amazing scene.
What are you talking about?
It was a very difficult scene for me.
(He means, "Keep talking.")
Times like this makes the shoot...
fun and interesting.
We nominate Kyung Ho as the king of ad-lib on Missing9.
(They show their respect.)
During the press conference scene,
Kyung Ho made ad-libs endlessly.
It's a scene from the first episode.
The director and I wanted to make it more humorous.
Which ad-lib was the funniest that you remember?
This is what the directors and staff members say.
They say we can shoot until tomorrow if they don't stop us.
- We kept making ad-libs. - I see.
There's a scene where we play hopscotch.
The director couldn't cut...
because it was too funny.
Do it like this.
You can't play it that fast. I can't see what's going on.
Playing it fast is important.
(It's all ad-lib from now on.)
You can take off this foot.
Once you take off the foot, you can't put it back down.
I said you can either take off the foot or step on it.
Once you take off the foot, what is it called?
What was it called?
Joon Ho, speaking clearly and not stepping on the line...
are the most important in hopscotch.
Did you speak clearly or not?
What was it called when you can't put down the foot again?
It's "No Turning Back".
- "No Turning Back". - I know.
You stepped on the line again.
I won't play it anymore.
There was a question of...
who livens up the mood at the film set.
I thought the person who livens up the mood...
was Lee Sun Bin.
I met her on a different show.
She's good at singing and dancing.
- She was on "King of Mask Singer". - What did you sing?
I sang "Drink Again" by Vibe.
(To break stereotypes, she appeared on "King of Mask Singer".)
(Many were impressed by her singing skills.)
(Her unexpected singing surprised everyone.)
Could you sing one measure?
(She sings a measure for the viewers.)
I'm nervous.
Go ahead.
I always drink.
(She has a sweet voice.)
She's good.
(It's time to enjoy her singing voice.)
We're strangers now.
(Sun Bin loves music and acting.)
We're strangers.
After losing you.
You and I are strangers.
Forever.
That was great.
Next is a conversation that involves pointing at someone.
Here's the first question.
If you can go to a deserted island with one person from the cast,
with whom would you like to go?
In 1, 2, 3.
(Kyung Ho chooses Soo Geun.)
Why did you choose him?
I think you and I will get along.
- Why can't I choose him? - Aren't we part of the cast?
- What are we? - Us?
Do we choose among the four of us?
I'm sorry for not understanding.
Please invite me to a deserted island. I'll be happy to come.
- They can be a couple. - From the back,
I look similar to Kim Byung Man.
There you go.
Most people pointed at you.
All three of them pointed at you.
It's because he's the eldest.
- I see. - I pointed at you.
- Really? Thank you. - I pointed at Jin Hee.
I pointed at Jin Hee.
Right, Sun Bin chose Jin Hee.
It was the case in the drama.
The more I get to know Jin Hee,
the more I realized that she's good at cooking.
That's why.
Soo Geun,
which one of them would you go to a deserted island with?
Let me go to an island first.
- You can't. - How about you?
Which actress would you go with?
- Please choose one of them. - Am I blushing?
Yes, you're blushing.
The important part is the anticipation of the actresses.
- Really? - Of course. Choosing...
is the fun part.
Whom do you choose?
Gosh, it's so difficult.
- In 1, 2, 3. - In 1, 2, 3.
There.
(He points at Jin Hee without hesitating.)
- Thank you. - Congratulations.
Since she's good at cooking,
I can catch something and give it to her.
- What are you doing? - All right.
He's told me many times...
that he likes women who are cute.
When did I say that?
Gosh, he's blushing a lot.
- Please stop. - I smell your ears burning.
His ears burning?
(Please stop, Soo Geun.)
Here's the second question.
Who looked the most pitiful on the deserted island?
- In 1, 2, 3. - In 1, 2, 3.
(Jin Hee and Sun Bin each get two votes.)
Why did she look pitiful?
It was cold, and her costume...
- was a short skirt. - That's right.
I'm sure it was difficult.
I pointed at Jin Hee because she has many solo scenes.
She has to swim alone to catch fish.
She has to find her luggage as well.
When everyone else had free time,
she had to shoot her solo scene.
She couldn't join us when other actors had meetings.
I felt bad for her.
She's the female version of Conan.
- That's true. - Don't you think?
The 1st episode of Missing9 will air next Wednesday.
Since it's full of mysteries and secrets,
not much information about the drama...
has been made public.
It's different from other dramas.
Here's what I prepared.
For you to enjoy more of Missing9,
here are the key points. Let's watch them together.
A sudden plane crash.
Nine survivors and a mysterious dead body.
There's only one witness.
Here's a preview of Missing9 full of mysteries.
These are the three key points.
(First key point)
Here's the 1st key point of Missing9.
Lost memories create dramatic suspense.
(After the plane crash)
After the plane crash, Ra Bong Hee loses...
all of her memories.
She can't remember anything.
I don't remember.
She seems very sleepy.
I was under a hypnosis.
The story of Missing9...
starts from her lost memories.
What should I do?
The press and the whole nation...
focus on Bong Hee.
I don't think so.
Close your eyes.
(They try to retrieve her lost memories.)
They try everything...
to retrieve her memories.
However, as she regains her memories,
the shocking truth is revealed.
As mysterious events from the past and Bong Hee's present life...
intertwine, they create dramatic suspense.
I regained...
(I regained all my memories.)
- all my memories. - I remember that scene.
What kind of story will her memories create?
(Instead of investigating the truth...)
Instead of investigating the truth,
the chairwoman of the special committee Cho Hee Kyung...
tries to hide and manipulate the truth to save her face.
Four months after the plane crash,
the committee decided that no one had survived...
and stopped to search them.
Did we do the right thing?
You're making it more complicated.
Bong Hee's return only shows...
how unjust and irresponsible the government was...
in dealing with the situation.
Do whatever you can...
to recover your memories.
(A man struggles to reveal the truth.)
On the other hand, there's a man who struggles...
to find out the truth.
I'm Prosecutor Yoon Tae Young.
The procedure was...
Will he be able to uncover the truth...
which the government buried?
Also, will one person's justice...
be able to win against the lies fabricated by those in power?
Can you trust me...
and follow my guidance?
This dichotomy makes us want to know more about the drama, Missing9.
This drama is actually...
a story about people who don't give up.
That's how I'd like to define it.
That's how our society is, too.
Those who don't give up values like justice or truth...
will eventually see a ray of light in the situation they're in.
In contrast, those who don't give up...
their selfish greed will end up...
encountering darkness in the situation they face.
That's what the story is about.
"According to the statement given by the survivor, Ra Bong Hee..."
(The government fails to save its citizens.)
From now on, I will...
brief you all on the crash of Legend Entertainment's private jet.
(The government is busy trying to conceal the truth.)
- My goodness! - Truth never remains buried.
Revealing how unprepared...
the Korean government is to manage such disasters...
is another key point of this drama.
(Second key point)
Here's the 2nd key point of Missing9.
The teamwork among the cast.
Here! Here.
First, let's take a look at the teamwork and chemistry...
between Kyung Ho and Jin Hee.
(At Jin Hee's very first shoot)
That was my first shoot.
- Do you remember that day? - Yes.
This romantic guy, Kyung Ho, visited the set secretly...
to cheer for Jin Hee on her first day of filming.
- Congratulations. See you tomorrow. - See you.
We could feel the chemistry between them before the filming even began.
Kyung Ho is such a great friend.
He visited her to cheer for her.
Once, Kyung Ho showed up at our shoot...
which took place on a beach on an extremely cold day...
- with ice cream. - My gosh.
(It was delicious, though.)
However, Kyung Ho transforms into a guy...
who is very cold towards Jin Hee in the drama.
It's as if he has a split personality.
This is why you shouldn't work with someone who has no experience.
A cranky celebrity...
and a stylist who has no experience.
Bring the outfits you have put together. I'm counting on you.
Even their first encounter was very special.
(They meet on a mud flat.)
Ra Bong Hee is desperately looking for job.
It stings. Next.
Seo Joon Oh tries to show her who the boss is.
(Seo Joon Oh bosses her around.)
Gosh, I'm exhausted.
(Bong Hee is burned out.)
- Let's resume the shoot. - No.
Let's start rolling again.
However, he can't remain as the boss for a long time.
Their situations get reversed on the deserted island.
(He's trying so hard.)
Is there anything you can do?
Joon Oh can't do anything without Bong Hee's help,
and he begins to completely rely on her.
- That's the first fish I ate there. - Was it good?
Look at his face.
(It was so delicious.)
(He starts developing feelings for Bong Hee.)
He gradually starts...
to develop feelings for Bong Hee.
How will their relationship evolve over time?
(What will happen between them?)
The bromance between Kyung Ho and Jung Se...
beats romantic chemistry between any couples.
- My gosh! - I'm so glad you're alive.
You said I can just eat it.
You have to catch it first, Joon Oh.
- That's not what I agreed on. - What do you mean?
Hey, congratulations!
From the top to rock bottom,
they've been through all the ups and downs together.
I didn't see this before.
(They're closer than family, but...)
Joon Oh.
Blocking each other's numbers is no big deal...
in their love-and-hate relationship.
- You never told me about it. - Those baby octopuses live there.
Did I have to tell you that part?
(They quibble over nothing.)
Ki Joon, we promised not to keep any secrets from each other.
I'm disappointed in you.
(They flaunt their bromance.)
There's another duo that wants to compete...
with their friendly bromance.
(Another duo flaunts their bromance.)
It's the two best scene stealers of Missing9,
Kim Sang Ho and Tae Hang Ho.
This duo is so funny.
- They're hilarious. - Yes.
- They look like they belong there. - They do.
They both look as if they were born and raised on the island.
From their similar looks...
How can you not catch these? They were already here.
You told me to just steer them. You said you'll catch them.
You said you've done this in the army.
This is a very different situation!
To their funny conversations and improvised lines.
I'm so hungry!
I should do it like this.
Showing off the best teamwork among the cast,
the two of them make the drama much more lively.
Paying attention to the various range of acting styles...
is another way to enjoy the drama more.
(Third key point)
Here's the 3rd key point of Missing9.
The plane crash scene is the most...
realistic one to date in the history of Korean dramas.
My gosh, it looks so real.
How did this amazing scene...
- come into being? - My gosh.
(How was the scene shot?)
All right. It's rolling. Ready...
and action.
In order to make it look as realistic as possible,
the best filming crew from films, "The Admiral: Roaring Currents"...
and "Haemoo", was brought in.
On top of that, they also got the body of the airplane made...
in order to make the turbulence look real.
Many types of special effects and equipment were used.
It was the very first time...
a plane crash scene was shot in the history...
of Korean film and drama.
Everyone worked so hard for a number of months...
in order to come up...
with the best solution to design and shoot the plane crash scene.
The plane crashes into the sea, so we needed water to rush in.
The process itself was challenging.
It was difficult to simulate the aircraft turbulence.
We had to use a few large-scale structures.
We also needed a huge water tank...
in order to show the plane getting submerged into the ocean.
We used water slides and reenacted an actual plane crash.
(This water cannon will eat up the plane.)
- That's a water cannon. - I see, a water cannon.
(My gosh!)
That really happened. Water actually rushed in like that.
(It actually happened.)
Meticulous computer graphics is a must to perfect the scene.
Unlike other dramas, many scenes at the beginning...
of Missing9 required...
use of highly advanced computer graphics.
In order to make them look as realistic as possible,
we've had to consult 3D and SF specialists.
We also had to manipulate lighting and use composite transformations.
Here's a special sneak preview exclusively for you.
(With the added touch of computer graphics, )
(it became a perfect airplane crash scene!)
The airplane crash scene looks so perfect.
Isn't it from a real crash?
Since it's a dangerous shoot, the air on set is very tense.
The actors are stumbling and falling.
It is a complete disaster.
Ji Ah! Gosh.
The plane crash scene could come into being...
because of all the actors and crew members' hard work.
It'll be revealed in the 1st episode of Missing9 next Wednesday.
(You'll be able to watch it in the 1st episode of Missing9.)
My gosh, I'm already so curious.
- There are three key points. - That's right.
- The drama sounds so amazing. - I agree.
I'm wondering what else you think sets...
- the drama apart. - What are your thoughts?
This kind of theme has never been explored...
- in a drama before. - That's right.
- I think it'll be refreshing. - Yes.
The 1st episode of Missing9 will air on next Wednesday.
- Since its genre is mystery, - Yes.
I trust that many fans of the genre...
will watch the drama.
- I'm really looking forward to it. - Yes.
I actually sent my agents out to gather Intel so that I can...
provide those of you who are watching this with information...
that will pique your curiosity before the drama begins.
I'll go ahead and reveal the secret Intel right now.
- Exclusively for our viewers? - Yes.
- I'm so excited. - It's our secret.
- Come closer. - Show us.
- It's secret. - Don't tell anyone.
(One night in 2017)
(Three articles of evidence are left in a secret place.)
(They contain secrets of the nine missing people.)
(They offer us pertinent clues.)
(The mysterious incident that takes place on the deserted island)
(What is the shocking truth...)
(behind it?)
(The answer...)
(is here.)
We went through hoops to obtain the pertinent clues...
that will help us unravel the secret of Missing9.
There are three clues in total,
and I'm going to reveal them to you one at a time.
(The 3 clues to the secret of Missing9)
The first clue that holds the key...
to the secret is...
It's... It's...
this necklace.
(It looks like a normal necklace.)
Ra Bong Hee...
was wearing this necklace when she was rescued.
What's surprising...
is that this necklace isn't hers.
(It's not Ra Bong Hee's necklace?)
That necklace you're wearing...
(Whose necklace is it, then?)
Whose necklace is this, then?
And why was Ra Bong Hee wearing someone else's necklace?
What is the truth behind this necklace?
Please look forward to it.
Here's the second clue that will...
help us uncover the secret of Missing9.
It's the USB stick here.
It's inside this USB stick.
I will reveal the video in it.
(He reveals the secret video inside the USB stick.)
(What kind of a video is inside it?)
Stop it!
The video shows someone's funeral where...
people of Legend Entertainment including...
members of Dreamers cry out in sorrow.
The man who died is Shin Jae Hyun.
I saw everything. That's why you scare me the most.
Don't you know why we disbanded? I mean...
(His death is related to the disbandment of Dreamers.)
why we had to disband?
In Legend Entertainment, it's a taboo to even mention...
his name.
What kind of shocking secrets...
are hidden behind his death?
The final clue to solve the mystery of Missing9 is...
this black jacket.
Its somewhat bloody smell makes you feel repelled.
Ra Bong Hee lost her memories.
The man who hovers around her...
always wears this black jacket.
(The man in the black jacket has a plot.)
The man in the black jacket approaches Bong Hee when...
she starts to recover her memory.
He is controlled by a great power...
that fears the truth coming out.
Who are you?
This dark shadow threatens Bong Hee.
- Get her! - Stop!
No!
Who is behind the man in this black jacket?
If you want to...
enjoy the thrilling drama series Missing9 to the fullest,
remember these three clues that will...
shock you in the end.
Please don't...
forget them.
Let's say your show...
records the highest ratings among other shows aired at the same time.
Then what do you think its ratings will be like?
The title has number 9, so maybe 19 percent.
(19 percent)
It was a little unexpected. She didn't say 9 percent.
(She could've said 9 percent.)
- She added 10. - Does the word "nine" mean 19?
Does the word "nine" mean 19?
(Nine percent is too little.)
With Missing9 as a start, I hope you'll make...
many big hits this year.
It's the new year, so let's hear what your wishes are.
I think it'll be meaningful to tell it to the viewers.
I'm starting this year with Missing9.
Meeting these great people is already a gift for me.
The fellow actors, actresses, and the staff members are so great.
I feel like I've already gotten...
a gift for this year.
I suppose we all had a tough last year.
Missing9 could be...
a good drama that makes you forget about the bad things.
It's fun and very touching.
I hope you'll look forward to it, and love the show.
- Gosh. - That was great.
I hope many people will watch Missing9 in 2017...
and get comfort from it.
We're working hard to shoot the show even in bad conditions.
I hope many of you will watch it.
Great.
- Dear viewers, Happy New Year! - Happy New Year!
- Also, please watch Missing9. - Please watch Missing9.
The new year 2017 has dawned.
We did our best to make a great show.
I hope you'll look forward to it.
It'll air on every Wednesday and Thursday at 10pm.
Please look forward to our show, Missing9. Thank you.
Joon Oh!
(Missing9)
The plane crashed.
Seo Joon Oh and Ra Bong Hee are the only survivors.
I don't remember.
(They're left in a deserted island.)
- Ki Joon! - Yeol!
- Joon Oh! - In the underground...
I don't remember what happened to those people.
You can kill someone again, right? This is a deserted island.
Let's not doubt and point swords at each other.
Please believe me.
You don't know whether they're alive or dead in that island.
Please don't abandon them.
(Missing9)